<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:06:46Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):29475" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418p718</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Heurtel, Annaik</creator><date>1969</date><subject>Molina, Tirso de, 1571?-1648.</subject><subject>Literature, Romance.</subject><subject>Fools and jesters in literature</subject><title>El papel del gracioso en las comedias religiosas de Tirso de Molina</title><language>spa</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q54g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418p718</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Spanish</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mw89p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Poulin, Marie Marthe Hélène.</creator><date>1968</date><subject>Literature, Canadian (French)</subject><title>La Relève : analyse et témoignages.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r2604.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mw89p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qt53n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Borins, Edward Harold, 1942-</creator><date>1968</date><subject>History, European.</subject><subject>Compagnie du Nord.</subject><title>La compagnie du nord, 1682-1700 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0324494.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt53n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nw040</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thomas F. Torrance (1913- 2007) is recognised as one of the foremost theologians of the twentieth century. Eschatology occupies a very significant place in his theology, although scholars interested in his work have paid little attention to this fact, focusing instead on his methodology. This thesis not only brings Torrance's eschatology to light through an exploration of his sermons, correspondence, lectures and short writings, it shows that it is a central component of his early theology, uncovering an eschatological orientation in his treatment of various Christian doctrines. It also takes cognizance of the fact that this eschatology is shaped by such events as WWII, the spread Clf communism, the modern eschatological debate and the world- wide ecumenical movement.  Torrance's eschatology seeks to recapture, on the basis of a high Christology, the  New Testament tension between the present realization of the Kingdom of God and the future consummation of it. In contrast to many contemporary eschatologies, Torrance's eschatology is apocalyptic, ecclesial and ecumenical. It is unique too in its attempt to do justice to the humanity of Christ and to the interrelation of the doctrines of creation and redemption.</description><description>Thomas F. Torrance (1913 - 2007) est reconnu comille l'un des principaux theologiens du XXe siecle.  L'eschatologie occupe une place importante dans sa theologie, bien que les chercheurs interesses par ses travaux ont porte peu d'attention a ce fait, se concentrant plutot sur sa methodologie. Cette these apporte non seulement l'eschatologie de Torrance a la lumiere a travers une exploration de ses sermons, sa correspondance, ses conferences et de courts ecrits, elle demontre aussi qu'elle est un element central des debuts de sa theologie, devoilant une orientation eschatologique dans son traitement des differente doctrines chretiennes. Elle prend egalement connaissance du fait que cette eschatologie est faconnee par des evenements comme la Seconde Guerre mondiale, la propagation du communisme, Ie debat eschatologique mod erne et Ie mouvement recumenique mondial. L'eschatologie de Torrance cherche a retrouver, sur la base d'une haute christologie, la tension neotestamentaire entre la realisation actuelle du Royaume de Dieu et son accomplissement futur. Contrairement a de nombreuses eschatologies, on decouvre chez Torrance une eschatologie qui est apocalyptique, ecclesiale et recumenique. Elle est aussi remarquable pour sa tentative de rendre justice a l'humanite du Christ et de l'interdependance des doctrines de la creation et de la redemption. fr</description><creator>MacLean, Stanley Stephen</creator><contributor>Douglas Farrow (supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Eschatology -- History of doctrines -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Torrance, Thomas F. (Thomas Forsyth), 1913-2007</subject><title>The eschatological orientation in the early theology of Thomas F. Torrance, 1939-1963</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn190.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw040</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f274h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sexual size dimorphism (SSD), or the difference in body size between males and females, is common in almost all taxa of animals and is usually assumed to be adaptive. Darwin's two main mechanisms for the evolution of SSD, sexual selection for larger males and fecundity selection for larger females, have often been demonstrated. However, males and females frequently share both genes and environment and more recent papers have noted that males and females must experience differences in lifetime selection on body size for SSD to be maintained. Over two generations I examined lifetime selection acting on adult body size (total length) in a common insect where females are larger than males, the waterstrider Aquarius remigis. Both fecundity selection for larger females and sexual selection for larger males are occurring in this species and both selective forces appear to target specific components of body size rather than total length; sexual selection targeting male genital length and fecundity selection targeting female abdomen length. While body size did not appear to influence adult prereproductive survival, longevity during the reproductive season was negatively related to body size for both sexes. When the opposing selection of reproductive success and reproductive longevity are combined, both males and females have an intermediate optimum body size. A remarkable result of this stabilizing selection was that the optimum size of males was smaller than that of females. I also examined the repeatability of reproductive success in both sexes and the trade-off between egg size and egg number. Finally, estimates of the quantitative genetic basis of the traits examined indicate that both male and female body size, and components of body size, are heritable and can respond to the selection detected. Components of body size in A. remigis are variable in both the degree and direction of sexual dimorphism and the genetic analysis indicates partial isolation of dimorphic and</description><creator>Preziosi, Richard F.</creator><contributor>Fairbairn, Daphne (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Roff, Derek (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Gerridae -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Sexual dimorphism (Animals)</subject><subject>Gerridae -- Size.</subject><title>Sexual size dimorphism and selection in the waterstrider Aquarius remigis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn20r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f274h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m3334</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A few months after having enacted a criminal statute creating the general offence of sexual harassment, the French Parliament enacted the Statute n° 92-1179 "relative a l'abus d'autorite en matiere sexuelle dans les relations de travail". In this statute, as in the criminal statute, the French legislator considers sexual harassment in a peculiar way, and departs from the North-American position on three points: First, while American law and Canadian law understand clearly sexual harassment as a form of sex discrimination, the French approach is more ambiguous. It appears that the French legislator understands sexual harassment more as an infringement to freedom than a form of sex discrimination. Second, the French legislator has defined sexual harassment in a more restrictive way than in North America. While American law and Canadian law prohibit hostile harassment and sexual harassment by colleagues, these forms of sexual harassment are not prohibited in French law. Finally, on the question of the employer's liability, the French approach is more "timid" than in American law and in Canadian law. The French legislator has justified its more restrictive approach to the problem of sexual harassment in comparison with the North-American position by two arguments: the fear of the "American 'drift'" and the peculiarity of the relationships between women and men in France. However, it is argued that the choice of the French legislator is not convenient because it leaves a significant number of victims outside the scope of the law, and is not clear enough on the employer's obligations. Furthermore, it is maintained that both arguments of the legislator are more caricatural than real.</description><creator>Benihoud, Yasmina.</creator><contributor>Sheppard, Colleen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Sex discrimination in employment -- France.</subject><subject>Sexual harassment -- Law and legislation -- Canada.</subject><subject>Sex discrimination in employment -- United States.</subject><subject>Sex discrimination in employment -- Canada.</subject><subject>Sexual harassment -- Law and legislation -- United States.</subject><subject>Sexual harassment -- Law and legislation -- France.</subject><title>Regard critique sur le droit français du harcèlement sexuel au travail à la lumière du droit américain et du droit canadien</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999816x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m3334</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rv924</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Literacy, as we have come to understand and teach it, is currently in a situation of critical change. New and increasingly complex electronic technologies are creating new literacies; however, our present concepts of literacy are heavily grounded in Gutenbergian print. This traditional understanding is inadequate for the new and complex literacy of digital discourse. This dissertation foregrounds the issue of how literacy, as manifest in the writing process, is affected when composing in hypertext, most especially in the context of the Internet.  This research takes the form of an emergent, field-based, modified case study approach. It is shaped in response to the overarching research question: How are writer's perceptions of the new rhetorical situtations presented by hypertext affecting thelr attitudes towards writing and the consequent decisions they make in response to these perceptions? Information was collected in the form of interviews, observations, journals, correspondence, and artefacts. Methods for collection included both personal contact and technology-assisted remote contact, including email, instant messaging, telephone, traditional mail, and fax. The experiences of seven major informants form the central focus of this study; the experiences of approximately ninety minor informants are included in a more peripheral way. This study offers a detailed description of the complex and dynamic ways in which these writers perceived hypertext as a new rhetorical space, and the consequent writing decisions they made in response to these perceptions. It interprets their experiences in the immediate context of writing theory and hypertext theory, suggests practical applications based on these interpretations, and projects a direction for further study.</description><creator>Mason, Jean S.</creator><contributor>Anthony Paré (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Hypertext systems.</subject><subject>Computers and literacy.</subject><title>From Gutenberg’s galaxy to cyberspace : the transforming power of electronic hypertext</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm554.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rv924</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c9038</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Emulsification behaviour caused by gas bubbles rising through a slag/metal interface was studied in both a thin-slice model and a three-dimensional model using low temperature oil/aqueous and oil/mercury analogues. A generalized model characterizing the transitional volume of droplets entrained in the upper phase in the emulsification process was developed. The transient volume of "metal" entrained, $ rm V sb{d}(t),$ following the start of bubbling followed the relation $ rm V sb{d}(t)=V sb{ propto}(1-e sp{-t/ tau}).$ Based on this model, the birth rate and mean residence time of droplets dispersed by rising bubbles could be quantified. Dimensional analysis was used to express the volume of lower liquid carried up into the emulsion per bubble, thereby allowing better estimates of the droplet birth rate in a practical emulsification process induced by bottom blowing. Emulsification behaviour in industrial in-bath smelting processes were interpreted with the present modelling results. Slag foaming in "in-bath" iron smelting was modelled by injecting gas through a porous disc into a vertical cylinder containing a variety of low temperature liquids. Based on experimental evidence and theoretical arguments, difficulties with previous studies characterizing foam height as a function of fluid properties were addressed, and an alternative analysis in the form of a general relationship was developed. The fractional volume of gas holdup, $ varepsilon,$ in foaming slags containing large spherical cap bubbles could be expressed as $ rm varepsilon=U sb{g}/ lbrack U sb{g}+(0.5gd sb{b}) sp{0.5} rbrack.$ The average bubble size in the foaming slag of the AISI pilot trials on the smelting reduction of iron ores was estimated to be 10-25 cm equivalent diameter, suggesting that significant coalescence of small bubbles (such as CO) occurs in the process. In modelling the mixing behaviour of ferroalloy additions in intensively stirred reactors, the AOD process was used to simulate slag chrome oxide reduction period by ferro-silicon additions. These phenomena were examined with the aid of a two dimensional slice model and then a three dimensional model using low temperature oil/aqueous analogues. Based on these modelling studies, it was observed that the ascending gas/liquid plume created two asymmetric mixing zones: a smaller mixing zone near the side wall fitted with tuyeres and a larger main mixing zone away from it. In "slag free" experiments, a dead zone formed at the far surface corner opposite the tuyeres. There, the particles simulating ferro-alloy additions accumulated. However, in the "slag covered" model experiments, the injected gas generated an emulsified "slag/metal" phase of lower apparent density which lead to the entrainment of the buoyant ferro-silicon alloy additions. This, in conjunction with the significantly modified flow patterns, and absence of any dead zones, allowed the particles simulating ferroalloy additions to be readily entrained within the recirculation flow. These results suggest that the mixing-in of such additions into the molten slag during the chrome oxide reduction period can be accomplished efficiently.</description><creator>Lin, Zuohua Joseph.</creator><contributor>Guthrie, R. I. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Industrial.</subject><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>The modelling of emulsification, slag foaming and alloy addition behaviour in intensively stirred metallurgical reactors /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n2661.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c9038</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z2351</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Magnetic carrier technology (MCT) has found a wide range of applications, including biological cell separation, waste remediation, and raw material recovery. The challenge to MCT is to develop a new method for the preparation of magnetic carriers with the following features: high density of reactive functional groups, diversity of functionalities, and durability of surface films. In this thesis, two novel methods, molecular self-assembly and silanation, were developed for the preparation of magnetic carriers. In molecular self-assembly, 16-mercaptohexadecanoic acid (HOOC-$ rm C sb{15}H sb{30}$-SH, ie. MHA) was anchored onto the $ gamma$-Fe$ rm sb2O sb3$ surface through chemical bonding between the carboxylic head group of the surfactant and iron on the surface, leaving the thiol or disulfide groups reactive. The molecular orientation of MHA self-assembled on $ gamma$-Fe$ rm sb2O sb3$ was studied by x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy (DRIFTS) and film flotation. The self-assembled MHA film on $ gamma$-$ rm Fe sb2O sb3$ was immobilized and resistant to acid and base attack. Magnetic carriers prepared as such showed a strong affinity to Ag$ sp+$ and Cu$ sp{2+}$ ions in an aqueous solution. In the preparation of magnetic carriers by silanation using 3-amino-propyltriethoxy silane (APTES), XPS, DRIFTS, and zeta-potential measurements indicated that direct silanation of APTES from either water or toluene solutions on bare magnetic particles was successful. In acid solutions, APTES films silanized on bare magnetic particles from toluene were more stable compared to the ones silanized from water. Both films were unstable in alkaline solutions. To improve the stability of silanized films, a thin silica layer was coated onto the magnetic particles using the sol-gel process, followed by dense liquid silica coating. Magnetic carriers with amino groups were prepared by the silanation of silica coated magnetic particles using APTES in toluene. Stability tests indicated that the silanized films on silica coated magnetic particles were more stable than the ones silanized on bare magnetic particles. Magnetic carriers with reactive amine groups were proved to be effective for removal or recovery of heavy metal ions such as Cu$ sp{2+}$ and Zn$ sp{2+}$ from aqueous solutions. Loaded metal ions on magnetic carriers were completely stripped off by 0.01 M nitric or hydrochloric acid. The possible recycling of magnetic carriers could offset the high price of magnetic carriers and lower the cost associated with industrial applications. Applications of magnetic carriers with reactive amine and thiol groups in biological cell separation, immobilization of enzymes, magnetic fluids, and waste remediation were also discussed.</description><creator>Liu, Qingxia, 1961-</creator><contributor>Xu, Zhenghe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>An innovative approach in magnetic carrier technology /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t067v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z2351</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dt55h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A statistical model is developed to estimate hurricane hazards in the Gulf of Mexico. The model is based on the analysis of the spatial frequency of hurricanes, the spatial variation of hurricane severity, and the attenuation of hurricane generated waves. The hurricane tracks are modelled as a random line process in space. Tests of the complete spatial randomness reject the hypothesis of a single uniform recurrence rate across the Gulf of Mexico and the inhomogeneous Poisson line process is selected as an alternative model. A non-parametric Kernel estimation procedure coupled with cross-validation is used to estimate the recurrence rate as a function of locations. Various goodness-of-fit statistics are used to evaluate the model. The optimal model appears to support the existence of a hurricane alley in the central Gulf region. The model and the estimation procedure are then evaluated for several idealized cases which demonstrate the applicability of the model to a wide variety of cases. Having defined a model for the spatial distribution of hurricane tracks, a model is developed to describe the spatial variation of hurricane severity. The proposed model is a marked line process, where the marks are distributed according to a probability distribution function whose parameters can vary smoothly as a function of location. Smoothness in the spatial variation of the parameters is introduced by using a maximum penalized likelihood approach where;the optimal penalty is selected through cross-validation. Again, several idealized cases are analyzed to demonstrate the general applicability of the model. Results for the Gulf of Mexico indicate that the parameters of the probability distribution function of hurricane severity is highly correlated with the warm water features in the Gulf of Mexico. Using the GUMSHOE data set, an attenuation function which describes the effects of hurricane at different locations along their paths are derived for both deep and shallow water sites. Finally, the above elements are integrated into a hazard model to estimate design criteria for any location in the Gulf of Mexico. Estimations are compared with current design criteria and demonstrate that spatial variations in the recurrence rate and severity can account for up to 20% increase or decrease in the current design wave height.</description><creator>Liu, Chang, 1964-</creator><contributor>Chouinard, L. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>A statistical study of hurricane hazards in the Gulf of Mexico /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r15n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dt55h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kp610</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this work, an artificial standard material was developed and used to examine the robustness of various different stereological correction procedures. The four correction procedures that were examined were: large-sections correction, Hill's fast approximation, Barbery's correction and PARGEN correction. There were three steps to this work: (1) refinement of the standard material--certain modifications were made to make the standard material (developed as an M.Eng. project) more versatile and easier to use. (2) sectioning and correction of computer-generated spheres--different liberation distributions of single-capped spheres were computer-generated and sectioned. The four correction procedures were used to correct the stereological bias in the sectioning data. The corrected liberation distributions were compared with the true liberation distributions. (3) sectioning and correction of standard material particles--the standard material was used to re-create the same distributions that were computer-generated. The particles were mounted, sectioned and the sectioning data measured with an electron microscope and image-analyzer. The data were corrected using the correction procedures and the corrected and true distributions were compared. A two-phase (glass/lead borate) standard material was successfully developed. This standard material can be made to exhibit granular, layered or simple locking. The correction of the sectioning of the computer-generated spheres and standard material particles yielded similar observations about the different correction procedures. The large-sections correction provided a simple, uncorrupted correction. It performed better in the sphere cases than in the standard material cases. Hill's fast approximation performed well except in the cases of narrow liberation distributions. The sectioning data of the standard material cases appeared to support the assumption in this correction that the locked section and locked particle distributions are identical. Barbery's correction performed better in the standard material cases than in the sphere cases. The correction had problems in situations where an incomplete beta function could not be fitted to the true liberation distribution. The PARGEN correction was able to provide a good estimate of the true amount of free material, but it had difficulty estimating the locked particle distribution.</description><creator>Lin, David.</creator><contributor>Finch, James A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>A standard material for liberation analyses and examination of the robustness of stereological correction procedures /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nm98f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp610</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246t53q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Icings are common hydrological phenomena in arctic and subarctic regions. Their bodies are made up of the accumulation of ice layers formed by the freezing of overflow water during the winter season. Icing formation is a process involving a complex system of thermodynamics and hydrodynamics. In this thesis, the formation mechanics of river icings and ground icings are studied in terms of both thermal and hydrological processes. The energy exchange systems during icing layer formation involve two ice water interfaces and some intra-layer water flow. Using energy balance analysis, this research finds that the outgoing energy components can be ranked according to their importance, with sensible heat being the most important component, radiation heat loss being of secondary importance, and latent heat loss being the least important factor. Further, this research illustrates that the heat conduction between the underlying ice and a newly formed icing layer is time dependent. For example, during the first half cycle of icing layer formation, heat is conducted into the underlying ice, but during the second half of the cycle the heat is conducted in an opposite direction. During icing layer formation, the energy input is supplied mainly by water and incoming solar radiation. Intra-layer running water provides a significant amount of energy when air temperatures are milder, but its significance decreases when air temperatures become colder. Solar radiation during the day may also play an important role in the energy supply regime. River icing formation involves several hydrological processes. The location of a river icing is basically controlled by the channel slope. The damming effect of icing mass plays a significant role in the extension of the icing body, especially in the upstream direction. River icings grow slowly, and generally experience three stages of development, namely the 'freeze-up' stage, 'obstruction' stage and 'overflow' stage, the third stage dominating icing growth. The formation of each icing layer is virtually a small-scale reproduction of these three stages. The model simulation shows that the thickness of icing accumulation increases with an increase in the initial water depth in the channel, but simulation also shows that there is a limiting threshold. The thickness of icing accumulation decreases when the initial channel water depth exceeds this threshold. The growth of an icing is an event-dominated discontinuous process. Even during one icing layer formation, simultaneous growth occurs only within a very limited distance. At a specific location, icing growth is related temporally only over a short period of time. As a discontinuous process, icing spreading and thickening during an overflow event depends entirely on the climatic and topographical conditions. Even though icing layering is influenced by many variables, under small discharge rates, as in the case of ground icing growth, statistical analyses show that the mean spreading length of an overflow event can be described efficiently by five variables: discharge, the temperature of the water, the product of air temperature and wind speed, air temperature and the icing surface slope previous to overflow. The maximum spreading length, however, may only be controlled by four variables: discharge, water temperature, air temperature and the product of air temperature and wind speed. Under field conditions, when wind speed is not measured, this wind related variable may be dropped with only a small decrease in confidence level.</description><creator>Hu, Xiaogang.</creator><contributor>Pollard, W. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Aufeis -- Cold Regions -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Heat budget (Geophysics) -- Cold regions.</subject><subject>Ice on rivers, lakes, etc.</subject><title>A hydrological analysis of icing formation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g4348.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246t53q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602235n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years, the Knelson Concentrator has become the predominant unit used for primary gold recovery by gravity. However, its application potential as a cleaner in the final gravity concentration stage and its separation mechanisms have not been well studied. In most Canadian gold mills, rougher gravity concentrates produced by the Knelson (operating at 60 gravity acceleration or 'g') are further upgraded with shaking tables, non-centrifuge units operating at one 'g'. As a result, tabling results in significant gold losses (mainly fines). It is also labour intensive and represents a security risk because of the high gold content of the material being processed. The main objectives of this research, therefore, are to study the separation mechanisms of the Knelson Concentrator and to explore its potential application as a cleaner to supplement, or even to replace, tabling. A methodology based on the use of synthetic feeds (tungsten, silica and magnetite) was designed to study the performance and mechanisms of a 7.5 cm Knelson. Four types of gangue were used, both fine and coarse silica and magnetite. The fluidization water flowrate was optimized for each gangue type, and the Knelson was then overloaded by feeding a high-grade feed. The extent of overload was found to be highly dependent on the size distribution and density of the gangue processed, from severe and immediate with coarse magnetite to non-existent with fine silica. A two-parameter model to describe the overload was derived, which showed a good fit with the experimental data. Two separable bowls were designed to analyze the nature of the material recovered in the five grooves of the Knelson bowl. It was found that the densest minerals, such as tungsten and gold, were mainly recovered in the inner groove sections, closest to the rotating axis. The outer sections packed at the beginning of the recovery cycle and served mostly to distribute fluidization water evenly. Three modified Knelson bowls, a cleaner bowl equipped with a filter at the bottom of each groove, the other two with different groove depth and fluidization water flowrate distribution, were tested using the synthetic feed methodology. Results generally confirmed the soundness of the basic designs of the conventional and cleaning bowls. The importance of superficial fluidization water velocity was also demonstrated. Recovery of gold with the 7.5 cm Knelson from seven samples of gold table tails from different Canadian gold mills was tested. Recovery significantly increased when the coarser, largely barren fraction was removed prior to processing. Concentrate grade significantly increased, up to 60% Au, by feeding a magnetite "filler" prior to the recovery cycle, and removing it magnetically at the end of the test, to mimic the effect of the cleaner bowl.</description><creator>Huang, Liming.</creator><contributor>Leplante, A. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Harris, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Upgrading of gold gravity concentrates : a study of the Knelson concentrator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f16x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602235n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dh315</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Risk assessment of environmental exposure to chronic, trace concentrations of contaminants presents an analytical challenge to interpret data in a biologically meaningful way. Biomarkers are compounds that can provide integrated information concerning the effects of contaminants on biochemical processes. The metal-binding protein, metallothionein (MT), is a biomarker of toxic heavy metals, such as cadmium (Cd), since these metals bind to MT in vivo and induce transcription of MT genes with subsequent MT protein synthesis. A high performance liquid chromatography (HPLC)-thermospray microatomization-atomic absorption spectroscopy (AAS) method was developed for detecting Cd proteins from two invertebrate models; freshwater mussels (Pyganodon grandis) from a whole lake ecosystem exposure to Cd (Experimental Lakes Area, Canada), and zebra mussels (Dreissena polymorpha) recently introduced to North America. Methods for coupling gel filtration HPLC to AAS or inductively coupled-mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) were developed to provide sensitive and selective information on metal-binding proteins in freshwater mussel extracts. Sensitive metal detection by these methods necessitated precautions to minimize HPLC column-protein exchange of metals. These interactions were relevant to the determination of low concentrations of mussel MT-like proteins (MLPs) by these metal-specific detection systems. Saturation methods employing Cd as a metallic marker for the quantification of characterized MTs were adapted for freshwater mussels exposed to low environmental Cd concentrations. Characterization of Cd-saturated mussel extracts by HPLC-ICP-MS demonstrated the presence of copper and zinc, metals physiologically bound to MT, in the principal metal-binding fraction of mussel extracts. Experimental results also indicated that mussel MLPs are not as heat-stable as mammalian MT. Zebra mussels were chosen as a bioindicator species for obtaining a standard of freshwater MT biomarker for toxi</description><creator>High, Kim.</creator><contributor>Blais, Jean-Simon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biochemical markers.</subject><subject>Metallothionein.</subject><subject>Liquid chromatography.</subject><subject>Freshwater mussels -- Effect of heavy metals on.</subject><subject>Cadmium -- Absorption and adsorption.</subject><subject>Zebra mussel -- Effect of heavy metals on.</subject><title>Metal-specific high performance liquid chromatography detection approaches for the characterization of metallothionein-like proteins from freshwater mussels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dn85q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dh315</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720f32j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>T cells expressing CD4 recognize antigens presented by class II following the contact of CD4 with non-polymorphic regions of class II. CD4 enhances T cell activation by acting as an adhesion molecule (co-ligand function), or by bringing the CD4 associated p56$ sp{lck}$ to the vicinity of the TCR (co-receptor function). To dissect the molecular interactions which lead to CD4 function(s), wild-type (WT) and mutant CD4 molecules were expressed in the CD4-dependent 3DT52.5.8 T cell hybridomas. Results showed that multiple sites on CD4 encompassing the CDR1, the CDR3 regions of D1 and the FG loop of D2 are involved in class II interaction. The opposite face containing the CDR2 region also plays a role, either as another class II binding site, or the TCR docking site, or in another function of CD4. Co-receptor function requires a much larger site on CD4, compared to co-ligand function. A stretch of 15 amino acids which links D2 and D3 of CD4 appears to be very important for maintaining CD4 conformation, or to provide CD4 the flexibility required for its interaction with other cell surface molecules, including class II, the TCR, etc. Crystallographic and functional studies have suggested that CD4 may dimerize, although biochemical evidence is lacking. To investigate the CD4 dimerization issue both human and mouse CD4 WT were co-expressed in 3DT52.5.8 cells. Surprisingly this led to a severe disruption of CD4 functions, although it has been shown that both human and mouse CD4 molecules are capable of interacting with human class II efficiently. As expected, co-expression of h-CD4 WT with class II-interaction-deficient CD4 mutants within the CDR1, CDR3 and the FG loop did not rescue CD4 functions. However, co-expression of CD4 WT with mutants from the CDR2 region resulted in an enhanced response. This result suggests that CDR2 mutants do not dimerize with WT molecule, therefore cannot behave as a dominant negative mutant, which is not the case for class II-interaction-deficient mutants from the CDR1, CDR3 and FG loop. Based on these results we suggest a model whereby dimerization involves, at least in part the CDR2 region. Final confirmation of this model awaits further structural data.</description><creator>Huang, Bei.</creator><contributor>Sekaly, Rafick-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Molecular interaction of the CD4 and MHC class II molecules : mapping the contact sites on CD4</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj1393555.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720f32j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kv40f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>These studies were conducted to determine the mechanisms by which prolactin (PRL) exerts its luteotropic effects on the mink corpus luteum (CL). Three experimental models were developed and utilized in these studies. In the first model, the ovaries from pregnant mink were collected at regular intervals throughout gestation, half the animals were treated with the dopamine agonist 2-bromo-$ alpha$-ergocryptine (bromocryptine), to suppress their endogenous PRL levels, and half were exposed to their endogenous PRL levels. The second model consisted of treating anestrous animals with exogenous gonadotropins to induce follicular development and ovulation, half the animals were then treated with PRL while the other half were left as untreated controls. In the third model, CL were collected from mink at several stages of mink gestation. The cells were enzymatically dispersed, placed in culture and incubated with different concentrations of PRL, luteinizing hormone (LH), follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) and (Bu)$ sb2$cAMP. Using these 3 models, the effects of PRL on P450 side chain cleavage (P450scc), 3$ beta$-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase (3$ beta$-HSD), steroidogenic acute regulatory protein (StAR), luteinizing hormone receptor (LHr) and prolactin receptor (PRLr) mRNA were determined. Messenger RNA levels for P450scc did not vary significantly over the course of mink gestation and treatment of animals with bromocryptine did not alter the abundance. In the anestrous model, treatment of mink with PRL reduced P450scc mRNA levels below that of the untreated control, while treatment of cultured mink luteal cells with increasing concentrations of PRL had no effect on the abundance of P450scc mRNA. The abundance of 3$ beta$-HSD mRNA varied over the course of mink gestation. Levels were low during embryonic diapause, increased during CL reactivation and peaked during post-implantation gestation. Treatment of mink with bromocryptine prevented the pre-implantation rise in 3$ bet</description><creator>Douglas, Deborah Ann.</creator><contributor>Murphy, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Downey, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Prolactin.</subject><subject>Corpus luteum.</subject><subject>Diapause.</subject><subject>Minks -- Pregnancy.</subject><title>Luteotropic effects of prolactin on the mink (Mustela vison) ovary during embryonic diapause and early post-implantation gestation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f4627019.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kv40f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kp628</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Scoliosis is a deformity of the spine that predominately affects adolescent females. Mild scoliotic curves are most vulnerable to progression during the adolescent growth spurt, however, only an unpredictable 15-25% progress to large incapacitating deformities. The present objective was to identify mechanical factors associated with the adolescent growth spurt which are instrumental to curve progression in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis (AIS). An initially curved and twisted, spatial beam-column model of a spine with a mild scoliosis was developed. The spine was embedded in a three-dimensional elastic medium to represent the ribcage. A finite element model of a ribcage was developed to establish its three-dimensional stiffness through a series of numerical experiments. Parametric analyses of both the ribcage and spine models were conducted to elucidate a better understanding of this mechanical system. The geometry, material properties and applied loads of the spine were then systematically changed to simulate both normal and aberrant growth patterns during the adolescent years. The three-dimensional stiffnesses of the ribcage were found to vary significantly with rib level and orientation, and were most sensitive to changes in the gross ribcage geometry and the material properties of the costotransverse joints. The parametric analysis of the whole spine model indicated that the progression of a mild scoliosis was most sensitive to the initial Cobb angle, the spine length, the body weight and the lateral translational stiffness of the ribcage. The progression of a mild scoliotic curve (Cobb angle $&lt;$ 20$ sp circ$) was found to be small due to mechanical changes associated with the normal adolescent growth spurt in both males and females. For an initial Cobb angle of 30$ sp circ$, significant progression was predicted for a female during normal growth. The mechanical changes associated with reported aberrant growth patterns could be key factors in the progression</description><creator>Duncan, Neil Alexander.</creator><contributor>Misra, Arun K. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Ahmed, Abdul M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>The mechanics of curve progression in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx325.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp628</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128ng134</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Suspensions of rod-like cellulose microcrystallites, 50-250 nm in length and $ sim$7 nm in width, and with negatively charged sulfate groups on the surface have been prepared. When the concentration of cellulose microcrystallites exceeds a critical value, the suspension separates into two phases, forming an upper isotropic phase and a lower chiral nematic anisotropic phase. The critical concentration for phase separation is very sensitive to the ionic strength, particle size, polydispersity of particles, counterion species, and preparation conditions. When the suspension is in pure water and in the biphasic region, the coexisting concentrations in both phases increase with the increase of total cellulose concentration. Suspensions with different counterions have different critical concentrations for phase separation. The critical concentration increases in the order $ rm H sb3{O sp+} &lt; {Na sp+} &lt; {K sp+} &lt; Cs sp+$ for inorganic counterions, and generally increases with increasing counterion size for some organic counterions. The salt-form suspensions demonstrate a good stability with temperature, but the acid-form suspension is unstable at temperatures higher than $50 sp circ$C. The suspensions show induced circular dichroism in the presence of dye, such as Congo red. The anisotropic phase has a very strong negative ICD peak when viewed along the chiral nematic axis, and the peak is much weaker when viewed at right angles to the axis. The isotropic suspension shows a small positive ICD peak. The behavior of the phase separation was compared with the theoretical predictions of Stroobants et al., and a relatively good agreement was obtained between theory and experimental data for suspensions in pure water.</description><creator>Dong, Xue Min.</creator><contributor>Gray, D. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Chiral nematic ordered suspensions of cellulose microcrystallites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j036f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng134</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dt572</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Adaptive coping behaviors of children with a mild to moderate intellectual disability educated in regular and special classrooms were examined using a comparative design incorporating both quantitative and qualitative analyses. Children's coping behaviors were examined using the Coping Inventory (Zeitlin, 1985) and their behavior was assessed using the Child Behavior Checklist (Achenbach, 1991). Children with an intellectual disability integrated in regular classrooms were found not to exhibit more adaptive coping behaviors than their counterparts in special classrooms. Descriptive analyses delineated several factors within both environments that influence children's coping efforts such as dependency on adults, external control, the quality of instruction, the social organization of the classroom, and the lack of direct instruction in developing children's adaptive coping efforts. Recommendations from the current study focus on the need for children with an intellectual disability to be provided with direct instruction of adaptive coping behaviors and facilitated opportunities to learn through trial and error in order to become more autonomous copers.</description><creator>Cohen Gazith, Karen.</creator><contributor>Derevensky, Jeffrey (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Adjustment (Psychology) in children.</subject><subject>Children with mental disabilities -- Education.</subject><title>Coping strategies of children with an intellectual disability in regular and special classrooms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t0684.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dt572</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354g775</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the improvement of working conditions in asbestos industries and the recognition that asbestos exposure is widespread, the asbestos controversy has shifted in the 1980s to the general environment. To assess lung cancer risks due to environmental asbestos exposure, risks in past asbestos workers have been extrapolated linearly to exposures 100,000 times smaller than historical occupational levels. Despite their enormous health and economic impact, such risk assessments have not been validated to this day. This is the first study to compare the risk of lung cancer in a population non-occupationally exposed to asbestos with those predicted by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency's (EPA) exposure-effect model. The study was carried out among the female population of Quebec's two chrysotile-mining agglomerations, where asbestos pollution has been visible commonly from 1882 to 1975. Six small exposure studies were conducted. These studies were synthesized by a panel of 5 international experts to estimate the historical levels of asbestos in the three main mining towns as well as the asbestos pollution brought home on the clothes of workers. These estimates were combined with a survey of lifetime neighbourhood and household exposures of female residents to assess the cumulative exposure of the females aged 30+ who resided in the mining agglomerations between 1970 and 1989. The average was 35 continuous fiber-years/mL. On the basis of the equivalent occupational exposure, the EPA model predicted a lung cancer relative risk of 2.47. Mortality of the female population of the asbestos-mining agglomerations aged 30+ was compared over the 1970-1989 period to that of 60 comparable agglomerations of Quebec. The lung cancer SMR was 0.99 (95%CI: 0.78-1.26) and the SPMR was 1.10 (95%CI: 0.88-1.38). Although the EPA model predicted 105 excess lung cancer deaths based on SMRs, none were observed in this population; based on SPMRs, an excess of 95 excess deaths was predicted, but only 6.5 observed. The EPA risk assessment on asbestos greatly overestimated the risk of lung cancer attributed to environmental asbestos exposure in this population.</description><creator>Camus, Michel, 1951-</creator><contributor>Siemiatycki, Jack (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Women's Studies.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Lung cancer mortality among females in Quebec's chrysotile asbestos-mining areas compared to that predicted by the U.S. E.P.A. exposure-effect model = Mortalité par cancer pulmonaire des femmes des régions minières de l'amiante du Québec comparée aux prévisions du modèle exposition-effet de l'E.P.A.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537263g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354g775</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tt20v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was designed to determine the potential biological effects of electric and magnetic fields (EMF), generated by 735 kV alternating current (AC) high tension lines upon the hormonal profile, some health-related parameters, stress response and productivity in dairy cattle. An EMF exposure chamber to house eight animals at one time was constructed. Forty-nine cows were divided according to their production stage; 8 pregnant non-lactating cows, 16 pregnant lactating cows, 16 non-pregnant lactating cows and 9 non-lactating non-pregnant heifers. They were exposed to an EMF of 10 kilovolts per meter (kV/m) and 30 micro-Tesla $( mu T)$ in two different fashions: (a) for three consecutive periods of 28 days in two sequences either with the EMF on/off/on or off/on/off, in a switch back design; (b) for three consecutive periods with the sequence OFF (5 days), ON (30 days) and OFF (5-12 days). The intensity of the EMF chosen for the experiments resembled a situation in which the cattle are standing continuously under a 735 kV AC high tension line when the line has a maximum load of current. In reality, these conditions are found only for a few days during the winter in the Province of Quebec. Milk production and composition, feed consumption, blood hormonal profiles and cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) components were assessed during the different periods of exposure. Most of the variables assessed were not affected by EMF. However, there was a positive association between EMF and feed consumption, milk fat content, blood plasma progesterone during pregnancy and estrous cycle length. Also, there were changes in the mineral and neurotransmitter metabolite concentrations in the CSF that showed a relationship to the EMF. In conclusion, it could be stated that EMF caused a biological response in dairy cattle. It is speculated that these changes do not represent a health hazard for exposed cattle, although they warrant further research.</description><creator>Burchard, Javier F.</creator><contributor>Block, Elliot (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Dairy cattle -- Physiology -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>ELF electromagnetic fields -- Physiological effect.</subject><title>Effects of 60 Hz electric and magnetic fields on productivity, reproductive hormones, plasma minerals and minerals and neurotransmitter metabolites in cerebrospinal fluid in dairy cattle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741t31r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt20v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278v66w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The statistical analysis of brain functional and structural change presents a formidable statistical problem. Computation of a test statistic indicating change at each location of the brain gives a 3-D statistical image. The global maximum of the statistical image has been proposed by Friston et al. (1991) and Worsley et al. (1992) to test for regions of high change based on the belief that the changes are localized, not distributed. To find the correct p value, Worsley et al. (1992) modelled the statistical image as a stationary random field under the null hypothesis. The approximate p value of the global maximum was then determined by the expected Euler characteristic (EC) of the excursion set, that is, the set of points with a value larger than a given threshold. The expected EC of excursion sets of stationary Gaussian random fields has been derived by Adler and Hasofer (1976) and Adler (1981) and extended to $ chi sp2, t$ and F fields by worsley (1994). The first part of the thesis aims to extend their results to Hotelling's $T sp2$ fields and apply the theory to a real example from 3-D brain deformations. Although the global maximum as a test statistic is more widely used, some workers have suggested an alternative: the size of the largest connected component of the excursion set, based on the belief that neural activity tends to stimulate changes over contiguous locations. Nosko (1969) derived the asymptotic distribution of the size of one connected component of the excursion set above high levels for a stationary Gaussian field. Applying this work, Friston et al. (1994) presented an approximate analysis for assessing the significance of focal changes by their spatial extent. Although the analysis was developed for Gaussian fields originally, it was suggested that it could also be applied to some non-Gaussian fields, like the t field, by appropriate "Gaussianization", that is, pointwise transformation to a Gaussian distribution. However, the Gaussianzied field is not a Gaussian random field and hence the approach is not strictly valid. The second part of the thesis aims to derive the asymptotic distribution of the size of one connected component of the excursion set for $ chi sp2, t$ and F fields and apply this to an experiment on pain perception.</description><creator>Cao, Jin.</creator><contributor>Worsley, K. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Statistics.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Excursion sets of random fields with applications to human brain mapping</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924d24z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278v66w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hd69g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>I examined the distribution of stable isotope ratios of nitrogen $( delta sp{15}$N) and carbon $( delta sp{13}$C) in fish and aquatic invertebrates. Animals are enriched in $ delta sp{15}$N compared to their diet and I hypothesized that among-lake variation in the $ delta sp{15}$N of a top predator should reflect variation in the length of the food chain leading to it. A comparative study of a biomagnifying contaminant, mercury, confirmed that the presence or absence of certain key organisms such as pelagic forage fish and the crustacean Mysis relicta determined among-lake variation in mercury in lake trout, a top predator in the lakes. Mercury levels from the longest food chains where pelagic forage fish and Mysis were present were higher than those from the shortest food chains where these last two components were missing. This biogeographic variation in food chain length was correlated with variation in the $ delta sp{15}$N of trout. The use of $ delta sp{15}$N as a continuous, integrative measure of trophic position was further supported by its correlation to mercury in lake trout. However, such cross-system comparisons in $ delta sp{15}$N can be complicated by differences in $ delta sp{15}$N at the base of the food chain. Using large primary consumers (unionid mussels) as bio-indicators, I showed that $ delta sp{15}$N increases markedly with the human population in the lake watershed, an effect of the high $ delta sp{15}$N of human sewage. Correcting for this baseline variation in $ delta sp{15}$N, I reported that food chains leading up to nearshore fish species varied by about only one trophic level among the 35 lakes studied. A study of the $ delta sp{15}$N of coral reef and intertidal organisms collected along the coast of the the Carribean island of Barbados extended these patterns observed in lakes to coastal systems: baseline variation in $ delta sp{15}$N was related to human density on the adjacent watershed and within-site variation $ delta sp{15}$N</description><creator>Cabana, Gilbert.</creator><contributor>Rasmussen, Joseph B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Aquatic ecology.</subject><subject>Food chains (Ecology)</subject><subject>Biogeochemical cycles.</subject><subject>Nitrogen -- Isotopes.</subject><title>A comparative study of food-web processes in aquatic systems using stable isotopes /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pb95n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hd69g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f462703v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation discusses medieval and Renaissance clerical and cultural constructions of femininity and female masculinity, and it analyses the complex relationship between such conceptions and the literary representation of the transvestite woman. Medieval theology legitimated female masculinity as transcendence of temporal sexuality. A woman who contained her affective femininity and replaced it with rational and ascetic behaviour was frequently lauded for having become male in all but body. In the middle of the first millennium, hagiographic legends abounded in which women appear to have embodied the patristic equation between spiritual rationality and masculinity. This dissertation proposes a radically different interpretation: the saint exchanges a sexualised form of femininity--ironically imposed upon her by a male society--for a non sexual but nevertheless feminine self valuation. Early modern culture perceived transvestism in a multiform manner. It signifies monstrosity in the polemical pamphlet, serves to indicate an estimable apex of humanity in Shakespearean comedy, and represents women in roles that range from monstrous disrupter to adept uniter in the works of such other playwrights as Ben Jonson and Thomas Middleton. While the pamphlet's social commentary argues that masculinity rendered a woman monstrously unfeminine, the literature finds ways of interrogating definitions of the sex-gender system in a world which was constantly and fundamentally mutating. The drama employs elements such as inversion, monstrosity and transgressions of class to negotiate a society in flux.</description><creator>Abdalla, Laila.</creator><contributor>Williams, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Gender identity -- History.</subject><subject>Femininity.</subject><subject>Transvestism.</subject><title>Man, woman or monster : some themes of female masculinity and transvestism in the Middle Ages and Renaissance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tq876.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462703v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mw91q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Most blasthole drills currently used in the mining industry are manually controlled. The drilling control systems which do exist are based mainly on ladder programming logic techniques. This thesis presents a comprehensive strategy for the automatic control of blasthole drills, based on closed loop feedback control approach. A detailed model for the controlled process consisting of the drill rig's mechanical actuators, machine structure, and the drilling process at the bit-rock interface is presented. The model equations are refined and validated by experimental (field) testing. The instrumentation of an Ingersoll-Rand DM-45E drill rig and the subsequent drilling tests in a limestone quarry are described, with an in-depth discussion of the field tests results. Analysis of the field tests data establishes the dependencies between the drilling variables and ground conditions during actual drilling. The transfer functions of the mechanical actuators of the machine are also identified. A strategy for automatic control of feed pressure and rotary speed is proposed. The controller is tested and tuned by interfacing it to a software simulator of the controlled process which implements the relationships identified from field testing. Simulation results are presented and analysed. Results of implementing the controller on a Gardner-Denver GD-120 electric drill, and an Ingersoll-Rand DM-H hydraulic drill at two surface coal mines in British Columbia, Canada, are also presented. These results validate the drilling controller design and tuning. The thesis concludes with suggestions for future research and refinement of the control strategy.</description><creator>Aboujaoude, Claude E.</creator><contributor>Daneshmend, Laeeque (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Peck, Jonathan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal.</subject><subject>Engineering, System Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Feedback control of vibrations in surface rotary blasthole drilling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v453m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mw91q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):29500</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>