<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:35:42Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38225" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g199q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Un défi important en lien avec les systèmes de gestion de                la circulation routière est de définir la situation actuelle du réseau routier dans                les régions où peu de données sont disponibles. Les données provenant d'une flotte de                40-60 ambulances munies d'un GPS ont été utilisées afin d'estimer la congestion                routière sur un réseau de plus de 20 000 rues dans la ville d'Ottawa, au Canada.                Essentiellement, le réseau routier est représenté par un graphe orienté et un                algorithme de propagation de confiance est utilisé pour interpoler les données                provenant de la flotte d'ambulances. Ce système comprend des caractéristiques                innovatives. Le système ne fait aucune distinction entre les autoroutes et les rues,                il intègre les données archivées et actuelles, il gère les informations entrées par                l'utilisateur au central concernant les fermeture des routes et les changements de                vitesse sur le réseau routier et il est efficace dans ses calculs puisqu'il fournit                des mises à jour de l'état du réseau routier toutes les 5-6 minutes sur un ordinateur                standard. Les résultats de l'expérience, la validation de la performance ainsi que la                fiabilité du système sont présentés.</description><description>A major challenge for traffic management systems is the inference of                traffic flow in regions of the network for which there is little data. In this                thesis, GPS-based vehicle locator data from a fleet of 40-60 roving ambulances are                used to estimate traffic congestion along a network of 20,000 streets in the city of                Ottawa, Canada. Essentially, the road network is represented as a directed graph and                a belief propagation algorithm is used to interpolate measurements from the fleet.                The system incorporates a number of novel features. It makes no distinctions between                freeways and surface streets, incorporates both historical and live sensor data,                handles user inputs such as road closures and manual speed overrides, and is                computationally efficient - providing updates every 5 to 6 minutes on commodity                hardware. Experimental results are presented which address the key issue of                validating the performance and reliability of the system.</description><creator>Phan, Andrew Minh Tri</creator><contributor>Frank P Ferrie (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Obtaining dense road speed estimates from sparse GPS measurements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f43t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g199q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429c05h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette th\`ese traite du probl\`eme de surmonter les                difficult\'es caus\'ees par l'effet de parallaxe et le mouvement d'objets lors du                mosaicage d'images. Les m\'ethodes traditionnelles de mosaicage d'images produisent                des panoramas en recalant des images de mani\`ere \`a minimiser les diff\'erences                d'intensit\'e ou de structure entre les r\'egions superpos\'ees de ces images. Afin                de r\'eduire les d\'efauts occasionn\'es par un mauvais recalage r\'esultant de                l'effet de parallaxe ou des mouvements d'objets, les m\'ethodes traditionnelles                requi\`erent soit une sc\`ene planaire, soit des images r\'esultant d'une simple                rotation d'une camera, soit encore un \'echantillonnage dense de la sc\`ene.                Toutefois, ces solutions sont souvent impraticables ou ne satisfont pas les besoins                de certaines applications. \newline\indent Dans cette th\`ese, nous pr\'esentons                trois nouvelles approches de mosaicage d'imagesF utilisant l'information de                profondeur afin de surmonter les limites \'enonc\'ees ci-haut. La premi\`ere approche                utilise l'\'echantillonnage dense virtuel afin de r\'eduire l'effet de parallaxe                entre les images acquises, ce qui r\'esulte en une nette am\'elioration de la                qualit\'e des panoramas par rapport \`a ceux obtenus avec les techniques                traditionnelles.\newline\indent La deuxi\`eme approche construit le panorama                correspondant \`a une position virtuelle de la cam\'era en utilisant des estimations                de profondeur. Lorsque ces valeurs sont raisonnables, le r\'esultat devrait \^etre                satisfaisant visuellement et libre de tout d\'efaut reli\'e \`a l'effet de                parallaxe.\newline\indent La troisi\`eme approche fait passer le mosaicage d'images                de la synth\`ese$</description><description>This thesis addresses the challenges of parallax and object motion in                image mosaicing. Traditional techniques construct their panoramas through an image                registration process that minimizes the differences in intensity or structure in the                overlapping areas between inputs. In order to reduce the artifacts due to                misregistrations caused by parallax and object motion, traditional approaches require                planar content or impose the constraint that inputs be provided either by a purely                rotational camera or from dense sampling of the scene. However, these solutions are                often impractical or fail to address the needs of all applications.\newline\indent In                this thesis, we present three novel mosaicing approaches that use depth information                to compensate for the above limitations. The first approach starts by synthesizing a                dense set of virtual images at positions between the source cameras. Next, an                appearance-based optimization procedure is applied to select a group of strips from                the collection of virtual images and the real inputs to construct the final mosaic.                The virtual dense sampling greatly reduces parallax effects between the real input                frames, and thus results in significantly improved mosaic outputs compared to                traditional image mosaicing algorithms.\newline\indent The second approach formulates                the image mosaicing as a view synthesis problem. It renders the panorama as a single                frame using depth estimates from the view point of a virtual mosaicing camera. It                notably includes the contents in non-overlapping regions between sources by using a                depth propagation procedure. Provided that the depth values are reasonable, the                output mosaic result is perceptually satisfactory and</description><creator>Qi, Zhi</creator><contributor>Jeremy Cooperstock (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Towards dynamic mosaic generation with robustness to parallax effects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jz97b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c05h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f306k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'accumulation et la décomposition de la matière organique                du sol est de grand intérêt aux fermiers et aux décideurs politiques, en raison de                ses fonctions importantes en structure de sol et dans le cycle de carbone global. Le                but de cette étude était de déterminer les effets à long terme des pratiques de                labourage et de la gestion de résidu sur (1) le rendement du Zea mays L. pour le                maïs-grain ou le maïs d'ensilage, (2) la taille du réservoir de carbone organique du                sol, (3) la quantité des formes labiles de carbone organique et d'azote organique du                sol, et (4) la biomasse et la structure de la communauté microbienne. Les parcelles                expérimentales à Ste-Anne-de-Bellevue, Québec, Canada ont été établies dans un sol                sableux-loameux en 1991 avec un design factoriel qui inclut trois niveaux de                labourage (semi-direct, labourage réduit et labourage conventionnel), et deux niveaux                d'entrant de résidu (les racines plus la tige, les racines seulement). En 2007, le                rendement de maïs-grain était entre 11.2 et 11.7 Mg matière sèche ha-1, mais non                affecté par des traitements de labourage ou de résidu. Après la récolte, échantillons                du sol ont été ramassés des parcelles à deux profondeurs : 0-5 cm et 5-20 cm. Le                réservoir de carbone organique de sol a été entre 37 et 58 mg C ha-1 à une profondeur                de 20 cm. Il n'y avait aucune différence entre les traitements de labourage, mais les                parcelles avec haut résidu (racines plus tiges) ont eu plus de carbone organique de                sol que lesquelles avec bas résidu (P&lt;0.05, test de Tukey). La minéralisation                de carbone et d'azote pendant une incubation de laboratoire durant 20 semaines a été                employée com</description><description>The accumulation and mineralization of soil organic matter is of great                interest to both farmers and policy makers, because of its important functions in                soil structure and in the global carbon cycle. The purpose of this study was to                determine the long term effects of tillage practices and residue management on (1)                the yield of Zea mays L. grown for corn grain or corn silage, (2) the size of the                total soil organic carbon pool, (3) the relative sizes of the labile soil organic                carbon and nitrogen pools, and (4) the size and structure of the microbial biomass.                The experimental plots in Ste. Anne de Bellevue, Quebec, Canada were established on a                sandy-loam soil in 1991 with a factorial design that includes three levels of tillage                (no-till, reduced tillage, and conventional tillage), and two levels of residue input                (corn roots and stover, corn roots only). At harvest in 2007, the corn grain yield                was between 11.2 and 11.7 Mg dry matter ha-1, but not affected by tillage or residue                treatments. Soils were collected from the plots following harvest at two depths: 0-5                cm and 5-20 cm. The total soil organic carbon pool contained between 37 and 58 Mg C                ha-1 in the top 20 cm. There was no difference between tillage treatments, but the                high residue plots had more soil organic carbon than the low residue input plots                (P&lt;0.05, Tukey test). Carbon and nitrogen mineralization during a 20 week                laboratory incubation was used as an indicator of the relative size of the labile                carbon and nitrogen pools under the different tillage and residue treatments. Both                labile carbon and nitrogen pools were affected significantly by tillage and residue                inputs. In the 0-5 cm depth, the labile carbon and</description><creator>Halpern, Moshe</creator><contributor>Joann Karen Whalen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Agriculture - Soil Science</subject><title>Tillage and residue management effects on soil organic matter dynamics in a sandy-loam</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v478g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f306k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cj38p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> La Maladie Pulmonaire Obstructive Chronique (MPOC) est                une maladie respiratoire caractérisée par une augmentation de la résistance au flot                respiratoire, de nature progressive et non-réversible. Le tabagisme est la principale                cause de la MPOC. La MPOC est une cause importante de morbidité et de mortalité dans                le monde entier, et la prévalence de la maladie continue d'augmenter de façon                alarmante, tout particulièrement chez les femmes. Malgré cet essor de la MPOC, nous                en savons peu sur les différences qui peuvent exister entre les sexes, au niveau des                manifestations cliniques, du traitement et de l'évolution de la maladie. Dans une                cohorte de patients traités pour une maladie pulmonaire obstructive et hospitalisés                avec un diagnostique principal de MPOC, nous avons comparé le traitement reçu ainsi                que le pronostic de la maladie chez les hommes et les femmes. La cohorte était                constituée de 19260 femmes et 23893 hommes, et l'âge moyen était de 77 ans. Plus de                femmes que d'hommes avaient été précédemment hospitalisées avec un diagnostic                d'asthme. Dans l'année précédant l'hospitalisation index, les femmes avaient reçu                moins de prescriptions pour des bronchodilatateurs (particulièrement le bromure                d'ipratropium et la théophylline), mais plus de prescriptions pour des                benzodiazépines et des antidépresseurs. Un total de 11245 (58.4%) femmes et 16754                (70.1%) hommes sont décédés après l'entrée dans la cohorte. La cause de décès la plus                fréquente chez les hommes comme les femmes était la MPOC. La survie moyenne, ainsi                que le temps moyen avant la ré-hospitalisation pour un diagnostic de MPOC ou                d'asthme, étaient plus élevés chez les fe</description><description> Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) is a respiratory disease                characterized by progressive airflow limitation that is not fully reversible. Tobacco                smoke is the most important risk factor. COPD is a leading cause of morbidity and                mortality worldwide, and the burden of disease has been increasing, particularly for                women. Despite these alarming trends, little is known about gender differences in the                clinical manifestations and management of patients with COPD. In a large cohort of                patients with chronic airflow obstruction hospitalized for COPD, gender differences                in the treatment and outcome of disease were investigated. The cohort consisted of                19,260 women and 23,893 men with a mean age of 77 years. Women were more likely to                have been previously hospitalized for asthma. In the year preceding the index                hospitalization, women were dispensed fewer prescriptions for bronchodilators                (particularly ipratropium bromide and theophylline) but were more likely to have                received benzodiazepines and antidepressants. There were 11,245 (58.4%) female and                16,754 (70.1%) male deaths after cohort entry. The most frequent cause of death in                both men and women was COPD. Mean survival and time to re-hospitalization for COPD or                asthma were higher for female patients.</description><creator>Gonzalez, Anne Valerie</creator><contributor>Samy Suissa (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Pierre Ernst (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Gender differences in the treatment and outcome of patients with COPD</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289k83k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj38p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cj39z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Water quality protection in Barbados is provided by means of a zoning                policy defined on bacteriological travel-times, based on matrix groundwater flow; and                without consideration of neither: surface/subsurface water karstic-hydrology-dynamics                (which characterise the island of Barbados), nor chemical pollution-transport and                -fate in surface water, which is the main source of groundwater recharge for the                island. This thesis explores the institutional frameworks, as well as the physical                data necessary to implement the use of a spatial, tightly-coupled Decision Support                System for water quality protection and management in Barbados. While a technical DSS                application is provided for demonstration purposes, focus is placed on the imminent                importance of establishing a National Spatial Data Infrastructure, and on the                necessary enhancement of institutional frameworks to meet the requirements for a DSS                implementation at the national level. It is concluded that under current                institutional and data quality, availability/accessibility conditions such an                endeavour will not be possible.</description><description>La protection de la qualité de l'eau sur l'île de la                Barbade est assurée par une politique de règlement de zonage définie par la mesure du                temps de propagation bactériologique basée sur une matrice d'écoulement des eaux                souterraines. Cette politique ne tient ni compte des dynamiques du système                hydrologique-karstique des eaux souterraines/de surface (qui caractérisent la                Barbade), ni du transport des polluants chimiques aboutissant en eaux de surface qui                représentent la principale source de réalimentation des réserves d'eaux souterraines                de l'île. Cette thèse explore les cadres institutionnels ainsi que les données                physiques nécessaires pour mettre en application un système spatiale d'Appui à la                prise de décision pour la protection de la qualité et la gestion de l'eau avec un                système complexe de logiciels associés à l'aménagement du territoire de l'île de la                Barbade. Tandis qu'une application technique SDD est fourni à des fins de                démonstration, l'accent est mis sur l'importance imminente d'établir une                Infrastructure Nationale de Données Géographiques, ainsi que la nécessité de                renforcer le cadre institutionnel pour répondre aux exigences de le mise en pratique                d'un SDD au niveau national. Il est conclu que due à la qualité des données et l'état                actuel des cadres institutionnels que les conditions de disponibilité/accessibilité                d'une telle entreprise ne sera pas possible. </description><creator>González Arriola, Santiago</creator><contributor>Robert B Bonnell (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Implementation of a spatial decision support system for water quality protection and management in the Holetown Watershed, Barbados: a case for the establishment of a NSDI for environmental management</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rj981.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj39z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n3004</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary goal of this research work was to devise a process to treat                hazardous fly ash, so as to render it environmentally stable and useful for                industrial, structural, and ornamental applications. The process selected entails                transforming fly ash into a glass-ceramic material. This involved melting the fly ash                into a slag at 1500°C for 2 hours, followed by water quenching. The amorphous                products obtained were then heat treated, so as to induce nucleation and                crystallization. The specific heat treatment devised was based on results obtained                from thermal analysis: nucleation was carried out at 805°C for 60min, followed by two                crystallization events at 905°C and 990°C, respectively, each lasting 30min. Material                characterization and analysis were carried out with the help of XRF, XRD, TCLP,                SEM/EDS, DTA, TMA, EBSD, FactSage modeling, Optical Microscopy, Nano-indentation, and                Vickers micro-hardness. The final product obtained was a glass-ceramic material with                randomly oriented crystals embedded in its residual amorphous matrix. The crystalline                phases forming were identified as Nepheline and Diopside. Leaching test results                revealed a significant reduction in heavy metal release. Values obtained from                mechanical testing showed that the fly-ash derived glass-ceramic material had                increased hardness and strength compared to its amorphous parent material.</description><description>Le but premier de cette recherché est de développer un                procédé de traitement des poussières volatiles dangereuses permettant de les rendrent                stables face à l'environnement et utiles pour des applications industrielles,                structurales et décoratives. Le procédé retenu transforme les poussières volatiles en                matériaux vitraux céramiques. Il implique la fusion des poussières en laitier en les                exposant à un traitement à 1500°C durant deux heures, suivi d'une trempe à l'eau. Les                produits amorphes obtenus sont ensuite traités thermiquement de façon à induire                nucléation et cristallisation. Le traitement thermique développé fut basé sur les                résultats d'analyse thermique effectués sur les produits amorphes et consiste en un                premier plateau à 805°C durant 60 minutes suivi de deux périodes de cristallisation à                905 et 990°C durant chacune 30 minutes. Les matériaux furent caractérisés par XRF,                XRD, TCLP, SEM/EDS, DTA, TMA, EBSD, modélisation thermodynamique avec le logiciel                FactSage, microscopie optique, nano-indentation, et micro-duretés Vickers. Les                matériaux finaux furent identifiés comme étant des vitraux céramiques composés de                cristaux aléatoirement orientés compris dans une matrice amorphe résiduelle. La forme                cristalline fut identifiée comme correspondant à de la Népheline et de la Diopside.                Les tests de dissolution indiquent une réduction significative de libération de                métaux lourds. Les essais mécaniques indiquent que les vitraux céramiques cristallins                obtenus de la fusion des poussières volatiles possèdent des résistances mécaniques et                des duretés améliorées comparées à leur contre parties amorphes.</description><creator>Al-Ghouleh, Zaid</creator><contributor>Roderick I L Guthrie (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Production of glass-ceramics from municipal solid waste (MSW) fly ash</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q807g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n3004</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vd27k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Airlines must maintain their aircraft up to a standard. This includes an                acquisition of new aircraft with more modern facilities and better safety-related                equipments. However, capital available for airlines to acquire their aircraft is                limited as the cost of borrowing is high. One of the many problems is the uncertain                law governing aircraft financing transactions. The Cape Town Convention and its                Aircraft Protocol are expected to be the solution for the above problem. The                Convention has successfully resolved some essential problems that historically                impeded aircraft financing transactions. However, it causes several new difficulties                which require international solutions. After critically analyzing the difficulties                created by the Convention and studying their impact on creditors and debtors, vague                terminologies used in the Convention and the opt-in and opt-out systems as well as                the absence of universal ratification are among the new difficulties. The Convention                is not without its weaknesses, but it does grant numerous economic benefits to the                aviation industry. Also, the sooner the problems are pointed out, the earlier the                better solutions are proposed. Thus, the Convention and the Aircraft Protocol may not                be the perfect solution but it is a necessarily tool that will lead aviation industry                to a greater step in the future.</description><description>Les compagnies aériennes ont l'obligation de maintenir                leur flotte à un certain niveau. Cela implique l'acquisition de nouveaux aéronefs                bénéficiant des dernières technologies et de meilleurs équipements en matière de                sécurité. Cependant, le budget dont disposent les compagnies aériennes, pour acquérir                de nouveaux appareils, est limité. Les taux d'emprunt sont élevés. L'un des nombreux                problèmes soulevés est le manque de sécurité juridique dans le domaine des opérations                de financement des aéronefs. La convention du Cap et son Protocole Aéronautique                devraient apporter des solutions aux difficultés sus-mentionnées. La Convention a                remarquablement résolu certains problèmes fondamentaux qui faisaient autrefois                obstacle aux opérations de financement des aéronefs. Cependant, elle soulève de                nouvelles difficultés qui demandent une réponse internationale. Après avoir analysé                de manière critique les problèmes engendrés par la Convention et étudié leur impact                sur les créanciers et les débiteurs, les terminologies floues utilisées par la                Convention, la possibilité de choisir le système applicable et l'absence de                ratification universelle font partie des nouvelles difficultés soulevées. Cette                Convention n'est pas sans faille, mais elle confère un certain nombre d'avantages                économiques à l'industrie aéronautique. Par ailleurs, plus tôt les problèmes sont                détectés, plus vite les solutions les plus adaptées sont proposées. Ainsi, la                Convention et le protocole aéronautique ne sont sans doute pas la meilleure réponse,                mais ils sont un outil nécessaire qui permettra à l'industrie aéronautique de gravir                un nouvel échelon dans le</description><creator>Uttarachai, Pleotian</creator><contributor>Ludwig Weber (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Robert Leckey (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>The legal impacts of the Cape Town Convention on aircraft financing transactions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k900.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd27k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010s007</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La diminution du poids des véhicules résulte dans l'apport                important de bénéfices au niveau de l'économie d'essence, la réduction des gaz à                effets de serre aussi bien que l'amélioration du rendement du véhicule. Le matériau                principal présentement utilisé pour la fabrication de la tête et du bloc moteur est                la fonte ductile. Le remplacement de la fonte par des alliages d'aluminium va                conduire vèrs une diminution (30-40%) significative du poids. Les alliages                d'aluminium de coulée actuels laissent voir dans le temps un ramolissement du métal                lorsque les températures d'opération du moteur exèdent 200ºC. Ce phénomène provoquera                à plus ou moins brève échéance un bris prématuré du moteur diésel. Deux nouveaux                alliages développés à partir de l'alliage commercial A356 sont présentés dans les                termes suivants : microstructure, fluage, comportement au vieillissement et                propriétés de traction à des températures élevées. L'alliage contenant les deux                groupes d'éléments soit péritectiques (Cr, Zr et Mn) dans un premier temps et pour le                durcissement structural par le vieillissement (Cu et Mg) dans un second temps,                démontre une réponse supérieure au vieillissement à la température de 200ºC pour une                période de 200 heures et de meilleures propriétés de fluage à la température de 300ºC                pour une période de 300 heures. De façon plus intéressant, l'alliage possède de                meilleures propriétés de traction (161MPa) à 250ºC avec une ductilité adéquate                comparativement aux alliages de bloc moteur fabriqués à partir des alliages A356 et                A356 + Cu. L'amélioration des propriétés mécaniques est ainsi attribuable aux                nouveaux précipit</description><description>Weight reduction in vehicles has important benefits of fuel economy and                reduction in greenhouse gas emissions as well as improved vehicle performance. The                current material for the diesel-engine block/head is mostly ductile iron and                replacing it with aluminum alloys would result in very effective weight reduction                (30-40%). Current commercial cast aluminum alloys, however, soften at engine                operating temperatures exceeding 200°C and would cause early fracture in the diesel                engine. Two new alloys derived from the commercial alloy (A356) are described in                terms of microstructure, creep, aging behavior and tensile properties at elevated                temperatures. The alloy containing both peritectic (Cr, Zr and Mn) and age hardenable                elements (Cu and Mg) shows superior aging response at 200°C (for 200 hours) and creep                properties at 300°C (for 300 hours). Interestingly, the alloy has better tensile                strength (161MPa) at 250°C with adequate ductility compared to the current engine                alloys, A356 and A356+Cu. The improvement in mechanical properties is attributed to                the newly formed thermally stable fine precipitates (ε-AlZrSi, α-AlCrMnFeSi…) inside                the α-Al dendrites.</description><creator>Ozbakir, Erol</creator><contributor>Mihriban Ozden Pekguleryuz (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Materials Science</subject><title>Development of aluminum alloys for diesel-engine applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g922n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010s007</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579v061</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Automated visual surveillance is one of the most actively researched                areas in the past decade. Although current behaviour recognition systems provide us                with a good understanding on the behaviour of individual moving objects present in an                observed scene, they are not able to efficiently recognize the behaviour of groups                formed by large numbers of moving objects. In this thesis, we present a HMM-based                group behaviour recognition system which is capable of recognizing group behaviours                effectively and efficiently. In our approach, we generate synthetic data for the                training and validation of our behaviour recognition system. In addition, we use a                single feature vector to represent the group dynamics, instead of using one feature                vector for each pairwise interaction. Experimental results show accurate                classification for both real-life data and simulated data from Lee's dataset.                Therefore, we conclude that the proposed approach is a viable and accurate technique                to perform group behaviour recognition in both simulated environment and real-life                situations. Moreover, the high accuracy of the classification results obtained on                real-life data, when only synthetic data was used for the training, suggests that it                is possible to develop group behaviour models using synthetic data alone.</description><description>La surveillance visuelle automatisée est un domaine de                recherche parmi les plus actifs au cours de la dernière décennie. Bien que les                systèmes actuels de reconnaissance des comportements nous fournissent une bonne                compréhension sur le comportement des objets en mouvement dans une scène observée,                ils ne sont pas en mesure de reconnaître efficacement le comportement de groupes                formés de plusieurs objets en mouvement. Dans cette mémoire, nous présentons un                système de reconnaissance des comportements de groupes basé sur le modèle de Markov                caché (MMC). Notre système est capable de reconnaître les comportements de groupe de                façon efficace et efficiente. Dans notre approche, nous générons des données                synthétiques pour former et valider notre système de reconnaissance des                comportements. De plus, nous utilisons un vecteur caractéristique pour représenter la                dynamique d'un groupe au lieu d'utiliser un vecteur pour chaque interaction entre                deux objets en mouvement. Les résultats expérimentaux montrent une classification                précise pour les données réelles et simulées utilisant la base de données de Lee. Par                conséquent, nous concluons que l'approche proposée est une solution viable et une                technique précise pour effectuer la reconnaissance des comportements de groupes dans                un environnement simulé et dans des situations de la vie courante. Les résultats                démontrent aussi qu'en utilisant uniquement des données synthétiques pour le former,                le système classe avec une grande précision les comportements issues de situations                réelles. Cela suggère qu'il est possible de développer des modèles de comportement de                groupe en utilisant seulement les don</description><creator>Yu, Shen</creator><contributor>Frank P Ferrie (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Artificial Intelligence</subject><title>A Bayesian machine learning system for recognizing group behaviour</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd60v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v061</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g2008</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Notre thèse soutient l'idée que la tragédie de la                renaissance anglaise reflète la culture religieuse de l'époque dans son évocation de                la violence sacrificielle. Elle conteste les présupposés du néo-historicisme à                l'égard de la relation entre la religion et la politique et entre la religion et la                littérature, en proposant que les dramaturges exprimaient à travers leurs tragédies                une crise sacrificielle girardienne qui caractérisait les exécutions des martyres au                seizième siècle et qui était alimentée par une crise de conscience par rapport à la                violence qui s'exprimait au sein même de l'église. Le premier chapitre fait état du                contexte historique. Nous nous intéressons d'abord à l'histoire des martyres                protestants et catholiques au seizième et au début du dix-septième siècles. Nous                détaillons ensuite la doctrine de l'église persécutée, c'est à dire la conviction                issue du nouveau testament que la véritable église est nécessairement une minorité                persécutée au nom du Christ, au travers des écrits de nombreux écrivains de l'époque.                Figure illustre parmi ces écrivains, le martyrologue John Foxe cultivait une tendance                anti-sacrificielle au sein de l'église nationale. Nous examinons enfin comment cette                théologie centrée sur la victime bouleversa le consensus face aux exécutions                religieuses, en présentant un champ émotionnel exploité par les dramaturges                tragiques. Chacun des trois chapitres suivants se consacre à un différent dramaturge.                Le deuxième chapitre aborde King Lear de Shakespeare qui se distingue précisément par                la compassion qui y est manifestée pour la victime sacrificielle. King Lear ne fait                preuve d'aucune</description><description>This dissertation argues that the tragedy of the English Renaissance                reflects the religious culture of the era in its depiction of sacrificial violence.                It contests New Historicist assumptions about both the relationship between religion                and politics, and the relationship between religion and literature, by arguing that                the tragedians were reflecting the Girardian sacrificial crisis that characterized                martyr executions in the sixteenth century and which was fuelled by uncertainty                within the church over the issue of violence. Chapter One develops the historical                framework. It begins by surveying the history of Protestant and Catholic martyrdom in                the sixteenth and early seventeenth centuries. It then traces the doctrine of the                persecuted church—the recovered New Testament sense that the true church is                necessarily a persecuted minority that suffers for Christ's sake—in various religious                writers of the period. The most important of these writers is the martyrologist John                Foxe, who fostered an anti-sacrificial strain of Christianity from within the                national church. Finally, I discuss how this victim-centred theology disrupted                consensus at religious executions, offering an emotional template that the tragedians                exploited. Each of the three subsequent chapters is devoted to a different tragedian.                Chapter Two discusses William Shakespeare's King Lear, a play which is radical in its                sympathy for the sacrificial victim. King Lear shows no particular faith in Christian                redemption, but in this very lack of transcendence it demystifies and condemns                sacrificial violence. Chapter Three is devoted to John Webster's two tragedies, The                White Devil and The Duchess of Malfi. Here, the</description><creator>Anderson, David</creator><contributor>Paul Edward Yachnin (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Literature - English</subject><title>Violence against the sacred: tragedy and religion in early modern England</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw260.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g2008</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483m04m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Through this investigation I hoped to illuminate and characterize any                combinatorial relationships that might exist amongst the regulatory sequences that                drive expression of the myelin basic protein gene. With such insight, I expected to                learn more of the mechanism/s regulating myelin sheath formation, maintenance and                repair. In the search for regulatory regions within the mbp gene, four highly                conserved non-protein-coding modules were found in its 5' flanking sequence. In the                context of reporter constructs in transgenic mice, these regulatory modules confer                distinct cell specificity and developmental expression programs. M1 and M3 drive                expression in oligodendrocytes while M4 drives Schwann cell expression. However, the                expression programs realized by these reporter constructs also exposed higher levels                of regulatory organization; e.g., when M3 is dissociated from neighboring flanking                sequences it acquires the ability to drive transient expression in Schwann cells. To                further understand how the four known mbp regulatory modules orchestrate the                expression of the mbp gene, I first generated reporter constructs designed to contain                most module combinations. These were inserted in single copy in a common orientation                at a common site 5' of the HPRT locus and their qualitative and quantitative                regulatory potential was analyzed. Based on the expression programming of reporter                genes, M3 is critical for achieving high levels of mbp expression in myelinating                oligodendrocytes. To determine if the expression phenotypes of reporter genes                accurately reflected the activity of enhancers in the context of the endogenous                locus, I used gene targeting to delete M3 in the endogenous mbp loc</description><description>Au cours de ma recherche j'ai voulu mettre en évidence les                combinatoires existantes parmi les séquences régulatrices qui gouvernent l'expression                du gène de la Protéine Basique de la Myéline (MBP). Ces connaissances devraient                pouvoir me permettre de mieux comprendre les mécanismes régulant la formation, la                maintenance et la réparation de la gaine de myéline. Lors de l'étude de la régulation                du gène de la MBP, quatre modules non codant extrêmement conservés ont été trouvés en                amont du gène de la MBP. Dans des souris transgéniques, ces modules confèrent des                propriétés d'expression temporelle et tissu spécifique aux constructions. Les modules                M1 et M3 gouvernent l'expression dans les oligodendrocytes alors que le module M4                gouverne l'expression dans les cellules de Schwann. Cependant, les programmes                d'expression de ces constructions révèlent une organisation de plus haut niveau :                Quand M3 est dissocié des séquences flanquantes du gène de la MBP il acquière la                capacité de gouverner une expression transitoire dans les cellules de Schwann. Pour                comprendre comment les quatre modules régulateurs de la MBP orchestrent l'expression                du gène, j'ai d'abord généré des constructions présentant la plupart des combinaisons                de modules. Ces constructions ont été insérées en copie unique de même orientation et                dans un locus commun en 5' du gène HPRT afin de pouvoir comparer qualitativement et                quantitativement leur expression. L'analyse de ces résultats montrent que le module                M3 est critique pour obtenir un haut niveau d'expression durant la myélination des                oligodendrocytes. Pour déterminer si l'expression des constructions reflète                correctement</description><creator>Dib Kandis Badine, Samar</creator><contributor>Alan Peterson (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Functional analysis of the Myelin Basic Protein gene regulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x51r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483m04m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v038z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A 5kb fragment of the pufferfish Fugu rubripes NR1 promoter spanning                nucleotides -2729 to + 2343 was shown to be sufficient to drive expression of the NR1                gene in zebrafish. I performed a cross-species sequence comparison of the 5kb Fugu                NR1 promoter with homologous pufferfish (Tetraodon nigroviridis), zebrafish (Danio                rerio) and stickleback (Gasterosteus aculeatus) genomes and identified five                non-coding evolutionary conserved regions (ECRs) containing cis-elements that serve                as putative binding sites for eleven different trans-acting factors. I performed 5'                serial deletions of the 5kb NR1 fragment based on the location of the ECRs and                subsequently injected the truncated promoter constructs into fertilized zebrafish                embryos to assess the activity of the deletion constructs. Analysis of the NR1                promoter requires an investigation of development in an intact organism. Thus, the                main aim of my thesis was to establish a transgenic line of zebrafish expressing the                5kb Fugu NR1 promoter. The transgenic data validated results obtained by in vitro                methods regarding the activation of the NR1, which occurs via promoter de-repression,                and the regulation of the NR1 gene, whereby tissue-specific trans-acting factors act                on its cis-elements and determine its expression. The results suggest the presence of                a putative fish NR1 gene control region that spans nucleotides -1360 to -194 and                contains ECRs 1-3. The results also demonstrate that the minimal cis promoter spans                nucleotides -149 to +131 and contains ECR4 and ECR5.</description><description>Un fragment de 5kb du promoteur NR1 de Fugu rubripes                comprenant les nucléotides -2729 à +2343 fut démontré à diriger l'expression du gène                NR1 chez le poisson zébré. J'ai entrepris une comparaison entre espèces des séquences                génomiques du promoteur 5kb du Fugu avec les séquences d'un poisson homologue                (Tetraodon nigroviridis), du poisson zébré (Danio rerio) et du « stickleback»                (Gasterosteus aculeatus). J'ai identifié cinq régions non-codantes conservées durant                l'évolution (ECRs) qui servent comme sites de liaison putatives pour onze différents                facteurs agissant en «trans». J'ai performé des délétions 5' du fragment NR1 5kb basé                sur la localisation des ECRs et par conséquence j'ai injecté les construits de                promoteurs tronqués dans des embryons de poissons zébré nouvellement fertilisés afin                de déterminer l'activité des construits tronqués. Une analyse du promoteur NR1                nécessite une investigation du développement comme il se produit chez un organisme                intacte. Ainsi, le but primaire de ma thèse fut d'établir une lignée transgénique                chez le poisson zébré exprimant le promoteur 5kb NR1 du Fugu Les données en                transgenèse ont validées les résultats obtenus par des méthodes in vitro concernant                l'activation du NR1, qui se produit par la dé-répression du promoteur, et la                régulation du gène NR1, par laquelle des facteurs agissant en trans de façon                spécifique aux tissus agissent sur ses éléments en «cis» et déterminent son                expression. Les résultats suggèrent la présence d'une région putative contrôlant le                gène NR1 chez les poissons qui comprend les nucléotides -1360 à -194 et qui contient                les ECRs 1-3. Les résulta</description><creator>Ali-Adeeb, Rana</creator><contributor>Robert James Dunn (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience</subject><title>«In vivo» promoter analysis in zebrafish of the «Fugu rubripes» NMDA receptor subunit 1 gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr172007m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v038z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt58j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We use a quantum master equation approach to study the transport                properties of a triple quantum dot ring. Unlike double quantum dots and triple                quantum dot chains, this geometry gives two transport paths with a relative phase                sensitive to magnetic ﬂux via the Aharonov-Bohm effect. This gives rise to a coherent                population trapping effect and what is known as a "dark state". Unlike other master                equation techniques valid only in the high bias voltage limit, our treatment                reproduces such results as well as giving an analytic zero-bias conductance formula.                As well as providing a more robust signature of this "dark state" physics, our model                further predicts a negative differential resistance in connection with high bias                rectiﬁcation already predicted.</description><description>Nous utilisons une approche d´equation quantique maîtresse                pour étudier les propriétés de transport des points quantiques triples en forme                d'anneau. Contrairement aux points quantiques doubles et triples en forme de chaînes,                cette géométrie offre deux chemins pour le transport avec une phase quantique                relative qui est sensible au ﬂux magnétique en raison de l'effet Aharonov-Bohm. Ceci                méne à un effet de piégeage de population cohérent et cela est connu sous le nom d'un                "état sombre". Contrairement à d'autres techniques d'équation maîtresse qui sont                seulement valides dans la limite d'un potentiel électrique élevé, notre méthode                reproduit les résultats de ces derniers en plus de donner une expression analytique                pour la conductance différentielle de zéro potentiel électrique. En plus de donner                une optique plus robuste de la physique "d´etats sombres", notre modèle prédit une                résistance différentielle négative qui est reliée au phénomène déjà prédit de                rectiﬁcation à potentiel élevé. </description><creator>Schneider, Adam</creator><contributor>Clerk, Aashish (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Theory</subject><title>Coherent electron transport in triple quantum dots</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gv44c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt58j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dp19b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent technological advances facilitating the acquisition of spatial                observational data and an increasing awareness of issues of spatial pattern and scale                have fostered the development and use of statistical methods for multi-scale                analysis. These methods can be interesting tools to improve our understanding of                natural systems, but their use must be guided by a good comprehension of the                statistics and their assumptions. This thesis is an effort to develop a coherent                framework for multi-scale analysis and to identify theoretical, statistical and                practical issues and solutions. After defining terminology and concepts, several                methods are compared using a common dataset in Chapter 2. The geostatistical method                of regionalized multivariate analysis is identified as possessing several advantages,                but shortcomings are identified, discussed and addressed in two manuscripts. In the                first one (Chapter 3), a mathematical formalism is presented to characterize the                spatial uncertainty of cokriged regionalized components and an approach is proposed                for the conditional Gaussian co-simulation of regionalized components. In the second                manuscript (Chapter 4), the theory underlying coregionalization analysis is discussed                and its robustness and limits are assessed through a theoretical and mathematical                framework. The assumptions underlying the method and the high levels of uncertainty                associated with its use highlight problems with the interpretation of results, and                issues with the application of probabilistic models in a spatial context (Chapter 5).                Coregionalization analysis with a drift (CRAD), presented in detail in two                co-authored publications, is proposed as a sensible alternative</description><description>Des avancées technologiques récentes facilitant                l'acquisition de données observationnelles spatiales, et la conscientisation                grandissante des chercheurs aux problèmes d'échelles, ont favorisé le développement                et l'utilisation de méthodes statistiques d'analyse multi-échelles. Ces méthodes                peuvent être des outils intéressants pour améliorer notre compréhension des                écosystèmes, mais leur usage nécessite une bonne connaissance des théories                statistiques et des hypothèses qui leur sont sous-jacentes. Cette thèse a pour but de                contribuer au développement d'un cadre conceptuel cohérent pour l'analyse                multi-échelles en identifiant des problématiques et des solutions théoriques,                statistiques et pratiques. La terminologie et les concepts appropriés sont d'abord                définis. Ensuite, dans le chapitre 2, plusieurs méthodes sont comparées en utilisant                un jeu de données commun. La méthode géostatistique d'analyse multivariable                régionalisée semble offrir plusieurs avantages, mais certains problèmes sont                identifiés, discutés et traités dans deux articles publiés. Le premier (chapitre 3)                présente un formalisme mathématique servant à caractériser l'incertitude spatiale des                composantes régionalisées cokrigées et propose une approche pour la co-simulation                conditionnelle Gaussienne de composantes régionalisées. Dans le deuxième article                (chapitre 4), l'analyse de corégionalisation est discutée et la robustesse ainsi que                les limites de cette méthode sont évaluées selon une analyse théorique et                mathématique. Les postulats de cette méthode et le haut niveau d'incertitude lié à                son utilisation mettent en évidence des problèmes associés </description><creator>Larocque, Guillaume</creator><contributor>James W Fyles (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Biostatistics</subject><title>Towards a coherent framework for the multi-scale analysis of spatial observational data: linking concepts, statistical tools and ecological understanding</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gq142.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp19b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h6357</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lamin A/C, an important component of the nuclear envelope, has been                associated with cell differentiation and tissue development. In bone, recent studies                have described that altered function of lamin A/C, due to mutations or incorrect                processing, is associated with accelerated and severe bone loss. This could be due to                alterations in the differentiation of mesenchymal stem cells (MSC) induced by lack of                lamin A/C activity. Therefore, considering that decreased osteoblastogenesis and                increased adipogenesis are the characteristic changes observed within bone marrow                microenvironment that leads to age-related bone loss, we have studied the effect of                inhibition of lamin A/C on MSC into either osteoblasts or adipocytes both in vitro                and in vivo. For in vitro studies, we identified the effect of pharmacological                inhibition of lamin A/C on adipogenesis. Subsequently, we inhibited lamin A/C by                using different doses of lamin A/C siRNA in osteogenic and adipogenic differentiating                MSCs as well as normal human osteoblasts. To further verify our results, we have used                Zmpste24-/- null progeroid mice that lacks mature lamin A/C and studied the bone                changes in absence of mature lamin A/C in in vivo. We have found that partial                inhibition of lamin A/C decreased osteoblast differention and function without                affecting their survival. Furthermore, our animal studies showed that absence of                mature lamin A/C induced a reduction in bone mass and bone quality associated with                low bone turnover. In contrast, accumulation of prelamin A induced significant levels                of adipogenesis within the bone marrow cavity. In summary, our results provide                evidence in support of a pivotal role of lamin A/C in the comm</description><description>Lamin A/C, un important composant de l'enveloppe                nucléaire, a été associé avec la différentiation cellulaire et le développement                tissulaire. Dans l'os, des études récentes ont demontrée que l'alteration de lamin                A/C, due a des mutations du gène LMNA, est associée avec une perte accélérée et                sevère de l'os. Ceci pourrait être dû à une altération de la différentiation des                cellules souches mésenchymateuses (CSM) induit par une perte de l'activité de lamin                A/C. Par conséquent, en considerant que la diminution de l'ostéoblastogènese et                l'augmentation de l'adipogènese sont les changements caractéristiques observés à                l'intérieur du micro-environnement de la moelle osseuse qui mènent à une perte                osseuse relié à l'âge, nous avons étudié l'effet de l'inhibition de lamin A/C sur la                différentiation des cellules souches soit en adipocyte ou en ostéoblast in vitro et                in vivo. Pour les études in vitro, nous avons identifiés l'effet de l'inhibition                pharmacologique de lamin A/C sur l'adipogènese. Par la suite, nous avons inhibé lamin                A/C en utilisant différentes doses de lamin A/C siRNA sur les cellules souches en                différentiatiation en ostéoblast et en adipocytes et aussi sur des ostéoblast                humaine. Pour confirmer nos résultats précedents, nous avons utilisés un modèle                progerique murin Zmste24-/-. Ces souris ne possedent pas la forme mature de lamin                A/C. Nous avons etudiés les changements osseux en absence de la forme mature de lamin                A/C in vivo. Nous avons trouvé qu'une inhibition partielle de lamin A/C diminue la                différentiation et la fonction des ostéoblastes sans affecter leur survie. En outre,                nos études sur les souris ont d</description><creator>Akter, Rahima</creator><contributor>Gustavo Duque (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Physiology</subject><title>Role of lamin A/C in the cellular features of age-related bone loss</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x089m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h6357</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz34d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Extending conjugation in 2-dimensions: Synthesis and characterization of                multidentate monomers Over the past decade pi-conjugated organic polymers have                attracted considerable attention because of their desirable characteristics similar                to plastics (e.g., mechanical flexibility, simplicity and low-cost processing, etc.)                as well as their interesting electronic/optical properties. The potential use of                these materials in molecular electronics provides impetus for the development of new                and modified pi-conjugated polymers. To that end, we propose to increase the                dimensionality of pi-conjugation through formation of a two dimensional polymer. The                synthesis of tri- and tetra-dentate monomers, which were designed for their predicted                ability to form continuous conjugated sheets via surface confined polymerization,                will be presented.</description><description>Conjugaison de élargissement dans 2 dimensions : Synthèse                et caractérisation des monomers multidentate Pendant la décennie passée, les                polymères organiques pi-conjugués ont attiré une attention considérable en raison de                leurs caractéristiques souhaitables semblables aux plastiques (par exemple,                flexibilité mécanique, simplicité, et traitement peu coûteux, etc.) en plus de leurs                propriétés électroniques/optiques intéressantes. L'utilisation potentielle de ces                matériaux dans l'électronique moléculaire fournit l'impulsion pour le développement                du nouveau et modifié polymères pi-conjugués. À cet effet, nous proposons d'augmenter                la dimensionnalité du pi-conjugaison par la formation d'un polymère bidimensionnel.                La synthèse des tri- et tétra-dentelés monomères, qui ont été conçus pour que leur                capacité prévue forme les feuilles conjuguées continues par l'intermédiaire de la                polymérisation confinée extérieure, sera présentée.</description><creator>Taerum, Tyler</creator><contributor>Dmytro Perepichka (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Chemistry - Organic</subject><title>Extending conjugation in 2-dimensions: synthesis and characterization of multidentate monomers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t8165.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz34d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zw278</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Un modulateur delta sigma 12-bit 2.8-MHz conçu pour des                applications ADSL est présenté dans ce mémoire. Le processus de conception est décrit                en deux phases: la conception au niveau du système suivie de la réalisation au niveau                du circuit. Lors de la première phase, les paramètres du système sont choisis et les                spécifications analogiques du circuit sont dérivées. La phase de l'implémentation du                circuit impliquait la conception de circuits analogiques tels que amplificateurs                opérationnels respectant les spécifications du système. La conception du circuit a                été réalisée sur la technologie 1-V 65-nm CMOS. Le doubleéchantillonnage a été                employé afin que les circuits de condensateurs-commutés soient plus économiques en                terme de puissance. La technique d'action directe (feedforward) a été utilisée sur le                signal d'entrée afin de réduire l'amplitude à la sortie des amplificateurs. La                technique d'action directe digitale sur le signal d'entrée est utilisée et présentée                comme une alternative à son homologue analogique.</description><description>A 12-bit 2.8-MHz delta sigma modulator intended for ADSL applications is                presented in this thesis. The design process evolved over two stages, namely, a                system-level design stage followed by a circuit-level design stage. During the first                phase of the design, the systemlevel parameters are selected and analog-circuit                specifications are derived. The circuitlevel stage involved the design of analog                circuitry such as operational amplifiers capable of meeting the system-level                specifications. The circuit design was carried out in 1-V 65- nm CMOS technology.                Double-sampling was employed to make the switched-capacitor circuits more power                efficient. Input-signal feedforward was used to lower the signal swing at the output                of the opamps. Digital input feedforward is used and presented as an alternative to                analog input feedforward.</description><creator>Sukhon, Mohammad</creator><contributor>Anas Hamoui (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Double-sampled digital-feedforward second-order delta-sigma modulator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k449m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw278</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z720w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines whether and under what conditions the recent                decentralization of irrigation management in Turkey can deepen democracy through a                comparative study of irrigation management decentralization in two provinces in                Turkey: Urfa and Aydin. In Turkey, the state agency, which planned, built, and                managed all major irrigation schemes, transferred the duty of water management, fee                collection and maintenance to Water User Associations (WUAs) starting in 1993. The                democratic processes established by WUAs in Urfa were plagued by allegations of                bribery, corruption, embezzlement and service delivery failures; whereas Aydin WUAs                have proven to be the very definition of successful decentralization in irrigation                management. The hypothesis is that inequalities in access to resources, unequal power                structures, low-levels of education and inexperience with civic activism lead to                weaker links between decentralization and democratic deepening. Moreover, these same                factors increase the likelihood that decentralized organizations will fail to satisfy                their users in the provision of efficient and effective services. Hence, I                hypothesize that the same factors are responsible for hampering the performance of                decentralized institutions. I argue that divergent outcomes in decentralized                irrigation management are a result of diverging social, economic and political                contextual variables. The study shows that if there are significant inequalities in                access to resources and power, decentralization does not promote democratic deepening                and does not improve the performance of service delivery. This is especially true if                the actors do not have a past of civic activism.</description><description>Cette thèse considère si la décentralisation récente de la                gestion de l'irrigation en Turquie peut approfondir les processus démocratiques, et                sous quelles conditions, au moyen d'une étude comparative sur la décentralisation de                la gestion de l'irrigation dans deux provinces turques : Urfa et Aydin. En Turquie,                dès 1993, l'organisme de l'État qui avait planifié, construit et géré l'ensemble des                plans d'irrigations a transféré les tâches reliées à l'aménagement des ressources en                eau, la collecte des frais et l'entretien aux associations des usagers de l'eau                (AUE). Les processus démocratiques établis par les AUE se plaignaient d'allégations                de trafic d'influence, de corruption, de détournement et de retards de livraison de                service tandis que les AUE d'Aydin ne manifestaient que du succès en gestion                d'irrigation décentralisée. L'hypothèse propose que l'accès inéquitable aux                ressources, l'inégalité des dynamiques de pouvoir, les faibles taux de scolarité et                le manque d'expérience en activisme communautaire contribuent à l'affaiblissement des                liens entre la décentralisation et l'approfondissement des processus démocratiques.                Or, ces mêmes facteurs réduisent les probabilités que les services de ces organismes                décentralisés seront fournis aux utilisateurs de manière efficace. Ainsi, je propose                que ces facteurs mêmes contribuent à la pauvre performance des organismes                décentralisés. Mon argument démontre que les résultats divergents relatifs aux                structures décentralisées de gestion d'irrigation sont liés aux variables sociales,                économiques et politiques du contexte. L'étude démontre que les inéquations d'accès                aux ressources</description><creator>Kadirbeyoglu, Zeynep</creator><contributor>Narendra Subramanian (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>Decentralization and democratization: the case of water user associations in Turkey</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc92d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z720w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214q94f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores four methods for improving quantitative diffuse                reflectance spectroscopy in light scattering media. In the introduction theories of                light propagation in scattering media, relevant instrumentation for measuring light                scattering properties, spectral data processing methods, and spectroscopically active                bioanalytes are outlined. Next, two novel instruments for practical scattering                measurements, and two novel data processing techniques are presented. Finally,                directions for future research into diffuse reflectance spectroscopy are suggested. A                novel photon time-of-flight instrument is used to measure scattering coefficients in                tandem with a portable diode spectrometer. Measured scattering coefficients are used                to correct co-measured near infrared spectra for scattering and for improving                quantification. Reduced scattering coefficients were measured with coefficients of                variation of 11.6% at 850 nm and 14.1% at 905 nm. This allows practical correction of                light scattering in point-spectra. Using scattering-correction, estimates of dye                concentration were improved by 35%. A novel device imaging annular patterns is                presented. This imaging instrument is used to measure reduced scattering coefficients                and absorption coefficients. Reduced scattering coefficients were measured with a                coefficient of variation of 12.6%, and absorption coefficients were measured with a                coefficient of variation 50% lower than using traditional imaging methods. A novel                method for using parsimony in the development of data processing methods using                genetic algorithms is presented. Genetic algorithms have been used to identify                spectroscopic data processing methods for complex samples. A</description><description>Cette thèse explore quatre méthodes pour l'amélioration de                la spectroscopie de réflectance diffuse quantitative dans des milieux qui diffusent                la lumière. En introduction, une description des théories de la propagation de la                lumière dans des médias qui diffusent celle-ci, des instruments pour mesurer les                propriétés de diffusion, des méthodes de traitement des données spectrales, et des                bioanalytes avec activité optique est donné. Un nouvel appareil à «temps de vol de                photon» est présenté. Cet instrument portatif est utilisé pour mesurer le coefficient                de dispersion en tandem avec un spectromètre à diode portable. Les coefficients de                diffusion mesurés sont ensuite utilisés pour corriger la dispersion dans les spectres                infrarouges co-mesurée, ainsi que l'amélioration de la quantification. Les                coefficients de dispersion ont été mesurés avec une variation de 11,6% à 850 nm et                14,1% à 905 nm. En prenant en compte la dispersion, les estimations de la                concentration de teinture ont été améliorées de 35%. Un nouvel appareil utilisant les                modes d'imagerie annulaire pour mesurer les coefficients de dispersion et                d'absorption est présenté. Les coefficients de dispersion ont été mesurés avec un                coefficient de variation de 12,6%, et les coefficients d'absorption ont été mesurés                avec un coefficient de variation amélioré de 50% par rapport aux méthodes d'imagerie                traditionnelle. Une nouvelle méthode pour améliorer l'utilisation des mesures de                simplicité dans le développement de méthodes de traitement des données via des                algorithmes génétiques est présentée. Les algorithmes génétiques ont été utilisés                pour identifier les mét</description><creator>Esmonde-White, Francis</creator><contributor>David H Burns (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Chemistry - Analytical</subject><title>Robust spectroscopic quantification in turbid media</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s426k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214q94f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r507</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The substantial recent advances in early universe observational                cosmology have confronted theoretical physics with a number of deep conceptual                questions. The standard model of particle physics and its natural extensions have                proven to be insufficient for explaining the recent observations. String theory as                the main candidate for a complete theory of quantum gravity provides us with the                possibility of resolving this discrepancy. In this dissertation, I begin by an                overview of thermodynamics in string theory. The issue of stability and the existence                of the thermodynamic limit have been addressed. I will describe the string gas                cosmology in detail, as the leading candidate of early universe cosmology. Successes                and shortcomings of the most recent model of string gas cosmology in matching with                observations are addressed. I conclude with comments on interesting directions for                future study and a possible link with black hole physics.</description><description>A la lumiere des plus recentes observations cosmologiques,                la physique theorique se trouve confrontee a de nombreuses questions conceptuelles.                Le Modele Standard de physique des particules et ses plus simples extensions se sont                averes insuffisants pour expliquer les recentes observations. La theorie des cordes,                qui est presentement la principale candidate pour une theorie complete de la gravite                quantique, nous offre la possibilite de resoudre ces lacunes du Modele Standard. Nous                debutons cette these par un apercu de la thermodynamique dans la theorie des cordes.                Nous nous penchons en particulier sur la stabilite et sur l'existence d'une limite                thermodynamique en theorie des cordes. Nous presentons par la suite les details de la                cosmologie des gaz de cordes et discutons des succes et des problèmes de cette                approche pour decrire l'evolution cosmologique du debut de l'univers. Nous concluons                en commentant sur les possibles travaux futurs et sur un lien entre ce sujet et la                physique des trous noirs.</description><creator>Lashkari, Nima</creator><contributor>Robert Brandenberger (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Elementary Particles and High Energy</subject><title>Hagedorn transition cosmology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n12p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r507</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cv78f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an analysis of the notion of the virtual as laid out in                works by Brian Massumi, Gilles Deleuze, and Félix Guattari. In it, I explore the                virtual across several Chinese films of the last two decades and with respect to                different challenges to identity. Through Center Stage, Farewell My Concubine, and                Frozen, I investigate the dangers of the virtual in performance and the difficulty in                recognizing the line between role and real. I then compare this to the similar yet                distinct notion of disguise in House of Flying Daggers and Infernal Affairs in order                to demonstrate the different manifestations and effects of the virtual when one's                performance is undisclosed to those to whom one plays. Finally, I examine identity                and the virtual through cinematic doublings in the films Center Stage and Suzhou                River.</description><description>Cette thèse est une analyse de la notion du virtuel telle                que présentée dans les travaux de Brian Massumi, Gilles Deleuze et Félix Guattari.                J'explore le virtuel au travers de plusieurs films chinois des deux dernières                décennies en ce qui a trait aux différents défis de l'identité. Par des films tels                que Center Stage, Farewell My Concubine, et Frozen, j'examine les dangers du virtuel                dans la performance et la difficulté de pouvoir reconnaitre la mince ligne entre le                rôle et le réel. Je compare, ensuite cela à la notion similaire mais quand même                distincte de camouflage dans House of Flying Daggers et Infernal Affairs de manière à                démontrer les différentes manifestations et les effets du virtuel lorsque la                performance d'un personne est non- dévoilée à quelqu'un avec qui elle joue.                Finalement, j'examine l'identité et le virtuel par les doublages cinématiques dans                les films Center Stage et Suzhou River.</description><creator>Steely, Danielle</creator><contributor>Peter Button (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Cinema</subject><title>Identity in Chinese film: conflict, transformation, and the virtual</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p340.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv78f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246t80m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Un patron de méthylation anormal, tel que                l'hyperméthylation régionale ou l'hypométhylation génomique, modifie la transcription                de gènes critiques jouant ainsi un rôle central dans la progression de nombreux                cancers chez l'humain. Il est donc devenu essentiel d'identifier les mécanismes                responsables de ces altérations afin de développer des traitements pharmacologiques                ciblés. Le but principal de cette thèse est d'examiner si certains facteurs                cellulaires sont impliqués dans l'établissement de l'ADN hypométhylé des cellules                cancéreuses, ainsi que l'effet des changements dans la structure de la chromatine sur                la méthylation de l'ADN. Il a été préalablement démontré que la protéine MBD2 possède                plusieurs rôles distincts lors de la transcription, elle peut agir à la fois comme un                répresseur de la transcription dépendant de la méthylation, comme un inducteur de la                déméthylation ainsi qu'un activateur de la transcription indépendant de la                méthylation. Les chapitres 3 et 4 présentés dans cet ouvrage démontrent que MBD2                induit la déméthylation de gènes spécifiques dans les cellules cancéreuses                pancréatiques et urinaires grâce au recrutement des activateurs transcriptionnels                AP-2, Sp1 ainsi que de l'histone acétyltransférase CBP au promoteur impliqué. Ces                résultats supportent l'hypothèse selon laquelle la déméthylation induite par MBD2                faciliterait le recrutement de facteurs de transcription au sein du gène afin                d'activer son expression. Les inhibiteurs de l'Histone déacétylase (HDAC) sont des                drogues pharmaceutiques développées afin de cibler les modifications de la                chromatine. Nous sommes parvenus à démontrer, dans le</description><description>Abnormal methylation patterns such as regional hypermethylation and                genomic hypomethylation often result in transcriptional changes of critical genes                that are central to the progression of human cancers. It is therefore important to                identify the mechanisms that are responsible for the alterations in order to identify                proper pharmacological targets. This thesis examines whether specific cellular                factors are involved in establishing the state of DNA hypomethylation in cancer cells                and whether changes in chromatin structure could affect DNA methylation. MBD2 is a                protein that has been previously characterized to possess distinct transcription                activities; it can either function as a methylation-dependent transcription                repressor, a methylation-independent transcription activator, as well as an inducer                of DNA demethylation. Chapters 3 and 4 demonstrate that MBD2 induces gene-specific                DNA demethylation in pancreatic and bladder cancer cells by recruiting                transcriptional activator AP-2, Sp1 and the histone acetyltransferase CBP to the                associated promoters. These results substantiate the idea that demethylation induced                by MBD2 might facilitate the recruitment of transcription factors to the gene to                activate its expression. Histone deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitors are drugs designed to                target chromatin modification. In chapter 5, we showed that increasing histone                acetylation by HDAC inhibitor TSA was associated with a significant decrease in                global methylation. TSA also induces histone acetylation, DNA demethylation and                expression of specific methylated tumor suppressor genes, such as E-CADHERIN and                RARβ2 in different human cancer cell lines. Our findings provide evidence for a</description><creator>Ou, Jing Ni</creator><contributor>Moshe Szyf (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</subject><title>Epigenetic crosstalk between DNA demethylation and histone acetylation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r032v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246t80m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053h91m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce mémoire étudie les défis auxquels les enfants réfugiés                non accompagnés d'un adulte sont confrontés dans leur démarche de recherche d'une                terre d'accueil. On y examine comment les discours et les politiques tenus tant au                Canada qu'ailleurs dans le monde, minent les efforts des enfants réfugiés non                accompagnés d'adulte dans leur tentative d'accéder au statut de réfugier et d'obtenir                une réponse positive à leur requête. En se basant principalement sur des théories                post colonialiste, ce mémoire rappelle le contexte historique à la base du phénomène                de l'immigration forcée des enfants et souligne le rôle que les pays du nord                continuent de jouer en perpétuant cette réalité. On questionne également, dans ce                mémoire, les lieus communs qui sont généralement accepté par le plus grand nombre. En                plus des théories post colonialistes, l'argumentaire s'appuie principalement sur le                concept du pouvoir de Foucault pour comprendre le conditionnement que les hommes,                principalement ceux des pays du sud, subissent. On y étudie aussi comment on en est                venu à percevoir ces enfants comme « un problème » et le rôle qu'à joué                l'argumentaire dans la construction de cette perception. Ce mémoire propose également                une analyse en profondeur des politiques concernant les enfants réfugiés non                accompagnés d'un adulte. On n'y étudie trois mécanismes international de protection:                the Convention of the Rights of the Child (CRC), 1951 United Nations Convention                Relating to the Status of Refugee and UNHCR 1997 Guidelines on Policies and                Procedures in Dealing with Unaccompanied Children Seeking Asylum, ainsi que deux                mécanisme canadiens: the Child Refugee Clai</description><description> The thesis seeks to explore the challenges faced by unaccompanied                refugee minors when seeking refugee protection. It will examine the way in which                discourses and policies, both in Canada and internationally, undermine unaccompanied                refugee minors accessing refugee protection or being successful in their claim.                Relying mainly on post-colonial theory, the thesis will address the historical                context that created the phenomenon of forced migration of children, and the role the                Global North plays in perpetuating it. Further, the thesis questions and                problematizes knowledge that it is taken for granted. It relies mainly on                postcolonial theories and Foucault's concept of power to understand how human                subjects, especially those from the Global South, have been constructed. It also                examines how this population of children became constructed as "problems" and the                role of discourses in assuming the nature of these problems. The thesis also provides                an in depth analysis of policy concerning unaccompanied refugee minors. Three                international protection instruments will be focused on: the Convention of the Rights                of the Child (CRC), 1951 United Nations Convention Relating to the Status of Refugee                and UNHCR 1997 Guidelines on Policies and Procedures in Dealing with Unaccompanied                Children Seeking Asylum, and two Canadian protection instruments, the Child Refugee                Claimants Procedural And Evidentiary Issues and the Immigration and Refugee                Protection Act. This thesis aims to shift and alter popular beliefs and perceptions                about the issue of unaccompanied refugee minors in the hope of bringing about                cultural-philosophical shift in attitudes.</description><creator>Diab, Soha</creator><contributor>Myriam Denov (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Social Sciences - Social Work</subject><title>Beyond borders: unaccompanied refugee minors and access to protection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cz35p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h91m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tt42w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La capacité des créanciers d'établir et de faire respecter                leurs droits envers leurs débiteurs est essentielle pour le financement de matériels                d'équipement mobiles d'une grande valeur marchande. Le nouveau cadre normatif de la                Convention relative aux garanties internationales portant sur des matériels                d'équipement mobiles et du Protocole portant sur les questions spécifiques aux                matériels d'équipement aéronautiques à la Convention relative aux garanties                internationales portant sur des matériels d'équipement mobiles tentent d'introduire                un système certain et efficace avec une procédure rapide qui pourra encourager les                financiers à investir dans les matériels d'équipement mobiles. Ce mémoire évalue les                remèdes recours disponibles lorsqu'un débiteur ne règle pas ses dettes échéances                Convention et les problèmes eventuels qui attendrons les créanciers si la Convention                et le Protocole ne sont pas exécutés (de la manière envisagée par leurs rédacteurs).                Nous incluons aussi une vue d'ensemble de cette Convention et du Protocole, en plus                d'un regard d'ensemble sur l'évolution de la réglementation juridique du financement                des aéronefs, en examinant l'instrument normatif antérieur le plus prestigieux -la                Convention relative à la reconnaissance internationale des droits sur les aéronefs.</description><description>The ability of creditors to establish and enforce claims against a                debtor is crucial for the financing of highly valuable moveable assets. The new                unified legal framework of the Convention on International Interests in Mobile                Equipment and the Protocol to the Convention on International Interests in Mobile                Equipment on Matters specific to Aircraft Equipment attempts to introduce a legally                certain, truly effective, and speedy enforcement system that can assure and encourage                the financiers to invest in Aircraft objects. This thesis assesses the default                remedies available upon a debtor's default as set out in these legal instruments and                the possible problems that the creditors might be confronted with should the Cape                Town Convention and the Aircraft Protocol not be implemented in the way the drafters                envisaged. It also provides an overview of the above mentioned Convention and the                Protocol, as well an overview of the evolution of legal regulation in aircraft                financing by examining the most important previous legal instrument - the Geneva                Convention on Recognition of Rights in Aircraft.</description><creator>Devinsky, Peter</creator><contributor>Yaell Emerich (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Speedy relief? The default remedies as set out in the Cape Town Convention and the Aircraft Protocol</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z64c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt42w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nc957</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:49:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Normal development of the placenta is crucial for embryonic survival and                growth. Tmed2 is a gene, which has been found to be necessary for the formation of                the labyrinth layer of the placenta, as well as for embryonic development. The                objectives of this thesis are to: describe the transcripts of Tmed2 using Northern                Blot analysis; elucidate the expression pattern of Tmed2 in the developing embryo and                placenta using whole mount and section in situ hybridization; determine whether                homozygous mutant embryos (Tmed299J/99J) are undergoing ER stress using RT-PCR. Tmed2                has three transcripts; however, only one of these transcripts contains exon 1 of the                gene. Tmed2 is expressed during the development of the embryo and placenta in those                tissues that are affected in the Tmed299J/99J mutants. Finally, Tmed2 homozygous                mutant embryos are not experiencing ER stress. Tmed2 is probably required for the                trafficking of an important protein(s) during development.</description><description>Le développement normal du placenta est essentiel à la                survie et la croissance embryonnaire. Tmed2 est un gène qui s'est révélé nécessaire                et important pour la formation de la couche labyrinthe du placenta, ainsi que pour le                développement embryonnaire. Les objectifs de cette thèse sont : de décrire la                transcription de Tmed2 en utilisant Northern Blot analysis; d'élucider le modèle                selon lequel s'exprime Tmed2 dans le développement de l'embryon et du placenta en                utilisant l'hybridation in situ complète ou en section; de déterminer si les embryons                mutants homozygotes (Tmed299J/99J) subissent un stress ER en utilisant le RT-PCR.                Tmed2 possède trois transcriptions; par contre, une seule de ses transcriptions                contient l'exon 1 du gène. Tmed2 s'exprime lors du développement de l'embryon et du                placenta dans les tissus qui sont affectés dans les Tmed299J/99J mutants. Finalement,                les embryons mutants homozygotes Tmed2 ne subissent pas de stress ER. Tmed2 est                probablement utilisé pour le trafic et le déplacement d'une ou de plusieurs protéines                importantes lors du développement.</description><creator>Achkar, Tala</creator><contributor>Loydie Majewska (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>The expression and role of «Tmed2»/TMED2 during the development of the murine embryo and placenta</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v964b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nc957</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38250</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>