<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:59:49Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2550" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vj93d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The clogging of fine-porosity geotextiles by soil particles is considered to be a problem in applications of these fabrics to filtering of municipal and industrial effluents. However, the clogging phenomenon can be an advantage for certain purposes, such as the creation of near-watertight membranes for sealing manure holding tanks. The conceived advantages of non-woven needle-punctured geotextiles are that they are less expensive due to lower material quantity, they are more resistant to tensile stresses compared to impermeable plastics and concrete, and they are easily installed. This thesis describes experimental work on the permeability and clogging characteristics of a Non-woven Polyester Geotextile with three different porosities (13.4, 19.5 and 26.0mum) but the same hydraulic conductivity (Kw = 10-5 m/s), when subjected to different heads of cattle slurry at 1, 2 and 4% total solids (TS) concentrations. The resulting infiltration rates were used to establish the effect of geotextile pore size and manure TS on geotextile sealing and to find the location of the seal, whether at the surface or within the geotextile. After 100 days of experimentation, the lowest infiltration rate of 1.1 L/m2/d was reached with the 13.4mum geotextile. Manure TS had a significant effect on the sealing and at least 4% TS was required to minimize the geotextile's infiltration rate. Clogging occurred within the pores, suggesting that the seal remains even after removing the manure. This advantage can be translated into economic benefit when fun cost comparisons with sealing liners such as geomembranes and concrete are undertaken. This research also reviews and analyzes the physical, chemical and biological processes leading to clogging of geotextiles as well as a cost-benefit comparison with the other sealing materials. The analysis concludes that clogged geotextiles are a wise choice for Canadian livestock producers.</description><creator>Jazestani, Jamshid</creator><contributor>Barrington, S. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Geotextiles.</subject><subject>Seepage.</subject><subject>Cattle -- Manure -- Storage.</subject><title>The sealing of non-woven geotextiles with cattle slurries /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qb999.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj93d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w197x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We have taken two approaches to evaluate the effects of drug resistant mutations in human immunodeficiency virus type-1 (HIV-1) reverse transcriptase (RT). First, we have expressed and purified histidine-tagged wildtype (wt) and mutant RTs by metal chelate affinity chromatography. The purification of wt RT and RTs containing the mutations M184V, M1841, E89G and E89G/M184V, by the method of Le Grice and Gruninger-Leitch (1990), will be discussed in Chapter 2. These enzymes were produced to evaluate the effects of these mutations on fidelity and processivity in vitro. Second, we have cultured wt and M184V-containing HIV-1 in the presence of a neutralizing monoclonal antibody, targeted to the V3 loop in gp120, and monitored for the emergence of neutralization escape variants. Although both cultures generated escape variants, sequence analysis revealed different neutralization escape mutations in wt and M184V-containing HIV-1. In the V3 loop cloned from wt cultures, the substitution of Lys for Arg at amino acid 20 (R20K) was associated with escape. In contrast, in M184V-containing cultures, the substitution of Tyr for Asn at amino acid 5 (N5Y) was associated with escape. The appearance of different neutralization escape mutations, encoded by different nucleotide substitutions, in wt and M184V-containing HIV-1 cultured under identical selection conditions is intriguing. We find the generation of an alternate escape variant by M184V-containing HIV-1 evidence that the mutational bias may be altered in this virus.</description><creator>Inouye, Phil.</creator><contributor>Wainberg, Mark A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Neutralizing autibody directed against the V3 loop selects for different escape variants in M184V-containing compared with wild-type human immunodeficiency virus type 1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m58p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w197x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c2820</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study of neuroplasticity following noxious stimulation has reinforced the clinical concept of pre-emptive analgesia, i.e. perioperative analgesic strategies aimed at diminishing post-operative pain. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the suppression of noxious stimulus-induced spinal sensitization by intravenous anaesthetics using FOS-like immunoreactivity (FLI) as an indicator of spinal sensitization in the rat formalin model. Pre-formalin injection (1.5% SC) treatment groups (3--4 rats/group) included IV saline controls, an IV anaesthetic (pentobarbital 20 mg/kg [barbiturate], propofol 10 mg/kc, [GABAergic anaesthetic], alphaxalone 1.5 mg/kg [steroid anaesthetic] or ketamine 10 mg/kg [dissociative anaesthetic]) and, for comparison, high-dose alfentanil 170mug/kg [synthetic mu-opioid]. Following perfusion 2 h post-formalin, spinal cords were dissected, sliced at 30 gm and processed by immunoperoxidase staining with an antibody against the FOS protein. Quantification and determination of the laminar distribution of FOS labeled nuclei were performed at the L4/5 spinal level ipsilateral to formalin injection. Drug groups demonstrating FLI suppression were comparatively studied in a 5 min post-formalin treatment group.</description><creator>Gilron, Ian.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Effects of intravenous anaesthetics on formalin-induced FOs immunoreactivity in the rat spinal cord</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km871.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c2820</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811km889</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The investigation of neuroendocrine abnormalities have been an active area of research in biological psychiatry. Nevertheless, there has been little prospective research on the Dexamethasone Suppression Test (DST) and 24 hour cortisol profile in Bipolar patients. These tests are measures of cortisol and the Hypothalamic-Pituitary-Adrenal axis which are indirect indications of abnormal limbic: system activity. The present study examined 24-hour cortisol levels and DST responses in 18 bipolar patients (6 depressed, 5 hypomanic and 7 euthymic) and 5 age and sex matched controls. In addition, two patients were examined in depressed, hypomanic, and euthymic states and served as their own control. The population studied consisted of outpatients between 25 to 62 years of age who were diagnosed with Bipolar Disorder following DSM-IV criteria. In the group study, bipolar patients in all phases exhibited substantially higher cortisol levels than age and sex matched controls. Higher cortisol levels in the hypomanic state have been observed when bipolar patients served as their own control. In addition, the DST did not appear to be highly sensitive or specific in bipolar patients and was not associated with 24 hour cortisol levels or severity of symptoms. The results demonstrate that HPA disturbances occur in all phases of bipolar disorder, not only during depressed states. These findings bring us closer to understanding the neuroendocrine pathophysiology occurring in bipolar disorder.</description><creator>Gelber, Stephen.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Psychology, Psychobiology.</subject><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>The Dexamethasone Suppression Test and 24 hour cortisol profile in depressive, hypomanic and euthymic phases of bipolar patients /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462761r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km889</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hm36b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Normal breast growth and development depends on functional androgen:estrogen (A:E) balance. Androgen actions are mediated by the androgen receptor (AR), a DNA-binding, transcriptional-regulatory protein. Decreased AR transactivational. activity lowers A:E balance and may result in functional hyperestrogenicity: this could promote the pathogenesis of breast cancer (BC). The present study is the first to seek AR mutations in female BC. The length of the polymorphic CAG-repeat in exon 1 of the AR correlates inversely with the transactivational activity of the AR. Using 10% polyacrylamide gels, I found a significant (p &lt; 0.0001) shift to greater CAG-repeat lengths in BC samples. This suggests a role for ARs with long polyglutamine tracts in the initiation and/or progression of BC. Exons 2--8 of the AR in 81 fresh frozen BC tumor tissues were screened for mutations using SSCP analysis. I did not detect any mutations in these exons.</description><creator>Elhaji, Youssef A.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Breast -- Cancer.</subject><subject>Androgens -- Receptors.</subject><title>Androgen receptor mutation in breast cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz752.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hm36b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b551r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is proposed that the viscosity dependence of the triplet lifetimes of aromatic chromophores arises from local diffusional-type motions around the chromophore. In an attempt to ascertain if motions of this type are indeed responsible for triplet quenching, the phosphorescence decay of carbazole covalently bound to a methyl acrylate (90%) methyl methacrylate (10%) copolymer backbone, with a glass transition temperature of 19°C, was studied as a function of temperature. The phosphorescence decay was non-exponential but well defined using a bi-exponential fit. It showed the greatest drop in intensity and lifetime centered around the glass transition temperature. Mechanical shear was exerted on the polymer with varying force, frequency and temperature, so as to induce motional perturbations on the carbazole. Frequencies matching the approximate timescale of the polymer motions, and temperatures slightly above the glass transition, showed the greatest effects of perturbation. Under optimal shearing conditions, relative increases in the short-lived component of the decay of up to 22% were observed, while the long lifetime dropped by 5%.</description><creator>Dracopoulos, John.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>The influence of shear on the triplet state decay of chromophores in synthetic polymers /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq285.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b551r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wf99k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Quadriceps, muscle endurance, fatigue and recovery were evaluated in elite and novice rowers in order to elucidate the mechanisms underlying the development and recovery from fatigue following several bouts of exercise. Baseline evaluations recorded the maximum voluntary contraction (MVC) using a force transducer, muscle activation via the Interpolated Twitch Technique (ITT) and the compound muscle action potential (m-wave) from the electromyographic (EMG) signal. Contractile properties of the twitch, which included the peak tension (Pt), time to peak tension (TPT) and half-relaxation time (RT 1/2), were also recorded. The rowers then completed a 2500 meter simulated rowing race and the muscle was re-evaluated. Two successive standard fatigue protocols (SFP) followed with subsequent evaluations taking place after each SFP. The successive bouts of exercise caused the MVC to drop considerably. Results revealed that excitation-contraction (E-C) uncoupling was the major factor behind the development of fatigue in both groups due to the differential effects of fatigue and recovery on Pt versus MVC. Activation levels dropped minimally and m-wave amplitudes were unchanged from pre-fatigue levels. Elite rowers' quadriceps muscles demonstrated superior endurance during both SFPs, but to a lesser extent following the second SFP. These results suggest that possible metabolic differences in the environment of the muscle may lead to increased resistance to local muscle fatigue in elite rowers. This research study contributes to the current understanding of neuromuscular fatigue and adds to the physiological profile of athletes who participate in the sport of rowing.</description><creator>Di Spirito, Michele.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Recreation.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Quadriceps muscle endurance, fatigue and recovery in rowers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gn12d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wf99k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc718</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The human androgen receptor (hAR) is a ligand-activated, DNA-binding nuclear transcription factor. Mutations in the hAR result in varying degrees of androgen insensitivity (AI); they may play a predisposing or pathogenetic role in both prostate and breast cancer. Expansion of the hAR's N-terminal polymorphic Glutamine (Gln) repeat causes a late-onset progressive motoneuronopathy which is associated with mild androgen insensitivity: spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA). SBMA belongs to a group of translated CAG trinucleotide repeat expansion neuronopathies that includes Huntington disease, dentatorubral-pallidoluysian atrophy and five distinct spinocerebellar ataxias. The fact that this group of disorders is caused by polyGln expansions in totally unrelated proteins, is one of the main reasons for postulating that a common gain-of-function mechanism must underlie their communal pathogenesis. This common pathogenetic mechanism is postulated to occur via aberrant protein interactions. I undertook a search for hAR-interacting proteins using a yeast two-hybrid system. A human testes cDNA library was screened several times with two forms of an N-terminal fragment of the hAR: a normal (20 Gin) hAR and an expanded (50 Gin) hAR. A few candidate hAR-interacting proteins were isolated during the library screenings and I tested them for physiological relevance. A second aspect of my project included the analysis of an aberrant 75-kD protein fragment generated in COS-1 cells transfected with a polyCAG-expanded (n = 44) hAR cDNA. Recent work in Huntington disease and spinocerebellar ataxia type 3 shows the accumulation of insoluble protein aggregates primarily in the nucleus of certain brain cells (Davies et al., 1997; Scherzinger et al., 1997; Paulson et al., 1997). I confirmed the presence of the aberrant hAR-fragment in the nucleus through western analysis of protein samples extracted from the nucleus.</description><creator>De Tourreil, Sunita.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Muscular atrophy -- Pathogenesis.</subject><subject>Androgens -- Receptors.</subject><title>Novel androgen receptor-protein interactions as possible contributors to the pathogenesis of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd856.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc718</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rq92v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Smoking cessation leads to weight gain but the reason for this gain is not clearly established. The objective of this study was to compare the mean change in dietary intake among quitters and non-quitters enrolled in a smoking cessation program. Mean dietary intake was measured using 24-hour recall over the telephone at baseline and 6 weeks after the scheduled 'quit date'. Baseline data were obtained from 177 subjects and 130 (73%) were recontacted with complete data. There were 47 quitters (27%). The mean self-reported weight gain among the quitters and non-quitters was 2.4 kg +/- 3.1 and 0.04 kg +/- 2.5 respectively (p = 0.001). Mean energy intake was the same at baseline between the quitters and non-quitters. There were statistically significant changes in dietary intake between quitters and non-quitters. Given the high within-individual variability (sd 832) this sample size was only sufficient to detect differences in the change in intake of approximately 460 kcals between quitters and non-quitters.</description><creator>Crawford, Caroline.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Diet.</subject><subject>Nicotine addiction -- Treatment.</subject><subject>Weight gain.</subject><title>The effects of smoking cessation on changes in dietary intake /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fk226.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq92v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q848q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The taxonomy of this genus is studied, three species of Eurycantha were chosen, E. horrida, E. coriacea and E. calcarata from which two subspecies were collected, termed and identified by the Phasmid Study Group: PSG 23 and PSG 44. Morphological characters and morphometrical data of the adults of E. calcarata PSG 23 and E. horrida as well as data on the ultrastructure and morphometrics of the eggs of all aforementioned species were obtained from this study to show differences and similarities between species and subspecies; partial 16S gene rRNA sequence was used to show genetic relationships between the species. Similarities of the various wild populations of E. horrida were determined based on morphological and genetic data, showing that even though the species is distributed vastly between mainland Papua New Guinea and surrounding islands, characteristics vary little. Egg measurements varied more between subspecies of E. calcarata than between E. calcarata and E. coriacea; the mtDNA sequence equally showed higher intraspecific differences between E. calcarata subspecies than within E. horrida populations. Morphological and genetic data showed that E. horrida and E. calcarata are very closely related. Morphometric ratios between the two species were not significantly different, although there was a variance close to 6.2 percent in the mtDNA sequencing results. Genetic data and morphological characters of the egg showed that E. coriacea was the farthest removed species of those studied with a variance in mtDNA sequencing of 7.3 percent with E. calcarata and 6.8 percent with E. horrida.</description><creator>Chee, Zoe Aimee.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Phasmatoptera -- Morphology.</subject><subject>Phasmatoptera -- Genetics.</subject><title>Morphological and genetic studies of Eurycantha species (Cheleutoptera:Phasmatidae)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r796.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q848q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k9389</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The magnocellular neurosecretory cells (MNCs) synthesizing and secreting the hormones vasopressin (VP) and oxytocin (OXT) are best known for their direct role in controlling the body fluid homeostasis through changing their firing rates in response to changes in the osmolarity of the extracellular fluid, and subsequent neurohypophysial hormone release. In response to dehydration, MNCs fire clusters of action potentials to maintain sustained high levels of VP to overcome the circulatory failure (Poulain et aL, 1988). Changes in the osmotic pressure have been shown ta be a potent regulater of MNC activity and neurohypophysial hormone release. In addition, recent eleetrophysiological studies have shown that different substances released in the central nervous system (CNS) such as catecholamines and neuropeptides can modulate the excitability of MNCs and play a role in their hormone release into the circulation.</description><creator>Chakfe, Yassar.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Patch-clamp analysis of peptidergic excitation in rat supraoptic neurons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj46w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k9389</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547t628</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Metabolites of arachidonic acid, known as eicosanoids, result from two enzymatic pathways: cyclooxygenase (COX) and lipoxygenase (LOX). Indomethacin (INDO), at a dose level of approximately 10 mg/kg, has been commonly used in studies on the role of prostagiandins (PG) in the porcine ovulatory process since it was believed to be specific in its inhibition of the COX pathway. Other evidence suggests that INDO also has inhibitory effects on the formation of LOX metabolites including 12- and 15-hydroxyeicosatetraenoic acid (HETE). There is also evidence that LOX metabolites may have a role in the ovulatory process of the rat and the pig. In the previous studies on PGs in porcine ovulation, the effect of INDO on LOX metabolites was not examined. It has been shown that progesterone has a role in the formation of eicosanoids in the ovary in the rat and the ewe. The results of this study indicate that an intramuscular injection of INDO, at dose levels as high as 5 mg/kg, reduces ovulation rat and preovulatory follicular fluid concentrations of PGF2alpha without affecting concentrations of 12- and 15-HETE in the gonadotropin-primed pig. Indomethacin, at dose levels as low as 1 mg/kg, reduced ovulation rate and intrafollicular PGF2alpha concentrations but 0.1 mg/kg had no effect on ovulation rate or PGF2alpha. In cultured granulosa and theca interna cells, 10 ng or greater of INDO per 3 x 105 cells reduces PGF2alpha accumulation in the media. Accumulation of 12- and 15-BETE in the media was reduced by 100 ng or greater of INDO per 3 x 10 5 cells. To examine the role of progesterone in the formation of eicosanoids, danazol, an inhibitor of steroidogenesis, was added to cultures of porcine follicular cells. This treatment had no effect on progesterone production by either cell type and, similarly, had no effect on eicosanoid production. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Cassidy, Carrie.</creator><contributor>Downey, B. R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Prostaglandins.</subject><subject>Ovulation.</subject><subject>Swine -- Reproduction -- Endocrine aspects.</subject><title>Further evidence that prostaglandin F2-alpha is the obligatory eicosanoid in porcine ovulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d2225.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547t628</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qp271</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The presence of persistent organic pollutants, including the pesticide toxaphene, has been reported even in remote regions such as the Arctic and is becoming a health concern. The technical mixture of toxaphene contains over 800 different congeners; however, the numbers decrease along the food chain. Only two major congeners, 2-exo, 3-endo, 5-exo, 6-endo,8,8,9,10,10-octachlorobomane (T2) and 2-exo, 3-endo, 5-exo, 6-endo,8,8,9,10,10-nonachlorobomane (T12) have been found in humans. Information on the embryotoxicity of toxaphene is based only on studies using the toxaphene technical mixture and not its major congeners. Diabetes mellitus, one of the most common maternal illness resulting in congenital defects, is now on an upgrowth trend in many native communities. Xenobiotics, such as toxaphene, may induce interactive effects with hyperglycemia, a teratogenic metabolic agent. In the present study, the relative dysmorphogenic effects of the toxaphene technical mixture or its congeners (T2 and T12) and the interactive effects of these compounds and high glucose concentrations were investigated using rat embryo culture. Early stage embryos (0--2 somite) were treated with three different doses of the toxaphene technical mixture, T2, T12, or 50:50 mixture of T2 and T12 and incubated in normal or hyperglycemic culture media for 48 h. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Calciu, Cristina Dana.</creator><contributor>Chan, L. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Kubow, S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Rats -- Embryos.</subject><subject>Hyperglycemia.</subject><subject>Toxaphene -- Toxicology.</subject><subject>Teratogenesis.</subject><title>The interactive effects of toxaphene, toxaphene congeners, and hyperglycemia on cultured rat embryos /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214r32n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qp271</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268735n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nitrous oxide (N2O) produced from agricultural activities must be determined if management procedures to reduce emissions are to be established. From 1994 to 1996, N20 emissions were determined under continuous corn and corn-legume rotations in different soils of Quebec. Continuous corn was studied on four sites, two from a long-term experiment, a Ste. Rosalie heavy clay (Humic Gleysol) and a Chicot sandy loam (Gray-Brown Luvisol), at 0, 170,285 and 400 kg N ha-1, and two from a corn rotation study, a Ste. Rosalie clay (Humic Gleysol) and an Ormstown silty clay loam (Humic Gleysol). Treatments in the rotation study included no-till (NT) and conventional tillage (CT), monocropped corn, monocropped soybean-, corn-soybean; and soybean-corn-alfalfa phased rotations. Nitrogen rates of 0, 90, and 180 kg N ha-1 for corn and 0, 20, and 40 kg N ha-1 for monocropped soybean were used, and soybean/alfalfa with no fertilizer N following corn. Rates of N2O emissions were significantly affected by N fertilization, tillage and soil moisture content. Generally, N2O emissions were higher in the NT systems, with corn, and increased with increasing N rates. Increased nitrogen applications led to linear increases in N2O emission over the three years for both Ste. Rosalie (2) and Ormstown soils at a rate of 1.0 to 1.6 percent of added N. The N 2O emission rates were significantly related to soil denitrification rates, water filled pore space, and soil NH4+ and NO3-- concentrations in all three years. A corn system using conventional tillage, legumes in rotation and reduced N fertilizer would decrease N2O emission from agricultural fields.</description><creator>Cadrin, François.</creator><contributor>Mackenzie, A. F. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Tillage.</subject><subject>Nitrous oxide.</subject><subject>Nitrogen fertilizers.</subject><subject>Cropping systems.</subject><title>Effets du travail du sol, des systèmes de culture (monoculture et rotation) et du niveau de fertilisation azotée sur les émissions d'oxyde nitreux (N2O)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b5521.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268735n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73pz14x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alvars are naturally open habitats which are found in the Great Lakes region in North America and in Scandinavia. The insect fauna of four types of alvars (grassland, grassland savanna, shrubland and pavement) was sampled in the summer of 1996 on Manitoulin Island, Ontario. A total of 9791 specimens from four target insect groups (Coleoptera: Carabidae, Homoptera: Auchenorrhyncha, Hymenoptera: Symphyta and Lepidoptera: Papilionoidea and Hesperioidea) was identified. Results showed that the grassland savanna and grassland alvars supported the highest number of insect specimens whereas the pavement alvar supported the highest number of species. The origin of the fauna differed between the taxa depending on their closer association with specific microclimatic conditions (Carabidae) or on the presence of host plants (Auchenorrhynca). This first inventory of alvar insects in North America revealed the presence of a high number of species of interest to conservation (rare, disjunct or restricted species).</description><creator>Bouchard, Patrice.</creator><contributor>Wheeler, T. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Insects -- Ontario -- Manitoulin Island.</subject><subject>Alvar regions -- Ontario -- Manitoulin Island.</subject><subject>Species diversity -- Ontario -- Manitoulin Island.</subject><title>Insect diversity of four alvar sites on Manitoulin Island, Ontario</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cz776.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73pz14x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vn118</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We investigated the feasibility of using X-rays to study self-assembled monolayers on inorganic surfaces. Variable-temperature X-ray powder diffraction measurements of metal alkylphosphonate salts measured the contraction and expansion of planar inorganic layers as the material passed through a series of phase transitions when heated and cooled. Small-angle X-ray scattering measurements of alkanethiolate-capped gold nanoclusters allowed the determination of the average nanocluster size and the average distance between nanoclusters. These techniques have been demonstrated to contribute useful information which, when combined with results from other probes, lead to a detailed model of the materials' structures and properties.</description><creator>Borthwick, Matthew A.</creator><contributor>Sutton, Mark (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>X-ray techniques for probing self-assembled monolayer structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc55n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vn118</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064799v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The influence of human disturbance on the nesting success of the Common eider (Sonateria mollissima) was investigated in the Mingan Archipelago National Park Reserve during summers of 1994 to 19%. Six colonies were used, four located on open islets and two on forested islands. Three experimental treatments were used that entailed varying the frequency and time occurrence of visits in incubation. Every years, each treatment was applied to several eider colonies differing in the density of nesting gulls on the same island. During visits, incubating females were flushed and nest fate recorded. Several variables also were measured during visits describing female quality (assessed by clutch size and laying date) and nest site quality (assessed by nest concealment, distance to shore, vegetation height, and density of nesting gulls on the island). Results showed that frequency of visits did not affect nesting success of eiders, mainly because most observed nest failures occurred after the first visit The time occurrence of the first visit during incubation was of primary importance; eider nests visited early were much more affected by our presence. The nesting success of eiders was related to the density of associated colonies of nesting gulls only when visits occurred during early incubation. Female eiders of greater reproductive quality were those most successful when disturbed regularly. These females were in greater proportion on islands associated with lower density of nesting gulls, i.e., on forested islands rather than on open islets. Within colonies, they were mainly found nesting near shore where nest concealment is sparse. Results showed that visits to eider colonies can greatly affect their reproductive output. Visits during early incubation on open islets had the greatest impact.</description><creator>Bolduc, François.</creator><contributor>Guillemette, Magella (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Titman, Rodger D. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Eider -- Québec (Province) -- Mingan Islands -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Eider -- Nests -- Québec (Province) -- Mingan Islands.</subject><title>The impact of human disturbance on the nesting success of the common eider Somateria mollissima /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408032x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064799v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236424m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The radiotracer methodology was combined with the Hoagland solution culture of growing soybean in a greenhouse to investigate the absorptions of phosphorus (P), calcium (Ca), and sodium (Na) as a function of salinity. Salt stress was varied by using zero to 120 mM NaCl. The research was initiated because of a need to increase soybean production in the saline soils of the semi-arid regions of the world. Although P absorption increased with time at each concentration of NaCl, increasing its concentrations ([NaCl]) to 120 mM reduced P uptake considerably. The addition of inorganic P (Pi) to the salt medium improved P absorption significantly (P &lt; 0.0001) in stem, petiole, and roots. Polynomial regressions showed the relationship between 22Na activity and [NaCl] for leaves and petiole to be cubic (R2 = 1) while in the stem a quadratic relationship prevailed. A maximum of P and Na absorption was observed at 40 mM NaCl. The relationship between 32P activity and increasing [NaCl] was linear for the roots (a positive slope) and the stem (a negative slope). 45Ca and 32P dual labelling part of the experiments failed to produce results because an unexpectedly high degree of tissue quenching which prevented from obtaining the minimum counting requirements for separation. Shoot fresh and dry weights decreased linearly with increasing [NaCl] as did the root fresh and dry weights. Leaf chlorophyll content during the last week of the final harvest showed a linear relationship with time. Chlorophyll increased with time linearly when the growth medium contained zero and 40 mM NaCl; whereas a negative slope was obtained for 80 and 120 mM NaCl. It seems that P fertilization of the soil could ameliorate the salt effect. 22 Na uptake results indicated that there is a mechanism for exclusion of Na from soybean plant parts.</description><creator>Attumi, Al-Arbe.</creator><contributor>Barthakur, N. N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Soils, Salts in.</subject><subject>Soybean -- Effect of salt on.</subject><subject>Phosphorus in agriculture.</subject><title>Effect of salt stress on phosphorus and sodium absorptions by soybean plants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fk23g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236424m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b5539</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this study was to further understanding of the ecology and propagation of an important wild food resource (Vatovaea pseudolablab (Harms.) Gillett of the community of Loodokilani, Kajiado District Kenya and by extension, contribute to its sustainable use. Vatovaea pseudolablab is found in occasional, yet distinct patches in Lookidalani and these patches may be associated with a particular soil-water regime. The associated soils are moderately developed, dark brown (7.5YR 3/2, Munsell) clayloams, with small (5.61 mm), angular blocky aggregates. The patches were moderately covered (30%) with medium-sized stones (9.5 cm). Woody and leafy cuttings from wild stock were collected and rooted easily using a minimum of technological inputs. Roofing percentages were better under the hotter and drier conditions in Kilinito. In conclusion, the data gathered for this study were analyzed within the framework developed by Amold et al. (1985) for evaluating sustainable use strategies for indigenous plants. The low densities of V. pseudolablab found within the patches coupled with the high grazing pressure make it unlikely that wild resources could sustain higher usage. This study highlights some of the greatest methodological problems facing ethnobotanical, and related, research in pastoral communities. More attention should be directed towards developing research methodologies to further our understanding of wild food plants in pastoral communities.</description><creator>Arnott, Sheri-Lee C.</creator><contributor>Johns, Tim (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Vatovaea pseudolablab -- Ecology -- Kenya -- Kajiado District.</subject><subject>Legumes -- Ecology -- Kenya -- Kajiado District.</subject><subject>Masai (African people) -- Food -- Kenya -- Kajiado District.</subject><subject>Wild plants, Edible -- Kenya -- Kajiado District.</subject><title>The ecology and propagation of Vatovaea pseudolablab : a wild food plant of the Maasai in Kajiado District, Kenya</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mf065.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b5539</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95052565</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has long been postulated that the facet joint geometry (FJG) has an important influence on lumbar segmental motion. Although their sagittal orientation has been described in detail, there are very few studies describing the three-dimensional (3D) FJG. None correlates the latter to segmental kinematics. In view, we developed a method to quantify 3D FJG and compared the results to segmental kinematics. In the ex-vivo set-up, facets of individual cadaveric vertebrae taken from a previous biomechanical. study were digitized using a 3D morphometer and the geometry of the facet joints in respect to the vertebra's local coordinate system was quantified. In the in-vivo set-up, re-recruited subjects from a previous kinematic study had a MRI of their lumbar spine. The images were digitized and the facet joint's 3D geometry was evaluated. The two methods used for FJG measurements were validated. Kinematic data derived from both previous studies was correlated with their respective FJG. We did not find a significant influence of the FJG or tropism on lumbar segmental kinematics. Different coupling patterns were measured in the ex-vivo and in in-vivo experiments. This is likely due to the absence of muscle activity in the cadaveric specimen. Future in-vivo studies should be done with simultaneous muscle activity recording to better understand the coupling patterns. Studying FJG in defined spinal pathologies may render valuable information on the etiology of spinal diseases.</description><creator>Andreou, Antonios.</creator><contributor>Aebi, Max (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>The influence of facet joint geometry on lumbar segmental kinematics : an ex-vivo &amp; in-vivo study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v86z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95052565</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Orthopaedic Research Laboratory</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p0371</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pharmacokinetics of verapamil were evaluated in the young and elderly after steady state administration of a sustained release formulation. The objective was to determine whether the interindividual metabolic variability of verapamil and its main metabolites could be correlated with the enzymatic activity of CYP3A4 by using dextromethorphan (DM) as an in vivo probe of CYP3A4 activity. Pharmacokinetic analysis showed a significant age related increase in the clearance of verapamil. Verapamil interindividual variability could not be correlated with formation of 3-methoxy-morphinan. Our results suggest that verapamil metabolism may be significantly mediated by other cytochromes.</description><creator>Anacleto, Ana Isabel.</creator><contributor>Wainer, Irving (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Interpatient variability with the disposition of verapamil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g952c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p0371</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m169b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>My study concerns the works of William James (1842--1910) and the Buddhist thinker Vasubandhu (circa fifth c.). In both cases there is a detailed examination of consciousness which looks at its physiological concomitants. Where James is concerned, this physiological study is found mainly within his Principles of Psychology (1890). In Vasubandhu's case the physiological preconditions of conscious life is inherited from traditional Buddhist psychology (skandhas), but are expanded into the Yogacara concept of the alaya-vijnana (storehouse consciousness). This novel form of consciousness has been interpreted as both a soul theory in Buddhism, and a form of metaphysical idealism. It is these elements that I juxtapose with similar notions found in Jamesian studies (self and idealism). Thus, Chapter One examines consciousness from the isolated perspective of each thinker, Chapter Two moves to an examination of self, and Chapter Three looks at the possibility of Idealism which is explicitly rejected by James, and is rejected also by many interpreters of the alaya-vijnana.</description><creator>Sims, Jeffrey H.</creator><contributor>Hayes, Richard P. (advisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>James, William, 1842-1910.</subject><subject>Yogācāra (Buddhism)</subject><subject>James, William, 1842-1910. Principles of psychology.</subject><subject>Consciousness -- History.</subject><subject>Vasubandhu.</subject><title>Piecemeal streams in Yogācārin themes : William James and Vasubandhu</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp920.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m169b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t4264</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a novel approach to the instruction scheduling problem for dynamic issue processors. Our approach aims at generating an instruction sequence with a low register pressure and a high level of Instruction-Level Parallelism (ILP) exploitable by the dynamic issue mechanism of the processor. Our objective is to improve the performance of the program by taking advantage of the out-of-order execution and register renaming mechanisms of the processor to reduce the amount of spill code introduced by the register allocator. Our approach uses a traditional ILP scheduler to generate an initial schedule for the program, and then reorders its instructions to reduce the register pressure of the program. This reordering is performed carefully. to ensure that the dynamic issue mechanism of the processor is able to exploit from the reordered sequence as much parallelism as available on the original schedule. We have proposed an approximate method to determine, for a given instruction sequence and a given instruction schedule, whether a particular dynamic issue superscalar processor can exploit from the sequence as much ILP as present in the schedule. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Silvera Muñoz, Raúl E.</creator><contributor>Gao, Guang R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Static instruction scheduling for dynamic issue processors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3389.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t4264</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x81g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many uses of process models have been suggested in the literature, such as process models can help in understanding a process or they can be used as a baseline for process improvement. However, there are few quantitative studies that have validated these uses. In this thesis, we describe one use of process models by demonstrating empirically how process models help in achieving common understanding of a process among the people associated with the process. Literature in management sciences prescribes achieving common understanding of the process as an essential element of an effective organization. To carry out our research, case study was used as the research method. The study involved modelling the Transport Canada Aviation Technical Training Planning Process. Data collected during the study was analyzed using our metrics and the results showed that in the absence process models, the process agents could specify approximately 26% of the activities and 10% of the artifacts of the Technical Training Planning Process, and demonstrated that process models helped in achieving a common understanding of the process among the people associated with the process.</description><creator>Siddiqui, Saeed.</creator><contributor>Madhavji, Nazim H. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Measuring the impact of process models on achieving a common understanding of a process : a case study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg004.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x81g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm613</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Infrastructure is the foundation and the basic framework which permits cities to function. However, there are significant infrastructure problems in North America. In cities across North America, the infrastructure is deteriorating. The efficiency of a community depends on the condition of its infrastructure. The health and welfare of the residents and the economy of a country requires an efficient and sound infrastructure. North America will not achieve prosperity if it allows its urban infrastructure to decay to the Developing World's levels. Increased new sources of revenue need to be explored by political officials to pay for the cost of upgrading our infrastructure to an acceptable level. In addition, developing an effective management, approach is a long-term way to handle a problem as large and as serious as our current infrastructure crisis. Current engineering and construction practices have proved to be detrimental to our environment and depletion of natural resources. The future role of civil engineers should be the prevention of any damage to our environment and natural resources, and this can be achieved by incorporating sustainability into the current engineering and construction practices. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Siddiqui, Sadaf.</creator><contributor>Mirza, M. Saeed (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><title>Infrastructure, sustainable development &amp; society</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft616.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm613</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2575</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>