<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:47:37Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):24500" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579t33q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The laws and regulations governing certification of aviation personnel constitute one of the essential elements of aviation legislation. They have a significant effect upon the global safety of the civil air transportation system. This dissertation aims at describing the existing regulations in the field of pilot licensing. Its scope is narrowed down to the highest category of licence applicable to professional pilots and known as the airline transport pilot licence. The thesis depicts and analyses the process of creation and the contents of licensing standards and recommended practices as developed by various ICAO bodies and incorporated in Annex 1 to the Chicago Convention. The survey of pilot licensing system currently in force in Canada provides the example of domestic legislation applicable in this respect. It is performed with the aim of exploring the compatibility of Canadian law with the global legal requirements as prescribed in Annex 1 and other supporting ICAO documentation.</description><creator>Swiecicki, Ewa</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Legal aspects of licensing of airline transport pilots : international standards versus Canadian aviation safety regulations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m7733.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579t33q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741s928</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examined the introduction of a Child Sexual Abuse Protocol, supported by a specialized training program, in a large social service centre, to determine effects on social work practice and case outcomes. The sample (N = 261) represented referrals during two years, one before and one after introduction of the Protocol. Data sources were agency files, supplemented by interviews with five key informants. It was found that the Protocol and training had little effect on worker practice or case outcomes. An uneven and ambiguous implementation process, combined with the lack of coordination of the social service, police, and judicial systems, were contributing factors. The conflicting views of managers were important influences. Interagency coordination, and application of consistent standards, are recommended. Effective intervention in child sexual abuse cases requires a revision of the Protocol, which takes into account the experiences and limitations of the participating systems.</description><creator>Thomas-Morton, Sherry</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Child health services -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Child sexual abuse -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Child sexual abuse protocol : changing social work practice?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v187.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741s928</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gf120</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this study was to evaluate the short-term (one-year) biomass production in red clover and to obtain an estimate of the heritability of this characteristic. Progenies from parents with high biomass had higher biomass than those from parents with low biomass or having one parent in each category. The narrow-sense heritability estimated from mid-parent offspring regression was 0.23, from parent-offspring correlation was 0.22, and realized heritability was 0.15, indicating that progeny testing would be required for successful selection of populations with greater biomass production. Plants selected for high biomass production tended to have higher shoot:root ratios and flower more profusely than the parental checks and the low biomass plants. This indicates that by selecting for high biomass, red clover will be selected for more annual growth habit at the same time.</description><creator>Kongkiatngam, Prasert</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Red clover.</subject><subject>Plant biomass.</subject><title>Short-term biomass production of red clover (Trifolium pratense L.) and its inheritance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bc78k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gf120</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xw122</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms has significantly changed the functions of the Canadian courts. Ever since its entrenchment in 1982, the third branch of government has enjoyed a powerful status in the Canadian polity. Countless Charter decisions, affecting the lives of all Canadians, have been rendered. The courts have been asked to rule on cruise missile testing, abortion, aboriginal rights, minority language rights and a whole range of other issues of a political, economic or social nature. Our political system, whose traditional foundations lay in the principle of parliamentary supremacy, has become one of constitutional supremacy. The new and powerful status of the nonelected judiciary has raised serious questions not only regarding the legitimacy of judicial review under the Charter but also the institutional capacity of the courts to face the Charter challenge. The author examines the nature of the judiciary's policy-making function under the Charter in order to determine the extent to which the courts are equipped to fulfil their task. The thesis suggests that in order to face the Charter challenge effectively, the courts can no longer operate within the framework of the traditional adversary process. Instead, the courts must constantly look to the prevailing values in our society as well as examine thoroughly social and scientific phenomena before rendering an "informed" policy decision. This can only be achieved through a coherent framework of Charter analysis and effective ways in handling extrinsic materials. The focus of the present paper is on section 1 of the Charter which, due to its open-ended language, most clearly invites courts to make policy-type decision.</description><creator>Zagalski, Cezar</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Judicial power -- Canada</subject><subject>Constitutional law -- Canada.</subject><title>The courts and public policy : towards more effective judicial policy-making</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149q93t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw122</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053h11p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to determine how one organization from the private sector managed the socialization and development of its middle management personnel at the growth career life cycle stages of its managers: recruitment and hiring, entry-level, mid-career, and the retirement stage. The organization studied was a Quebec based retail chain composed of twenty stores located in Quebec and Ontario. The findings indicated that there was a discrepancy between what the organization stated it was doing and what its middle management perceived was actually occurring. In three out of the five career life cycle stages, as described in the review of literature, the necessary formal structures and processes required to accomplish the socialization and development of the organization's middle management personnel were nonexistent. In only two of the career life cycle stages did the organization have in place a formal structure and set of processes relating to the specific socialization and development stages of its employees. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Brown, David, 1951-</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Career development</subject><subject>Personnel management -- Québec (Province) -- Case studies</subject><title>A case study of the structures and processes involved in the socialization and development of middle management personnel in the private sector /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ch74b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h11p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483k46x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a study on the response of the British and the French to Muhammad 'Ali's policies. Muhammad 'Ali success in transforming Egypt into a powerful state was aimed at developing Egypt's commercial network and expanding her territorial boundary. The gains that Muhammad 'Ali achieved from the commerce and territorial conquest, however, was at the expense of what England had enjoyed before Muhammad 'Ali rose to power. In order to regain what had been lost to Muhammad 'Ali England undertook a strong response consisting of economic, military and diplomatic pressure which led to the collapse of Muhammad 'Alis power. France, on the other hand, had a positive reaction and gave full support to Muhammad 'Alis expansionist policy. Nevertheless, France's final act was to abandon policy of support for Muhammad 'Ali as a result of European politics when a new French government sought rapprochement with England. Muhammad 'Ali became a cost of rapprochement.</description><creator>Hamim, Thoha</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Egypt -- History -- Mohammed Ali, 1805-1849</subject><title>The British and the French responses to Muhạmmad Ali's policies /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wd915.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483k46x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jc51d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis analyzes Kenneth Burke's rhetoric of identification. I will examine the extent to which Burke's earliest critical writings, which focus on the suasive nature of literary forms, affected the writing of his later critical works, which deal with how language functions as a type of symbolic action. In his later texts, Burke breaks with his earlier concern with literary discourse by attempting to expound a critical theory that accounts for historical change, human motivation and the role of language in collective communities. He argues that language motivates people to identify with a certain sets of beliefs by transcending an opposing set of beliefs. Section One is an account of Burke's earlier conception of ideology in relation to his view of literary discourse. In Section Two the emphasis shifts toward a study of how Burke integrates his notion of ideology with his theory of a rhetoric of identification.</description><creator>Behr, Martin</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Burke, Kenneth, 1897-1993.</subject><title>Continuity and change in the thought of Kenneth Burke</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wn94b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jc51d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558f39w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The muscle of shellfish, in particular shrimp, is characterized by high amounts of free amino acids especially glycine as well as proline, serine and alanine which all contribute to the overall pleasant and desirable flavour perceived. The two major proteolytic enzymes, chymotrypsin and trypsin, were used at different ratios (E/S, 0.0-0.3%), temperatures (25$ sp circ$C-45$ sp circ$C) and time of hydrolysis (1-3h) for frozen and fresh shrimp. These conditions were optimized in order to generate a product with desirable sensory and chemical characteristics. The thermal stability of chymotrypsin and trypsin were investigated, to determine the suitability of heat to stop the hydrolysis reactions at desired conditions. The results for the frozen shrimp showed that chymotrypsin was found to be inactivated after incubation for 1 min at 80$ sp circ$C while trypsin was found to be relatively heat stable. The commercial soybean trypsin inhibitor was used to inactivate trypsin. The use of both enzymes accelerate the rate of hydrolysis to some extent. Higher free amino acids yield for glycine, serine, and proline were obtained for chymotrypsin-treated hydrolysates. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Nayeri, Gita</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Flavoring essences.</subject><title>Enzymatic hydrolysis of shrimp for recovery of taste active compounds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp32j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558f39w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t3144</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Specimens of freshwater bryozoans (Ectoprocta) and sponges (Porifera: Spongillidae), two of the most poorly known faunal groups in Canada, were obtained from various locations in Ontario, Quebec, New Brunswick, Nova Scotia, Prince Edward Island, and Newfoundland. A total of 14 species of bryozoans and 15 species of sponges were identified. In 31 cases, these species were recorded from a province for the first time. Species new to Canada include the bryozoans Lophopodella carteri, Plumatella orbisperma, and Pottsiella erecta, and the sponges Radiospongilla crateriformis, Spongilla aspinosa, and Trochospongilla horrida. The morphology, taxonomy, distribution, and ecology of each species are examined. Several taxonomic revisions are made. Eunapius mackayi and Plumatella orbisperma are redescribed. Spongilla heterosclerifera, considered an endangered species, is shown to be a species mixture. Taxonomic keys to Eastern Canadian species of freshwater bryozoans and sponges are presented. New limits of tolerance to pH, calcium and magnesium levels, and water temperature are established for several species.</description><creator>Ricciardi, Anthony</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Bryozoa -- Canada, Eastern.</subject><subject>Sponges -- Canada, Eastern.</subject><title>Taxonomy, distribution and ecology of the freshwater sponges (Porifera:Spongillidae) and bryozoans (Ectoprocta) of eastern Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2686299.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t3144</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hd31j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hardware alone is insufficient to allow high-performance computer systems to become successful; sophisticated compilers are also required. Compilers for systems of this type will achieve their effectiveness, not from any single optimizing transformation, but from advanced program analysis and selective application of many proven code-improving transformations. One such analysis technique which holds promise, especially for FORTRAN-90 applications, is a collective analysis technique developed by Sarkar and Gao which uses graph coloring to determine whether a cluster of loops can be processed in a pipelined manner (SG91). The loop clusters we consider in this case are those consisting of loops which define arrays and successor loops which use them. In this document we describe enhancements to Sarkar and Gao's loop coloring technique which improve transformation effectiveness of optimizing compilers for uniprocessors; we also describe a minimum-cost partitioning heuristic to achieve efficient transformation in the event a loop cluster contains non-compatible loops. We then show the benefit from loop transformation can be substantial. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Olsen, Russell</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Collective analysis and transformation of loop clusters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55md11t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hd31j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343t34r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis shows that major object-oriented features can be implemented in a relational database to improve its ease of use. Such object-oriented features as class hierarchy, inheritance of attributes and methods, polymorphism, and collections of classes, are captured by three meta-relations in which the relationships between classes, association of methods with classes, and the composition of collections, are recorded. Each of these meta-relations implies a modification of the relational algebra operators so that they can be applied both to the independent relations and to the relations which are part of the class hierarchy. We describe the relational algebra implementation of all the modifications to the relational operators necessary to accommodate the object-oriented features mentioned above. New syntax is suggested when these modifications are not sufficient.</description><creator>Mnushkin, Ellen</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Inheritance in a relational object-oriented database system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741s94t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343t34r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qn126</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the structures guiding and informing reading intrinsic to James's "late" style. It seeks to explore James's analogy between reading as an ethical activity and his own and his characters' acts of storytelling. It looks first at the necessities of reading as they are presented through the character of Isabel Archer in The Portrait of a Lady, to find that reading for James is itself a form of storytelling. James's concept of "revision," which replaces the concept of "re-writing," unites the activities of reading and storytelling because both activities, to be free, must be guided by the contingencies of experience. James's emphasis on the determinations of experience, which yields changing apprehensions of the same material, at once makes reading a test of the reader's resources in dealing with unexpected and complex situations, and storytelling an act of improvisation if it is to be faithful to the demands of its subject. The second half of the thesis examines Maggie Verver's command of storytelling in The Golden Bowl. It finds that ethical storytellers must have the same faith in their subject matter as ethical readers must have in the texts they engage. Finally, the thesis unites the study of reading with storytelling by examining the ways in which stories are exemplary performances whose the most significant subject is the audience. It is the forms of judgement that a work of art elicits which are essential to establishing alternative conceptions of the good and new modes of valuation in a community.</description><creator>Valihora, Karen</creator><date>1991</date><subject>James, Henry, 1843-1916 Golden Bowl</subject><subject>James, Henry, 1843-1916 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>James, Henry, 1843-1916 Portrait of a lady.</subject><title>Reading the late James</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c166d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn126</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s595m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In much dystopian SF, the city models a society which represses the protagonist's sense of historical time, replacing it with a sense of "private" time affecting isolated individuals. This phenomenon appears in dystopian SF novels of 1960-75--including Thomas M. Disch's 334, John Brunner's The Jagged Orbit, Philip K. Dick's Martian Time-Slip, J. G. Ballard's High-Rise, and Samuel R. Delany's Dhalgren--as well as some precursors--including Wells, Zamyatin's We, Huxley's Brave New World and Orwell's Nineteen Eighty-Four. In these novels the cities also reveal in their chronotopic arrangement the degree to which revolutionary forces can oppose the dystopian order. While the earlier dystopias see revolution crushed by despotic state power, those of 1960-75 see it thwarted by the dehumanizing effects of capitalism. The period from 1960-75 ends in resignation to an existence in which individual action can no longer effect political change, at best tempered by irony (Disch, Delany).</description><creator>Zajac, Ronald J. (Ronald John)</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Dystopias</subject><subject>Science fiction -- History and criticism</subject><title>The Dystopian city in British and US science fiction, 1960-1975 : urban chronotopes as models of historical closure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c857.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s595m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j3333312</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A thermogravimetric analyzer was used to study the Si-O-N system. Pure, polished single crystal silicon wafers were heated in the analyzer in an atmosphere of flowing high purity nitrogen or argon. The sample weight was measured continuously over specified temperature ranges. The high affinity of silicon for oxygen made it extremely difficult to form silicon nitride. Zirconium metal strips were placed near the sample to further reduce the local oxygen concentration. Silicon nitride was formed at 1250$ sp circ$C with a nitrogen gas with a bulk oxygen concentration of less than 5 ppm. Two distinct modes of formation of silica (SiO$ sb2$) were observed. These were active and passive oxidation. Active oxidation involved the evolution of SiO and resulted in a weight loss while passive oxidation resulted in a weight increase. Due to the formation of silicon dioxide, weight measurements were not useful in determining silicon nitride kinetics.</description><creator>Safoniuk, Michael</creator><contributor>Berk, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Munz, R. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>A thermogravimetric study of the Si-O-N system /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w846s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3333312</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v6569</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the design and implementation of a Nursing Workload Manager module for a Patient Data Management System in an intensive care unit. The Nursing Workload Manager aids in the planning and documentation of the nurse's workload. It automates the generation of the nursing care plan and automatically assigns a score to the care plan based on a nursing workload measurement system. In the thesis a literature survey of patient data management systems, nursing workload measurement systems and system evaluation methods is presented. This is followed by an overview of the work environment of an intensive care unit. The functionality of the Nursing Workload Manager is described and details of the software environment and application implementation are discussed. Finally, the results of a user evaluation of the module are presented, and future work on the module is discussed.</description><creator>Roger, Kathleen Mary Louise</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Health Sciences, Health Care Management.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Nursing.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A nursing workload manager for a patient data management system /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dt25s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v6569</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j671q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study is about the activities of public entities in international trade, more precisely, about international government procurement. The law of government contracts, in international and municipal law, seeks to balance the stability of contractual relations between the parties and the mutability of the contract which flows from a recognition of the primacy of the public interest. The precise balance struck varies from one legal system to another. Part One of the work looks, firstly, at the recognition, immunities and capacity of public entities in international commercial transactions. Secondly, it treats the conflict of laws rules applicable before national and arbitral jurisdictions. Thirdly, it explores the various possibilities of applicable law, namely the law of the contracting State, the lex mercatoria and public international law. Part Two examines, from a comparative perspective, the notions of "public body", "public contract" and "contrat administratif" in Ameircan, English and French law. The third part explores two main themes. Firstly, the process of procurement in national law, European law, and under the Agreement on Government Procurement; and secondly, the question of the stability of the contractual obligations which can be disturbed by unilateral interventions of the contracting public entity and by external supervening events.</description><creator>Desgagné, Richard.</creator><date>1991</date><subject>International trade</subject><subject>Government purchasing -- Law and legislation</subject><subject>Public contracts</subject><title>La participation des états au commerce international : les contrats gouvernementaux en droit comparé et en droit international</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f706v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j671q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128b97f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thrust of this research lies in Chapter II in which the study using, inter alia, travaux preparatoires attempts to give an analytical and critical review and interpretation of the provisions of the Convention on the Marking of Explosives for the purpose of Detection of 1991. Analysing the provisions of the Convention, the study tries to preserve and reflect the atmosphere that characterised the deliberations of the International Air Law Conference of 1991, an exercise that is thought to be helpful when one is coupling the theoretical analysis with the practical problems of implementation. For this reason, the study is not restricted to theoretical questions of treaty law. The author benefited from personal participation, as an observer, in the International Conference on Air Law held at Montreal from 14 February to 1 March 1991. The first chapter presents a full picture of the legal measures for safeguarding aviation security. This chapter endeavours to review the interpretation and implementation of the aviation security multilateral instruments presently in force.</description><creator>Tswanya, Lutando Simphiwe</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Transportation.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Analysis of the convention on the marking of plastic explosives for the purpose of detection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m291t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128b97f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193b12r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The European Organization for the Safety of Air Navigation (Eurocontrol) was created in 1960 for the centralization and harmonization of air traffic control, to meet the new requirements of increasing air traffic. The primary functions of Eurocontrol were modified because of the reluctance of several European member States to transfer their control on ATC. But air traffic was still increasing and is deemed to increase until the next century. The problem remains unsolved. Today, a new political trend in favor of Eurocontrol is emerging. This trend is shared by most of the European States as well as other organizations as the European Community and the European Civil Aviation Conference. The main legal aspects of Eurocontrol are analysed in this thesis, as well as its cooperation with other organizations involved. Eventually, the future of Eurocontrol is analyzed with respect to future air navigation systems (FANS) based on satellite technology.</description><creator>Saillard, Sébastien</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Transportation.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Les institutions et aspects juridiques relatifs au contrôle aérien en Europe : Eurocontrol</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sw99k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193b12r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d0958</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The legislators of Quebec and Canada have recently adopted a number of environmental statutes implementing the "polluter pays principle". Certain provisions of these statutes specifically provide for the liability of directors and officers of corporations. This thesis focuses on these provisions as well as on the general principles of civil liability (of both Quebec and the Common Law provinces), penal and criminal liability.</description><creator>Paquin, Marc, 1964-</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>Le droit de l'environnement et les administrateurs d'entreprises /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623d676.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d0958</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q513h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem of geometrical distortion in MR images is addressed in the context of the applicability of stereotactic techniques. For this purpose, the distortion of phantom images is measured at various readout bandwidths and the spatial linearity is evaluated in view of the use of a stereotactic frame. The presence of a contribution to the overall distortion of non-linear magnetic gradients is shown from the data, although the distortion observed seems to be mostly attributable to the main field inhomogeneity. The specific problems of distortion of the fiducial markers due to bulk magnetic susceptibility effects is addressed. The occurrence of such effects is characterized with the help of imaging, and the role of the phenomenon on proper target localization is demonstrated. In addition, a method of bypassing the detrimental aspect of these effects is presented. Various distortion correction approaches are discussed, and their benefits and drawbacks are evaluated. In the light of this discussion, a recently reported correction method is then presented. This method allows the calculation of an image free from geometrical and intensity distortion from the combined effect of main field inhomogeneity, susceptibility effects and chemical shift.</description><creator>Gauvin, Alain</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Physics, Optics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Geometrical distortion of magnetic resonance images</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741s953.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q513h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mk16d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Concentrations of Fe, Al, Mn and Zn were measured monthly from April to October at 24 rural riverine sites in Ontario and Quebec. Empirical models were developed predicting riverine metal concentrations from a small set of within-stream and catchment variables. Models explained a significant proportion of the variation in Fe (85%), Al (90%), Mn (57%) and Zn (37%). Simple models predicting annual catchment exports of metals from average riverine suspended particulate concentrations and runoff were also developed. These models explained most of the variation in annual exports of Fe (94%), Al (92%), Mn (62%) and Zn (75%) from the 24 catchments. Models such as these can be used both to estimate catchment exports of metals to lakes, and to estimate riverine metal concentrations without requiring chemical analyses. The models also serve to distinguish background levels from those indicating metal contamination, and will, therefore, be useful in design of water quality guidelines.</description><creator>Cuthbert, Iain Dawson</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Trace elements in water -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Trace elements in water -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Rivers -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Metals -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Rivers -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Predicting the riverine concentrations and catchment exports of metals in rural drainage basins of Ontario and Québec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462661j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk16d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vp69m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A stereotype exists of party- and state-affiliated media as little more than passive reflections of the mobilizing agendas of their sponsors. In analyzing the evolution of Barricada, the former official organ of the Sandinista National Liberation Front (FSLN), the thesis argues that alongside the paper's mobilizing function, there has evolved a professional function with its roots in core principles of journalistic craft. Transformations at Barricada since the Sandinistas' 1990 electoral defeat--in the areas of party/paper relations, editorial strategy, and business management--primarily reflect staffmembers' longstanding professional aspirations, as well as the newly-salient economic pressures that now confront the paper. The broader significance of the findings is suggested via a comparison with Central and Eastern European media systems. It is argued that an understanding of the impact of political transition on media organs is vital to comprehending pres behaviour in transition situations.</description><creator>Jones, Adam, 1963-</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Press -- Nicaragua</subject><title>Beyond the barricades : the Sandinista press in transition, 1979-1991</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sk61w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vp69m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881n14w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis looks at the development of Canadian satellite policy between 1960 and 1980 through a study of the policy decisions relating to Telesat Canada, its specific corporate structure, and mandates and ownership patterns. The analysis draws upon a modified "interplay" model, which examines public policy as an amalgam of interacting ideas, interests and institutions. On the basis of available documents, supplemented by interviews, and supporting secondary analyses, the sometimes contradictory decisions made by the DOC and the CRTC with regards to Telesat's Agreement with the Trans Canada Telephone system during this period are argued to reflect a policy process driven by the interplay of competing views of Telesat's primary purpose and, by extension, competing visions of what constitutes the public interest.</description><creator>Marston, Wendy</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Artificial satellites in telecommunication -- Canada</subject><subject>Artificial satellites</subject><title>Conflict of interests : the ideas, interests and institutions involved in the development of Canadian satellite policy from 1960-1980</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dg87t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881n14w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q514s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thin silver interconnectors are used in the space communication industry to ensure electrical conductivity between neighbouring electronic modules. In order to accommodate a large range of strains, these interconnectors are manufactured with a stress-relief loop shape. The main goal of this thesis is the study of the experimental aspects of the low cycle fatigue of these interconnectors. The development of an in-situ automated fatigue testing procedure is described in detail. This procedure, which involves a miniature cycling device situated inside the vacuum chamber of a scanning electron microscope (SEM), was applied to several pure silver interconnectors with different loop heights. The use of the SEM enables observation, at high magnification, of the interconnector while it is being tested. A new parameter, $ kappa$, which includes the interconnector's geometrical characteristics, is introduced. The experimental results show that the fatigue life of interconnectors can be predicted from a knowledge of $ kappa$. A new approach to the measurement of strain at the top of interconnectors' loop is also proposed. The technique requires the use of the SEM and the deposition of 2 $ mu$m spheres as surface markers. In addition to the experimental technique, a three-dimensional linear finite element analysis of the interconnectors is performed. This analysis is carried out using more than 2,000 elements and three different materials. Strain evaluations are found to be in good agreement with those experimentally obtained.</description><creator>Kosseim, Nadia M.</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Experimental investigation of the fatigue characteristics of silver loop interconnectors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b230p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q514s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dg883</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:09:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An examination was made of the effect of a variety of process parameters on the foam capacity of a fermentation broth. The foaming was found to be directly related to the concentration of bacillomycin L, a surface active antibiotic produced by a strain of Bacillus subtilis. Changing the pH was found to have no direct effect on foam capacity. Lowering the incubation temperature reduced foaming but only by decreasing the production of bacillomycin L. Likewise, reductions in the concentration of glutamic acid, the nitrogen source in the medium, resulted in corresponding reductions in foam capacity, bacillomycin concentration and biomass concentration. When glutamic acid was replaced with sodium nitrate, the effects were similar. However, when glutamic acid was replaced with ammonium chloride, cell growth was poor and bacillomycin production was very low. When the pH was controlled by increasing the amount of phosphate in the medium, growth returned to normal while bacillomycin concentration and foam capacity remained relatively low. When the phosphate was replaced with Tris buffer, both bacillomycin production and foam capacity increased to normal levels, indicating that the production of bacillomycin is inhibited by the presence of inorganic phosphates. Finally, when the overall electrolyte concentration of the Tris-buffered medium was increased by 3-4 times, bacillomycin production was high but much of the foaming was suppressed.</description><creator>Kuzak, Stephen G. (Stephen Gerard)</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Chemistry, Pharmaceutical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Foaming and the production of the antibiotic bacillomycin L</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tq42v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dg883</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):24525</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>