<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:59:39Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43675" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r353n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The reverse transcriptase (RT) of the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) has both polymerase and ribonuclease H (RNase H) activity, and is a key enzyme in the HIV life cycle as it converts the viral RNA genome into double-stranded DNA. A series of studies built around the theme of chemically modified nucleic acids are described in order to: (1) better understand the biochemical processes of reverse transcription in HIV-1, (2) synthesize antiretroviral agents directed to novel targets on HIV-1 (RT), and (3) develop screening methods incorporating fluorescent nucleobase analogues to uncover new drug candidates.  We demonstrated how chemically modified nucleic acid hairpins inhibited the RNase H activity of HIV-1 RT. For example, substituting natural RNA for 2'-deoxy-2'-fluoro-ribonucleotides, 2'-deoxy-2'-fluoro-arabinonucleotides, locked nucleic acids or conjugation of cholesterol at the 5'-terminus modulated the potency of hairpins for RNase H activity. Biochemical methods indicated that the substrate for HIV-1 RT, a short primer-long template, may be bound at the polymerase domain with its trajectory diverted away from the RNase H domain by the presence of the synthetic hairpins. Furthermore, the binding of hairpins to HIV-1 RT had no adverse affects on the potency of chain terminators such as 3'-azido-3'-deoxythymidine (AZT), a widely used antiviral agent. This discovery supports a model where the RNase H activity can be an antiretroviral target independent of the rest of RT.  We synthesized 6-phenylpyrroloribocytidine (PhpC), a novel fluorescent cytidine analogue incorporated into RNA. The PhpC-containing RNA formed native-like duplex structures with complementary strands and fluorometrically reported upon binding to complementary RNA and DNA strands. PhpC was shown to rank among the brightest fluorescent cytidine analogues based on quantum yields. RNA containing PhpC was cleaved by HIV-1 RT RNase H with a 14-fold increase in fluorescence intensity. In contrast</description><description>La transcriptase inverse (RT) du virus de l'immunodéficience humaine de type 1 (VIH-1) possède deux activités: polymérase et ribonucléase H (RNase H), en faisant l'enzyme clé pour le cycle de vie du VIH puisqu'elle convertit l'ARN viral génome en ADN à double brins. Des études portant sur des acides nucléiques modifiés chimiquement sont ici décris afin de: (1) mieux comprendre les procédés biochimiques sous-tendant la transcription inverse du VIH-1, (2) synthétiser des agents antirétroviraux dirigés contre de nouvelles cibles de la RT, et (3) développer des méthodes de criblage incorporant des analogues de nucléobase fluorescente afin de découvrir de nouveaux candidats thérapeutiques.  Nous avons ainsi démontré comment de petits acides nucléiques modifiés (épingles) inhibent l'activité RNase H de la RT VIH-1. La substitution de l'ARN naturel par des acids nucléiques modifiés chimiquement ont modulé la puissance de l'épingle face à l'activité de la RNase H. Des méthodes biochimiques ont démontré que le substrat de la RT VIH-1 peut être lié au domaine polymérase lorsque sa trajectoire est déviée du domaine RNase H par la présence d'épingles. Cette découverte supporte le modèle selon lequel l'activité de RNase H représente une cible antirétrovirale indépendante du reste de la RT.  Nous avons synthétisé la 6-phénylpyrroloribocytidine (PhpC), un nouvel analogue fluorescent de la cytidine incorporé dans l'ARN. Cet ARN contenant de la PhpC a formé des structures ressemblant à des brins doubles natifs ayant des branches complémentaires et est reconnu par fluorométrie après liaison à une branche d'ARN ou d'ADN complémentaire. Se basant sur son rendement quantique, la PhpC se révéla un des analogues fluorescents de la cytidine les plus lumineux. Mais encore, l'ARN contenant de la PhpC fût coupé par la RNase H de la RT VIH-1, augmentant quatorze fois l'intensité de la fluorescence. Contrairement aux mêmes ol</description><creator>Wahba, Alexander</creator><contributor>Masad J Damha (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Chemistry - Organic</subject><title>Modified nucleotides and nucleic acids for the discovery of antiretroviral agents targeting HIV-1 reverse transcriptase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gt06r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r353n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wg36z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les inhibiteurs de l'enzyme 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl coenzyme A (HMG-CoA) réductase (aussi nommés statines) sont largement prescrits à des patients souffrant d'hypercholestérolémie  afin de diminuer le risque de problèmes cardiovasculaires. Ces drogues réduisent efficacement les taux de morbidité et de mortalité reliés aux maladies cardiovasculaires en empêchant la biosynthèse de cholestérol résultant en une réduction du taux de cholestérol sanguin. Outre la diminution du taux de cholestérol, plusieurs autres effets secondaires ont été observés incluant l'amélioration de la fonction des cellules endothéliales et la diminution de l'inflammation vasculaire. À ce jour, l'influence des statines sur les cellules endothéliales in vitro a été principalement étudiée dans des conditions statiques. Le travail présenté dans cette thèse porte sur l'expression de certains gènes importants pour la fonction des cellules endothéliales suite à l'application simultanée de simvastatine et de forces de cisaillement (constantes, pulsatiles et oscillatoires). Plus précisément, nous avons évalué l'expression du facteur de type Krüppel KLF2, de l'oxyde nitrique synthétase endothéliale (eNOS) et de la thrombomoduline (TM), lesquels sont reliés à l'inflammation et la thrombose des vaisseaux sanguins. Nous avons aussi étudié l'expression des protéines pro-inflammatoires (molécule d'adhésion des cellules vasculaires) VCAM-1 et (molécule d'adhésion intra-cellulaire) ICAM-1. Nos résultats démontrent que la simvastatine amplifie l'effet du facteur nécrosant des tumeurs alpha (TNFα) pour des conditions statiques. Cependant, l'application de forces de cisaillement élimine l'augmentation de VCAM-1 et ICAM-1 par la simvastatine. Nous avons aussi observé que la simvastatine et les forces de cisaillement appliquées séparément augmentent l'expression de KLF2, eNOS et TM. L'application simultanée de simvastatine à de faibles concentration</description><description>3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl coenzyme A (HMG-CoA) reductase inhibitors (also known as statins) are widely prescribed to patients with hypercholesterolemia to mitigate the risk for a cardiovascular event. These drugs effectively reduce cardiovascular related morbidity and mortality by inhibiting the biosynthesis of cholesterol, which consequently reduces blood cholesterol levels. In addition to lowering cholesterol, there is also ample evidence that statins have pleiotropic or non-lipid lowering benefits, which include improving endothelial cell function and reducing vascular inflammation. To date, the influence of statins on endothelial cell biology has been conducted primarily under static conditions. The lack of a hemodynamic environment in current in vitro models may be limiting our understanding of the non-lipid lowering effects of statins. The work presented in this thesis reports the combined effects of simvastatin and shear stress (steady, non-reversing pulsatile and oscillating) on the expression of select markers of endothelial cell function. Specifically, we evaluated Kruppel-like factor 2 (KLF2), endothelial nitric oxide synthase (eNOS) and thrombomodulin (TM) expression which are associated with maintaining an anti-inflammatory and anti-thrombotic blood vessel. We also examined the expression of inflammatory proteins, vascular cell adhesion molecule-1 (VCAM-1) and intercellular adhesion molecule-1 (ICAM-1), which allow attachment and migration of leukocytes across the blood vessel. Our results show that simvastatin potentiates the tumor necrosis factor α (TNFα)-induced increase in VCAM-1 and ICAM-1 mRNA in static culture. This potentiating effect of simvastatin was eliminated by unidirectional laminar shear stress. We also report that simvastatin and unidirectional steady or pulsatile shear stress separately enhances KLF2, eNOS and TM expression. Combining both simvastatin and shear stress (steady or non-reversing pulsatile) resulted in an additive in</description><creator>Rossi, Joanna</creator><contributor>Jean Claude Tardif (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Richard L Leask (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Endothelial cell response to simvastatin and fluid wall shear stress: an investigation into statin-shear stress interactions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322d68w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wg36z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708w88j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>ABSTRACT This study explores the experience of adopting and implementing a Rights-Based Approach (RBA) to community practice in Palestine using a case study methodology. The studied case is a community-based organization that is university affiliated and voluntary efforts-oriented; the Community Service Center (CSC). CSC is affiliated to An-Najah National University, Nablus, Palestine and is a partner in the McGill Middle East Program in Civil Society and Peace Building (MMEP), Montreal, Canada. CSC works in a context that is characterized by political, social and economic instability and uncertainty. Community work in this context, as a method of social work, is expected to target its goals through addressing issues of social and political nature simultaneously; contribute to national aspirations of building a state after decades of occupation and working to realize human rights of the disadvantaged through their empowerment and participation.  Human rights-based social work constituted the theoretical framework of the study. This framework is based on linking human rights and social work in a way consistent with the mission of social work as a profession that targets the barriers to accessing human rights; poverty, discrimination, and lack of education. Therefore, a human rights-based community practice should imply respect of human rights in its means and outcomes.  Data about this experience was collected from three sources; CSC documents, a sample of persons who were involved in CSC work, and the researcher's own experience as a founding director of the organization. Data was collected using qualitative methods; interviewing study participants, reviewing documents, and reflection on researcher's experience. Data was analyzed using qualitative traditions. The study concluded that successful adoption and implementation of RBA is conditioned by five factors: opportunity for the organization, professionality of the organization's team, team's commitment, RBAing</description><description>Résumé Cette recherche explore l'expérience d'adoption et de mise en oeuvre d'une approche de la pratique communautaire en Palestine basée sur les droits de l'homme et utilisant une méthodologie d'une étude du cas. Le cas étudié est une organisation communautaire affiliée à l'université et imprégnée par l'esprit volontaire: le Centre du Service Communautaire  (CSC) est affilié à l'Université Nationale An-Najah (UNA), à Naplouse, en Palestine, et il est un des partenaires au Programme de McGill en société civile et rétablissement de la paix au Moyen Orient, Montréal, Canada (PMMO). Ce Centre travaille dans un contexte d'incertitude et d'instabilité politique, économique et sociale. Comme prévu, le travail communautaire, comme une méthode du travail social, dans un tel contexte tend à réaliser ses objectifs en traitant des problèmes à la fois politiques et sociaux, et contribue aux ambitions nationales par rapport à la construction de l'Etat après des décennies d'occupation et de travail en ce sens. Et tout cela pour  faire accéder les désavantagés aux droits de l'homme par leur empowerment (responsabilisation) et leur participation.     Le travail social basé sur les droits de l'homme a constitué le cadre théorique de l'étude. Ce cadre d'analyse est basé sur le désir de lier les droits de l'homme et le travail social d'une manière qui paraît correspondre à la mission du travail social en tant que profession visant les obstacles à l'accès aux droits de l'homme comme la pauvreté, la discrimination et l'absence d'éducation. Par conséquent, la pratique communautaire basée sur les droits de l'homme doit impliquer le respect des droits de l'homme au niveau des moyens et des fins.  Les données concernant cette expérience ont été collectées à partir de trois sources: les documents du Centre du Service Communautaire, un échantillon composé des personnes engagées dans le travail du Centre, et l'expérience personnel</description><creator>Zaidalkilani, Sami</creator><contributor>James Torczyner (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Social Sciences - Social Work</subject><title>Adopting rights-based approach to community practice: the experience of the Community Service Center, Nablus, Palestine - a case study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z565t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708w88j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j850s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objectif initial de mon projet consistait à mettre au point divers tests permettant d'étudier le rôle du facteur de transcription à homéodomaine p110 CUX1 au cours du cycle cellulaire. J'ai d'abord observé que p110 CUX1 stimule la prolifération cellulaire lorsque exprimé de façon soutenue. À partir d'analyses par cytométrie en flux et de marquages au BrdU, j'ai démontré que l'expression de p110 CUX1 suscite une accélération de l'entrée en phase S. Cet effet s'est manifesté dans trois situations : à partir de la phase de quiescence (G0), à partir d'une synchronisation en G1/S et à partir de la phase G2/M lors d'un enrichissement par centrifugation à contre-courant (élutriation). En accord avec ces résultats, les fibroblastes murins isolé à partir d'embryons Cux-/- proliférèrent plus lentement par rapport aux fibroblastes Cux+/+ à cause d'une prolongation de la phase G1. J'ai identifié les gènes cycline E2 et cycline A2 comme deux cibles transcriptionnelles de p110 CUX1 pouvant expliquer son effet sur la transition G1/S. J'ai observé qu'il se développait une sous-population tétraploïde dans certaines lignées cellulaires exprimant p110 CUX1. Alors que la tétraploïdie cause généralement un arrêt de la prolifération ou la mort cellulaire dans les cellules normales, j'ai noté que l'expression de p110 CUX1 permettait aux cellules tétraploïdes d'avoir une division bipolaire normale malgré la présence de plusieurs centrosomes. J'ai démontré que cet effet était dû à la capacité de p110 CUX1 d'induire la transcription de plusieurs gènes permettant une activation efficace et prolongée du point de contrôle mitotique. J'ai établi un lien entre l'instabilité génomique des cellules tetraploïdes exprimant p110 CUX1 et l'acquisition de caractéristiques tumorales. De plus, j'ai noté que plus de 80% des cellules de tumeurs mammaires provenant de souris transgéniques CUX1 sont quasi tétraploïdes. Je propose donc un nou</description><description>The goal of my project was to develop cell-based assays to investigate the functions of the p110 CUX1 homeodomain transcription factor during cell cycle progression. I observed that constitutive expression of p110 CUX1 stimulates cell proliferation. Using fluorescence-activated cell sorting (FACS) analysis and BrdU incorporation, I demonstrated that p110 CUX1 can accelerate entry into S phase whether cells were coming out of quiescence, were allowed to resume progression through the cell cycle after synchronization at the G1/S or were simply enriched in G2/M using counter-flow centrifugal elutriation. Consistent with these observations, mouse embryo fibroblasts (MEFs) derived from homozygous cux1-/- mice proliferated more slowly and spent more time in G1 than wild type MEFs. I identified the cyclin E2 and cyclin A2 genes as some of the downstream targets of p110 CUX1 that mediate its stimulatory effect on the G1/S transition.  Constitutive expression of p110 CUX1 in some, but not all, cell lines led to the emergence of cells with a tetraploid DNA content. Whereas the induction of tetraploidy in normal cells causes cell cycle arrest or cell death, cells expressing p110 CUX1 were able to undergo bipolar division in spite of the presence of more than two centrosomes. Using various experimental approaches, I demonstrated that p110 CUX1 contributes to the establishment of a transcriptional program that allows cells to sustain a robust spindle assembly checkpoint. Tetraploid cells eventually evolved to become aneuploid and tumorigenic. Similarly, over 80% of mammary tumor cells from CUX1 transgenic mice exhibit a near-tetraploid DNA content. I therefore propose that one mechanism by which elevated p110 CUX1 expression contributes to tumor development is through its effect on the spindle assembly checkpoint. In this manner, p110 CUX1 enables the survival of cells that harbor supernumerary chromosome and/or centrosome numbers and have the capacity to generate a large num</description><creator>L'Epicier-Sansregret, Laurent</creator><contributor>Alain Nepveu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>The cellular roles of CUX1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375w63h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j850s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gk20p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>ARS ET INGENIUM: THE EMBODIMENT OF IMAGINATION IN THE ARCHITECTURAL DRAWINGS OF FRANCESCO DI GIORGIO MARTINI   This study focuses on the work of the Renaissance architect and theorist Francesco di Giorgio Martini (1439-1501), particularly on his Trattati di architettura, ingegneria e arte militare (1475-1490). The characteristics of the act of drawing and its connection to architectural imagination as defined by Francesco are the two themes that structure the inquiry.   In addition to an abundant number of captivating drawings which accompany the text, Francesco writes about the reason why drawings are to be used, and what role they have in conveying ideas and images to the reader of his theories. While in the context of the Quattrocento Francesco's use of drawings is not necessarily a novelty, his formulation of drawing as the main vehicle for architectural thought is distinctive. He offers a unique format for architectural theory, rooted in classical and medieval traditions, and yet original in its annexation of text and drawings. His thoughts on disegno (connoting both design and drawing) prove him vocal in highlighting the role of drawing in an architectural process.   Francesco suggests that creativity, invention and imagination are all quintessential elements at work in disegno. He identifies both intellect and the senses, especially sight, as providing the criteria of judgment in architecture. His drawings combine elements of the past, insights of the present and anticipations of things yet to come by engaging memory, sense, the intellect and the imagination. In the Trattati drawing becomes a fertile field for infinitely dynamic investigations, by acting as a vehicle for the architect's inquires as well as a vessel for conversations with others.   Examining Francesco's work within the two frequently intersecting lines of drawing and imagination enable us to better formulate our expectations of architectural drawings, in the midst of a significant shift in</description><description>ARS ET INGENIUM: L'INCARNATION DE L'IMAGINATION  DANS LES DESSINS ARCHITECTURAUX DE FRANCESCO DI GIORGIO   Cette étude se concentre sur les travaux de l'architecte et théoricien de la Renaissance, Francesco di Giorgio Martini (1439-1501), en particulier sur son traité: Trattati di architettura, ingegneria e arte militare (1475-1490). Les caractéristiques de l'acte de dessiner et de sa connexion à l'imagination architecturale telle que définie par Francesco sont les deux thèmes qui structurent cette étude.  En plus d'un grand nombre de dessins fascinants qui accompagnent le texte, Francesco décrit les raisons pour lesquelles les dessins doivent être utilisés, et le rôle qu'ils jouent dans la transmission des idées et des images au lecteur de ses théories. Dans le contexte du Quattrocento, l'utilisation des dessins par Francesco n'est pas nécessairement une nouveauté, par contre la mise en valuer du dessin comme médium principal de la pensée architecturale est unique. Francesco crée un format unique pour sa théorie architecturale, ancré dans les traditions classiques et médiévales, et pourtant original dans son annexion des dessins au texte. Ses réflexions sur disegno (portant à la fois sur la conception et le dessin) en font un partisan de la mise en évidence du rôle du dessin dans un processus architectural.  Francesco suggère que la créativité, l'invention et l'imagination sont toutes des éléments essentiels à l'œuvre pour parvenir à disegno. Il identifie à la fois l'intellect et les sens, surtout la vue comme fournissant les critères de jugement pour l'architecture. Ses dessins combinent les éléments du passé, le savoir du présent et les anticipations du futur en mettant en jeu la mémoire, les sens, l'intellect et l'imagination. Les dessins du Trattati deviennent un terrain fertile pour des recherches infiniment dynamiques, en agissant comme un vecteur pour les investigations de l'architecte ainsi qu'un médium pour des</description><creator>Riahi, Pari</creator><contributor>Alberto Perez-Gomez (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Architecture</subject><title>Ars et ingenium: the embodiment of imagination in the architectural drawings of Franceso di Giorgio Martini</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p509c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk20p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515n787</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is made up of three essays that explore the informational content of index and individual equity option prices. In the first essay, we investigate the pricing of systematic variance risk in the equity options market. Cross sectional tests on synthetic variance swap returns reveal no evidence of a negative market variance risk premium. Furthermore, we show that a class of linear factor models cannot simultaneously explain index and equity option prices. In particular, equity options appear to be underpriced relative to index options. To exploit the mispricing, we analyze an investment strategy known as dispersion trading. After transaction costs, the strategy generates a Sharpe ratio which is more than four times greater than that of the market. We also find that equity option prices are related to underlying firm characteristics: Options on small and value stocks are more expensive than options on large and growth stocks, respectively. In the second essay we investigate the computation of one of the most important tools in finance practice, market betas. Existing approaches compute market betas using historical data. While these approaches differ in terms of statistical sophistication and the modeling of the time-variation in the betas, they are all backward-looking. This essay introduces a radically different approach to estimating market betas. We use information embedded in the prices of individual equity and index options to compute an option-implied market beta at the daily frequency. This beta can be computed using option data for a single day, and is able to reflect sudden changes in the structure of the underlying company. Based on an empirical investigation of daily cross-sections of option contracts on one hundred underlying companies, we conclude that these option-implied betas contain information relevant for forecasting future betas that is not contained in historical betas. In the third essay, we propose the use of option-implied beta, a</description><description>La présente thèse se compose de trois mémoires ayant trait à l'information qu'on peut tirer des cours des options sur indice et des options sur actions individuelles. Dans le premier mémoire, nous examinons la tarification du risque lié à la variance systématique dans le marché des options sur actions. L'analyse sectiorielle des rendements des swaps sur simulation de la variance ne permet de déceler aucune prime de risque liée à la variance négative du marché. Par ailleurs, nous montrons qu'une série de modèles d'analyse factorielle linéaire ne peut pas expliquer à la fois les prix des options sur indice et les prix des options sur actions. De façon plus particulière, les options sur actions semblent être sous évaluées par rapport aux options sur indice boursier. Le mémoire analyse une stratégie de placement connue sous le nom de négociation liée à la variabilité, qui permettrait de tirer parti de cette anomalie. Après déduction des frais de négociation, la stratégie génère un ratio de Sharpe qui est plus de quatre fois supérieur à celui du marché. Nous constatons également que les cours des options sur actions sont liés aux caractéristiques de la société sous jacente : les options sur les actions de sociétés à faible capitalisation et sur les actions de type valeur coûtent plus cher que les options sur les actions de sociétés à forte capitalisation et les actions de type croissance, respectivement. Dans le deuxième mémoire, nous examinons le calcul de l'un des outils les plus importants du monde de la finance : les coefficients bêta. Les approches existantes pour effectuer ce calcul se fondent sur les données antérieures. Bien que ces approches varient sur le plan de la complexité des calculs statistiques et de la modélisation de la variation temporelle des coefficients bêta, elles sont toutes rétrogrades. Le présent compte rendu adopte une approche résolument différente pour l'estimation des coeffici</description><creator>Vainberg, Gregory</creator><contributor>Peter Frederik Christoffersen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Kris J J Jacobs (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Economics - Finance</subject><title>The relative pricing of index and equity options</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zw93k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515n787</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Desautels Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306sz64n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>En surveillance maritime, les données multi-senseurs diffrent, dans une large mesure, en terme de leur résolution temporelle. De plus, en raison de la gestion du traitement d'information de sécurité multi-niveau, plusieurs rapports de contact sont reçus des heures après leur observation. Ceci rend les données des rapports de contact disponible pour traitement en lot. L'information multi-source provenant d'environnements dissimilaires, les rapports de contact ont des erreurs hétéroscédastiques et corrélées (i.e., des erreurs de mesure caractérisées par une distribution de probabilité normale et une matrice de covariance non constante et non diagonale), ainsi qu'une erreur de mesure pouvant être relativement large. En conséquence, le choix approprié d'un algorithme d'estimation de trajectoire adressant les problèmes susmentionnés de données de surveillance contribuera significativement à accroître la perception de situation dans le domaine maritime.  Cette thèse présente deux nouveaux algorithmes pour l'estimation en lot de trajectoire de navire simple et employant une approche d'estimation bayésienne: (1) un algorithme de filtration linéaire stochastique, et (2) un algorithme de lissage de courbe réalisant une régression non-paramétrique par inférence statistique bayésienne.  L'algorithme de filtration linéaire stochastique emploi la combinaison de deux processus stochastiques, c'est-à-dire le processus d'Ornstein-Uhlenbeck intégré (IOU) et le processus de marche aléatoire (RW), pour décrire le mouvement du navire.  Les suppositions de modèle linéaire et de distribution gaussienne bivariée des erreurs de mesure permettent l'utilisation du filtre de Kalman et du lissage optimal de Rauch-Tung-Striebel. Dans l'algorithme de lissage de courbe, la trajectoire est considérée représentée par un spline cubique avec un nombre de noeuds inconnu dans le plan euclidien à deux dimensions, en longitude et latitude. L'estimation de f</description><description>In maritime surveillance, multi-sensor data  differ to a great extent in their temporal resolution.    Additionally, due to multi-level security and information management processing, many contact reports arrive hours after observations.  This makes the contact report data usually available for batch processing.  The dissimilar multi-source information environment results in contact reports  with heteroscedastic and correlated errors (i.e. measurement errors characterized by normal probability distributions with non-constant and non-diagonal covariance matrices),  while the obtained measurement errors may be relatively large.  Hence, the appropriate choice of a trajectory estimation algorithm, which addresses the aforementioned issues of the surveillance data,  will significantly contribute to increased awareness in the maritime domain.   This thesis presents two novel batch single ship trajectory estimation algorithms employing Bayesian approaches to estimation:  (1) a stochastic linear filtering algorithm  and (2) a curve fitting algorithm which employs Bayesian statistical inference  for nonparametric regression.  The stochastic linear filtering algorithm employs a combination of two stochastic processes,  namely the Integrated Ornstein-Uhlenbeck process (IOU) and the random walk (RW), process to describe the ship's motion.  The assumptions on linear modeling and bivariate Gaussian distribution of measurement errors allow for  the use of Kalman filtering and Rauch-Tung-Striebel optimal smoothing. In the curve fitting algorithm, the trajectory is considered to be in the form of a  cubic spline with an unknown number of knots in two-dimensional Euclidean plane of longitude and latitude. The function estimate is determined from the data which are assumed Gaussian distributed. A fully Bayesian approach is adopted by defining the prior distributions on all unknown parameters: the spline coefficients,  the number and the locations of knots.  The calculation of the p</description><creator>Hadzagic, Melita</creator><contributor>Hannah Michalska (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Bayesian approaches to trajectory estimation in maritime surveillance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870w24w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306sz64n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j1395</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes the experimental configuration and theoretical and computational techniques used to estimate the surface permeability of Indiana Limestone. The experimental procedure involves the application of a uniform flow rate to an open central region of a sealed annular patch. The law governing fluid flow within the porous medium is described by Darcy's Law which relates the steady flow rate to the steady state pressure within the central region. Both theoretical and computational models can be used to determine the distribution of intrinsic surface permeability of the cuboidal Indiana Limestone sample measuring 508 mm. Using the surface data and an inverse analysis, the spatial permeability distribution within the sample is determined. The spatial distribution can then be used to estimate the effective permeability of the tested block. The effective permeabilities are also estimated using theoretical relationships found in the literature and the spatial values obtained from surface data and the inverse analysis.</description><description>Cette thèse présente la configuration expérimentale ainsi que les techniques théoriques et numérique utilisées pour l'estimation de la perméabilité superficielle du Calcaire d'Indiana. La procédure expérimentale consiste en l'application d'un débit d'eau constant à la région centrale ouverte d'un ‘patch' annulaire. Les lois qui définissent l'écoulement d'eau à travers des milieux poreux sont décrites par la loi de Darcy qui relie le débit constant d'un fluide à l'obtention d'une pression constante de ce fluide dans la région centrale. Les deux modèles (théorique et numérique) peuvent être utilisés pour déterminer la distribution de la perméabilité superficielle intrinsèque dans l'échantillon cubique de Calcaire d'Indiana qui mesure 508 mm de côté. Les données superficielles et l'analyse inverse sont utilisées pour déterminer la distribution spatiale de la perméabilité dans l'échantillon. Cette distribution spatiale permet l'estimation de la perméabilité effective de l'échantillon. La perméabilité effective est aussi estimée en appliquant les données spatiales obtenues avec les données superficielles et de l'analyse inverse dans des relations théoriques trouvées dans la littérature.</description><creator>Selvadurai, Paul Antony</creator><contributor>Shao, Yixin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Permeability of Indiana limestone: experiments and theoretical concepts for interpretation of results</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rt715.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j1395</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sk048</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>En dépit des améliorations récentes dans notre compréhension de sa pathogénèse, le virus de la rougeole (MeV) demeure un souci constant pour la santé internationale. Dans des pays en voie de développement, son impact est particulièrement importante, en partie dû à des problèmes de qualité du vaccin et de malnutrition chez les enfants. Bien que le mécanisme demeure mal compris, la morbidité et la mortalité dues à la rougeole chez les enfants mal nourris peuvent être sensiblement améliorées par des suppléments de vitamine A. Un modèle animal est essentiel pour mieux comprendre l'activité antivirale de la vitamine A. Malheureusement, il n'y a aucun modèle animal approprié pour la rougeole dû au tropisme limité de ce virus. Cependant, le virus de la maladie de Carré (CDV) et le MeV font tout les deux partie du genus des morbillivirus et sont très étroitement liés (homologie de 88% en acide aminé). L'infection du furet avec une souche atténuée de CDV est similaire a celle de la rougeole chez humain, reproduisant les mêmes signes et symptômes, y compris l'éruption cutanée, la dissémination systémique du virus et l'inhibition du système immunitaire chez l'animal. En utilisant ce modèle, notre laboratoire a récemment démontré que le traitement avec une forte dose de vitamin A résulte en une réduction marquée de la morbidité chez les furets infectés par le CDV. En outre, une étude récemment publiée a démontré que le traitement de vitamine A peut inhiber la réplication du MeV dans plusieurs souches de cellules humaines d'origines épithéliales et immunitaires. fr Malgré notre progrès, beaucoup d'autres aspects de l'influence de la vitamine A sur les infections par des morbillivirus demeurent à être caractérisés. Pour fournir le lien absent entre l'étude in vivo du furet infecté par le CDV et in vitro du MeV, nous avons démontré que le traitement in vitro de vitamine A inhibe la réplication du CDV chez des cellules lymphoides canines pareillement à MeV chez les cellules humaines. En outre, nous avons utilisé le modèle du furet infecté par le CDV pour étudier le rôle de la déficience en vitamine A chez l'infection par des morbillivirus. fr Le furet infecté par le CDV est un des premiers modèles qui peut reproduire loyalement la pathogénèse du MeV chez l'homme. Nos résultats attesterons davantage de la validité d'employer le modèle de CDV-furet pour étudier la pathogénèse des morbillivirus et les mécanismes antiviraux de la vitamine A sur leurs infections.</description><description>Despite recent advancements in our understanding of its pathogenesis, measles virus (MeV) remains a major concern for human health. In developing countries, the impact of MeV infection is particularly dire in part due to vaccine quality issues and malnutrition. Although the mechanism remains poorly understood, the morbidity and mortality due to MeV infection in undernourished children can be significantly improved by vitamin A (VA) supplements. Small animal models can be very helpful to better understand the activity of defined micronutrients in viral infection. Unfortunately, there is no appropriate small animal model for MeV infection due to the limited host tropism of this virus. Canine distemper virus (CDV) and MeV are both members of the morbillivirus genus and share 88% amino acid homology. Ferret infection with attenuated CDV is highly reminiscent of human MeV, producing many of the same signs and symptoms, including rash, systemic viral dissemination and immunosuppression. Using in vitro models, our laboratory has recently characterized the molecular mechanism of retinoid action against MeV. Using the ferret model, our laboratory has recently demonstrated significant reduction in morbidity in CDV-infected ferrets given high dose VA treatment. The central goal of this thesis work was to better understand the apparent beneficial influence of VA in CDV infection and to provide the 'missing link' between the in vivo MeV-human and CDV-ferret observations and the in vitro MeV studies. Using immortalized canine cell lines, we have demonstrated that in vitro VA treatment can inhibit CDV replication similarly to the suppression of MeV in human cells. In addition, we used the CDV-ferret model to study the impact of vitamin A deficiency on morbillivirus infection. CDV-infected ferrets are one of the first models to faithfully reproduce the classic signs and symptoms of MeV in humans. Our results provide further evidence of the utility of this model to study MeV pathogenesis and to explore the antiviral mechanisms of vitamin A during morbillivirus infection.</description><creator>Yao, Han</creator><contributor>Brian Ward (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Virology</subject><title>The anti-viral effects of retinoids in canine distemper virus infection: the missing link between measles and Vitamin A</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g5592.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sk048</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nk96p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La présence de récepteurs couplés aux protéines G (RCPG) au noyau cellulaire n'est pas universelle et il a été suggéré que ces récepteurs nucléaires possèdent des fonctions de transcription de gènes, tandis que les récepteurs au niveau de la membrane plasmique semblent plutôt induire des effets aigus indépendants de la transcription de gènes. Le récepteur activé par protéase 2 (PAR-2) fait partie de la famille des RCPG. PAR-2 au noyau a été observée dans divers tissus cellulaires. L'origine des RCPG au noyau et les mécanismes menant à cette localisation ne sont pas connus. En utilisant PAR-2 comme modèle, le but de ce travail était d'évaluer si l'activation des RCPG par des peptides mène à leur translocation au noyau.  Nous avons étudié les rôles possibles de la translocation nucléaire de PAR-2 dans l'induction de l'expression génique et l'angiogénèse rétinienne. De plus, nous voulions aussi étudier le mécanisme de régulation de l'expression génique du PAR-2 nucléaire. PAR-2 était transloqué de la membrane plasmique au noyau suite à sa stimulation. Cette translocation est indépendante de la clathrine et des cavéolines, mais nécessite des microtubules intactes. Le domaine C-terminal et les deux séquences NLS de PAR-2 sont importants pour sa translocation nucléaire. L'importineb1 et le SNX11 interagissent avec PAR-2 et sont essentiels pour la translocation nucléaire du récepteur. L'expression de VEGF induite par l'activation de PAR-2 est dépendante de la translocation nucléaire du récepteur. L'expression de PAR-2 et de SNX11 sont essentielles pour une néovascularisation normale de la rétine de souris. L'activation de PAR-2 résultait en une interaction du récepteur avec le facteur de transcription Sp1 au niveau du noyau cellulaire. Sp1 est essentiel pour la régulation de l'expression génique de PRIM1 et VEGF induite par la stimulation de PAR-2 et pour la régulation de la prolifération et migration cellulaire. En conclusion, PAR-2 au niveau de la membrane plasmique diffère de PAR-2 au noyau dans la régulation des gènes pro-angiogéniques, plus spécifiquement dans l'induction des gènes pro-angiogéniques tant au niveau in vitro que in vivo. Sp1 joue un rôle important dans la régulation de l'expression des gènes induite par l'activation de PAR-2 nucléaire.</description><description>The existence of GPCRs at the cell nucleus is not universal and these nuclear receptors were reported to evoke functions related to gene transcription while plasma membrane receptors induce mostly acute non-genomic effects. Protease-activated receptor 2 (PAR-2) is a member of the GPCR family. Although many responses induced by PAR-2 can result from its activation at the cell surface, nuclear localization of PAR-2 has been detected in cell tissues. However, the origin of nuclear GPCRs and the mechanisms leading to such localization are not known. Therefore, we used PAR-2 as a model to evaluate whether peptide-activated GPCRs translocate to the cell nucleus. We investigated the possible contributions of PAR-2 nuclear translocation to gene induction and retinal angiogenesis. In addition, we aimed to study the mechanism of nuclear PAR-2 regulation of gene expression. Cell surface PAR-2 translocated to the nucleus upon stimulation. PAR-2 nuclear translocation pathway is independent of clathrin and caveolin but requires intact microtubules. The C-terminal domain and both NLS sequences of PAR-2 are important for its nuclear translocation. Importinb1 and SNX11 are shown to interact with PAR-2 and are essential for nuclear translocation of the receptor. VEGF expression induced by PAR-2 activation is dependent on nuclear translocation of the receptor. Silencing PAR-2 or SNX11 decreased mice retinal neovascularization while re-expression of PAR-2 in PAR-2 knockout mice was shown to restore normal neovascularization of the retina. Activation of PAR-2 resulted in the interaction of the receptor with Sp1 transcription factor in the nucleus. Sp1 is essential for the regulation of PRIM1 and VEGF gene expression induced by PAR-2 and for PAR-2 regulation of cell proliferation and migration. In conclusion, PAR-2 at the cell nucleus contributes in serving distinct functions from PAR-2 at the cell surface, specifically induction of major proangiogenic genes both in in vitro and in in vivo model of angiogenesis. Sp1 transcription factor plays an important role in the regulation of gene expression induced by nuclear PAR-2 activation.</description><creator>Nim, Satra</creator><contributor>Sylvain Chemtob (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Mechanism of translocation of PAR-2 from the plasma membrane to the nucleus: implications for angiogenesis and neovascularization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741s244.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nk96p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r606b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les mécanismes impliqués dans le développement des maladies aortiques telles que les anévrismes de l'aorte ascendante (AA) humaine sont inconnus. On pense que la capacité de remodelage des cellules endothéliales (CE) et musculaires lisses (CML) combinées avec une distribution non uniforme des contraintes à la surface et dans le tissu aortique dû à une hémodynamie perturbée produit par une valve aortique malade jouent un rôle important dans la progression de la maladie. Dans cette thèse, on fait l'hypothèse qu'il existe un remodelage aortique local dans les tissus aortiques dilatés et que ce remodelage dépendent du type valve. Cependant, très peu de données sont disponibles sur les propriétés mécaniques et structurelles de l'AA saine et dilatée. Une description détaillée de ce tissu fournira des indices essentiels pour mieux comprendre la progression de la maladie et aidera à identifier les mécanismes impliqués. L'analyse régionale a révélé une variation circonférentielle de la rigidité, de l'épaisseur et du contenu en collagène dans les tissus sain et BAV-T1 dilatés mais non présents dans les tissus TAV dilatés. En moyenne, on a montré des différences d'épaisseur et du contenu en collagène entre les tissus dilatés TAV et BAV-T1. On a également trouvé des variations régionales de la densité et de l'orientation des CML dans l'AA porcine. La grande courbure montre une densité plus élevée de CML orientées dans la direction axiale. Bien que l'activation des CML à la phenylephrine ait eu un effet significatif sur la rigidité de l'AA, aucunes variations circonférentielles ou directionelles de cet effet ont été trouvées. On observe la présence de remodelage local, suite à une reconstruction de l'arche aortique, causé par la différence de compliance entre l'aorte native et le greffon de remplacement. Aucune étude n'avait essayé de quantifier cette différence dans l'aorte reconstruite. Nous avons trouvé des$</description><description>The exact mechanisms involved in the pathogenesis of aortic aneurysms of the human ascending aorta (AA) are unknown. It is believed that the remodeling capabilities of the endothelial cells (ECs) and vascular smooth muscle cells (VSMCs) combined with abnormal and non-uniform shear and tissue stresses, generated by a perturbed hemodynamics produced by a diseased aortic valve, are the precursors in the disease progression. In this work, we hypothesize that local remodeling of the dilated AA exists and is valve type dependent. However, very little data exists on the local mechanical and structural properties of healthy and dilated AA. A detailed description of these tissues will provide valuable clues about the progression of the disease and help identify the mechanisms involved. The regional analysis has revealed a significant location dependency in stiffness, thickness and collagen content in healthy and dilated BAV-T1 AA tissues. However, these natural regional variations were not evident in dilated TAV tissues, which suggests a loss of the natural heterogeneity with dilation. On average, collagen content and thickness have shown differences between dilated TAV and BAV-T1 tissues, which suggests two distinct remodeling processes. Regional variations in the density and orientation of the VSMCs have also been found in pig AA. The outer curvature has a higher cell density with cells tilting towards the axial direction in response to higher tissue stresses in this quadrant. Although, VSMCs activation with phenylephrine had a significant effect on the stiffness of the pig AA, which was independent of location or direction. Local remodeling often occurs after an aortic arch reconstruction surgery because of compliance mismatch between the native AA and the replacement material. Since no study has carefully quantified this degree of mismatch in the repaired AA, such an investigation was needed. We have found significant differences in stiffness and anisotropy between re</description><creator>Tremblay, Dominique</creator><contributor>Richard L Leask (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Rosaire Mongrain (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Mechanical and structural characterization of ascending aortic tissues and graft materials used in the aortic arch reconstruction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gg82k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r606b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719m85r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Des mesures pompe/sonde résolues en états quantiques de résolutions temporelles de l'ordre du femtoseconde ont été effectuées pour examiner la dynamique, dépendante de la taille, des transporteurs de charges de points quantiques de CdSe fortement confinés. Après l'excitation optique, la relaxation de la bande de conduction s'effectue  par le mécanisme Auger, tel que prédit, alors que dans la bande de valence la présence d'un mécanisme de relaxation précédemment inobservé  est détectée. Ce mécanisme est associé aux interactions non-adiabatiques avec les ligands de surface. La nature quantitative de ces mesures, résultant d'une recherche explicite sur les taux de transition d'état-à-état, a permis de développer  un portrait d'ensemble de la relaxation d'exciton pour ces matériaux. Dans ce système, le taux de transition associé aux porteurs de charge se compose de différentes contributions, chacune ayant une dépendance de taille distincte. Ces méthodes résolues en états quantiques ont été également appliquées à l'étude du développement du gain optique dans les points quantiques de CdSe. Il a été observé que la capacité de ces systèmes à atteindre le régime du gain optique dépend fortement de l'état excitonique initial. Au fur et à mesure que l'énergie de l'état fondamental fût augmentée, il fùt progressivement plus difficile d'obtenir un gain optique à cause de l'influence des interactions multiexcitoniques, dépendantes des états. Ceci explique donc l'incapacité des études antérieures, ayant utilisées des sources fixes d'excitation de longueur d'onde,  à démontrer le gain optique des petites particules. La prévision émise antérieurement selon laquelle les points quantiques seraient un médium de gain universel a été confirmée en conservant l'identité pour l'état pompé dans des tailles de particules différentes. La capacité des interactions multiexcitoniques d'ordres spécifiques supérieures à manoeuvrer le gain optique résultant a aussi été prouvée.</description><description>State-resolved pump/probe measurements with femtosecond temporal resolution were made to examine the size dependent charge carrier dynamics of strongly confined CdSe quantum dots.  Following optical excitation, relaxation in the conduction band is shown to be consistent with the expectations of an Auger mediated process.  In the valence band, the presence of a previously unobserved relaxation mechanism is detected.  This mechanism is associated with non-adiabatic interactions with the surface ligands.  The quantitative nature of these measurements, resulting from the explicit investigation of state-to-state transition rates, allowed for the development of a unified picture of exciton relaxation in these materials. Here the total transition rate associated with the charge carriers is composed of a manifold of different contributions, each with a distinct size dependence. These state-resolve methods were further applied to investigate the development of optical gain in CdSe quantum dots.  It was observed that the capacity of these systems to achieve the regime of optical gain has a pronounced dependence on the initially prescribed excitonic state.  In general, as the energy of the initial state was increased it was progressively more difficult to achieve optical gain due to the impeding influence of state dependent multiexcitonic interactions.  This explains the inability of prior research which used fixed wavelength excitation sources to demonstrate optical gain in small particles.  By maintaining the identity for the pumped state in different particle sizes, the long standing prediction that quantum dots would be a universal gain medium was recovered.  In addition, evidence for the capacity of specific higher order multiexcitonic interactions to manipulate the resulting optical gain spectrum was provided.</description><creator>Cooney, Ryan</creator><contributor>Patanjali Kambhampati (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Chemistry - Physical</subject><title>Charge carrier dynamics and the development of optical gain in semiconductor quantum dots</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784m24p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719m85r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w271r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objective: The purpose of this study is to test the osteoconductivity of Bone Ceramic® (BC) alloplastic material when used as an onlay graft under biodegradable poly L-lactide, polyglycolide acid (PLA/PGA) chambers (Inion® GTR™, Finland). Materials and Methods: 11 New Zealand white rabbits were used. On each rabbit's mandible, one test sample (BC chamber) was placed on the (right or left) body, while its control sample (empty, E chamber) was placed on the contralateral side. Randomized placement of the test and control samples to the right and left bodies of the mandibles was applied and identified. Twelve weeks postoperatively, the animals were sacrificed and the samples were extracted for analysis. Gross sample assessment, Micro-CT imaging, histology, and histomorphometry were used to analyze the differences between the test and control groups. The parameters evaluated are bone volume, bone surface area, and bone distribution. Results: Comparing the data of the BC and the E groups revealed significant statistical difference. Micro CT analysis showed statistically significant more bone volume in the BC than the E group, (P value &lt; 0.0001). The mean of the bone volume percentage in the BC group was 25.86% compared to 3.12% in the E group. Moreover, histomorphometry showed statistically significant more bone surface area in the test group (mean 20.70%) than the control group (mean 6.23%), P value &lt; 0.0001. Conclusion: BC was found to be osteoconductive when used as an onlay graft under PLA/PGA biodegradable chamber.</description><description>Objective: L'objectif de cette étude est d'étudier l'ostéoconductivité du matériel pour greffe allogène Bone Ceramic® utilisé comme onlay sous une chambre de maille (Inion® GTR™, Finlande). Ce matériel est composé principalement de polymères biorésorbables dérivés d'acide lactique et d'acide polyglycolide (PLA/PGA). Les paramètres employés pour l'évaluation des résultats sont le volume et la distribution de la greffe, ainsi que la superficie calcifiée de tissu. Méthodes: 11 lapins blancs de la Nouvelle-Zélande ont été utilisés. Sur chaque lapin, un os en céramique (BC, spécimens d'essai) a été placé dans la chambre d'Inion d'un côté de la mâchoire inférieure. Du côté opposé, une chambre sans os en céramique (Vide, spécimens E) a été placée comme contrôle. Le placement des spécimens du côté droit ou gauche de la mâchoire inférieure a été fait de manière aléatoire. Les chambres ont été fixées à la mâchoire inférieure utilisant des vis en titanium.  Environ douze semaines après la procédure, les animaux ont été sacrifiés et les spécimens ont été extraits pour l'analyse. L'évaluation brut, l'imagerie Micro-CT, l'histologie, et l'histomorphométrie ont été employées pour analyser les différences entre les groupes d'essai et les contrôles. Résultats: En comparant les données des groupes BC et E utilisant un test du t à deux queues, une différence statistique significative a été notée. L'analyse Micro-CT a démontré de façon statistiquement significative une plus grande distribution d'os dans le groupe BC que le groupe E (P &lt; 0.0001). La moyenne du volume d'os dans le groupe BC était 25.86% et celle du groupe E, 3.12%.  L'histomorphométrie a démontré davantage de formation d'os au groupe d'essai (moyenne 20.70%) qu'au groupe de contrôle (moyenne 6.23%), P &lt; 0.0001. Conclusion: BC est considéré ostéoconducteur quand utilisé comme greffe d'os onlay sous la membrane biorésorbable de</description><creator>Almasri, Mazen</creator><contributor>Timothy W Head (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Dentistry</subject><title>Is bone ceramic an osteoconductive material when used as an onlay graft? A prospective experiment on Rabbits' mandible</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247ds57v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w271r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mm72p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Demographic transition theorists posit that, beginning in the 1960s, biomedical contraceptive technologies and foreign countries, the United States in particular, have been primarily responsible for changes in medical fertility control ideas and practices in Peru. This dissertation argues that biomedical technologies and transnational political actors have played a role, but not always in the ways that demographic transition theorists indicate. The mass distribution of contraceptives such as the pill and the intra-uterine device, for example, depended on the existence of US-funded birth control organizations. However, these birth control organizations did not justify their existence in Peru only in terms of the promotion of development, but also by making appeals to the integrity of the family, values that many local physicians cherished. In addition, biomedical knowledge concerning the control of fertility began to be applied long before the 1960s, and not all of it originated in the United States nor was it all oriented towards the limitation of birth rates. Moreover, demographic transition theory's assumption that financial calculations were the primary reason for the prevention or spacing of births overlooks other factors, such as marital strife, that also affected the desire for offspring. Through archival material and oral histories in Peru and the United States, this dissertation raises questions about the ideologies and practices of medical experts, and their interactions with state agencies, foreign governments, the Catholic Church, and people who had abortions.</description><description>La théorie de la transition demographique suggere une transformation telle que, depuis les années 1960, les technologies biomédicales et les pays étrangers, espécialement les États-Unis, fut principalement responsables pour les changements des idées et pratiques en matière du contrôle medical de la fertilité au Pérou. Cette thèse argumente que les technologies biomédicales aussi que les acteurs politiques transnationaux en effet jouèrent un rôle, mais pas toujours dans la façon prévue par les théoristes de la transition demographique. La distribution massive des méthodes contraceptifs, tel que la pillule et le dispositif intra-uterin, par example, dépendit de l'existence des organismes de contrôle de la natalité financiés par les États-Unis. Cependent, cettes organismes ne justifièrent leur présence au Pérou seulement par la promotion du developement. Ils attachaient aussi de l'importance à l'integrité de la famille, un valeur que beaucoup des médecins entretinrent. D'ailleurs, des connaissances biomédicales sur le contrôle de la fertilité commencèrent à être appliquées avant les années 1960, et une partie importante d'entre elles ne provinrent pas des États-Unis. De plus, la supposition que la théorie de la transition demographique fasse sur la prevention ou l'espacement des naissances comme simples resultats des calculs economiques néglige autres facteurs, tel que les querelles des couples, lesquelles affectaient aussi le désir d'avoir des enfants. A travers des materiaux d'archives et des intervues au Pérou et aux États-Unis, cette thèse nous emmene a considerer les ideologies et les pratiques des experts médicaux, aussi que les interactions entre eux et des agences gouvernamentales, des gouvernements étrangers, l'église Catholique, et des gens qui avortaient.</description><creator>Necochea Lopez, Raul</creator><contributor>Andrea Tone (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>History - Latin American</subject><title>A history of the medical control of fertility in Peru, 1895 - 1976</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732d941q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mm72p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h238j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This master's thesis looks at the content of social studies textbooks used in public elementary education in the Dominican Republic, and analyzes the way discourse is used to construct a "national" identity.  Particular emphasis is placed on the ways racial and cultural ideologies are embedded in the depictions of Dominican identity.  The rationale for this study is to assess the Dominican curriculum, which rests almost entirely on the use of textbooks, and therefore draw conclusions as to the ways that Dominican children are socialized in their educational environment.  To this end, this qualitative inquiry addresses the following questions: How do textbooks used in public elementary schools in the Dominican Republic portray Dominican identity?  What notions of race and culture are included in these portrayals?  I show that the prevailing notions of identity found in the DISESA textbooks consist of the celebration of "racial mixing," which identifies the majority of Dominicans as mulattoes, and the recognition of Spanish culture as the foremost precursor to Dominican society.</description><description>La présente thèse examine le contenu des manuels de sciences humaines utilisés pour l'éducation élémentaire publique en République Dominicaine et analyse la manière dont le discours est utilisé pour construire l'identité « nationale ».  Un regard particulier est porté sur les manières par lesquelles les idéologies raciales et culturelles sont déterminées dans les représentations d'identité dominicaine.  La raison fondamentale de cette étude est l'évaluation du programme d'étude dominicain qui repose presque entièrement sur l'utilisation de manuels scolaires.  Cette évaluation vise à tirer des conclusions quant aux voies par lesquelles les enfants dominicains sont socialisés dans leurs environnements éducatifs.  À cette fin, cette recherche qualitative répond aux questions suivantes : Comment les manuels utilisés dans les écoles primaires publiques en République Dominicaine décrivent-ils l'identité dominicaine ? Quelles notions de race et de culture sont incluses dans ces portraits ? Je démontre que les principales notions d'identité trouvées dans les manuels DISESA se composent de la célébration « de mélange de race » identifiant la majorité des dominicains comme mulâtres et de la reconnaissance de la culture espagnole comme le précurseur principal à la société dominicaine.</description><creator>Perez Saba, Leovigildo</creator><contributor>Teresa Strong (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Education - Curriculum and Instruction</subject><title>Dominant racial and cultural ideologies in Dominican elementary education</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nk95d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h238j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3011895</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objectif: Elucider l'effet du diabète mellitus type I sur la cascade signalisatrice de l'oxytocin (OT)- peptides natriurétiques (NPs)-oxyde nitrique (NO). Méthode: Des rats Wistar masculin de 200-250 grammes ont été injectés intrapéritonéament avec 65 mg/kg de streptozotocin (STZ) pour produire un diabète expérimental. Ces derniers ont été sacrifiés 5.5 et 10.5 semaines plus tard. Les niveaux d'expressions des gênes et des protéines ont été déterminés en temps réel PCR et Western blot, respectivement. Résultats: Une augmentation significative dans l'expression de d'OT dans le ventricule gauche à été trouvée dans les deux cas: après 5.5 (640%) et 10.5 semaines (420%) de diabète. Une augmentation élevée de l'expression des gênes à été observée dans le ventricule gauche dans les deux horizons temporels pour l'ANP (370% et 160%, respectivement) et pour le BNP (210%, 190%). Conclusion: La régulation à la hausse du système OT-NPs se produit dans le ventricule gauche du rat diabétique après les deux périodes de 5.5 et 10.5 semaines de diabète laissé sans traitement, ce qui peut exemplifier un mécanisme adaptatif visant à opposer l'effet délétère de l'hyperglycémie. </description><description>Objective: To elucidate the effect of type I diabetes mellitus on the cardio-protective oxytocin (OT)-natriuretic peptides (NPs)-nitric oxide (NO) signaling cascade. Methods: 200-250 grams Male Wistar rats injected intraperitoneally with 65 mg/kg streptozotocin (STZ) to induce experimental diabetes were sacrificed 5.5 and 10.5 weeks later. Gene and protein expression levels were determined by Real-Time PCR and Western blot, respectively. Results: A significant increase in the gene expression of OT in the left ventricle (LV) was found after both 5.5 (640%) and 10.5-weeks (420%) of diabetes. Elevated gene expression was additionally found in the LV in both time frames for atrial natriuretic peptide (ANP) (370% and 160%, respectively) and brain natriuretic peptide (BNP) (210%, 190%). Conclusion: Upregulation of the local OT-NPs system occurs in the LV of the diabetic rat after both 5.5 and 10.5 weeks of untreated diabetes, perhaps exemplifying an adaptive mechanism aimed at opposing the deleterious effects of hyperglycemia.</description><creator>Dimitrova, Maria</creator><contributor>Jolanta Gutkowska (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Marek Jankowski (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - General</subject><subject>diabetic cardiomyopathy</subject><subject>natriuretic peptides</subject><subject>oxytocin</subject><subject>diabetes mellitus</subject><subject>streptozotocin</subject><subject>left ventricular hypertrophy</subject><title>The effect of experimental diabetes on the cardiac oxytocin system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w7751.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3011895</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50ts09n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les Kinases TES (TESKs) règlent la dynamique de l'actine par la phosphorylation de cofilin, et peuvent aussi règler des voies de signalisation indépendamment de leurs activités de kinase. Les deux isoformes sont exprimés en cerveau, mais leurs modèles d'expression et rôles fonctionnels dans le système nerveux central (SNC) n'ont pas été décrits. Dans cette thèse nous décrivons (1) le modèle d'expression des TESKs dans le SNC de la souris adulte et en développement, et (2) le rôle des TESKs dans le réarrangement cytosquelettiques et le poussement des neurites dans des cellules neuroblastomes et des neurones. Nous avons observé une expression régionale pour les deux isoformes dans le SNC adulte et en développement. La supra-expression de l'une ou l'autre isoforme a causé une accumulation significative de F-actine en cellules neuroblastomes et a empêché de manière significative le poussement des neurites dans des neurones primaires. L'expression des TESKs inactifs n'a pas affecté le F-actin ou le poussement des neurites. L'abattrement de TESK1 avec siRNA a causé une augmentation significative dans le poussement des neurites en cellules neuroblastomes N1E-115, suggérant un rôle pour les TESKs dans le poussement des neurites qui est indépendant de l'activité kinase.</description><description>TES Kinases (TESKs) regulate actin dynamics via phosphorylation of cofilin, and can also regulate signaling pathways independently of kinase activity. Both isoforms are expressed in the brain, however their expression patterns and functional roles in the CNS have not been described to date. In this thesis we describe (1) the expression pattern of TESKs in the adult and developing mouse CNS, and (2) the role of TESKs in cytoskeletal rearrangements and neurite outgrowth in neuroblastoma cells and neurons. We observed regionally-restricted expression of both isoforms in the developing and adult CNS. Overexpression of either isoform caused a significant accumulation of F-actin in neuroblastoma cells and significantly inhibited neurite outgrowth of primary neurons. Expression of kinase-inactive TESKs did not affect basal F-actin or neurite outgrowth. siRNA knock-down of TESK1 caused a significant increase in neurite outgrowth in N1E-115 neuroblastoma cells, suggesting a role for TESKs in neurite outgrowth that is independent of kinase activity.</description><creator>Pribiag, Horia</creator><contributor>Alyson Elise Fournier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience</subject><title>Spatiotemporal expression and functional role of TES Kinase in neurons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nr39s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50ts09n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tp83w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les modèles stochastiques de populations discrètes apparaissent dans une variété de contextes.  Dans cette thèse, nous considérons trois thèmes de la modéllisation : les épidémies qui se propagent par la transfusion sanguine et de la chirurgie, l'expression des gènes stochastique et l'accumulation d'erreurs dans les statistiques de vitesse de simulations de dynamique moleculaire.  Nous examinons les modèles spécifiques dans chaque cas et en tour nous illustrons des méthodes d'extraction des statistiques quantitatives des systèmes d'information.  En plus, nous discutons la façon dont les approches differentes s'inscrivent dans le cadre mathématique plus général pour des populations discrètes qui évoluent par les dynamiques stochastique. Les épidémies stochastiques sont estimé par des processus de branchement et des techniques de fonctions génératrices les moments sont utilisés pour calculer des distributions de l'état finale du nombre de personnes infectés et des produits contaminé de sang ou de la chirugie dans le cas où l'épidémie est souscritique.  Ce modèle simple fournit un cadre pour l'extension au systèmes plus complexes tels que ceux qui intègrent les populations stratifiés en fonction de l'age ou le risque d'exposition.  À notre connaissance, cette approche mathématique n'a pas été appliquée À ce type d'épidémie de modèles ailleurs dans la littérature. Les modèles stochastiques de l'expression des gènes sont développés d'un manière similaire aux modèles de l'épidémie, mais avec l'ajout de la diffusion spatiale des molécules.  La présence de la motilité moléculaire mène À des nouvelles questions quantitatives qui ne sont pas posée par les modèle non-spatiales.  Nous précisons plusieurs de ces questions et effectuons des calculs analytiques pour des quantités liés À la corrélation des molécules d'ARNm et de protéines À l'état stationnaire.  Ces quantités donnent une idée de l'échelle spatiale de les grappes l'ARNm et de protéines autour d'un point source d'ADN. Généralement, les simulations des Dynamiques Moléculaires impliquent l'intégration numérique des dynamiques Newtoniennes qui régissent le mouvement des systèmes de particules.  Souvent, les particules interagissent uniquement par le biais de collisions et une méthode À pas de temps constant est utilisée pour intégrer les équations de motion.  système dans le temps.  Dans ce cas, des petites erreurs s'accumulent dans les deux coordonnées de position et de vitesse.  Par des considérations de mécanique statistique, nous écartons l'information des position des particules et abordons le système comme une population de particules, distuinguée par leurs vitesses, en évolution aléatoire par des collisions.  Employant des hypothèses de la taille de la vitesse d'erreurs et de la distribution des vitesses des particules, nous construisons un modèle de diffusion pour la dérive de l'énergie.  Ce modèle est vérifiée par des simulations et il est indiqué de prévoir avec précision la dérive de l'énergie dans les systèmes À faibles densité avec un pas de temps modéré.</description><description>Stochastic models of discrete populations appear in a broad range of contexts.  In this thesis, three of these modelling settings are considered: epidemics which spread through both blood transfusion and surgery, stochastic gene expression, and the accumulation of error in velocity statistics in Molecular Dynamics simulations.  We examine specific models in each case, illustrating methods for extracting quantitative statistical information from the systems, and discuss how each approach fits into the more general mathematical framework for discrete populations evolving under stochastic dynamics. The stochastic epidemics are approximated by branching processes.  Generating function techniques are used to derive distributions of the final number of infected individuals and contaminated blood or surgery products in the case that the epidemic eventually dies out (subcritical).  This simple model provides a framework for extension to more complicated systems such as those that incorporate populations stratified by age or risk of exposure.  To our knowledge, this mathematical approach has not been applied to these kinds of epidemic models elsewhere in the literature. Stochastic models of gene expression are developed in a similar manner as the epidemic models, with the addition of spatial diffusion of the molecules.  The presence of molecular motility leads to quantitative questions not present in the non-spatial model.  We pose several of these questions and analytically calculate quantities related to the correlation of mRNA and protein molecules in the steady state.  These quantities give a sense of the spatial scale of protein and mRNA clusters around a DNA point source. Molecular Dynamics simulations typically involve the numerical integration of Newtonian dynamics governing the motion of systems of particles.  Often the particles interact only through collisions, and a fixed time step integrator is used to move the system forward in time.  In this case, small errors accrue in both position and velocity coordinates.  By statistical mechanical considerations, we discard the positional information of the system and model it as a population of particles, distinguished only by their velocities, undergoing evolution via random collisions.  Employing additional assumptions about the size of the velocity errors and the distribution of particle velocities, we construct a diffusion model for the drift in energy.  This model is verified with simulations and is shown to accurately predict the energy drift in dilute systems for moderate time scales.</description><creator>Cottrell, David Daniel</creator><contributor>Paul Frederick Tupper (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Peter Swain (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</subject><title>Analysis of three stochastic models for discrete populations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cg97f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tp83w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zh31p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La super-résolution (SR) vise à reconstruire une image ou une séquence vidéo de haute résolution (HR) à partir d'images dégradées de basse résolution (BR). La complexité des calculs requis par plusieurs méthodes de SR peut entraver l'utilisation de ces dernières lorsque le temps d'exécution est critique. Ceci motive notre intérêt pour l'accélération d'algorithmes de SR préservant les contours dans l'image. Les méthodes à préservation de contours sont préférables aux approches quadratiques car elles produisent des images aux contours mieux définis. Premièrement, nous proposons une méthode de préconditionnement pour l'accélération de problèmes de restoration d'image employant une PSF spatialement invariante. Cette application est un cas spécifique de SR d'une seule image de BR avec un facteur de grossissement unitaire. Nous démontrons que l'approche proposée est plus simple et souvent plus rapide que les méthodes traditionelles employées pour l'accélération de problèmes similaires. Deuxièmement, nous adaptons l'approche précédente aux problèmes de SR s'appliquant à des images translatées. Notre technique réordonne les pixels de HR d'une manière similaire à ce qui se fait pour les formulations quadratiques. Toutefois, en raison des exigences de préservation de contours, la matrice hessienne de la fonction objective varie durant la minimisation. Nous développons une méthode de mise-à-jour rapide du préconditionneur pour surmonter cette situation. Contrairement à d'autres stratégies d'accélération qui arrondissent les déplacements entre les images de BR sur la grille de HR, notre méthode ne sacrifie pas l'optimalité du modèle d'observation. Troisièmement, nous décrivons une technique pour le préconditionnement de problèmes de SR employant un facteur de grossissement rationel. L'utilisation de tels facteurs est motivée par le fait que, dans certaines circonstances, les facteurs optimaux ne sont pas des entiers. Nous démontrons qu'en réorganisant les pixels des images de BR, la structure du problème est modifiée de manière à permettre l'utilisation de préconditionneurs basés sur les matrices circulantes. Finalement, nous appliquons nos techniques d'accélération à des séquences vidéo compressées et à des images Bayer acquises avec une caméra dotée d'un filtre CFA. Par le biais d'expériences, nous démontrons que les techniques proposées peuvent accélérer les calculs de manière significative dans plusieurs scénarios.</description><description>Image super-resolution (SR) attempts to recover a high-resolution (HR) image or video sequence from a set of degraded and aliased low-resolution (LR) ones. The computational complexity associated with many SR algorithms may hinder their use in time-critical applications. This motivates our interest in techniques for accelerating computations associated with edge-preserving image SR problems. Edge-preserving formulations are preferable to quadratic ones since they yield perceptually improved images with sharper edges. First, we propose a simple preconditioning method for accelerating the solution of edgepreserving image restoration problems in which a linear shift-invariant (LSI) point spread function (PSF) is employed. This application is a special case of SR with a single LR image and a magnification factor of one. We demonstrate that the proposed approach offers significant advantages of simplicity, and in several cases, speed, over traditional methods for accelerating such problems. Secondly, we adapt the previous approach to edge-preserving SR problems from multiple translated LR images. Our technique involves reordering the HR pixels in a similar way to what is done in preconditioning methods for quadratic formulations. However, due to the edge-preserving requirements, the Hessian matrix of the cost function varies during the minimization process. We develop an efficient update scheme for the preconditioner in order to cope with this situation. Unlike some other acceleration strategies that round the displacement values between the LR images on the HR grid, the proposed method does not sacrifice the optimality of the observation model. Thirdly, we describe a technique for preconditioning SR problems involving rational magnification factors. The use of such factors is motivated in part by the fact that, under certain circumstances, optimal SR zooms are non-integers. We show that by reordering the pixels of the LR images, the structure of the problem to solve is modified in such a way that preconditioners based on circulant operators can be used. Finally, we apply our SR acceleration techniques to compressed color video sequences and to Bayer pattern images taken from a camera whose sensor is covered with a color filter array (CFA). Through experimental results, we demonstrate that the proposed techniques can provide significant speed improvement in many scenarios.</description><creator>Pelletier, Stéphane</creator><contributor>Jeremy Cooperstock (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - General</subject><title>Acceleration methods for image super-resolution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569503j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh31p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dq14x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Memories once acquired, are retained in a stable state that is relatively impervious to change. However, following reactivation these memories are destabilized and require a reconsolidation process to once again be stabilized. If the reconsolidation process is disrupted, amnesia will ensue. This has opened the possibility that reconsolidation could be used a therapeutic tool for attenuating detrimental memories such as those that govern post-traumatic stress disorder and drug addiction. Contextual cues previously associated with rewarding drugs induce powerful cravings which are believed to be a major cause of relapse. Disrupting memory reconsolidation for these associations may provide a means to attenuate cue-induced craving and relapse. This thesis shows that post-reactivation administration of the amnestic agents propranolol and midazolam will disrupt a morphine place preference in a manner consistent with reconsolidation blockade. A further study shows that over-learning acts as a boundary condition that inhibits reconsolidation. However the impact of memory strength can be overcome by allowing the memory to age and decay prior to reactivation. Another study demonstrates that post-reactivation propranolol treatment disrupts reconsolidation when administered immediately after a first, but not a second, non-reinforced reactivation session. This suggests that a certain degree of novelty is required at the time of reactivation for reconsolidation to be triggered. Finally the impact of drug dependence on the reconsolidation phenomenon is explored and shown to produce resistance to post-reactivation amnesia. In fact, it reverses the effect of propranolol and results in an enhancement of the preference for the drug-paired cues. These findings support the concept of reconsolidation as a therapeutic approach for treating cue-induced relapse in former drug addicts, but highlight the critical impact that prior dependence may have on the phenomenon.</description><description>Une fois acquises, nos mémoires sont préservées dans un état stable et à l'écart de tout changement. Cependant, suivant leur réactivation, ces mémoires sont déstabilisées et exigent un processus de reconsolidation afin d'être stabilisé de nouveau. Or lorsque ce processus de reconsolidation est perturbé, l'amnésie survient. De là a découlé l'idée d'exploiter le processus de reconsolidation en tant qu'outil thérapeutique afin d'atténuer, voire d'éliminer, les mémoires nuisibles comme celles qui régissent le syndrome de stress post-traumatique et la toxicomanie. Les associations contextuelles liées à l'usage de certaines drogues d'abus induisent des désirs de consommation, lesquels constituent une cause majeure de rechute. La perturbation de la reconsolidation de la mémoire pour ces associations peut fournir un moyen d'atténuer ces désirs et ainsi réduire les taux de rechute. Cette thèse démontre que l'administration post-reconsolidatoire de certains agents amnésiques - le propranolol et le midazolam - perturbe une préférence conditionnée d'endroit à la morphine d'une manière compatible avec une interférence du processus de reconsolidation. Elle prouve également que le sur-apprentissage d'une association agit de manière à empêcher l'enclenchement de la reconsolidation. Cependant la robustesse d'une mémoire peut être surmonté en permettant à cette mémoire de vieillir et se délabrer avant la réactivation. Une autre étude démontre que le traitement avec propranolol suivant la réactivation perturbe la reconsolidation une fois administré juste après une première séquence de réactivation, mais non après une seconde. Cela suggère qu'un certain degré de nouveauté est nécessaire au moment de la réactivation pour que la reconsolidation soit déclenchée. Cette thèse explore, en dernier lieu, l'impact de la dépendance à la drogue sur le phénomène de reconsolidation. Les résultats démontrent ici qu'une dépe</description><creator>Robinson, Michael James</creator><contributor>Keith B J Franklin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Psychology - Experimental</subject><title>Analysis of the reconsolidation phenomenon in a morphine conditioned place preference</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n842v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dq14x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d017w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In an attempt to improve the information parents provide on screening measures for autism spectrum disorders (ASD), Delgado, Venezia, and Mundy (2004) incorporated pictures next to each item depicting the behaviours parents were asked to rate on a new tool called the Pictorial Infant Communication Scale (PICS).  The psychometric properties of the PICS appear promising, yet a question only version of the PICS without pictures has not yet been examined against the PICS with pictures. Understanding the role pictures play to clarify constructs for parents on screening tools may result in a more time and resource efficient screening process. A series of analyses were conducted to examine differences between the two versions of the PICS questionnaire, the PICS version with pictures (PPICS) and the PICS version without pictures (NPICS). The participants included 66 typically developing infants and one parent per child. The PPICS was administered to one group and the NPICS to the other. When the children were 12 months of age, parents completed the PICS and the MacArthur Communication Development Inventories - Short Form (MCDI), a questionnaire that measures language development and the children were assessed with the Early Social Communication Scale (ESCS) to obtain a clinical measurement of the child's joint attention skills. When the children were 18 months of age the PICS, MCDI and ESCS were administered again, along with the Expressive and Receptive Language Scales of the Mullen Scales of Early Learning, a standardized measure of language development. When the children were 24 months of age the MCDI and Mullen were re-administered. Cross-sectional and longitudinal correlations between scores on the PICS, MCDI, ESCS and Mullen were assessed for both groups. The overall findings revealed the PPICS, as compared to the NPICS, at 12 months of age was more highly correlated to the ESCS. Both the PPICS and the NPICS did not correlate to language development. However, there</description><description>Dans le but d'améliorer les renseignements que les parents fournissent lorsqu'ils sont soumis aux outils de mesure des examens de dépistage des troubles du spectre autistique (TSA), Delgado, Venezia, et Mundy (2004) ont intégré des images à côté de chaque point décrivant les comportements que les parents doivent évaluer, et créé un nouvel outil appelé le Pictorial Infant Communication Scale (PICS) (échelle illustrée : communication de l'enfant).  Les propriétés psychométriques de PICS semblent prometteuses. Pourtant une version avec seulement des questions de PICS, sans images, n'a pas encore été comparée au  PICS sans images. Un procédé de dépistage plus efficace en termes de temps et de ressource permettra peut-être de comprendre le rôle que jouent les images dans la clarification des constructions destinées aux parents, soumis aux outils de dépistage. Une série d'analyses a été conduite pour examiner les différences entre les deux versions du questionnaire PICS, la version de PICS avec images (PPICS) et la version de PICS sans image (NPICS).  Ont participé : 66 enfants au développement typique et un parent pour chaque enfant. Un groupe a été soumis au PPICS et un autre groupe au NPICS. Au 12 mois de l'enfant, les parents ont complété le PICS et les Inventaires Macarthur du Développement de la Communication- Forum court (IMDC), un questionnaire qui mesure le développement du langage et les enfants ont été évalués avec l'Echelle de Communication Sociale Précoce (ECSP), afin d'obtenir une mesure clinique des capacités d'attention conjointe de l'enfant. Au 18 mois de l'enfant, on a de nouveau administré les PICS, IMDC et ECSP, ainsi que les Echelles d'évaluation du langage expressif et réceptif des Echelles Mullen d'apprentissage précoce, un outil de mesure standardisé du développement du langage. Au 24 mois de l'enfant on a de nouveau administré le IMDC et le Mullen. Les corrélations longitudinales et trans-sec</description><creator>Matejka, Anna</creator><contributor>Tony Charman (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jacob A Burack (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Education - Psychology</subject><title>Are pictures worth a thousand words? Testing two versions of the Pictoral Infant Communication Scale</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nx411.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d017w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150j69j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Congestive heart failure (CHF) and depression, two  leading problems in the community, are independently known to result in significant  functional impairments, deterioration in quality of life and high mortality. While  depression has been found to be a significant predictor of cardiac events and  cardiac mortality, the importance of concurrent depression in patients with CHF has  only recently been addressed. Studies of adjustment to chronic illnesses suggest  that patients' beliefs about their illness or illness perceptions are important  factors that may not only explain variations in patients' response to the same level  of disease severity but may also influence more directly patients' outcomes such as  adherence to treatment regimen, psychological and physical outcomes. Objectives. The objectives of this study were to assess the  relationships between six dimensions of illness perceptions ( Identity, Timeline,  Consequences, Personal Control, Treatment Control and Coherence), and later measures  of depression symptoms and functional performance in patients with CHF, and to  explore the moderating effect of social support in the relationships between illness  perceptions and later depression symptoms and functional  performance. Methods. A longitudinal study was conducted on 142 ambulatory  CHF patients treated at the Heart Failure Clinic at the Montreal Heart Institute.  Patients included in the study had left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) of less  than 40% and were able to speak and read French or English. Baseline assessment  included depressive symptoms (Cardiac Depression Scale, CDS), functional  performance, (Functional Performance Inventory, FPI-SF), illness perceptions  (Revised Illness Perceptions Questionnaire, IPQ-R), and social support  (Interpersonal Relationship Inventory, IPRI). Four-month telephone follow-up  included assessment of depressive symptoms and functional  performance. Results. The prevalence of depressive symptoms was high, with  46.3% (n=136) of the sample reporting depressive symptoms, 27.9% moderately severe  depression and 18.4% severe depression. After controlling for age, sex, education,  living alone, LVEF, and comorbidity, patients who reported a greater number of  symptoms identified with heart failure label ( Identity), more serious Consequences,  longer illness duration (Timeline), weaker beliefs about Personal Control and the  effectiveness of Treatment Control, and lower understanding of their illness  (Coherence), reported significantly higher levels of depression symptoms and lower  functional performance. In the longitudinal analyses, after controlling for baseline  depression, beliefs about Treatment Control at baseline explained significant  additional variance in depression at follow-up (p&lt;.01). Weaker beliefs about  Personal Control were significantly associated with higher depression symptoms and  worse functioning at lower levels of social support, but these relationships were  not apparent at higher levels of social support. Conclusions. Depression was highly prevalent in this sample of  outpatients with CHF, confirming the need for improved recognition of depression in  this group. Patients' beliefs about their illness appear to be particularly relevant  in patients adjusting to CHF. Interventions that modify or take into account  patients' negative beliefs about illness may have the potential to influence  behaviour and reduce depression symptoms in CHF.</description><creator>Parent, Nicole, 1964-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Nursing.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Epidemiology.</subject><title>The role of illness perceptions in relation to depression symptoms and functional performance in patients with heart failure /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cq92p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150j69j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z129p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse consiste en une série de contributions théoriques à des  méthodes algorithmiques pour la récupération de phase à partir de  mesures d'intensités de diffraction. Notre travail est présenté en  trois parties liées mais indépendantes. La première partie consiste en un raffinement des méthodes de  propagation de phase développée par Bates et al. en  1982. Nous introduisons un terme de  correction pour le calcul de la différence de phase entre des  échantillons réels dans l'espace réciproque. Nous montrons,  numériquement, la façon dont notre méthode mène à des  reconstructions d'image améliorées en 1D. Dans la seconde partie, nous développons un algorithme pour la  récupération de phase basé sur le dévelopement en série de  Fourier d'un support carré. Nous obtenons une série d'équations qui  décrivent la dépendance entre les différents points dans l'espace  réciproque, et nous démontrons que cette dépendance devient plus  simple lorsque seuls quelques termes de l'expansion sont pris en compte.  Notre algorithme est composé de deux étapes: dans la première,  quelques-unes des équations couplées sont résolues en vue d'obtenir  la phase dans une région localisée. Elle est suivie par une étape de  propagation dans laquelle le reste des valeurs de phase inconnues sont  obtenues au moyen de la méthode de propagation simple. Nous présentons  un exemple numérique dans lequel nous utilisons une méthode de  minimisation de descente pour résoudre les équations qui se posent sur  la première étape. Enfin, nous proposons une stratégie pour la récupération de la phase  des mesures de diffusion de rayons x d'un système subissant  la cinétique d'une transition de premier ordre, après une  trempe. Nous utilisons un modèle théorique simple et des simulations  numériques afin d'obtenir une expression du temps moyen de   décorrélation de phase dans la dynamique d'ordre. Nous présentons  un  exemple pour montrer comment ce résultat peut être utilisé pour   résoudre le problème de la phase plus vite et avec des taux plus   élevés de convergence.</description><description>This thesis consists of a series of theoretical contributions to  algorithmic methods for phase retrieval from diffraction intensity  measurements. Our work is presented in three related, but somewhat  independent parts. The first part consists of a refinement to the phase propagation methods developed by Bates et al. in  1982. We introduce a correction term  for the calculation of the phase difference between actual samples in reciprocal space. We show, numerically, how our method leads to improved image reconstructions in 1D. In the second part we develop an algorithm for phase retrieval based on the  Fourier series expansion of a sharp, square object support. We obtain a series of equations that describe the dependence between different points in reciprocal space, and show that this dependence becomes simpler when only a few terms of the  expansion are taken into account. Our algorithm consists of two  stages: In the first one, a few of the coupled equations are solved in order to obtain the phase within a localized region. This is followed by a propagation stage in which the rest of the unknown phase values are obtained by means of simple propagation method. We present a numerical example in which we use a downhill minimization method to solve the equations that arise on the first stage. Finally, we propose a strategy for phase retrieval from  x-ray diffraction measurements of a system undergoing the kinetics of a first-order transition following a temperature quench. We use both, a simple theoretical model and numerical simulations to obtain an expression for the average phase-decorrelation time  in ordering dynamics. We present an example to show how this result  can be used to solve the phase problem faster and with higher convergence rates.</description><creator>Montiel, David</creator><contributor>Martin Grant (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Physics - Optics</subject><title>Phase retrieval from x-ray intensity measurements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fc031.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z129p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rf01w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using as a case study the role that Morocco played in the drafting processof The United Nations Convention against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment, this dissertation explores whether human rights are universal or are merely a colonial product. Through an investigation of pertinent UN archives, this research asserts that the drafting of human rights conventions involves negotiations between states that belong to different forms of civilization worldwide, a stance that I share with the scholar Susan Waltz. By analyzing the passive role that Morocco played in the construction of the Convention against Torture, my research expands on previous scholarship. Through an investigation of Moroccan colonial and post-colonial histories, and Moroccan carceral literature, this research opposes artificial binaries such as positing cultural imperialism against political delegitimization of human rights. Although many scholars, including Joseph Massad and Abdullahi An-Naïm, maintain that human rights are a byproduct of colonialism and imperialism, the analysis of the role that Morocco played in the drafting of the Convention against Torture demonstrates that human rights are an active discipline, and not simply an artifact of colonialism or imperialism.</description><description>En analysant le rôle que l'État du Maroc a joué dans le processus de rédactionde la Convention contre la torture et autres peines ou traitements cruels inhumains oudégradants, cette recherche examine la validité des thèses qui sont véhiculées entreautres par l'historien Joseph Massad et le juriste Abdullahi An-Naïm, et quiconsidèrent les droits fondamentaux comme la suite logique de la mission civilisatricecolonialiste. Ce faisant, l'investigation des archives des Nations Unies portant sur larédaction de la Convention contre la torture rejoint les travaux de Susan Waltz : lespetits États sont présents dans le processus d'élaboration des droits universels aumême titre que les États puissants. Néanmoins, en analysant le rôle limité que l'Étatdu Maroc a joué dans ce processus, cette recherche va au-delà de ces travaux. Eneffet, l'examen de la littérature carcérale et de l'histoire coloniale et postcoloniale duMaroc montre que loin d'être un indicateur d'une soi-disant résistance à un ordreinternational colonialiste, le rôle joué par l'État du Maroc dissimule en fait des enjeuxpolitiques internes : l'élite dirigeante a recours à la torture en tant que mode degouvernance. Or, loin de condamner cette élite, dépendamment de leurs intérêtsgéopolitiques, les États puissants contribuent, directement ou indirectement, à lapratique systématique de la torture au Maroc. Par conséquent, l'ordre international nepoursuit pas la production des droits fondamentaux, et encore moins leuruniversalisation.</description><creator>Tremblay, Nathalie</creator><contributor>Setrag Manoukian (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>François Crépeau (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>History - Modern</subject><title>La conception des droits fondamentaux : discours et pratiques</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t9049.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rf01w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405s981v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:24:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Progranulin (PC-cell derived growth factor, acrogranin,  granulin-epithelin precursor) is a secreted glycoprotein with growth promoting  activities for diverse cell types and is the precursor for the 6 kDa granulin  peptides. These peptides were initially identified in inflammatory cells i.e.  neutrophils; and this led to the hypothesis that the grn(granulin ) gene and its  products may be regulated during, and function in, wound repair. In response to  tissue injury, the grn gene is induced in endothelial cells and fibroblasts.  Expression was observed in epithelial and inflammatory cells with higher expression  in the inflammatory cells in the early phases of wound healing. This is the first  evidence that demonstrates grn gene regulation in an adult physiological state.  Given the high expression of the grn gene in hematopoietic cells, particularly the  cells of the myeloid lineage, and that these cells are a source of granulin  peptides, it was important to understand the signals that regulate progranulin  transcript levels in these cells. For this investigation, two myelogenous cell  lines, U937 (human histiocytic lymphoma) and HL-60 (human promyelocytic), which are  models for monocytic and granulocytic maturation were chosen. Both these lineage  related cell lines displayed differential regulation of the progranulin mRNA. The  two cell lines were responsive to all three of the differentiation agents,  investigated; all-trans retinoic acid (ATRA), dimethylsulphoxide (DMSO) and  phorbol-12-myristate-13-acetate (PMA) with the exception of PMA-treated HL-60 cells  which exhibit no change in the progranulin transcript levels. As differentiation  occurs, the levels of progranulin transcript are up-regulated. However, progranulin  does not stimulate the differentiation of these cells as assessed by the expression  of the surface marker, CD11b which suggests that the increased levels of progranulin  transcript is likely to be a characteristic of matured cells (inf</description><creator>Ong, Colin Heng Piew, 1968-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of granulin gene expression in wounds and myelogenous leukemic cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pn366.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405s981v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43700</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>