<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:07:45Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):45425" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02870x00h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Catabolic glucocorticoids (the end-product of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) axis) can contribute to the occurrence of hippocampal neuronal loss. The issue addressed in this thesis is whether increased HPA activity is associated with cognitive impairments in aged rats. Using the Morris Swim Maze, fifty-eight male rats (22-27 months old) were screened to assess their spatial memory ability. Only 28% showed clearly impaired performance, while 34% were unimpaired. Among age-impaired (AI) rats, plasma concentrations of corticosterone and basal adrenocorticotropin (ACTH) levels were significantly elevated over those in either age-unimpaired (AU) or control animals. There was a significant decrease in type II corticosteroid receptor binding in the hippocampus in aged animals, particularly in AI animals. Decrease in neuron density was significantly greater among the AI animals relative to the controls. These results present evidence that impaired HPA activity is selectively associated with cognitive dysfunction and hippocampal neuronal loss and is not merely a correlate of age.</description><creator>Issa, Amalia Mary</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The relationship between hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal dysfunction and hippocampal pathology in senescent rats /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w193.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870x00h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150k366</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Canada, as a leader in satellite telecommunications, is an active ITU Member. The ITU is responsible for spectrum management at the international level. Hence, the ITU is composed of various organs for day-to-day work and for the elaboration of legal instruments. Also, the IFRB, an organ within the ITU, ensures the application of regulations by administrations implementing telecommunication satellites. The First Come, First Served principle is now augmented by the planning of the Fixe-Satellite Service (FSS) and Broadcasting-Satellite Service (DBS) for certain bands. Although the new procedure for the FSS is recognized to be flexible, Canada will not have much choice. Each of the three allotments provided for Canada cover one third of its territory. To obtain a single assignment covering the whole territory on the basis of its allotments, Canada will probably have to use the procedure provided by WARC Orb-88 for additional uses on the basis of Nairobi Convention principles edicted in article 33 par. 2.</description><creator>St-Arnaud, Diane</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>La mise-en-oeuvre en droit canadien des règlementations et conventions internationales en matière de télécommunications spatiales /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Diane St-Arnaud, 1991</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mg683.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150k366</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613mz71d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During most of the 1960s, the CSN was both an advocate of provincial autonomy and a defender of federalism. In the late 1960s and early 1970s, however, a majority of its leaders and militants came to favour separatism. Many of them saw independence as a precondition for the creation of a socialist Quebec. In 1972, the CSN rejected capitalism, endorsed socialism, and envisaged an internal referendum on the independence issue. The internal debate, however, took place only after the Parti quebecois was elected to power in 1976. Fearing internal divisions and disaffiliations, the CSN did not endorse separatism. Being disappointed with the Parti quebecois' governmental record, the CSN was content to give a critical support to a yes vote in the referendum in 1980.</description><creator>Güntzel, Ralph Peter</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Confédération des syndicats nationaux</subject><subject>Québec (Province) -- History -- Autonomy and independence movements</subject><subject>Labor unions -- Québec (Province) -- Political activity.</subject><title>The Confédération des syndicats nationaux, the idea of independence, and the sovereigntist movement, 1960-1980 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xs86h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613mz71d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999786d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The possibility of observing CP (or T) violation from the leptonic sector of the Standard Model in $e sp pm p$ scattering at HERA is investigated. Neglecting fermion masses, an effective-Lagrangian approach is used to compute model-independent predictions of an eventual CP-breaking asymmetry. The asymmetry is defined as the difference between the number of final electrons (for charged-current events), or jets (for neutral-current events), that leave the detector to the left and right of the plane defined by the axis of the incoming electron beam and its direction of polarization. It is found that HERA should be reasonably sensitive to CP-violation in the case of charged-current $e sp- p$ scattering events.</description><creator>Mangin, Ch.-M. (Christian-M.)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Perspectives on observing CP-violation from beyond the standard model at Hera</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t3187.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999786d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440t561</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The temporal variability of North Pacific Ocean surface cyclones is presented, based upon a nine cold-season dataset from the National Meteorological Center. Our results show that: (1) January is the most active month for oceanic cyclone activity; the most active zone of the cyclonic characteristics is at its southernmost location in January; (2) Interannual variability of cyclone activity is pronounced. The interannual variability of cyclone activity is predominantly stronger than the seasonal variability; (3) Analyses of objectively defined regimes, defined on the basis of a 30-day clustering of surface cyclone activity, reveal that regional climatological anomalies of surface cyclone frequency, significant at the 95% level of confidence, can be identified as precursors to the onset of these 30-day circulation regimes.</description><creator>Li, Tianshi</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Temporal variability of north Pacific Ocean surface cyclones</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k8294.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440t561</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429b42f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Ingenika Range forms part of a large zone of structural divergence that roughly coincides with the boundary between North America and Superterrane I. Contrasting tectonic histories from the Intermontane, Omineca and Foreland Belts at the latitude of the thesis area are consistent with a collisional model involving tectonic wedging, delamination and large-scale backthrusting. The Upper Proterozoic Ingenika Group in the Ingenika Range has undergone a progressive deformational history involving pre-, syn-, and post-metamorpic structures. During the Middle Jurassic regional structural vergence changed from northeast- to southwest-directed folds and faults. Regional metamorphism reached amphibolite grade and was synchronous with west-vergent deformation. Minor structures in the study area suggest that the Swannell fault was an east-dipping thrust fault that emplaced North American strata over allochthonous rocks of Quesnellia. The Swannell fault was probably also active during the Middle Jurassic and may have acted as the structural discontinuity between a backthrusted crustal flake and an underlying, eastward moving wedge.</description><creator>Bellefontaine, Kim Angelina</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Geophysics.</subject><subject>Geology.</subject><title>The tectonic evolution of the Ingenika group and its implications for the boundary between the Omineca and Intermontane belts, north-central British Columbia /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pb55p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429b42f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xw17f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the main goals of this project was to systematically evaluate the virus-inducible properties of the individual human interferon-beta (IFN-$ beta$) enhansons. Synthetic oligonucleotides representing the different enhansons were subcloned into an enhancerless SV$ sb1$CAT vector; the hybrid plasmids obtained were tested in different human cell lines by transient expression assay. The P2 motif, which is 80% homologous to the NF-$ kappa$B recognition sequence, was inducible by Sendai virus. In contrast, the P1 enhanson was transcriptionally silent. Unexpectedly, a multimer of the P5 motif conferred significant virus inducibility to a heterologous transcription unit. A DNA fragment encompassing P5, P1, and P2 mimicked the transcriptional activity of the whole IFN-$ beta$ promoter, indicating that the three enhansons act synergistically to confer a virus-inducible expression pattern. The effect of certain trans-acting factors on the individual IFN-$ beta$ enhansons was also assessed. Together, these experiments indicate that the synergism between the P5, P1, and P2 enhansons is mediated by at least two distinct transcription factors, NF-$ kappa$B and IRF-1.</description><creator>Leblanc, Jean-François</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Functional analysis of human interferon-beta gene transcriptional regulatory elements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r426z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw17f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kk82f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A relativistic equation, known as the Kemmer-Duffin-Petiau (KDP) equation, for spin-0 particles is used to study low energy pion-nucleus scattering. This equation is linear and the optical potential is completely local in contrast to the quadratic Klein-Gordon equation which contains gradient terms in the p-wave part of the potential when applied to pion-nucleus scattering. Specifically, if we use an almost minimal coupling scheme (scalar and vector potentials), then this equation is equivalent to the Klein-Gordon equation with a Kisslinger potential and an effective Ericson-Ericson-Lorentz-Lorenz parameter $ lambda$ = 3. Experimentally, the $ lambda$ parameter is subject to uncertainty and no agreement has been reached about its value, though it must be greater than 1.6. The full KDP optical potential is obtained by taking the impulse terms from $ pi$-N scattering data and folding this with the nuclear density and then adding a true absorption contribution which is quadratic in the densities. It is shown that good agreement can be obtained for elastic scattering on light nuclei at low energies.</description><creator>Alvarez del Castillo Astiazarán, Ricardo Ignacio</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><subject>Physics, Nuclear.</subject><title>The Kemmer equation for pion-nucleus scattering.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193b149.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kk82f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603qz651</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1988, an important Quebec chain of supermarkets organized and sponsored a campaign to promote healthy eating habits and regular physical activity. Six comprehensive articles were published weekly in a free flyer. The hypothesis underlying this study is that the program changes the buying habits of customers, as reflected by the content of their grocery carts. Data were collected at four points in time in one supermarket. Four independent samples of customers (N = 465) answered a brief questionnaire and the descriptive sales slip was used to analyze the food items in their shopping carts. The major dependent variables were the portions of various food groups, and fiber and lipid densities per dollar. Results show that, over time, customers lowered the lipid content and increased the fiber content of their purchases. This suggests that the food industry can play an effective role in improving the well-being of their clients.</description><creator>Laurendeau, Hélène</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Business Administration, Marketing.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition.</subject><title>Les effets d'un programme d'information nutritionnelle sur le contenu du panier de provisions /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9354169.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qz651</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25x9662</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the institution of the Moroccan Protectorate by the French in 1912, the military command had as its primary intention that of restoring law and order. Under the strong personality of the "resident general", Lyautey, a new era of "soft" political colonization was introduced in Morocco; brutish military conquests were followed by a certain cooptation process of the Moroccan elite. This association policy allowed the perception of real cooperation between the French and the Moroccans but was actually aimed at the tight regulation of the population. The efficiency of this regulation was achieved through its technocratic approach; it showed respect for the Moroccan Islamic traditions and its institutions. This study analyses the French colonial policy in Morocco between 1912 and 1925 through the means of reforms introduced into the judicial Islamic system. The author compares the system's organization, its jurisdictions and its procedures before 1912, and their reforms throughout the 1912 to 1925 period, when Lyautey was in command.</description><creator>Audet, Eric</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Islamic law -- Morocco</subject><subject>Morocco -- History -- 20th century</subject><title>The reforms of the Islamic legal system by the French in Morocco between 1912 and 1925 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343t369.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25x9662</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t752t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Saguenay-Lac St. Jean and Charlevoix regions of Quebec are characterized by high incidences of hereditary diseases such as vitamin D-dependent rickets type I (VDD1), cystic fibrosis, and tyrosinemia. This phenomenon may be due to founder effect or genetic drift. Therefore, one may also detect differences in allele frequencies of neutral polymorphisms between these populations and the general population. An assessment of genetic variation was performed utilizing genetic markers spanning chromosome 12q14. Allele frequencies for the genetic markers in the sample populations did not differ significantly from those published for other Caucasian populations. One haplotype, observed in strong linkage disequilibrium with the VDD1 mutation, was found to be infrequent on normal chromosomes. This suggests that all of the VDD1 mutant alleles could be identical by descent, in keeping with a founder effect for VDD1 in northeastern Quebec.</description><creator>Ross, Michelle</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Genetic variation in the French Canadian populations of the Saguenay-Lac St. Jean and Charlevoix Regions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q753c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t752t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tq477</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three sugarbushes were selected for the study of root distribution. Saint-Hippolyte was the best site for the distribution and production of fine roots. A high water-table and an abrupt change in texture limited the extension of the root system to the top 40 cm at the Vaudreuil site. In Tingwick, an acid mineral B horizon with a low Ca saturation restricted the production of fine roots in that horizon. A sugarbush in Norbertville was used as a replacement for the Vaudreuil site for the study on root chemistry. The Saint-Hippolyte site had the best overall nutrient status. The molar ratio Ca/inorganic Al and Mg/inorganic Al in solution never reached values low enough to be considered toxic for the growth of fine roots. However, Al seems to increase the imbalance between Ca and K and may be responsible for the low foliar P found at Norbertville. Aluminium may also inhibit Ca uptake by roots due to very low Ca content in Tingwick.</description><creator>Lajeunesse, Denyse</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Roots (Botany) -- Québec (Province) -- Growth.</subject><subject>Sugar maple -- Québec (Province) -- Roots.</subject><title>Le système racinaire de quelques érabliéres du Québec /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x01s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tq477</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vm180</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The basic research question this thesis addresses is how the secondary status of Bangladeshi women is reinforced through household labour. It is argued that gender relations and housework shape each other. To develop this, it examines the degree of participation of women in different areas of housework and family decisions. The thesis further explores whether the autonomy of women coming from the traditional Bangladeshi family set-up has increased as a result of their immigration to Canada and their exposure to Canadian family values. This is done by a comparison of the family experiences of Canadian and Bangladeshi women. Finally, it is suggested that age, position in the family and length of immigration are the indices of the autonomy of Bangladeshi women in Canada.</description><creator>Ahmed, Shameem</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Women -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Bangladesh</subject><subject>Housewives -- Bangladesh</subject><subject>Housewives -- Canada</subject><subject>Sexual division of labor -- Canada</subject><subject>Sexual division of labor -- Bangladesh</subject><title>Day in and day out : women's experience in the family and the reconstruction of their secondary status</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq17b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vm180</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290b64r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this dissertation, I reconceptualize the concept of violence to consider its physical, sexual, psychological and economic dimension. I attempt to add to existing meanings of "violence" to include not only forms of abuse on the individual and group level but also abuse practiced by legal, political, ideological and economic institutions in a collective and systemic manner. Due to the significance of child maltreatment around the globe, I focus on the impact of law on this problem specifically through a study of domestic and international use of the best interests' doctrine; evidentiary issues relating to children; child abuse reporting mechanisms and protection schemes in Canada and elsewhere; and the international protection of children's rights. Lastly, I analyze the benefits of a reoriented rights-based approach to empower children within and without the legal arena.</description><creator>Kachroo, Gaytri</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Philosophy.</subject><subject>Sociology, Public and Social Welfare.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Children, violence, and law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752h83b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290b64r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vh83z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The affordability crisis in the North American housing market has prompted the construction industry to reexamine technologies designed to lower cost through the factory mass production process. This thesis concentrates on modular prefabricated housing in the Province of Quebec in order to determine if this housing option can supply a less expensive alternative to comparable conventionally built housing. As issues of construction cost are allied with the quality of construction, a comparison between the conventional and the manufactured building industries, at this level, is also essential. Surveys evaluating sales cost and quality of construction have been developed for the modular prefabricated and conventional single family detached housing industry for the Province of Quebec. Fifteen prefabricated home builders and six conventional home builders were surveyed in order to facilitate the comparison between the two industries. It was found, based on the builders surveyed, that the average level of construction quality was consistent in both industries. The prefabricated residential home builders, however, proved on average to be approximately ten percent more expensive than the conventional home builders surveyed. Reasons for these cost discrepancies have been found to be related to the high start-up costs inherent in the manufactured housing industry, the overall cyclical market demand for housing, as well as price protection for distributors of manufactured housing.</description><creator>Wiedemann, Stefan J.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Buildings, Prefabricated -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Architecture, Domestic -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Construction industry -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Modular construction -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Modular prefabrication versus conventional construction as a cost effective alternative for the construction of single family detached housing in the Montreal area</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mg69c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vh83z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vm201</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The soleus H-reflex modulation pattern was measured in 8 normal and 8 spastic paretic subjects during standing and walking, under the conditions of 0% and 40% body weight support (BWS). In standing, both the normal and patient groups showed no significant difference (p $&lt;$ 0.01) in the H-reflex amplitude between 0% and 40% BWS. Normal subjects had a phase dependent modulation of the H-reflex during gait, there being no significant difference (p $&lt;$ 0.001) in this modulation with 40% BWS. The patients had an abnormally elevated H-reflex throughout the step cycle, although five showed some modulation. In the patient group, 40% BWS produced a decrease of the H-reflex amplitude mainly in the push-off phase. BWS produced a decrease in electromyographic (EMG) mean burst amplitude of the lower limb muscles investigated, with more appropriate EMG activity timing. BWS improved knee and ankle angular displacements in patients, which were associated with an improved locomotor pattern. However, these improvements in locomotor pattern were not reflected clearly by changes in the H-reflex modulations. Thus the relationship between H-reflex amplitude, EMG activity, and ankle position under 0% and 40% BWS, needs to be further investigated.</description><creator>Blunt, Robert A. (Robert Andrew)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Influence of body weight support on soleus H-reflex modulation in normal and spinal cord injured human subjects during standing and walking</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547s63b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vm201</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nc40n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Replacement matrix dolomite (RMD) is present throughout the Leduc/Cooking Lake Formation, but is restricted to the bank margin in the Swan Hills Formation. RMD has an average crystal size of 140$ mu$m and fluoresces yellow in the Leduc/Cooking Lake Formation but has an average crystal size of 250$ mu$m and fluoresces green in the Swan Hills Formation. RMD formed before the onset of stylolitization. It has abundant inclusions, a homogeneous red cathodoluminescent response, and similar trace element concentrations in both formations. $ delta sp{18}$O values overlap for the most part, but some Swan Hills dolomites are 1 to 2$ perthous$ lighter in $ delta sp{18}$O. The Leduc/Cooking Lake dolomite has a slightly greater range in $ delta sp{13}$C, with several samples lighter than +1.5$ perthous$. Diagenetic fluids derived from seawater are supported by average $ delta sp{13}$C, $ delta sp{18}$O (1.77$ perthous$, $-$4.19$ perthous$; 2.81$ perthous$, $-$4.95$ perthous$), and $ sp{87}$Sr/$ sp{86}$Sr (.7082;.7086) values in the Leduc/Cooking Lake and Swan Hills dolomite respectively. Yellow fluorescence and pyrolysis parameters in the Leduc/Cooking Lake dolomite could be caused by the presence of mature organic compounds.</description><creator>Laflamme, Andre K.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Replacement dolomitization in the Upper Devonian Leduc and Swan Hills formations, Caroline area, Alberta, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wr39b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nc40n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193b16v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phenomenon of self-stimulation has been used to map the neural circuitry of reinforcement and determine its neurophysiological and neurochemical characteristics. More recently, it has been proposed that drugs of abuse control behavior by their effects on the same neural systems. However, drug effects rise and fall over minutes or hours while conventional brain stimulation trains have abrupt onset and offset and last less than one second. Possibly because of this, the pattern of responding produced by drug reinforcers is different from the pattern produced by conventional brain stimulation. Furthermore, pharmacological antagonists of drug reinforcement increase the rate of drug self-administration while antagonists of brain stimulation reinforcement depress self-stimulation. To test the hypothesis that the differences in the characteristics of brain stimulation and drugs as reinforcers are due to differences in the kinetics of drugs and brain stimulation, we have modelled drug kinetics with frequency modulated brain stimulation trains. It is reported that animals will self-administer such brain stimulation and that, under these conditions, dopamine antagonists can induce an increase in the rate of self-administration.</description><creator>Lepore, Marino</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Reinforcement (Psychology)</subject><subject>Drug abuse.</subject><subject>Brain stimulation.</subject><title>Self-administration of brain-stimulation : an exploration of a model of drug self-administration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gp528.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193b16v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xm93f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Radiosurgery is a radiation treatment modality in which a high radiation dose (few 1000 cGy) is given to a small volume (few cm$ sp3$) within the patient's brain during a single treatment. The main physical characteristics of radiosurgery are narrow circular radiation beams, stringent requirements on the numerical ($ pm$2%) and spatial ($ pm$1 mm) accuracy of dose delivery to the target and the need for sharp dose fall-offs outside the target volume. Physical aspects of radiosurgery based on isocentric linear accelerators (linacs) are presented. The equipment and techniques used in the measurement of various radiosurgical beam parameters are discussed. Also discussed is the accuracy of radiation beam delivery to the target, the calculation and measurement of 3-dimensional isodose distributions obtained from circular beams, and the production of cylindrical dose distributions with rectangular beams. It is shown from the physics point-of-view that linac-based radiosurgery is a viable alternative to radiosurgery with the commercially available Gamma unit.</description><creator>Sixel, Katharina E. (Katharina Elisabeth)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Physical parameters of narrow photon beams in radiosurgery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g404j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xm93f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jp915</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An epidemic of hepatitis B occurring in a rural area of Nova Scotia in 1988 and 1989 was investigated. Illicit injectable drug use (IIDU) was the major determinant of transmission. The epidemic was the first highly visible indication of IIDU in Nova Scotia. A contact-tracing approach was used to identify the cohort of IIDUs. Of 186 IIDUs, 78 had serological evidence of hepatitis B infection. Using epidemiological criteria, it was determined that 57 of these formed a definite cluster of hepatitis B infections. Age, the total number of IIDU-contacts named and the number of hepatitis B seropositive IIDU-contacts named were identified as risk factors for hepatitis B infection. Six cases of delta hepatitis coinfection were found among the cluster cases, with a secondary attack rate estimated at seven percent. Risk-reduction and immunization strategies for the prevention of viral illnesses associated with IIDU were recommended.</description><creator>Poulin, Christiane Claire</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Hepatitis B and delta hepatitis in Nova Scotia : association with illicit injectable drug use</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kh56x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jp915</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827c91c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Flaubert's Trois Contes have long been a literary enigma before which critics have stumbled. Unlike the major novels of Flaubert, these Contes offer a more optimistic view of the world. Though each story unfolds differently, the heroes find similar salvations through metamorphosis. In some instances this has been refered to as sanctity, while in other cases, it was not deemed a powerful enough motif to link Trois Contes together. The study at hand will strive to show, by analysing the development of their personality, how each character self-realizes and finds salvation. As we progress through the three texts, it will become apparent that a sequence was intended for the reader to follow, and that the order in which the texts were published is capital.</description><creator>Gascon, Christopher</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Flaubert, Gustave, 1821-1880. Trois contes</subject><title>Trois Contes de Flaubert : La quête de l'unité</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z658m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827c91c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257g20s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lipid is a major fuel in trauma and sepsis. Previous in vitro studies have demonstrated an increased $ beta sb1$-adrenergic stimulated lipolysis in the adipose tissue of trauma patients. With sepsis there was a decrease in $ beta sb1$ stimulated lipolysis. Subsequent in vitro studies have shown that E. coli endotoxin decreases $ beta sb1$-stimulated lipolysis and that this effect may be occurring at the level of the G-protein, a component of the $ beta$-adrenergic receptor mechanism. The object of this study is to demonstrate the effect of E. coli endotoxin on lipid metabolism in vivo and to correlate this with in vitro receptor data obtained using adipose tissue biopsies.</description><creator>Meterissian, Sarkis</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Effect of E. coli endotoxemia on lipid metabolism in swine</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053h17b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257g20s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b446p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the process of extracting silver from lead bullion, zinc is added to the lead bullion to form a zinc crust. The crust is subsequently distilled and metallic zinc is condensed for reuse. In the present work, four aspects of the process were studied: the thermodynamic properties of zinc in zinc crust (the Pb-Ag-Zn ternary system); the heat and mass transfer of zinc vapour in a vertical tube condenser in the presence of a non-condensable gas; the cooler-condenser design for the vapour and gas mixture; and the zinc vapour condensation behaviour.</description><creator>Wang, Zhou</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Metal vapour condensation at reduced pressures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zv514.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b446p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000001163</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study reports on the treatment of 62 primary alcoholic patients using either Cranial Electrotherapy Stimulation (CES) or sham stimulation in a control group. The treatment consisted of half-hour sessions given five days per week during a four-week period. The variables analyzed included age, socio-demographic status, duration of alcohol dependence, frequency and volume of consumption, craving, and duration of sleep. Michigan Alcoholism Screening Test (MAST), Alcohol Dependence Scale (ADS), Drinking Behavior Inventory (DBI), Symptoms Checklist-90 Revised (SCL-90R), Hamilton Psychiatric Rating Scale for Depression, Hamilton Anxiety Scale and Diagnostic Interview Schedule concerning organic brain syndrome, were used. Laboratory tests included serum Gamma-Glutamyl Transferase (GGT) and Mean Corpuscular volume (MCV). Significantly greater improvements were obtained in the active treatment group in the depression subscale and in the Positive Symptoms Distress Level of SCL-90R. The active stimulation reduced alcohol consumption significantly during weekends, but no significant difference in the average weekly consumption was observed between active and sham treatment groups. Consistently more favorable results were observed in the active treatment group in other dependent variables.</description><creator>Malec, Tadeusz Stanislas</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><title>Cranial electrotherapy stimulation in the treatment of primary alcoholism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bj36k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000001163</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wp04c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:36:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a probabilistic model, specifically a nonhomogeneous Markov model, for the description of fatigue crack growth. This model is capable of predicting the statistics of crack growth, the mean crack size and the variance in the crack size, at future times given two empirically determined system parameters, $ lambda$ and $ kappa$, and an initial crack size distribution. Prior to the mathematical development of this model a brief review of existing crack growth models is presented. After the mathematical development of the model has been presented the results from a previous application in the study of pitting corrosion are presented. Following this, the results from the modelling of several existing fatigue data sets are examined in order to determine the necessary empirical material parameters and also to verify the model's applicability. Once the model has been verified and the empirical parameters determined one data set is chosen in order to illustrate the uses of this model for component reliability predictions. These uses include reliability at a future time, inspection optimization and the effect of changes in repair policy on reliability.</description><creator>Bohn, Steven R. (Steven Raymond)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>A Markov model for fatigue crack growth and the prediction of component reliability /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397945f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wp04c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):45450</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>