<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:58:41Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43475" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83kz765</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) at certain frequencies increases thresholds for motor evoked potentials and phosphenes following stimulation of motor or visual cortex. Consequently rTMS is often assumed to introduce a "virtual lesion" in stimulated brain regions, with correspondingly diminished behavioral performance. Here we investigated the effects of rTMS to visual cortex on subjects' ability to perform visual psychophysical tasks. Contrary to expectations of a visual deficit, we find that rTMS often improves the discrimination of visual features.  For coarse orientation tasks, discrimination of a static stimulus improved consistently following theta-burst stimulation of the occipital lobe.  Using a reaction-time task, we found that these improvements occurred throughout the visual field and lasted beyond one hour post-rTMS. Low-frequency (1 Hz) stimulation yielded similar improvements. Finally, we observed improved depth discrimination following high-frequency rTMS to V3A, and these effects were highly task-specific, yielding improved discrimination of disparity but not orientation. Overall our results suggest that rTMS generally improves or has no effect on visual acuity, with the nature of the effect depending on the type of stimulation and the task.  We interpret our results in the context of an ideal-observer model of visual perception.</description><description>La stimulation magnétique transcrânienne répétitive (rTMS) à certains seuils fréquences augmente pour potentiels évoqués moteurs et phosphènes suite d'une stimulation du moteur ou du cortex visuel. Par conséquent rTMS suppose souvent de mettre en place une lésion «virtuel» des régions cérébrales sollicitées, avec des performances comportementales réduit d'autant. Ici, nous avons étudié les effets de la rTMS au cortex visuel sur l'aptitude des sujets d'effectuer des tâches visuelles psychophysiques. Contrairement aux attentes d'un déficit visuel, nous constatons que rTMS améliore souvent la discrimination des caractéristiques visuelles. Pour les tâches d'orientation grossière, de la discrimination d'un stimulus statique améliorée à la suite constamment theta-burst stimulation du lobe occipital. L'utilisation d'un temps de réaction tâche, nous avons constaté que ces améliorations se sont produites tout au long du champ visuel et a duré plus d'un heure après l'rTMS. Basse fréquence (1 Hz) stimulation permis des améliorations similaires. Enfin, nous avons observé une meilleure discrimination en profondeur suivant à haute fréquence rTMS à V3A, et ces effets ont été très tâches spécifiques, ce qui donne de faciliter la distinction de disparité, mais pas l'orientation. L'ensemble, nos résultats suggèrent que rTMS améliore de manière générale ou n'a pas d'effet sur l'acuité visuelle, avec la nature de l'effet en fonction du type de stimulation et de la tâche. Nous interprétons nos résultats dans le contexte d'un modèle idéal-observateur de la perception visuelle. </description><creator>Waterston, Michael</creator><contributor>Christopher Pack (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience</subject><title>Improved discrimination of visual stimuli following repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sd19p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83kz765</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xs02g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Breast cancer is the second most common type of cancer after lung cancer  and the fifth most common cause of cancer death. It is by far the most widespread cancer amongst women, with an incidence rate of more than twice that of colorectal cancer and cervical cancer and about three times that of lung cancer. In this thesis, for the first time, a novel nanoparticle for effective drug delivery using the antibody trastuzumab and genipin crosslinking agent was designed and evaluated for its use in breast cancer. In vitro studies were also conducted to compare different crosslinkers in the preparation method of the drug loaded nanoparticles.  In addition the efficacy of noscapine drug loaded nanoparticles were evaluated in breast cancer cell lines. Results showed that novel  nanoparticles containing targeting antibody trastuzumab can be an alternate method for breast cancer treatment and other biomedical applications. This work highlights the potential of novel antibody targeting nanoparticles crosslinked with genipin or glutaraldehyde as a drug delivery system for breast cancer therapy as they can effectively deliver drugs such as noscapine. Further in-vivo studies however are required to evaluate the full potentials.</description><description> Suivant le cancer des poumons, le cancer du sein est le deuxième type de cancer le plus répandu et commun à travers le monde. C'est la cinquième cause de décès du à un cancer. Certes, il est le cancer le plus commun parmi les femmes, ayant un double taux d'incidence à ceux du cancer du colon et cancer du col de l'utérus, et triple à celui des poumons. Dans cette dissertation, une drogue carrière qui combine les anticorps trastuzumab et la drogue noscapine, a été conçue et évaluée pour être utilisée dans le traitement du cancer du sein. Des études « in vitro » ont étés conduites pour comparer différents crosslinkers dans la méthode de préparation des nanoparticules chargées de cette drogue. De plus, l'efficacité de nanoparticules chargées de drogues a été évaluée au niveau des cellules du cancer de sein. L'objectif de cette étude est le développement d'une procédure coacervation pour la préparation et la caractérisation in vitro  des nanoparticules HSA sous un aspect d'une taille contrôlée, en combinaison d'une distribution mono dispersée. Leur propriétés sont donc étudiés pour la délivrance optimale, prudente et efficace de drogues anti-cancer. Les résultats prouvent que les nanoparticules chargées de noscapine qui contiennent l'anticorps trastuzumab peuvent être une méthode alternative pour le traitement du cancer du sein ainsi que d'autres applications biomédicales. Des études "in-vivo" plus profondes sont recommanés pour évaluer leur potentiel maximum. Ce travail mets en valeur le potentiel des trastuzumab-modifié nanoparticules charges de noscapine reliés avec du genipin ou du glutaraldehyde comme un system de drogue conçu pour la thérapie du cancer du sein. fr</description><creator>Sebak, Safaa</creator><contributor>Satya Prakash (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - General</subject><title>Novel nanoparticles for breast cancer targeted delivery: preparation and in vitro characterization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gw636.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xs02g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w773g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dual Diagnosis, the co-occurrence of intellectual disability and psychopathology, was evaluated in 31 individuals with 22q13 deletion syndrome. Parents filled out the Reiss Scales for Children's Dual Diagnosis, The Vineland Adaptive Behavior Scales, and the Family Quality of Life Survey in order to describe the mental health, adaptive functioning and family quality of life of the subjects. Six subjects (19.35%) met the criteria for dual diagnosis, three had significant attention problems and another four had significant withdrawn behavior. Dual diagnosis was associated with overall mental health, attention problems, withdrawn behavior, autistic symptoms, anger/self control problems and social skills. Psychotic and attention deficit symptoms were the most frequent symptoms among the Reiss scales. Psychosis was not associated with overall mental health or dual diagnosis; however, it significantly correlated with family interaction, parenting, emotional well-being and quality of life.  Maladaptive behavior was marked by a significant increase in externalizing behaviors with age.</description><description>Le double diagnostic, la cooccurrence d'une incapacité intellectuelle et psychopathologique, fut évalué avec 31 individus souffrant du syndrome de délétion 22q13. Les parents ont passé le test des échelles de Reiss pour le double diagnostic des enfants, Le Vineland Adaptive Behavior Scales, et le sondage sur la qualité de vie familiale de manière à décrire la santé mentale, le fonctionnement adaptif et la qualité de vie familiale des sujets. Six sujets (19.35%) ont rempli le critère du double diagnostic, trois souffraient de problèmes d'attention significatifs et quatre autres individus souffraient d'un comportement de retrait significatif. Le double diagnostic fut associé avec la santé mentale générale, les problèmes d'attention, le comportement de retrait, des symptômes autistiques, des problèmes de colères ou de contrôle de soi et les habiletés sociales. Les syndromes psychotiques ou de déficits d'attention furent les plus fréquents dans les échelles de Reiss. La psychose ne fut pas associée avec la santé mentale générale ou le double diagnostic; cependant on observa une corrélation significative avec l'interaction familiale, le parentage, le bien-être émotionnel et la qualité de vie. Les comportements mésadaptés furent marqués par une augmentation significative de l'externalisation des comportements avec l'âge.</description><creator>Sharma, Akanksha</creator><contributor>Steven Shaw (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Education - Psychology</subject><title>Dual diagnosis in individuals with 22q13 deletion syndrome</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g19d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w773g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558d748</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'expression des gènes est régulée, en grande partie, par la liaison des facteurs de transcription à de courtes séquences d'ADN. Trois études sont présentées, portant sur l'identification in silico de motifs régulateurs dans les séquences promotrices de gènes végétaux. Dans la première étude, un algorithme d'initiation discriminative exacte est présenté. L'algorithme surpasse plusieurs algorithmes populaires lorsque appliqué à des données biologiques de référence. Dans la deuxième étude, l'algorithme est utilisé pour l'identification de motifs cis-régulateurs conservés dans les promoteurs de gènes de protéines de réserve des graines chez diverses espèces végétales. Des motifs connus ainsi que de nouveaux motifs sont identifiés. Dans la troisième étude, des groupes de gènes orthologues sont identifiés chez cinq espèces dicotylédones, et une recherche de motifs cis-régulateurs est réalisée dans les séquences promotrices proximales pour chaque groupe. La présence de trois larges grappes de groupes d'orthologues partageant des motifs similaires est mise en évidence.</description><description>The regulation of gene expression is driven primarily by transcription factors binding to short DNA sequences. Here three studies related to promoter cis-regulatory motif discovery in plant promoters are presented. In the first study, an exact discriminative seeding DNA motif discovery addressing key issues associated with popular DNA motif discovery algorithms is proposed. The Seeder algorithm outperforms popular motif discovery tools on biological benchmark data. In the second study, the algorithm is applied to the identification of cis-regulatory motifs in seed storage protein gene promoters. Known and new motifs are discovered. In the third study, groups of orthologous genes are identified among five dicotyledonous plant species, and DNA motif discovery is carried out in the proximal promoter sequence within each group. The presence of three large clusters of groups of orthologous promoters sharing similar motifs is revealed.</description><creator>Fauteux, François</creator><contributor>Martina Stromvik (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Bioinformatics</subject><title>Computational DNA motif discovery in plant promoters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n8388.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558d748</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dq12c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La thèse soutient que, dans les cas observes dans le Delta de Niger, la Commission Africaine a appliqué le règlement sur les recours locaux d'une manière flexible en mettant l'accent sur l'obligation de l'État répondant de prévoir un recours légal effectif plutôt que de s'appuyer machinalement sur le principe voulant que le requérant doit d'abord épuiser le recours domestiques. Cette approche représente une application juste du règlement dans le domaine de la protection des droits humains.  De plus, la thèse soutient que les déclarations de la Commission Africaine concernant l'absence de recours légaux domestiques effectifs au Nigeria ont ouvert la porte aux améliorations dans les institutions légales de ce pays.  Cette approche flexible au règlement sur les recours locaux devrait donc être applicable a toute pétition méritoire dans le système de droits humains en Afrique.</description><description>The thesis argues that the local remedies rule as applied by the African Commission in the Niger Delta cases in a flexible manner which focused on the Respondent State's obligation to provide effective legal redress rather than the mechanical act of exhaustion of local remedies by the petitioner, represents a correct application of the rule in human rights protection and that the African Commission's pronouncements regarding the absence of effective domestic legal remedies in Nigeria facilitated improvements in Nigeria's legal institutions.  A flexible approach to the local remedies rule should therefore be applicable in all meritorious communications in the African human rights system.</description><creator>Agocha, Bernadine</creator><contributor>Payam Akhavan (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>The application of the local remedies rule under the African Charter on Human and Peoples' Rights: with a case study of communications from the Niger Delta</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zw96d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dq12c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773w12v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Si l'oeuvre de Sylvie Germain est bien connue des critiques littéraires, la thématique de l'errance, qui occupe une place principale dans son écriture, demeure relativement inexplorée. Le présent mémoire étudie l'errance en présentant le thème dans l'oeuvre de l'écrivaine et, ensuite, en examinant, plus particulièrement, son rapport avec le personnage féminin dans le roman Magnus. Cette analyse propose trois modèles de femmes errantes : la femme aliénée, l'aventurière et la criminelle.</description><description>If Sylvie Germain's works are well known to literary critics, the theme of wandering, which holds an important place in her writings, remains relatively unexplored. This thesis studies the theme of wandering by presenting it firstly within the body of the writer's oeuvre, and then, by examining more thoroughly its relation to the female character in the novel, Magnus. This analysis proposes three models of wandering women: the alienated woman, the adventurer and the criminal.</description><creator>Rogowska, Edyta</creator><contributor>Jane Everett (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Literature - Modern</subject><title>Trois modèles de femmes errantes dans «Magnus» de Sylvie Germain</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246s527.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773w12v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418n691</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les titres sont-ils représentatifs du contenu des histoires?  Est-ce qu'ils varient de manière systématique du contenu qu'ils illustrent?  Cette thèse  prend en considération la façon dont les titres portant sur la politique représentent l'offre complète d'information politique disponible pour les citoyens.  Les titres sont présentés comme l'équivalent médiatique des heuristiques cognitives.  On assume qu'ils résument les nouvelles quotidiennes, et qu'ils fournissent ainsi aux citoyens un raccourci médiatique, leur permettant de se tenir informés des affaires publiques.  Ils soulignent aussi le contenu qui les suit et signalent quelles nouvelles sont les plus importantes selon les rédacteurs.  Ces fonctions permettent le développement des hypothèses sur la nature du lien entre les titres et les histoires. Cette relation est jaugée en examinant une typologie d'information politique essentielle qui inclut les partis politiques, les candidats, la probabilité de succès électoral, l'idéologie et l'approbation.  Ces éléments sont considérés comme essentiels pour comprendre les politiques électorales dans les démocraties libérales contemporaines.  Cinq hypothèses portent sur la manière dont ces éléments d'information, présents dans l'histoire complète,  sont représentés dans les titres.  Les données utilisées pour cette analyse incluent tous les titres et histoires de la campagne électorale canadienne de 2006, parus dans les journaux quotidiens majeurs, dans les téléjournaux, à la radio et sur les principaux sites d'information en ligne (N = 11 002).  Six entrevues avec des rédacteurs et journalistes d'influence complètent cette analyse empirique. Les résultats indiquent que le contenu des titres correspond bien au contenu de leur histoire.  Les titres semblent offrir un volume de couverture similaire du concours électoral et des problématiques.  Les problématiques que les gens voient dans les titres ressemblent étroitement à ce qu'ils trouveraient dans le contenu en y payant plus attention. Cependant, les résultats montrent également des différences systématiques entre les titres et les histoires qu'ils représentent. Au Canada, contrairement à ce qu'on en attendrait d'après les histoires, les titres tendent à se concentrer plus sur les leaders des partis politiques, et moins sur les partis politiques eux-mêmes. Les titres tendent aussi à exagérer (positivement ou négativement) la performance des partis et de leurs candidats.  En plus des comparaisons entre titres et histoires au niveau global, l'étude comporte une analyse hiérarchique unique de la relation entre le titre et son histoire. Alors que les titres des journaux semblent généralement être les moins semblables aux histoires, les titres des téléjournaux semblent être très proches du contenu qui suit. Les implications de l'utilisation des titres comme raccourcis médiatiques sont discutées dans le cadre de la politique démocratique.</description><description>Are headlines microcosms of a bigger picture?  Do they differ in systematic ways from the stories they lead?  This dissertation considers how headlines about politics represent the more comprehensive supply of political information available to citizens.  Headlines are presented as the media equivalent of cognitive heuristics.  They are widely assumed to encapsulate the news of the day, and thus provide citizens a media-generated shortcut for keeping informed of public affairs.  They also draw attention to what follows them and signal the news that editors deem most important.  With these functions in mind, hypotheses are developed about the relationship between headlines and stories. This relationship is assessed based on a typology of essential political information.  Party, candidate, viability, ideology, and endorsement cues are defined as essential for processing electoral politics in modern liberal democracies.  Five hypotheses address how these types of information cues, as depicted in stories, are represented through the lens of headlines.  All election headlines and corresponding stories during the 2006 Canadian election campaign that were published, broadcast, and posted by leading dailies, television newscasts, radio news programs, and internet news websites are included in the analysis (N=11,002).  The empirical study is complemented by in-depth interviews with six prominent news editors and journalists. Results indicate news content in headlines and stories strongly correlate.  Headlines appear to report a similar volume of horserace versus issue-oriented coverage.  The issues people see and hear about in headlines closely resemble what they would get by paying closer attention.  Yet, results also identify systematic ways in which headlines distort the news they represent.  Headlines are leader-focused in Canada, and party politics gets considerably less attention than coverage in stories would predict.  They also tend to exaggerate how well (or badly) parties and candidates are performing.  In addition to aggregate-level comparisons between headlines and stories, this study develops a unique multilevel analysis of the relationship between a headline and its story.  While newspaper headlines generally prove to be least consistent representatives of stories, television headlines tend to be close proxies of what follows.  The implications of headlines as media-generated shortcuts are discussed for democratic politics.</description><creator>Andrew, Blake</creator><contributor>Stuart Soroka (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>Media-generated shortcuts: the supply and demand of political information</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0967534.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418n691</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bv02g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Accurate Mass and Time (AMT) tag approach to high-throughput proteomics uses reversed-phase liquid chromatography (RPLC) coupled to high accuracy mass spectrometry to measure both the masses and chromatographic retention-times of tryptic peptides in complex mixtures. These measurements are matched to the mass and predicted retention-times of peptides in a library to identify the associated sequences. This dissertation comprises two journal article manuscripts, a conference paper, and a third manuscript describing a sequence of Bayesian statistical models addressing key aspects of AMT tag matching. The first manuscript described a statistical model that matched accurate mass measurements to the masses of peptides in a library constructed from partial knowledge of the composition of the sample under analysis. Although no individual match was assigned with high confidence, in aggregate they enabled the detection and correction of calibration errors in the mass spectral data. In RPLC, a peptide's relative affinities for the solid and liquid phases, termed "hydrophobicity", is the physical property that determines its retention-time. The second manuscript described a statistical model that used a large data set of measured retention-times of identified peptides to estimate their hydrophobicity. The conference paper described a model for predicting a peptide's hydrophobicity from its sequence. The parameters of the model were fit using the results of the second manuscript and tested using an independent data set of measured retention-times of identified peptides. Together, the models of second manuscript and the conference paper provided estimates of peptide hydrophobicity for arbitrary peptide sequences. The third manuscript described a statistical model integrating a retention-time-matching component (made possible by the availability of estimated peptide hydrophobicities) into the first model, yielding probabilities of correctness for matches between AMT tags and predicted masses and retention-times of peptides in a library. The probabilities were validated by comparison with a set of "gold standard" peptide identifications acquired by MS/MS. The accuracy of the model was verified by demonstrating that its predicted receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve matched the ROC curve generated by the gold standard data set.</description><description>L'approche basée sur le temps de rétention et la masse déterminée de façon précise (ou approche AMT, Accurate Mass and Time tag) de la protéomique à haut débit fait appel à la RPLC (chromatographie liquide en phase inversée) couplée à la spectrométrie de masse de haute précision pour mesurer les masses et les temps de rétention des peptides trypsiques d'un mélange complexe. Ces mesures sont comparées aux masses et aux temps de rétention prévus de peptides d'une banque pour identifier les séquences associées. Cette thèse est constituée de deux articles de journaux, d'un article présenté dans une conférence et d'un troisième manuscrit, et décrit une suite de modèles statistiques bayésiens traitant les aspects essentiels des appariements basés sur la stratégie AMT. fr Le premier article décrit un modèle statistique qui compare les mesures précises de la masse aux masses des peptides d'une banque construite à partir de la connaissance partielle de la composition de l'échantillon analysé. Bien qu'aucun des appariements n'ait pu être établi avec un degré de confiance élevé, ensemble, ils ont permis de détecter et de corriger des erreurs de calibrage dans les données de spectrométrie de masse. fr En RPLC, l'affinité relative d'un peptide pour les phases solide et liquide, appelée « hydrophobicité », est la propriété physique responsable du temps de rétention du peptide. Le deuxième article décrit un modèle statistique faisant appel à un vaste ensemble de données de mesure de temps de rétention de peptides identifiés pour estimer leur hydrophobicité. L'article présenté dans le cadre d'une conférence décrit un modèle permettant de prédire l'hydrophobicité d'un peptide à partir de sa séquence. Les paramètres du modèle ont été ajustés à l'aide des résultats présentés dans le deuxième article et vérifiés au moyen d'un ensemble indépendant de données de mesure de temps de rétention de peptides connus. Ensemble, les modèles décrits dans le deuxième article et dans l'article de la conférence ont permis d'obtenir une estimation de l'hydrophobicité de séquences peptidiques arbitraires. fr Le troisième manuscrit décrit un modèle statistique qui intègre une composante de comparaison des temps de rétention (rendue possible par la disponibilité d'estimations de l'hydrophobicité peptidique) dans le premier modèle, permettant ainsi d'obtenir la probabilité de l'exactitude des appariements entre les marqueurs AMT et les masses et temps de rétention des peptides d'une banque. Les probabilités ont été validées par comparaison avec un ensemble de peptides de référence identifiés par MS/MS (spectrométrie de masse en tandem). La précision du modèle a été vérifiée en démontrant que la courbe de ROC (receiver operating characteristic, caractéristique de fonctionnement du récepteur) correspondait à la courbe de ROC obtenue avec les données de référence.</description><creator>Yanofsky, Corey</creator><contributor>Robert E Kearney (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>A Bayesian approach to peptide identification by accurate mass and time tags in proteomics experiments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zd965.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bv02g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128b39j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For St. John's, Newfoundland, at the confluence of several North American storm tracks, we identify synoptic-scale characteristics and precursors of various classes of cool-season precipitation events. Such events, based upon a climatology for 1979-2005, are separated into three categories based on precipitation amount.  We find that the storm systems responsible for extreme precipitation events originate farther south and east than corresponding features in moderate and light events.  A wind climatology shows that extreme precipitation events at St. John's are characterized almost exclusively by easterly surface and 925 hPa geostrophic winds, and that both the surface and 925 hPa geostrophic winds rotate clockwise with decreasing precipitation amount. Focusing on extreme events, we utilize two methods of manual synoptic typing to further partition events.  The first method uses backward air parcel trajectories to separate events by air parcel source region.  One subset of events ("west") is characterized by strong upper-level dynamics and high precipitable water values in the central United States, which helps to produce a strong cyclone upon reaching the Atlantic Ocean; this is not seen for "west" events outside the extreme category.  The second method of synoptic typing utilizes time series of three ascent-forcing quasi-geostrophic (QG) variables.  While most events are characterized by a strong upstream sea-level cyclone originating from the Gulf of Mexico ("cyclone"), a subset are dominated by strong low-level frontogenesis, in the absence of a substantial upstream cyclone ("frontal"). Finally, a dynamic and thermodynamic analysis, and forecast model evaluation is completed for consecutive extreme events in December 2008, which produced over 125 mm of precipitation over six days. The first event is a "cyclone", and is marked by strong QG forcing for ascent in the presence of low static stability and high values of subtropical moisture.  The second event is a "frontal" event, and is associated with a persistent quasi-stationary baroclinic zone in the presence of moderately stable air and large values of low-level frontogenesis, in the absence of substantial temperature and vorticity advection.  These two events highlight rather disparate means by which an extreme precipitation event can occur at St. John's.</description><description>Pour St. John's, Terre-Neuve, à la confluence de plusieurs trajectoires de tempêtes nord-américaines, nous identifions des caractéristiques à l'échelle synoptique et des précurseurs d'une variété de type d'événements de précipitation de la saison froide. Ces événements, basés sur une climatologie allant de 1979-2005, sont séparés en trois catégories basées sur la quantité de précipitation. Nous trouvons que les systèmes de tempêtes responsables des événements de précipitation extrêmes débutent plus au sud et à l'est que les événements correspondants avec précipitation modérée ou faible. Une climatologie des vents montre que les événements de précipitation extrêmes à St. John's sont caractérisés presque exclusivement par des vents de surface et géostrophique à 925 hPa provenant de l'est, et tournant dans le sens des aiguilles d'une montre avec une diminution de la quantité de précipitation. En se concentrant sur les événements extrêmes, nous utilisons deux méthodes de classification synoptique manuelle pour séparer davantage les événements. La première méthode utilise une trajectoire renversée des parcelles d'air pour séparer les événements en fonction de leur région d'origine. Un sous-ensemble des événements ("ouest") est caractérisé par une forte dynamique dans les  niveaux supérieurs et des valeurs d'eau précipitable élevées dans le centre des États-Unis, ce qui aide à produire un puissant cyclone lorsque l'océan Atlantique est atteint; ceci n'est pas observé pour les événements "ouest" en dehors de la catégorie des extrêmes. La seconde méthode utilise des séries temporelles de trois variables quasi-géostrophiques (QG) forçant l'ascension. Bien que la plupart des événements sont caractérisés par un puissant cyclone au niveau de la mer en amont qui origine du Golfe du Mexique ("cyclone"), un sous-ensemble est dominé par une forte frontogenèse dans les niveaux inférieurs, en l'absence substantielle de cyclone en amont ("frontal"). Finalement, une analyse dynamique et thermodynamique, ainsi qu'une évaluation de modèle de prévision est complétée pour des événements extrêmes consécutifs en décembre 2008, qui produisent plus de 125 mm de précipitation sur une période de six jours. Le premier événement est du type "cyclone", et est marqué par un puissant forçage QG d'ascension en présence de faible stabilité statique et de hautes valeurs d'humidité subtropicale. Le deuxième événement est de type "frontal", et est associé à une zone barocline persistante d'air modérément stable et de hautes valeurs de frontogenèse dans les niveaux inférieurs en absence d'advection de température et de vorticité substantielle. Ces deux événements mettent en valeur des manières plutôt différentes par lesquelles un événement de précipitation extrême peut se produire à St. John's.</description><creator>Milrad, Shawn</creator><contributor>John Richard Gyakum (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</subject><title>A climatology and synoptic-dynamic basis for distinguishing cool-season precipitation events at St. John's, Newfoundland</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g799v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128b39j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h241v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le génie des écosystèmes, soit la pratique de concevoir, créer ou manipuler, et faire la suivi des écosystèmes, s'applique, souvent de manière intégrée, au bénéfice de la société humaine et de l'environnement naturel. Quoiqu'il y ait des principes de base pouvant servir à de tels ingénieurs dans le développement et mise en oeuvre de tels écosystèmes, présentement il n'existe aucune théorie compréhensive pouvant guider la conception d'écosystèmes artificiels. Afin qu'une telle théorie soit énoncée, il nous faut acquérir des connaissances approfondies quant aux interactions existant entre les constituants et le comportement de l'écosystème, et quant à comment procéder dans l'analyse et l'intégration de ces connaissances.  Il devient donc nécessaire de pouvoir faire l'évaluation qualitative et quantitative de grands ensembles de données par des méthodes d'analyse multivariable. L'objectif de ce projet fut donc d'étudier l'utilisation d'une méthodologie de raisonnement par cas pour recueillir et faire l'analyse de grands ensembles de données écologiques, autant pour servir à des prédictions qu'à des fins d'ingénierie, une application préalablement inévalué. Afin de maximiser le nombre de cas pouvant être analysés sans limiter les données d'entrée à celles décrites dans les ouvrages scientifiques, un écosystème virtuel et une plateforme de simulation furent conçus. Les données de sortie des simulations et les valeurs pour les mesures mises en oeuvre furent compilés dans une base de cas conçue pour servir d'intrant à un raisonneur par cas qui servirait à prédire les résultats de plusieurs écosystèmes virtuels supplémentaires, chacun créé de façon aléatoire.  Ces résultats furent comparés aux valeurs prédites.  L'exactitude des prédictions du raisonneur  par cas varia, mais, 83.3% du temps, dépassa 75%.  Un essai préliminaire fut entrepris pour mettre en oeuvre cette démarche d'ingénierie d'écosystème pour des niveaux de performance précis dans le cadre d'un écosystème virtuel. Quoique les niveaux de persistance visés ne furent pas atteints, les écosystèmes virtuels "façonnés" furent, dans l'ensemble, plus persistants que ceux bâtis de façon aléatoire, avec un rapport moyen des espèces ayant survécu aux espèces initiales de 0.40527,  comparé à 0.20750 pour les écosystèmes aléatoires.  Cela met en évidence le potentiel de cette nouvelle démarche pour l'analyse de données en génie des écosystèmes.</description><description>Ecological engineering, the practice of designing, creating or manipulating, and monitoring ecosystems, is applied for a variety of purposes benefiting both human society and the natural environment, often integratively.  While there are basic principles that help practitioners in the development and implementation process, at this time there is no comprehensive theory that guides the design of ecosystems. In order for such theory to be developed, extensive knowledge about the interactions between ecosystem constitution and comportment, and ways to analyze and integrate this knowledge, are needed.  Consequently, the ability to qualitatively and quantitatively evaluate large datasets in a multivariate fashion is required.  Thus, the objective of this project was to investigate the use of case-based reasoning as a method of gathering and analyzing large sets of ecological data not only for prediction but for engineering purposes, a previously untested application. To maximize the number of cases to be analyzed without limiting the inputs to only known systems described in the literature, a virtual ecosystem and simulation platform was created.  Simulation outputs and values for applied measures were compiled into a case base for use with a case-based reasoner to attempt to predict the results of several additional randomly created virtual ecosystems.  Actual results were compared to the predicted results.  The accuracy of the predictions made by the case-based reasoner varied, but they were more than 75% accurate 83.3% of the time.  An initial attempt was made to apply this approach to "engineering" ecosystems for specified performance levels within the virtual ecosystem framework. While the targeted values of persistence were not obtained, the "engineered" virtual ecosystems were more persistent overall than the randomly created systems, with an average ratio of 0.40527 surviving species to initial species versus an average persistence of 0.20750 for the random systems.  This is indicative of the potential of this novel approach for data analysis in ecological engineering.</description><creator>Lanphere, Tania Ruth</creator><contributor>Grant Clark (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Using case-based reasoning to learn about ecological engineering</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q192n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h241v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nh583</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dissertation investigates narrative strategies employed by the contemporary American novel to criticize and counteract the dynamics of domination. The study focuses primarily on Charles Johnson's Middle Passage (1990), Richard Powers's The Time of Our Singing (2003), and Leslie Marmon Silko's Almanac of the Dead (1991). These three novels address problems of sociopolitical repression and racial discrimination arising from the preconditions and heritage of colonial rule and the enslavement of Native Americans and African-Americans. While Johnson, Powers, and Silko refer to concrete historical moments, the critique implicit in their novels does not primarily arise from narrated historical facts or fictional experience, but from the narrative configurations they construct, and in which they embed these facts and experiences. They juxtapose naturalized assumptions about fixed meanings of space, temporality, and ensuing notions of self prevailing in the narrated historical past to ever changing combinations of ethnic, cultural, and social belonging within shifting spatial and temporal parameters, until these assumptions become untenable. Their method of exposition is therefore basically dialogic, and the insights that these novels yield constitute a form of knowledge that becomes available precisely through the combination of dialogics and literary narrative. To the degree that previous assumptions still prevail, all three novels provide a critique of the foundations on which members of Western culture across racial and ethnic lines construct their sense of authority within dynamics of power today. Johnson, Powers, and Silko are associated with African American, mainstream American, and Native American literature, or, in the case of Silko, with the field of American women's writing, and yet, while belonging in these subfields of American studies, go beyond and indeed defy such institutional categories in the conceptual reach of their work. Their novels participate</description><description>La thèse examine les stratégies narratives employées par le roman américain contemporain en vue de critiquer et de contrecarrer la dynamique de la domination. L'étude se concentre principalement sur Middle Passage de Charles Johnson (1990), The Time of Our Singing (2003) de Richard Powers et Almanac of the Dead (1991) de Leslie Marmon Silko. Ces trois romans abordent les problèmes socio-politiques de répression et de discrimination raciale découlant des conditions préalables et de l'héritage de la domination coloniale et l'asservissement des Amérindiens et des Afro-Américains. Tandis que Johnson, Powers et Silko se rapportent à des moments historiques concrets, la critique implicite que l'on retrouve dans leurs oeuvres n'est pas principalement issue des faits historiques narrés ou des expériences fictives proposées, mais des configurations narratives qu'ils construisent, et dans lesquels ils intègrent ces faits et ces expériences. Ils juxtaposent des hypothèses établies touchant les significations convenues de la temporalité et de l'espace qui mènent des notions d'autonomie en vigueur dans le passé historique rapporté jusqu'à l'évolution constante des combinaisons de facteurs ethniques, culturels et sociaux appartenant au transfert des paramètres temporels et spatiaux, et ce, jusqu'à ce que ces hypothèses deviennent insoutenables. Leur méthode d'exposition est donc essentiellement dialogique et les propositions offertes par ces romans constituent une forme de connaissance qui devient disponible notamment à travers la combinaison de la dialogique et de la narration littéraire. Dans la mesure où les hypothèses antérieures continuent de prévaloir, les trois romans fournissent une critique des fondements sur lesquels les membres de la culture occidentale à travers les frontières raciales et ethniques construisent leur sens de l'autorité au sein de la dynamique du pouvoir exercé aujourd'hui. Johnson, Powers, et Silko sont associ</description><creator>Oltmann, Christina</creator><contributor>David C Hensley (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Literature - American</subject><title>Dynamics of domination and dialogic narrative strategies in Charles Johnson's «Middle Passage», Richard Power's «The Time of Our Singing», and Lesie Marmon Silko's «Almanac of the Dead»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz21f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nh583</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xm35j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude présente une nouvelle approche d'analyse de données spectrales résultant de l'utilisation de la spectroscopie infrarouge à transformée de Fourier couplée à un détecteur type «matrice à plan focal» (FPA-FTIR) à balayage rapide. Les spectromètres FPA-FTIR ont une capacité de capture de données de plusieurs ordres de grandeur supérieurs aux spectromètres traditionnels et nécessitent donc des techniques avancées d'analyse de données pour exploiter cette mine d'information que représente l'imagerie infrarouge. La spectroscopie FPA-FTIR a été utilisée dans cette étude pour l'identification des bactéries. L'étape initiale, celle de la comparaison de trois spectromètres FPA-FTIR sur les points de vue fidélité de l'image, tant image-image qu'entre images, a révélé de grandes variabilités qui sont propres à cette technologie. Cette étape est suivie du développement de routines de filtration de pixels permettant d'extraire les données caractéristiques de l'imagerie infrarouge des échantillons non-uniformes. Un algorithme génétique (GA) est ensuite introduit pour déterminer la pertinence des caractéristiques spectrales sur le plan de la classification bactérienne et a été comparé à d'autres formes de classification optimisée. Une étude de démonstration de la capacité de la technologie d'imagerie infrarouge pour la détection des échantillons de bactéries provenant de cultures mixtes s'en est suivie. Pour terminer, une méthodologie globale combinant ces techniques d'analyse de données et incluant d'autres étapes telles le développement, la mise à niveau et la validation des bases de données d'imagerie infrarouge a été présentée. Cette méthodologie met l'emphase sur le développement et l'implantation d'un système expert accessible d'utilisation à de non-experts.</description><description>This study presents new techniques for the analysis of data acquired by focal plane array Fourier transform infrared (FPA-FTIR) spectroscopy. FPA-FTIR spectrometers are capable of acquiring several orders of magnitude more data than conventional FTIR spectrometers, necessitating the use of novel data analysis techniques to exploit the information-rich nature of these infrared imaging systems. The techniques investigated in this study are demonstrated in the context of bacteria identification by FPA-FTIR spectroscopy. Initially, an examination is made of the image fidelity of three FPA-FTIR instruments and demonstrates the high degree of within-image and between-image variability that is encountered with this technology. This is followed by a description of the development of pixel filtration routines that allow for the extraction of the most representative data from the infrared images of non-uniform samples. A genetic algorithm (GA) approach is introduced for determining the relevancy of spectral features in relation to bacterial classification and is compared to other forms of classifier optimizations. A proof-of-concept study demonstrating the potential use of infrared imaging to detect bacterial samples originating from a mixed culture is then presented. Finally, an overall methodology involving the combination of these data analysis techniques and including additional approaches towards the development, maintenance, and validation of databases based on infrared imaging data is described. This methodology has been developed with an emphasis on accessibility by implementing the elements of an expert system which allows for this technology to be employed by a non-technical user.</description><creator>Ghetler, Andrew</creator><contributor>Ashraf A Ismail (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Artificial Intelligence</subject><title>Development of an expert system for the identification of bacteria by focal plane array Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g7979.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xm35j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655h13d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pourquoi certains groupes ethniques appuient-ils l'utilisation du terrorisme et de la violence afin de modifier le statut quo alors que d'autres s'y opposent? Il est généralement admis que la répression peut engendre plus de violence. Or, le sens de cette relation ne fait toujours par consensus dans la littérature. Cette étude présente une théorie visant à expliquer l'appui des groupes ethniques au terrorisme (TEST) et qui suggère que les cas où les groupes ethniques se voient refuser l'accès au politique comme moyen pacifique de résolution de conflits créent des conditions de répression structurelle. Celle-ci devient alors un motif pour les groupes ethnique de se mobiliser afin de trouver des modes extra-institutionnels et des avenues extra-juridiques de résoudre les conflits, incluant le terrorisme. L'avenue choisie par les groupes ethniques dépend de la réponse offerte par l'État à leurs stratégies de mobilisation. Cette réponse peut inclure des réformes aux institutions répressives, minant l'appui des groupes à la violence et au terrorisme, ou l'utilisation discrète d'actes de répression conduits par des individus, générant une augmentation du soutien au terrorisme au sein des groups ethniques. Dans le cadre de cette étude, la théorie TEST est donc évaluée à la lumière des cas des Catholiques irlandais du Nord et de l'IRA, des Québécois et du FLQ, ainsi que des Corses et du FLNC. Elle démontre que, d'une part, la volonté des États de répondre aux revendications des groupes ethniques marginalise, si ce n'est éradique, l'utilisation du terrorisme par ces groupes. D'autre part, les États qui choisissent de négliger, d'aliéner ou de discriminer les groupes ethniques les empêchent d'utiliser les voies politiques de résolution des conflits, provoquant une augmentation de l'appui de ces groupes à l'utilisation de la violence et du terrorisme.</description><description>Why do some ethnic groups support the use of terrorism and violence to change the status quo and others do not? Conventional wisdom suggests repression may provoke more violence, but consensus has not been reached on how this relationship works. I propose a Theory of Ethnic Group Support for Terrorism (TEST) that argues that the denial of political access to ethnic groups to resolve conflict through peaceful means creates conditions of structural repression. This structural repression then engenders ethnic groups to mobilize around seeking extra-institutional and often extra-legal avenues of change including terrorism. The avenue chosen depends upon the state's response to ethnic group mobilization, which may include reforming repressive institutions, thus undermining support for violence and terrorism, or may include using agent-driven discrete acts of repression, triggering increases in ethnic group support for terrorism. The TEST is applied and assessed in light of the cases of Northern Irish Catholics and the IRA, Quebecois and the FLQ and Corsicans and the FLNC. Ultimately, the TEST demonstrates that states' willingness to effectively address ethnic group grievances will marginalize, if not eradicate terrorism. In contrast, states that choose to neglect, alienate and discriminate against ethnic groups fail to enable them to use political channels to change the status quo, causing increases in support for terrorism.</description><creator>Cox, Amy S</creator><contributor>Stephen Saideman (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Political Science - International Law and Relations</subject><title>Self-fulfilling prophecies: the government's role in generating support for ethnic terrorists</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3655656.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655h13d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505099j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We examined the effects of bright light on social interaction and mood in healthy individuals with mild seasonality. In a cross-over design, 38 mildly seasonal individuals received three weeks of bright light and three weeks of placebo (low-density negative ions). Using an event-contingent method participants recorded their mood and behaviours during social interactions and wore a light-sensor actigraphy at the wrist to monitor adherence to home based light exposure. During light administration, 23 participants adhered to the light protocol and exhibited more quarrelsome behaviours and no change in mood. Participants who provided no evidence of adherence had similar mood and social behaviour during both interventions. The results indicate the need for effective methods for determining adherence to the protocol in light studies.  Furthermore, in individuals with mild seasonality light administration may not improve mood and may have adverse effects on social behaviour.</description><description>Nous avons examiné les effets de la lumière forte sur les interactions sociales et l'humeur chez des individus sains avec un caractère saisonnier léger. En utilisant un plan d'étude croisé, 38 individus légèrement saisonniers ont été exposés à trois semaines de lumière forte et trois semaines d'un placebo (ions négatifs à intensité basse). En utilisant la méthode des événements liés (les participants ont enregistré leur humeur et comportement durant leurs interactions sociales et ont porté un détecteur de lumière au poignet pour vérifier leur adhérence à l'exposition à la lumière à la maison. Durant l'administration de la lumière, 23 participants ont adhéré au protocole de lumière et exhibé plus de comportements querelleurs et aucun changement d'humeur. Parmi les autres participants qui n'ont fourni aucune preuve d'adhérence, et leur humeur et comportement social étaient semblables pendant les deux interventions. Les résultats indiquent un besoin de méthodes efficaces pour déterminer l'adhérence au protocole de lumière. Qui plus est, chez les individus avec caractère saisonnier léger, il est possible que l'administration de lumière n'améliore pas l'humeur et exerce des effets adverses sur le comportement social. fr</description><creator>Hsu, Yu-Chien</creator><contributor>Simon N Young (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Mental Health</subject><title>Exposure to bright light and social interactions in every-day life in healthy mildly seasonal people</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r838r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505099j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t238h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aging, advanced cancer and cancer cachexia are distinct entities that share common signs and symptoms. With the increase in cancer patient survivorship, especially in the cohort of patients 65 years of age and over, there is a need to distinguish the commonalities and differences in markers of inflammation, body composition, functional performance, and the metabolic and nutritional profiles that characterize aging, advanced cancer and cancer cachexia. In characterizing elderly patients with advanced cancer, this thesis focuses on two areas: 1) validating the assessment tools that measure both body composition and physical strength, and 2) applying these tools to determine which of the above characteristics could be ascribed to physical aging, advanced cancer and/or cancer cachexia. A better understanding of these conditions can lead to more personalized cancer care and targeted treatment plans for improving quality of life in elderly cancer patients.</description><description>Le vieillissement, le cancer avancé et la cachexie d'origine cancéreuse sont des états qui partagent des symptômes communs. Puisque les personnes atteintes du cancer vivent plus longtemps, particulièrement celles âgées de 65 ans et plus, il est important de distinguer les différences visibles au niveau des marqueurs d'inflammation, de la composition corporelle, de la performance fonctionnelle et des profils métaboliques et nutritionnels qui caractérisent les trois états ci-haut mentionnés. En caractérisant les patients âgés atteints d'un cancer avancé, cette thèse se concentre sur deux sujets: 1) la validation des instruments de mesure de la composition corporelle et de la force musculaire; 2) l'application de ces instruments pour déterminer si les caractéristiques précédentes sont attribuées au vieillissement, au cancer avancé ou à la cachexie. Une meilleure connaissance de ces conditions peut amener à des soins personnalisés visant à améliorer la qualité de vie des patients âgés atteints du cancer.</description><creator>Trutschnigg, Barbara</creator><contributor>Jose A Morais (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Antonio Vigano (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</subject><title>Metabolic, nutritional, inflammatory, and functional performance characteristics in elderly patients with advanced gastrointestinal cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dc97p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t238h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kt343</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The push for educational reform in the province of Quebec,  Canada has brought to the foreground many ideas about what needs to be done to  improve the learning experience of students. While there has been some movement in  the primary grade levels, change in the secondary level is still in its infancy.  There are some teachers, however, in high schools who have been on the cutting edge  of educational reform. The purpose of this study is to look at participation within  a secondary classroom where the philosophy of the reform is being acted upon. The  study, qualitative in design, is a type of ethnographic investigation of a teacher  and students in a Grade VII language arts classroom. The classroom is a part of an  exclusive program, namely the Alternative Learning Program, nested in a public high  school in the Montreal area. Using various means of data collection such as field notes and  interviews, the researcher examines the various dimensions of participation as it  unfolds in this particular classroom. The researcher identifies these dimensions as  assigned and shared participation. The data suggests that dynamics beyond assigned  and shared participation are also evident. The dynamics, identified as participative  tone, contribute to student views of the uniqueness of this particular learning  environment. To present a trustworthy description of what is observed, however, the  investigator shows situations in which participation is not apparent. These  situations are identified as participative resistance. The researcher deduces that  participation and participative resistance need to be viewed as context-bound and  are, in many respects, points on a continuum. Attempts have been made in the research to allow the study  participants to express their views. Through interviews, students share in their own  words what participation means to them. Their words add depth to understanding of  what student participation is. The study suggests that notions of the child-centered  or student-centered classroom, while commendable, are not necessarily an aspiration  to strive for. The study affirms that the teacher plays a key position in the  classroom environment. The study begins by showing the various roles that the  teacher assumes in her daily practice. Views of the teacher are presented along with  perceptions of the students and the researcher to determine the various roles played  out in this site. The study concludes that the teacher conducts her practice by  exceeding the boundaries of her roles so identified. The study shows that the classroom does not stand in isolation,  but is subject to various influences from the school, as well as the community at  large. The researcher identifies these influences as context and conditions using  another site as a point of reference. The secondary sight brings clarity to what the  researcher observes. The researcher concludes that in addition to communal  influences, learning in the primary site takes place under the banner of what is  defined as an arts-oriented curriculum. The arts-oriented curriculum contributes to  the sense of community in the classroom. But data also suggest that the classroom  does not always function as a community. In spite of the teacher's good intentions,  tensions sometimes foster a competitive rather than collaborative spirit among the  students.</description><creator>Sturge Sparkes, E. Carolyn</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Arts -- Study and teaching (Secondary)</subject><subject>Teacher-student relationships</subject><subject>Classroom environment</subject><title>Being and becoming an 'I want to learn person' : participating in an arts-oriented learning environment : perception and context</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hj57p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kt343</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612p119</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Native peoples of North America still confront the  challenges of lingering colonial cultural imperialism. One such challenge is that of  Native education, and its unfortunate management by the European-descended political  powers. Using tactics such as assimilation, segregation and integration, the  establishment used schooling as a blunt tool to solve the so-called "Indian  problem"---that is, the assimilation of the Native population into the European  way of life. The results were predictably tragic; the current education system is  still perceived as a tool of colonization by many Natives. After so many failed attempts, policy-makers are finally looking  to return to the First Nations the education they need, not what North America  thinks they should have. One example of this is the proposal to create an  institution of higher learning within the Cree communities of Northern Quebec. This  dissertation examines the possible challenges and benefits of such a project. It  explores the relationship between Cree students and the current  "mainstream" education system by way of research, participant-observation  narrative and the voice of the Cree themselves while interviewed. Since they must travel to non-Native communities to pursue  higher education, Cree students typically deal with culture shock, alienation and no  small degree of racism while studying. In addition a commonality of experience  between the Cree and students of other Native communities while attending a  "white" school precipitates a pan-Indian/super-tribal perspective, which  becomes an important factor in their world view. Because this dissertation uses participant-observation and  interview methodologies for research, and because the subjects of the observation  and the interviews are Cree students, then it is necessary for this dissertation to  first survey the topics of Pan-Indian Identity and Culture Shock and put them into  context. In fact, a large part of the participant-observation narrative is that of  the author integrating into a Cree community as an educator. This narrative  essentially documents the author's own stages of culture shock, a mirror to that  which the Native student faces "down south" at college. These are examples  of the real anxieties and challenges faced when immersed in a new and different  culture. The Native perspective is provided by the Cree students  themselves in interviews that were fortunately rich in narrative recollection. In  addition to answering the standard interview questions, the interviewees offered  their own anecdotes, observations and insights into their experiences within the  "mainstream" education system. The conclusions drawn in this body of research may go towards  dealing with the legacy of Cree distrust towards an educational system possibly  perceived as an imposition of a colonizing society, and to answering the real needs  of Native students who are seeking to benefit from education, whatever its  form.</description><creator>Stonebanks, Christopher Darius</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Cree Indians -- Education, Higher -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Culture shock</subject><subject>Cree Indians -- Ethnic identity</subject><title>James Bay Cree students and higher education : issues of identity and culture shock</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zf00j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612p119</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418n712</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tuberculosis, caused by Mycobacterium tuberculosis, is globally  a leading cause of morbidity and mortality. While a host genetic contribution to  tuberculosis susceptibility is known to occur, the extent and nature of host genetic  variability to tuberculosis pathogenesis are unknown. Thus, to better understand the  role of host genetic factors in tuberculosis susceptibility, we have tested the  contribution of candidate gene variants to tuberculosis susceptibility in three  geographically, epidemically, and clinically distinct populations. We chose four  candidate genes involved in the innate immune response, namely, NRAMP1, MBL, SFTPA1,  and SFTPA2. Since the global spread of tuberculosis is highly dependent on  HIV/AIDS pandemic, we investigated the association of genetic MBL variants and HIV-1  infection in 278 Colombian HIV-infected and control individuals. MBL genotype  frequencies were similar for both groups, and no association was detected between  MBL alleles B, C, and D and susceptibility to HIV-1 infection (P = 1.0). These  results do not support the hypothesis that MBL levels are a risk factor for HIV-1  infection in Colombia. Moreover, we were able to show that MBL variants do not  contribute to tuberculosis susceptibility in this population. In a pediatric population composed of 184 families we found  allelic variants in the NRAMP1 gene to be associated with tuberculosis disease (P =  0.01; Odds ratio [OR] = 1.75 [95% confidence interval: 1.10--2.77]). Common NRAMP1  alleles were identified as risk factors for pediatric tuberculosis while these same  alleles were reported to be protective in adult cases, suggesting that the common  alleles promote rapid progression from infection to tuberculosis disease.  Furthermore, the association of NRAMP1 with pediatric tuberculosis disease was  significantly heterogeneous (P = 0.01) between simplex (P &lt; 0.0008; OR = 3.13  [1.54--6.25]) and multiplex families (P = 1) suggesting an interplay between  mechanisms of genetic control and exposure intensities. Finally, we tested the  correlation between the NRAMP1 risk and NRAMP1 functional activity by measuring the  recruitment efficiency of mannose-6-phosphate receptor (M6PR) to Salmonella  containing vacuoles (SCV) in monocyte-derived-macrophages (MDM). We show that  recruitment of M6PR to SCV is significantly lower ( P = 0.024) in MDM from patients  homozygous for the risk allele as compared to MDM from heterozygous patients. Thus,  altered function of NRAMP1 appears to modulate the rate of progression from  infection to disease.</description><creator>Malik, Suneil</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Genetics of host innate immune factors in Tuberculosis susceptibility</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t906v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418n712</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f1642</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Canadians faced an unprecedented threat after the Second World  War. Located between two competing superpowers Canada could become the battlefield  of a third world war. How did Canadians respond to the nuclear threat? The  government of John Diefenbaker warned that millions of Canadians could die in a  nuclear war. It strengthened Canada's contribution to the defence of North America  and Europe and dedicated more resources to civil defence. Between 1957 and 1963 the  domestic issue of nuclear arms acquisition and growing cold war tensions combined to  draw attention to the threat. Newly founded anti-nuclear groups as well as Canadian  unions, newspapers, magazines, student groups, churches and community organizations  confronted nuclear issues. These groups shared a concern about survival but reached  different conclusions about how Canada could avoid nuclear devastation. Their  attempts to come to terms with the threat of nuclear war highlight broader themes in  the history of postwar Canada including the influence of the cold war on the  attitudes and behaviours of Canadians and the nation's relationship with the United  States. While more Canadians discussed the nuclear threat in these years  the majority did not join the debate. Polls showed the public supported a nuclear  defence. They believed few would survive a nuclear attack but did not worry about  nuclear war. Economic concerns always ranked higher. The public was, on the whole,  not mobilized either in preparation or in protest. Diefenbaker questioned what else  he could do to increase public concern about survival. Both the civil defence  program and the nuclear disarmament movement struggled. Polls showed that most  Canadians did nothing to prepare for a war fought at home. Anti-nuclear groups  remained small, divided over their platforms and methods and faced financial  constraints. The debate about survival grew in the period between 1957 and 1963 but  was dominated by elected officials, civil defence authorities and anti-nuclear  activists. Even these groups found it difficult to balance the Soviet threat with  the risk of a nuclear war and struggled to achieve policies that would provide  security for the nation and its population.</description><creator>Hunter, Jennifer Lynn</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Antinuclear movement -- Canada -- History</subject><subject>Civil defense -- Canada -- History</subject><subject>Cold War</subject><subject>Canada -- Defenses -- History -- 20th century</subject><title>"Is it even worthwhile doing the dishes?" : Canadians and the nuclear threat, 1945-1963</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b5918991.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f1642</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hj56d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to grasp an object, the human nervous system must  transform the intended hand displacement into control signals distributed to motor  neurons and ultimately to muscles. The aim of this thesis is to describe the nature  of the internal representations that the human motor system uses to perform reaching  movements. The aim of the first study was to provide a clear and simple way  to test whether dynamical information is coded by the nervous system in an  extrinsic, Cartesian, versus intrinsic, muscle- or joint-based, system of  coordinates. As a means to determine the frame for reference used by the motor  system, we examined how adaptation to externally applied forces transfers across  different arm configurations. We trained subjects to make reaching movements while  holding a robotic arm that applied forces proportional and perpendicular to the  tangential velocity of the hand. While in the first trials hand paths were  substantially deviated, subjects rapidly adapted to the new dynamic condition; they  learned to compensate for the forces in order to restore the kinematics observed in  the absence of load. Learning of the new dynamics transferred across movements  performed in different regions of the workspace when the relation between joint  displacements and experienced torques remained unchanged, rather than when the  mapping between hand displacements and forces was preserved. This provided support  to the idea that dynamics are encoded in muscle- or joint-based  coordinates. The results of the first study described a process of  generalization that relies on the invariance of the mapping between torques and  joint displacements. While this clearly points to an intrinsic coding of dynamics,  it does not explain whether or how generalization over the workspace occurs when the  pattern of torques changes with the configuration of the arm. In the second study,  subjects learned a force field in which the forces acted always in the same  direction relative to an external frame of reference, which defines a mapping  between joint displacements and torques that varies with the configuration of the  arm. Our idea was to test if in the absence of invariance in the pattern of torques,  generalization would occur on the basis of the invariance in the direction of the  forces represented in an extrinsic system of coordinates. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</description><creator>Malfait, Nicole</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Neuromuscular transmission.</subject><subject>Dynamics</subject><subject>Learning.</subject><subject>Motor ability.</subject><title>Characteristics of dynamics learning and generalization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n384w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hj56d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731446q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phrase 'Covenant Chain' is unique in the English language  and along with its antecedents---'linked arms', 'the rope', and the 'iron  chain'---the Haudenosaunee established relationships with the Europeans. The  'Covenant Chain' has been the subject of extensive discussion since the mid-1980s  when a group of scholars in Iroquois Studies published several volumes on the  diplomacy of the Haudenosaunee during the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries. Most  studies focus on the political aspects of the Covenant Chain and the role it played  in creating and sustaining alliances. This study examines the meaning of the word  'covenant' and related ideas in the context of Haudenosaunee cosmology, history,  culture and religious traditions. The numerous metaphors employed by the  Haudenosaunee in council oratory and the many meanings associated with these  different metaphors are discussed with a view to better understanding the Covenant  Chain in relation to what Mohawk scholar Deborah Doxtator calls 'history as an  additive process'. In order to facilitate this discussion, the religious dimensions  of covenant in European thought during this period are examined. While the basis of  post-Reformation covenant theology differs radically from Haudenosaunee ideas of  covenant, points of convergence do exist particularly in the area of political  theory making. Johannes Althusius' (1557-1638) concept of 'symbiosis' is one such  example. Surprisingly, Europeans who were involved in or who had knowledge of the  Covenant Chain provide no theological discourse on it. Philosophical and theological  discussions of the chain come from the Haudenosaunee themselves. These relationships went well beyond contractual obligations and  along with the idea of the 'middle line' which separates people and at the same time  joins them together. Contrary to the widely accepted scholarly view that the  chain---either the 'Covenant Chain' or the 'Iron Chain'---was associated only with  alliances between the Haudenosaunee and the British, this study shows that the  Haudenosaunee used the same expressions in their alliances with the French as  well.</description><creator>Johnston, Louise</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Iroquois Indians -- Government relations</subject><subject>Iroquois Indians -- Religion</subject><title>The covenant chain of peace : metaphor and religious thought in seventeenth century Haudenosaunee council oratory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r844w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731446q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gn654</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis analyzes Viktor Pelevin's Chapaev i Pustota (1996)  from the perspective of its (extra-)literary context, and status as a threshold text  on various levels. It argues that through the expression of satire, parody, and  nostalgia, Pelevin's novel exemplifies and transcends the threshold between the  Soviet and post-Soviet literary narrative. Against the background of various  comparison texts, by such precursors and contemporaries as Kaledin, Makanin,  Petrushevskaia, P'ietsukh, Sorokin and Tolstaia, Pelevin's novel is shown both to  conform with and diverge from the (post-)glasnost' literary text. Common features on  the levels of theme and motif are identified, in order to establish both the notion  of literary threshold, and a link to its extra-literary counterpart, in keeping with  the crises of national transition from late- to post-Soviet status. Using Bakhtinian  theory as a point of departure, the notion of threshold is identified on various  levels of Pelevin's text, including theme, motif, and bifurcated structure in the  form of dual time frames and plotlines. Through satire, Pelevin is shown to  reconcile the notion of threshold as change, with that of frozen  transition. Overtly parodic, Chapaev i Pustota manipulates three principal  constructs of Socialist Realism: the positive hero, the mentor/disciple  relationship, and the spontaneity/consciousness dialectic. The thesis traces the  role and development of these constructs in the four (un-)official versions of the  so-called 'Chapaev myth' before examining Pelevin's own manipulation of the  constructs against three distinct models of parody by Gary Saul Morson, Linda  Hutcheon, and the Russian Formalists. As an aesthetic manifestation of the extra-literary threshold  state, the expression of nostalgia is examined in various texts of the  (post-)glasnost' period. Pelevin's parody and satire of nostalgic expression attests  to the evolution in his novel from Socialist Realism to sots-art, and  beyond.</description><creator>Steiger, Krystyna</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Pelevin, Viktor. Chapaev i pustota</subject><subject>Parody in literature</subject><subject>Satire</subject><title>Satire, parody, and nostalgia on the threshold : Viktor Pelevin's Chapaev i Pustota in the context of its times</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b6520.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gn654</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405s9824</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Understanding the origins of biological diversity is a  fundamental goal of evolutionary biology. A large body of theory attributes  ecological and genetic diversification to divergent natural selection for resource  specialization. This thesis examines adaptive radiation in response to selection for  resource specialization in microcosm populations of the asexual bacterium  Pseudomonas fluorescens. The general protocol for these experiments is to introduce  a clonal population of Pseudomonas into a novel environment and to allow evolution  to occur through the spontaneous appearance of novel genotypes carrying beneficial  mutations. Adaptation can then be quantified through direct comparisons between  evolved populations and their clonal ancestors. These experiments show that resource  heterogeneity generates divergent natural selection for specialization on  alternative resources, irrespective of the spatial structure of the environment.  Adaptive radiation is possible in sympatry because of genetic trade-offs in the  ability to exploit different resources, but these trade-offs are often not the  result of antagonistic pleiotropy among loci that determine fitness on alternative  resources. The rate of phenotypic diversification declines during adaptive  radiation, apparently because the ecological opportunities required to support  specialist lineages disappear as a consequence of initial diversification. The  ultimate outcome of repeated instances of adaptive radiation is the evolution of a  community of ecologically equivalent specialists that share similar adaptive traits,  despite differences in the underlying genetic basis of specialization in replicate  radiations. Comparisons with the literature on experimental evolution in microbial  populations illustrate the results of this thesis are well-supported by experiments  in a wide range of microbial microcosms.</description><creator>MacLean, Roderick Craig</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Pseudomonas fluorescens -- Adaptation</subject><subject>Microbial populations</subject><subject>Resource partitioning (Ecology)</subject><title>Adaptive radiation and the evolution of resource specialization in experimental populations of Pseudomonas fluorescens</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rf04q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405s9824</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45q942z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Drawing upon a review of literature and interviews with four  artist-teachers, this thesis explores the implications of post-modernism on the  studio teaching of painting. Additional emphasis is placed on uncovering the issue  of the-death-of-painting and its links to post-modernism, and my own reflexivity as  a painter and a teacher of art. The thesis presents also an attempt to respond to an  apparent lack of educational research that addresses post-secondary studio teaching  of art, and that engages artist-teachers in reflection on their teaching  philosophies. The overall objective of this thesis is to generate a body of  knowledge that could be of assistance to other practitioners in the field in their  own pedagogical reflections and development of contemporary studio instruction. Thus  the questions and ideas brought in this study present both an invitation and  directions for future inquiries in this area of education.</description><creator>Spicanovic, Vladimir</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Painting -- Study and teaching</subject><subject>Postmodernism</subject><title>Pedagogical reflections : post-modernism in the studio teaching of painting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gg887.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45q942z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c8007</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The neuronal system that generates saccadic eye movements has  been well studied over the last three decades. However, this system has been  extensively characterized only in the simplified case where the head is kept  immobile, and the two eyes rotate identically (conjugate saccades). In everyday  life, we often need to rotate our eyes differently when looking between objects  located at different depths (disjunctive saccades), and we often utilize eye and  head movements to reorient to objects of interest (gaze shifts). In the present  thesis, we describe a series of experiments that were aimed at determining the role  of the brainstem saccadic burst generator, a key element of the saccadic subsystem,  during these more complex movements. With respect to disjunctive saccades, a very influential theory  (Hering's theory) was proposed a century ago in which the brainstem saccadic burst  generator [including excitatory (EBN) and inhibitory (IBN) brainstem saccadic burst  neurons, and omnipause (OPN) neurons], and burst-tonic neurons (BT) only encode  conjugate saccades. Here, we clearly demonstrate that this theory does not apply  during disjunctive saccades. We have found that the discharge dynamics of the  premotor neurons described above reflect the asymmetry in eye movements that is  characteristic of disjunctive saccades. Moreover, we show that these signals are  sufficient to shape the activity of motoneurons in the abducens  nucleus. We also demonstrate that during eye-head gaze shifts, the same  EBNs, IBNs and OPNs encode the movements of the head as well as those of the eyes.  To do so, we designed a sophisticated paradigm in which head movements could be  perturbed during gaze shifts, while we simultaneously recorded the activity of  isolated neurons. This highly challenging experiment has allowed us to conclusively  demonstrate that neuronal activity with the brainstem saccadic burst generator  reflects the artificial perturbations applied to the head. In summary, the studies described in this thesis have unmasked a  new role for the brainstem saccadic burst generator in the generation of disjunctive  saccades. They have also confirmed its role in the control of eye-head gaze shifts.  We conclude that the brainstem saccadic burst generator does far more than  generating conjugate saccades, and that it is in fact involved in controlling the  movements of the two eyes in space.</description><creator>Sylvestre, Pierre Alexandre</creator><contributor>Cullen, Kathleen E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>A new view of the saccadic burst generator : the coordination of multiple effectors during disjunctive saccades and eye-head gaze shifts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278t53m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c8007</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43500</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>