<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:23:29Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33650" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q566j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cosmological constant is historically reviewed from its introduction in classical and relativistic cosmology through its modern quantum guise where it appears as a vacuum energy density. Limits on the empirical value are in glaring contradiction to the expectations of field theoretical calculations. Motivated by the natural connection between dilatation invariance and the extinction of the vacuum energy density, a phenomenological realization of a global scale symmetry is constructed. A complete treatment of such a realization in the context of a supergravitational toy model is calculated to one loop using an effective potential formalism. Particular attention is paid to the quantization of both supersymmetric and general coordinate gauges and to the concomitant ghost structure since traditional treatments have introduced non-local operators in the ghost Lagrangian and generating functional. Contributions to the effective potentid from the gravity sector are thus determined that contradict the literature. A particular class of tree-level scalar potentials that includes the 'no-scale' case is studied in the that space limit. While it is found that scale invariance can be maintained at the one-loop level and the cosmological constant made to vanish for all potentials in the class this is directly attributable to supersymmetry. A richer form of the Kahler potential or an enlarged particle content may facilitate the breaking of supersymmetry. Phenomenological consequences of supergravity are investigated through a one-loop calculation of the electromagnetic form factor of the gravitino. Should such a form factor exist a signature of the gravitino might be found in processes with unlabeled products such as $e sp+e sp- to nothing.$ It is found that the form factor vanishes to this order, the Lorentz structures generated being too impoverished to withstand a constraining set of polarization conditions. Finally the wormhole solution to the cosmological constant problem is examined in a semiclassical approximation. The notion that scalar field worm-holes must have associated conserved charges is questioned and a model of massive scalar field wormholes is delineated and proven to provide a counterexample. As the model allows baby universes nucleated with a certain eigenvalue of the scalar field momentum to classically evolve to a different value, competing semiclassical paths contribute to the same transition amplitude. Numerical simulations demonstrate that the novel semiclassical paths available to massive solutions cannot be overlooked in approximating the tunneling amplitude.</description><creator>Hagan, Scott</creator><contributor>Burgess, C. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><subject>Physics, Astronomy and Astrophysics.</subject><title>Scale invariant and topological approaches to the cosmological constant problem</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dx03s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q566j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j707w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study implemented an experimental design to investigate the impact of psychotherapists' transient affective states (mood) on the formulation of client problem and on treatment recommendations. Moderating influence of personality traits and situational factors was also explored. Thirty-two counseling interns participated in a between-subject experiment which compared the impact of 20 minutes of positive or negative mood inductions (achieved by exposure to a humorous or a conflictive film segment) upon their assessment of stimulus material consisting of a 20-minute segment of an initial counseling interview. Three measures were obtained prior to mood induction: (a) background information consisting of demographic data, theoretical orientation, and clinical experience, (b) the Life Events Report (LER) measuring level of satisfaction in various life areas and self-reported actual mood, and (c) the Eysenck Personality Inventory (EPI) to define levels of Extraversion and Neuroticism. Immediately following mood induction a double mood check was obtained through rating of the film just watched, and the Profile of Mood States (POMS). Finally, the Client Assessment Form (CAF) was administered immediately after exposure to the stimulus material in order to obtain an assessment of the client and ensuing treatment recommendations. Although a series of univariate analyses of variance failed to reveal between-group differences, multivariate statistical tests showed significant differences relative to client assessment. Results indicated that mood and current life events accounted for a substantial percentage of the variance for the assessment variables considered. Findings suggest that negative mood (distressed) clinicians assess global severity in less serious terms than positive mood (nondistressed) clinicians. Clinicians reporting current negative life events (stressed clinicians) assess client problems in less serious terms than clinicians reporting current positive life events (nonstressed clinicians). Additionally, a post-hoc exploratory series of two-way univariate analyses of variance showed unexpected biasing effects of mood on the assessment produced by psychodynamicists relative to their humanist counterparts. Findings of this study support the main hypotheses in that they show significant differences in assessment ability attributable to clinicians' mood and current life events. In addition, post-hoc data analyses suggest that clinicians with certain theoretical approaches may be more sensitive to the biasing effects of mood than others.</description><creator>Herskovitz-Kelner, Nora</creator><contributor>Dumont, Florence (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Psychotherapist and patient</subject><subject>Psychotherapists -- Psychology</subject><title>The influence of psychotherapists' mood, personality traits, and life events on clinical formulations and treatment recommendations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526d911.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j707w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm51w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the nature of an electronic medium known as hypertext in relation to the act and experience of writing and expression. Essential to the thesis is a conviction that the experiential realm that is created by a particular medium of communication and/or representation is capable of also creating new 'habits of mind' or 'worldings.' These two concepts are indicative of the intensity of experience that is made available via an expressive act and the extent to which the various aspects of this intensity are capable of transformations on personal and public levels. One of the central issues of the thesis is an ongoing re-evaluation of the euphoric claims that trumpet hypertext as usurping the so-called tyranny of the book and the domain of linear thinking in general. In many evaluations of the medium, hypertext is commonly presented as a communications medium that offers a far greater panorama of choices and freedoms than does the printed word and, in addition, is far closer to the way in which the human mind 'actually works.' One of the intentions of this project is to not only critique and study such claims but also to explore their numerous offshoots with respect to cultural, philosophical and ideological practices and techniques. Thus, this thesis unfolds via four major thematic clusters that each, in its own way, challenges and probes at the emerging medium of hypertext as it relates to the activity and cultural practice of writing itself. The first of these clusters is organized around the challenges and problems of constructing an appropriate interpretive methodology with which to approach hypertext. The second cluster offers an analysis of hypertext's defining characteristics and their relation to melancholy, isolation and anxiety. What follows is an analysis of the major figures in the history of hypertext and their relationship to the dynamics of power and knowledge. The thesis concludes with a meditation on how the act of writing (electronic or otherwise) has profound implications on the very structure and form of the creative human mind and world.</description><creator>Kitzmann, Andreas Gernot</creator><contributor>Massumi, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Literature and technology</subject><subject>Hypertext systems -- Philosophy</subject><title>The melancholic hypertext : the fate of the writer in the tangential narrative</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jq38v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm51w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vd137</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work challenges common arguments as to the division of the political from other fictional genres and, in treatments of nineteenth-century fiction and culture, the private from the public sphere. Through an examination of works by Mary Wollstonecraft, Amelia Opie, Maria Edgeworth, and Elizabeth Gaskell, I uncover a common concern with the preconditions of liberal selfhood which posits the household as the space in which the political rights-bearer, defined by interiority and mental qualities, comes to be. This rights-bearer is not, as has been argued, defined by purely formal and abstract procedural reason, but in terms of a capacity for reason which includes the capacity for emotion. This work therefore shows domestic space to be the foundation of, rather than the occluded counterpart to, the liberal polity, and argues that an account of the household, in which the liberal self is disclosed, is likewise at the centre of Victorian political fiction.</description><creator>Johnston, Susan, 1964-</creator><contributor>Bristol, Michael D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Political fiction, English -- History and criticism</subject><subject>Women in literature</subject><subject>English fiction -- 19th century -- History and criticism</subject><title>Calling the question : women and domestic experience in British political fictions, 1787-1869</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r9400.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd137</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x26d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ocean currents flowing through the earth's main magnetic field are known to induce secondary magnetic fields. Hence, variations in the ocean circulation induce variations in the net magnetic field. This research is aimed at exploring the potential for using geomagnetic data to study variability in ocean circulation and climate. First, general relativity theory is used to formally establish the proper set of electromagnetic equations to be used for observers in a rotating (accelerating) frame of reference observing a medium (the ocean, in this case) with relative velocity. Extra terms due to rotation are derived and described and a generalized Schiff's charge density is shown to be potentially significant for the application to ocean circulation. We extend the theory of electromagnetic fields generated by ocean currents. Many analytical solutions are found for idealized ocean features including sheared flow, jets, and a Stommel gyre. Results indicate that the ocean-induced magnetic fields will typically have magnitudes of 10's-100's of nT within the ocean. Outside of the ocean, the magnitudes are smaller (typically 1-10 nT) but decay on scales set by the horizontal scale of the ocean feature. We investigate the time-scales associated with the adjustment of electromagnetic fields generated by low-frequency ocean currents. We find that the time scales can be quite long, prohibiting a quasistatic assumption in the treatment of the electromagnetic fields generated by the important tidal, inertial, and diurnal-frequency ocean currents. Three-dimensional explicit time-dependent and steady-state finite-difference numerical models are constructed to study the electromagnetic fields generated by more realistic ocean current and conductivity features. The ocean currents generate electromagnetic forces on the fluid at the surface of the earth's core. If these forces lead to significant core motion, the effect of the oceans on the generation and variability of the earth's magnetic field may be nontrivial. We estimate the form and magnitude of these forces and make comparisons with observations. Despite many uncertainties, we find evidence to suggest the ocean forcing mechanism may be significant and conclude that this process should be further investigated in the context of a larger study. This work indicates that it is likely that the geomagnetic record has captured oceanic signals. From a preliminary data analyses we find that aside from the oceanic tidal signals, the magnetic record shows other signals of possible oceanic origin including an apparent correlation between magnetic records from the equatorial Pacific and the Southern Oscillation Index. We discuss the prerequisites that are necessary to extract information about ocean circulation variability from the geomagnetic record.</description><creator>Tyler, Robert H.</creator><contributor>Mysak, Lawrence (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Geophysics.</subject><subject>Physics, Electricity and Magnetism.</subject><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>Electromagnetic fields generated by ocean currents and the potential for using geomagnetic data in ocean and climate studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z004w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x26d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv228</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis concerns the origins, creation and progress of the International Development Research Centre (IDRC). Most scholars believe that development assistance is largely motivated by self-interest. At first glance, the Centre appears to be an anomaly in Canadian foreign aid. The IDRC's disbursements are not formally tied, has an international board of governors, and its structure was specifically designed with autonomy in mind. This Canadian federal organisation has spent one and a half billion dollars are funded over 5,500 projects since its founding in 1970. During this time, the Centre has disbursed between 70-95% of its programme funds overseas, mostly to developing country university researchers. These researchers have designed and executed research intended to help developing countries alleviate poverty, social decay and more recently, environmental challenges. A detailed archeology is conducted of Pearson's own internationalism regarding science and technology, foreign policy, development assistance, environment and culture. Our analysis shows how Pearson's thinking, and that of colleagues who were to have key influences on the Centre, Barbara Ward and Maurice Strong, were embedded in deeply held beliefs and values. We identify a tension between an internationalist impulses and Canadian-centered or parochial pre-occupations common in most of the federal public service, especially central agencies. Central agents, responding to pressures from academics, and the internal values and beliefs that tend to form in these secretaria, have sought to make the IDRC conform to their own expectations. The author concludes that the Centre has survived and prospered, despite these pressures, partly because of the skill of its top officers, but principally because of the IDRC's capacity to lay claim to being an expression of internationalism. We also show how another dialectic, between more socially-oriented perspectives and more technical ones affected the development of the IDRC. The thesis suggests that the two dialectics, the internationalist and parochial, and the technical and social, are both synthesising into, respectively, interdependence and holism.</description><creator>Stockdale, Peter</creator><contributor>Noumoff, Samuel J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Economic assistance, Canadian</subject><subject>International Development Research Centre (Canada) -- History</subject><title>Pearsonian internationalism in practice : the International Development Research Centre</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430637k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv228</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r2672</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The neuropathogenicity of two retroviruses was investigated. The human immunodeficiency virus, in addition to its profound effect on the immune system, also causes degenerative changes in the brain, the spinal cord and peripheral nerves. In order to elucidate how it affects the nervous system, transgenic mice were generated that express the entire HIV genome in neurons in the anterior thalamus and in the anterior horn of the spinal cord, and examined clinically, neuropsychologically, electrophysiologically and histologically. Animals developed a neurological syndrome characterized by hypoactivity and weakness, and by axonal degeneration in peripheral nerves. These results provide evidence for a role of HIV in affecting both the central and peripheral nervous systems. In a second project, pathological effects associated with a disease determining region contained in the gp70 envelope protein of the Cas-Br-E murine leukemia virus, were investigated. In infected mice, this virus causes hind limb paralysis and a spongiform myeloencephalopathy with gliosis and neuronal loss. Stably transfected fibroblasts that express gp70 were injected into the brains of mice, and the animals were examined for histopathological changes attributable to the effects of gp70. While gp70 protein was detected at the implantation site, this was not accompanied by any specific histological changes. These data suggest that the intracerebral expression of the neuropathogenic gp70 protein alone is not sufficient to cause disease, and lend indirect support to a model according to which gp70 causes disease by altering the cytokine profile of infected mononuclear cells in the central nervous system.</description><creator>Thomas, Kurt Florian Patrick</creator><contributor>Jolicoeur, Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Animal models of retroviral neurological diseases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0324604.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r2672</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515p928</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of buffer additives in capillary electrophoresis (CE) separations of various biologically important molecules were studied. Buffers containing $ beta$-cyclodextrin ($ beta$-CD) and borate were used to separate mixtures of monophosphorylated nucleotide isomers. The electrophoretic mobility of nucleotide isomers was altered as a result of selective complex-forming reactions with $ beta$-CD. In addition, complexation of 5$ sp prime$-nucleotides with borate increased the migration time window and led to better separation. Mono- and di-phosphorylated isomers of the insulin receptor peptide (IRP), were resolved in buffers containing sodium dodecyl sulfate, (SDS). The effects of SDS concentration and pH on electrophoretic velocity and resolution were investigated. The use of polyacrylamide coated capillaries resulted in increased resolution and decreased analysis time. The effects of various detergents on the electrophoretic behaviour of plasma apolipoproteins in uncoated and polyacrylamide coated capillaries were studied. Interaction between apolipoproteins and detergents was strongly influenced by the nature of the polar head group of the detergent. Capillaries coated with various crosslinked hydrophillic polymers were prepared. Coatings based on poly(2-hydroxyethylmethacrylate) crosslinked with dimethylol ethylene urea exhibited the best performance for CE separations of basic proteins.</description><creator>Tadey, Tanya</creator><contributor>Purdy, William C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><title>Effects of buffer modifiers and polymeric surface coatings in capillary electrophoresis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vj347.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515p928</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354g88p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This investigation explored special education and mainstreaming in the social-historical context of U.S. general formal public education and society from the American Revolution to 1990. Its main purpose was to examine the obstacles to and prospects of 'purposeful' mainstreaming in this wider context. First, special education was placed in the context of general education and society. Second, the objectives of general education were viewed historically to examine the influence of evolving societal conditions on special education. Third, the outcomes of PL 94-142 (Education for All Handicapped Children Act) from its passage to the late 1980s were explored in conjunction with the various models and practices of mainstreaming. Fourth, the meaning of the 1980s' 'excellence' reforms were scrutinized. It was found that: (1) the concept of 'society as primarily an economic entity' has had a decisive influence on the objectives of U.S. formal education and special education; (2) special education has functioned mainly as a means of educational amelioration and social control; (3) there have been three major waves of reform in special education arrangements in U.S. history--in the first two waves the element of social control outlasted the element of educational remediation; (4) the latest wave of special education reform, led primarily by the federal government and corporate business and targeting disadvantaged students and their families, has commenced since the 1960s; and (5) the principal mode of reform for the latest wave appears to be 'interagency collaboration' which has inherent elements of educational improvement and social control. Implications of these findings for 'purposeful' mainstreaming are discussed. Based on the suggestion that the obstacles to mainstreaming be situated in the wider social-historical context of the U.S. society, several recommendations are given for strategic planning and more meaningful reform.</description><creator>Karagiannis, Anastasios</creator><contributor>Cartwright, Glenn F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Mainstreaming in education -- United States.</subject><subject>Special education -- United States</subject><title>The social-historical context of special education and mainstreaming in the United States from independence to 1990</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k6787.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354g88p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z2483</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explored the influence of fish behavior and distribution on the accuracy and precision of quantitative estimates of fish biomass and abundance as assessed by hydroacoustic techniques. Rainbow smelt (Osmerus mordax), a pelagic fish known to undertake diel vertical migrations and to exhibit changes in aggregation intensity associated with these movements was used as the model species for this study. The diel vertical migrations of smelt resulted in their potential inaccessibility to the acoustic gear. To obviate this problem a model of the diel migration of smelt based on observations of their behavioral responses to ambient light and water temperatures, was developed and used to time acoustic estimates of fish biomass and abundance to periods when they were unbiased by inaccessibility. Acoustic surveys were then conducted to evaluate the direct influence of fish aggregation on estimates of fish abundance, and to examine the effect of changes in fish distributions on the statistical validity of acoustic analyses. Comparative acoustic surveys, conducted when fish were schooled and dispersed, showed abundance was underestimated by up to 50% when schooling prevailed. The influence of changes in the level of fish patchiness, induced by diel schooling, on the statistical precision of acoustic estimates of abundance and biomass was found to be insignificant. Cluster sampling, a robust approach to the inherent problems of transect sampling created by autocorrelated data series was applied to acoustic data for the first time and its effectiveness was assessed. Cluster sampling yielded estimates of biomass and of abundance that were more precise than were estimates based on the traditional approach of analyzing complete transects.</description><creator>Appenzeller, Alfred R. (Alfred Rudolf)</creator><contributor>Leggett, W. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Fish populations -- Measurement</subject><subject>Rainbow smelt</subject><subject>Fishes -- Behavior</subject><subject>Echo sounding in fishing</subject><subject>Fishes -- Geographical distribution</subject><title>On the application of hydroacoustic methods to analyses of the distribution and abundance of pelagic fishes : behavioral and statistical considerations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429b814.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z2483</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j955c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We study the behavior of a simple cubic crystal interface through the analysis and simulation of the Ising model in three dimensions; we use an algorithm which permits local temperature variations by emulating thermal diffusion. We derive a description of the interface based on the thermal fluctuation population at equilibrium and then use it to identify the equilibrium and dynamic roughening transitions observed under a variety of circumstances including a planar interface at equilibrium, a metastable bulk inclusion, an evaporating inclusion and a planar interface in the presence of a driving force. We also study strongly driven interfaces which exhibit an instability and pattern formation behaviour known as the Mullins-Sekerka instability. We use a special two-dimensional version of the simulation model to examine the linear growth of unstable modes of a driven interface; we compare our simulation data to theoretical predictions for the cases of an unstable flat interface and circular disk interface. Returning to the fully three-dimensional code, we present simulation data of late-time dendrites growth, including an analysis of the information available in the thermal fields. We also show that, at low temperatures, the tips of dendrites are facetted and demonstrate a response to the driving force which is consistent with the dynamic roughening transition.</description><creator>Jörgenson, Loki Michael</creator><contributor>Harris, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Simulation studies of cubic crystal interfaces : instabilities and transitions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dx05b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j955c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jz848</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is focused upon the development of the computer as a communication medium in history. To accomplish this, the computer is understood as constructed by language and technology where these are in turn grounded upon their roles as forms of cultural mediation. As methodology is of paramount importance, the digital medium is heuristically employed to discuss the epistemic and phenomenological significance of communications media. The more general inference therefore concerns the role of socially constructed media in the fabric of cultural development. In addressing this concern, the paper finds that communications media stand as the repositories of knowledge in the form of artificial memory and figurative technique. The computer then, as a medium in history, may arguably be declared as a paradigmatic instantiation of this role.</description><creator>Devon, Terrence J. (Terrence John)</creator><contributor>Crowley, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Computers -- History</subject><subject>Computers -- Social aspects</subject><title>Language, media, and the concept of a machine : toward a unified theory of communication in history</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903155g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz848</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f288v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The morphology and properties of polymer blends are closely related to processing conditions. The minor phase dimensions usually range from 0.1 to 10 $ mu$m. A skin/core morphology, with a minor phase undergoing variations in orientation and aspect ratio from the surface to the core of the material is observed in processes such as the injection molding of blends. The use of optical inspection is a potential tool to control the stability and the quality of the product on-line. In this thesis, polymer composites made from different glass fibers and glass microspheres embedded in a matrix of PS are used to simulate two-phase polymer blend morphology with a skin/core configuration. Two apparatuses have been used to characterize the morphology of the specimen by light scattering in reflection. The first had an incident light beam at 45 degrees from a normal to the surface of the sample. The second apparatus projected the laser beam incident perpendicularly on the surface of the sample and used polarized light. Distinctive reflected light scattering patterns were obtained in both cases and analyzed. In the first case, ratios of the axes of the ellipsoidal iso-intensity curves were plotted as a function of the position from the center of the light beam. The anisotropy of the iso-intensity lines is also plotted as a function of the position of the center of the beam for the second case. In both situations, information is obtained from the change of the anisotropy ratio as function of the distance from the center of the beam for depth-varying morphology samples. The skin, and the core content as well as the skin thickness effect can be isolated from the processed images. The second technique gave more information and patterns which were easier to process. A Monte Carlo program was written to simulate the propagation of photons in the samples containing a spherical morphology. The simulation is a potential tool for the analysis or two-phase systems but requires further development to be a useful tool.</description><creator>Bélanger, Christian</creator><contributor>Patterson, W. I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Characterization of polymer blend morphology from patterns of reflected scattered light</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w37638608.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f288v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t075j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Eukaryotic cellular mRNAs have a 5$ sp prime$ cap structure (m7GpppX) that facilitates their binding to ribosomes and is required for efficient translation. An initiation factor, elF-4F, mediates the function of the cap and consists of three subunits. elF-4E, one of the subunits which binds the cap directly, is present in the cell in limiting amounts. We demonstrated that overexpression of elF-4E in NIH 3T3 and Rat 2 fibroblasts causes their tumorigenic transformation. We have also shown that elF-4E cooperates with an immortalizing, nuclear oncogene (ie. v-myc or E1A) to cause transformation of rat embryo fibroblasts. These findings categorize elF-4E as a proto-oncogene. The mode of transformation by elF-4E is similar to that of Ras-like proteins. To further elucidate the mechanism of elF-4E transformation we determined Ras activity in elF-4E transformed REFs. We detected an activation of Ras in eIF-4E overexpressing cells as compared to parental REFs. In addition, overexpression of GAP (GTPase activating-protein), a negative regulator of Ras, suppressed the transformation of REFs by elF-4E. In summary we have established an important link between Ras, which plays a key role in cellular signal transduction, and elF-4E which is a critical component of the translation machinery.</description><creator>Lazaris-Karatzas, Anthoula</creator><contributor>Sonenberg, Nahum (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Eukaryotic translation initiation factor 4E : its characterization as a proto-oncogene and mechanism of action</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666614h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t075j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d585s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Presented in this thesis are novel methodologies for the analysis and optimization of planar, spherical, and spatial linkages associated with the problems of function generation, path generation, and rigid-body guidance. An up-to-date literature survey in the area of mechanism optimization is also provided in the thesis. Both the input-output (I/O) equation and the I/O curve are employed in the input-output analysis of four-bar linkages. Based on these, the properties of a special class of linkage, the constant-branch linkage, as well as its engineering application are discussed. Two schemes are developed for the optimization of function-generating linkages, namely, a constrained least-square procedure using slack variables and an unconstrained method based on I/O curve planning. The issue of data-conditioning is also discussed so that singularities can be avoided in the optimization procedure. With the help of linkage coordinate systems defined in this thesis, equations governing the coupler-link motion are derived for both path generation and rigid-body guidance. In the optimization of path-generating and rigid-body guiding linkages, a two-loop scheme based on a constrained least-square procedure is first proposed. Then, as an extension to I/O curve planning in function generation, a method resorting to input-output-coupler (I/O-C) curve planning is developed for path generation and rigid-body guidance. Using unconstrained approaches, this method simplifies the optimization procedure to a great extent.</description><creator>Liu, Zheng, 1962-</creator><contributor>Angeles, Jorge (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Kinematic optimization of linkages</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462711j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d585s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kp717</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the wake of the abolition of the Caliphate in the Islamic world with the advent of the Mongols in the 13th century, Islamic scholarship paradoxically flourished, especially in the Shi'i milieu. This era marked a renaissance which has influenced the course of Shii thought ever since. Through its major thinkers, i.e. Ibn Sa'ada, 'Ali ibn Sulayman and Maytham, the school of Bahrain contributed vigorously to this renaissance by integrating philosophy and mysticism into Shi'ism. Yet, the writings of this school are barely known to modern scholarship and many are still in manuscript form. Drawing upon both published and unpublished sources, this study reveals the importance of this school by offering a descriptive and historical analysis of this intellectual contribution to philosophy, theology and mysticism. It also demonstrates that the school of Bahrain was the first Shii school to derive its rational infra-structure in a unique way from a diversity of sources ranging from the Mu'tazili and Ash'ari theology to the Ibn Sinian philosophy and Ibn al-'Arabis mysticism. Its originality thus lies in its synthetic methodology and its interpretation of Shii literature in light of speculative sciences.</description><creator>Oraibi, Ali</creator><contributor>Landolt, Hermann (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Shīʻah -- Bahrain</subject><subject>Philosophy, Islamic -- Bahrain</subject><title>Shīʻī renaissance : a case study of the theosophical school of Bahrain in the 7th13th century</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj24b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp717</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b4886</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A kinetic study on the thermal decomposition of 2,2-dichloro-3-(9-fluorenyl) episulfide (28) was investigated in detail. Solid evidence as to the nature of the desulfurization process is given. A two-term rate equation is derived to account for the overall rate changes. Both a unimolecular and bimolecular ionic mechanism involving the concatenation of sulfur atoms was proposed to account for the observed kinetic behaviour. An extended study in 15 different solvents at different temperatures showed the desulfurization is ionic in nature. Activation parameters were calculated and rationalized with respect to differences in solvation of the ground and transition states. A linear isokinetic relationship was found indicating a similar mechanism of decomposition in these solvents. Rates of reaction were also found to be linearly correlated with dielectric constant as well as the $ pi sp *$ scale of Kamlet and Taft. A solvent isotope effect was found to exist and the rate of desulfurization is decreased in the presence of acetic acid. A radical mechanism is discounted from a rate study in the presence of radical inhibitors. Several new disubstituted 9-fluorenones were prepared for the first time using Meyers methodology. These and other mono and disubstituted fluorenones were employed in an effort to synthesize a variety of novel stable thiiranes. Only three thiiranes were prepared in this manner. The X-ray crystal structures of 2,2-dichloro-3,3-diphenyl episulfide (110) and 2,2-dichloro-3-dibenzosuberonyl episulfide (123) were also obtained for the first time. Thiirane 28 as well as sodium cyanodithioformate (139) were investigated as possible precursors to diatomic sulfur but no evidence of this interesting intermediate was detected. The chlorination of tetramethylthiuram disulfide, however, in the presence of 1,3-dienes, afforded products consistent with the trapping of diatomic sulfur. (Abstract shortened by UMI.) ftn*Please refer to the dissertation for diagram.</description><creator>Chew, Warren</creator><contributor>Harpp, David N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Sulfur extrusion reactions of thiiranes : kinetics and mechanistic investigations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784n344.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b4886</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p627h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The hunting of narwhals (Monodon monoceros) has been an important element in the cultural and economic life of indigenous people in the eastern Canadian Arctic and Greenland for centuries. This dissertation explores factors that have motivated the hunters and ways that non-indigenous forces have intervened to restrict hunting activities. Particular attention is paid to commercial (trade) aspects of the hunt and to how these have developed and changed through time. Concern about narwhal conservation first arose during the late 1960s and early 1970s. This concern has focused on a presumed positive correlation between the monetary value of tusk ivory for export and the intensity of hunting by the Inuit. An idealized model of conflict development and resolution is used to facilitate comparisons among six cases, including bowhead whale (Balaena mysticetus) hunting in Alaska, beluga (Delphinapterus leucas) hunting in southeastern Baffin Island and northern Quebec, dugong (Dugong dugon) hunting in Australia and Papua New Guinea, and narwhal hunting in Canada. These comparisons suggest that the conflict surrounding narwhal-hunt management is in a middle to late phase of development. Also, its commercial dimensions and geographically dispersed markets for products (ivory and maktaq) distinguish the narwhal hunt from the other marine-mammal hunts considered here. The continuing demand for narwhal products necessitates a hunt-management regime that is rooted in scientific knowledge, has legitimacy in Inuit communities, and keeps the kill rate within sustainable bounds.</description><creator>Reeves, Randall R.</creator><contributor>Muller-Wille, Ludger (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Whaling</subject><subject>Narwhal</subject><subject>Fishery management -- Canada</subject><title>What is a narwhal worth? : an analysis of factors driving the narwhal hunt and a critique of tried approaches to hunt management for species conservation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515p93j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p627h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sh85b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study is to develop a terrain evaluation system for road corridor selection applicable to the intermontane basins in northern Thailand. The first stage involves database construction of the terrain factors which have a direct effect on construction costs. These factors are land cover, topography and landforms, surficial geology, soil strength, topsoil removal, difficulty of excavation, embankment height, construction materials, and drainage characteristics. Remote sensing and terrain evaluation techniques, field investigations and geotechnical laboratory tests are used to prepare maps of these terrain factors. The resulting maps are converted into digital database form as map layers by using Geographical Resources Analysis Support System (GRASS)--a raster-based Geographic Information System (GIS). These factors are incorporated into cost models. These are constructed using local engineering cost assessments which control the selection and specification of terrain factors. Under the GRASS environment the digital map layers of different terrain attributes are converted, based on the cost models, into cost surfaces (cost per unit area). The cost surfaces are subsequently combined into an integrated terrain-cost model. With different assigned end points and cost models, the applications of the single theme cost surfaces and the integrated terrain-cost models to least-cost route selection are provided. An existing road network can be incorporated in these applications. The quality and benefits of the database and system developed related to terrain conditions, data capture by remote sensing, GIS manipulation and modelling, and cost modelling are discussed.</description><creator>Sarapirome, Sunya</creator><contributor>Parry, J. T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Geography -- Computer programs</subject><subject>Roads -- Thailand -- Surveying</subject><title>A terrain evaluation system and GIS for road corridor selection applicable to intermontane basins in northern Thailand</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wr83w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sh85b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m824c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this thesis is to solve model order selection, and change-point detection problems in real time using a form of predictive stochastic complexity. A consistent method for finding the best model order for certain kinds of ARMA processes is presented. An interesting fact is that the estimator "badness", obtained when using fixed gain, increases the "badness" of overparametrization. Model order selection simulations involving AR processes illustrate this fact very clearly. A successful model order selection simulation for ARMA processes is presented. A change-point detection method for certain kinds of ARMA processes is obtained for time variant change-points. Also, the abrupt jump parameter case and change-point detection using undermodeling are considered. A novel result is that undermodeling could in many cases improve the performance of the change-point detection scheme. Some results of the analysis of the change-point detection scheme are obtained and extensive simulations show that the approach exhibits surprisingly good detection capabilities. Lastly, we prove that the original form of the adaptive controller for linear time invariant systems, as obtained in (Ger90a), can be computed in a much less expensive manner. Simulations for an ARX system exemplify the stability and tracking capability of the adaptive controller. Moreover, the effect of dithering on closed loop performance is illustrated.</description><creator>Baikovicius, Jimmy</creator><contributor>Caines, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Theory and applications of predictive stochastic complexity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801ph94k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m824c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333391h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the first chapter we intend to present, although in a restricted sense, some of the positions of the most recent critics, which will allow us to determine the meaning of our Author. The next chapter is mainly dedicated to giving information which establishes the relationships between the most important mythological traditions and classical works. Such information will serve to find and establish the components of the Pavesian culture. Cesare Pavese was born in Piemonte, Italy, in 1908, he lived in the historical period during which fascism and nazism triumphed and through all the horrors of the immediate after-war. Pavese's incapacity to be concretely active in the political field brings him to relive, in his writings, the ancient Italian cult of the Evocativo. This technique of his is a hermetic method of going through with his ethical social mission. To evoke a god in a moment of national crisis is a traditionally Italian ritual; while the invocation to a God or a Muse is also part of the literary tradition. The classicism of Pavese is now recognized by different critics. Their basis for this decision is his work Dialoghi con Leuco. However, our attention is more focused on the romance Il diavolo sulle colline which occupies the central part of the trilogy La Bella Estate. This text Il diavolo sulle colline contains many meanings which requires different approaches--such as the cultural precedents of other authors, and even those of Pavese himself--to decipher. The many messages in this work can all be traced back to the concept of death and rebirth. Pavese uses themes which are beloved to Dante and the humanists, who were themselves inspired by the great Greek and Latin authors. And thus, we are left wondering whether Il diavolo sulle colline was conceived according to the norms of the classical tragedy, which was based on the celebrations in honor of the god Dionisus (the Hellenic demon venerated by the Latins under the name of Bacchus, and affiliated with an old Italian divinity whose symbolic name was Liber Pater). Poli, a dominating figure in Il diavolo sulle colline could be the double of this god. Our discussion will therefore be founded on the testimony of mythographers. From a methodological point of view, our analysis will not take into account the chronological sequences, but rather the themes which imply the operation of segmenting the text.</description><creator>Guardo Siino, Lina, 1936-</creator><contributor>Gilardino, Sergio Maria (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Pavese, Cesare -- Knowledge -- Mythology, Greek.</subject><subject>Pavese, Cesare. Diavolo sulle colline.</subject><subject>Mythology, Greek, in literature.</subject><title>Il mito classico nell'opera di Cesare Pavese</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x557j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333391h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801ph95v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cold-acclimation-specific (CAS) gene expression was examined by screening a cDNA library prepared from poly(A)$ sp+$ RNA of cold-acclimated seedlings of a freezing-tolerant variety of alfalfa (Medicago falcata cv Anik). Three distinct CAS cDNA clones, pSM784, pSM2201, and pSM2358 were isolated. The genes corresponding to all three clones are coordinately induced by cold. Expression of these genes is not triggered by other stress treatments such as heat shock, water stress, wounding, or treatment with exogenous ABA. A positive correlation was observed between the level of expression of each gene and the degree of freezing tolerance of four alfalfa cultivars. A full-length cDNA clone for the most abundantly-expressed gene, cas18 was isolated and sequenced. The deduced polypeptide, CAS18, is relatively small (167 amino acids), is highly hydrophillic, rich in glycine and threonine, and contains two distinctive repeat elements. It exhibits homology with members of the LEA/RAB/Dehydrin gene family--proteins which accumulate in response to water stress or abscisic acid (ABA). The cas18 cDNA hybridizes to three transcripts of 1.6, 1.4 and 1.0 kb in cold acclimated seedlings and cell cultures. The clone described here, Acs784, corresponds to the 1.0 kb transcript. Expression of this gene is 30-fold greater in cold-acclimated cells than in nonacclimated cells after one week of low temperature treatment. Return to room temperature (deacclimation) results in the rapid disappearance of the three transcripts within just 5 hours. Studies of nuclear "run-on" transcription and transcript stability show that low temperature regulates the expression of cas18 at both the transcriptional and post-transcriptional levels.</description><creator>Wolfraim, Lawrence A. (Lawrence Allen)</creator><contributor>Dhindsa, Rajinder Singh (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Plant genetic regulation</subject><subject>Alfalfa -- Genetics</subject><subject>Alfalfa -- Frost resistance</subject><title>Cloning, characterization and regulation of expression of a cold-acclimation-specific gene, cas18, in a freezing tolerant cultivar of alfalfa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73px62c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801ph95v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df132</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The adhesion of biological particles (bacteria, red blood cells, and liposomes) on glass surfaces has been studied under well-defined hydrodynamic conditions with an impinging jet apparatus, combined with either microscopic image analyzing or evanescent wave light scattering. Many kinetic aspects of cell adhesion were examined, with this technique, including initial adhesion rates of the cells; characteristic time for the adhering cells to escape; surface area blocked per adhering cell; average lifetime of a cell remaining on a surface under different shear rates; strengthening of adhesion with time. Some key parameters affecting adhesion kinetics such as intensity of the flow, salt concentration, pH of the medium, cell shape, size and flexibility were evaluated. Kinetics of specific adhesion of red blood cells through antigen-antibody bonds were also investigated. Experimental results were compared with either analytical or numerical solutions of mass transfer equations for the hydrodynamic conditions applied, with/without considerations of colloidal and hydrodynamic interactions. It was found that the adhesion kinetics of spherical red blood cells and rod-shaped bacteria on glass surfaces can be well-described by these theories. The ratio of the experimental adhesion rates to the theoretical ones can reach unity at suitable flow conditions for red blood cells and bacteria. The theory that liposomes do not adhere below a critical size was confirmed. The adhesion kinetics of liposomes are affected by pH, calcium ion concentrations and liposome diameter. Adhesion energy for the specific adhesion was found to increase with time, mainly due to deformation of the cells.</description><creator>Xia, Zheming</creator><contributor>van de Ven, Theo G. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Kinetics of specific and non-specific adhesion of biological cells subjected to flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311q98s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df132</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128ng24n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The equilibrium phase behaviour of ternary mixtures of water, oil and surfactants is examined using both a lattice-gas model and a Ginzburg-Landau model. The lattice model is based on the Blume-Capel model with additional orientational degrees of freedom for surfactants, and the Ginzburg-Landau model is based on two local scalar fields. When the concentrations of water and oil are equal the following phases are observed: a water and oil rich phase, a lamellar phase, and a disordered phase which is divided into an ordinary disordered fluid and a microemulsion region. In the lattice model, a square phase is also observed. The effects of fluctuations on the lattice model is studied via Monte-Carlo simulations and by the Langevin approach in the Ginzburg-Landau model. In both cases, we found that in the vicinity of the water/oil coexistence region, the lamellar phase becomes unstable against the microemulsion. Furthermore, we have studied the effects of surfactants on the dynamics of phase separation of two immiscible fluids, and found a drastic alteration in the kinetics. In particular, we found that surfactants slow down the growth to a non-algebraic one leading eventually to a microphase separation.</description><creator>Laradji, Mohamed</creator><contributor>Zuckermann, Martin J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Physics, Fluid and Plasma.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Ternary mixtures of water, oil and surfactants : equilibrium and dynamics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wr85f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng24n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qb493</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Polyphenoloxidases (EC 1.10.3.1) (PPO) were extracted from the skin layer between the muscle and exoskeleton, of lobster (Homarus americanus) by the successive steps of (NH$ sb4) sb2$SO$ sb4$ fractionation, ion-exchange chromatography and isoelectric focusing. The lobster 'PPO-fraction' recovered by the 40-80% (NH$ sb4) sb2$SO$ sb4$ fractionation step was found to exist in the inactive precursor form which required trypsin for activation and was inhibited by polyvinyl pyrrolidone (PVP). A comparative study of the lobster 'PPO-fraction' and the commercial tyrosinase from mushroom (EC 1.14.18.1) indicated that the two enzymes were similar with respect to substrate specificity, response to pH and selected inhibitors (cysteine, EDTA and PABA). However, both enzymes differed from one another in terms of their thermal and pH stabilities. Their catalytic efficiencies indicated that tyrosinase was better suited to catalyze oxidation of DOPA than lobster 'PPO-fraction'. Also, the activity of both enzymes were enhanced by copper. Further purification of the 'PPO-fraction' by ion-exchange chromatography and preparative isoelectric focusing with a Rotofor unit yielded three isozymes designated PPO 1, PPO 11 and PPO 111. These isozymes had pI values of 3.89, 4.26 and 4.54 and molecular weights of 32,180, 35,480 and 39,300 respectively. The isozymes were similar with respect to their pH and temperature activity profiles but differed from one another (especially PPO 1 versus PPOs 11 and 111) in terms of their pH and thermal stabilities. They also exhibited varying degrees of differences in their catalytic efficiencies. All three isozymes were inhibited by PABA, EDTA and cysteine, with PABA being a competitive inhibitor, and EDTA or cysteine a noncompetitive inhibitor. Lower concentrations of ascorbate and mercaptoethanol had no effect on the isozymes. The free amino acid analysis suggested that melanosis might originate from the skin of the lobster.</description><creator>Opoku-Gyamfua, Angelina</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Melanosis.</subject><subject>American lobster.</subject><title>Polyphenoloxidases from lobster (Homarus americanus) : extraction, purification and characterization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx039.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qb493</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33675</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>