<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:57:39Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):27025" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kg51b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explores discussion forums within two autistic community websites in an attempt to gain intimate insights into the educational experiences and cultural identification of high functioning autistics (HFAs). Throughout this thesis I have referred to people with Autism as 'autistics' or HFAs in recognition of their self-referencing on the websites and to strike consistency with their identity politics. (ex: Autistic Pride Parade). The study maintains a narrative component from the perspective of a teacher-researcher as a means of facilitating the development of a grounded theory for educating high functioning autistics. The study begins with an examination of contemporary controversies within the field of autistic studies, with a particular focus on issues surrounding the classification of Asperger's Syndrome under the deficit model of mental disorders. Several tables are then presented from data collected from Aspiesforfreedom.com and Wrongplanet.net. The tables present high functioning autistic opinions, thoughts and experiences related to emerging autistic advocacy efforts, as well as retrospectives of their social and academic experiences over the course of their schooling. An Internet Culture Theory (ICT) develops which honors the existence of an authentic community of autistics online. ICT explores how this acknowledgment can help shape educational policies and practices related to improving the self-esteem, identity formation, academic success and social experiences of HFAs in both our schools and communities. The study contends that modifications should be implemented prior to grade 7 due to reports of emotional deterioration during this particular year of development. Existing programs operating in the spirit of ICT are discussed in order to provide some concrete examples of what certain modifications might look like.</description><creator>Goodman, Jason, 1977-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Autism.</subject><subject>Internet -- Social aspects.</subject><title>Autistic culture and I.E.P.'s : exploring online forums from autistic community websites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jason Goodman, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wg270.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kg51b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r3378</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study suggests that cultural acknowledgement of the integral partnership between a human community and the environment it inhabits is central to the development of positive human-environment relationships. The comparison of two community environmental projects illustrates cultural implications of human land occupancy through comparisons of their governing land use institutions as well as social and individual experiences. In the Paakumshumwaau-Wemindji project environmental responsibility is strongly motivated by the interaction of shared cosmological understandings with direct experience in the landscape. The creation of Edgewater Park in suburban Pointe Claire is a clear indication of community environmental responsibility working its way towards new partnerships with lakeshore ecological communities. The fundamental difference in these partnerships inheres however in the distinct ways the two human communities understand the voice of the non-human elements within the partnership.</description><creator>Forrest, Margaret Anne.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Landscape protection -- Québec (Province) -- Saint Louis, Lake, Region.</subject><subject>Landscape protection -- Québec (Province) -- Paakumshumwaau River Watershed.</subject><subject>Landscape protection -- Québec (Province) -- Pointe-Claire.</subject><subject>Landscape protection -- Québec (Province) -- Wemindji.</subject><title>Stewardship as partnership : a comparative study of positive human-environment relationships in East Cree and suburban Montreal communities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Margaret Anne Forrest, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q420q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r3378</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fp24j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates Canada's border security policy, practices and technologies and the discourses in which they function, to better understand the U.S-Canadian "Smart Border" and the post-9/11 geographies of the nation-state. With the erasure of economic and military borders and the erection of new security-oriented police borders, Canada's "Smart Border" is no longer at the edges of territory but is a series of spaces reproduced in and outside of Canada through technologies such as the passport, immigration and anti-terrorism legislation, security agencies, monuments, and maps. The "Smart Border" perpetuates colonial distinctions and projects as a site of tension between the national construction of Canadian identities, policing technologies and the enforcement of a global apartheid that restricts access to political and economic resources by enforcing a regime of differential access to mobility. As a site of resistance, the "Smart Border" is also a space from which to displace colonial-national genealogies.</description><creator>Gordon, Aaron Andrew.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Border security -- United States.</subject><subject>Border security -- Canada.</subject><subject>National security -- United States.</subject><subject>National security -- Canada.</subject><title>Spaces and geographers of the 'Smart Border&amp;quot; : technologies and discourses of Canada's post 911 borders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Aaron Andrew Gordon, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f371k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fp24j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558d63r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explores perspectives of feminist therapists on working with adolescent girls. The participants in this study were three feminist therapists, two of whom were pursuing doctoral studies in counseling psychology and one of whom was an experienced therapist, trained in social work. The research data were collected through in-depth, semi-structured interviews, as well as through questionnaires. Triangulation of the data (Creswell &amp; Plano Clark, 2007) and interview coding formed the basis of the analysis. The results indicated that participants held well-defined ideas as to the meaning which they gave to feminist therapy and the methods which they used to implement it, in the form of principles, objectives, techniques, and characteristics of the therapeutic relationship, both with adolescents and with adults. In addition, participants revealed their thoughts regarding the appropriateness and relevance of feminist therapy for working with adolescent girls. Furthermore, several challenges to practicing feminist therapy were discussed.</description><creator>Guberman-Caron, Ariane.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Feminist therapy.</subject><subject>Therapist and patient.</subject><title>A qualitative analysis of the perspectives of feminist therapists on working with adolescent girls /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Ariane Guberman-Caron, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jb74h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558d63r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558d641</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In his 2005 work entitled The Marketing of Rebellion , author Clifford Bob explores the phenomenon of political marketing and its use by insurgent groups struggling to achieve their aims, most often against a central government opposed to their platform. In his book, Bob makes two central arguments: that courting support from non-governmental organizations (NGOs) is central to the success of insurgent groups; and that support is given to insurgent groups from NGOs not because of need, but rather because of political marketing techniques that insurgent groups use to attract that support. Thus, a successful and savvy insurgent group or opposition movement must employ sophisticated political marketing techniques in order to acquire the support they seek, and thus succeed in their struggle. Using Bob's framework as a model, this paper examines the Mojahedin-e Khalq (MeK) and their use of political marketing techniques, largely in the period of 2001-2006. In existence since 1965, the MeK is Iran's largest opposition group, having been formed to oppose the rule of Shah Reza Pahlavi, and currently opposed to the clerical regime in Tehran. The bulk of the group has been based in Iraq since 1986, and has been confined to their main base, Camp Ashraf, since the U.S.-led invasion that toppled the Ba'ath regime in Iraq in 2003. The MeK aggressively uses political marketing to promote their cause and attract support, and thus the paper examines their strategies, discusses characteristics of the MeK, and ultimately offers a series of explanations as to the outcome of their efforts as they stand in 2006.</description><creator>Bedford, Christian.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Insurgency -- Iran.</subject><subject>Mass media.</subject><subject>Non-governmental organizations.</subject><subject>Government, Resistance to -- Iran.</subject><subject>Public relations.</subject><title>An analysis of the use of political marketing by an insurgent group : a case study of the Mojahedin-e Khalq Organization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Christian Bedford, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z556v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558d641</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tr947</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a Tamil to English translation of Tirukkaḷirruppaṭiyar (TKP), composed by Uyyavanta Tevanayanar toward the end of the twelfth century C.E. The work contains one hundred quatrains of Tamil poetry composed in veṇpa meter. It is a poetic expansion of Tiruvuntiyar (TU), an earlier composition likely by the author's teacher's teacher. The TKP is a transitional text between the devotional religious bhakti(patti -Tamil) hymns of the nayanmar, who lived between the sixth century and the twelfth, and the Saiva-Siddhanta (Caiva Cittantam-Tamil) Theo-philosophical system, which developed between the thirteenth and the fourteenth centuries. TKP is the second work in the canon of fourteen texts called the Meykaṇṭa Sastra (Meykaṇṭa Cattiraṅkaḷ -Tamil), TU being the first. The introduction in the thesis discusses the date of the author, his position in the lineage of teachers, major themes found in the work such as the importance of a teacher, types of worship, miracles of the Saiva saints and final release from the cycle of births and deaths. TKP's similarities and differences with the TU, and how the TKP provides a foundation for later Saiva Siddhanta thought are addressed. Besides translation, each verse has a gloss and there are several appendices, tables and charts with additional information.</description><creator>Balasubramanian, Ranganathan.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Tamil literature.</subject><subject>Philosophy, Indic.</subject><title>The Tirukkaḷiṟṟuppaṭiyār : transition from Bhakti to Caiva Cittāntam philosophy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ranganathan Balasubramanian, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579s441.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tr947</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kb01m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The most ordinary man or woman has means of knowledge concerning his own feelings and circumstances that immeasurably surpass those that anyone else can have.-John Stuart Mill, On Liberty One feature that varies within competing conceptions of medical shared decision-making is how a patient's values are to be engaged by a physician. One detail that can be overlooked under "shared" decision-making is whether or not a physician ought (or be allowed) to attempt to persuade the patient to adopt particular health-related values. Some argue that it is incumbent on a physician to share her privileged understanding of medicine so as to help her patient embrace "better" values. This thesis argues that it is dangerous to patient autonomy for a physician to exert moral suasion on her patient to attempt to influence or change those values; the danger lies in the power imbalance between patients and physicians that seems inherent in medical encounters, and is exacerbated by the sick role. Thus, while a physician ought to help her patient articulate his health-related values, she ought not try to change them.</description><creator>Bigney, Mark W.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physician and patient -- Moral and ethical aspects.</subject><subject>Persuasion (Psychology) -- Moral and ethical aspects.</subject><subject>Communication in medicine -- Moral and ethical aspects.</subject><subject>Medical ethics.</subject><title>Neither mechanic nor high priest : moral suasion and the physician-patient relationship</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Mark W. Bigney, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn3011674.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kb01m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505080t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis evaluates how equitably market efficiency education reforms deliver the public good of education. It critiques extreme market education initiatives for prioritizing efficiency above equality and for neglecting matters of equality, and then conducts a case study on the McKay Scholarship Program, a voucher designed for students with disabilities, evaluating the program against a framework of educational equality. Overall, study finds that this voucher program seriously neglects its students equality, comments on the challenges of efficiency-based reforms being able to equitably distribute public goods such as education and calls for further research to be done on this issue.</description><creator>Brown, Victoria, 1978-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Educational vouchers -- Florida.</subject><subject>Educational equalization -- Florida.</subject><title>Efficiency for equality? : a case study of the McKay Scholarship Program</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Victoria Brown, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3655460.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505080t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708w75g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Discrete Fourier Transform (DFT) encoding over the real (or complex) field has been proposed as a means to reconstruct samples lost in multimedia transmissions over packet-based networks. A collection of simple sample reconstruction (and error detection) algorithms makes DFT codes an interesting candidate. A common problem with DFT code sample reconstruction algorithms is that the quantization associated with practical implementations results in reconstruction errors that are particularly large when lost samples occur in bursts (bursty erasures). Following a survey of DFT decoding algorithms, we present herein the Tandem Filterbank/DFT Code (TFBD). The TFBD code consists of a tandem arrangement of a filterbank and DFT encoder that effectively creates DFT codes along the rows (temporal codevectors) and columns (subband codevectors) of the frame under analysis. The tandem arrangement ensures that subband codevectors (the frame columns) will be DFT codes, and we show how the temporal codevectors (frame rows) can also be interpreted as DFT codes. All the subband and temporal codevectors can be used to reconstruct samples entirely independently of each other. An erasure burst along a particular codevector can then be broken up by reconstructing some lost samples along the remaining orientation; these samples can then be used as received samples in reconstructing the original codevector, a technique that we refer to as pivoting. Expressions related to the performance of the Tandem Filterbank/DFT (TFBD) code, including an expression for the temporal code reconstruction error and for temporal-to-subband pivoting operations, are derived and verified through simulations. The expressions also prove useful in the selection of the many parameters specifying a TFBD encoder. The design process is illustrated for two sample TFBD codes that are then compared to a benchmark DFT code at the same rate. The results show that the TFBD encoder is capable of reconstruction error improvements that are more than four orders of magnitude better than that of the benchmark DFT code.</description><creator>Zepeda Salvatierra, Joaquin Alejandro.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Tanden filterbank DFT code for bursty erasure correction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Joaquin Alejandro Zepeda Salvatierra, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dc733.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708w75g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20ss74c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The atmospheric pressure glow discharge plasma torch (APGD-t ) was used to treat cell cultures to investigate potential reactions with biological tissue. The plasma jet successfully detached HAAE-1 and HepG2 cells from a culture surface. The cells surrounding the void did not show any morphological damage after treatment. The detached HepG2 cells were transplanted to a new vessel, where they reattached. A viability assay showed the transplanted cells had functioning mitochondria up to 7 days after exposure to the plasma jet. These cells were also shown to have a permeabilized cell membrane for 4 hours after treatment, with resealing of the cell membrane occurring within 24 hours of transplantation. This work could be useful for localized tissue removal, and the injection of foreign DNA and RNA into cells for gene therapy. In separate experiments, sterilized bacterial grade polystyrene (BGPS) was functionalized with the plasma jet to improve cell adhesion. The contact angle of treated BGPS decreased from 93° to 35°, likely due to the addition of polar oxygen and nitrogen groups to the surface. The width of the functionalized track was visualized using the adhesion of HAAE-1 cell cultures, and was found to correspond to approximately double the diameter of the plasma jet. Direct plasma micropatterning using the APGD-t could replace the masks and chemicals required in present photolithographic techniquesIn separate experiments, sterilized bacterial grade polystyrene (BGPS) was functionalized with the plasma jet to improve cell adhesion. The contact angle of treated BGPS decreased from 93° to 35°, likely due to the addition of polar oxygen and nitrogen groups to the surface. The width of the functionalized track was visualized using the adhesion of HAAE-1 cell cultures, and was found to correspond to approximately double the diameter of the plasma jet. Direct plasma micropatterning using the APGD-t could replace the masks and chemicals required in present photolithographic techniques.</description><creator>Yonson, Sara.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Cell treatment and surface functionalization using the atmospheric pressure glow discharge plasma torch (APGD-t)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sara Yonson, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d003j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20ss74c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913q16f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the past decade, p-type ZnO material has been investigated extensively. Its properties offer the potential for broad applications including the development of ultraviolet light emitting devices. Although n-type ZnO material is well known and studied for decades, the fabrication method and properties of p-type ZnO material are still to date not clearly understood. In this report, reproducible p-type ZnO thin films sputtered on glass substrates are reported. On the same substrate, p-type ZnO film is local and surrounded by n-type ZnO regions. The thickness of the films is typically three microns after several hours of deposition by radio-frequency magnetron sputtering technique. Both p-type ZnO and n-type thin films are characterized by optical and electrical measurements at room temperature. The crystal structure of p-type ZnO is examined by X-ray diffraction patterns. The X-ray diffraction patterns show that the material is polycrystalline and has (100) and (101) preferred orientation. Photoluminescence spectra of ZnO help to identify the energy levels in the material and spectra analysis reveals the presence of defects and dopants in the material. For p-type ZnO, the resistivity, the hole concentration and hole mobility are found to be 148.8 O-cm, 4.34 x 1018/cm3 and 1.72 x 10-2 cm2/V-sec respectively.</description><creator>Yang, Hung-Pao, 1980-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>A study of P-type zinc oxide thin films /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Hung-Pao Yang, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182k40p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913q16f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429946b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is a need in today's industry to model the resonant frequency of the rectangular microstrip patch antenna very accurately because of its narrow bandwidth and increased use in communication applications. In this thesis, the cavity model is presented and updated in order to accurately analyze microstrip patch antennas. Also a genetic algorithm (GA) is used to optimize the patch for length and width so that in turn the maximum resonant frequency could be determined. The enhanced cavity model is shown to give more accurate results than another popular model while still being quite a simple model. It is further demonstrated that the GA can provide the global maximum for resonant frequency given a range for length and width of the patch.</description><creator>Zaman, Sadat.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A simple enhanced cavity model for microstrip patch antennas and calculations of optimized parameters using a genetic algorithm /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sadat Zaman, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kn380.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429946b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354f51t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Due to its high data transmission capability and robustness against multi-path propagation, Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexing (OFDM) has become increasingly popular for both wire-line and wireless communications. In signal recovery, the efficient and accurate estimation and correction of the symbol time offset (STO), carrier frequency offset (CFO), sampling frequency offset (SFO) and channel distortion are extremely important for the receiver to achieve good system performance. In this thesis, we study and develop joint synchronization, channel estimation and decoding schemes to provide high system performance at a relatively low complexity for uncoded and coded OFDM systems. We first investigate and evaluate the performance of low-complexity time-domain joint synchronization and channel estimation scheme suitable for uncoded OFDM systems. The proposed scheme can operate with a large initial CFO range (up to +/-100% of carrier spacing). Its complexity is reduced by using a special FFT block for time-to-frequency channel response conversion and a track-and-hold (TAH) estimation strategy based on mid-ambles to eliminate the additional IFFT block required by time-domain estimation. We then consider the turbo concept to develop an iterative joint synchronization, channel estimation and decoding scheme for coded OFDM systems operating at very low signal-to-noise ratios (SNRs). Instead of hard decisions, the estimator uses soft decisions of the transmitted data obtained from previous soft-input soft-output (SISO) decoder and consequently produces better estimates of the unknown parameters. These estimation results will then help data detector to generate more reliable soft inputs to the decoder. The whole process will be performed in an iterative manner and good system performance can be achieved with only a few iterations for moderate initial synchronization errors.</description><creator>Li, Si, 1981-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Joint synchronization, channel estimation and decoding techniques in OFDM systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Si Li, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fh39z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f51t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pg52v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The finite-element method is based on the discretization of a distributed system. The system subdivision process is called mesh generation. The number, order, geometric characteristics (shape, size and orientation) and physical characteristics (material properties, boundary conditions and load conditions) of elements in the mesh will affect the accuracy of the finite-element solution. The objective of this project is to establish a number of criteria for evaluating 3-D mesh-generation software, and to select the 3-D mesh generator that is most suitable for use in our software pipeline for modelling and simulation of complex natural structures. The evaluation criteria for this project include: ability to preserve the surface mesh during 3-D mesh generation; mesh quality; robustness; time efficiency; and cost. The mesh quality is assessed by visualization methods; histograms of the shape qualities and sizes of elements; solution residuals; condition numbers; and closeness to the exact solution as estimated by a convergence curve. Four unstructured mesh-generation programmes (GiD, Gmsh, GRUMMP and TetGen) have been evaluated. A thin block and three structures (one ligament and two ossicles) of the middle ear were chosen to be the models for the evaluation. A programme was developed to convert the surface definitions describing the models to the native file formats of the mesh-generation programmes, to verify that the surface meshes of these models could be successfully imported into the mesh-generation programmes, and to verify that the resulting volume meshes are topologically correct. The results of the evaluation indicate that the mean value of the shape qualities of elements, the root mean square of the solution residuals, and the closeness to the exact solution are good indicators of the overall mesh quality. The Gmsh programme is finally selected as the best 3-D mesh generator for the purposes of our software pipeline.</description><creator>Liu, Hengjin, 1967-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>3-D mesh generation for finite-element modelling of complex natural structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Hengjin Liu, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246s331.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pg52v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613mx81f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aluminum foam is a porous form of solid aluminum. One method of producing aluminum foam is the powder metallurgy process. Aluminum powder is mixed with a foaming agent, generally titanium hydride (TiH2), and pressed to form a compact. In the foaming process, the compact is heated and hydrogen gas is released from the agent to form bubbles within the surrounding aluminum. However, there is a significant gap between the onset of the decomposition temperature of the TiH2 (400°C) and the melting point of aluminum (660°C). The hydrogen gas evolution begins while the aluminum is still solid, creating an accumulation of gas pressure which eventually causes microfissures inside the matrix. As a result, the final structure has interconnected pores and inferior properties. This problem may be overcome by delaying the temperature of hydrogen evolution so that it coincides with the melting point of aluminum. Coating the titanium hydride with copper or nickel can create a kinetic barrier that retards the flow of hydrogen into the surrounding matrix. Electroless plating is a process that can be used to deposit metallic coatings on non-conductive materials. Metallic ions in solution are reduced by a suitable agent, creating a metal deposit on the substrate. The process is autocatalytic and continues until all the metallic ions are consumed. The objective of this work was to investigate the effect of the copper and nickel coatings on the hydrogen evolution of titanium hydride powders. It was found that the metal coatings do tend to delay the temperature of gas release and that this could potentially be used to improve the foaming process.</description><creator>Mariani, Laura Leana.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Electroless coatings on titanium hydride for use in the production of aluminum foam</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Laura Leana Mariani, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hc45p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613mx81f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k7530</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Serializer/Deserializers (SerDes) commonly used in telecommunication networks are now becoming widespread in computer and embedded systems to meet higher data bandwidth demand and support higher peripheral device performance requirements. These input/output (IOs) peripherals are design to provide reliable high speed data transfer capabilities to computers and embedded devices. This thesis provides a novel phase detector design in clock recovery system of a multi-level SerDes component. The multi-level phase detector incorporates a high speed array Flash Analog to Digital converter (ADC) front-end and an all-digital phase detection block. The all-digital design allows for lower power consumption and ease of transfer between technologies. This thesis also presents a Built-In-Self-Test (BIST) component that provides an enhancement to existing SerDes BIST measurements of duty cycle fitter. The measurement method provides better accuracy and is scalable due to its digital implementation. We provide histogram analysis for the enhanced BIST measurement for both constant and varying test input, repeatability and the effect of histogram bin size.</description><creator>Lim, Kahn Li, 1979-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Serializerdeserializer component design and text</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kahn Li Lim, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r588m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k7530</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gk01g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explores the issues related to the comparison of native English teachers and Korean English teachers, in the context of children's English education in a private language institute, Smarty English Institute, in Seoul, Korea. Specifically by analyzing class activities led by native and Korean English teachers as well as a full bilingual English teacher, I investigate the strengths and weaknesses of class activities led by English teachers whose first languages are different. I challenge the wide-spread notion in Korea that native English speakers are inherently better English teachers. I offer an holistic portrait of the activities in Kindergarten language classrooms in a private language institute in Korea from the diverse perspective of Korean teachers, parents, legislators, and administrators. I used participant observation of classrooms and interviews with teachers and children as the main tools of data collection. I examined the class activities in terms of the communicative interactions between teachers and children, the relevance of the class activities to the children's interest, and their authenticity. Based on this analysis of class activities, I also present recommendations for improved English education, particularly teacher education programs customized for the teachers' needs and their differing levels of English proficiency as well as more specialized curricula for native English teachers and Korean English teachers.</description><creator>Sung, In Ja, 1968-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Korea (South) -- Seoul.</subject><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Korean speakers.</subject><title>A comparison of class activities led by teachers in English kindergarten : Korean children's attitudes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© In Ja Sung, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hs196.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk01g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zr06z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As many theorists have pointed out, queer history is often erased within traditional, heteronormative historiography. Consequently, historians cannot recount the gay and lesbian past by conventional techniques of evidence and documentation. Instead they recuperate and reinvent queer history using strategies normally associated with the writing of fiction. This thesis examines three works of late twentieth century lesbian historical fiction that rewrite the past in order to render visible queer intimacy, sexuality, and desire. Jeanette Winterson's The Passion (1987), Sarah Waters' Tipping the Velvet (1998), and Helen Humphreys' Leaving Earth (1997) employ spectacularly visible lesbian heroines who symbolically reverse lesbian invisibility in mainstream historical narratives by displaying themselves as public figures or stage performers. There are ongoing debates in contemporary queer theory and historiography about the extent to which it is politically useful to privilege highly visible individuals when recovering the marginalized gay and lesbian past. Winterson's, Waters', and Humphreys' novels enact this debate, and exemplify a trend in contemporary lesbian historical fiction in which lesbian heroines are empowered by their ability to control their own visibility and to ensure the perpetuation of their history.</description><creator>Smith, Jenna.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Winterson, Jeanette, 1959-. Passion.</subject><subject>Lesbians in literature.</subject><subject>Humphreys, Helen, 1961-. Leaving earth.</subject><subject>Waters, Sarah, 1966-. Tipping the velvet.</subject><title>Spectacular lesbians : visual histories in Winterson, Waters, and Humphreys</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jenna Smith, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xm259.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zr06z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b148x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This paper examines and compares the different ways in which Charles Taylor and Richard Rorty critique the representationalism and foundationalism characteristic of modern epistemology (Chapter One), then considers how their critiques affect their respective understandings of morality (Chapter Two) and of the role of religious belief in modern secular societies (Chapter Three). Rorty's and Taylor's epistemological debate is presented as an example of the differences between, on the one hand, 'anti-ontological' or pragmatic post-foundational philosophies (such as Rorty's) and, on the other, 'weak ontological', contact realist alternatives (such as Taylor's). The paper concludes with a defense of Taylor's position over Rorty's, and, in doing so, makes a case for the rejection of strictly naturalist accounts of the moral and religious life in favor of a (weak ontological) picture of the human person as necessarily oriented in relation to transcendent goods of other trans-human realities.</description><creator>Sozek, Jonathan.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Knowledge, Theory of.</subject><subject>Taylor, Charles, 1931-</subject><subject>Rorty, Richard.</subject><title>After rationalism : the moral and religious implications of Taylor's and Rorty's epistemological critiques</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jonathan Sozek, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p0577.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b148x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816m84q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Romantic literature's preoccupation with subjectivity, and the nature of the self, is recognised as influential on modern conceptions of consciousness, and in particular as a precursor of psychoanalysis. This thesis examines Coleridge's understanding of consciousness, as expressed in his prose, to demonstrate that he theorised a language of the unconscious; a non-arbitrary, authentic language that remains inaccessible. By comparing this idea with Julia Kristeva's theory of Semiotic language, the thesis will show that this language is indeed recognised in her psychoanalytic theory as a product of the unconscious. Most importantly, it will show that while Coleridge's supernatural poetry laments the inaccessibility of unconscious language, Kristevan theory demonstrates it to be present in that very poetry.</description><creator>Stokes-King, Lisa.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Coleridge, Samuel Taylor, 1772-1834 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Coleridge, Samuel Taylor, 1772-1834 -- Language.</subject><subject>Kristeva, Julia, 1941-</subject><title>&amp;quot;Lovely shapes and sounds intelligible&amp;quot; : Kristevan semiotic and Coleridge's language of the unconscious</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Lisa Stokes-King, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4304927.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816m84q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pn15f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Spontaneous nociceptive behaviours (SNBs) are an important but under-studied component of chronic pain conditions. The group I metabotropic glutamate receptor (mGluR) agonist DHPG produces SNBs when injected intrathecally and group I mGluR antagonists are effective at reducing symptoms of neuropathic and inflammatory pain. The present experiments tested whether rats with sciatic nerve injury or persistent inflammation exhibit greater SNBs following intrathecal DHPG compared with control animals. SNBs were observed following intrathecal injection of DHPG between the L4 and L5 vertebrae. When DHPG was injected in rats with chronic constriction injury (CCI) of the sciatic nerve, they showed increased paw stamping behaviour compared to DHPG-injected sham controls. Results of the complementary experiment in rats with complete Freund's adjuvant (CFA)-induced inflammation did not show significant effects. Both CCI and CFA rats injected with DHPG showed increased paw licking and biting behaviour in the ipsilateral paws. These results provide evidence for behaviourally relevant contributions of group I mGluRs to SNBs in models of neuropathic and inflammatory pain.</description><creator>Duckworth, Phoebe E.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Pain.</subject><subject>Nociceptors.</subject><title>Nociceptive behaviours evoked by intrathecal (R, S)-3,5-dihydroxyphenylglycine to rats with neuropathic and inflammatory pain conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Phoebe E. Duckworth, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0967267.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn15f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jr44w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis argues that the development of new transportation and communication networks in and around the Ottoman city of Salonica was largely responsible for its remarkable growth in the late nineteenth and early twentieth-century. The success of these new networks of steamships, telegraphs and railways, hinged upon their ability to overcome the geographical limitations of the region which, as in any pre-industrial society, had made the movement of people and goods both glacially slow and thus costly since time immemorial. The development of these new networks had many serious effects: it served to bring Salonica and the Empire under greater influence of the European powers, deeply link it to the emerging international economy and all but destroy traditional networks such as caravans and sailing vessels. Salonica was a central part of the late Ottoman story for a variety of reasons, and thus, attempting to understand its development provides us with a way to understand the late Ottoman story as a whole.</description><creator>Ferguson, Michael, 1981-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Thessalonikē (Greece) -- History -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Thessalonikē (Greece) -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Transportation -- Greece -- Thessalonikē -- History.</subject><subject>Communication -- Greece -- Thessalonikē -- History.</subject><title>Transportation and communication networks in late Ottoman Salonica : 1800-1912</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Michael Ferguson, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741s10s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jr44w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806001q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The contemporary fine art auction house is a space where aesthetics and commerce merge into a spectacular experience. Sotheby's, London is one example of an auction house turned entertainment space, which masks its blatant capitalist tendencies through the replication of validated cultural institutions. The auction house mimics museum and theatre space in order to create a legitimate social and cultural experience for its clients. Every aspect of the auction event is choreographed to generate demand for its art and an authentic experience for its patrons. Individuals with the approved educational and economical background have access to these constructed locations, and attend the auction performance to purchase social status in conjunction with the art. As a result of this, Sotheby's effectively transforms economic capital into class acceptance through its spectacular space and legitimized cultural events.</description><creator>Eller, Erin E.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Sotheby &amp; Co. (London, England)</subject><subject>Art auctions -- England -- London.</subject><title>A legitimate space for the consumption of art : how Sotheby's, London sells a cultural experience through fine art auctions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Erin E. Eller, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k7548.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806001q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c0755</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a third-grade teacher's examination of student engagement. The promotion of student engagement is an important issue for teachers and educational researchers since engagement is considered essential for learning to occur. The purpose of this study was to identify and discuss several classroom contexts in which students motivate themselves for engagement, that is, to behave, feel, and think in ways that relate positively to school and learning. The method chosen was self-study, which is a form of narrative inquiry, whereby the author used memory work to recall and reflect on his childhood and professional experiences of student engagement. The insights gained and the issues raised from this inquiry are organised around three key themes: relationships, meaningful instruction, and goal orientation. Connections are made between the author's childhood and teacher experiences, and these experiences are linked to empirical and theoretical research on student motivation in classroom settings.</description><creator>Doucet, Richard John.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Motivation in education.</subject><title>Student engagement : understanding the science and the stories of motivation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Richard John Doucet, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719m67t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c0755</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gw483</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite more conservative surgical treatment for breast cancer, lymphedema and arm dysfunction remain sources of significant morbidity. The study for this thesis was conducted to explore methods for defining and identifying lymphedema and arm dysfunction after treatment for breast cancer. In order to establish cut-points in the differences in the sizes of arms to define the presence of lymphedema among women previously treated for breast cancer, the distributions of the differences in the sizes of arms, using measures of circumference and volume, among 40 women with no history of breast cancer were determined. The selected cut-points in the differences were defined as the mean plus one, two, or three standard deviations. A questionnaire (referred to as the Lymphedema Identification Tool) based on self-reported symptoms was developed to identify women with lymphedema. The Lymphedema Identification Tool and the 'Disabilities of the Arm, Shoulder and Hand' (DASH) questionnaire were sent to 596 women previously treated for stage I or II breast cancer and 50 women attended an evaluation session. At this evaluation session, measurements of the sizes of their arms were made and the Lymphedema Identification Tool and the DASH were repeated. This allowed for the evaluation of test-retest reliability, internal consistency reliability, and criterion validity of the Lymphedema Identification Tool. From these measurements and responses to the questionnaires, the association between arm dysfunction, as assessed by the DASH questionnaire, and the presence of lymphedema, as determined by the measurements of arm sizes and by women's self-report was determined. In addition, through the development of logistic regression models, the Lymphedema Identification Tool, the DASH questionnaire, age at diagnosis, and body mass index were found to predict the presence of lymphedema, as defined by the measurements of arms. Lymphedema appears to be a condition associated with a spectrum of symptoms and functional impairment varying from mild to severe. This thesis, even though results are preliminary, suggests a methodology for identifying lymphedema and arm dysfunction.</description><creator>Latella, Jennifer.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Lymphedema after treatment for breast cancer : a pilot study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jennifer Latella, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d449q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gw483</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):27050</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>