<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:54:50Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42675" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mh25s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:17:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Physical barriers are known to limit species' ranges, but, in the absence of physical barriers, what prevents adaptation and expansion at the periphery? Genetic influence from central populations may prevent adaptation to ecological barriers by swamping peripheral populations with suboptimal genes. If this is the case, then isolation may enable local adaptation and further range expansion. Barriers such as rivers provide ideal tests of the influence of gene flow and may explain differences in range sizes. This study investigates northern range limitations and phylogeography of the Northern Two-lined ( Eurycea bislineata) and Northern Dusky (Desmognathus fuscus ) stream salamanders. Phylogeographic patterns of populations throughout Quebec and Labrador were investigated by sequencing portions of cytochrome b and 12S rRNA mitochondrial DNA genes. Interpopulation divergence was low for both species, however, unique genetic haplotypes and morphological variation on the north shore of the St. Lawrence indicate that the river is acting as a barrier to gene flow.</description><creator>Markle, Tricia M.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Phylogeography -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Labrador.</subject><subject>Phylogeography -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Northern dusky salamander -- Home range -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Northern dusky salamander -- Home range -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Labrador.</subject><subject>Northern two-lined salamander -- Home range -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Labrador.</subject><subject>Northern two-lined salamander -- Home range -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Range limitations and phylogeography of stream salamanders in Quebec and Labrador</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Tricia M. Markle, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g9163.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mh25s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78th383</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:17:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Networks of cameras such as building security systems can be a source of localization information for a mobile robot assuming a map of camera locations as well as calibration information for each camera is available. This thesis describes an automated system to acquire such information. A fully automated camera calibration system uses fiducial markers and a mobile robot in order to drastically improve ease-of-use compared to standard techniques. A 6DOF EKF is used for mapping and is validated experimentally over a 50 m hallway environment. Motion planning strategies are considered both in front of a single camera to maximize calibration accuracy and globally between cameras in order to facilitate accurate measurements. For global motion planning, an adaptive exploration strategy based on heuristic search allows compromise between distance traveled and final map uncertainty which provides the system a level of autonomy which could not be obtained with previous techniques.</description><creator>Meger, David Paul.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Television in security systems.</subject><subject>Computer vision.</subject><subject>Electronic surveillance.</subject><subject>Mobile robots.</subject><title>Planning, localization, and mapping for a mobile robot in a camera network</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© David Paul Meger, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w652c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78th383</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311t664</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:17:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A chemical bath deposition technique has been used in the fabrication of thin film transistors (TFT), which have been deposited on a 200mum polymer substrate. This thesis documents the chemistry and microfabrication techniques used to create the TFTs. Because TFTs have not been fabricated on plastics in this manner before, insights gained from understanding the mechanical properties of the polymer, and how these interact with those of the inorganic components of the TFTs, were used to guide development of processes specifically suited to adapt the polymer to TFT fabrication.</description><creator>MacNab, Finlay.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Electronic polymers.</subject><subject>Thin film transistors.</subject><title>Thin film transistors from II-IV semiconductors on polymer substrates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Finlay MacNab, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257j915.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311t664</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fw856</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A summary of methods from functional analysis in application to the analysis of several complex variables, based upon Hormander's estimate for &amp;part; operators on pseudoconvex domains.</description><creator>McKeown, Jesse.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Functions of several complex variables.</subject><title>Functional methods in analysis of several complex variables</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jesse McKeown, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440x93s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fw856</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qp07t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Glucocorticoids are commonly used to treat cows with clinical ketosis and fatty liver disease. This study investigated the effects of 10 mg/mL of FlucortRTM and PredefRTM 2X on the day of calving on blood metabolites, immune function and milk composition on 30 transitional Holstein cows. Sample of blood and milk were analyzed for energy metabolites (glucose, NEFA, BHB and insulin), mineral metabolites (Ca, P, Na, K, Cl and Mg), energy function parameters (antibody, lymphocyte), milk compositional parameters (protein, fat, lactose, SCC). There were no differences in glucose, Na, Cl, Mg, antibody, lymphocyte and milk fat, were observed among treatments. FlucortRTM treated cows had significantly lower NEFA on D1, higher BHB on D21 and D28, lower insulin on D14, higher Ca on D1 and lower P on D1. PredefRTM 2X treated cows had significantly higher BHB on D21, higher insulin on D7, lower Ca on D1, higher SCC on D1 and higher milk protein on D1. With respect to the significant data in this study, the use of glucocorticoids FlucortRTM and Predef RTM 2X in a single intramuscular injection on d1 for the treatment of ketosis is not warranted.</description><creator>Sindhwani, Madhu Rani.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Acetonemia -- Chemotherapy.</subject><subject>Glucocorticoids.</subject><subject>Holstein-Friesian cattle -- Diseases -- Chemotherapy.</subject><subject>Fatty liver -- Chemotherapy.</subject><title>The effect of Predef 2X and Flucort on blood metabolites, immune function and milk composition in Holstein dairy cows /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Madhu Rani Sindhwani, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rn44b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qp07t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784q66t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Schizophrenia (SCZ) is believed to be a neurodevelopmental disorder resulting from genetic and environmental factors. Obstetric complications, particularly fetal hypoxia, seem to be a risk factor for SCZ. The hippocampus is highly sensitive to ischemic episodes, and there is substantial evidence for hippocampal malfunction in SCZ. Thus, utilizing a rat model of global anoxia (15 min and 21 min) during Cesarean-section birth (C-section), hippocampal proliferation was examined in the dentate gyrus and CAI region at postnatal day 21 and day 60. Incorporation of 5-bromo-2-deoxyuridine (BrdU) was used as a marker of cell proliferation. Rats were sacrificed 2 hours after BrdU injection to quantify cell proliferation, or 4 weeks after BrdU injection to quantify survival of newly proliferating cells and to identify if these cells express a neuronal phenotype. Only rats that had undergone 15 minutes of hypoxia during C-section birth compared to C-sectioned controls, showed a significant increase in cell proliferation in the dentate gyrus on postnatal day 21. Thus perinatal hypoxia can have lasting effects on the hippocampus that depend on the duration of the hypoxic insult.</description><creator>Labban, Margaret.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The effects of perinatal hypoxia on hippocampal neurogenesis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Margaret Labban, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g917c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784q66t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593v0654</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We show that the long-standing assumption of "no-communication" between the provers of the two-prover model is not sufficiently precise to guarantee the security of a bit commitment scheme against malicious adversaries. Indeed, we show how a simple correlated random variable, which does not allow to communicate, can be used to cheat a simplified version (sBGKW) of the bit commitment scheme of Ben-Or, Goldwasser, Kilian, and Wigderson [BGKW88]. Instead we propose a stronger notion of separation between the two provers which takes into account correlated computations. To emphasize the risk that entanglement still represents for the security of a commitment scheme despite the stronger notion of separation, we present two variations of the sBGKW scheme that can be cheated by quantum provers with probability (almost) one. A complete proof of security against quantum adversaries is then given for the sBGKW scheme. By reduction we also obtain the security of the original BGKW scheme against quantum provers. For the unfamiliar reader, basic notions of quantum processing are provided to facilitate the understanding of the proofs presented.</description><creator>Simard, Jean-Raymond.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Cryptography -- Mathematics.</subject><subject>Quantum theory.</subject><subject>Zero-knowledge proofs.</subject><title>Classical and quantum strategies for bit commitment schemes in the two-prover model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jean-Raymond Simard, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h589n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593v0654</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z9366</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent evidence shows neuroanatomical changes related to chronic lower back pain and headache. This thesis examines whether there are neuroanatomical changes related to other chronic pain syndromes. We studied brain grey matter (GM) density of patients with fibromyalgia (FM) and vulvar vestibulitis (VVS), chronic pain syndromes thought to involve central changes in pain modulatory systems. Specifically, we hypothesized that in comparison to matched controls, patients will have multiple regions of altered GM density and GM volume. We analyzed the T1-weighted anatomical brain images of patients and healthy, matched controls. FM and VVS patients demonstrated significant differences in the GM density of several pain- and disease-related cortical and subcortical structures. These findings support previous functional neuroimaging studies showing abnormal sensory processing, and provide further evidence for the hypothesis that central pain modulatory systems may be disrupted in chronic pain.</description><creator>Kuchinad, Anil.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>A morphometric study of patients with fibromyalgia and vulvar vestibulitis syndrome /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Anil Kuchinad, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kv52s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z9366</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90f044m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis begins with a review on the topic of molecular electronics. The purpose of this review is to motivate the need for good theory to understand and predict molecular electronics behaviour. At present the most promising theoretical formalism for dealing with this problem is a combination of density functional theory and nonequilibrium Green's functions (NEGF-DFT). This formalism is especially attractive because it is an ab-initio technique, meaning that it is completely from first principles and does not require any empirical parameters. An implementation of this formalism has been developed by the research group of Hong Guo and is presented and explained here. A few other implementations which are similar but differ in some ways are also discussed briefly to highlight their various advantages and disadvantages. One of the difficulties of ab-initio calculations is that they can be extremely costly in terms of the computing time and memory that they require. For this reason, in addition to using appropriate approximations, sophisticated numerical analysis tech niques need to be used. One of the bottlenecks in the NEGF-DFT method is solving the Poisson equation on a large real space grid. For studying systems incorporating a gate voltage it is required to be able to solve this problem with nonperiodic boundary conditions. In order to do this a technique called multigrid is used. This thesis examines the multigrid technique and develops an efficient implementation for the purpose of use in the NEGF-DFT formalism. For large systems, where it is necessary to use especially large real space grids, it is desirable to run simulations on parallel computing clusters to handle the memory requirements and make the code run faster. For this reason a parallel implementation of multigrid is developed and tested for performance. The multigrid tool is incorporated into the NEGF-DFT formalism and tested to ensure that it is properly implemented. A few calculations are made on a benzenedithiol system with gold leads to show the effect of an applied gate voltage.</description><creator>Peacock, Darren.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Density functionals.</subject><subject>Multigrid methods (Numerical analysis)</subject><subject>Molecular electronics -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Parallelized multigrid applied to modeling molecular electronics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Darren Peacock, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x5459.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90f044m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hf11k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although insulin resistance of glucose and fat metabolism in type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) is firmly established, that of protein remains controversial for methodological reasons. A hyperinsulinemic (40MU/m2·min) euglycemic (5.5 mmol/L) isoaminoacidemic (postabsorptive concentrations) clamp was combined with [3-3H]glucose and [1-13C]leucine kinetics to concurrently assess protein and glucose metabolism in 10 hyperglycemic men with T2DM and 11 men without (all BMI=29+/-kg/m2), matched also for age, body composition, and waist circumference. In response to hyperinsulinemia, protein turnover and synthesis were stimulated in controls, but not in T2DM. Both insulin-stimulated total and non-oxidative glucose disposal were diminished in T2DM vs. controls. There was a robust positive correlation between the change in synthesis and glucose disposal. Hence, there is an additive effect of T2DM, beyond that of having excess fat, on insulin resistance of whole body protein turnover and synthesis. Furthermore, protein sensitivity to insulin parallels that of glucose, establishing this as an important concern in T2DM management.</description><creator>Pereira, Sandra M.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Insulin resistance.</subject><subject>Proteins -- Synthesis.</subject><subject>Non-insulin-dependent diabetes -- Chemotherapy.</subject><title>Impaired response of protein synthesis and turnover to insulin in men with type 2 diabetes mellitus : by Sandra M. Pereira.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Sandra M. Pereira, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859k82j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hf11k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r748m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this Master's project was to characterize the postural control patterns of individuals with chronic whiplash-associated disorders and to compare these patterns with those of healthy individuals. The postural reactions in response to low-intensity translations of the sitting position were assessed by way of kinematic and electromyographic analyses. We found that whiplash individuals display an earlier onset of their head displacement and a pattern of trunk displacement characterized by greater flexion at the upper levels of the spine, compared to the lower levels. Moreover, whiplash individuals present a tendency for a late recruitment of their neck flexors and for a greater use of a pattern of neck extensor muscle inhibition. These results suggest that individuals with whiplash-associated disorders may compensate their altered neck functional ability by modifying their relative movements along the spine and by adopting altered motor strategies to compensate for their painful muscles.</description><creator>Patenaude, Isabelle.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Whiplash injuries.</subject><subject>Posture disorders.</subject><title>The effects of whiplash-associated disorders on the kinematic and the electromyographic responses of individuals submitted to anterior surface translations in the sitting position /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Isabelle Patenaude, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tw71r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r748m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053m56n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nanostructures, molecular assemblies at the nanometer scale, are currently influencing diagnostics, imaging, and therapeutics. Many nanostructures are built using supramolecular chemistry principles, where hydrogen bonding between simple building blocks causes the formation of specific morphologies. Here we hypothesize that a six stranded DNA nanotube can be generated by tethering triaminopyrimidine and cyanuric acid building blocks as bases on the natural DNA backbone. We also hypothesize that cyanuric acid, a secondary oxidation product of guanine, will form complex architectures with adenine, its natural hydrogen bond complement. To test these hypotheses, we used multi-step synthetic strategies to generate DNA strands of cyanuric acid and triaminopyrimidine. The synthesis of the cyanuric acid DNA strand is complete and preliminary self-assembly studies with adenine DNA strands have been performed. The synthesis of the triaminopyrimidine DNA strand is ongoing. This thesis provides the groundwork for incorporating supramolecular building blocks into DNA to generate complex DNA architectures.</description><creator>Palmer, Alison Lesley.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Nanostructures.</subject><subject>Supramolecular chemistry.</subject><subject>Nucleosides -- Derivatives.</subject><title>Novel nucleoside analogs with supramolecular and biological applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Alison Lesley Palmer, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sf862.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053m56n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82kc632</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sodium/proton exchangers (NHEs) are secondary active transporters that catalyze the electroneutral exchange of Na+ and H+ down their respective concentration gradients using the inward electrochemical Na+ gradient established by the plasma membrane Na+ /K+-ATPase. NHEs play a fundamental role in maintaining the intracellular pH (pHi) homeostasis and cell volume which are required for stable protein activity, and ultimately cell survival. To date, nine NHE isoforms (NHE 1-9) have been identified, and are expressed in a tissue/cell specific manner, which indicates a degree of specialization in their respective cellular functions. NHE1 through 5 are plasmalemmal-type exchangers, whereas NHE6 and 7 accumulate predominantly in organellar compartments. Substantially less information is known about NHE8 and NHE9. Initial reports have shown that both NHE8 and NHE9 mRNA are ubiquitously expressed, and that NHE8 protein can be detected in the proximal tubules of kidney nephrons (Goyal et al., 2003; de Silva et al., 2003). To gain further insight into the subcellular distribution and function of these latter isoforms, full length cDNAs of NHE8 and NHE9 were cloned, epitope tagged and transfected into cultured cell lines. Examination of their subcellular localization by confocal microscopy showed that NHE8 and NHE9 are targeted to lysosomes and endosomes respectively. Furthermore, co-immunoprecipitation experiments indicated that NHE9 can form homodimeric complexes. Co-immunoprecipitation studies and confocal microscopy also indicated that NHE9 may form heterocomplexes with NHE8. In order to further characterize NHE9 under native conditions, a native polyclonal antibody was raised against a distinct region of its C-terminal cytoplasmic tail.</description><creator>Jones, Ewen St. Clair.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Characterization of the human organellar sodiumproton exchanger isoforms NHE8 and NHE9</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ewen St. Clair Jones, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35td40s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82kc632</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zg280</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Biological invasions are among the leading causes of species diversity loss; however, the impacts of invasion are context-dependent and can vary with the local environment. The mechanisms governing variation in impact and their relationship to specific abiotic and biotic factors remain largely unexplored. Recent local declines in native unionid mussels have been attributed to the invasion of North American lakes and rivers by the Eurasian zebra mussel ( Dreissena polymorpha), as a result of intense fouling of unionid shells by zebra mussels. My research investigated the role of abiotic and biotic factors in mediating the impact of zebra mussels on native mussels. I examined the impact of zebra mussels on unionids in a habitat thought to be suboptimal for zebra mussels and compared this to the impact observed in other invaded habitats. A predictive model relating fouling intensity to local environmental variables (calcium concentration, sediment particle size) was developed, and a predator-exclusion experiment was conducted to investigate the role of predation in mediating fouling intensity. Overall, I found that two abiotic factors of the local environment were significant predictors of fouling intensity and that relationships used to predict the impact of zebra mussels could be extended to a broader range of habitats.</description><creator>Jokela, Anneli.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Zebra mussel -- Saint Lawrence River.</subject><subject>Unionidae -- Effect of exotic animals on -- Saint Lawrence River.</subject><subject>Unionidae -- Effect of exotic animals on -- Richelieu River (N.Y. and Vt.-Québec)</subject><subject>Zebra mussel -- Richelieu River (N.Y. and Vt.-Québec)</subject><title>Factors affecting the impact of invasive mussels on native freshwater mussels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Anneli Jokela, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547w66s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zg280</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qh436</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A quantum computer can only solve classically intractable problems like factoring large integers if it can perform quantum computations scalably. The minimum accuracy required among the components of a quantum computer to perform scalable computation is called the quantum accuracy threshold, epsilon 0. We explore the accuracy threshold for Calderbank-Shor-Steane codes of distance 5. Our accuracy thresholds are based on the threshold theorem proven by Aliferis et al. [3]. Their threshold theorem is applicable to concatenated codes and can be used to derive a rigorous lower bound on the threshold. In this thesis we consider degenerate codes with parameters [[17,1,5]] and [[19,1,5]], and a non-degenerate [[21,1,5]] code. For each code we design a set of logical operations sufficient to perform universal computation. We estimate the thresholds using simulation tools for an independent stochastic error model. Our simulations incorporate randomized sampling techniques to estimate the number of ways our largest logical operation can fail. A lower bound of epsilon0 ≥ 3.624 x 10-5 is derived for the [[17,1,5]] code.</description><creator>Khalid, Omar.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Quantum accuracy threshold for distance-5 codes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Omar Khalid, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89db67k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qh436</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj2366551</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Incompressible hyperelastic materials are used extensively in construction and manufacturing and are often reinforced with fibers aligned in a single direction. There are numerous mathematical constitutive models that are used to model the behavior of hyperelastic materials but few of them have been accurately applied to reinforced hyperelastic materials. The goal of this work is to develop a simple model that will allow a researcher to predict the effective shear modulus of a reinforced hyperelastic material in plane strain and model the material as if it were a homogenous material. A series of computational simulations were performed with reinforced hyperelastic materials and the data was used to develop predictive formulae. The formulae were then applied to the reinforcement of a rubber automobile bushing.</description><creator>Kaden, Jason.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Computational simulations of fiber reinforced hyperelastic materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jason Kaden, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dh67s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj2366551</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860c116</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In a living cell, signals are usually transmitted from outside to the intracellular machinery through receptors on the cell membrane. Once bound to their ligand (e.g. a hormone or another protein), receptors become activated and trigger chemical reactions inside the cell. To stop the response, receptors are often removed from the cell membrane (internalization). A protein called arrestin binds to the receptor and targets it to a vesicle, which detaches from the membrane and fuses with other vesicles to form an endosome, a sphere-like structure containing many receptors. After internalization, arrestin must dissociate from the receptor before the latter returns to the membrane or is degraded. By using fluorescence recovery after photobleaching data and a reaction-diffusion model, we estimate the in vivo affinity of arrestin for bradykinin type 2 receptor. We use the Hough transform to automate fluorescence quantification and a Bayesian approach to fit the model to the data.</description><creator>Gousseva, Veronika.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>A quantitative fluorescence recovery after photobleaching analysis of receptor-protein interactions on vesicles /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Veronika Gousseva, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vg72t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860c116</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c672b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The document describes a search for the rare decay B¯ → K¯vv̄ in a data set of about 230 millions of BB̄ pairs recorded by the BABAR detector at the PEP-II B Factory, via the process e⁺e⁻ → ϒ(4S) → BB̄. The method used selects events in which the B+ meson is fully reconstructed, and looks for a K¯ in the rest of the event. This is accomplished by applying kinematical and topological restrictions that select B¯ → K¯vv̄ events with the largest possible efficiency, while rejecting a maximum amount of background events. The number of background events is estimated from data and from simulated events, while the value of the selection efficiency relies solely on the simulation of B¯ → K¯vv̄ decays in the BABAR detector. These two numbers are required in order to set an upper limit on the branching ratio. We analyze a subset of the data sample and provide an interpretation of the result.</description><creator>Harnois-Déraps, Joachim.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>B mesons -- Decay.</subject><subject>Kaons.</subject><subject>Antineutrinos.</subject><subject>Neutrinos.</subject><title>A search for the rare decay of a charged B meson into a charged K meson, a neutrino and an anti-neutrino /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Joachim Harnois-Déraps, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k230r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c672b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bg939</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Striatal dopamine is well known to be involved in reward. Indeed, drug of abuse allowed DA release in the striatum as previous PET experiment demonstrated. Here, is investigated the change of DA in different conditions of monetary reward in healthy subjects to identify which subcomponent of reward provokes Dopamine release using 11C Raclopride of PET. In a first time we scan 10 healthy male subjects 3 times in different conditions: unpredictable monetary reward, novel visual and audio stimuli, and sensorimotor control. In a second time, we compared different amounts of work load to get monetary reward. Unpredictable passive reward as well as novelty failed to release significantly DA in comparison to the sensorimotor control task. Conditions of increasing effort to obtain the reward failed to release DA in comparison to the condition of passive receipt of reward. Limitations of the PET technique, as well as the paradigm's ones are presented.</description><creator>Hakyemez, Hélène.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Dopamine and monetary reward : two positron emission tomography studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Hélène Hakyemez, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hh536.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bg939</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tt42g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When survival data are collected as part of a prevalent cohort study, the recruited cases have already experienced their initiating event. When these initiating times are generated from a Stationary Poisson Process, these survival data are termed "length-biased". Our interest is to estimate the Survival function, from the initiating event time, which is often known only with uncertainty, to the failure or censoring time. We derive the likelihood function and propose two methods to estimate the survival function incorporating the possible uncertainty. We verify the methods by the means of simulation. We also illustrate the methods using a real set of data on survival with dementia collected as part of the Canadian Study of Health and Aging (CSHA).</description><creator>Guo, Hui, 1974-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Doubly censored prevalent cohort survival data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Hui Guo, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sj055.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tt42g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999b925</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Daughters of gestational diabetes (GDM) affected pregnancies are at greater risk for the development of type 2 diabetes mellitus (DM) later in life. Adiponectin is an early marker of DM risk. Dietary fat quality has been proposed to be involved in the development of insulin resistance. Plasma fatty acids are a marker of recent dietary exposure. The objectives of this research were to determine whether differences in adiponectin exist in daughters of GDM pregnancies, and to describe how dietary fatty acids impact adiponectin concentrations. Fasting adiponectin and plasma fatty acids were examined for 180 adolescent daughters born to mothers with and without GDM. No differences were observed in adiponectin between study groups, however; a significant difference was detected upon comparison of daughters from mothers who were presently diabetic with those from healthy mothers. The association between fatty acids and adiponectin varied by visceral adiposity. Adiponectin was inversely associated with monounsaturated and omega-3 (n-3) fatty acids in the high waist group. Further knowledge on the interactions between fatty acids, desaturase activity and adiponectin would be helpful in planning early interventions for individuals at risk for diabetes.</description><creator>Gallo, Sina.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Non-insulin-dependent diabetes -- Risk factors.</subject><subject>Fatty acids.</subject><subject>Diabetes in pregnancy.</subject><subject>Fat cells.</subject><title>The determinants of adiponectin in female adolescents : offspring of gestational diabetes and non-diabetes affected pregnancies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sina Gallo, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x340s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999b925</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pn89db68v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In a large multi-center study where many groups collaborate to produce data, the conditions under which the data are collected can vary significantly. In the case of the NIH funded MRI study of normal brain development (NIHPD), 6 centers across the US collect MRI scans of the developing child brain. In all, four different models of scanners from 2 manufacturers are used. The subject of this thesis is to quantify differences in acquired data that are due to scanner differences and thus enable improved biological study. The aim of this study is to analyze the scanner-induced differences across sites using a specialized phantom recommended by the American College of Radiology (ACR). Together with the 7 tests listed by the ACR MRI accreditation manual, phantom data from each site can be analyzed for parameters that are characteristic of image quality. The measurements are done automatically using programs written at the MNI, that use MINC tools and the MNI autoreg package to compute the necessary parameters. The results demonstrate that, in general, all data obtained complied with the 7 tests of the ACR MRI manual. Statistically significant variations over time and between sites were found in the data. However, the magnitude of the variations is of the order of 1%-2% indicating stable data acquisitions and comparability of data between sites.</description><creator>Fu, Luke.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Automated analysis of multi-site MRI data for the NIHPD</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Luke Fu, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z2316.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89db68v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623h79m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The eastern race of the Loggerhead shrike (Lanius ludovicianus ssp. migrans) is a grassland bird federally listed as endangered. There are approximately 30 pairs remaining in the Canadian wild today. Captive breeding and release programs have been developed in Canada to help alleviate the decline. However, little is known about the fate of the released birds and the factors influencing their reproductive success. To help in the understanding of the movement, behaviour and survival of the shrikes post-release, we tested whether radio telemetry was an effective technique to follow these birds. Despite limited behavioural effects in captivity, a tail-mount was not suitable for released Loggerhead shrikes due to unreliable retention times. The second portion of this study addressed the factors influencing reproductive success in captivity, including breeding behaviour and individual characteristics. Distance between individual pairs in their cages, female nesting activity and male origin were the best predictors of success. Recommendations for managers are made.</description><creator>Fraser, Sarah Jane.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Loggerhead shrike -- Radio tracking -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Loggerhead shrike -- Reintroduction -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Captive wild birds -- Breeding -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Loggerhead shrike -- Québec (Province) -- Reproduction.</subject><title>Assessing a Loggerhead shrike captive-release program using reproductive success and telemetry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sarah Jane Fraser, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n2741.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623h79m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c2501</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Coherent X-ray diffraction and X-ray Intensity Fluctuation Spectroscopy (XIFS) are ideal methods and techniques to perform measurements on the dynamics of fluctuations in condensed matter materials. To investigate more systems and faster fluctuations by being able to tune the coherence length, we use a zone plate to change the coherence length and beam size but keep most of the intensity. Using the zone plate, experiments were carried out to measure the properties of the focused beam. We applied a formalism to calculate the effect of optics on coherence. We tested our results by doing measurement at Advanced Photon Source. We measured the focal properties of the zone plate, speckle sizes and contrast, obtained by using coherent X-ray diffraction from an disordered Fe3Al crystals. Our theoretical calculations are compared with the experimental results.</description><creator>Feng, Zhenxing, 1982-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Coherence (Optics)</subject><subject>Speckle.</subject><subject>X-rays -- Diffraction.</subject><subject>X-ray spectroscopy.</subject><title>Experimental and theoretical investigation of the coherent x-ray propagation and diffraction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Zhenxing Feng, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v6841.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c2501</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tr15d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The fuel ethanol industry is now making use of a very efficient process where virtually all sugar substrates are converted to ethanol. Nevertheless, some metabolic by-products excreted from Saccharomyces cerevisiae tend to reduce the ethanol yield. Of such, glycerol is the major one, accounting for about 5-10% relative to the amount of ethanol produced. Glycerol plays an important role in maintaining the redox balance within the cells by oxidizing the cytosolic NADH under anaerobic conditions. It is also believed that it acts as an osmoprotectant and would be favourably produced in high osmotic pressure conditions. In order to mitigate the production of glycerol, various aeration strategies were investigated in a single-stage continuous fermentation system. Oxygen dissolved in the fermentation medium put the yeast in aerobiosis, acted as an oxidizing agent and hence minimised the specific glycerol production by 36% as compared to a completely anaerobic fermentation. This has hardly been reproduced in a more industrially relevant system using a multi-stage continuous fermentation process. Indeed, oscillations in the concentrations of the various metabolites over time made difficult the assessment of significant changes. Nevertheless, these findings open the door to further investigations in order to understand the effect of oxygen in continuous fermentations using very high gravity feeds, such as in the fuel ethanol industry.</description><creator>Cyr, Normand.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Alcohol as fuel.</subject><subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Biotechnology.</subject><title>Effect of aeration strategy on the performance of a very high gravity continuous fuel ethanol fermentation process</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Normand Cyr, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gs42n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tr15d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42700</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>