<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:49:58Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25175" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021f855</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the last years, brane world scenarios have been studied  extensively, but most of these studies have been done in the case of  five-dimensional spacetime. It is therefore of interest to investigate which of the  particular features observed are proper to one extra dimension and which are generic  to any number of dimensions. In this thesis, I present an overview of models and  solutions to Einstein's equations for six-dimensional brane world scenarios.  Solutions for a simple setup with cylindrically symmetric bulk centered about a  three-brane are derived and classified. There are two main kinds of topology: either  solutions are compactified in a spherical topology, closed up by another  three-brane, or they have a disc topology, which must be terminated by a four-brane.  One of the particular features of codimension-two branes is demonstrated, namely  that their tension, or vacuum energy, induces a deficit angle in the bulk. Solutions  for different arrangements of codimension-one and codimension-two branes are also  reviewed. Although the review focuses on topological and cosmological properties of  the solutions, models using a field theoretical approach to the brane-world  scenario, i.e. considering the brane as a topological defect arising from higher  dimensional fields, are also considered.</description><creator>Descheneau, Julie</creator><contributor>Cline, James M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>A review of six-dimensional braneworld solutions /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d7092.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021f855</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn009z373</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>B6.YTIR sex-reversed mice with bilateral ovaries develop an  apparently normal female phenotype, but their eggs fail to develop after  fertilization. Our previous studies have shown that the primary cause of infertility  in the XY female can be attributed to the incompetence of its oocytes for  postfertilization development rather than their surrounding somatic cells. The  objective of this study was to examine the segregation of chromosomes during two  successive meiotic divisions in the oocytes from XY females and the oocytes from XX  females as a control. Oocyte-cumulus complexes were collected from gonadotropin  (PMSG)-primed ovaries and matured in culture. MII-oocytes after culture for 19--21  hours were activated by 5mM SrCl2. The number and arrangement of chromosomes were  observed under a light microscope with phase contrast or processed for FISH to  identify the X and Y chromosomes under a fluorescence microscope. The oocytes at  varying times of culture and after activation were fixed and immunocytochemically  stained for observation of microtubule assembly and cell cycle progression.</description><creator>Chen, Hai Ying</creator><contributor>Taketo, Teruko (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>The defects in the oocytes of B6.Ytir sex-reversal female mice /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784m36g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z373</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977v472</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Eilenberg has shown that the notion of varieties in  semigroups/monoids can be naturally made to correspond with varieties of languages  that they recognize. This has significantly deepened and organized our understanding  of finite automata and regular languages. Several researchers have later recognized  that the more appropriate algebraic objects to look into are finite categories which  generalize monoids in a way that is explained in the work. This point of view not  only refines the existing theory but is indispensable when dealing with serial  decompositions of automata. In this thesis we try to advance this theory by  exploring the connections between the algebraic structure of a finite category and  the combinatorial description of languages recognized by it which is a central theme  of algebraic theory of automata. The method of congruence has proved quite successful in the  study of languages recognized by finite monoids. In this thesis we show that this  method remains powerful and successful even in the categorical setting. Using graph  congruences, we obtain some new proofs of old results and some completely new  results.</description><creator>Chattopadhyay, Arkadev</creator><contributor>Therien, Denis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Languages recognized by finite categories</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bf570.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977v472</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f178d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The gait pattern during treadmill walking is comparable with  overground walking in healthy subjects, but the effects due to the mode of walking  in stroke subjects have not been established. Purpose. (1) To compare the maximum  gait speed of stroke subjects walking on treadmill vs. the ground. (2) To estimate  the temporal-distance determinants of the maximal gait speed. (3) To compare  temporal distance factors and body kinematics of stroke subjects walking at  comfortable vs. maximum speeds during the two modes of locomotion. Subjects. Ten  subjects (aged 63 +/- 19 years) with a hemiparesis due to a stroke (&lt;3  months) were tested. Methods. Subjects walked at comfortable and maximal speeds on  the treadmill and overground, and gait outcomes were thus compared. Results.  Overground walking resulted in higher maximal speeds, greater stride lengths and a  lower cadence, as compared to treadmill. The comfortable gait speed and the maximum  stride length proved to be strong determinants for the maximal speed on both modes  of locomotion, but the maximum cadence was correlated to maximum speed only  overground. At matched speed, the hip and knee joint demonstrated greater excursion  overground for both the paretic and nonparetic sides. Conclusions. Stroke subjects  walked slower on the treadmill as compared to overground. Furthermore, a different  strategy was implemented to increase gait speed on each surface. A guarded gait  pattern was evident in the lower extremity kinematic patterns during treadmill  ambulation, perhaps due to muscle weakness, reduced stability and fear of falling on  the treadmill.</description><creator>Bayat, Roain</creator><contributor>Lamontagne, Anouk (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Treadmill and overground walking : the effects of speed on gait outcomes in subjects with stroke</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qj291.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f178d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62f8829</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A subset of the leukaemic clone, the leukaemic stem cell  (L-HSC), is responsible for the maintenance and propagation of a leukaemia. Most  current therapies, however, do not target this population. In this thesis, I show  that a determinant of disease phenotype is the frequency of the leukaemic stem cell  within the leukaemic population. Moreover, the frequency of L-HSC in a leukaemia is  predetermined by the inherent properties of the cell that is transformed and can be  attributed to the ontogenic origin of the cell. Ideal therapies would specifically  target mechanistic defects in leukaemic stem cells; however, the pathways that are  involved and what oncogenic defects can be targeted for therapy remain to be  discovered. As it is not known if all oncogenes can be targeted or what the  determinants of oncogenic dependency are, I have developed a system to further  elucidate this as described herein.</description><creator>Austin, Pamela M.</creator><contributor>Sauvageau, Guy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Defining biological properties of the leukaemic stem cell in Hoxa9Meis1-induced leukaemia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83kz986.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f8829</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dm936</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tethered satellites systems have been studied for several  decades from which the concept of tether-connected space manipulators developed. The  advantages of such robots derive from the extensive reach that can be provided by  the tether. This would benefit applications such as satellite repair and space  debris removal. This thesis first examines the dynamics of a tethered space  manipulator as its end-effector traces a prescribed trajectory. The platform, to  which the robot arm is attached, is postulated to be much larger than the other  components of the system and is specified to follow a circular orbit around Earth.  The tether is modelled as a straight rigid rod and the motion of the system is  assumed to be restricted to the orbital plane. The tether tension is monitored to  ensure that the tether is not subjected to compressive forces. The system is also studied under torque restrictions; namely,  the torques acting on the tether attachment points are set to zero. The possible  trajectories traced by the end-effector of this constrained system are investigated.  In addition, a method is outlined to determine a feasible end-effector path between  two given points while satisfying the zero-torque constraint on the  tether.</description><creator>Woo, Ming-Yin Priscilla, 1978-</creator><contributor>Misra, Arun K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>Planar dynamics of tethered space manipulators</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rv04h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dm936</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fh74j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This paper examines the dynamics of a tether connected  multi-spacecraft system, arranged in a wheel-spoke configuration, in the vicinity of  the L 2 Lagrangian point of the Sun-Earth system. First, the equations of motion of  a N-body system are obtained and equilibrium configurations of the system are  determined and small motions about one of these configurations are analyzed. Then, a  numerical analysis of the free tether libration is carried out for a three-mass case  when the system is near L2 and the parent mass is assumed to be in a halo orbit of  different sizes. Finally, a set of control goals are defined and a time domain state  feedback control system is integrated into the numerical model. The performance of  the control system is tested under different conditions.</description><creator>Wong, Brian, 1978-</creator><contributor>Misra, Arun (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>Dynamics of a multi-tethered satellite system near the sun-earth Lagrangian point</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848r18v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh74j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722h9474</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, a novel 6 degree-of-freedom parallel mechanism  is evaluated as a flight simulator motion base. The mechanism consists of three  fixed-length legs, each supported by a three-wheeled mobile robot. The three legs  support a platform, which acts as the end-effector of the mechanism. Thus, the  mechanism has the advantage of portability and simple design, because of the  specific actuating system. Two different designs are evaluated: one with ball joints  at the upper ends of the legs and revolute joints at the lower ends and one with the  opposite configuration. The inverse kinematics and inverse dynamics analysis of the  mechanism, including its actuation system, is conducted. Our simulations lead us to  conclude that the configuration with the ball joints at the lower ends of the legs  performs better. The mechanism is then evaluated as a motion base for a flight  simulator, using typical aircraft maneuvers. Certain problems are observed that make  this application questionable. However, the mechanism shows potential as a motion  base for a driving simulator, which is certainly worth exploring  further.</description><creator>Rekleitis, Georgios</creator><contributor>Meyer, Nahon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Modeling and evaluation of a new parallel mechanism as a flight simulator motion base</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z140p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722h9474</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c8121</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The vibrations caused by road imperfections, which are  transmitted to a car frame through the suspension, are one of the major sources of  ambient noise inside the passenger compartment of an automobile. A solution to this problem is the addition of  feedback-controlled actuators between the suspension attachment points and the car  frame. These actuators can be driven to provide an active control of the vibrations,  thus reducing greatly the magnitude of the forces exerted on the car frame at the  suspension attachment points. In order to implement a robust yet effective  controller, a model of a ¼ car suspension (suspension associated to a  single wheel) is derived from experimentally acquired data. The structure's modal  parameters are extracted from Frequency Response data, and are used to obtain a  state-space realization. The performance of controller design techniques such as LQR  and Hinfinity is assessed through simulation using the model of the  suspension.</description><creator>Roumy, Jean-Gabriel</creator><contributor>Boulet, Benoit (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Automotive.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Active control of vibrations transmitted through a car suspension</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gg98g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c8121</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214p68m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The re-circulating region of the turbulent flow produced by a  sudden lateral expansion in the width of an open-channel flow was study  experimentally for the effect of bed friction on the flow. Dye was introduced into  the recirculating region at a steady rate and the depth-averaged concentration of  the dye was determined by the video imaging method. Instantaneous dye concentration  images were recorded by a digital video camera. The advantage of video imaging  method is its simplicity and its ability to acquire data over a large area of the  turbulent flow at the condition when the lighting condition is highly  non-uniform. Experiments of the re-circulating flow were conducted over a  range of water depth to study the friction effect on the transverse mixing by the  horizontal turbulence. A series of four tests was carried out. Mean concentration and root-mean-square concentration profiles  were obtained at a number of cross sections along the flow in the open channel. The  data were analysed for the length of the recirculating eddies, the width of the  mixing layer, the width of the wake, and the dominant period of the flow  oscillation. The dye concentration in the wake as an indicator of the mixing process  by the horizontal turbulence, is a strong function of the bed-friction number. The  results obtained from the present measurements have shown the friction effect on the  horizontal turbulence to be far more significant than that was able to be detected  by the previous investigation conducted in a smaller facilities using a light  absorption probe.</description><creator>Liu, Fang, 1971-</creator><contributor>Chu, V. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Recirculating flow by video imaging method</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w534n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214p68m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q455t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experimental investigation is presented for the aeroelastic  response of a two-degree-of-freedom airfoil positioned in an incompressible flow. In  particular, the effects of cubic structural nonlinearities in the pitch  degree-of-freedom are considered. These nonlinearities are introduced via a  specially designed pitch cam, which permits different degrees of nonlinearity, as  well as a linear system, to be obtained. Several linear and nonlinear system tests are presented, and the  results compared and analyzed. The effects of linear plunge stiffness on the  stability of the aeroelastic system are discussed, and the nonlinear system response  is studied for different degrees of cubic nonlinearity in pitch. In several nonlinear system tests, limit cycle oscillations  (LCO) are observed when the air speed is above the linear flutter speed. The effects  of airfoil initial conditions and air speeds on the LCO amplitude, frequency, and  convergence rate are studied. The effective linear flutter speed is predicted using the  so-called "flutter-margin" method for both the linear and nonlinear cases.  The prediction results for the nonlinear cases are compared with those for the  linear cases and with the actual flutter speed.</description><creator>Liang, Lijun</creator><contributor>Price, Stuart J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>Experimental investigation of an aeroelastic structure with continuous nonlinear stiffness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246s67v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q455t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26xx86s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The degradation of common di-ester plasticizers, including  di-2-ethylhexyl phthalate, di-2-ethylhexyl adipate and di-(propylene glycol)  dibenzoate, by several strains of soil bacteria has been previously shown to lead to  an accumulation of metabolites that are more toxic than the parent compounds. This  research has shown that the pattern of degradation of these plasticizers can be  significantly different in the presence of biosurfactants or synthetic surfactants.  In particular, the additions of surfactin, sophorolipid or Pluronic L122 to cultures  of Bacillus subtilis each resulted in increases in the quantities of the first  metabolites in the plasticizer degradation pathway. One of these was 2-ethylhexanol,  which had been previously shown to be the most toxic intermediate released during  plasticizer degradation. The other was mono-2-ethylhexyl adipate, the mono-ester  released from the hydrolysis of di-2-ethylhexyl adipate. This compound was isolated  in this work and found to have a toxicity comparable to that of  2-ethylhexanol. The cause of the significant accumulation of the first and most  toxic plasticizer metabolites in the presence of surfactants was investigated.  Results were obtained that suggested that the action of the surfactants was to  sequester these initial metabolites. The effect of this would be to reduce the  observed rates of subsequent degradation of these two intermediates to less toxic  compounds.</description><creator>Grochowalski, Adam</creator><contributor>Cooper, David G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Microbial degradation of Di-ester plasticizers in the presence of surfactants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kt432.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26xx86s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mq33c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The production of sophorolipids from the yeast Candida bombicola  (ATCC 22214) was studied. Heptadecane resulted in the highest percentage of direct  incorporation into the sophorolipid products of all the hydrocarbon substrates used.  The diacetylated lactone form of the sophorolipid product was favoured when the  hydroxycarboxylic acid was sixteen or seventeen carbon atoms long. Crystalline  product was only obtained when a high degree of uniformity of both the type of  sophorolipid and the number of carbon atoms in the fatty acid part of this lipid was  achieved. These conditions were only met when the hydrocarbon substrate was  hexadecane or heptadecane and the specific products in these cases were diacetylated  lactones. The surface properties of the sophorolipids were analyzed using  a modified evaporating drop technique. The lactone sophorolipids were more effective  at reducing the surface tension of water than the acid sophorolipids. This could be  part of the explanation for the fact that the lactones have been shown to be more  effective than the acid form of the sophorolipids for several different  applications.</description><creator>Glenns, Robert N.</creator><contributor>Cooper, D. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Structures and properties of Sophorolipids from Candida bombicola</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579s80w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mq33c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cw91m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experimental study of spatially periodic fully developed  flows of air in straight rectangular ducts with interrupted-plate inserts is  presented. These flows have features similar to those produced in plate-fin passages  of compact heat exchanger cores. The formulation of mathematical models and  numerical solution methods for the prediction of these flows continues to be a  challenging and largely unattained goal. The main goal of this work is to contribute  experimental results suitable for testing and refining such models and solution  methods. Airflows in nine different interrupted-plate rectangular ducts were  considered. Reynolds numbers considered (based on Kays and London's definition of  hydraulic diameter and the maximum average streamwise velocity) ranged from about  2,000 to 65,000. Time-mean static pressure distributions along the axial centreline  of the top wall of the ducts, and module friction factor versus Reynolds number  data, all in the spatially periodic fully developed region, were  obtained.</description><creator>Candanedo Ibarra, José A.</creator><contributor>Baliga, B. Rabi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Time-mean wall static pressure distributions and module friction factors for spatially periodic fully developed flows in interrupted-plate rectangular ducts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gh009.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cw91m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074v76s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>RHex is a man-packable, six-legged robotic platform capable of  traversing highly varied and rugged terrain, as well as running up to five body  lengths per second. This thesis describes the development of two gaits for RHex:  bounding and stair descent. The procedures involved in the development of these  gaits are the analysis of video footage of experimental operation and logged-data  analysis. Important elements of the functioning bounding gait are proper touchdown  detection and energy storage in the compliant legs. For stair descent, the important  element is control of the sliding motion of the robot body on the stair. A  description of the platform is also presented.</description><creator>Campbell, Donald, 1978-</creator><contributor>Buehler, Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Bounding and stair descent in the hexapod RHex</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214p71x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074v76s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pt354</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This paper examines the way in which two contemporary Canadian  women writers, Anne Carson and Gail Scott, integrate subjective theory into two of  their respective texts (Carson's Men In the Off Hours, and Scott's Main Brides).  This study rejects the presentation of a single protagonist and instead focuses  heavy emphasis upon the presentation of subjective experiments. In this paper the  subjects in Men In the Off Hours and Main Brides are examined through the desires  they exhibit for the absent other---that which the subject perceives he/she does not  have---as central to his/her own conception of him/her self. The paper first  acknowledges that subjective theory, the quest for the self, has maintained a  central position in scholarly studies. It then proceeds to disseminate and critique  Lacanian subjective theory thereby setting the stage for close readings of Carson's  Men In the Off Hours through theorist Julia Kristeva's notion of abjection, and of  Scott's Main Brides through Jacques Derrida's theory of the borderline. The paper  closes by questioning the possibility of a fully realized subject.</description><creator>Wunker, Erin</creator><contributor>Cooke, Nathalie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Carson, Anne, 1950- . Men in the off hours</subject><subject>Self in literature</subject><subject>Scott, Gail. Main brides</subject><title>Borders of becoming : an examination into absence and desire for self and subjectivity in Anne Carson's Men in the off hours and Gail Scott's Main brides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tv68z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pt354</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff365571b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This phenomenographic study explores the intentions, ideals, and  practices that shape educational leaders' conceptions of curriculum integration. The  study uses documents and interviews to analyse the integrative elements of three of  Quebec's key educational reform documents: The final report from the commissioners  of the Estates General on Education; Reaffirming the mission of our schools: Report  of the task force on curriculum reform ; and the Quebec Education Program. Fifteen  curriculum reform leaders who participated in the process of drafting these  documents were interviewed about their conceptions of curriculum integration. The  conceptual framework used to study Quebec's conceptions of curriculum integration  stemmed from the review of the research literature. This study's revised framework  may provide curriculum developers and other educational leaders with a template for  exploring integrative intents, ideals, and practices coherent with their  conceptions.</description><creator>Younk, Karina</creator><contributor>Lusthaus, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Curriculum change -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Curriculum planning -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>One province's conception of curriculum integration : transforming educational reform ideals into the Québec education program</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343s83g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365571b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547s01b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis discusses the prohibition of human cloning in  contemporary Islamic legal discourse, which relies on two distinct doctrines: the  first seeks support in the Qur'anic text, while the second depends on method of  utilitarian legal hermeneutics (al-istiṣlaḥ ). These  doctrines are examined by comparing them to the method that contemporary Islamic  legal discourse adopts, namely, uṣul al-fiqh. When this is done, a  discrepancy emerges in the first doctrine that traces this prohibition back to the  text of revelation, which in turn requires further clarification of the foundations  of hermeneutics in uṣul al-fiqh---identified here as textual and  legislative consistency. For this, Shaṭibi's theory of  maqaṣid al-sharī'ah offers one of the most reliable bases  for the hermeneutics to evaluate the second doctrine. The methodological venture in  this thesis aims at criticizing the current methodology while at the same time  offering a justified approach to hermeneutics in contemporary Islamic legal  discourse and in the case of human cloning.</description><creator>Obiedat, Ahmad Z.</creator><contributor>Hallaq, Wael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Islamic law</subject><subject>Human cloning -- Moral and ethical aspects</subject><subject>Hermeneutics -- Religious aspects -- Islam</subject><title>Uṣūl al-fiqh hermeneutics as reflected on the debate on human cloning : a critical analysis of contemporary Islamic legal discourse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m232n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547s01b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pt36d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The fantastic stands as an important part of Chinese culture. It  is in fact through its literature that it has been made possible for us to enjoy  this heritage. With the study of fantastic tales and anomaly accounts, this thesis  tackles the problem of rationalism in relation with supernatural. It attempts to  understand the mechanisms of the intermingling of the concepts of fiction and  history, through the comparison of Chinese historical and fictional texts, as well  as parallels between China and Europe. It will also deal with the concepts of  nature, in both the perspectives of China and Europe, and the  Enlightenment.</description><creator>Pelletier, Valérie</creator><contributor>Button, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Supernatural in literature -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Legends -- China -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Legends -- Europe -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Etude sur l'entremêlement des concepts d'histoire et de fiction dans la littérature historique et fantastique en Chine</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t254w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pt36d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wq814</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A major environmental concern throughout the tropics is  deforestation. While many forests are in a state of crisis, such an encompassing  narrative can obscure significant instances where forest-cover expands. This  research investigates the geography of forest regeneration in rural Costa Rica from  a social and institutional perspective. Attracted to the Pacific coast, foreigners  purchase farms, change the patterns of land ownership, and extensively promote  secondary forest growth. Environmental change and a declining agriculture sector  have forced peasants to sell or abandon land and diversify their livelihoods. Two  conservation NGOs collaborate at an institutional level to promote reforestation and  consolidate protected properties into the Mesoamerican Biological Corridor. Drawing  on foreign funding, they serve as an avenue through which external visions of land  management become reproduced locally. This case illustrates how the values and  management decisions of a constellation of actors synergistically interlink to  influence local land-use and ultimately join to expand forest-cover.</description><creator>Ibrahim, Camellia Klara</creator><contributor>Meredith, Thom C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Forest regeneration -- Costa Rica</subject><subject>Land use -- Costa Rica</subject><title>Changing communities, expanding forests : how constellations of actors change land-use and forest-cover in southwest Costa Rica</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722h948d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wq814</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w290z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the emergence of the modern state of  Afghanistan and the consequences of centralization of power, as well as the creation  of a national myth, for the Hazara people, one of the country's most significant  minorities. The Hazaras, who inhabit the central highlands of Afghanistan  and constitute around 20% of the national population, have not only been  marginalized economically and socially, but have also been denied a place in the  history of the country. The thesis investigates their history over the last century  and charts their struggles in the light of the last two decades of upheaval in  Afghanistan, arguing that accommodation and compromise with the ethnic minorities is  essential to building a modern, post-Ṭaliban  Afghanistan.</description><creator>Hussain, Mohammad, 1962-</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. U. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Hazāras</subject><subject>Afghanistan -- Ethnic relations</subject><title>The Hāzaras of Afghanistan : a study of ethnic relations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t63m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w290z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z839j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explores the relationships among technology, language  literacy and instruction in University Continuing Education Institutions. Adult  second language education strives to update media resources in an information era in  which literacy encompasses the abilities to communicate both in different languages  and in a variety of media across disciplines. The main assumption underlying this study is that teaching  adults to use language in an era in which networks and multimedia are major  components, is a challenging task and responsibility. Instructional implications of  literature regarding the implementation of new technologies in language learning  suggest a persistent disagreement on the merits of new technologies as learning  tools and a mismatch between expectations and applications of new media. I interview  four teachers of second or foreign languages to adults to explore the challenges  embedded in mediating adults' literacy in using multiple representations of second  language knowledge within technology enhanced classroom  environments. Teachers are shown to integrate digital technologies into  traditional print and audiovisual tools to advance three main literacies: Cultural  literacy relates to the ability to make socioculturally appropriate links of  language and media. Disciplinary literacy denotes the ability to effectively  identify, analyze, evaluate and apply language resources in various contexts. Media  literacy denotes the ability to make informed choices among the various language  representations. Integrated media applications are challenging for teachers who need  to be aware of media benefits and constraints. The ongoing development of teachers'  media literacy is a prerequisite for meaningful and constructive uses of the  instructional resources available that will enable adults to apply second language  knowledge within and beyond linguistic, cultural, and disciplinary  contexts.</description><creator>Georganta, Angeliki</creator><contributor>Maguire, Mary H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Second language acquisition</subject><subject>Continuing education.</subject><subject>Language and languages -- Study and teaching (Adult education)</subject><subject>Adult learning.</subject><subject>Educational technology.</subject><title>Integrating new technologies in university second language instruction : teachers' perspectives</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mq35x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z839j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nh68b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As a result of migratory movements in recent decades, an  increasing number of children are educated in a language which is not their mother  tongue. For these children, learning to read takes place in their second language.  This learning context is made unique by two challenges. First, the learning of the  written code occurs simultaneously with the learning of the oral language. Second,  no reference to the written code of the maternal language is made available to these  children. This particular learning context can lead to inequity between  the second language learner and his or her unilingual peers in terms of phonetic  encoding and decoding. Furthermore, the limited vocabulary of a beginning language  learner can impede the direct lexical access used when learning to  read. Fourteen students were evaluated for their metalinguistical  abilities, lexical and phonic knowledge. Following these tests, an analysis was  conducted of student reading errors made in a real reading context. This descriptive study explores the interaction between reading  strategies used by second language learners: bottom-up (word comprehension derived  from the context of the text) and top-down (text comprehension derived from word  recognition). In addition, this study seeks to describe the linguistic and  metalinguistic abilities of these second language students in the process of  learning to read.</description><creator>Gagné, Andréanne</creator><contributor>Sarkar, Mela (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Second language acquisition</subject><title>Acquisition de la lecture en langue seconde : profil des stratégies utilisées par les apprentis lecteurs</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vt982.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nh68b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451j11q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main premise of this thesis is to demonstrate how the  Gypsies, (Roma)---both Muslim and Christian, both settled and nomadic---were  marginalized by the Ottoman State and society in Rumelia (Rumili) and Istanbul  during the "Classical Age" of this tri-continental Islamic  Empire. The Ottoman state and the society's attitudes towards this  marginal group are analyzed through the examination of the Muhimme Registers of the  second half the sixteenth century and four major Kanunnames concerning the Gypsies  issued in the fifteenth and sixteenth centuries. Travelers' accounts and Turkish  oral traditions have also been used to explore the social status of the Gypsies in  Ottoman society, as well as their image in Ottoman popular culture. The history of people who were marginal and voiceless in their  societies is not just important for its own sake but for what it reveals about the  nature of the societies in which they lived. Thus, this present work not only sheds  light upon the history of the Gypsies but also attempts to open new grounds for  further discussions on the functioning of the "Plural Society" of the  Ottoman Empire.</description><creator>Çelik, Faika</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Romanies -- Balkan Peninsula -- History</subject><subject>Romanies -- History</subject><subject>Turkey -- History -- Ottoman Empire, 1288-1918</subject><subject>Romanies -- Turkey -- History</subject><title>Gypsies (Roma) in the orbit of Islam : the Ottoman experience (1450-1600)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gt267.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451j11q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zr319</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Silence has traditionally been analysed in linguistic terms as  those moments of non-speech/non-sound interspersed between words and sounds. I will  attempt to take this academic reasoning further to deconstruct established notions  of silence and incorporate contemporary methods of investigation to arrive at a more  viable and dynamic observation of the event. Silence goes beyond this simple  dualistic and binary contrast and I believe may reveal itself as negotiator of  language, wherein the impossibility of an absolute truth is translated into the  imminent. This thesis will be an attempt at a discourse that redefines silence's  fleeting site as an impending source for the political as such.</description><creator>Chbib, Bachar</creator><contributor>Straw, Will (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Silence</subject><title>The politics of silence /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wj93q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zr319</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25200</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>