<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:21:28Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33175" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g913p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent anatomical investigations have revealed that the striatum is an intrinsically heterogeneous structure that forms multiple parallel circuits with different cortical areas. The present series of experiments investigated the possibility that such anatomical diversity may promote functional differences between subregions of the rat dorsal striatum. Using different versions of the water maze and radial arm maze tasks, evidence is presented showing that the medial and lateral subregions of the caudate-putamen make distinct contributions to behaviors guided by either ambient spatial or discrete cues. The findings support a multiple subsystems view of dorsal striatal function. Specifically, the lateral (sensorimotor-innervated) caudate-putamen may mediate the process of habit formation based on simple stimulus-response associations, whereas the medial (limbic-innervated) caudate-putamen may contribute to the cognitive/spatial control of behavior in competitive response situations. Further evidence is presented suggesting that the medial caudate-putamen is functionally related to the hippocampal system. Together, these structures may form a functional limbic circuit that mediates the serial processing of cognitive/spatial information.</description><creator>Devan, Bryan David.</creator><contributor>White, Norman M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Hippocampus (Brain)</subject><subject>Rats -- Physiology.</subject><subject>Neostriatum.</subject><title>Functional organization of the dorsal striatum : comparison to the hippocampal system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z519.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g913p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qk54k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study describes a laboratory scale development of an in-situ bioremediation method, which uses a water table management system to supply nutrients to subsoil microorganisms, for biostimulation and subsequent biodegradation of pollutants such as fertilizer-nitrate and hydrocarbons (e.g., diesel oils), in the unsaturated zone of the soil. The study, which was divided into two parts: first nitrate bioremediation and secondly diesel biodegradation, was carried out on packed soil columns. For the nitrate study, different levels of glucose were introduced into packed soil columns, 1,000 mm long x 200 mm, diameter, via subirrigation in order to supplement the organic carbon levels in the soil. Two sandy soils were used, with 1.6% and 3.4% organic matter content, respectively; and the water table in the soil columns was maintained at a depth of 350 mm below the surface. Fertilizer-nitrate was applied to the soil surface at a rate of 180 kg/ha nitrate-N. Simulated rainfall was used to leach nitrates to lower depths. The efficacy of using the subirrigation system, as a method for nutrient delivery in the bioremediation of leached nitrate, was monitored with time and with reference to the nitrate residue, redox potential of the soil solution, and solubilized Fe and Mn. Leached nitrate was denitrified to less than 10 mg/L nitrate-N, which is the limit permitted in drinking water. The ideal organic carbon range was considered to be the glucose level (20 mg/L glucose-C) that reduced mom nitrate and gave redox potential and soluble Fe and Mn levels, similar to the control soil solution, when subjected to 96 days of subirrigation. Successful delivery of nutrient for the bioremediation of nitrate, within the farm boundaries, will be considered a "break through" toward nitrate residue control if this novel approach to nitrate control is demonstrated in the field. The delivery method will offer a technical solution to on-farm nitrate pollution. It is inexpensive, easy to adopt, and does not require major changes in the current farm practices. In the second part of the study, a diesel contaminated sandy soil was packed in columns, 2,000 nun long x 200 nun diameter. The subirrigation method was used to supply two different combinations of treatments to the microorganisms in the soil for the biodegradation of the diesel namely: air, water and nutrients (N, P etc.), and air and water. The success of using subirrigation, to deliver nutrients to the soil in the columns, was monitored by measuring the trend in the reduction of soil diesel-TPH (diesel-total petroleum hydrocarbon) residue with time. Results obtained from the treated columns were compared with each other, and with the control columns undergoing passive biodegradation. The study showed that subirrigation can be used as a method of nutrient delivery in the -bioremediaton of diesel contaminated soil. The TPH in the contaminated soil decreased, from an initial 670 mg diesel TPH/kg soil to an acceptable level of 40 mg diesel TPH/kg soil, in 82 days in the columns subjected to a combination of nutrient, air and water treatments. If this method of delivering biostimulants to the subsoil microbial population is demonstrated in the field, it will be invaluable to in-situ bioremediation of contaminated soils.</description><creator>Ugwuegbu, Benjamin U.</creator><contributor>Prasher, S. O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>In situ bioremediation.</subject><subject>Soils -- Nitrate content.</subject><subject>Subirrigation.</subject><subject>Soil remediation.</subject><subject>Oil pollution of soils.</subject><title>A laboratory study on the development of a biological pollution control system for contaminated soils /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s1907.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk54k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wh77d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation presents two new systematic feedback approaches for set point feedback stabilization of drift free systems which employ Lie algebraic techniques. Due to some special features, drift free systems are known to be difficult to stabilize. For such systems, linearization, and state feedback linearization techniques, fail to be useful. In this dissertation two new feedback approaches the guiding functions approach and the trajectory interception approach are introduced. The importance of these approaches is due to their simplicity and the fact that they do not require any special transformation techniques. The guiding functions approach delivers piece-wise constant control sequences and relies on the construction of special guiding functions which are not Lyapunov functions. However, a comparison of their values allows to determine a desired direction of system motion and permits to construct a sequence of controls such that the sum of these guiding functions decreases in an average sense. The guiding functions strategy is first analysed with reference to systems which appear in a special rectified form and requires the construction of as many guiding functions as there are control variables. Later, this approach is extended to apply to general drift free systems and usually results in the construction of only a pair of guiding functions. The most important feature of this strategy is that it often leads to dead beat control. For higher order systems, a combined strategy which employs sinusoidal steering in conjunction with the guiding functions approach is also examined. The trajectory interception approach provides a universal method for the construction of time varying stabilizing feedback control for drift free systems. The resulting feedback law is a composition of a standard stabilising feedback control for a Lie bracket extension of the original system and a periodic continuation of a specific solution to an open loop, finite horizon control problem stated in terms of a formal equation on a Lie group. The open loop problem is solved as a trajectory interception problem in logarithmic coordinates of flows. The construction proposed in this approach demonstrates that synthesis of time varying feedback stabilizers for drift free systems can be viewed as a procedure of combining static feedback laws for a Lie bracket extension of the system. This approach is employed to drift free systems which are characterized by both nilpotent and non-nilpotent controllability Lie algebras. The applicability of both approaches is demonstrated on a variety of drift free systems with different algebraic structures: a unicycle, Brockett's system, a front wheel drive car, a rigid spacecraft, a hopping robot in flight phase, an underwater vehicle, a fire truck, a mobile robot with trailer, and a class of wheeled mobile robots. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Rehman, Fazal Ur</creator><contributor>Michalska, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Set point feedback stabilization of drift free systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q327r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh77d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418p94k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Equipment has been developed to test x-ray sensor designs suitable for texture analysis and plasticity prediction of rolled sheet in the production environment. A general method has been developed to optimize the complete sensor design by minimizing the rms error of the sensor's texture and property estimates for the sheet. A versatile reflection, x-ray diffraction sensor has been designed and built for the laboratory to test how accurately the optimized designs classify the quality of commercial rolled product. Experimental testing with the laboratory sensor was made on two sets of specimens: (1) a set of cold-rolled and annealed, interstitial-free steels; and (2) a set of hot-rolled, 3004 alloy aluminum sheets. Tests performed on the aluminum specimens showed that an optimized design sampling the mid-plane texture is able to classify the quality of the set's members; an optimized design sampling the surface texture can also perform the same classification. Tests performed on the steel specimens showed that an optimized design sampling the mid-plane texture can predict the average r-value, r¯, and the 2-fold anisotropy measure, (r90-r0)/2, with an accuracy of s = 0.10 and 0.03, respectively; an optimized design sampling the surface texture of the sheet can predict the same plasticity measures with an accuracy of s = 0.18 and 0.06. As a whole, the work has demonstrated the following: (1) workable reflection sensors can be developed for certain industrial applications; however, optimized transmission sensors are generally superior because the mid-plane texture leads to more accurate predictions, (2) statistically reliable predictions of the bulk texture and plasticity of commercial sheet can be made using specialized sensor designs that measure 10 to 50 pole densities, and (3) the general method developed to optimize the sensor design significantly reduces the sensor error---by as much as 140% over the unoptimized designs.</description><creator>Blandford, Peter.</creator><contributor>Szpunar, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Industrial.</subject><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>Equipment for testing X-ray methods for on-line texture measurement and plasticity prediction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd525.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418p94k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nz930</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Thesis is divided into three parts. First, it discusses the international setting of satellite communications, presenting the diversity of their legal regimes. It then addresses, in two subsequent parts, the two major regulatory markets which are moulding the evolution of the international setting of space-based communications. In a second part, it presents North-America which was the inceptor of the deregulation trend and of the LEO systems and which firmly holds the lead of the regulatory trend. Then, it addresses Western Europe which is attempting to exert a part of the control of the evolution of the LEO lion's share in a context of US regulatory and technical dominance. The outcome of this Thesis is multifold. The accent is given all along on the changes affecting the regulatory environment of space-based communications within space-law concepts and stresses the dominant relationship between state regulators and their corporate partners, with a constant questioning on the leeway that seems to characterise the evolution of the law of space applications. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Salin, Patrick A.</creator><contributor>Milde, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Mass Communications.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Regulatory changes affecting satellite communications in the late 1990s, for the benefit and in the interests of all countries?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698925j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nz930</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s420x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We present direct numerical simulations of the spatial development of a triad of normal mode perturbations to boundary layers with Falkner-Skan velocity profiles. The perturbations are comprised of a plane wave and a pair of oblique waves inclined at equal and opposite angles to the primary flow direction. The conditions for resonance are satisfied exactly and the phase speeds of the plane wave and the oblique waves are equal. As a result, all modes share a common critical layer, thereby facilitating a strong interaction. These oblique waves initially undergo a parametric type of subharmonic resonance, but the system becomes fully coupled. From that point on, the amplification of all modes, including the plane wave, substantially exceeds the predictions of linear stability theory. Good agreement is obtained with experimental results for small pressure gradients. We also present results for larger pressure gradients corresponding to incipient separation, where comparable experimental data are not available. For the numerical method, the unsteady Navier-Stokes equations were solved using a vorticity-velocity formulation for the disturbance variables. Fourier series were used in the spanwise direction. Both implicit Crank-Nicholson and explicit Runge-Kutta schemes were used in a time-splitting method. The spectral element method was utilized to discretize the velocity and vorticity equations in space. The resulting system of algebraic equations was solved by using the preconditioned conjugate gradient method. This avoids the formation of either element or global matrices to achieve high efficiency so the method is matrix-free. At the inflow boundary, the disturbance forcing used was provided by normal modes of linear stability theory. At the outflow boundary, the buffer domain technique was used to prevent convective wave reflection or upstream propagation. Within the buffer domain the behavior of the equations is parabolic rather than elliptic and it is added to the computational domain of interest.</description><creator>Liu, Chonghui.</creator><contributor>Maslowe, Sherwin A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Physics, Fluid and Plasma.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>A numerical investigation of instability and transition in adverse pressure gradient boundary layers /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cc64v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s420x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687k094</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Warm season grasses are increasingly being cultivated in North America for summer forage, soil conservation, and biomass production. In more northern environments, temperature and length of growing season have an overriding effect on the productivity of warm season grasses. There is limited information on the adaptability and production potential of warm season grasses in these short season areas. A study was conducted in south-western Quebec from 1993 to 1996 to evaluate the productivity of five species of warm season grasses. Phenological development, canopy leaf area development and architecture, radiation-use efficiency (RUE), yield and chemical composition were determined. In terms of phenology, there was a diversity of developmental patterns and the genotypes of greatest potential were characterised by early spring growth and late onset of dormancy in fall. Most of the genotypes that were early in spring growth were also early maturing and low yielding. Late maturing genotypes were generally late in spring growth, high yielding and generally of southern origin. Differences in developmental patterns were partly explained by differences in base temperatures for germination and growth, and growth rates. Seed osmoconditioning and/or matriconditioning alleviated effects of low temperatures on switchgrass seed germination and potential establishment. Maximum leaf area index ranged from 6.1 to 8 and the vertical leaf area distributions and light interception levels varied among genotypes. Average end of season biomass yields ranged from 8.5 to 14.4 Mg ha-1. Switchgrass rates of DM accumulation ranged from 175 to 191 kg ha-1 day-1 and RUE 0.89 to 1.1 g MJ-1 of incoming solar radiation. Moderate amounts of N fertilisation increased yield and quality of switchgrass, which could be harvested in a 2-cut system. NDF and ADF ranged from 77--88 and 46--57% respectively, and showed a rapid increase to a mid season plateau. Nitrogen concentrations declined curvilinearly wit</description><creator>Madakadze, Ignacio Casper.</creator><contributor>Smith, D. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Grasses -- Québec (Province) -- Growth.</subject><title>Physiology, productivity and utilisation of warm season (C4) grasses in a short growing season area</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vj49v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687k094</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n966n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>B lymphopoiesis in mouse bone marrow (BM) represents a delicate balance between B cell production and loss. The present study has aimed to examine the differentiation and selection of B lineage cells during their development in BM. A comparison has been made between two major B cell differentiation models, one based on BM cell fractions sorted by immunofluorescence labeling and flow cytometry of cell surface markers and the other using fluorescence microscopy of the B lineage differentiation markers, TdT and mu heavy chains of IgM. The results have revealed a heterogeneity of B cell differentiation stages within each sorted BM fraction, contributing toward a unified model of B cell development. To examine the nature of selection during B cell development, a variety of criteria have been used to demonstrate that B cell loss in BM takes the form of apoptotic cell death. The apoptotic incidences of B cells at various developmental stages ex vivo and the rates of entry into apoptosis analyzed by flow cytometry, have demonstrated that B cells are particularly prone to apoptosis at two differentiation stages, known to follow Ig VH gene rearrangement and antigen receptor expression, respectively. It has been revealed that intracellular levels of Bcl-2 and Bax proteins are developmentally regulated in precursor B cells and are involved in the control of B cell death in both normal and RAG-2 gene-deficient mouse BM. The use of IL-7 transgenic mice, IL-7 gene-deficient mice and stromal cell cocultures demonstrates that the stromal cell-derived cytokine, IL-7, exerts an anti-apoptotic effect, associated with changes in Bax/Bcl-2 ratio. Accelerated apoptosis in op/op mutant mice suggests an augmented B cell loss in the absence of CSF-1. The results demonstrate that the loss of B lineage cells in mouse BM involves programmed cell death at critical quality control checkpoints in B cell development, influenced by both intrinsic cellular mechanisms and microenvironmental factors</description><creator>Lu, Liwei.</creator><contributor>Osmond, Dennis G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>B lymphopoiesis and B cell selection by apoptosis in bone marrow of normal and gene-modified mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x314w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n966n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021g98f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the course of follow-up studies designed to assess the time to an event of interest, longitudinal variables are usually monitored. These longitudinal variables are often prognostic and, as such, are a potential rich source of information regarding the true time-to-event of censored subjects. In this thesis I propose methodology that uses information from markers, these longitudinal prognostic variables, to enhance inference on (i) parametric time-to-event models, (ii) semi-parametric models, in particular, Cox's (1972) model and (iii) log rank tests. Using simulations I determine if and by how much markers can enhance inference on these models and tests, as a function of a marker's prognostic ability. These simulations are based on a novel method of random data generation whose properties I also examine.</description><creator>MacKenzie, Todd.</creator><contributor>Abrahamowicz, Michal (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Gu, Ming Gao (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>The use of markers to enhance time-to-event analysis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m165.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g98f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386m17f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the last few years, a growing body of evidence revealed the involvement of the serotonin (5-HT) system in the therapeutic effect of antidepressant treatments. Hence, several investigations have suggested that long-term treatments with various classes of antidepressant drugs lead to an enhanced 5-HT neurotransmission. By using electrophysiological paradigms in the rat, the present research endeavour was undertaken to (1) investigate the role of different factors modulating central 5-HT neurotransmission and to assess interactions between the 5-HT and noradrenergic (NA) systems; (2) to further confirm the presence of an enhanced 5-HT neurotransmission following chronic antidepressant treatments. The study of the automodulation of 5-HT system via 5-HT3/4 receptor subtypes suggested that the suppressant effect, observed in vivo, of the prototypical 5-HT3 receptor agonist 2-methyl-5-HT on the firing activity of somatosensory and hippocampus pyramidal neurons was not mediated via 5-HT3 receptors but rather via 5-HT1A receptors. In contrast, the enhancing effect, observed in vitro , of 2-methyl-5-HT on the electrically-evoked release of [ 3H]-5-HT was mediated via 5-HT3 receptors. The reducing action of the 5-HT3/4 receptor ligand R-zacopride on the endogenous release of 5-HT induced by the electrical stimulation of the ascending 5-HT pathway was mediated via 5-HT4 receptors. The studies of the heteromodulation of 5-HT system induced by the alpha2-adrenoceptor antagonist mirtazapine showed that acute administration of mirtazapine produced a transient increase of the firing activity of dorsal raphe 5-HT and locus coeruleus NA neurons whereas long-term mirtazapine treatment produced a sustained increase of the firing activity of these two types of neurons. Both acute and chronic administration of mirtazapine antagonized the activation of alpha 2-adrenergic auto- and heteroreceptors in the dorsal hippocampus. The sustained enhancement of the firing activity of 5-HT and NA neurons and the desensitization of alpha2-adrenergic heteroreceptors on 5-HT terminals produced by long-term mirtazapine administration have been proposed to underlie the antidepressant activity of this drug. The study of the modulation of the 5-HT system via monoamine oxidase-A (MAO-A) inhibition revealed that short-term administration of the selective and reversible MAO-A inhibitor befloxatone reduced the firing activity of 5-HT neurons which is followed by a recovery after its long-term administration. Given that the firing activity of 5-HT neurons was even above the control value following short-term treatment with both befloxatone and the 5-HT1A receptor antagonist (--)pindolol, it is suggested that this combined treatment could be expected to produce the same
enhancing effect on 5-HT neurotransmission as after long-term treatment with befloxatone alone.
The study of the interaction between the S-HT and NA systems revealed that the suppressant
effect of the selective 5-HTIA receptor antagonist WAY 100635 on the firing activity of locus
coeruleus NA neurons \-vas due to an enhancement of the function of 5-HT neurons mediated via
presynaptic 5-HTlA receptors and postsynaptic 5-HT2A receptors. Finally, in the last study, it has
been demonstrated that chronic treatments with either befloxatone, mirtazapine, the selective S-HT
reuptake inhibitor paroxetine or with the partial 5-HTlA receptor agonist gepirone enhanced the
tonie activation of the postsynaptic S-HTIA receptors in the dorsal hippocampus, as revealed by
the enhancing effect of the administration of WAY 100635 on pyramidal neuronal firing activity.
These results constitute further direct evidence that an enhanced S-HT neurotransmission may
underlie the antidepressant response in humans and further emphasize the crucial role played by
the 5-HT system in regulation of mood.</description><creator>Haddjeri, Nasser.</creator><contributor>Blier, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Auto- and heteromodulation of the rat brain 5-HT system : involvement in the mechanism of action of antidepressant drugs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn50g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m17f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505224w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Composite materials can be produced through a novel process known as reactive plasma spray forming. This technique was used to fabricate Al-TiAl 3 composites by injecting both Al and TiCl4 vapor into a triple plasma system. The microstructures of the Al-TiAl3 composites were compared with those of more conventional processing routes. The resulting microstructures were strongly dependant on processing method. The cast microstructure exhibited an acicular morphology of TiAl3 in an Al matrix. Composites produced by powder metallurgy and vacuum plasma spray contained coarse equiaxed particles of the intermetallic phase whereas the microstructure of the reactive plasma sprayed material was very uniform and exhibited a very fine dispersion of TiAl3 in the matrix. It was demonstrated that the atomization process occurring prior to Al-TiCl 4 reaction has a strong effect on the product due to its control over the average particle size and consequently on the temperature of the plasma atomized particles. It was observed that coarse particles (&lt;100 mum) react only on the surface. Particle temperatures higher than 1340°C produce a uniform microstructure while lower temperatures result in only surface reacted particles. The study showed that the alignment of the plasma torches, small wire diameters, proper power to Al feed rate ratio, and the use of an accelerating nozzle decrease the average particle size of the sprayed materials. A non-uniform distribution of Ti was observed across the deposits produced through reactive plasma atomization and was attributed to non-uniform particle size, temperature, and velocity distributions across the atomization plume. Chlorine was detected in the product, and varied from 0.3 to 1.3 wt% depending on the experimental conditions. The chlorine was reduced to 0.1 wt% through vacuum sublimation after removal from the reaction chamber. The reactively produced bulk materials were porous and required further consolidation through hot rolling. The hot rolled and annealed materials tested at room temperature retain 75% of their strength after annealing for 196 hours at 300°C. The TEM analysis revealed the presence of very fine (60 nm) intermetallic phases in the microstructure after annealing at 300°C. The stability of such fine precipitates suggests that Al-TiAl3 composites would offer superior high temperature mechanical properties in comparison with conventional Al alloys.</description><creator>Entezarian, Majid.</creator><contributor>Drew, R. A. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Reactive plasma spray forming of Al-TiAl3 composites using a triple plasma system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236386d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505224w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085n058</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The human insulin-like growth factor-II is an important fetal mitogen with demonstrated effects on growth, proliferation and survival of a wide spectrum of cells and tissues in mice and humans. The transcriptional regulation of the gene (IGF2) is under developmental control and is subject to epigenetic and genetic effects. At the epigenetic level, the mouse gene is parentally imprinted with exclusive expression of the paternally-inherited gene copy in most of the tissues examined. In this work, we demonstrate that the human gene is also subject to genomic imprinting and that the trait is tissue-specific and polymorphic whose basis may be genotype-dependent. Additionally, we show that in culture, primary placental fibroblasts lose the ability to functionally imprint IGF2. In instances of biallelic IGF2 gene expression, both in human tissue as well as in culture, we observe that the adjacent, reciprocally-imprinted H19 gene, which is normally expressed from the maternally-transmitted allele, is undetectable. The imprinted IGF2 gene is located in close physical proximity to a variable number of tandem repeats (VNTR) sequence polymorphism that is found upstream of the insulin gene promoter, in humans. Alleles of the VNTR have demonstrated transcriptional effects on insulin gene expression in human fetal and adult pancreas in vivo and in pancreatic beta cells in vitro. In this work, we show that the VNTR also has allelic effects on IGF2 expression in human placenta in vivo and on INS-IGF2 reporter gene activity in human lymphoblasts, in vitro. Alleles of the 5' INS (VNTR) are associated with susceptibility to type I diabetes mellitus. The preferential transmission of paternal susceptibility haplotypes at this locus suggests the functional involvement of a nearby imprinted gene in the susceptibility to type I diabetes. The demonstration of allelic effects of the VNTR on IGF2 mRNA levels, in vivo and in vitro, makes IGF2 an attractive functional candidate.</description><creator>Giannoukakis, Nick.</creator><contributor>Deal, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Polychronakos, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>The genetic and epigenetic regulation of insulin-like growth factor II gene expression in humans /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx217.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085n058</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zz328</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>These studies investigated relationships between the working alliance, client good moments, therapist verbal response modes, and client experiencing. Correlations between increased levels of the working alliance and increased occurrence of good moments were only between the bond aspect of the alliance and good moments of provision of significant information. The best fitting models of the working alliance, therapist verbal response modes, and client good moments indicated that a 3-way interaction was a good fit in the provision of significant information modality. Two-way interactions between the working alliance and therapist response modes revealed that low structure response modes, Particularly reflection/restatement occurred more frequently than expected at moderate alliance levels, and high structure interventions, particularly direct guidance/advice, occurred more frequently than expected at low and high affiance levels. It was suggested that the context of collaboration and liking (high alliance), and the context of struggle (low alliance), may be having an influence that prompts therapists to structure their interventions. The interactions between the working alliance and good moments in the exploratory and affective/expressive modalities showed that the high proportions of good moments occurred in the high and low working alliance sessions. The lowest proportions of good moments occurred in the moderate alliance sessions suggesting that different processes may be in operation at different alliance levels. The best fitting models of interactions of client experiencing, therapist verbal response modes, and client good moments in indicated that 2-way interactions best explained the data. In general, as experiencing levels rose, there were increases in the frequency of occurrence of client good moment. The interactions between therapist verbal response modes and experiencing indicated that specific levels of experiencing seem to be associated with specific c</description><creator>Fitzpatrick, Marilyn.</creator><contributor>Stalikas, Anastassios (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Psychotherapy.</subject><subject>Therapist and patient.</subject><title>The working alliance, therapist interventions, client experiencing, and client good moments : a psychotherapy process study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rj92c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz328</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wp564</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this research was to investigate the knowledge high school students acquire from science instruction in Zimbabwe, and their ability to reason from and apply their knowledge based on previous learning. Science educators in Zimbabwe are concerned with improving the quality of student's achievement and that students develop a conceptual understanding of basic science rather than a rote memorisation of facts and that students become better prepared to acquire science content on their own. The research reported here utilises the discourse comprehension analysis model and methods developed by Frederiksen (1975, 1986) to investigate students' learning. Based on these methods, it is possible to examine: (a) how students acquire knowledge and understanding, and (b) how they apply what they learn to reason using their conceptual knowledge. The design of the study involved the use of three texts each of which represented different information types within a science domain, 'gas pressure'. The content of the texts was presented by the same teacher during natural classroom instruction to classes at two levels (higher and lower) of a high school grade. The first text concerned Basic Knowledge (concepts and principles) in the domain, and the second and third texts described Familiar and Unfamiliar experiments respectively within the same science domain. In addition, for both of these experiments, several types of information were presented: Procedures, Observations and Explanations. Students' responses to comprehension questions were subjected to a conceptual (propositional) analysis and coded against an 'expert' model of the content of the texts used by the teacher during instruction to the students. The study focused on identifying the extent to which the students' responses directly matched the 'expert' model or consisted of modifications (inferences) that indicated alternative (true or false) conceptual knowledge frameworks that the students may have possessed. The major findings of this research were as follows: Students' answers to questions about their knowledge of basic concepts comprised a large number of responses that directly matched (i.e., literally recalled) the information presented by the teacher during instruction and also included a high number of incorrect inferences. Students' comprehension of the Familiar and Unfamiliar experiments was also characterised by a high degree of 'literal learning' as shown in the generally high amounts of recall of propositional information compared to inferences. Students' responses to these questions consisted mostly of Observation information, and least of Explanations. This suggests that they were more likely to recall observed events that they were to interpret. Students' reasoning was generally poor relative to their comprehension of both experiments, and their responses consisted of more recall responses than inferences. In addition, students' reasoning about the Unfamiliar experiment was characterised by a high number negative higher-order inferences. Finally, students in the higher level displayed higher levels of competence than those in the lower level, particularly in their knowledge of Procedures and Observations in contrast to Explanation information, for both experiments.</description><creator>Chitepo, Thokozile, 1961-</creator><contributor>Donin, Janet (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Science -- Study and teaching (Secondary) -- Zimbabwe.</subject><title>Students' ability to apply their knowledge and reason from science instruction in Zimbabwe</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr639.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wp564</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290c26j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A small addition of elements with a high affinity to oxygen can have a profound effect on the high temperature oxidation behaviour of many metals and alloys. In order to explain the improvement in oxidation resistance, the research was conducted using Ni-NiO as a model system of cation-diffusing oxides, and Ce as a typical reactive element. Three essential techniques were employed to modify the surface of Ni with Ce and CeO2: ion implantation, sol-gel technology, and reactive sputtering. The improvement of Ni oxidation resistance was assessed by oxygen uptake measurements mainly during the early stages but also for long-term exposures at temperatures between 873 and 1073 K in pure oxygen, both at low and atmospheric pressures. The variety of oxides produced were examined in detail by several advanced techniques including Rutherford backscattering spectrometry, Auger electron spectroscopy, secondary ion-mass spectrometry, transmission- and scanning-transmission electron microscopy equipped with electron and x-ray analyzers, atomic force microscopy, infrared spectroscopy, and x-ray diffraction techniques. In order to provide direct evidence regarding the mechanism of oxide growth, a sequential oxidation using oxygen isotopes 16O2/18O2 was conducted. After conversion to the form of ceramic coating, superficially applied CeO2 sol-gel significantly reduced the Ni oxidation rate as well as changing the NiO morphology and internal microstructure. The extent of the effect depended on coating thickness, size of CeO2 particles, substrate surface finishing and preoxidation before coating. Under optimum conditions, the reduction in the Ni oxidation rate achieved by sol-gel, reactive sputtering, and ion implantation, was similar. It was found that Ni oxidation resistance is controlled by a well-defined NiO sublayer that is composed of randomly-oriented NiO grains and CeO2 particles. Moreover, in this sublayer, the Ce4+ ions segregate to the NiO grain boundaries. At high temperatures, the Ce4+ ions block the outward diffusion of Ni2+ cations along the NiO grain boundaries while allowing the inward diffusion of O2 anions to continue. The "dynamic-segregation mechanism" is proposed in which Ce ions do not statically block the NiO grain boundaries, but actively diffuse along them. It is suggested that the NiO texture and microstructure, which are primarily influenced by the crystallographic orientation of the Ni substrate, are of critical importance for the stability of the reactive element concentration at NiO grain boundaries over the oxidation time.</description><creator>Czerwinski, Franciszek.</creator><contributor>Szpunar, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>The growth and structure of thin oxide films on nickel superficially modified with ceria and cerium /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx56r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c26j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qk57d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several multilevel converter topologies have stimulated widespread interests amongst researchers because they have the capabilities of (i) reaching high voltage ratings without magnetics and transformers and (ii) attaining low Total Harmonic Distortions (THD), using the low switching frequencies of gate-turn-off thyristors (GTOS). This thesis focuses on the diode-clamped multilevel converter topology as the basic module for realizing the high kV voltage rating and the high MVA rating in controllers for the Flexible AC Transmission Systems (FACTS). The thesis has extended the topology configurations to include: (i) multiple modules of multilevel converters and (ii) multimodules of multilevel converters in a back-to-back rectifier/inverter link. These configurations form the backbones for the following multilevel FACTS controllers: (a) the Shunt STAT(ic)COM(pensator), (b) the Series STATCOM, (c) the Unified Power Flow Controller (UPFC) and (d) the Asynchronous Link. A number of key technical innovations have been assembled together to make the new multilevel FACTS controllers possible. On the sides of the ac lines, the Fundamental Frequency Switching strategy has been extended so that it succeeds in simultaneously (a) lowering the Total Harmonic Distortions in the voltage and current waveforms, (b) controlling directly the ac voltage magnitudes, and (c) sharing the current loading in the parallel modules. On the side of the dc links of the STATCOMs, feedback controls have succeeded in: (a) regulating the total dc link voltages and (b) equalizing the dc capacitor voltages in all the levels. The voltage equalization by feedbacks cannot be accomplished in the case of the Unified Power Flow Controller (UPFC) and the Asynchronous Link. A system of locally controlled class-B choppers which transfer the charges from dc capacitors with the higher voltages to their contiguous neighbours with the lower voltages succeeds in equalizing the dc capacitor voltages. The proofs of performance of the multilevel FACTS controllers are substantiated by digital simulations. The equalization of the multilevel rectifier/inverter using the system of class-B choppers has been proven experimentally.</description><creator>Chen, Yiqiang.</creator><contributor>Ooi, Boon-Teck (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>High MVA facts controllers based on diode-clamped multilevel converter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j35n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk57d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752j543</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The subsurface mobility of metals and chlorophenols occurring together in contaminated groundwaters is controlled by the extent of aqueous complexation between them and by their adsorption onto aquifer materials. However, no previous experimental studies have quantified these interactions within a thermodynamic framework. This study has investigated the aqueous complexation of Cd, Pb and Cu by 2,4,6-trichlorophenolate (TCP--) and pentachlorophenolate (PCP--) at 25°C, using ion selective electrode potentiometry and ultraviolet spectrophotometry. A single 1:1 aqueous complex forms in each system, with log stability constants and is errors calculated to be: Cd(TCP) +, 2.5 +/- 0.2; Pb(TCP)+, 3.0 +/- 0.3; Cu(TCP) +, 4.9 +/- 0.2; Cd(PCP)+, 2.9 +/- 0.2; Pb(PCP) +, 2.8 +/- 0.3; and Cu(PCP)+, 4.2 +/- 0.2. The adsorption of Cd, Pb, Cu and Al by the common soil bacterium Bacillus licheniformis has been examined at 25°C in electrolytes of varying ionic strength. The cell walls display carboxyl, phosphate and hydroxyl surface functional groups, with pKa values and 1 s errors of 5.2 +/- 0.3, 7.5 +/- 0.4 and 10.2 +/- 0.5, respectively. The average log K values for Cd, Pb, Cu and Al adsorption onto the B. licheniformis surface carboxyl sites, with 1s errors, are 3.9 +/- 0.5, 4.6 +/- 0.3, 4.9 +/- 0.4 and 5.8 +/- 0.3, respectively. The Constant Capacitance double layer model provides the best description of ionic strength-dependent adsorption behaviour, although the model parameters vary between independently grown bacterial cultures, possibly due to cell wall variation arising from genetic variation during reproduction. There is insignificant adsorption of TCP to alpha-A12O3, but a strong affinity between TCP and B. subtilis. The TCP-B. subtilis adsorption data are best described by a site-specific model in which the negative form of TCP forms a 1:1 surface complex with the neutral hydroxyl functional groups of the bacteria (log K = 2.3 +/- 0.3) and the neutral form of TC</description><creator>Daughney, Christopher J.</creator><contributor>Few, Jeremy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><subject>Hydrology.</subject><title>Selected geochemical reactions in heavy metal-chlorophenol systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c440n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j543</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t377d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, I analysed the mating behaviour of the solitary-nesting American kestrel (Falco sparverius) in southern Quebec (Canada) and the colony-nesting lesser kestrel (F. naumanni) in Aragon (Spain). DNA fingerprinting of 26 families of lesser kestrels revealed that 3.4% of nestlings were extra-pair, which may have arisen through either extra-pair copulation or mate replacement. Two nestlings in two different nests were also the result of intraspecific brood parasitism. DNA fingerprinting of 21 American kestrel families showed that all the nestlings in two nests were extra-pair (10% extra-pair young overall), most probably due to mate replacement. I analysed the mating behaviour of both species in two studies with a similar aim, i.e. to test why mated pairs copulate so frequently. Sixteen pairs of wild American kestrels and 12 pairs of "solitary" lesser kestrels (14 nests per 0.3 km$ sp2)$ were analysed in terms of four hypotheses that explain high frequency of within-pair copulations both outside and during the fertile period. First the Paternity Assurance Hypothesis, i.e. males control timing and frequency of copulations to best assure fertilization, was rejected because extra-pair copulation attempts were low in both species ($&lt;$1% of all copulations observed), within-pair copulation frequencies did not increase with nest density in the lesser kestrel, and copulation and mate attendance did not increase as the fertile period approached. Second, the Immediate Material Benefits Hypothesis, i.e. females trade copulations for food, was refuted because copulation most often occurred without food transfers. Third, the Female Mate-Guarding of Males Hypothesis, i.e. females distract their mates from other mating opportunities by copulating frequently, was rejected because male loss was low, males and females solicited similar amounts of copulations, and females did not differ in the timing or frequency of solicitations. Finally, the Mate Assessment Hypothesis, i.e. assessment of mate quality is mediated by copulation, most closely predicted the behaviour observed since within-pair copulation was high outside the fertile period and during pair formation in both species.</description><creator>Villarroel, Morris Ricardo.</creator><contributor>Bird, D. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Lesser kestrel -- Behavior -- Spain -- Aragon.</subject><subject>American kestrel -- Behavior -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Sexual behavior in animals.</subject><subject>Lesser kestrel -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>American kestrel -- Reproduction.</subject><title>Copulatory behaviour and paternity in solitary- and colony-nesting kestrels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc41s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t377d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x571c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Environmental and industrial systems have been investigated using vibrational spectroscopy. These applications were chosen to demonstrate the potential of vibrational spectroscopy as a means of obtaining molecular information from either in-situ or model environments in a rapid, convenient manner requiring minimal sample handling. Diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy (DRIFTS) has been used to investigated two systems in the area of environmental chemistry. Using the characteristic CO stretching bands of the Mn(CO)$ sb3$ fragment, methylcyclopentadienyl manganese tricarbonyl (MMT), an additive to Canadian gasoline, was detected on soils treated with gasoline up to twelve months after exposure. Its longevity on and its interaction with different soils and various substrates was studied. A breakdown of the local symmetry of the manganese tricarbonly moiety suggests a Bronsted-type interaction between the soil and the carbonyl ligands of MMT. The uptake by harbour sediments of two tributyltin species used as marine antifouling agents, was also studied using DRIFTS. Water/sediments ratios and salinity were investigated as factors affecting adsorption. A novel infrared cell for probing the gas-phase infrared spectroscopy (HAGIS) cell was used to study the thermal decomposition products of ethylxanthanate-treated sulphide minerals and those of the related ethylxanthate metal complexes. The gas-phase decomposition products from sulphide minerals treated with ethylxante include $ rm CS sb2, COS, CO sb2, CH sb4, SO sb2,$ ethanol and possibly metal xanthates. The relative amounts of the products depend on the type of mineral surface, the temperature and the atmosphere in the cell. Iron, zinc, lead, nickel and copper ethylxanthate complexes were synthesized, and their thermal decomposition products were also studied by HAGIS. The complexes were classified according to the generation of the primary gas-phase decomposition products. Schemes for the produ</description><creator>Vreugdenhil, Andrew J.</creator><contributor>Butler, I. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Applications of vibrational spectroscopy to inorganic environmental and industrial systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3334122.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x571c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085n06j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On numerous occasions Ricoeur has characterized the goal of his philosophical analyses as the "exchange of the ego, master of itself, for the self, disciple of the text." Our investigation follows the development of this theme through careful examination of Ricoeur's phenomenological-hermeneutical philosophy. By way of contrast with Husserl's phenomenology we see how Ricoeur initiates a program of self-recovery that decenters consciousness from the immediacy of self-grounding radicality. Looking instead to the polysemic world of the text, Ricoeur chooses a path of indirect imaginative mediation as the route towards self-interpretation. The imagination, correlative with the works of culture (signs, symbols and texts), forms the central core of Ricoeur's understanding of selfhood. Already operative in his early publications as the mediating structure of selfhood, the work of imagination is transformed from a transcendental third term into a linguistic process that constructs sonorous worlds in front of consciousness for the self to inhabit. Ricoeur's analysis of metaphor and narrative shows selfhood to be a task accomplished by means of linguistic interpretation. However, such an interpretation of the self, with the textual world as its other, is a linguistic construction that is caught up in semantic self-identification. Ricoeur's program for the exchange of the self-enclosed ego, for a self discipled by the text, becomes entangled in the semantics of identity to such an extent that selfhood is equated with the objectifications of the reflective process and is never dealt with on the intimate level of the reflexive structure of the self in relation to otherness. This has significant consequences which need to be critically examined by philosophy of religion.</description><creator>Venema, Henry I.</creator><contributor>Boutin, Maurice (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Ricœur, Paul -- Contributions in philosophy of the self.</subject><subject>Religion -- Philosophy -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Self (Philosophy) -- History -- 20th century.</subject><title>Paul Ricoeur's interpretation of selfhood and its significance for philosophy of religion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c441x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085n06j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139375n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A dinuclear copper(II) complex has been investigated for promoting the transesterification of a phosphate diester, 2-hydroxypropyl-p-nitrophenyl phosphate (HPNP), that is a model for RNA. Rate enhancements of over 10$ sp5$ have been obtained at neutral pH over the background hydroxide rate. For this study the dinucleating ligand 2,6-bis ((bis(benzimidazolymethyl)amino)methyl) -p-cresol was prepared and the reactivity of the copper(II) complex for cleaving 2-hydroxypropyl-4-nitrophenyl phosphate was determined. The two metals were shown to be acting cooperatively by comparing the reactivity of the dinuclear complex to that of a mononuclear complex, copper(II) 2-(bi(benzimidazolymethyl)amino)methyl-4,6-dimethylphenol. A mechanism involving double Lewis acid activation of HPNP is proposed to account for the 10$ sp5$ rate acceleration. The reactivity of mononuclear Cu(II) and Zn(II) complexes of 2,9-diamino-1,10-phenanthroline (DAP) have been investigated for promoting the hydrolysis of phosphate diesters with good and poor leaving groups. The CuDAP and ZnDAP complexes were shown to be able to provide 10$ sp{10}$ and 10$ sp7$ orders of magnitude rate acceleration for hydrolyzing $2 sp prime,3 sp prime$-cAMP. A novel mechanism which combines metal ion catalysis with intramolecular hydrogen bonding has been proposed to account for the unprecedented rate acceleration. Crystallographic evidence and potentiometic titration data are provided, in addition to kinetic data, to support the proposed mechanism. The results with CuDAP are compared with the copper(II) complex of 2,9-dimethyl-1,10-phenanthroline (CuNeo) to evaluate the rate enhancement provided by intramolecular hydrogen bonding. It is found that intramolecular hydrogen bonding interactions increase the reactivity of CuDAP relative to CuNeo by a factor of 10$ sp3.$</description><creator>Wall, Mark J.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Multiple modes of activation in phosphate diester hydrolysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c27t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139375n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cc66d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new testing paradigm called Built-In Self-Test (BIST) has been gaining increasing acceptance over the traditional automatic test pattern generation for testing the current complex integrated circuits. The basic idea in BIST is to integrate the design with test functionalities like pattern generation, response analysis, and test control. Of the various schemes, pseudo-random pattern testing is an attractive technique for BIST because of the simple hardware required for on-chip test pattern generation. Besides, structures for pseudo-random pattern generation like linear feedback shift register (LFSR) or cellular automata (CA) can also be utilized for on-chip response analysis. In general, pseudo-random BIST is effective only for combinational circuits. This is due to the difficulty associated in obtaining a specific sequence of vectors, through a pseudo-random source, that may be necessary for detecting a fault in a sequential circuit. Thus during test mode, the circuit-under-test (CUT) is transformed to a combinational circuit by configuring memory elements into scan chain(s). However, this may not suffice for circuits that contain random pattern resistant faults or faults not easily detected by random patterns. Two distinct classes of solutions have been proposed to address the random pattern resistance problem--those that modify input patterns and those that modify the CUT. This thesis presents a new, effective circuit modification method for scan-based BIST of integrated circuits. The proposed circuit modification technique utilizes control and observation points to improve the fault coverage, much like the previous techniques. However, unlike the previous methods, the proposed technique is based on a constructive methodology. A divide and conquer approach is used to partition the entire test into multiple phases. In each phase control/observation points targeting a specific set of undetected faults are identified utilizing a new technique called probabilistic fault simulation. This technique blends fault-free simulation and analytical forward fault propagation to accurately compute the information necessary for the identification of control/observation points. Observation points in the proposed scheme are kept enabled for the entire test. However, control points are enabled during specific test phases by fixed values. The usage of fixed values leads to a simple and inherent sharing of the logic driving them. This sharing, as well as the reduction of number of control points result in significant reduction in area overhead. Furthermore, fixed values reduce power dissipation during test mode, since control points instead of toggling are set to a constant value during the entire phase. Experimental results indicate that complete or near-complete stuck-at fault coverage can be achieved by the proposed technique with the insertion of few test points and phases. Results show that modification of less than 1% of circuit nodes is sufficient to achieve complete coverage or greater than 99% coverage. In addition, the proposed techniques are fast and hence are applicable to large circuits.</description><creator>Tamarapalli, Nagesh V.</creator><contributor>Rajski, Janusz (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A method of constructive test point insertion for scan-based built-in-self-test /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq279.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc66d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t378p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two perceived limitations of conventional atomic spectrometry were addressed in these studies. One limitation is that the time required for sample preparation can exceed the actual analysis time by two or more orders of magnitude. High pressure homogenization in combination with high speed blending was evaluated for the preparation of slurries which could be directly analyzed by graphite furnace atomic absorption spectrometry (GF-AAS). Cadmium, copper and lead concentrations were successfully determined in certified reference materials (CRMs) of biological origin and frozen cervine liver and kidney. By capping the flat valve head of the homogenizer with a ruby disc, metal contamination introduced by the processing was reduced appreciably (but not eliminated) and the procedure was extended to the determination of chromium, iron, manganese and nickel in botanical CRMs and air dried animal feeds. The one problematic analyte element proved to be selenium which was consistently underestimated with this procedure. However, the combination of high pressure homogenization and partial enzymatic digestion with a crude protease alone or admixed with lipase or cellulase, released Se-residues from zoological and botanical CRMs so that Se could be accurately determined by slurry introduction GF-AAS. This technique was also applied successfully to freeze-dried, fresh and boiled fish tissues. The principal advantages of the slurry preparation technique are its speed, simplicity and lack of operator intervention. The second limitation involved the loss of chemical speciation information during analysis. To preserve this speciation information, individual chemical species were separated chromatographically then detected in the column eluate using a novel all silica T-tube interface coupled with AAS. The advantages of the current interface design over previous prototypes were the compatibility with both organic or aqueous mobile phases and the low limits of detection (LODs) for Ag, Cd, Cu or Zn. The feasibility of the approach was demonstrated by monitoring levels of metal analyte bound to individual metallothionein isoforms which had been partially resolved by size exclusion or ion exchange HPLC. Whereas the metallothionein-I (MT-I) isoform was enriched in Cu relative to the MT-II isoform, the reverse was true for Zn. Also, a Ag-saturation procedure rapidly and efficiently replaced the bound Cd, Cu and Zn in these polypeptides.</description><creator>Tan, Yanxi.</creator><contributor>Marshall, W. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Trace elements -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Atomic spectrometry.</subject><title>Novel approaches to the determination of trace elements by atomic spectrometry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v721d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t378p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494b17q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts to provide a complete textual analysis of Ivan Timofeyev's Vremennik. The first three chapters establish Timofeyev's biographical data, examine the extant manuscript and review prior research. Timofeyev's biography has been restored by putting together the data from earlier biographical studies and by utilising the information hidden within the text of Vremennik. The production of the extant manuscript should be dated to the 1650s rather than the 1630s. The remaining four chapters of this dissertation deal with the elements of Vremennik which were largely ignored by other scholars. Timofeyev expressed an outlook on the state based on his "Novgorodian vision", his understanding of Novgorod's role in the development of the new Russian state. I believe that this Novgorodian element is the key to the correct interpretation of Vremennik. Timofeyev also formulated on original concept of the "ideal tsar". He perceived a monarch's legitimacy not only on his hereditary rights but also on the basis of his moral behaviour, in a way creating a moral code for a Christian monarch. He viewed the events of Smuta as a total degradation of the country and attempted to provide the solutions by developing a distinct political theory. It was based on the traditional notion of a possibility of cleansing and redemption of the whole country through an adherence to the Christian doctrine and consequently a return to the paradise of pre-Smuta days. Timofeyev recognized his own apostolic mission of revealing the truth in order to facilitate this process.</description><creator>Swoboda, Marina.</creator><contributor>Austin, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Goldblatt, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Russia -- History.</subject><subject>Timofeev, Ivan, d. ca. 1629. Vremennik Ivana Timofeeva.</subject><title>Tradition reinvented : the vision of Russia's past and present in Ivan Timofeyev's Vremennok</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c001p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494b17q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p6488</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study deals with the reconstruction of the administration of justice in Hesse during the Allied military occupation of Germany. (1945-1949). The argument is analysed through two main elements: the restoration of judicial institutions and the denazification of judicial personnel. It is argued that the significance of the institutional element took precedence over the personnel element, since the denazification programme in the U.S. occupation zone was abandoned when it proved impractical. The evidence presented in this work is based on archival research, government documents, eyewitness accounts, and secondary sources.</description><creator>Szanajda, Andrew.</creator><contributor>Hoffmann, P. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Germany -- History -- 1945-1955.</subject><subject>Hesse (Germany) -- History.</subject><subject>Justice, Administration of -- Germany -- Hesse.</subject><title>The restoration of justice in Hesse, 1945-1949 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt535.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p6488</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33200</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>