<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:49:04Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12125" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qw019</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>“It is no use trying to sum people up,” said Virginia Woolf of Jacob, the elusive hero of Jacob’s Room, her first radically experimental novel. “One must follow hints, not exactly what is said, nor yet entirely what is done —“1 A lifetime of research would not serve to assemble and interpret everything that Virginia Woolf herself in her life, said and did. And the significance of most of these things in the final summation of her personality would be of little use, as irrelevant to any rounded picture of a life as is any one of the multitude of impressions and moments which surround Jacob in Jacob’s Room. But we must believe that there is some order in the world; that human activity is partially predictable; that there is continuity of character and interest and aspiration and personality. Else we should all drop our tools where we stand and give up the struggle of living with ourselves and with other people, long before we reached the age of fifty-nine. The process of arriving at judgments concerning the personalities of other people is one of our most important pursuits. However, in everyday life, our evaluation of the people about us is necessarily hurried, unmethodical, and inexact, founded on prejudices, unconscious motives and associations, which have served us in the past. Our language is rich with words that enable us to label these snap judgments of personality — gay, frivolous, attractive, honest, strong, melancholy, phlegmatic, etc.[...]</description><creator>Stewart, Lyall Stanley.</creator><contributor>Files, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941.</subject><title>The personality of Virginia Woolf as revealed in her creative works.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jx72k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qw019</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343w281</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the progress of soil survey work in Canada and with the consequent recognition and definition of a large number of soil units the proper classification of soils has become a very urgent problem. Up to the present time some 220 million acres of land have been surveyed in Canada of which approximately 40 million acres are located in the provinces of Ontario and Quebec. In these provinces alone the number of soil series established to date is close to 300. As the number of recognized differing soil units increases it becomes imperative that soils which have some major characteristics in common be grouped together into higher categories. Attempts have been made, with various success, to group Canadian soils into higher categories, particularly the “great soil groups,” which have been defined elsewhere, mainly in the United States. Some of these higher categories have been defined on limited numbers of known soil units and these in some cases have not represented the entire range of soils which should logically be grouped into the same higher category. The definitions of some great soil groups, have also not been specific enough to permit the separation of border line soils into the respective groups. The shortcomings of the present definitions of some great soil groups are recognized not only in this country but also elsewhere.[...]</description><creator>Stobbe, P. C.</creator><contributor>DeLong, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Comparative study of the grey-brown podzolic brown podzolic and brown forest soils of southern Ontario and southern Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qg46t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343w281</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t536k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Petrographic methods as generally understood comprise the methods by which material collected in the field is investigated in the laboratory. Although for strictly petrological purposes it may be sufficient simply to effect the qualitative and quantitative examination of sediments, geologically speaking the investigation is incomplete without carrying the inquiry still further, viz. to a consideration of the source or sources of origin of the sediments and its bearing on the palaeogeography of the area at the time of deposition. Commenting on the value and nature of such investigation Milner (1940 p. 490) says “The perusal of this more philosophical aspect of the science is not merely academic; indeed, one might almost say that without such inquiry all petrographic work must lose both in precision and value: it will certainly lack vitality. “Tracing the source of constituent particles of a deposit is often by no means a straightforward matter, especially where the locale of a distributive province capable of furnishing the material is obscure or where, owing to widespread erosion, no direct evidence of such a province exists. The problems to be faced are, from their very nature, some of the most complex and absorbing that a geologist has to solve and each case must perforce be dealt with on its own merits.”</description><creator>Stocken, Charles Galihad.</creator><contributor>Cranck, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Petrographic methods of determining the source of clastic sediments.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440w997.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t536k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d570091z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the 1949 summer field season the writer had the opportunity of mapping the geology of two groups of claims for Falconbridge Nickel Mines limited. The location of these groups, in western Ontario and south eastern Manitoba, is indicated on the accompanying map of the general area. A geophysical survey and diamond drilling program had been completed during the winter months and over the break up period on the Werner Lake group. Geological mapping on a scale of two hundred feet to one inch was commenced early in May in order to correlate the results of the winter’s work. The mapping of the Bird River group of claims was commenced late in June and in conjunction with the mapping a magnetometer survey was carried out. The object of this work was to investigate several known occurrences of copper-nickel sulphides on the property and to locate if possible, by geophysical methods, any other mineralized zones, that may have lain undiscovered under the cover of drift. In this area also, peridotite is the host rock for banded chromite deposits and, as peridotite was known to outcrop on the claims, it was thought that magnetometer survey might reveal the presence of this type of deposit.</description><creator>Taylor, William Leonard Wyndham.</creator><contributor>O'Neill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Copper-nickel sulphide deposits of the Werner Lake, Ontario and Bird River, Manitoba areas.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107229f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d570091z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qw02k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this survey the writer will be concerned with mental hygiene in its practice which directly assists children living at home in the Province of Quebec. The study will concern an analysis of the provisions in the province for the detection, diagnosis and treatment of children with social and emotional problems. These children will be those “who are in distress because of unsatisfied inner needs, or are seriously at outs with their environment - children whose development is thrown out of balance by difficulties which reveal themselves in unhealthy traits, unacceptable behaviour, or inability to cope with scholastic and social expectations.” Only those agencies or clinics organized specifically to perform a diagnostic or treatment service for the above type of patient will be included in this survey. It is not proposed to study services provided for mentally retarded, mentally defective or physically handicapped children. As stated above, the analysis will be made of the clinics’ direct service to children living at home. However, to give a more complete picture of what is actually being done, it will be necessary to mention any additional services provided.[...]</description><creator>Thompson, C. E. R.</creator><date>1950</date><subject>Social Work.</subject><title>Mental health services for children in Quebec province.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w789n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qw02k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wt75m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> In 1901 Weichselbaum and Stangl described unique changes in the islets of Langerhans of 18 pancreases from comatose diabetic human subjects. Having found the affected islet cells uncolored by methods designed to demonstrate hyaline and mucoid forms of degeneration, they (1902) later interpreted the lesion as a manifestation of cytoplasmic vacuolation and liquefaction, and applied the term hydropic degeneration to indicate its presumably aqueous character. Allen (1913) accomplished the first experimental production of a similar lesion in the islets and ductules of the pancreatic remnants of dogs made diabetic by resection of nine-tenths of the pancreas. At about the same time Homans (1914, 1915) demonstrated that in the islets of such experimental material degranulation and vacuolation developed only in the beta cells. Both Allen and Homans failed to find fat, mucin or glycogen in the affected cells; both concluded, as Weichselbaum did, that the vacuoles represented aqueous fluid. Richardson (1939-40), Ham and Haist (1941), Lukens and Dohan (19140, 1942) and Lukens, Dohan, and Wolcott (1943) described the pancreases of dogs and cats treated with anterior pituitary extract; these authors apparently accepted the idea of aqueous vacuolation as the basis of “hydropic degeneration” in their material.[...]</description><creator>Toreson, Wilfred E.</creator><contributor>Duff, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Glycogen infiltration (so-called hydropic degeneration) of the pancreas in experimental and human diabetes mellitus.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qq412.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wt75m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150n210</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Melampsorella cerastii (Pers.) Schroet. is an organism which causes witches` brooms (Hexenbesen) in our firs (Abies spp.) and spruces (Picea spp.). It belongs to the group of higher fungi (Basidiomycetes) known as the rusts (Uredinales). The alternate hosts are various species of the Caryophyllaceae e.g. Cerastium and Stellaria (Alsine). Pycnia and aecia are produced on the coniferous host, while the uredinia and telia are borne on the caryophyllaceous host. The mycelium is perennial in both hosts, frequently living as long as the host does, and thus rendering the parasite more permanent even if the required alternate hosts are rare. In fact, it appears that the aecidial host is not necessary for its continued existence (Wilson 1934). Infection takes place in the buds of the spruces and firs and causes hyperplasia and hypertrophy of the tissues. Apical dominance is lost, or, at least, reduced and numerous lateral branches develop resulting in the formation of conspicuous witches’ brooms. These brooms may eventually grow to large size: Pady (1941) shows one on Picea which is six feet long and two or three feet in diameter. Those on Abies, however, are much smaller, more compact and usually more nearly spherical. Typical brooms are shown in Plates 1(a) and 1(d), the first in its fourth year and the latter in its sixth.[...]</description><creator>Turnau, Edmund Albert Otto.</creator><contributor>Pady, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Balsam fir -- Diseases and pests.</subject><title>A comparison of the morphology and anatomy of normal Abies balsamea and that infected by Melampsorella cerastii (Pers.) Schroet.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bj14t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150n210</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Botany</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vv08c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The term “feeding reflex” is intended to imply the actions of the most rostral part of the digestive tract during the ingestion of food. This includes tongue, lip, and jaw movements, salivation, the pharyngeal, laryngeal and esophageal phases of deglutition and the motor and secretory responses aroused in the stomach. This complex presents a number of points which bear mention. It is marked, of course, by its phylogenetic antiquity and the paucity of specialization apparent in its responses as the phylogenetic scale is ascended. It appears as though Nature had struck upon a satisfactory mechanism and then felt little need to make the improvements so evident in many other responses in higher animals. Throughout the species it is a reflex of considerable complexity, calling into action a great variety of muscular and glandular elements but being characterized by its stereotyped responses. As the tract descends from lips to stomach the musculature comes less and less under voluntary control. This implies that the lower portions come increasingly under the guidance of the autonomic system. The independent motility of the stomach and its variable response to apparently similar stimuli pose puzzling problems in interpretation to the investigator.[...]</description><creator>Van Buren, John M.</creator><contributor>Babkin, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Neurology &amp; Neurosurgery.</subject><title>The cortical representation of the feeding reflex.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z411v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vv08c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579w52b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The saturated ring hydrocarbons are generally believed to behave as aliphatic compounds, for which reason they are frequently referred to as alicyclic. Just as in an homologous series of aliphatic chain compounds there is not a steady gradation in behaviour (e.g. the extreme lack of reactivity of neopentyl derivatives in negative ion-replacement reactions as compared with the corresponding propyl and isobutyl derivatives (1)), so in the alicyclic series, striking differences have been observed in the chemical behaviour of cyclohexyl derivatives as compared with derivatives of smaller and larger saturated rings. For example, although the rates of esterification of cyclopentanol, cyclohexanol and cycloheptanol decrease steadily with increase in the number of carbon atoms in the ring (2), the rate of decomposition of sodium bisulphite derivatives of alicyclic ketones shows a minimum with the six membered ring (3).[...]</description><creator>Van Straten, Sylvia Florence.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Exchange reactions between alicyclic iodides and sodium iodide.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289n210.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579w52b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h764w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A microscopic examination of thin sheets of certain kinds of mica, notably biotite, reveals the presence of small areas containing groups of concentric circles darker in colour than the surrounding mica. Usually a minute particle, more or less transparent, is observed at the centre of each circle. The circular marks are called pleochroic haloes and the particle at the centre is commonly referred to as the nucleus. Joly and Rutherford (1) were the first to show that the haloes are due to darkening of the mica by alpha particles emitted by radioactive material associated in some way with the nucleus. The first attempt to classify haloes according to their radioactive parent element was made by Joly (2a). He was able to distinguish between uranium and thorium types but could not account for a few other varieties which he encountered. More recently, however, Henderson (3) has made a systematic study of the haloes in mica from many localities and has been able to account satisfactorily for their origins. At least six distinct types (3d) have been recognized, each resulting from a different radioactive parent. These are shown diagramatically in Figure 1. From the measured radius of a given halo and a knowledge of the energies of the alpha particles emitted by different radioactive atoms, converted into their range in mica, identification of the halo with a particular radioactive element in the nucleus can be effected.[...]</description><creator>Wagner, Sydney.</creator><contributor>Shaw, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>An x-ray diffraction study of the nuclei of pleochroic haloes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m5107.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h764w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892f221</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While a number of studies have been concerned with the fears of children of various ages, little seems to be known about the objects end situations that are feared by adolescents and young adults. The present study is aimed at gaining some knowledge of the fears of these latter groups in order to get a more complete picture of the changes in fear with age. Relationships of fear to intelligence and personality are also explored. Each of the 85 subjects reported his or her fears in two or more interviews. These data were then treated statistically. Findings show that young women report more fears than adolescent girls, while young men have fewer fears than adolescent boys. Varying types of fears are found to be typical for different age groups. Intelligence is seen to aid in control of fears. The study failed to reveal any relationship between fears and certain selected aspects of personality. A number of hypotheses are advanced to explain these results.</description><creator>Wake, F. R.</creator><contributor>Bindra, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Psychology.</subject><subject>Fear.</subject><title>Changes of fear with age.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4307845.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892f221</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qg473</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ability of certain polymer molecules to form side chains or branches has been suspected for some time, but the complexity of the systems where it is believed to occur has made the determination of the existence or extent of branching uncertain. The work which follows was done with two main objectives in mind; to develop a controlled method of producing branched and linear polymers suitable for comparative studies and, if successful, to investigate some of their properties, it was hoped that the information forthcoming would be of assistance in the further study of branching phenomena and an aid to the interpretation of experimental results in complicated systems, such as GR-S where branching is believed to have considerable influence on the properties of the final product. Before presenting the experimental results, it is necessary to describe some of the characteristics of high polymers which have bearing on the problem of branching.[...]</description><creator>Walker, Osman James.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies of branched and linear polymers: Part I - Preparation and viscosity characteristics of branched and linear polymers; Part II - Rate and Mechanism of solution of branched and linear polymers.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z22t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qg473</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75rc16b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Effects of electric shock stimulation and experimentally induced failure on perception were investigated by making use of a visual speed-of-word recognition task. Each word was tachistoscopically presented at successively increasing exposure times, and the number of trials needed for correct recognition was recorded. Results indicated that when words of a given class had been paired with shock during the training series, other words of that class were later recognized in fewer trials. When failure had been associated with these words, recognition required more exposures. These results ware interpreted as follows: a set to see a particular class of words was formed during the training series; shock facilitated, while failure inhibited this set formation. Assuming that failure constitutes a greater threat to self-esteem than does shock, these results may be regarded as indicating the significance of the variable of ego-involvement for perceptual activity. Suggestions for further study of this variable in perception are advanced.</description><creator>Wallerstein, Harvey.</creator><contributor>Bindra, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Visual discrimination.</subject><subject>Word recognition.</subject><title>The role of ego-involvement in perceptual activity.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xc834.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rc16b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33s072c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Werner Jaeger has remarked, “Aristotle is the only great figure of ancient philosophy and literature who has never had a Renaissance.” Although this statement was made possibly thirty years ago and may not now be true for all of Aristotle’s philosophy, it is, I fear, true for at least his Ethics. Whereas Plato’s theories have enjoyed almost constant re-examination and criticism throughout recent years, the same cannot, unfortunately, be said for those of his great successor. One explanation for this lies, perhaps, in the fact that contemporary Ethical investigation is not interested in the same things in which Aristotle was interested: it is not interested in casuistry: it is not concerned primarily with answering such questions as ‘what is the nature of the good life?’ But neither does it concern itself so much with such matters as the moral character and how a man becomes good. For Aristotle, on the other hand, these questions were the most important. While modern Ethics tends to enquire into the meanings of certain terms like ‘right’ and ‘good’ and ‘obligation’, Aristotle either quickly establishes meaning or assumes it and hastens to enquire into processes: how we come to know what the human good is; how we become good; how we become responsible for our actions; how we make a judgment of what we ought to do in a particular situation.[...]</description><creator>Watson, Gordon Alfred Brabant.</creator><contributor>Maclennan, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Aristotle. Nicomachean ethics. English.</subject><title>Aristotle’s doctrine of practical wisdom.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr26t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s072c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nv120</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The experiments to be reported in this treatise were carried out with the object of contributing to the general knowledge of the human disease, acute diffuse glomerulonephritis. Albino rabbits were used in all experiments. These animals exhibit many important anatomical and physiological differences from humans. It is therefore obvious that any findings reported will depend for their ultimate validity upon the demonstration that, in certain respects at least, rabbits are capable of responses similar to those of humans, and vice versa. Limitations of time and material resources have not permitted the work to reach this decisive point. Thus, any equivalence existing between the experimental disease in rabbits and the natural disease in humans will have to be reached via deduction, which must, itself, be based upon knowledge of the human disease and its presumed experimental counterpart. The various aspects of human glomerulonephritis will, therefore, be considered in some detail before discussion of artificially induced nephropathies in rabbits is entered.</description><creator>Waugh, Douglas.</creator><contributor>More, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Glomerulonephritis produced in rabbits by massive injections of foreign proteins.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dg86s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nv120</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3014613</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The exact process by which narcotics, and anaesthetic agents in general, produce depression of nervous activity and unconsciousness in animals, is a problem which has long intrigued workers in the fields of pharmacology, physiology, and biochemistry. It has been only comparatively recently, however, that biochemical techniques were developed which made it possible to accurately determine various aspects of the metabolism of surviving, excised tissue preparations in vitro by manometric methods. Although the great bulk of scientific literature dealing with the mechanisms of narcosis has been concerned with the pharmacological action of narcotic agents in the intact animal, the effects of narcotics on the respiration of brain tissue in vitro has been studied by several workers. However, most of these investigations have concerned themselves almost wholly with the inhibitory effects of narcotics on tissue respiration, and no thorough study of the in vitro effects of narcotics on the glycolytic mechanisms of brain tissue in the presence of narcotics has been attempted.[...]</description><creator>Webb, James L.</creator><contributor>Elliott, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Effects of narcotics and convulsants on brain tissue metabolism.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w790d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3014613</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920g104g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:13:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is the purpose of this study to indicate the need for case work services to displaced persons admitted to Canada from Europe during the decade following world war II. It is the basic assumption of this enquiry that these people need more than casual friendly help from those among whom they settle. The immigrants are strangers to a new homeland, to a new community, to another culture. The D.Ps. face more than the usual difficulties and hardships of adjustment to a new community and its way of life. They have been subject to additional traumatic pressures of a sociological and psychological nature which in many cases have torn asunder their social relationships, family affiliations, political and citizenship status and seriously weakened the ego structure of their personalities. The fears and the anxieties which have been accumulated by them need to be understood and relieved. They need help which will permit them to regain a wholesome acceptance of themselves as individuals with a readiness to assume the responsibilities and the privileges of membership in a community in their new homeland.[...]</description><creator>Weiner, Miriam.</creator><contributor>Younge, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Social Work.</subject><title>Case work services for displaced persons immigrating to Canada.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn536.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920g104g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30px051</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study has two aims; first, to draw some conclusions concerning the stimulus factors, or evidences, which influence the direction of autokinetic movement; second, to utilize these conclusions in elucidating the nature of the autokinetic effect.</description><creator>Westcott, James William.</creator><contributor>Luchins, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>PSYCHOLOGY -- MENTAL TESTS</subject><title>An investigation of some factors influencing the autokinetic effect.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fv914.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30px051</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jh72r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bleaching of wood pulp with alkaline hypochlorite is of great economical importance in the pulp and paper industry. Considerable work has been done on the problem of such bleaching but mainly from an industrial point of view with the object of effecting economies in the chlorine consumption while at the same time maintaining high quality in the pulps. All of this work, too, was hampered by the necessity of studying the reactions of bleaching either on whole wood or on isolated lignins known to be altered in structure in obscure but probably drastic ways. Some years ago it was found possible to isolate most of the lignin from wood in a state that was only slightly chemically changed. The product, periodate lignin, was a light brown powder preserving much of the original morphological detail, and differing from most other isolated lignins in retaining the original insolubility of lignin in all liquids investigated. The availability of "periodate" lignin encouraged the writer to study the actions of a typical bleaching agent, sodium hypochlorite, and a closely related substance, sodium hypoiodite, upon it. This work supplements earlier results that were complicated by the presence of carbonydrates of wood or by the use of a less suitable type of lignin.[...]</description><creator>Whittall, Norman Stanley.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Oxidations of periodate lignin with alkaline hypoiodite and hypochlorite.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445ch53w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jh72r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xm83g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A compact, low cost, positive ion accelerator was built. Hydrogen ions were obtained from a metal capillary ion source with an outlet hole of 0.5 mm. diameter- An ion current of 5.5 microamperes was accelerated by two focussing electrodes and three accelerating electrodes to a lithium target . The resultant alpha particles were counted on a zinc sulphide screen; the maximum yield was 23 particles per minute, through a solid angle of 0.11. The accelerating voltage, supplied by a Cockcroft-Walton voltage multiplier circuit, was varied from 45 to 90 kv.</description><creator>Whittier, A. C., 1921-</creator><contributor>Mennie, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>The design and construction of a 100,000 volt linear ion accelerator.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fc50n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xm83g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397c49z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The studies in land use control of the physical planning seminar at McGill University, during the session 1948-49, are the background to this thesis. These studies were based on a cooperative survey of Mount Royal Ward, Montreal, by the student members of the seminar. They were an architect, two economists, a geographer and a socioligist. The architect directed a survey of the effects of the existing land use controls on the density of the Ward. It revealed that there is a confusion of theoretical considerations on which the controls are based, and that in the main the existing controls are ineffective. One of the conclusions of the total survey was that the social and economic forces directing the process of city growth result in conditions of crowding and dispersal, and that this forms the basis for the social control of density. These facts gave the lead to the development of this thesis. The first part of the thesis is a review of the theoretical considerations determining a method of control of residential density. […] The second part of the thesis is a field study of the existing controls in Mount Royal Ward. […]</description><creator>Wiesman, B.</creator><contributor>Spence-Sales, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>City planning.</subject><title>The control of residential density.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032624p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397c49z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kx06j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The interpretation of the structures in this study is based largely on the work of Snodgrass (1935), with frequent reference to that of Freeman (1947) and occasional reference to that of Madden (1944). The interpretation of the face is based on the work of Du Porte (1946); that of the male genitalia, on papers by Beirne (1942) and Hardwick (1948); that of the sternum, on lectures at Macdonald College, McGill University. FACE The most prominent sclerite on the anterior aspect of the head (Fig.l) is the frons (Fr), which is about as broad as long, and convex, being more sharply rounded both ventrally and dorsally. Between the antennal sockets (As), there runs a distinct white line, somewhat rounded backward. This line is not marked internally by a ridge and is apparently the frontal suture (fs), the coronal suture being possibly represented by a thin median line in the vertex devoid of scale scars; the mid-cranial sulcus is lacking; the frontal suture marks the dorsal limits of the frons. The frons is limited laterally by the frontogenal sulcus (fgs), which, with its interior ridge, runs ventrally from the mesoposterior borders of the antennal sockets close to the compound eyes (Ce), which are very large and descend below the level of the frons. The antennae are thus borne dorsolaterally on the frons. The compound eyes occupy the genal area except for a very narrow posterodorsal rim. [...]</description><creator>Wigmore, Robert Hazen.</creator><contributor>DuPorte, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>1 . A list of Phalaenidae of P.E.I. 2. The external morphology of Apamea americana Speyer. 3. A study of the external genitalia of 63 species of Phalaenidae.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139525v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kx06j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278x55s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For centuries bone was considered a very inert substance. The hardness of the bone as compared to other tissues, the slowness of repair following fracture, and the length of time for bone autolysis, all supported this concept. However, some doubt was cast on this theory, when in 1887 Macewan noted the difference in strength and brittleness in the bones of young children, adults and the very aged. He also observed that in sickness the bones of children became very soft and pliable and that 2 weeks after recovery they had returned to their former hard state. This surely suggested that the metabolism of bone reflected the general body condition.Sixty years after the work of Macewan, Newman and Riley made the following statement, “Bone cannot be considered to be a stable system in which the inorganic phase is inert. Rather, the stability of the skeletal system can be attributed only to an extremely efficient control of the inorganic composition of the circulating fluids”.[...]</description><creator>Wilkinson, Gordon W.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>The deposition of radioactive phosphorus in bones, teeth and healing fractures of rats as shown by autographs and specific activity determinations.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92gb47q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278x55s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:794081260</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A review of the literature indicates that blood lipid levels are normally relatively constant, and are independent of age, body weight and ordinary meals. Variations from normal levels occur in pregnancy, under duress, in certain pathological states, and after fat ingestion.  Extremes in fat intake influence the levels directly. Low fat diets increase the saturation of the component fatty acids. Levels of blood lipid fractions tend to change slowly and proportionally. Phospholipid and neutral fat levels rise during fat absorption but not in proportion to the amount of fat ingested; cholesterol levels change inconsistently. Experimental work confirms the above observations regarding alimentary lipemia and, in multiple sclerosis patients, shows that with low fat diets blood cholesterol and phospholipid levels fall temporarily and neutral fat levels remain depressed. The physical State of blood fat is discussed. The methods used to determine four lipid fractions are minutely described and discussed.</description><creator>Wilmot, Valerie C.</creator><contributor>Swank, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Blood lipids in relation to diet.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jv40d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/794081260</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t2546</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During World War II, the serious shortage of edible fats and oils in Canada stimulated investigations on the use of domestic vegetable oils for foods. Attention was concentrated on linseed oil, which could be produced in large quantities; but hydrogenated linseed shortenings developed serious flavor reversion. This made them totally unacceptable to the consumers. Evidence was obtained in this Department that linolenic acid on hydrogenation forms precursors of reversion compounds. Investigation of means for the removal of linolenic acid from linseed or soybean oil triglycerides led to the use of thermal polymerization, followed by solvent segregation into an "edible" fraction and a drying fraction of superior film-forming properties. The "edible"fraction yielded a hydrogenated shortening of acceptable stability and flavor. However, it showed markedly lowered nutrutuve value when included in the diet of rats at levels of 10$ or over. The primary aim of the research reported herein has been to concentrate and identify the material responsible for the deleterious nature of heat-polymerized linseed oil. It is likely that similar products are responsible in heated soybean or other oils. Linseed oil was chosen for study because the damage occurs with Short heating periods, and because most previous data were obtained with linseed oil.[…]</description><creator>Wiseblatt, Lazare.</creator><contributor>Common, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>On the nature of the nutritionally deleterious constituents of heated vegetable oils.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569750b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t2546</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12150</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>