<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:21:46Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33250" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wx38t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation explores the question of whether Tagalog, a language of the Philippines, is an ergative language. It is claimed that Tagalog is best characterized as neither accusative nor ergative but rather as a language that is a hybrid of these two language types. Tagalog's hybrid nature is neatly captured structurally within Principle and Parameters theory using VP internal subjects. In terms of Case, Tagalog not only has nominative-absolutive Case checking and ergative Case checking but it also makes extensive use of inherent accusative Case assignment. As a result, Tagalog has both a (NOM ACC) basic transitive sentence type, like accusative languages, and a (ERG ABS) basic transitive sentence type, like ergative languages. A specific structural analysis is given for these basic sentences under an Economy approach. This analysis is extended to account for complex sentences including sentences involving morphological causatives, conjunction reduction and raising.</description><creator>Maclachlan, Anna E.</creator><contributor>Travis, Lisa DeMena (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Tagalog language -- Ergative constructions.</subject><subject>Tagalog language -- Syntax.</subject><title>Aspects of ergativity in Tagalog</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881n597.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx38t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752j38q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA methylation is a postreplicative covalent modification of the DNA which is catalysed by the DNA methyltransferase enzyme. DNA methylation plays an important role in controlling the gene expression profile of mammalian cells. The hypothesis presented in this thesis is that the expression of the DNA methyltransferase gene is upregulated by cellular oncogenic pathways, and that this induction of MeTase activity results in DNA hypermethylation and plays a causal role in cellular transformation. Novel DNA methyltransferase inhibitors may inhibit the excessive activity of DNA methyltransferase in cancer cells and induce the original cellular genetic program. These inhibitors may also be used to turn on alternative gene expression programs. Therefore specific DNA methyltransferase antagonists might provide us with therapeutics directed at a nodal point in the regulation of genetic information.</description><creator>MacLeod, A. Robert (Robert Alan), 1966-</creator><contributor>Szyf, Moshe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>DNA methylation and oncogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dn97h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j38q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838217x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis focuses on the renin-angiotensin system and atrial natriuretic factors (ANF) two hormonal systems which are stimulated and which may exert important antagonizing actions on the regulation of mean arterial pressure (MAP) and body fluid homeostasis during pregnancy. All experiments were conducted in healthy nonpregnant and/or pregnant (gestational age of 105 to 140 days, term = 145 days) mixed breed ewes, using a facility designed for studies of large animals. Findings from the first study with unilateral denervated kidneys provide evidence that renal nerves are a necessary component in the control of renin secretion in both nonpregnant and pregnant ewes. The second study demonstrates that angiotensin II (AngII) and ANF do not account for the dramatic suppression of renin secretion in response to the reduction of renal perfusion pressure in sheep with bilateral renal denervation. The data from these two studies suggest that the renal baroreceptors influence renin secretion indirectly through activation of renal afferents rather than by a direct action on the juxtaglomerular apparatus. In order to study the possible effects of increased plasma AngII on ANF production during pregnancy, four doses of AngII (0.5, 5, 20, 40 ng/kg/min) and nitroprusside were simultaneously infused to separate indirect hemodynamic actions on ANF secretion from direct hormonally mediated effects on ANF secretion by AngII. The data clearly show that AngII increases plasma ANF in a dose-dependent manner but: only in the presence of the AngII pressor effect. A striking finding was the demonstration that the natriuretic and diuretic responses to intrarenal artery infusion of three doses of ANF (0.3, 1.5, 3.0 pmol/kg/min) are increased during ovine pregnancy and these responses are solely limited to actions on the distal part of the nephron without altering renal vascular or glomerular function. Finally, a study with 10 days of intrarenal artery infusion of low dose AngII (1 ng/kg/m</description><creator>Fan, Li, 1967-</creator><contributor>Quillen, Ed. W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Interactions of renin-angiotensin and natriuretic peptide systems in control of blood pressure during ovine pregnancy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq172.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838217x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c214v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem of computing closed bounding contours from a visual image is addressed. The approach is motivated by the fact that many important image structures are heterogeneous and therefore cannot be segmented by traditional region-based methods based on homogeneity or smoothness constraints. Both psychophysical and computational aspects of the problem are studied. Psychophysical evidence is presented which shows that properties of bounding contour such as closure act as binding features for the segmentation of 2-D shapes, whereas texture (a region property) does not. These psychological results motivate an investigation of local and global issues in the computation of bounding contours for the purpose of figure/ground segmentation. Novel techniques for the local analysis of contour are presented which allow edges to be reliably detected and localized over a broad range of blur scale and contrast in images with shallow depth-of-field and shadows. Local estimates of contour blur are shown to be useful for computing depth segmentation from focal blur in complex images where the continuity assumptions required by existing Fourier techniques do not apply. It is hypothesized that in order to integrate contours fragmented by occlusion and insufficient contrast, the human visual system exploits a measure of geometric contour closure. The results of psychophysical experiments show that a measure for closure based on $L sb2$ norm of contour gaps in psychophysically consistent. The existence of this measure is evidence for the computation of geometric closure by the human visual system. These psychophysical findings motivate an algorithm for computing closed bounding contours as cycles of curve tangents. Tangent cycles extracted from a variety of real images are shown to correspond to the bounding contours of 2-D image structures, many of which are heterogeneous over their interior. Thus closure computations are seen to complement region-grouping methods by extending the class of structures which may be segmented to include heterogeneous image structures.</description><creator>Elder, James H.</creator><contributor>Zucker, Steven W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>The visual computation of bounding contours</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb3979801.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c214v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p625z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to determine whether there were differences in mortality, dialysis method survival, hospital admissions and days of hospitalization, between diabetic patients with end-stage renal disease (ESRD) treated by continuous ambulatory dialysis (CAPD) and those treated by haemodialysis (HD). All diabetic patients (n = 241) treated for newly diagnosed ESRD in four university teaching hospitals, in Montreal, between 1980 and 1993, were studied (n = 112 began with CAPD, n = 129 with HD). The data regarding these patients were analyzed using actuarial methods and Cox's proportional hazards model, controlling for severity of pre-treatment co-morbid conditions. Intent-to-treat (ITT) and treatment history (TxHx) censoring criteria of analysis were also used. At baseline, the CAPD patients were younger and had more co-morbid conditions, particularly cardiovascular diseases, than the HD patients did. The findings regarding mortality and first dialysis method change were similar in both the ITT and TxHx analyses. The mortality rate ratios varied with time since beginning of treatment. The adjusted mortality rate ratios (ARR) for CAPD patients relative to HD patients during year 1, 2, 3, and thereafter were 1.1, 1.6, 2.9, and 4.5 respectively. The rate of dialysis method change was also greater in the CAPD patients compared with HD patients (ARR = 4.4, P $&lt;$ 0.001). Both the rate of hospital admissions and average days of hospitalization for the CAPD patients were about twice those for the HD patients (0.21 vs 0.11 admissions, and 4.6 days vs 2.4 days, per month of first dialysis therapy). The findings regarding mortality suggest that in the short term, the initial choice of dialysis method and any subsequent switch between CAPD and HD for a patient can be made without serious concern about the influence of the dialysis modality on patient survival. However, in the longer term, the influence of the choice of the initial dialysis on patient survival is substantial.</description><creator>Fenta, Haile</creator><contributor>Hanley, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Outcomes in diabetic patients on maintenance dialysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999827f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p625z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r012c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neurological diseases are a common consequence of retroviral infections. The pathogenesis of these diseases however remains undetermined. In an attempt to elucidate the mechanisms involved in certain of these disorders, we have used an experimental approach involving transgenic mice. Transgenic animals provide an important tool in the study of retroviral diseases, since they allow us to circumvent the complex process of retroviral infection. In addition, when retroviral sequences are expressed under the regulation of a CNS-specific promoter, transgenic experiments allow us to evaluate the effects of expressing viral gene products in a given CNS cell population. Specific aspects of the neurological disorders caused by HIV-1, HTLV-1, and Cas-Br-E MuLV were evaluated. Transgenic mice experiments were generated in order to study the pathogenesis of the CNS white matter diseases caused by human retroviruses HIV-1 and by HTLV-1, and to evaluate the function of astroglial cells in mediating the CNS disease associated with Cas-Br-E MuLV infection. On the basis of our experimental results, we propose novel pathogenic mechanisms which may contribute to our understanding of the CNS diseases caused by these retroviruses.</description><creator>Goudreau, Guy</creator><contributor>Jolicoeur, Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Transgenic models of retrovirus-mediated central nervous system diseases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v4619.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r012c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vj35h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was designed to better define the molecular interactions that govern cell surface depletion of the CD4 receptor after HIV-1 infection of susceptible cells. The effects of intracellular association between the envelope glycoprotein precursor gp160 and CD4 were addressed in the U-937 monocytic cell line. Formation of complexes between these molecules was shown to impact on the maturation and transport of both in U-937 cells that were chronically-infected with either wild-type virus or with viruses unable to cleave the viral envelope precursor protein gp160. This arrest in maturation was demonstrated to be pre-Golgi in nature and was characterized by a lack of oligosaccharide trimming and proteolytic cleavage, for CD4 and gp160, respectively. In addition, the half-lives of both proteins were increased as compared with uncomplexed counterpart molecules. This indicated that the disappearance of CD4 from the cell membrane was due to a blockage in the endoplasmic reticulum and not to gp160-induced degradation. The putative negative effect of HIV-1 infection on CD4 translation was further examined using both tissue culture and cell-free models. First, levels of immunoprecipitable CD4 in chronically-infected U-937 cells were altered as compared with uninfected cells despite an absence of CD4 mRNA down-modulation and a lack of vpu expression. The mechanisms underlying inhibition of CD4 translation were therefore addressed in a cell-free translation system. In the presence of canine pancreatic membranes, we observed that co-translation of gp160-encoding mRNAs resulted in a profound dose-dependent inhibition of CD4 synthesis. This effect was specifically targeted at CD4 and functionally distinct of vpu-mediated, post-translational degradation or CD4. We have further identified the gp160/gp120 envelope glycoproteins as the necessary and sufficient components in mediating the inhibition of CD4 translation in vitro. To better define the molecular mechanisms involved, we asked whether the high affinity interaction between CD4 and gp160 played a role in this inhibition. Mutated CD4 molecules, which possessed a 20-fold lower affinity for gp160/gp 120 than wild type CD4, were protected from co-translational inhibition by HIV-1 mRNAs that encoded gp160. This suggests that direct interactions between gp160 and nascent CD4 peptides, caused premature termination of CD4 translation.</description><creator>Bour, Stéphane</creator><contributor>Wainberg, Mark A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Translational and post-translational modulation of the CD4 receptor following HIV-1 infection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tt27s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj35h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811km294</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The injury-induced alterations in sulfated proteoglycans (PG) were studied, in neointima, developed in response to a selective deendothelialization of the aorta, of normocholesterolemic rabbits. Light microscopic radioautography and size exclusion chromatography revealed differences in PG between neointima not covered by regenerated endothelium, and reendothelialized neointima or normal aorta. These differences included radioautographic reaction, concentration, size distribution and composition. Further studies were conducted to examine the putative role of the altered PG in lipoprotein (LP) sequestration and lipid accumulation during atherogenesis. LP-PG complexes were isolated by anti apo-B affinity column, from intima-medial tissues from normal and injured aortas. These complexes contained low density and very low density LP, chondroitin sulfate PG and hyaluronic acid. It appeared that endothelial injury enhanced the formation of LP-PG complexes, particularly in areas covered by regenerated endothelium. The uptake and degradation of LP-PG complexes, derived from normal (LP-NPG) or injured aortas (LP-IPG), by arterial smooth muscle cells (SMC) and blood monocyte-derived macrophages (BMDM) were also examined. LP-PG complexes stimulated LP binding, internalization and degradation by SMC and BMDM. Both cell types showed a higher affinity for LP-IPG than LP-NPG. The uptake of LP-PG complexes was mediated mainly by the LDL receptor pathway and phagocytosis. The scavenger receptor played a minor part in the uptake of LP-PG complexes. Data from this study provide evidence that endothelial injury could trigger alterations in neointimal PG, which in turn, facilitate LP accumulation both extracellularly and intracellularly during atherogenesis.</description><creator>Ismail, Nermine Ahmed Ehsan</creator><contributor>Alavi, M. Z. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Characterization of lipoprotein-proteoglycan complexes in balloon catheter deendothelialized aorta of rabbits and the uptake of these complexes by smooth muscle cells and macrophages</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db57t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km294</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vv856</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study was designed to further characterize the role of insulin and glucagon in the regulation of glucose fluxes during two hours of mild to moderate intensity exercise in postabsorptive healthy male subjects. Endogenous insulin and glucagon were suppressed by somatostatin (SRIF) infusion and the pancreatic hormones were then replaced singly or in combination to match the hormonal concentrations observed during similar exercise in control subjects. Glucose kinetics were determined using stable isotopes of glucose. The exercise protocol was sufficient to induce a 26% decrease in insulin and a 20% increase in glucagon. In all conditions, there were a 1.5- and 2-fold increase in glucose utilization and in glucose metabolic clearance rate, respectively when compared to the resting levels. Exercise alone was able to maintain the increase in glucose metabolic clearance rate despite a deficiency in insulin. Hepatic glucose production and gluconeogenesis increased to values representing 228 and 144% of the resting level, respectively. In the absence of glucagon, these increases during exercise were totally abolished. From our observations, it is concluded that during mild to moderate intensity exercise insulin was not essential for glucose uptake indicating that muscle contractions per se can stimulate glucose uptake by muscles and the increase in hepatic glucose production and gluconeogenesis are essentially dependent on the increase in glucagon. Insulin remains important, however, for maximal glucose uptake by contracting muscles and for preventing glucose overproduction and possibly hyperglycemia.</description><creator>Lavoie, Carole</creator><contributor>Chaisson, Jean-Louis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, General.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Recreation.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>The regulation of glucose fluxes during exercise in healthy male subjects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r268b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vv856</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cj232</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The structure of rat hepatic prolactin (PRL) receptors was examined in various subcellular fractions by immunoblotting. In all subcellular fractions, a single 42 kDa species was identified. Tri- and/or tetrantennary complex carbohydrates compose $ sp sim$7 kDa of the weight of the receptor. Enzymatic deglycosylation of the mature receptor does not appreciably reduce ligand binding or antibody recognition of the receptor. However, core glycosylation of the receptor is necessary for the acquisition of binding capacity and antibody recognition. The intracellular distribution of PRL receptors was determined by Percoll gradient centrifugation and application of the diaminobenzidine (DAB)-shift methodology. There was a sex-dependent distribution of PRL receptors, with females having a 3-fold higher concentration of receptors in early endosomes than males. This discrepancy disappeared when male rats were treated with estrogen. No such sex-dependent distribution of intracellular receptors were discovered for insulin receptors. Colchicine treatment of estrogen-induced male rats prevented newly synthesized receptors from reaching the cell surface, and allowed the accumulation of at least some of these receptors into an endosomal compartment. These studies suggest that under conditions of colchicine blockade, PRL receptors may access an endosomal compartment by an entirely intracellular route. To date, such a route has only been described for mannose-6-phosphate receptors.</description><creator>Dorato, Andrea</creator><contributor>Posner, Barry I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Characterization of the structure and subcellular distribution of the rat hepatic prolactin receptor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d1458.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj232</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967523t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of fluid-rock interaction at hydrothermal conditions were investigated by a detailed study of altered quartz diorite around a single gold-bearing quartz vein, and by experiments reacting quartz diorite with water, using a single-pass, continuous-flow system. Alteration in the natural environment produced ankerite and albite distal to the vein, and albite adjacent to it. Mass balance calculations show that there was a progressive mass loss (up to 30%) towards the vein, due primarily to the dissolution of quartz. In experiments at 200$ sp circ$C, SiO$ sb2$, Na and CO$ sb2$ concentrations were controlled by the dissolution of quartz, albite and ankerite. SiO$ sb2$ reached a steady state concentration below quartz saturation. The concentrations of Ca, Mg, Fe, and Al were buffered by the precipitation of smectite, boehmite and calcite. These experiments show that a fluid may not reach quartz saturation at 200$ sp circ$C, especially if the infiltrating fluid contains dissolved components which can promote the formation of secondary, quartz-consuming minerals. In the experiment at 350$ sp circ$C, the fluid reached quartz saturation almost immediately. The secondary minerals were anorthite, chlorite, boehmite, and titanite, which formed at the expense of albite, calcite, and ankerite, thereby increasing pH and releasing Na, SiO$ sb2$, CO$ sb2$ and Al to the fluid. Quartz was completely dissolved within 500 hours. The most significant conclusion from this experiment is that the progressive loss of quartz to a quartz-undersaturated fluid increases the surface area of more resistant minerals and promotes their dissolution. Investigations of both the natural and experimental systems emphasize the importance of quartz dissolution in creating porosity, and mineral reaction kinetics in controlling wall-rock alteration.</description><creator>Mountain, Bruce W. (Bruce William)</creator><contributor>Williams-Jones, A. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>Fluid-rock interaction paths : natural and experimental examples</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v554.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967523t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bn386</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The solution of dense systems of linear equations is at the heart of numerical computations. Such systems are best solved by direct methods based on one of the LU, Cholesky or QR factorizations. Typical parallel algorithms for the LU, Cholesky and QR factorizations of dense matrices stored on a message passing multicomputer hide latency by overlapping communication with arithmetic and by restricting communications to occur along a subring of processors. We show empirically that exploiting the full connectivity of the underlying multicomputer is essential for designing communication efficient algorithms. A specialized total exchange algorithm is presented for improving communication load balance during an LU factorization with pivoting. Threshold pivoting is proposed as a way of significantly reducing processor idle time due to row exchanges during an LU factorization with pivoting. The columns of the Q factor computed by modified Gram-Schmidt QR factorization algorithms can be far from orthogonal. Parallelizations of the algorithm proposed by Bjorck and Paige for safely using the computed Q are also presented.</description><creator>Malard, Joël</creator><contributor>Friedman, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Paige, C. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Block solvers for dense linear systems on local memory multiprocessors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945s52m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn386</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sx49k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present studies used the classical method of serial transections of the neuraxis to examine the neural mechanisms of injury-produced pain and morphine analgesia in the formalin test. The results showed that the behavioral response that follows formalin injection is complete within the brainstem, whereas telencephalic structures are critical for morphine to produce analgesia. In contrast, when the tail flick test, a model of noninjurious pain was used, both the behavioral response, and analgesia, were intact in the brainstem transected rat, in keeping with the current model of analgesia for this test. Brain areas classically associated with pain processing were not sufficient for morphine to produce analgesia in the formalin test. Instead, the amygdala, part of the emotion-mediating limbic system, was critical. It is argued that the formalin test may be a model of "dissociative" analgesia, in which reduction of the negative affective consequences of the pain plays a major role.</description><creator>Matthies, Brigitte Karin</creator><contributor>Franklin, Keith (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Opioids.</subject><subject>Analgesia.</subject><subject>Pain -- Physiological aspects.</subject><title>Neural mechanisms of pain and opioid analgesia in the formalin test</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t362s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sx49k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w37638587</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a new approach to the theory of the labor-managed firm, based on the case of the Yugoslavian labor-managed economy. Instead of income per worker maximization, we suggest that a labor-managed firm in a certain environment and given institutional setting maximizes revenue, while under uncertainty another approach is taken, namely that of social welfare maximization. Inefficient allocation may result in a labor-managed firm whose workers have no transferable property rights. We explore creation of an internal shares market as the means to acquire efficiency. Internal market for shares is also seen as a possible form of transition of the labor-managed firm, given the path of transformation of the institutional setting in former Yugoslavia, through a kind of industrial democracy with private (transferable) property rights.</description><creator>Novkovic, Sonja</creator><contributor>Long, N.V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Employee ownership -- Yugoslavia</subject><title>Theory of the labor-managed firm : the Yugoslavian case</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hk78n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w37638587</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x27p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The importance of discontinuous hormonal signals in endocrine communications is suggested by the ability of sustained hormonal signals to shut down, as opposed to stimulate, target cells, and by the observation that a change in pulse pattern can alter the response elicited. Serial sampling of the serum in catheterized, conscious, freely-moving rats was employed to investigate two aspects of pulsatility in the hypothalamo-pituitary-testicular feedback loop regulating reproduction in the adult male. First, in response to treatment with moderate to high doses of the testosterone (T) metabolite, dihydrotestosterone (DHT), pituitary responsiveness to exogenous LHRH was suppressed, and elevated post-castration mean LH levels declined due to a dose-dependent suppression of LH pulse frequency and amplitude. LH pulse amplitude was not suppressed by low dose DHT treatment, in spite of a dramatic suppression of pituitary responsiveness as measured, implying that a stimulatory androgenic influence on amplitude might be exerted upon hypothalamic LHRH release; blocking the endogenous opioid peptide system did not abolish this phenomenon. A stimulation of LH pulse amplitude was observed in orchidectomized rats given a low (sub-physiological) dose of T, and again, this effect was apparently mediated at a supra-pituitary site as pituitary responsiveness appeared unaltered at this T dose. These results suggest that the feedback regulatory actions of exogenous DHT, like those of T, are mediated at both the hypothalamus and the pituitary; this is consistent with the hypothesis that endogenous DHT mediates some of the negative and positive feedback effects of T in intact or T-treated orchidectomized animals. A second aspect of pulsatility was investigated in testes-intact rats. Fluctuations in serum T concentration are of a dual nature, reflecting both acute pulsatile bursts and prolonged episodes of testicular secretory activity, the precise pattern of which varies between and withi</description><creator>Bayly, Suzanne F.</creator><contributor>Robaire, Bernard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>The role of androgens in the regulation of the hypothalamo-pituitary-testicular axis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh09d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x27p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429b82d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We examined the mechanical properties of oocytes and eggs from Xenopus laevis frogs, in relation to the cells' ability to maintain volume in dilute media. Elastic properties were assessed by measuring intracellular pressure (Pic) and cell volume (Vc) during osmotic swelling. Cytoplasmic rheology was determined by magnetometry after microinjection of magnetic iron microparticles. Both oocytes and eggs had a small but measurable Pic. Oocytes markedly increased both Pic and Vc during osmotic swelling. The relationship between Pic and Vc was not linear and showed hysteresis indicating that oocytes are viscoelastic. After removal of the vitelline envelope, the Pic-Vc curve remained qualitatively similar but the Pic rise was reduced by 70%. During osmotic swelling, eggs increased Vc to a lesser extent than did oocytes and Pic did not change. Neither oocytes nor eggs displayed a regulatory volume decrease in response to hypotonic shock and osmolyte loss did not appear to limit swelling. Since Pic was low in eggs and did not increase with swelling, increased stiffness of the vitelline envelope was ruled out as the explanation for their reduced water uptake. Rheologic data indicated that cytoplasmic apparent viscosity and elastic shear modulus were lower in eggs than in oocytes, an observation not compatible with our hypothesis that eggs took up less water because their cytoplasm was a gel. We now feel that Vc of eggs may be controlled by the cortical actin cytoskeleton.</description><creator>Kelly, Suzanne Marie</creator><contributor>Macklem, P. T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Cell mechanical properties and volume control</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q67j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429b82d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gv22b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Normal and diseased human tissues were analyzed for the expression of genes of the carcinoembryonic (CEA) family. The use of portions of the CEA and NCA cDNA clones as hybridization probes has shown the existence of CEA and NCA transcripts in colon mucosa, NCA transcripts in breast tumours, and NCA and a third CEA-like transcript (CGM6) in chronic myelocytic leukemia (CML) cells. A library prepared from CML cells was used to isolate a cDNA clone of CGM6. The predicted product of this novel CEA family member displays 85% sequence similarity to CEA and NCA and its expression is limited to CML and normal human bone marrow cells. Southern blots of DNA did not reveal any CEA gene rearrangements or amplifications accompanying CEA expression. DNA digested with methylation-sensitive endonucleases demonstrated that CEA expression is correlated with a decreased level of methylation in the 5$ sp prime$ region of the CEA gene.</description><creator>Boucher, Danny</creator><contributor>Fuks, Abraham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>A study on the expression of the carcinoembryonic antigen gene family</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z698k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv22b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741t428</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this work we prove dualities for Diers categories, Barr categories and small Barr-exact categories. The latter duality solves a problem of M. Makkai. Further, we prove a stronger version of the strong completeness theorem on $ kappa$-Barr-exact categories. Finally we prove that an accessibly embedded subcategory of a locally presentable category satisfies the solution-set condition if it is accessible. This improves work of J. Adamek and J. Rosicky on injectivity in locally presentable categories.</description><creator>Hu, Hongde</creator><contributor>Mokkai, Micheal (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Dualities for accessible categories</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k77f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t428</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df12s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>American foreign assistance to the Ngo Dinh Diem regime in South Vietnam was a controversial issue during the Eisenhower and Kennedy years, straining the executive-legislative relationship and provoking discord within Congress. For Dwight D. Eisenhower, the programme was the best means of containing communism, short of ordering American forces to the region. Both major parties were divided on the issue. Conservatives and liberals in each party perceived foreign aid differently. Old Guard Republicans and southern Democrats were skeptical about the expensive assistance programme. They contended that the "give-away" legislation would undermine Saigon's resolve to attain economic and political autonomy. Generally suspicious of America's allies, conservatives were especially critical toward Diem since they considered him an unproven ally who could take advantage of United States' generosity. Liberal Republicans and Democrats, who harboured an internationalist perspective, acknowledged foreign aid as a legitimate means of countering communism. Perceiving Diem as an alternative to Ho Chi Minh's leadership and Bao Dai's incompetence, liberals supported the Premier's pro-democratic aspirations. The French reversal at Dien Bien Phu, the "fiasco" of the Geneva Conference, and the subsequent foreign assistance investigations by the legislative branch brought about a tenuous truce between conservatives and liberals. Although fundamental differences remained, both groups were convinced that a reappraisal of the aid programme was needed before the President committed America too heavily in Vietnam. The increasing commitments by Eisenhower's successor and his lack of co-operation with Capitol Hill solidified the conservative-liberal entente. Diem's assassination in November 1963 sobered Congress and strengthened its disapproval of America's assistance policy. Such congressional activism peaked by the late 1960's and early 1970's. The experience acquired during the Eisenhower and Kennedy years allowed Congress, not the President, to oppose United States military intervention in Vietnam during the Nixon Presidency. It also provided the initiative to rationalize the foreign aid legislation, favoring economic and technical development rather than military commitments.</description><creator>Doré, Gilbert</creator><contributor>Randall, Stephen J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>United States -- Foreign relations -- Vietnam</subject><subject>Vietnam -- Foreign relations -- United States</subject><title>United States foreign assistance diplomacy : Congressional policy on aid to Vietnam, 1952-1963</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt32d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df12s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr233</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, I propose a theory of ergativity in which NP arguments are checked for Case by moving to projections of agreement at LF. The Case-marking pattern of an ergative language arises when transitive subjects move to the projection of agreement usually associated with objects (AGR.o), while transitive objects and intransitive subjects move to the projection of subject agreement (AGR.s). While this proposal assigns the same underlying structure to clauses in an ergative language (unlike Marantz, 1984), it does have distinctive syntactic effects. In this it contrasts with a purely morphological approach to ergativity, such as that of Anderson (1976). Arguments can move to the specifier position of agreement, or adjoin to its maximal projection. Movement cannot take place across the same kind of position as the landing site, which leads us to predict that transitive subjects cannot undergo grammatical extraction in an ergative language. This prediction turns out to be correct in a number of languages, including Chamorro, Mam, and other members of the Mayan group. Our theory also allows for a plausible account of split ergativity--non-canonical patterns in an otherwise ergative language where transitive and intransitive subjects are marked the same, but behave differently under extraction. The proposal that NPs are not checked for Case until LF entails that they remain in their base positions at S-structure. Evidence for this claim is adduced from the distribution of empty pronoun arguments whose contents must be identified. Our prediction is that transitive subjects in an ergative language will interfere in the identification of an empty object pronoun, since it is closer to the pronoun than its legitimate identifier, AGR.s. This is also shown to be the case.</description><creator>Campana, Mark.</creator><contributor>Baker, Mark (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Ergative constructions.</subject><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Agreement.</subject><title>A movement theory of ergativity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q547.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr233</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pf53f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A series of novel biphenols and activated aromatic difluorides of general structure 1 and 2, respectively, were prepared employing readily available starting materials and reagents. These monomers were subsequently polymerized by nucleophilic aromatic substitution using anhydrous potassium carbonate as base in a dipolar aprotic solvent (equation 1)* to afford a series of high molecular weight (inherent viscosity = 0.5-1.24 dl/g) poly(aryl ether)s of the type 3 which exhibit high glass transition temperatures (160-314$ sp circ$C) and exceptional thermo-oxidative stability ($-$10% weight loss in the range 500-560$ sp circ$C). Most of these materials are readily soluble in common organic solvents such as methylene chloride and chloroform, allowing for facile solution processing to afford tough and flexible films. We also synthesized polymers from aromatic difluorides 2 which contain a moiety Y which can be cross-linked thermally. The resulting poly(aryl ether)s can be rendered solvent-resistant by heating. (Abstract shortened by UMI.) ftn*Please refer to dissertation for diagram.</description><creator>Strukelj, Marko</creator><contributor>Hay, Allan S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>High performance polymers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mh25h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pf53f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w135x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents Islamic modernism in Malaya as reflected in the life and works of Sayid Syekh al-Hadi (1867-1934). Having first described and evaluated the previous writings mentioned about al-Hadi, it outlines the main characteristics of Islamic modernism, and discusses al-Hadi's life and his thought covering four topics namely: ritualism, education, woman and politics. The study has shown that al-Hadi was a Malayan Muslim modernist. He seriously advocated Islamic modernism to overcome what he had perceived as the causes contributing to Malayan Muslim decadence and backwardness. He believed that Malayan Muslims could advance and progress even though they were under British rule because Islamic teachings are practicable and realistic.</description><creator>Abu Bakar, Ibrahim bin</creator><contributor>Adams, Charles J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Scholars, Muslim -- Malaysia -- Biography</subject><subject>Sheikh bin Ahmad al-Hadi, al-Syed, 1867-1934</subject><subject>Islam -- Malaysia</subject><title>Islamic modernism in Malaya as reflected in Hadi's thought</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q7922.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w135x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qn614</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new technique is presented for measuring the spatial and momentum distributions of a buffer-gas cooled ion cloud in a Paul trap by extracting it from the trap and fitting the time profile of the extracted ion signal. A thermodynamic model based on the Gibbs distribution has been developed which describes the initial ion cloud phase space volume and fits the measured time distributions of the extracted cloud using only one parameter: temperature. A time-of-flight system has been built to systematically vary the ion extraction conditions and compare predictions of the model to various measurements of the ion cloud time profile. A new numerical method using a multipole expansion was developed to compute the extraction fields. Agreement between the ion simulations and the time-of-flight data is better than 2% of the total flight time. Ion cloud temperatures were measured for seven different trap loadings of potassium ions and four loadings of sodium ions, in both cases down to clouds of about 1000 ions. This is the first time that temperature measurements have been made for such small numbers of buffer-gas cooled ions. The results show that the temperature of the ions above the buffer gas temperature appears to be proportional to the two-thirds power of the number of ions in the cloud. Dynamic manipulation of the extracted ion cloud phase space volume was also accomplished using a time-varying acceleration voltage to change the ion cloud energy spread in flight. A concept is also outlined to measure the detailed phase space area of the extracted cloud using the projection-slice theorem of tomographic imaging. These measurements have applications for the use of ion traps as beam collectors for nuclear physics experiments at isotope separator facilities and possibly for nano-circuit fabrication.</description><creator>Lunney, Matthew David Norwood</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Physics, Electricity and Magnetism.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>The phase space volume of ion clouds in Paul traps</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m0961.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn614</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k06989052</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Inducible LAK cell responses were studied in HIV-seropositive individuals lacking clinical symptoms, and overt AIDS patients. Inducible LAK cell responses have been operationally defined as, non-MHC-restricted and antigen-nonspecific cytotoxic activity observed following IL-2 stimulation. HIV-seropositive asymptomatic individuals exhibited an enhanced LAK cell response against HIV-infected targets while lysis of uninfected targets remained at control levels. LAK activity of AIDS patients however, was significantly diminished when compared to healthy controls. Immunomagnetic negative selection depletion experiments indicated that LAK cell activity is mediated primarily by CD56-expressing lymphocytes, both at the progenitor and effector cell level. Of interest, in HIV-seropositive asymptomatic individuals we observed the emergence of a second CD8-expressing cytotoxic population that mediates IL-2-induced non-MHC-restricted and antigen-nonspecific cytotoxicity. Overall we demonstrated that CD56-expressing LAK cells of HIV-seropositive patients exhibited a decreased ability to mediate cytotoxicity on a per cell basis against a panel of different targets. In vivo, this inhibition may be amplified by decreases in absolute numbers of CD56-expressing lymphocytes per ml of blood. HIV-infection therefore results in dramatic changes on the number, function and phenotype of the effector cells mediating IL-2 inducible LAK cell responses.</description><creator>Gryllis, Chryssa</creator><date>1992</date><subject>HIV-1.</subject><subject>Interleukin-2.</subject><subject>HIV.</subject><title>Characterization of IL-2 inducible cytotoxic LAK function in HIV-1 infected individuals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w1366.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k06989052</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h344w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The H$ sp+$-translocating inorganic pyrophosphatase from vacuolar membranes of red beet storage roots (Beta vulgaris L.) was purified after solubilization in Triton X-100 through a combination of anion-exchange and size exclusion chromatographies. SDS-PAGE showed strong correlation between a 67 kDa polypeptide and pyrophosphatase activity. Radiation-inactivation studies of the H$ sp+$-PPase indicate a functional size of 91 kDa for hydrolysis and 320 kDa for H$ sp+$ translocation, suggesting an oligomeric structure for the holoenzyme. Affinity purified antibodies were used to screen cDNA libraries of Arabidopsis thaliana yielding clones which contained sequences matching amino acid sequences obtained from tryptic fragments of the 67 kDa hydrolytic subunit. The predicted protein is highly hydrophobic with a molecular size of 81 kDa. Southern analyses show a single copy for the H$ sp+$-PPase in Arabidopsis. The lack of sequence identities between the H$ sp+$-PPase and other known proteins implies a novel class of ion translocases.</description><creator>Sarafian, Vahé</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Pyrophosphates</subject><subject>Plant enzymes</subject><subject>Tonoplasts</subject><title>Molecular characterization of a pyrophosphate-energized proton pump</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x553.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h344w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33275</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>