<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:48:46Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12025" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096b320</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Professor Wilder Penfield has accumulated, in a meticulous and laborious manner, data representing the effects of stimulation of the human cerebral cortex. Although these stimulations have been carried on for twenty odd years, it has been only during the past four years that more especial attention has been directed towards speech. In 1946, Dr. Preston Robb summarized the effect on speech of excising various cortical areas. These patients had had previous cerebral injuries with resultant focal cerebral seizures. Dr. Robb also began to assist Dr.Penfield in the operating room during the period of stimulation. The examination of patients before and after operation and the assistance in the operating theater have been and will be continued by this writer. The results of cortical stimulation on speech or, better, electrical arrest of certain speech mechanisms are presented at this time in order to summarize the present data and give suggestions for future study. Electrical arrest of three, or possibly four discrete cortical regions produces disturbances in speech other than simple arrest of speech. Few definite conclusions have been reached by either Dr. Robb or this author, but the groundwork has been laid. It is hoped and expected that a real contribution to the localization of areas producing specific speech defects and to the physiology of speech will be forthcoming at the conclusion of this project on stimulations and excisions of the cortex.[...]</description><creator>Roberts, Henry L.</creator><contributor>Penfield, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Neurology &amp; Neurosurgery.</subject><title>A study of certain alterations in speech during stimulation of specific cortical regions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f4471.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096b320</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k567r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary object of the investigation was the determination of the specific external surface of pulp fibres. Of the methods available for this purpose, the permeability method based on the Kozeny equation was selected as the most suitable. It has been found to provide reproducible results. The effective specific volume of the investigated material is an important factor in the Kozeny relationship and had to be determined. A procedure was employed which permitted the simultaneous evaluation of the specific surface and the apparent specific volume. Both of the quantities determined are of great practical and theoretical value in the investigation of the properties of fibrous materials. The specific surface of pulp fibres has been related to the properties of finished paper and the development of specific surface in the beater has been followed. The important application of specific volume measurement has been to assess the degree of swelling of pulp in various media and to determine the relation of swelling to the beating process.</description><creator>Robertson, Alexander Allan.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Specific surface and flocculation studies of pulp fibre suspensions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b4282.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k567r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z838j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the light of recent interest in the diagnosis of malignancy by the microscopic examination of exfoliated cells, it was felt that the practical value of this method, in one particular field, could usefully be compared with standard histological practices. Cancer of the lung was selected, specifically for this investigation for the following reasons: 1. Bronchogenic carcinoma is an extremely important disease, constituting approximately 10% of all adult male cancers (Jones 1947). 2. In the early stages of the disease practical therapy is available in the form of pneumonectomy. 3. However, because of late diagnosis, the five year survival rate remains in the neighbourhood of 8%, (Ochsner, DeBakey &amp; Dixon 1947).</description><creator>Ross, Roderick C.</creator><contributor>Duff, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>A comparison of pathological methods in the diagnosis of cancer of the lung.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q751b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z838j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vm188</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The commercial electro-winning of cadmium from sulphate solutions is limited to low current densities and requires frequent stripping of the cathode because of the high tendency to “tree formation”. Zinc, similar in many respects to cadmium, can be deposited from sulphate solutions (with suitable addition agents) at current densities ten times those used in cadmium production. While the problem of eleminating tree-formation with cadmium might be solved by an empirical search for a suitable addition agent, a fundamental study to determine the mechanism of cadmium deposition, such as that made by Hutcheon (1) seems a preferable approach to the problem.[...]</description><creator>Roxburgh, James Maxwell.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Overvoltage studies on cadmium cathodes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644v940.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vm188</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rp50f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many attempts have been made to lighten the obscurity which surrounds the physio-pathology of bronchial asthma, but the varying degrees of success encountered have been greatly decreased by the limitations of the methods of study available. A great deal of information has been compiled from reports on clinical observations and on studies of blood pressure, blood chemistry, x-ray, spirometric and electrocardiographic findings. Animal experiments and the results obtained from a variety of therapeutic procedures have provided indirect evidence which has set off many trains of thought and activity along a confusing number of tracks. A few valiant efforts have been made to establish order, but the fact still remains that the observations which have been made provide a very incomplete picture of a multifacetted problem. These considerations indicate that the sort of method needed is one which will give a composite picture of bronchial asthma by reflecting changes which occur in the respiratory and cardiovascular systems, since these appear to be most affected. The technique of cardiac catheterization, supplemented by puncture of a systemic artery, measurements of oxygen intake and by certain other techniques to be described, would seem to fulfill the foregoing requirements more satisfactorily than the methods hitherto employed. The degree of success which might be expected is, however, difficult to predict.[...]</description><creator>Rusted, Ian E.</creator><contributor>Rose, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>The effects of induced asthma-like attacks in man on the intake of oxygen, blood oxygen content and cardiac output.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m456.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rp50f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63t0142</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Tricarboxylic Acid Cycle is now believed to represent the main pathway for the oxidative metabolism of carbohydrate, fat and protein. The compounds of the Cycle are dicarboxylic and tricarboxylic acids that arise in the course of the metabolism of these substances. The development of the Cycle began with the systematic search by Thunberg (1) (1906-1920) for substances that could be metabolized by animal tissues. Using the acceleration of the decolorization of methylene blue by the tissue as the criterion that an added substrate was oxidized, Thunberg listed lactate, succinate, fumarate, malater citrate and glutamate, among many other substances, as metabolites. This work was confirmed and extended by Batelli and Stern (2). Enzymatic studies of the oxidation of the dicarboxylic acids revealed their close relationship in metabolism; the series of reactions. Succinate⇌Fumarate⇌Malate⇌Oxalacetate was established (3, page 203).[...]</description><creator>Saffran, Murray.</creator><contributor>Denstedt, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Metabolism of tricarboxylic acid cycle compounds in kidney and liver tissue.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085p42m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63t0142</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c580t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Soil contains many and varied microorganisms which are able to cope with and actively metabolize the materials, both organic and in some cases inorganic, that are presented to it under natural conditions. This must be expected for otherwise there would gradually accumulate those substances which could not be so transformed. Hence soil has proved to be of great use to the microbiologist and the bacteriologist in their search for new and specific microorganisms. However successful these studies have been their end has almost invariably been the isolation of a pure culture of such microorganisms and an investigation of their properties in this form. A rather different picture presents itself in soil as found in the field as under this condition the biological transformations are proceeding either simultaneously or successively and cannot be adequately paralleled by experiments on individual pure cultures.[...]</description><creator>Scholefield, Peter Gordon.</creator><contributor>Quastel, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Soils -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Soil biochemistry.</subject><subject>Soil chemistry.</subject><title>Studies in soil metabolism.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hs84r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c580t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55zb97v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this paper is to demonstrate the ability of a mass of living insects to function as a group of pseudomolecules, and so imitate some of the properties of gases, liquids and solids. In the past many inanimate systems have been shown to act like animate systems. Typical examples are the chemical gardens, based on sodium silicate reactions, and the ameboid action of oil droplets on granular materials. This paper is an attempt to reverse the above procedure and make animate entitles react in a manner similar to inanimate systems.</description><creator>Scott, David P., 1926-</creator><contributor>Stanley, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><subject>Insects.</subject><title>A mass of living insects considered as a pseudo-substance, the moving insects acting as pseudomolecules.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430783w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zb97v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c383g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An infra red total absorption method for estimating the time courses of photosynthesis and transpiration was described in a recent paper by Scarth, Loewy and Shaw (1948). For the present investigation the use of an improved design of this apparatus has been combined with that of a resistance porometer to follow photosynthesis or transpiration and stomatal movement simultaneously in one and the same leaf. The aim of the research was not only to test the value of the infra red technique for a variety of purposes, but also in so doing to obtain a clearer picture of the entire relationship between stomatal movement and the processes of transpiration and photosynthesis.[...]</description><creator>Shaw, Michael.</creator><contributor>Scarth, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Plant Pathology-Botany.</subject><title>Mutual and environmental relationships of transpiration, photosynthesis and stomatal opening.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892f20g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c383g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology and Botany</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hs851</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Disturbances in the function of the adrenal cortex in man are associated with several clinical syndromes. In some patients, however, the classical features known to be associated with abnormalities in adrenal function may not be apparent, in spite of the fact that such disturbances are present. In these cases, various methods of evaluation of adrenal cortical function must be used in order to demonstrate the abnormality. One of these methods is to estimate the quantity of hormones secreted by the adrenal cortex by measuring the level of these hormones, or their metabolites, in the urine. This has been done by means of biological and chemical assays, and has yielded considerable knowledge regarding the nature of the disturbances present, as well as their degree. It has repeatedly been demonstrated that enhanced adrenal cortical activity is an important feature in the resistance of the organism to varied types of stress. [...] The chemical and biological assays mentioned above give an indication of the level of activity of the adrenal cortex, but do not give any information about the ability of the gland to respond to stressful situations. It seemed important, then, that an investigation into adrenal cortical function and reserve in health and disease be undertaken, and that the response to stimulation by ACTH, as measured by urinary hormone studies, be used as an indication of adrenal cortical reserve.Disturbances in the function of the adrenal cortex in man are associated with several clinical syndromes. In some patients, however, the classical features known to be associated with abnormalities in adrenal function may not be apparent, in spite of the fact that such disturbances are present. In these cases, various methods of evaluation of adrenal cortical function must be used in order to demonstrate the abnormality. One of these methods is to estimate the quantity of hormones secreted by the adrenal cortex by measuring the level of these hormones, or their metabolites, in the urine. This has been done by means of biological and chemical assays, and has yielded considerable knowledge regarding the nature of the disturbances present, as well as their degree. It has repeatedly been demonstrated that enhanced adrenal cortical activity is an important feature in the resistance of the organism to varied types of stress. [...] The chemical and biological assays mentioned above give an indication of the level of activity of the adrenal cortex, but do not give any information about the ability of the gland to respond to stressful situations. It seemed important, then, that an investigation into adrenal cortical function and reserve in health and disease be undertaken, and that the response to stimulation by ACTH, as measured by urinary hormone studies, be used as an indication of adrenal cortical reserve.</description><creator>Singer, Bertha.</creator><contributor>Hoffman, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Effect of adrenocorticotrophic hormone on the urinary excretion of corticoids in health and disease.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445ch51b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hs851</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f4489</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The object of this investigation is to describe and to discuss the origin of some porphyroblastic and porphyritic rocks that outcrop on Salmon Arm, Shuswap Lake, B.C. The outcrop is a “sill-sediment” complex consisting of granite porphyry sills and associated porphyroblastic and aplite sills lying in a micaepidote schist parallel to its schistosity. The complex is also cut by a few aplite dikes. The structural and petrographical data obtained indicate that the porphyroblastic and porphyry sills and also at least one aplite sill were formed by replacement.</description><creator>Skinner, Ralph G.</creator><contributor>Kranck, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>A Study of some intrusive rocks and replacement phenomena in the Salmon Arm area, B.C. : (Shuswap terrane).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kd916.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f4489</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53k128h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study of clothing on a minimum adequate standard was prompted by the writer’s observations during seven years’ experience as a social service worker with the Jewish Family Welfare Department in Montreal, During that period it became more and more apparent that the agency’s system of providing clothing to its clients was a weak link in its chain of services. Families in the above agency have consistently complained for several years of the system of clothing distribution. Many felt it degrading to be deprived of an opportunity to make a choice. Others were of the opinion that given the same amount of money spent by the agency they could have shopped to their own individual taste and made better investments. In other words, it was evident that families had not accepted the clothing room favourably. Clients and workers together were aware that clothing received through the agency was poor in quality and insufficient in quantity. The social case worker was also conscious of the clients’ emotional conflict which evolved from the necessity of clients visiting the agency’s clothing room to collect the needed items. Many clients were fearful of meeting friends or neighbours from whom they wished to conceal their association with the agency. There were always conflicting pressures in making decisions on clothing: the pressure of more important needs and wants, and the pressure of limitation of resources available by the agency for clothing.[...]</description><creator>Spector, Esther.</creator><contributor>Younge, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Social Work.</subject><title>A Study of clothing budgets on a minimum adequate standard for a family agency in Montreal, 1947-1948.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945v15w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k128h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795c00b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>C’est un roman plein d’émotion, de mouvement et de vie que “Les Misérables” de Victor Hugo. Nous y faisons la connaissance de plusieurs caractères qui excitent nos plus profondes sympathies et â qui nous nous intéressons de plus en plus jusqu’à la dernière page. Par conséquent nous resterons toujours reconnaissants à Victor Hugo narrateur. Il arrive assez souvent a l’auteur d’interrompre son récit pour faire une dissertation philosophique dont les idées ont été inspirées par l‘histoire elle-même» Dans “Les Misérables”, Victor Hugo cependant, n’est pas uniquement chroniqueur et philosophe. Il a non seulement créé des caractères et exposé ses idées personnelles sur la philosophie, mais de plus il  a utilisé les circonstances, les moeurs et l a vie de ses personnages pour peindre leur milieu. A travers les agissements de Jean Valjean, de Cosette, de Marius et des autres, nous sentons toujours vivre la grande ville de Paris. Victor Hugo nous peint de temps en temps de magnifiques vues de la métropole, de sa grandeur et de sa majesté, de sa gaieté et de sa joie, de ses beaux édifices historiques, de ses épreuves politiques et sociales, de ses quartiers riches et pauvres, et des malheurs de ses habitants infortunés.</description><creator>Stewart, Marie Isabella.</creator><contributor>Furness, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Paris (France) -- In literature.</subject><subject>Hugo, Victor, 1802-1885. Misérables.</subject><title>Le Paris des "Misérables".</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343w24x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795c00b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gp24d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Penicillin, an antibacterial principle produced by certain strains of the mold Penicillium notatum or Penicillium chrysogenum, has been found to be highly effective in inhibiting the growth of most Gram positive as well as some Gram negative organisms. As will be indicated in the historical review, the exact mechanism of the antimicrobial activity is still unknown[...] The purpose of the investigational studies presented is the experimental examination of the effect of Penicillin on this enzyme, and of the response in hyaluronidase production by Streptococcus pyogenes to subinhibitory levels of the antibiotic during its metabolism. As a result of this investigation, some insight may be gained into the reaction of one facet of bacterial metabolism when submitted to sublethal concentrations of Penicillin, and thereby obtain the resultant “in vitro” effect produced by one of the possible constituents of bacterial invasiveness. The studies presented here are part of a long range problem, which has been designed to differentiate the circumstances under which an antibiotic will inhibit bacterial cell reproduction, and circumstances under which less than this, will inhibit one enzyme system, which in this case is hyaluronidase. This problem has a bearing on the whole understanding of the effect of antibiotic levels in the tissues of the body.</description><creator>Stock, John J.</creator><contributor>Smith, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Bacteriology.</subject><title>The effect of penicillin on hyaluronidase production by bacteria.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mj71t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gp24d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bacteriology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397c48p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Part of the overall process of adjustment to external environmental conditions is the replacement of worn out material at the body surface. The protective coating of epidermis which encases the whole body does not remain unchanged from birth to death, but is continually being worn out and shed, while at the same time new material is supplied to make good the loss. In some of the lower vertebrate forms, such as the urodele amphibians, the worn out skin surface is lost in a single shedding or moulting, but only after the new skin surface that is to take its place has been completely formed. In mammalian forms the replacement process is a gradual one, and proceeds at different rates in various regions of the body, usually depending upon the amount of exposure of that part of the body surface to mechanical pressure in the external environment. [...]</description><creator>Storey, Winnifred F.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Anatomy</subject><title>The study of renewal rates in the epidermis of the albino rat.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zh637.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397c48p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hs869</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is no known account of the Physical Geography of the Avalon Peninsula of Newfoundland, compiled in the style of modern geographic works. Some pertinent information is contained in various publications both old and new, but most commonly as incidental impressions of investigators in other fields of research, such as geology, botany or history. No attempt has been made to collect this material into one work. Furthermore, any material written concerning the Geography of the Avalon Peninsula has been for the greater part descriptive rather than analytical or interpretative. It consequently lacked the qualifications which are the essential basis for a modern geographical report. The purpose of this report is, therefore, to analyse the various elements of the Physical Geography of the Avalon Peninsula, showing the relationship between each and the combined relationship with the overall economic pattern of the district.</description><creator>Summers, William Francis.</creator><contributor>Hare, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Glacial erosion -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Avalon Peninsula.</subject><subject>Glacial landforms -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Avalon Peninsula.</subject><subject>Avalon Peninsula (N.L.)</subject><title>The physical geography of the Avalon Peninsula of Newfoundland.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g49f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hs869</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b662g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The frequency modulated radio frequency system of the McGill synchro-cyclotron is described. This equipment has been built and tested, and found to operate in a satisfactory manner, producing a beam of protons of one hundred million electron volts energy. An historical section outlines the radio frequency systems of fixed frequency cyclotrons, and the advent of frequency modulation. The design and construction of the individual components of the McGill cyclotron radio frequency system are described in detail. Lastly a description of the successful operation of the equipment is given, complete with graphs, drawings and photographs.</description><creator>Telford, W. M. (William Murray), 1917-</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Terroux, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Radio frequency system of the McGill synchro-cyclotron.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dd23d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b662g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dq455</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since 1942, a series of investigations have been carried out in the Department of Chemistry at McGill University using aluminum hydrosilicates as catalysts in various vapour-phase organic reactions. It was found by a number of workers in this field that Morden bentonite, a clay mined at Morden, Manitoba, is an effective catalyst in a number of reactions; namely, the dealkylation of straight and branched chain hydrocarbons, and the dehydration of alcohols, ketones, and cyclic alcohols. Toluene was obtained in good yields from p-cymene. Ethylbenzene was found to give benzene, toluene, and small amounts of styrene. Butadiene was obtained from butanediol-2,3, butanone-2, and cyclohexanol. Styrene was produced by the pyrolysis of 1,1-diphenylethane. High yields of unsaturated hydrocarbons were obtained by dehydration of aliphatic alcohols such as amyl alcohol, and diethylcarbinol. In these studies mentioned above, activated Morden bentonite was found to be the best of the catalysts used. Since this aluminum hydrosilicate appeared to be a very versatile and efficient catalyst, it was decided to extend the investigations to other classes of organic compounds, and to determine aniline, and N,N-diethylaniline. Aniline has also been pyrolysed.[...]</description><creator>Tonks, David Bayard.</creator><contributor>Nicholls, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Alkylations and isomerizations catalysed by an aluminium hydrosilicate.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tj65n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dq455</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117s192</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since there is the danger of fall frosts damaging a large part of the tomato crop before it is completely harvested, the fruits may be picked in the mature-green stage when frosts appear imminent, and ripened artificially. In some cases, the tomato plants are set out late in the season so that the vines and fruits are at their prime when frosts are likely to occur. The fruit is then harvested in the mature-green stage, stored for a short period and then ripened. This practice lengthens the period of availability of locally grown fresh tomatoes. Tomatoes for the winter and spring markets are grown in the South and shipped to northern cities for the retail trade. The fruit generally arrives in the mature-green stage, and therefore it is necessary to ripen this fruit before putting it on the wholesale or retail markets. The present experiments were therefore designed to determine the optimum ripening conditions of mature-green tomatoes.</description><creator>Trossman, Walter A.</creator><contributor>Murray, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Horticulture.</subject><title>The artificial ripening of mature-green tomatoes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk43h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117s192</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Horticulture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386n78c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is the aim of the historical geographer to recreate the geography of past epochs, and to trace the past relationship between man and his physical environment which has resulted in the present landscape. In the following pages an attempt is made to do this with respect to the St. Maurice Valley. There have been three main types of occupance in the valley since the founding of Three Rivers in 1634. At first the settlements were dependent mainly upon the fur-trade, and upon a few small local industries. This was a long period in the history of the St. Maurice Valley and did not end until 1852, mainly because of the treacherous character of the river. The second period was characterised by the exploitation of the forest wealth of the valley, and lasted from 1852—1898. It produced a different cultural landscape with new settlements growing up and older ones becoming redundant. Finally, in the period 1898 to the present, the power of the river has been harnessed to produce electricity. A new industrial region has come into being with new kinds of towns in new locations. The following work thus falls quite logically into three sections. In each of these periods the valley has had a distinctive geography, and although the transitions are not sharp they are clear enough to make such a division useful and valid.</description><creator>Uren, Philip Ernest.</creator><contributor>Hare, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Mauricie (Québec)</subject><title>The historical geography of the St. Maurice valley : with special reference to urban occupance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qc97z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386n78c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514np595</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Sherbrooke series was examined in detail in the vicinity of Lake Memphremagog in the Eastern townships of Quebec. More specifically, the area lies within the eastern half of the Memphremagog map-area (Canada Sheet 31 H/1) . This map derives its name from the most priminent topographic feature, namely, Lake Memphremagog, which, running north and south, divides the sheet roughly into east and west halves. The Sherbrooke series occupies a triangular area, with its apex at McGoon Point, bounded on the west by Lake Memphremagog and then on the southeast by a line running from McGoon Point along Fitch Bay, Bunker Hill into Lake Massawippi, and on the north by the northwest shore of the latter lake to the eastern edge of the map sheet. In the following pages this area will be designated the Memphremagog triangle.[...]</description><creator>Veilleux, Brendon Michael.</creator><contributor>Clark, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Structure and stratigraphy of the Sherbrooke series in the Memphremagog area.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x7013.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np595</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b191g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>At the Central Laboratory of the Division of Botany and Plant Pathology Ottawa, tests are run throughout the winter on pea seed samples for the presence of pathogenic and non-pathogenic fungi on them. The seed samples are sent in by growers throughout the Ottawa district. Ascochyta spp. and Fusarium spp. are the dominant fungi isolated from pea seed originating in the Ottawa district. As shown by Jones in 1927 there are three Ascochyta fungi which cause disease on peas; Ascochyta pisi Lib., Mycosnhaerella pinodes (Berk, and Blox.) Stone and Ascochyta pinodella Jones. The percentage of seed infected with Ascochyta pisi in these samples varies from 0 to 100%. The percentage of seed infected with Ascochyta pinodes and Ascochyta pinodella does not usually run above 5%. Due to the high percentage of A. pisi in the seed and the importance of this fungus in causing reduced stands when infected seed is used for planting, investigations have been undertaken for a number of years in an effort to discover methods of controlling the organism. Most of the work on control at Ottawa is concerned with the effectiveness of seed dusting.[...] The importance of soil infestation and seed treatment studies have also been undertaken. The investigations were conducted during the summers of 1945, 1946, 1947 and 1948 at Ottawa and during the winter of 1947 - 1948 at Macdonald College.</description><creator>Wallen, Victor R.</creator><contributor>Coulson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Plant Pathology.</subject><title>A study of the biology and control of ascochyta blights of peas.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hc981.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b191g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x702c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study of galactose metabolism in man is important for three reasons: (l) galactose serves, particularly in early life, as an important source of glucose; (2) it is required for the formation of galactolipids, important constituents of the central nervous system; (3) abnormalities of its metabolism are used in the diagnosis of disease. [...]</description><creator>Walsh, George C.</creator><contributor>Hoffman, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Glucose</subject><title>Glucose and galoctose metabolism in health and disease.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wr027.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x702c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gk66t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the manner of Segre and Helmholz it has been possible using an expansion in spherical waves and elementary vector analysis methods to derive expressions for the field intensities resulting from electric and magnetic dipole radiation and electric quadrupole radiation in terms of the corresponding moments of the nucleus. These same methods however are not applicable to higher orders of multipole radiation. The form of the vector potential resulting from electric and magnetic 2l-pole radiation has been treated in a paper by Heitler. In this paper he considers the expression for the vector potential resulting from electric dipole radiation and then generalizes to obtain the vector potentials resulting from electric and magnetic 2 -pole radiation. A further discussion of these results is given by Dancoff and Morrison. A completely different approach to the problem is given here in which the total field intensities resulting from a nuclear radiation are broken into two parts, one resulting from electric multipole radiation, and the other resulting from magnetic multipole radiation. The parts are in turn written in the form of an expansion, the individual terms of which are the field intensities for the various orders of multipole radiation present.[...]</description><creator>Watson, H. A. (Hugh A.)</creator><contributor>Wallace, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Multipole radiation.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g580k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk66t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343w256</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:12:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis comprises a group of historical and critical studies of the Canadian nature poetry which appeared in both English and French from the time of Canada’s earliest literary beginnings up to the second decade of the present century. These studies deal in part with the parallels and contrasts to be found in the work of the leading English and French Canadian poets of the period designated. Unless otherwise indicated, the terms “English” and “French” stand throughout for English Canadian and French Canadian. Biographical and bibliographical material is presented more extensively in the case of the French poets since it is the aim of the writer to make a definite contribution to the meagre store of factual knowledge English Canadians have of the literary history of their French compatriots. The majority of Canada’s poets, both English and French, demonstrated in varying degree their powers of observation and detailed reportage as well as their emotional or aesthetic appreciation of their subject. The French poets, however, stopped considerably short of the philosophical approach; they had yet to show an awareness of the opportunity and the challenge in a philosophical view of nature.[...]</description><creator>Wearing, Parker Lovell.</creator><contributor>Phelps, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Canadian poetry -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Nature in literature.</subject><title>Studies in Canadian nature poetry.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t9616.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343w256</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12050</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>