<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:25:23Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):36050" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752h39s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study seeks to undertake an analysis of the topic of 'science and the media' as it has been constituted in academic discourse since the end of the Second World War. It finds that concern has polarized in two distinct camps: The larger, participant in the traditional project of North American media studies, blames the press for what it perceives as a widespread and deleterious "scientific illiteracy" on the part of the laity. The more recent, indebted to critical developments in social theory, philosophy of science, and the study of mass communication, works to expose the assumptions on which press coverage of science has been based and the interests which have benefited. The thesis argues that the adequacy of the dominant concern to its object of analysis is at best suspect, but that nevertheless its agitations have been chiefly responsible for the form which popular science has predominantly assumed.</description><creator>Dornan, Chris.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Scientific literature -- Use studies</subject><subject>Science -- Information services -- Use studies</subject><subject>Communication in science -- Use studies</subject><title>Science as ideology : the problem of science and the media reconsidered</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mm91w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752h39s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zr408</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experiments were conducted to examine the role of dietary selenium (Se) and changes in antioxidant capacity during DMBA-induced mammary carcinogenesis. Weanling rats were fed graded amounts of Se in an AIN-76 diet, modified to approximate the amount and type of dietary fat consumed in Canada. Animals fed 3-4 ppm Se had a reduced tumor incidence but there was evidence of chronic Se toxicity. Low Se did not elevate tumor incidence. Thus, supplemental dietary Se did not offer any protection in reducing the incidence of cancer when rats were fed a diet representative of North American intakes of fat. Blood GSHPx activity was elevated in rats that remained free of tumors (NT group) compared to animals that would eventually develop tumors (WT group). SOD activity was reduced in WT and NT rats, but appeared to be related to carcinogen administration. These differences were observed before tumor development and over a wide range of Se intakes. WT rats excreted more $ sp{75}$Se compared to both control and NT rats. These changes, however, were not reflected in elevated lipid peroxidation. Thus, one of the protective mechanisms during carcinogenesis may be the capacity of the animal to elevate GSHPx activity.</description><creator>L'Abbé, Mary R.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Rats -- Diseases.</subject><subject>Selenium in animal nutrition.</subject><subject>Selenium -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Carcinogenesis.</subject><title>Role of dietary selenium as an antioxidant during carcinogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z150x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zr408</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418n94c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An isoenzyme survey of several taxa within the genus Lotus was undertaken to provide markers for genetic research and to test hypotheses concerning the phylogenetic origin of Lotus corniculatus L. A preliminary study identified seven enzyme systems PGI, TPI, PGM, MDH, IDH, 6-PGDH and ME, that produced consistent clear phenotypes in L. uliginosus Schkuhr. Variation in phenotype with tissue type and stage of development suggested the presence of several isozyme zones in the phenotypes. Enzyme phenotype was constant for shoot tissue of plants older than six weeks. A second study examined recombination and segregation of isoenzyme phenotypes in interspecific hybrids, allo- and autopolyploids, and in L. corniculatus. Duplication and quadruplication of pgi2 loci in hybrids, amphidiploids, and in L. corniculatus was used as evidence that the latter is a segmental allotetraploid. A third study surveyed the occurrence of various isoenzyme alleles in L. alpinus Schleich., L. japonicus (Regel) Larsen, L. tenuis Waldst. &amp; Kit., L. uliginosus and L. corniculatus. Lotus uliginosus had unique distinct alleles for several enzymes that did not occur in the other species. This evidence argues against the involvement of L. uliginosus in the origin of L. corniculatus.</description><creator>Raelson, John Verner</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Lotus</subject><subject>Isoenzymes.</subject><subject>Plant genetics.</subject><title>An isoenzyme study in the Genus lotus (Fabaceae) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603qz14j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418n94c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h511f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of the present study is to recover from selected Hindu and Buddhist texts ideas and images of aging and illumine their historical, semantic and metaphysical dimensions. The results of this endeavor indicate that as cultural adaptive systems, both religion and gerontology share a common concern in seeking to provide aging with purpose and meaning. Further, the internal logic and semantics expressing this relationship in the texts examined are governed by the formal and literary modes of simile, metaphor and myth. The analysis of such age-sensitive concepts as jara (aging), asrama (stages of life), kala (time), parinama (change), karma (determinate actions), kama (desire), and vaja (rejuvenatory and revitalizing force) suggest that the bond between the traditional Indian values of life and gerontology is particularly close and mutual.</description><creator>Tilak, Shrinivas, 1939-</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Aging -- Religious aspects -- Hinduism</subject><subject>Aging -- Religious aspects -- Buddhism</subject><title>Religion and aging in Indian tradition : a textual study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20st30h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h511f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53ww48v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The structure and the regulation of the hepatic $ alpha sb1$-adrenergic receptors have been studied in the rat. The in vitro incubation of isolated liver cells in a serum-free buffer for 4 hr leads to the conversion of the adrenergic activation of glycogen phosphorylase from an $ alpha sb1$- to a $ beta$-adrenoceptor-mediated event. This change is associated with no change in the glycogenolytic response to vasopressin and a reduction of the glycogenolytic response to glucagon. The time-dependent shift in the adrenergic control of glycogenolysis does not influence the density or the affinity of ($ sp3$H) prazosin-labeled $ alpha sb1$-receptors and ($ sp3$H) CGP-12177-labeled $ beta$-receptors. The change in the adrenergic control of glycogenolysis is reversed by a 30-min incubation with 50 nM lipomodulin, whereas in freshly isolated cells lipomodulin doesn't affect the predominant $ alpha$-receptor response. Conversely, exposure of freshly isolated cells to a monoclonal antibody to lipomodulin in the presence of 10 $ mu$M phenylephrine, or to 2 $ mu$g/ml mellitin, results in a shift in the adrenergic control of glycogenolysis from $ alpha sb1$- to $ beta$-type within 30 min. It is proposed that coupling of hepatic $ alpha sb1$- and $ beta$-adrenoceptors to postreceptor pathways is regulated in an inverse reciprocal manner by changes in membrane phospholipase A$ sb2$ activity. The mechanism of activation of the Ca$ sp{2+}$-linked receptors for vasopressin and adrenaline was studied in isolated liver cells. Sequential treatment of cells with 10$ sp{-7}$M vasopressin and 1 mM of bifunctional cross-linker disuccinimidyl suberate (DSS), followed by washout of the drugs, doesn't influence the dissociation of vasopressin from its receptor, but results in permanent activation of glycogen phosphorylase. Similarly, when the cells are stimulated with 10$ sp{-5}$M adrenaline and treated with DSS, glycogen phosphorylase is permanently activated. It is proposed that agonist activation of vasopressin or $ alpha sb1$-adrenergic receptors involves the microaggregation of receptors or their coupling to other membrane proteins. A novel irreversible antagonist for the $ alpha sb1$-adrenergic receptors, I-phenoxybenzamine (I-POB) has been synthesized and pharmacologically characterized. We have shown that I-POB binds to the $ alpha sb1$-adrenergic receptor in rat liver plasma membranes with high affinity (K$ sb{ rm i}$ = 2 nM). (Abstract shortened with permission of author.)</description><creator>Tchakarov, Liouben E.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Biochemical and pharmacological studies of the hepatic alpha1 r-adrenergic receptor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193974j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53ww48v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s549h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Determining the higher level relationships of the modern amphibian order Gymnophiona (caecilians) poses a number of methodological problems. A cladistic methodology is outlined by which the phylogenetic relationships of this group can be determined objectively. Among the possible sister groups analyzed, which include dissorophid temnospondyls, aistopods, nectrideans, lysorophoids, microsaurs, anurans and urodeles, the microsaurs of the families Gymnarthridae and Goniorhynchidae are the most plausible sister group of caecilians, based on cranial osteology. Hence, the three modern orders of amphibians, caecilians, anurans and urodeles, do not constitute a monophyletic assemblage exclusive of all other groups. Ingroup analysis indicates that the Ichthyophiidae is the most primitive living caecilian family. The cladistic analysis suggests that features of the unique jaw apparatus define two groups of caecilians which diverged, phylogenetically, early in the group's history. Morphometric analysis reveals that elements of the jaw apparatus compose a functional suite of features. Aspects of the development, function, and significance of the jaw to miniaturization of the caecilian skull are inferred from the morphometric analysis.</description><creator>Walsh, Denis M.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Amphibians, Fossil.</subject><subject>Caecilians.</subject><title>Systematics of the caecilians (Amphibia: Gymnophiona)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k59w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s549h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t2619</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The central focus is on the testing of the causes and effects of export earnings instability in Brazil, 1953-1983. While Brazil has been included in some cross-sectional studies of fluctuations in export earnings, it has not been the subject of a case study, as is provided here. We test the traditional theory which stipulates that increased diversification of exports will decrease export earnings instability, and that in turn, a decrease in export earnings instability will enhance economic growth. While we do find that export diversification in Brazil did result in lower export earnings instability, the lower export earnings instability did not in turn stimulate economic growth. Our results indicate that the export earnings instability of manufactured goods was positively associated with the growth rate of Brazil's Gross National Product. The results of this case study may prove relevant to other developing countries striving to emulate the Brazilian success in diversifying into manufactured exports.</description><creator>Smith, Margaret.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Brazil -- Economic conditions -- 1945-1964</subject><subject>Brazil -- Economic conditions -- 1964-1985</subject><subject>Export sales contracts -- Brazil</subject><subject>Brazil -- Commercial policy</subject><title>Export earnings instability in Brazil, 1953-1983</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t701.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t2619</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r1659</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Maximum wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) yields in Zambia were obtained with weekly irrigation at 85% of class A pan evaporation during the whole irrigation interval and split application of urea N of which the initial portion of the fertilizer was either broadcast and incorporated or broadcast after the crop had established itself. This corresponded with maximum utilization of fertilizer N. The proportion of N derived from fertilizer was independent of fertilizer placement at various water regimes and N utilization was primarily a function of water availability. Two nonnodulating soybean (Glycine max L.) cultivars, Clark RJ1 and N77, or in their absence Pearl millet (Panicum glaucum L.) were judged to be appropriate reference crops for estimating N$ sb2$ fixation by soybeans using $ sp{15}{ rm N}$ isotope dilution techniques. A local soybean cultivar, Magoye, was rated highest among three cultivars tested for its ability to support N$ sb2$ fixation by Bradyrhizobium japonicum and contributed biologically fixed N$ sb2$ to a subsequent wheat crop.</description><creator>Munyinda, Kalaluka.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Wheat -- Zambia</subject><subject>Nitrogen -- Fixation.</subject><subject>Wheat -- Zambia -- Irrigation</subject><subject>Soybean -- Zambia -- Irrigation.</subject><subject>Soybean -- Zambia.</subject><title>Efficiency of water and nitrogen use by wheat and legumes in Zambia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wn55n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r1659</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c117g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sampling and analytical techniques to estimate abundance and productivity of stream invertebrates are examined for their precision and accuracy, and then utilized to develop empirical models of sampling variability, abundance, and growth rates of overwintering larvae of black flies (Diptera: Simuliidae). Sampling variability of density estimates of stream benthos increases with mean density, and decreases with sampler size. Artificial substrates do not consistently reduce sampling variability, and introduce variable bias in estimates of simuliid density. Growth rates of overwintering simuliids are mainly a function of their body size, but available data show that growth rates also increase with water temperature. Biomass of overwintering simuliids in lake outlets in Southern Quebec is positively related to chlorophyll concentration and current velocity, and negatively related to distance from the lake, water depth, and periphyton biomass. Computer simulations show that published methods fail to produce reliable confidence intervals for estimates of secondary production for highly aggregated populations, and a reliable method, based on the Bootstrap procedure and the Allen curve, is presented.</description><creator>Morin, Antoine</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Simuliidae.</subject><subject>Sampling (Statistics)</subject><title>Estimation and prediction of black fly abundance and productivity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb3979003.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c117g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386j95d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Stress relaxation measurements were carried out on a plain carbon and four Ti steels over the temperature range 850 to 1050$ sp circ$C. The results show that the stress relaxation of plain carbon austenite after a 5% prestrain can be described by the relation $ sigma$ = $ sigma sb0$-$ alpha$ln(1 + $ beta$t). By contrast, in the solution-treated Ti steels, relaxation is arrested at the start of precipitation and is resumed when precipitation is complete. As a result, this new mechanical method is suitable for following carbonitride precipitation in microalloyed austenite at hot working temperatures. PTT diagrams were determined by the present technique for the steels containing 0.05, 0.11, 0.18 and 0.25% Ti. The PTT curves obtained are C shaped for all the steels. The upper parts of these curves are shifted to significantly longer times as the Ti and C concentrations are reduced. By contrast, the positions of the lower arms of the curves are relatively independent of the current values of the solubility product (Ti) (C). This phenomenon is attributed to the catalytic effect of trace amounts of dissolved N on the nucleation rate of Ti(CN) in austenite. Changes in the size distribution and morphology of the precipitates during relaxation of the 0.25% Ti steel were followed by means of electron microscopy. The cube shaped Ti(CN) precipitates were heterogeneously distributed in either a chain-like or a cell-like manner. Electron microanalysis was additionally carried out to determine the compositions of the Ti carbosulphide-Mn sulphide inclusions. Finally, the experimental results are compared with the predictions of classical nucleation theory and of the diffusion controlled particle growth theory. Good agreement was obtained between the predictions of the theories and the experimental results. It is demonstrated by means of the thermodynamic analysis of nucleation that the Ti(CN) precipitate/austenite interface is of a semi-coherent nature. It is shown that the interface between a critical nucleus and the matrix can be characterized by the newly introduced coherency loss parameter C.</description><creator>Liu, Weijie.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Precipitation hardening</subject><subject>Austenite</subject><subject>Titanium steel</subject><title>Precipitation of Ti(CN) in austenite : experimental results, analysis and modelling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17ct66f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386j95d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w5519</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Expression of cDNA clones of the M1 double-stranded RNA killer preprotoxin coding region in Saccharomyces cerevisiae successfully directed the synthesis of secreted active toxin. Transformants harbouring these expression plasmids also displayed a K1 specific immunity phenotype. Immunoprecipitation of intracellular proteins with antitoxin antiserum showed that these transformants synthesize a 42kd glycosylated preprotoxin precursor. Two smaller unglycosylated immunoreactive species could also be resolved. These toxin precursor species were characterized by using secretory-defective hosts, by comparative electrophoretic mobilities, and by tunicamycin susceptibility. Such studies indicate that these protein species represent intermediates generated by signal cleavage of the preprotoxin and its subsequent glycosylation and provide evidence that these events occur post-translationally. Mutational analysis of the 44 amino acid preprotoxin N-terminal leader indicated that it is functionally bipartite, consisting of an N-terminal signal sequence and a C-terminal pro-sequence. Deletion of the leader perturbed but did not eliminate secretion of toxin.</description><creator>Lolle, Susan Janne</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Microbial genetics.</subject><title>Expression of killer preprotoxin cDNA in Saccharomyces cerevisiae : functional analysis of the N-terminal leader domain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qq26q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w5519</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9997366</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Prostaglandins E$ sb1$ and E$ sb1$ are bound with high affinity and specificity to particulate fractions from bovine, ovine and human adrenal medulla. An identical fraction from fetal bovine and ovine adrenals binds PGEs with similar kinetic properties and specificities. The ${ rm lbrack sp3H rbrack}$PGE$ sb2$-binding site complex dissociates in a biphasic manner, suggesting the presence of both a low and high affinity form of the complex. Gpp(NH)p, a stable GTP analogue, inhibits PGE$ sb2$ binding by promoting the conversion of the high affinity form of the complex to the lower affinity state. In subcellular fractionation studies, PGE$ sb2$ binding sites co-purity with acetylcholinesterase and Ca$ sp{2+}$-ATPase activities (marker enzymes for the chromaffin cell plasma membrane). Bovine adrenal medullary cells in culture, prelabeled with ${ rm lbrack sp3H rbrack}$arachidonic acid, metabolize the precursor fatty acid to PGE$ sb2,$ 6-oxoPGF$ sb{1 alpha}$ and other unidentified products, when stimulated with the calcium-ionophore A23187. PGE$ sb2$ (10$ sp{-9}$ M) inhibits both nicotine and high K$ sp+$-induced catecholamine secretion from chromaffin cells by a mechanism unrelated to alterations in intracellular levels of cyclic nucleotides. LTC$ sb4$ and LTB$ sb4$ stimulate spontaneous catecholamine release but this effect is not always reproducible. NDGA attenuates nicotine-induced secretion, while indomethacin has no effect. These data suggest that the inhibitory effect of PGE$ sp2$ on chromaffin cell secretion is initiated by the release of the prostaglandin during cellular activation, followed by the binding of PGE$ sb2$ to its receptor and the subsequent interaction of this complex with a guanine nucleotide-binding protein.</description><creator>Karaplis, Andy C.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Biology, General.</subject><title>The role of prostaglandin E2 and other eicosanoids in catecholamine secretion from adrenal chromaffin cells /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f187c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9997366</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838126p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis concerns the mechanisms responsible for preferential translation of reovirus mRNA in infected cells. The absence of a poly(A) tract at the $3 sp prime$-end is one of the structural differences that distinguishes reovirus mRNA from cellular mRNA. Addition of free poly(A) inhibits in vitro translation at the level of initiation of protein synthesis, probably by competition between free poly(A) and mRNA. Reovirus mRNA is resistant to this inhibition and this property might confer a translational advantage to the viral mRNA. Another difference between reovirus mRNA and cellular mRNA is the absence of a $5 sp prime$-cap structure on late viral mRNA. This mRNA is translated much more efficiently in lysates from infected than uninfected cells, even in the absence of inhibition of host cell protein synthesis. Addition to uninfected cell lysates of proteins from infected cells stimulates translation of late viral mRNA without effect on other mRNAs; the presence of the sigma 3 viral protein is shown to account for the stimulation of translation. Sigma 3 binds to ribosomes, probably during initiation of protein synthesis, but apparently does not interact directly with mRNA. The sigma 3 protein exists in multiple forms, differing in isoelectric point but possessing all the known properties of sigma 3. These forms possibly result from mutations in the gene encoding sigma 3. The cloned gene which encodes sigma 3 was expressed in L cells without apparent detrimental effect on the cells. Lysates prepared from these cells translate late viral mRNA with an increased efficiency. The sigma 3 protein is associated with the ribosomes in these cells even if no viral mRNA is present. It is suggested that the sigma 3 protein acts as a viral-specific initiation factor of protein synthesis.</description><creator>Lemay, Guy.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Study of a reovirus protein involved in viral mRNA translation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w061b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838126p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xs38v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In light of the remarkable antiviral activity of acyclic nucleoside analogues such as that of BIOLF-62 against the herpes viruses, a number of products in which heterocyclic bases were coupled to the active acyclic sugar moiety were prepared and submitted for biological testing. Various dimethoxytritylated and t -butyldimethylsilylated derivatives of arabinoadenosine were prepared and fully characterised by $ sp1$H and $ sp{13}$C NMR spectroscopy. $ sp{29}$Si INEPT as well as $ sp{29}$Si-$ sp1{ rm H}$ correlated NMR were used to study various t -butyldimethylsilyl and triisopropylsilyl substituted ribonucleosides. In an effort aimed at the development of new and better nucleoside protecting functions, the 2,4-dinitrobenzenesulfenyl group which is stable to both acidic and basic conditions, was used for $5 sp prime$-hydroxyl protection of ribonucleosides and its compatibility with the phosphodichoridite nucleoside coupling procedure was investigated. The nitrobenzenesulfenyl group was used in conjunction with the dimethoxytrityl group for $2 sp prime$-hydroxyl protection in the synthesis of a UpU dimer. The latter was fully characterised by enzymatic degradation and HPLC analysis of the products.</description><creator>Boisvert, Suzanne, 1955-</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Antiviral agents</subject><subject>Nucleosides</subject><title>Preparation of novel heterocyclic-ring analogues of BIOLF-62 : application of 29SI NMR nucleosides and the investigation of 2,4-dinitrobenzenesulfenyl as a protecting group for ribonucleotide synthesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397901c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xs38v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r376z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the behaviour and design of triangular trusses fabricated from Hollow Structural Sections (HSS), with two Warren-type web planes and a single tension chord. Experimental programs are described in which triangular truss segments and simplified joints were tested in order to investigate the behaviour of compression web members and tension-chord welded joints. The mechanics of joint deformations are analysed in relation to the yield line theory, and simple models are shown to give a good prediction of the joint stiffnesses and strengths. Complex yield line models are investigated, but are slightly or not superior to the simple models. Recommendations are established covering the design of tension and compression chord joints, as well as chord and web members. The design of a 22 m span triangular truss is outlined.</description><creator>Bauer, Dominique.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Trusses</subject><subject>Trusses -- Testing.</subject><title>Triangular trusses fabricated from rectangular hollow sections</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dq34d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r376z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161686t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electric power systems are characterized by their immense complexity. The assessment of their security on-line has always been a challenging task. Many possibilities were investigated in the past in an attempt to characterize the secure operating region of a power system. Pattern recognition is thus far the only tool that can take various degrees of network complexity into consideration. In the present study, an efficient algorithm which learns adaptively the secure operating region is proposed. At each iteration, training operating points are generated sequentially on a piecewise linearly approximated separation surface computed by the one-nearest-neighbor (1-NN) rule. The separation surface so estimated approaches the true one as the number of training points increases. The algorithm not only provides a consistent technique in learning an unknown region, it generates a highly efficient training set. It is found to be effective in reducing the size of the training set without adverse effect to the classifier. Once the secure region of a power system is available, the task of on-line security monitoring reduces to one of determining whether the current operating point resides in the secure region. As demonstrated in the thesis, both the security status and the security margin of the operating point can be assessed very efficiently. By using the piecewise linearly approximated secure region, the thesis proceeds to give efficient ways of moving an insecure operating point into the secure region. This comprises the problem of security enhancement. The regionwise methodology via the Voronoi diagram developed in the thesis is also applied to a wide range of problems, such as network planning, coordinating tuning of machine parameters and automatic contingency selection. The major merit is that the dynamics and the nonlinearity of the system no longer present a limitation to solving these problems.</description><creator>Fok, Danny Sik-Kwan</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Electric power systems -- Control</subject><subject>Pattern recognition systems</subject><subject>Electric power systems</subject><title>Secure operation and planning of electric power systems by pattern recognition by Danny Sik-Kwan Fok.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881m67q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161686t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999738r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A validation methodology is proposed for natural language software specifications of standard graphics functions. Checks are made for consistency, completeness and lack of ambiguity in data element and function descriptions. Functions and data elements are maintained in a relational database representation. The appropriate checks are performed by sequences of database operations. The relational database manager INGRES was used to support a prototype implementation of the proposed technique. The methodology supports the development of a scenario-based prototype from the information available in the specification. This permits various function sequences to be checked without implementation of the environment specified. The application of a prototype implementation of the proposed methodology, to the specification of the GKS software package, demonstrates the practicability of the method. Several inconsistencies in GKS, related to the definition of data elements, have been identified.</description><creator>Fraser, Steven D.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Computer graphics</subject><subject>Computer software -- Validation</subject><title>Graphics function standard specification validation with GKS</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c483.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999738r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:707958427</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The behaviour of second phase particles in molten steel processing vessels was investigated, using the E.S.Z. (Electric Sensing Zone) method, in conjunction with aqueous modelling and molten steel systems. 1. Slag droplet entrainment/dispersion is an axisymmetric gas injection stirred system was investigated: A tank containing a water-olive oil simulation of stirred ladles of molten steel was used. Extensive numerical predictions of the oil (slag) droplet population distributions within the vessel were also carried out, and reasonable agreement with the experimental data achieved. Droplet dispersions were shown to be time and spatially dependent. 2. Inclusion separation characteristics in tundishes of continuous steel casting operations were investigated. The mixed reactor model proved to be adequate for predicting particle separation behaviour, proved that the effective upper surface area of the dispersed plug flow region is known, a priori. 3. An on-line method for the detection and measurement of inclusions in molten steel systems was developed. Inclusion removal rates within an induction furnace, as well as inclusion separation behaviour in a commercial scale tundish for continuous billet casting, were measured.</description><creator>Nakajima, Hidemasa.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Steel -- Inclusions</subject><title>On the detection and behaviour of second phase particles in steel melts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s5508.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/707958427</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hw03b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As far back as Euclid's ruler and compass constructions, computation and geometry have been domains for the exploration and development of fundamental mathematical concepts and ideas. The invention of computers has spurred new research in computation, and now with a variety of applications couched in the fundamentals of Euclidean geometry, the study of geometric algorithms has again become a popular mathematical pursuit. In this thesis, the computational aspects of a fundamental problem in Euclidean geometry is examined. Given a set of line segments in the Euclidean plane, one is asked to connect all the segments to form a simple closed circuit. It is shown that for some sets of line segments it is impossible to perform this task. The problem of deciding whether a set of line segments admits a simple circuit is proved to be NP-complete. A restriction of the class of permissible input allows a polynomial time solution to the simple circuit decision problem. It is also shown that a polynomial solution can be realized by restricting the class of simple circuit in the output. All the polynomial time decision algorithms exhibited deliver a simple circuit if one exists. Furthermore, in all cases the simple circuit obtained can be optimized with respect to area or perimeter.</description><creator>Rappaport, David, 1955-</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Geometry -- Data processing.</subject><title>The complexity of computing simple circuits in the plane /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vv06j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hw03b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752h41t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The 4-substituted glutarimide required for the synthesis of sesbanimide (53) was obtained by free radical addition of iodoacetamide onto the $ alpha, beta$-unsaturated ester (81) mediated by tributyltin; the lactol ring C was prepared by the analogous free radical cyclization of the $ alpha$-bromo-dipropargyl ketal 73. The syntheses of tricyclic carbapenems involved appropriately substituted monocyclic azetidinone precursors. Free radical 5- exo cyclizations led to the relatively unstable benzo carbapenems 116, 119 and 120. The 6- exo mode, however, afforded stable benzo carbacephems 125, 127, 132 and 133. $ alpha$-Bromo- and $ alpha{,} alpha$-dibromoazetidinones were converted stereoselectively to the $ alpha$-alkylazetidinones 149 and 153, or to $ beta$-alkylazetidinones 151, 154 and 159 by a free radical addition onto olefins 148 or allyltributyltin.</description><creator>Sacripante, Guerino.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Free radical reactions</subject><subject>Organic compounds -- Synthesis.</subject><title>Radical reactions in organic synthesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3655770.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752h41t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848r32p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Wrangell volcanic belt lies in a transpressional zone that results from the oblique convergence between the NE Pacific and North American plates. Transitional lavas predominate in the SE transform regime, whereas a calc-alkaline arc lies to the NW. The geochemical evolution of the St. Clare Creek field (Yukon) reflects changes in mode of crustal interaction and nature of mantle source components. The Wolverine centre (18-16 Ma) consists of alkaline and voluminous transitional lavas overlain by calc-alkaline lavas. The Klutlan centre (16-10 Ma) comprises calc-alkaline and Fe-rich transitional lavas followed by voluminous Fe-poor transitional basalts and more felsic transitional lavas. Primitive Fe-rich Wolverine transitional and alkaline lavas have higher Nb/Y ratios relative to Klutlan lavas, suggesting an enriched lithospheric mantle source with high $ sp{87}$Sr/$ sp{86}$Sr (0.7042) and low K/Nb ratios. Younger Fe-poor transitional lavas have high K/Nb ratios similar to calc-alkaline lavas. The Klutlan calc-alkaline lavas have high K/Nb ratios and low $ sp{87}$Sr/$ sp{86}$Sr ratios ($ sim$0.7035) derived from a slab component. Depleted Klutlan basalts have low La/Yb, low $ sp{87}$Sr/$ sp{86}$Sr (0.7031) and high $ sp{143}$Nd/$ sp{144}$Nd (0.5131) ratios reflecting an origin in the depleted asthenospheric mantle. Mixing between enriched, slab-derived, and depleted mantle components accounts for the trace element and isotopic composition of primitive transitional magmas, whereas different degrees of partial melting of depleted mantle are required to explain the range of Fe contents. Crustal assimilation accompanied the differentiation of early evolved Wolverine alkaline and late Klutlan transitional lavas. Selective contamination resulted in K-enrichment of evolved intervening transitional lavas.</description><creator>Skulski, Thomas</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Magma genesis along an arc-transform transition zone</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708x271.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848r32p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mc65x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Analysis of high resolution observational data gathered during a mesoscale field experiment in central Alberta (LIMEX-85) has led to a conceptual model of severe convective outbreaks in Alberta. It is proposed that most severe convective events result when upper-level cooling, associated with an advancing, synoptic-scale trough, occurs in phase with strong surface heating over the Alberta foothills. The deep destabilization over the elevated topography acts to amplify the mountain-plain circulation and to generate mesoscale upslope moisture transport. Concurrently, the surface synoptic pressure gradient gives rise to east-northeasterly winds which advect the moisture-rich air of the eastern plains into the lower-branch of the mountain-plain circulation. In this manner, the plains moisture is permitted to reach the convectively active foothills through underrunning of the capping lid. The end product of the synoptic-mesoscale interactions is the initiation of well-organized, severe convective storms which move eastward with the westerly component of the mid-tropospheric winds. A statistical analysis based on archived hail data provides additional evidence for the key synoptic-scale features of the conceptual model.</description><creator>Smith, Stephan Bryan</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>The causes of severe convective outbreaks in Alberta /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860770j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mc65x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20st31s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The preparation and characterization of new materials to make ion-selective membranes are described. The usefulness of zinc orthophosphate and zinc mercuric thiocyanate to make a carbon-support electrode responsive to zinc was investigated. Better results were obtained with zinc orthophosphate. However, the electrode response was lowered by the formation of acidic oxides on the surface of the electrode, and interferences from copper(II), lead(II), and cadmium(II) were observed. An indirect potentiometric method based on the selective monitoring of chlorozincate(II) or cyanozincate(II) anions with a coated-wire ion-selective electrode was proposed as an alternative for monitoring zinc ion. The application of quaternary ammonium, phosphonium, and alkyl phosphate ionic polymer membranes to potentiometric and voltammetric analysis was also studied. Ionic polymer membranes offer a number of advantages, namely improved membrane lifetime and enhanced adherence to solid-substrate electrodes, when compared to conventional ion-selective membranes. The last stage of this research focused on the application of ionic polymer membrane electrodes in flow injection analysis.</description><creator>Rocheleau, Marie-Josée</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Investigation of membrane materials for solid-state, ion-selective electrodes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860771t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20st31s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hs63r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a new concurrent method for the decomposition and factorization of Boolean expressions based on two simple objects: two-literal single-cube divisors, and double-cube divisors along with their complements. It is proved that the presence of common multiple-cube algebraic divisors, from a set of Boolean expressions, can be found by analyzing the set of double-cube divisors. It is also shown that in order to find the duality relations that may exist between various objects, only a subset of two-literal single-cube and double-cube divisors needs to be analyzed. Since the number of these objects grows polynomially with the size of the network, the number of objects that are to be analyzed for finding common algebraic divisors, and for finding the duality relations between them, is much less than the set of all algebraic divisors. Also, since the duality relations between these objects are exploited along with DeMorgan's laws, these objects constitute a richer set of divisors than the strictly algebraic divisors. It is also proved that the transformations based on these simple objects preserve testability. This result implies that if the input Boolean network before decomposition and factorization is 100% testable for single stuck-at faults by a test set T, then the area optimized output network will also be 100% testable for single stuck-at faults, and can be tested by the same test set T. These results are proved using the concepts of corresponding faults in the circuits and relations between complete test sets. Since the method assumes that the initial network is only single stuck-at fault testable, and because single stuck-at fault testability is maintained through the transformations, the method can be applied to a large class of irredundant two-level and multi-level circuits to synthesize fully testable circuits. Experimental results are presented and compared with various logic synthesis systems to demonstrate the efficiency and effectiveness of the method.</description><creator>Jagadeesh, Vasudevamurthy</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>On the testability-preserving decomposition and factorization of Boolean expressions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36tz247.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hs63r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr169</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transcendence and transformation have been established as key motifs in apocalypses. The transformation of a seer during a heavenly journey is found commonly in such esoteric apocalypses as I Enoch. No heavenly journey occurs in the works treated here. Rather, symbolic women figures--"ladies" in the classical sense--who are associated with God's City or tower, undergo transformation at key points in the action. The surface structures of Joseph and Aseneth, 4 Ezra, the Apocalypse and The Shepherd of Hermas are traced, and the crucial transformation episode or episodes are located within each structure. Transformation of figures representing God's people suggests the significance of identity within the apocalyptic perspective. Apocalypses allow the world to be viewed from the future or from the heavens (J. J. Collins' "temporal" and "spatial" axes); the genre also invites the reader to change identity (the "identical" axis), and so become someone in tune with divine mystery and revelation.</description><creator>Humphrey, Edith McEwan</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Hermas, 2nd cent. Shepherd</subject><subject>Apocalyptic literature -- History and criticism</subject><title>The ladies and the cities : transformation and apocalyptic identity in Joseph and Aseneth, 4 Ezra, the Apocalypse and The shepherd of Hermas</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tq05q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr169</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):36075</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>