<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:46:59Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40925" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053g858</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To avoid the methodological problems of previous observational studies, we conducted a controlled clinical trial of restricted in-hospital formula supplementation. In a pre-trial sample of 621 newborns, a comparison of two well-baby nurseries found no differences in either hospital supplementation practices or the proportion of infants still breast-fed at 4 or 9 weeks postpartum. Restriction of supplementation in one of the nurseries for the trial period (n = 781) did not result in higher breast feeding rates at 4 or 9 weeks. There was, however, a slightly greater mean percent birth weight lost in the restricted group (6.0 vs 5.1%; P &lt; .001). In a descriptive analysis of the pre-trial data, socioeconomic status, parity, and infant formula supplementation were statistically significant predictors of breast feeding duration. This "observational" association between supplementation and a shorter duration of breast feeding contrasts with the trial results and suggests that in-hospital supplementation is a marker, rather than a cause, of breast feeding difficulties.</description><creator>Gray-Donald, Katherine.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Health Sciences, General.</subject><title>Effect of infant formula supplementation on the duration of breast feeding : a controlled clinical trial</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sd484.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053g858</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623hz50w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A model of faculty advising suggests that the tasks performed by faculty advisors are explained by three conceptual constructs differing in levels of complexity and type of skill. The three constructs identify a routine set of tasks termed Providing Information and two complex sets of tasks termed Developing Academic and Educational Goals, and Providing Personal Support. However, no empirical data exist to support this model. To test the model, a sample consisting of 481 University of Vermont undergraduate students rated their advisors on the three sets of items. The data were subjected to confirmatory factor analyses using maximum likelihood procedures with the LISREL model. The existence of the three categories of advising tasks was confirmed. The nature and complexity of advising tasks must be addressed when assessing faculty advisor performance and designing development activities for advisors.</description><creator>Trombley, Toni Beresford.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Faculty advisors.</subject><subject>Faculty advisors -- Rating of.</subject><title>The effectiveness of faculty advisors : theory and assessment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx885.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623hz50w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb4949281</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Some novel optical methods to study the structure of ordered latices have been developed. These methods, as well as the Bragg diffraction technique, have been used in rheo- and electro-optical studies of latex structure. In the rheo-optical studies, ordered latices were subjected to a simple shear field and a three-dimensional deformation of the structure was observed. The increase in spacing between parallel layers of particles is qualitatively explained by a proposed two-dimensional sliding layer model. In the electro-optical studies, ordered latices were subjected to an electric field and an asymmetrical particle distribution was found. The electric field effect was found to be large for low volume fractions and low ion concentrations. These dependencies are explained semi-quantitatively by a proposed model. A widely used equation describing the optical condition of diffraction in ordered latices was reconsidered and given a firm theoretical basis.</description><creator>Tomita, M. (Minoru)</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Electrooptics.</subject><subject>Latex.</subject><title>Rheo- and electro-optical studies of ordered latices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50ts340.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb4949281</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967448g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Environmental pollutants are becoming increasingly conspicuous in modern society. Lung function testing is one of the ways of assessing their impact on the health of the public. However lung function tests present large between individual variation, some of the determinants of which are race, sex, age and morphometric characteristics. These are generally taken into account using prediction formulae derived from the best fit equation to a set of values observed in a particular survey. In the present study new formulae were developed which used current physiological knowledge of the determinants of lung function. These formulae together with some of the models in current use were fitted to a single training data set and the homogeneity of the fit across all ages was then compared. The models so developed, together with some of the formulae proposed in the literature were then used to predict the values of certain lung function tests in two independent populations to assess the bias of the predictions. In the working age range (25 to 65) in males all formulae yielded comparable predictions; however in females and teenagers of both sexes the proposed model or the model proposed by Schoenberg predicted the data better. The model proposed included a smoking module. However in the population studied ex smokers were found to present better lung function than non smokers, so that the model proposed to evaluate the effect of smoking is only applicable for current smokers. The effect of smoking was acceptably predicted for the tests derived from the forced expiratory maneuver. One of the possible reasons why the proposed model did not fit the training data better than the empirical models may lie in the incomplete knowledge of the determinants of lung function. Further research is needed to identify such determinants and to find an objective and simple methodology for their evaluation.</description><creator>Ghezzo, Ruben Heberto.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Normalization of lung function tests for epidemiological studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pn70h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967448g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440t137</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives of this research are to assess the impact of prenatal courses on the birthweight of newborns, and on two intermediate variables: cigarette consumption and maternal weight gain during pregnancy. Ninety-eight per cent (98%) of primiparous women giving birth in one of four Montreal hospitals during the nine-month study period, completed a questionnaire during their postpartum stay in hospital. Medical data on mothers and newborns were extracted from the medical records. Women who participated in prenatal courses were of higher socioeconomic status than nonparticipants. An analysis of covariance showed that prenatal courses did not affect: the mean birthweight of newborns, the proportion of women who gained less than 20 pounds (9.1 kilos) during pregnancy, and cigarette consumption during the last five months of pregnancy. The results were consistent regardless of the &gt; of the prenatal course which was measured by it duration, content, and trimester of enrolment in the prenatal course. Prenatal courses did not affect the birthweight of newborns or cigarette consumption during pregnancy in women at higher risk for have low birthweight babies. Although prenatal courses did reduce by half the proportion of these higher risk women who gained less than 20 pounds, the result is of little importance since birthweight was not affected. From a community health perspective, prenatal courses are not appropriate interventions to increase the mean birthweight of newborns. The apparent effect of prenatal courses on the birthweight of newborns is eliminated after adjusting for confounding variables. It is important to adjust for confounding variables when evaluating prenatal courses. The analysis of co-variance is an appropriate analytic technique to perform this adjustment.</description><creator>Robitaille, Y.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Impact des cours prénatals sur le poids des nouveau-nés</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dw29q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440t137</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j182f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study analyzes ownership and directorship links among larger Canadian-owned corporations. These links have received insufficient attention from Canadian economists. It shows that these corporations did not undergo the radical changes predicted for their counterparts in other countries: proprietor ownership remains high, and the board of directors persists as the centre of power. Ownership links form the basis for the development and empirical investigation of the "Shadow Group" concept. The taxonomical classification of shadow groups reveals complex structures accompanying diversification strategies. Interlocking directorships exist among "core" corporations inside the groups and are frequent between the shadow groups and the rest of the economy. Shadow groups were at the heart of mergers and acquisitions between 1978 and 1981. A case study shows that external growth (especially takeovers) is their characteristic tactic for expansion. Hence, the necessity exists for amending economic theories to account for the behaviour of these groups.</description><creator>Antoniou, Andreas.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Corporations -- Canada.</subject><subject>Directors of corporations -- Canada.</subject><subject>Consolidation and merger of corporations -- Canada.</subject><title>Ownership and control of the largest Canadian owned corporations, 1979</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xf95h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j182f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r650w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of crustacean zooplankton in changing the size structure of phytoplankton communities was examined in Lake Memphremagog, Quebec. The hypothesis that zooplankton have a selective effect on various algal size classes, within the net- and nannoplankton, was tested during different periods of the growing season in controlled field experiments. Depending on the pattern of loss rates imposed by zooplankton on different algal size fractions, it is shown that zooplankton can both accelerate and decelerate successional events in the phytoplankton. Manipulation of zooplankton biomass produced significant changes in algal phosphorus demand, estimated from observations on the short-term dynamics of orthophosphorus. It is shown that the presence of zooplankton reduces the phosphorus deficiency of the phytoplankton in early periods of the season. Empirical relationships are also presented, based on literature observations, to predict variation in feeding selectivity of cladocerans and variation in the biomass of zooplankton among lake ecosystems.</description><creator>McCauley, Edward.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Freshwater zooplankton.</subject><subject>Freshwater phytoplankton.</subject><title>The impact of zooplankton on the dynamics of natural phytoplankton communities /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nm23c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r650w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150j96f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mouse bone marrow was shown to contain a population of null lymphocytes which lack molecular markers of both B and T lineages ($ mu sp-,$ B220$ sp-,$ Thyl$ sp-).$ Null cells represent 12-14% of all bone marrow small lymphocytes. Studies on population dynamics have revealed that these null cells turnover rapidly with a production rate almost 1/3 as great as that of B lymphocytes. Some newly-formed null lymphocytes express natural killer (NK) cell-associated markers, including NK1.1. Some small lymphocytes in the bone marrow express low intensities of Thyl. These Thyl$ sp{ rm lo}$ cells are also rapidly renewing and some express NK1.1, suggesting that these cells, in addition to null lymphocytes, form part of the rapidly generated lineage of NK cells. During growth of a transplantable tumor, there were marked increases of limited duration in the numbers of null, NK1.1$ sp+,$ and Thyl$ sp{ rm lo}$ cells in the bone marrow. The increase in null cells was further enhanced in tumor-bearing mice given indomethacin. These findings suggest that the production of null small lymphocytes in the bone marrow includes the neogenesis of NK cells, possibly playing an important role against naturally occurring malignancies.</description><creator>Rahal, M. Dwayne</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Genesis of a "Null" lymphocyte population with natural killer cell characteristics in bone marrow of normal and tumor-bearing mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xs40w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150j96f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kt55v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A chamber technique was developed allowing recovery of cytokines and T-cells from human DTH reactions. These cells were cloned, and were enriched, relative to the blood, for T-cells reactive to the antigen eliciting the DTH. Antigen-specific CD4+ clones, had two phenotypes; an IL-2/IFN-g producing group not providing help for Ig synthesis, and a group providing help but not producing IL-2 or IFN-g. Cytotoxicity and TNF production were found in both groups. TNF and IFN-g were present in the chambers over DTH reactions. Anergic patients demonstrated deficient mononuclear cell delivery to DTH sites which was restored to normal by co-injection of MLC supernatants with antigen. T-cell clones from such sites were similar to those from normal DTH sites. Additional experiments established that MLC supernatants contained 2 distinct factors, one restoring DTH in anergic patients, and another, which protected anergic rats from lethal peritonitis.</description><creator>MacPhee, Martin James</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Cellular and soluble mediators of delayed-type hypersensitivity and their use in correcting anergy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021g002.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kt55v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn009z551</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this thesis was to elucidate the physicochemical and metabolic bases of Hyperapobetalipoproteinemia (HyperapoB). This disorder, which is likely the commonest metabolic abnormality associated with premature coronary artery disease, was defined as a combination of a normal, or near-normal, LDL cholesterol in the face of an elevated LDL apoB. LDL, even in normals, is heterogeneous. The experimental findings herein confirm this. They also extend this concept to indicate that familial hypercholesterolemia (FH) and HyperapoB each imprint LDL in different and characteristic ways, each an exaggeration of the typical relations between LDL composition and size in normals. At one extreme is HyperapoB, which is characterized by most of the LDL particles being smaller and denser than normal because they contain less cholesteryl ester but the same amount of apoB as normal. At the other is FH, which is characterized by larger, cholesteryl ester-enriched particles. There is, as well, a predictable relation between LDL particle size and the immunoreactivity of certain apoB epitopes. Turnover studies of hepatic apoB using traditional analytic models showed that hepatic apoB is overproduced in HyperapoB, a finding which stands in marked contrast to the impaired catabolism of apoB in FH. A new multi-compartmental model of LDL metabolism has been developed which appears to elucidate several of the basic mechanisms involved in the pathogenesis of HyperapoB. All the data to date indicate that the characteristic abnormalities of LDL in HyperapoB are all consequences of the overproduction of hepatic apoB. Obviously, the goal for future research must be to understand the basis for this overproduction. A preliminary study with adipose tissue suggested that the overproduction of hepatic apoB might be secondary to a defect in peripheral tissue triglyceride biosynthesis.</description><creator>Teng, Ba-Bie.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Metabolic and physicochemical bases of hyperapobetalipoproteinemia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tq060.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z551</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483k009</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of tryptophan availability in the regulation of 5-hydroxytryptamine (5HT) metabolism and function has been examined in rats and humans, by manipulation of dietary components. It was demonstrated that in the rat, protein and carbohydrate can alter 5HT levels in peripheral tissues as well as brain. A new method for the determination of 5HT in the cisternal cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) of the rat was developed and used as an index of functional 5HT, using pharmacological agents known to act on 5HT function. Using this technique, it was then shown that tryptophan administration potentiates the release of 5HT when the animals are aroused, and thus when their 5HT neurons are firing at high rates. However, the smaller changes in brain 5HT after ingestion of protein or carbohydrate did not lead to altered CSF 5HT. In humans, similar conclusions were drawn. The administration of an amino acid mixture deficient in tryptophan significantly altered macronutrient selection, a behavior thought to be mediated by lowered tryptophan availability and 5HT function. However, when protein or carbohydrate breakfasts were given, no effect on macronutrient selection was observed, suggesting that the physiological changes resulting from dietary intake were not affecting functional 5HT. The final study measured amine precursors and metabolites in human lumbar CSF after the administration of protein or carbohydrate breakfasts and supported this hypothesis. No effects on CSF tryptophan or 5-hydroxyindoleacetic acid, the major metabolite of 5HT, were observed. In conclusion, the results of these studies suggest that, though large changes in precursor availability can alter 5HT function, the effects of dietary intake on 5HT metabolism are not normally of sufficient magnitude to alter 5HT function in rats or humans, or brain 5HT metabolism in humans.</description><creator>Teff, Karen</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition.</subject><title>Relationships between tryptophan, diet, 5-hydroxytryptamine metabolism, 5-hydroxytryptamine function and behavior</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945r50v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483k009</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hw04m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The current management of malignant gliomas is unsatisfactory compared to other solid tumors. Expected median survival is less than one year with even the best of care. At some point in their illness, most patients with neurological tumors are capable of mounting an immune response to their disease. This study focused on the humoral immune response of brain tumor patients by preparing human-human B cell hybridomas from autologous peripheral blood lymphocytes and a human myeloma-like cell line, designated as TM-H2-SP2. Eighteen fusions were successfully performed, and 15.8% of all microwells screened contained human immunoglobulin with anti-tumor activity. Five hybridomas, designated as BT27/1A2, BT27/2A3, BT32/A6, BT34/A5, and BT54/B8 were selected for detailed study. All five produced monoclonal IgM in a range of 2.4-44 $ mu$g/ml, had a similar (but not identical) pattern of reactivity against a panel of human tumor cell lines, and did not react with normal human astrocytes. All five human monoclonal antibodies (HmAbs) recognized a subpopulation of tumor cells based on multiparameter flow cytometric studies. Cell sorting experiments suggested that the identified subpopulation may share certain properties with hypothetical tumor stem cells. Preliminary antigen characterization indicated that the HmAbs are directed to cell surface glycolipids. These HmAbs possess certain properties of reactivity that suggest potential roles for them in the future diagnosis and clinical management of human malignant gliomas.</description><creator>Dan, Michael</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Human anti-glioma monoclonal antibodies from patients with neurological tumors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j169w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hw04m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795844s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study was conducted for two growing seasons in northeastern Syria to evaluate the effect of N and P fertilizers and previous crops--i.e. vetch (Vicia sativa L.), barley (Hordeum vulgare L. cv. Beecher) or fallow--on water consumption, development, growth and yields of barley in a semi-arid, Mediterranean-type climate. The two seasons contrasted in rainfall and temperature which affected soil N, water use and yields. Fertilizer addition and residual P were the major determinants in barley yield increases. Rotation effects were significant only when fertilizers were added. Fallowing was an inefficient way of storing water, but stored water was used most efficiently by subsequent barley crops when fertilized. Fertilizers did not increase total evapotranspiration. Water use efficiency was related to dry matter production at stem elongation (DMse). Grain weight was a stable component of grain yields. Grain number was related to crop growth rates during the three week pre-anthesis period and to DMse, in turn affected by temperature, nutrient and moisture conditions. Vetch yields were in the order of 2.5 t.ha$ sp{-1}$ in the wetter season (1982/83). Results showed that substantial barley yield increases can be obtained with innovative crop rotations and appropriate use of fertilizers in semi-arid environments.</description><creator>Rached, E. M.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Barley -- Yields -- Syria.</subject><subject>Barley -- Fertilizers -- Syria.</subject><subject>Crop rotation -- Syria.</subject><title>The effects of fertilization and crop rotations on rainfed barley development, growth and yields, in a semi-arid mediterranean-type climate /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j874c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795844s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vh45j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives of this observational study were to describe and evaluate the impact of emergency services on trauma mortality in Montreal. Urgences-Sante provides pre-hospital care in the greater Montreal region. Physicians provide on-scene care including advanced life support (ALS). Basic life support (BLS) is provided by emergency medical technicians or physicians. The study was conducted over a one-year period from April 1, 1987 to March 31, 1988. The results of this study showed that the response and total pre-hospital times of Urgences-Sante were similar to those in other North American cities. Pre-hospital time exceeding 60 minutes was associated with increased mortality. A significant trend towards lesser mortality in hospitals with higher level trauma care was observed. The use of ALS by physicians was not associated with reduced mortality. However, ALS and the presence of a physician were significantly associated with increased pre-hospital time.</description><creator>Sampalis, John Sotirios</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><title>Evaluation of pre-hospital trauma services in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s0919.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vh45j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343s894</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines in vivo and in vitro the effects of prolonged exposure of target cells to PTH on PTH receptors and postreceptor components of the adenylate cyclase system. Using a vitamin D-deficient ($-$D) rat model, hyperparathyroidism in vivo resulted in a decreased number of PTH receptors in kidney and a decreased amount of G protein $ alpha$ subunits. The decreased amount of G$ sb{ rm s} alpha$ was shown to be specific for PTH target tissue and may have played a role in the heterologous desensitization of CT-stimulated adenylate cyclase, demonstrated in renal membranes from the $-$D rats. The study of the control of PTH receptors was pursued using an osteosarcoma clonal cell line, UMR-106, in vitro. Initial characterization of these cells revealed abundant, saturable, cell surface PTH receptors linked to the adenylate cyclase system. Demonstration that the majority of PTH binding was associated with morphologically distinct cells in the UMR-106 population indicated that PTH receptors may be maximally expressed during specific stages in the cell cycle. PTH receptors in UMR-106 cells were shown to be regulated by distinct homologous and heterologous mechanisms. PTH-mediated, homologous desensitization was associated with down-regulation of PTH receptors and loss of G$ sb{ rm s} alpha$ protein form the cell membrane. Heterologous desensitization of PTH responses by PGE$ sb2$ was shown to be cAMP mediated, resulting in a reversible modification of the PTH receptors. This work has demonstrated that multiple mechanisms exist for the regulation of PTH responses both in vivo and in vitro that involve modifications of both the PTH receptors and postreceptor components of the adenylate cyclase system.</description><creator>Mitchell, Jane</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Characterization of parathyroid hormone receptor desensitization in vivo and in vitro</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cd962.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s894</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k795h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The 5$ sp prime$ untranslated region (UTR) of c-myc and human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) mRNAs were used as models in a variety of in vitro and in vivo systems in order to study the role of this region in the control of eukaryotic gene expression. Using an ultraviolet light-induced crosslinking assay, a 55 kilodalton protein was identified in extracts of HeLa, mouse erythroleukemia, and other cell lines, which interacts specifically with a purine-rich RNA sequence in the 5$ sp prime$ UTR of c-myc. The function of this protein in control of c-myc expression is not known, but may be implicated in the process of transcriptional elongation. The 5$ sp prime$ UTR of HIV-1 mRNAs was shown to inhibit strongly the translation of a heterologous mRNA; this inhibition was dependent on the secondary structure predicted to form in this region, and on the accessibility of the cap structure to initiation factors. The structural requirements in the HIV-1 5$ sp prime$ UTR for trans-activation by the viral tat gene product were examined by mutagenesis studies; the base-pairing in the stem-loop structure, the sequence of the loop, and the presence of a three nucleotide bulge were found to be critical features necessary for complete trans-activation. These findings indicate that the 5$ sp prime$ UTR can have important effects on the expression of eukaryotic genes.</description><creator>Parkin, Neil T.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Regulation of gene expression by the 5' untranslated region of eukaryotic mRNAS : c-myc and HIV-1 as examples</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns0646727.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k795h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fc30x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Controversy exists concerning the role that dopamine plays in analgesia. In the present studies, dopamine agonists produced analgesia, and D-amphetamine potentiated morphine analgesia, while treatment with 6-hydroxydopamine or mixed or selective D1 and D2 dopamine receptor antagonists attenuated or abolished morphine and D-amphetamine-induced analgesia, in the formalin test. Furthermore, microinjection of morphine into the ventral tegmental area (VTA) and ventral striatum produced analgesia, while intra-VTA microinjection of naloxone methylbromide antagonized the analgesia produced by systemic morphine, in the formalin test. In contrast, similar manipulations of dopamine had little or no effect in the tail flick test. Thus, dopamine appears to play a facilitatory role in formalin test analgesia, and there appear to be fundamental differences between the formalin and tail flick tests and parallels between the role of dopamine in the formalin test and in clinical pain, the vocalization after-discharge test and reward.</description><creator>Morgan, Michael J.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Dopamine -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Analgesia.</subject><subject>Pain -- Physiological aspects.</subject><subject>Opioids -- Physiological effect.</subject><title>Opioid-dopamine interactions in analgesia in the formalin test</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999740s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fc30x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859g40d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A change-point is said to occur at $ tau$ in a sequence of random variables $X sb1,X sb2,$ ...,$X sb{T},$ if $X sb1,X sb2,X sb3,$ ...,$X sb tau$ are identically distributed with distribution function $F sb1,$ and $X sb{ tau+1},$ ...,$X sb{T-1},X sb{T}$ are identically distributed with distribution function $F sb2,$ with $F sb1 ne F sb2.$ The current literature deals only with the change-point problem in the context of the observation of a single sequence. However, in this thesis, inference will be based on the observation of N sequences of random variables, i.e., multi-path problems. Two classes of multi-path change-point problems are considered. If the change-point occurs at the same position in each sequence, then the terminology "fixed-tau multi-path change-point" will be used. In other cases, one may expect the change-point to occur at random positions in each sequence, according to some distribution, a "random-tau multi-path change-point" problem. Both classical and Bayesian (including empirical Bayesian) techniques are discussed. The methods are illustrated by applications to real and simulated data sets.</description><creator>Joseph, Lawrence</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>The multi-path change-point /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kb42v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859g40d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h2645</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experimental and numerical investigations of turbulent spatially-periodic fully developed flows in straight ducts of rectangular cross section, with interrupted-plate inserts, are presented in this thesis. A computer code, based on a finite volume method and incorporating a low-Reynolds-number k-$ epsilon$ turbulence model, for the simulation of two-dimensional, steady, spatially-periodic fully developed flows in interrupted-plate channels was developed, tested, and used in the numerical investigation. The experimental work was complementary to the numerical work. It was aimed at obtaining accurate and complete data that would allow fair evaluation of the numerical model and lead to an enhanced understanding of spatially-periodic fully developed turbulent flows. Turbulent spatially-periodic fully developed flows in three different interrupted-plate ducts, each having different plate thicknesses, were investigated, with module Reynolds numbers in the range 5 $ times$ 10$ sp3$ $ le$ Re$ sb{ rm m} le$ 33.5 $ times$ 10$ sp3$. The results presented include (i) module friction factor versus Reynolds number plots; (ii) plots of intramodular time-mean wall static pressure distributions; (iii) plate surface streamline photographs; and (iv) a variety of numerical results, including plots of streamlines, and distributions of plate shear stress, wall shear stress, axial momentum flux, axial velocities, mean turbulence kinetic energy and turbulence Reynolds numbers. The details and implications of these results are discussed in this thesis.</description><creator>McBrien, Robert K., 1958-</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Fully developed turbulent flow in rectangular interrupted-plate ducts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296wz78q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h2645</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vh473</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Members of the HSAG family of mammalian genomic elements were subcloned into the pSV2-DHFR expression vector and shown to encourage vector amplification in cis when transfected into a variety of cell lines. The interaction of multiple positive acting elements was required for this effect, with the native configuration of these elements in HSAG-1 producing the greatest effect. These positive acting elements; purine-pyrimidine tracts, Alu-like repetitive elements, stem-loop structures, and A+T rich sequences, have been previously associated with "hotspots" for recombination. Analysis of the structure of amplified vector sequences in MTX resistant pSV2-DHFR-HSAG-1 transfectants showed that these cells possessed a greater number of novel-joints indicating that HSAG elements may stimulate local recombination. Other experiments demonstrating an interaction between vector and HSAG sequences support this conclusion. We suggest that the stimulation of local recombination events by HSAG elements during vector amplification produces novel joints which then encourage further amplification.</description><creator>McArthur, James G.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Genetic elements which increase the frequency of gene amplification</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jm08r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vh473</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806048m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Today, three net magnetostatic loading force formulations are commonly used for finite-element-based electromagnetic and electromechanical computer-aided analysis and design, but none seems sufficient to calculate reliable results at a reasonable cost without expert user interaction. A new, fully automatic, field-error tuned force method is presented. The formulation is based on a volume integration of the computed fields over the entire free space region enveloping the body under force. Numerical tests indicate that the new method is significantly more accurate and consistent than the other methods currently available at a comparable cost. In addition, three important benchmark force problems are introduced; many of the computational difficulties inherent to the currently available force methods are explained; and a new restructuring of the relationships between the different force formulas is provided.</description><creator>McFee, James Stephan</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Accurate and consistent force calculation for finite element magnetics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pg96x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806048m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vk72k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The production of the final states K$ sp+$K$ sp-$ and $ eta sp prime to pi sp+ pi sp- gamma$ in $ gamma gamma$ collisions has been measured using the ARGUS detector. The product $ Gamma sb{ gamma gamma}( eta sp prime)$Br$( eta sp prime to rho gamma)$ has been determined. The topological cross section for the production of charged kaon pairs in two-photon collisions has been measured and the $ gamma gamma$-widths and interference parameters for the tensor mesons f$ sb2$(1270), a$ sb2$(1320) and f$ sbsp{2}{ prime}$(1525) have been extracted. The helicity structure assumed for the K$ sp+$K$ sp-$ continuum contribution has a significant effect on the result. Upper limits have been obtained for the $ gamma gamma$-widths of the glueball candidate states f$ sb2$(1720) and X(2230).</description><creator>McLean, Kenneth W., 1961-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>pi]+[pi]- gamma and [kappa]+[kappa- production in two photon collisions at ARGUS</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8381287.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vk72k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k568s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using fluorescein isothiocyanate-dextran filled inside-out vesicles derived from 4$ sp prime$,4-diisothiocyano-2$ sp prime$,2-disulfonic stilbene treated human red blood cells, we investigated the mechanistic basis for the decrease in the Na:Rb(K) stoichiometry of the Na,K-ATPase observed when the cytoplasmic sodium concentration is decreased below 0.4 mM (Blostein, R., 1983, J. Biol. Chem. 258: 12228-12232). First, we considered the possibility of H$ sp{+}$ replacing Na$ sp{+}$ and/or K$ sp{+}$. It was found that in the absence of Na$ sp{+}$, a decrease in pH from 7.4 to 6.0 effected an increase in ATPase activity $( upsilon)$, an increase in phosphoenzyme intermediate (EP) and a strophanthidin-sensitive ATP-dependent H/K exchange. Conversely, in the absence of K$ sp{+}$, a decrease in pH from 7.4 to 6.0 effected an increase in $ upsilon$, a decrease in EP and a strophanthidin-sensitive ATP-dependent Na/H exchange. These results suggest that protons can substitute for sodium and potassium in the sodium pump reaction. Second, it was shown that under conditions where H$ sp{+}$ do not replace Na$ sp{+}$ or K$ sp{+}$, the membrane potential $( Delta Psi)$ effected by the sodium pump is cytoplasmic side-negative at (Na$ sb{ rm cyt}$) $&gt;$ 1 mM and extracellular side-negative at (Na$ sb{ rm cyt}$)  7.8. Our results are consistent with the notion that protons, sodium and potassium ions are transported by a similar mechanism in P-type ATPases.</description><creator>Polvani, Carlomaria</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Ion transport and charge transfer by P-type ATPases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b415p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k568s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451j24s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the interpretive possibilities in the shorter fiction of Post-War German literature. The corpus includes works by Rolf Hochhuth, Friedrich Durrenmatt and Martin Walser. The historical framework of the theory of the novella and short story provides a basis for a discussion of genre, extended to include the coordinates of metaphor and metonymy. With the exception of one text designated as a novel, these works demonstrate interlocking and restricted motif complexes, repetitive and parallel structure and the integration of most narrative components. They project a tenor of hermetic plurality from a vehicle of abbreviated and truncated referential discourse. They use myth and intertextuality to show general principles to be extrapolated from specific contexts. Metafiction complements the theme of the subject not at one with itself. A partial resolution to the incertitude of existence, rendered according to Freud and Lacan, is offered through the emerging role of women as a stabilizing factor.</description><creator>Plouffe, Bruce</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Walser, Martin, 1927-</subject><subject>Dürrenmatt, Friedrich</subject><subject>Short stories, German -- History and criticism</subject><subject>German fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism</subject><subject>Hochhuth, Rolf</subject><title>The post-war novella in German language literature : an analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kh12v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451j24s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jx753</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:06:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Through the use of the texts published from 1893 to 1903 by Alphonse Allais, we analyse what we call the mystifying discourse, in other words the power of fiction. We show how the author succeeds to deceive the reader. We emphasize the artificial aspects of the language and the style used by Allais to make fun of his readers. This technical study of the writing of Allais allows us to compare with other kinds of works, notably the dreamlike images and the vaudeville. We study therefore the tricks and the traps of the language employed by Allais with the aim of laughing at our expectations. From this point, we will demonstrate that, most of the time, a rupture between the conclusion and the beliefs of the readers exists regarding the fiction which is presented in the tales. Emphasizing the absurd in the texts, we accentuate the various literary techniques. As a result, we illustrate how the humour of Alphonse Allais turns out to be a technical work.</description><creator>Poulin, Marguerite</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Allais, Alphonse, 1854-1905 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Allais, Alphonse, 1854-1905 -- Technique</subject><subject>Absurd (Philosophy) in literature</subject><title>Le discours mystificateur chez Alphonse Allais /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763757r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jx753</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40950</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>