<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:08:07Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):17175" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386p26t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:14:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This essay examines varying theories on the nature and essences of classical texts from the Western literary canon. These ideas range from the notion that the classic is a single work, to viewing these great works as accommodating multiple meanings over time, to the belief that their distinguishing feature is their ability to relate identifiable and universal themes that transcend readers' particular circumstances. In exploring these three perspectives, it becomes clear that The Bible fulfills the requirements for classical designation and should therefore be regarded as a seminal part of the West's literary heritage. Finally, this paper discusses the educational implications for teaching Scripture as classical text in the high school classroom.</description><creator>Dias, Lisa.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Canon (Literature)</subject><title>Infinity goes on trial : examining the characteristics of classic literature and educational implications for inclusion of the Bible in the Western canon</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zs09j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386p26t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d5701206</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:14:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this qualitative study is to understand how children within a Canadian Czech diasporic context, create and discover their Czech heritage language and culture through meaningful active participation in areas provided within the constructs of a non traditional setting such as a summer camp. Five contextual areas of the camp were identified and studied. The areas are: activities, food, camp counselors, staff dynamics and location. Braziel and Mannur (2003) and Rampton's (1990) aspects of "language inheritance" and "language affiliation" inform the analysis.</description><creator>Dejmek, Andrea Theresa.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Children of immigrants -- Canada.</subject><subject>Czechs -- Canada.</subject><subject>Multicultural education -- Canada.</subject><title>The Canadian Czech diaspora : bilingual and multilingual language inheritance and affiliations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tw16p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d5701206</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f727v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the complex interplay between colonial modernity and Sakta (goddess-centered) devotion in the context of an elite family of zamindars (landholders) in Bengal. One consequence of colonialism in Bengal was the efflorescence of overt Sakta religiosity among Bengal's elite. Religious practice, supposedly "protected" by the colonial order, became the site where indigenous elites expressed political will and, to an extent, resisted foreign domination. I argue that the zamindars of Bansberia in the Hugli district of Bengal were creative agents, engaging and resisting the various cultural ruptures represented by colonial rule in the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. Employing analyses of archival material, contemporary ethnography, and architectural style, this thesis is an ethnohistory of a modern zamindari-kingdom that locates its political voice in an emblematic Sakta-Tantric temple. It demonstrates the powerful relationship between religion and politics in colonial Bengal and discusses the implications of this strong association in the contemporary context.</description><creator>Datta-Ray, Mohini.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Religion and politics -- India -- Bengal.</subject><subject>Tantrism -- India -- Bengal.</subject><subject>Hindu temples -- India -- Bengal.</subject><title>Monumentalizing Tantra : the multiple identities of the Haṃseśvarī Devī Temple and the Bansberia Zamīndāri</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hd392.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f727v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848v11j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the ways in which a group of male youths from Montreal interpret the world and construct their identities through the lens of hip-hop. The theoretical framework draws mainly from discussions of youth subcultural theory as articulated by the Center for Cultural Studies in Birmingham, as well as current research on hip-hop culture and youth identities. Using narrative inquiry as a methodological framework, this study highlights how the participants' perceive their neighbourhoods through gangster rap culture, and construct their identities according to these perceptions. This study also reveals how the participants' create original rap lyrics as a self-reflexive tool, and how listening to rap music shapes their linguistic expression.</description><creator>Celemencki, Jacqueline.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Subculture -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Young men -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Hip-hop -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Gettin' skooled : how hip-hop culture shapes the identities of urban youth</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk96j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848v11j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mg61f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis evaluates the Lightning II and the Radio Baton gestural controllers for musical applications within two main perspectives. The first involves a technical specification of each in terms of their construction and sensing technology. This step, along with an analysis of the insights by long-term users on the controllers in question, provides an understanding about the different musical contexts each controllers can be and have been used in. The second perspective involves studying the Radio Baton and the Lightning within a specific musical context, namely that of a simulated acoustic percussion instrument performance. Three expert percussionists performed basic percussion techniques on a real drum, a drum-like gestural controller (the Roland V-Drum), the Radio Baton and the Lightning II. The motion capture and audio data from these trials suggest that certain acoustic percussion playing techniques can be successfully transferred over to gestural controllers. This comparative analysis between gestural controllers adds to the ongoing discussion on the evaluation of digital musical instruments and their relationship to acoustic instruments.</description><creator>Casciato, Carmine Davide.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Music and technology.</subject><subject>Electronic musical instruments -- Evaluation.</subject><title>On the choice of gestural controllers for musical applications : an evaluation of the Lightning II and the Radio Baton</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k605z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mg61f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wk804</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For Milan Kundera, the question of identity is one of the essential questions around which a novel is constructed. The novelist attempts to define the issue by exploring the existential themes that are tied to it. These themes are examined from different angles with the aid of what the author calls "motifs". Our study is centered on one of those motifs, that of the mirror, through which the author explores the "enigma of the ego". The typological analysis of this motif in Kundera's ten novels brings out in the characters two fundamental attitudes with regard to their identity. The first consists in clinging to it, which results in the character's disquiet, while the second consists in freeing oneself from it, which leads to a better understanding of reality as well as to a certain form of wisdom.</description><creator>Campeau-Devlin, Marianne.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Mirrors in literature.</subject><subject>Kundera, Milan -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Identity (Philosophical concept) in literature.</subject><title>Le motif du mirror dans l'œuvre de Milan Kundera /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q9916.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wk804</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xd32v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examined the relationships between social physique anxiety (SPA) and physical activity and sedentary behaviours among older adolescents. The research was grounded in self-determination theory (SDT; Deci &amp; Ryan, 1985). Three hundred and eighty one males and females completed scientifically-supported questionnaires. Multivariate and univariate analyses of variance revealed that male adolescents reported lower SPA and higher competence, relatedness, self-determined motivation, and physical activity levels compared to females. Regression analyses supported the integration of SPA in SDT, and the main tenets of SDT were maintained. Specifically, the basic psychological needs were important correlates of motivation, and motivation was a positive correlate of PA behaviour and a negative, albeit weak, correlate of sedentary behaviour. Collectively, these findings suggest that SPA experiences can be understood within a motivational framework that explains the functional role played by SPA on health behaviour.</description><creator>Brunet, Jennifer.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Anxiety in adolescence.</subject><subject>Exercise.</subject><subject>Body image in adolescence -- Social aspects.</subject><title>Social physique anxiety and physical activity among adolescents : a self-determination theory perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d775z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xd32v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526g87v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Global education is founded upon numerous theoretical frameworks. In this thesis, following a review of relevant literature, I will carefully consider Pike and Selby's (1995) four-dimensional model of global education. Although I regard theirs as the most promising of recent conceptualizations, it doesn't seem to provide a clear articulation of the specifics of their four dimensions, as well as the way in which these can be fostered in learners. In an attempt to address this incompleteness, I will turn to global communications pioneer Marshall McLuhan whose discussion of the global village contains key concepts and definitions that may provide more specific language for the individual's relationship to the local and the global. Moreover, his ideas regarding the intersection of culture, technology, and the arts within the global village, illuminated by the work of artist Char Davies, can help situate the arts within a newly conceptualized theoretical foundation for global education.</description><creator>Berry, Eleonor.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>International education.</subject><title>State of the art -- states of mind : a reconceptualization of global education's theoretical foundation through alternative expressions of global</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vg10t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526g87v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42nc530</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research sought to explore the meaningfulness of belonging to a choir. Members of 14 Canadian choirs (N=404) responded to 18 statements concerning the perceived benefits of choral singing. Choristers ranked six aspects of choral singing in the following order of importance (from greatest to least): musical, intellectual, emotional, physical, social, and spiritual. An in-depth analysis of three central areas of the choral experience (social, intellectual, and emotional) was done and six sample populations were compared: paid vs. volunteer choristers, choristers living in different areas (urban, suburban, and rural), choristers with a music degree vs. non-degree, age of choristers (young adult, middle-aged, and senior), choir size (large, medium, and small), and type of choir (community and church). Results showed that choristers in small choirs felt like valued members of their choirs, felt a positive connection with the other choristers, and that singing in choir raised their mood to a significantly higher degree than choristers in medium and large choirs. Significant findings showed that volunteer singers, to a greater extent than paid singers, found that choir raised their mood, helped them to relax, and was a satisfying experience which gave them a sense of accomplishment. The differences in responses between middle-aged and senior choristers were minimal, but both gave responses that were significantly higher when compared with young adult choristers. The older singers felt that singing in choir raised their mood, helped them to relax, provided them with a sense of accomplishment, and that there was a sense of unity within their choir more so than young adults.</description><creator>Baird, Maureen Jaymin.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Singing -- Psychological aspects.</subject><title>Perceived benefits of choral singing : social, intellectual, and emotional aspects of group singing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58ph544.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nc530</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rp873</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous studies show that recovering alcoholics exhibit deficits in perceiving facial affect. The present study investigates whether these deficits are present prior to the onset of alcoholism. Participants with a family history of alcoholism (FHP) and participants without such a family history (FHN) selected the emotion label they felt most closely corresponded with stimuli viewed on a computer screen. Zuckerman's Sensation Seeking Survey was also completed. The data revealed a relationship between family history of alcoholism and the perception of facial expressions. Additionally, FHP participants were higher in sensation seeking compared to FHN participants and high sensation seekers were less accurate in categorizing fearful expressions. Disinhibition and boredom susceptibility were identified as the traits driving the effect between sensation seeking and fear categorization accuracy. An account of how these traits may be associated with both decreased fear perception and a greater risk for alcoholism is discussed, and future research directions suggested.</description><creator>Averill, Farah.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Facial expression.</subject><subject>Visual perception.</subject><subject>Alcoholism.</subject><title>Perception of facial expressions of emotion in individuals with a family history of alcoholism versus controls</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386p273.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rp873</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x4941</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transparency and access to information have become important elements of the Mexican political transition. The goal of this study is to contribute to the debate on those fields by: first, providing a theoretical framework that helps to understand the notions of transparency and access to information and their linkage to a democratic regime; second, by offering an account of the institutions that preceded the enactment of this norm; and third, explaining the legislative work that led to the approval of the Transparency and Access to Governmental Information Federal Law (LFTAIPG) in Mexico in 2002. This thesis/paper argues that the LFTAIPG can be seen as the result of the liberalization of the Mexican regime, and as a product of the political transition by promoting accountability in the federal government.</description><creator>Arteaga Cano, Issac Armando.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Government liability -- Mexico.</subject><subject>Mexico -- Politics and government -- 2000-</subject><subject>Freedom of information -- Mexico.</subject><title>Recent development of transparency and access to information at the federal level in Mexico</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vc252.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x4941</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g621m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Do welfare and social service provisions affect the childbearing decisions of Anglophone single mothers living below the low-income level in Montreal? Neoliberal rhetoric has asserted that increased welfare generosity will ultimately breed dependence on social services and propagate a lack of self-sufficiency for single mothers. Rather than a direct cause-and-effect relationship between welfare generosity and the birthrate of single mothers relying on welfare, my evidence suggests a weak correlation: while these provisions may alter the context in which childbearing decisions are made, they do not solely or primarily determine the outcomes of a pregnancy. By altering the economic context in which childbearing decisions are made, an environment is created that may be supportive of single motherhood to a greater or lesser degree; however this alone will not determine outcomes.</description><creator>Adams, Elise.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Public welfare -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Single mothers -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Economic conditions.</subject><title>The role of socio-economic strategies in the childbearing decisions of Anglophone women in Montreal, Quebec /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462891p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g621m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vg113</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Quantitative analysis of Drosophila melanogaster gap gene expression data reveals valuable information about the nature and strengths of interactions in the gap gene network. We first explore different models for fitting the spatiotemporal gene expression data of Drosophila gap gene system and validate our results by computational analysis and comparison with the existing literature. A fundamental problem in systems biology is to associate these results with the inherent cause of gene regulation, namely the binding of the transcription factors (TF) to their respective binding sites. In order to relate these expression-based estimates of gap gene regulation with the sequence-based information of TF binding site composition, we also explore two related problems of (i) finding a set of regulatory weights that is proportional to the binding site occupancy matrix of the transcription factors in current literature and (ii) finding a set of position weight matrices of the TFs that produce a new binding site occupancy matrix showing a greater level of proportionality with our regulatory weights. Our solution to the first problem yielded a regulatory weight matrix incapable of explaining the true causes of gene expression profile despite its relative numerical accuracy in predicting the gene expressions. On the other hand, the second optimization problem could be solved up to a reasonable level of accuracy, but further analysis on the result demonstrated that this optimization problem may be under-constrained. We devise a simple regularization strategy that helps us to reduce the under-constrained nature of the problem.</description><creator>Al Zamal, Faiyaz.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Genetic regulation -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Transcription factors.</subject><subject>Drosophila melanogaster -- Molecular genetics.</subject><title>Relating the expression-based and sequence-based estimates of regulation in the gap gene system of Drosophila melanogaster</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085p798.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vg113</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v2195</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cobalamin must be metabolized intracellularly in order to bind two enzymes: methionine synthase in cytoplasm and methylmalonyl-CoA mutase in mitochondria. Defects in this process cause different inborn errors of cobalamin metabolism (cblA-cblG and mut). A previous study described a cobalamin-binding protein, in addition to methylmalonyl-CoA mutase, in crude mitochondrial fractions. The amount of [57Co]cobalamin bound to this protein was increased in cblB, mut and cblD variant2 cell lines, compared to control cell lines. In the present study, this protein was identified as transcobalamin (TC). Mitochondrial fractions from a cblB cell line were incubated with anti-TC antibodies, which precipitated the cobalamin-bound protein. Analysis of mitochondrial and cytoplasmic fractions isolated from a chloroquine-incubated cblF cell line showed that isolated mitochondrial fractions contain lysosomal material, suggesting that the identified TC is lysosomal. Quantification of cobalamin-bound TC levels in whole cell extracts showed significant increases in cblB and mut groups compared to control cell lines.</description><creator>Yamani, Lama.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Metabolism, Inborn Errors -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Mitochondrial Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Fibroblasts -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Vitamin B 12 -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Transcobalamins -- metabolism.</subject><title>Studies on transcobalamin in cultured fibroblasts from patients with inborn errors of cobalamin metabolism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698c28s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v2195</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m3056</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We are interested in understanding the molecular mechanisms that govern synaptic growth and plasticity. Recent evidence from several laboratories suggests that small GTPases play an important role in the promotion of neurite outgrowth; however, their role in the control of synaptic growth and functional plasticity is not well understood. The goal of this thesis is to investigate the role of small GTPases (including Rac, Rho and Cdc42) in the regulation of synaptic growth in vivo, using the Drosophila larval neuromuscular junction (NMJ) synapses as a model system. Our results show that presynaptic overexpression of Rac, but not of Rho or Cdc42, positively regulates both synaptic structure and function. Genetic loss of Rac leads to embryonic lethality, making it impossible to assess the full loss-of-function phenotype using conventional mutants. To circumvent this, we use the MARCM (Mosaic Analysis with a Repressible Cell Marker) technique to generate single motor neuron clones devoid of all genetic copies of Rac. Our data suggest that Rac activity is crucial for normal synaptic development. In support of this conclusion, we demonstrate that genetic removal of trio, a guanine nucleotide exchange factor (GEF) that is known to activate Rac, leads to a drastic reduction in the number of synaptic boutons. In addition, genetic removal of one copy of trio is sufficient to suppress the gain-of-function phenotype of Rac. Moreover, we demonstrate that partial removal of the fragile X mental retardation gene (dfmr1), a known suppressor of Rac, enhances the gain-of-function phenotype of Rac. Taken together, our findings support a model in which Rac signaling positively regulates synaptic growth and function at the Drosophila larval NMJ.</description><creator>Warren-Paquin, Maude.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Neuromuscular Junction -- physiology.</subject><subject>rac GTP-Binding Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Drosophila -- physiology.</subject><subject>Drosophila Proteins.</subject><subject>Synaptic Transmission -- physiology.</subject><subject>Neuronal Plasticity -- physiology.</subject><title>Regulation of synaptic plasticity at the Drosophila larval NMJ : the role of the small GTPase Rac</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494c959.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m3056</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77st64w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Membrane rafts are small plasma membrane domains that contain high levels of cholesterol and sphingolipids. They have been implicated in processes as diverse as signal transduction, endocytosis and cholesterol trafficking. Traditional methods for the biochemical preparation of lipid rafts involve the extraction of membranes with nonionic detergents followed by the separation of a low-density, detergent-resistant membrane fraction on density gradients. Because of concerns regarding the possible introduction of artifacts through the use of detergents, several methods were developed for the isolation of lipid rafts that do not involve detergent extraction. In this study, we compared three different biochemical methodologies of membrane rafts preparation from purified rat liver PM. Only detergent-resistant membranes (DRMs) fulfill the requirements of membrane rafts. We subsequently found using the low dose of EGF (1 ug/100 g BW); the content of EGFR in PM-DRMs did not changed significantly following EGF administration. When a higher dose of EGF (5 ug/100 g BW) is administrated we observed a rapid and almost complete disappearance of EGFR (around 80%) from both PM and DRMs fractions. Interestingly, following the administration of a low or high dose of EGF, the pool of EGFR in the PM-DRMs fraction becomes highly Tyr-phosphorylated. In accordance with the higher level of EGFR Tyr-Phosphorylation, EGF induced an augmented recruitment of Grb2 and Shc proteins to PM-DRMs compared with whole PM. Furthermore neither high nor low dose of EGF affects the caveolin content in DRMs and PM. These observations suggest that EGFR located in DRM are competent for signaling and non-caveolae PM rafts are involved in the compartmentalization and presumably internalization of the EGFR.</description><creator>Wang, Ye, 1975-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Signal Transduction.</subject><subject>Membrane Microdomains -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Liver -- chemistry.</subject><subject>Receptor, Epidermal Growth Factor -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Detergents -- pharmacology.</subject><title>The trafficking and signaling of EGF receptors in hepatocyte rafts /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903364v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77st64w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qt58m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During early development of Xenopus laevis, gastrulation is a key morphogenetic event which transforms the embryo into three of primary germ layers: ectoderm, mesoderm, and endoderm. In order for the physical separation of these layers to occur, cells have to acquire specific properties that distinguish one layer from another. These properties, which include cell adhesion and migration, should be reflected in the tissue-specific proteome. While genetic analysis has led to the determination of a number of proteins involved in germ layer formation, this method would not have identified those proteins regulated on a translational or post-translational level. In this study, we have developed a two-dimensional gel based comparative proteomic approach employing difference gel electrophoresis (DiGE) to identify proteins involved in germ layer morphogenesis during Xenopus gastrulation. Differences between the physical properties of the ectoderm and mesoderm are likely based on differences in the proteomes of the cell surface and/or cortex. We therefore analyzed plasma membrane enriched fractions, obtained using discontinuous sucrose density gradient centrifugation. The Decyder program was used to quantify expression changes with statistical confidence across multiple DiGE gels, provide independent confirmation of distinct expression patterns from the individual experiments, and demonstrate high reproducibility between replicate samples. The identity of 23 proteins, which were obtained from 33 analyzed spots, was determined using mass spectrometry. Our proteomic analysis of Xenopus ectoderm and mesoderm identified alterations in proteins involved in cytoskeletal organization, signal transduction, protein folding, vesicle trafficking, and in glycolysis. We have also demonstrated the feasibility of proteomics in Xenopus, and have therefore shown that proteomics may be a valuable tool for analysis of early development in this system.</description><creator>Wang, Renee Wan-Jou, 1979-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Xenopus laevis -- Embryology.</subject><subject>Proteomics.</subject><subject>Gastrulation.</subject><title>A comparative proteomic analysis of ectoderm and mesoderm in Xenopus laevis during gastrulation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pv25n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qt58m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848v12t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objectives. beta-blockers can alter bone turnover and increase bone formation in animals. It is unknown whether beta-blockers have similar bone protective effects in humans. We aimed to estimate the effects of beta-blockers on bone mineral density (BMD) and fractures using data from the Canadian Multicentre Osteoporosis Study, a large prospective cohort study. Methods. All medications, including beta-blockers, taken at baseline and after five years of follow-up were recorded. BMD was measured at baseline. During the five years of follow-up, incident minimal trauma fractures were documented by yearly questionnaires. To compare users of beta-blockers to non-users while controlling for possible confounders, multiple linear regression was utilized to estimate between group differences in BMD and multivariate logistic regression was employed to estimate differences in fracture risk. Results. Of the 9423 participants, 236 of 2884 males (8.2%) and 600 of 6539 females (9.2%) used beta-blockers at some point during the study. In men, beta-blocker users had differences of +1.1% (95% confidence interval [CI] -0.9%, 3.0%) and +1.2% (95% CI -0.5%, 4.0%) in baseline BMD at the total hip and at the lumbar spine, respectively, compared to non-users. In women, beta-blocker users had differences of +0.05% (95% CI -1.2%, 1.3%) and +0.2% (95% CI -1.3%, 1.7%) for the BMD of the total hip and the lumbar spine, respectively, compared to non-users. For users of beta-blockers at baseline, the adjusted odds ratio (OR) for any minimal trauma fracture was 1.23 (95% CI 0.67--2.25) in men and 1.02 (95% CI 0.76--1.35) in women. Chronic use (user at baseline and year 5) in men had an OR for any minimal trauma fracture of 2.1 (95% CI 1.0--4.3). In women who used beta-blockers at baseline but not at year 5, the OR for hip fracture was 6.3 (95% CI 2.0--19.3). The risk of fractures for other sites was inconclusive owing to wide confidence intervals. Conclusion. Despite relatively large numbers of subjects, wide confidence intervals do not permit strong conclusions with regards to the effect of beta-blockers on BMD in men. Using a 2% limit of clinical importance for BMD, there appears to be no effect of beta-blockers on BMD in women. There is some evidence from our study that beta-blockers may be associated with an increased risk of fractures in certain subsets of users.</description><creator>Vautour, Line.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Adrenergic beta-Antagonists -- pharmacology.</subject><subject>Fractures, Bone -- epidemiology.</subject><subject>Bone Density -- drug effects.</subject><title>The effect of [beta]-blockers on bone mineral density and fractures in the Canadian Multicentre Osteoporosis Study (CaMos) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rm886.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848v12t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bg301</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We investigate the effect of allowing freedom in the primordial power spectrum of curvature perturbations upon the measurement of other cosmological parameters, in particular the Thomson optical depth due to cosmic reionisation which is present in cosmic microwave background (CMB) observations. We find that the constraint on the optical depth from Wilkinson Microwave Anisotropy Probe (WMAP) data broadens by approximately 10% upon allowing spectral freedom on large scales, and by a slightly larger factor when considering data from future experiments with lower noise in measurements of CMB polarisation. We also present a reconstruction of the primordial power spectrum on the largest scales from WMAP, which is jointly obtained from this analysis.</description><creator>Van Engelen, Alexander.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Cosmic background radiation.</subject><subject>Anisotropy.</subject><title>Cosmic reionisation and the primordial fluctuations in the Universe</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tq62k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bg301</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t9969</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Childhood maltreatment is extremely common in patients diagnosed with psychotic disorders. Moreover, it has been linked with impaired functioning of the Hypothalamic-Pituitary-Adrenal axis. Furthermore, abnormality of the HPA has been found in psychotic patients. Presence of childhood maltreatment could then explain why the HPA axis is dysfunctional in these subjects. Our objective was to clarify the role of childhood trauma in the cortisol profiles of psychotic patients. Thirty-one patients underwent assessments of childhood maltreatment. Diurnal cortisol and cortisol after a controlled psychosocial stress were also collected. Our results show that childhood trauma is associated with lower cortisol levels during the morning and during 24 hours. In men diagnosed with psychosis, childhood trauma is also associated with a higher cortisol response during psychosocial stress. This suggests an alteration of the HPA axis in psychotic patients, resulting from early trauma. Moreover, our results suggest that looking at specific types of childhood abuse may also be important.</description><creator>Valiquette, Luc François.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Child Abuse.</subject><subject>Psychotic Disorders -- physiopathology.</subject><subject>Hydrocortisone -- secretion.</subject><subject>Stress -- physiopathology.</subject><title>Association between self-reported childhood maltreatment and cortisol profiles in psychotic patients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k178q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t9969</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644w34r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>SRY (Sex determining Region of Y chromosome) is the master gene initiating testis determination in mammals. To shed light on the molecular mechanism of SRY action during testicular differentiation, we examined the effects of TAT-HMG fusion protein on gonadal sex differentiation in culture. HMG is the DNA binding motif of SRY and "TAT" is a protein transduction domain. Each pair of CD1 mouse gonadal primordia at 11.5 days post coitum (dpc) was cultured with or without TAT-HMG dissolved in dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) up to 3 days. Immunocytochemical labeling and Real-time RT-PCR of Sry, Sox9 and Mis indicated that DMSO blocked testicular differentiation, Sertoli cell differentiation and testis cords formation, downstream of SRY. TUNEL showed a massive mesenchymal cell death, which might be responsible for disruption of testis cord formation. Treatment with TAT-HMG rescued Sertoli cell differentiation, probably by up regulation of Sry, but not testis cord formation or cell death.</description><creator>Tavallaee, Ghazaleh.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Sex differentiation.</subject><subject>Sex Differentiation.</subject><subject>Y chromosome.</subject><subject>Genes, sry.</subject><title>Molecular mechanism of SRY action during testicular differentiation in the mouse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204272z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644w34r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r4755</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Retinal ganglion cell (RGC) axon arbors within the optic tectum are refined in development through a dynamic process of activity-dependent remodeling. The synaptic adhesion molecule N-cadherin is a candidate for mediating selective stabilization and elaboration of RGC axons due to its localization to perisynaptic sites and its modifiability by neural activity. RGCs of Xenopus tadpoles were co-transfected with plasmids encoding a dominant negative N-cadherin (N-cadDeltaE) and eGFP or eYFP. Using two-photon in vivo time-lapse imaging, we found that axons expressing N-cadDeltaE became less elaborate than controls over three days of daily live imaging. Shorter interval time-lapse imaging of axons expressing synaptophysin-GFP to visualize putative synaptic sites revealed that N-cadDeltaE expressing axons form fewer stable branches than controls and that stabilization of axonal branches at synaptic sites is altered. We conclude that N-cadherin participates in the stabilization of axonal branches in the Xenopus retinotectal system.</description><creator>Tavakoli, Aydin.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Cadherins -- physiology.</subject><subject>Visual Pathways -- growth &amp; development.</subject><subject>Xenopus.</subject><subject>Optic Lobe, Nonmammalian -- growth &amp; development</subject><subject>Retinal Ganglion Cells -- cytology.</subject><subject>Axons -- physiology.</subject><subject>Nerve Net -- growth &amp; development.</subject><title>Cadherin involvement in axonal branch stability in the Xenopus retinotectal system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vs20s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r4755</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mg62q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Efficient muscle regeneration is essential in mammals in order to overcome daily stress such as wounds, exercise and pathologic processes. This regeneration relies on muscle stem cells, the satellite cells. After a lesion, satellite cells are activated, proliferate and differentiate in fonctionnal muscle fibers. Our laboratory has previously shown that the transcription factor GATA-6 is expressed in the satellite cells. The present thesis confirms the expression of this factor in this cell type. Also, it seems that GATA-6 could be implicated in the maintaining of quiescence of these cells. The GATA-6 heterozygous mouse muscle is characterized by an increase level of Myf5 and Pax7+ cells. Moreover, suppression of one copy of the GATA-6 gene in a muscular dystrophy model mouse, the mdx mice, alleviates its phenotype. Further experiments on a muscle-specific GATA-6 null mouse will allow a better understanding of the role of GATA-6 in muscle regeneration.</description><creator>Tardif, Derek.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Regeneration.</subject><subject>Satellite Cells, Skeletal Muscle -- cytology.</subject><subject>GATA6 Transcription Factor.</subject><title>Implication du facteur de transcription GATA-6 dans la régénération musculaire</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fw31w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mg62q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032659s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Extensive emphasis on selection for milk yield with minimal attention to the animals' functional performance has increased the yield of North American dairy cattle. The high intensity of selection for production traits such as milk yield, protein yield and fat yield has also brought about a rapid increase in genetic relationships among animals. In dairy cattle, correlated response to selection for milk yield includes fertility and susceptibility to diseases. Although the high producing cows have greater net profit, they also have higher mammary and discarded milk costs associated with high production. Long-term genetic selection against clinically diagnosed diseases might be useful to diminish their incidence. The Scandinavian countries have incorporated the health traits into their selection indices. Canadian breeding programs realize the need to consider traits other than the yield in selection decisions. The objective of this study was to determine the genetic variability of various clinically diagnosed health traits. Data from 171 herds of the Ontario milk-recording program were used. These herds are collaborating with the University of Guelph (Dr. David Kelton) to record health traits. A major impediment to estimating heritabilities for the majority of the disorders was that the progeny group size per sire was not large enough to enable detecting a significant difference among sires. Hence, heritability estimates were not obtained for all the health disorders included in the study. The progeny group size per sire has to be increased such that there are at least 5 cases per progeny group to enable detecting a difference among sires. Heritability estimates for retained placenta and displaced abomasum in the first lactation were 0.067 and 0.212 respectively. The heritability estimate of cystic ovaries in the second lactation was 0.092. In the third lactation, the heritability estimate of mastitis was 0.10 whereas retained placenta had a heritability of 0.25.</description><creator>Al-Abri, Mohammed Ali.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Holstein-Friesian cattle -- Diseases -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Holstein-Friesian cattle -- Ontario -- Diseases -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Genetic variability of health disorders in Ontario Holstein cows</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qd398.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032659s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zj11p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:15:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The acid-catalysed hydrolysis of amides has for a long time been assumed to involve a protonation of the amide in a fast preequilibrium step, followed by the rate-determing attack of a molecule of water on this protonated intermediate (1,2,3). Recently it has been shown that by taking account of the basic strength of the amide, many features of its hydrolysis might be explained; in particular, the fact that the rate of hydrolysis increases to a maximum and then decreases with increase in concentration of acid (4). [...]</description><creator>Chang, Hang Shing.</creator><contributor>Taurins, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1960</date><subject></subject><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Ionization of Substituted Benzamides in Acid.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gm06k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zj11p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):17200</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>