<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:34:34Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):37975" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd4731420</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La fibrose kystique (FK) est une maladie héréditaire fatale caractérisée par une inflammation chronique et exagérée. Les voies respiratoires des patients atteints de FK présentent un afflux soutenu de neutrophiles et d'interleukine (IL)-8, l'agent chimiotactique majeur des neutrophiles. La thérapie anti-inflammatoire est un focus du traitement de la FK et il existe un besoin évident de nouvelles thérapies sûres et efficaces. Des effets biologiques, incluant des effets antioxydants et anti-inflammatoires ont été attribués aux protéines de lactosérum. Des recherches antérieures ont suggéré une suppression de la réponse inflammatoire induite par le facteur de nécrose tumorale (TNF)alpha par des hydrolysats de protéines de lactosérum (WPH). De plus, il a été suggéré que le traitement par pression hyperbare (PH) des isolats de protéines de lactosérum (WPI) peut potentialiser leurs activités biologiques. Les effets d'un traitement PH sur la digestibilité et les activités anti-inflammatoires et antioxydants des WPI ont été explorés dans une série d'études mécanistes in vitro et dans un essai clinique. Des hydrolysats de protéines de lactosérum pressurisées (pWPH) et non pressurisées (nWPH) ont été générés par le moyen de deux différents protocoles de digestion in vitro imitant le processus de digestion gastro-intestinal humain. Le prétraitement HP a entrainé une augmentation de la digestibilité in vitro et de l'activité antioxydante des WPI, malgré les différences entre les deux protocoles de digestion et entre les profiles de peptides résultant des digestions, signifiant que la pression génère une augmentation des peptides bioactifs générés quel que soit l'environnement protéolytique. Les profiles des peptides des pWPH ont exhibé des différences qualitatives et quantitatives comparés aux nWPH. Pour explorer les mécanismes possibles par lesquels WPH pourraient exercer leurs effets anti-inflammatoires, des lignées cellulaires normales et déficientes du Régulateur de la Conductance Transmembranaire Mucoviscidose (CFTR) ont été traitées avec nWPH ou pWPH et stimulées avec TNFalpha, IL-1beta, ou lipopolysaccharide (LPS). Les nWPH et pWPH ont diminué la sécrétion d'IL-8 induite par LPS, bien que les pWPH aient été plus puissants, requérant de moindres doses pour exercer une inhibition significative. pWPH a augmenté l'activité antioxydante des surnageants des cultures des deux lignées cellulaires. Aucun type de WPH n'a inhibé la sécrétion d'IL-8 induite par TNFalpha ou IL-1beta. Puisque LPS et IL-1beta partagent une voie commune de signalisation suivant l'activation de leurs récepteurs respectifs, des expériences ont été menées sur des événements prenant place en amont de la convergence des deux voies de signalisation, au niveau du récepteur Toll-like receptor (TLR)4. Les nWPH ni les pWPH n'ont eu d'effet sur l'expression du TLR4, mais la liaison entre LPS et les récepteurs de surface a été réduite par les deux traitements. Aucun WPH n'a exhibé de liaison directe ou de neutralisation du LPS. Il est donc probable que les WPHs aient exercé la suppression d'IL-8 induite par LPS en inhibant la liaison du LPS avec son récepteur et par conséquent l'activation du TLR4. Pour explorer les effets cliniques in vivo des WPI pressurisés, un essai clinique pilote d'une durée d'un mois a été mené, où des enfants et adultes souffrant de FK ont été supplémentés avec des protéines pressurisées. Le statut nutritionnel des enfants et adultes a été amélioré. Une amélioration des fonctions pulmonaires chez les enfants a été observée et le taux sanguin de protéine C réactive a diminué chez la majorité des patients chez qui les taux étaient élevés au début de l'étude. Globalement, les résultats de cette dissertation fournissent un nouveau mécanisme par lequel les WPI pressurisés peuvent exercer des effets anti-inflammatoires et suggèrent de nouvelles avenues potentielles pour l'usage des WPI pressurisés en tant qu'agent nutritionnel thérapeutique ou préventif.</description><description>Cystic fibrosis (CF) is a fatal inherited disease characterized by chronic, persistent and exaggerated inflammation. The airways of CF patients exhibit a sustained influx of neutrophils and interleukin (IL)-8, the major neutrophil chemoattractant. Anti-inflammatory therapy is a focus of CF treatment, with a clear need for novel, safe and effective therapies. Whey proteins have been attributed a number of biological activities, including antioxidant and anti-inflammatory effects. Previous research has suggested a suppression of the inflammatory response to tumor necrosis factor (TNF)alpha by whey protein hydrolysates (WPH) in respiratory epithelial cell lines. Furthermore, it is suggested that hyperbaric pressure (HP) treatment of whey proteins can potentiate their biological activities. The effect of HP treatment on the digestibility, anti-inflammatory and antioxidant activity of whey protein isolates (WPI) was explored in a series of mechanistic in vitro studies and in a clinical trial. Hydrolysates of pressurized (pWPH) and native (nWPH) whey protein isolates were generated using two differing in vitro digestion protocols that mimic human gastrointestinal digestion. Hyperbaric pressure pre-treatment resulted in enhanced in vitro digestibility and antioxidant activity of WPI regardless of major differences in enzymatic conditions and the resulting peptide profiles, signifying that pressure processing generates an enhanced release of bioactive peptides regardless of the proteolytic environment. The peptide profiles obtained from the hydrolysates of pWPH exhibited quantitative and qualitative differences from those of nWPH. To explore the possible mechanisms by which WPH may exert their anti-inflammatory effects, wild-type and cystic fibrosis (CF) conductance regulator-deficient cells were treated with either nWPH or pWPH and stimulated with TNFalpha, interleukin (IL)-1beta or lipopolysaccharide (LPS). Both nWPH and pWPH suppressed LPS-induced IL-8 secretion, although pWPH were more potent requiring lower doses to exert significant inhibition. pWPH increased the ferric-reducing antioxidant activity of cell culture supernatant in both cell lines. Neither type of hydrolysate suppressed TNFalpha- or IL-1beta-induced IL-8 secretion. Since LPS and IL-1beta, beyond the activation of their respective receptors, share a common intracellular pathway, further experiments were conducted on signalling events that occur prior to the convergence of the two pathways, at the level of Toll-like receptor (TLR)4. There was no effect of either nWPH or pWPH on the cell membrane expression of TLR4. Neither type of WPH exhibited direct binding and neutralization of LPS, but both significantly reduced the binding of LPS to cell surface receptors. It is therefore likely that the WPHs exerted the observed LPS-induced IL-8 suppression by suppressing the binding of LPS to its receptor with the consequent inhibited activation of TLR4. To explore the possible in vivo clinical effects of pressurized WPI, a one-month, open-label pilot study of supplementation with pressurized WPI in children and adults with CF was conducted. Nutritional status was enhanced in both children and adults. An improvement in lung function was observed in children, and C-reactive protein decreased in the majority of patients with initially high values. Overall, the thesis results provide a novel mechanism by which whey proteins and pressurized whey can exert anti-inflammatory effects and suggest new potential avenues for the use of pressurized whey protein isolate as a nutrition-based anti-inflammatory therapeutic or preventative agent.</description><creator>Iskandar, Michele</creator><contributor>Larry Lands (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Stan Kubow (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>Effect of native and pressurized whey protein isolates on inflammation in respiratory epithelial cells expressing either wildtype or mutant cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator (CFTR)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591d28w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd4731420</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rj58n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Liver metastases are a frequent and often fatal occurrence in cancer patients.  A better understanding of the biology of liver metastasis is essential to improve survival statistics for these patients. Although the contribution of IGF-IR to malignancy has been recognized for over 2 decades, the role that the IGF axis plays in metastasis is not yet fully understood. Using a murine Lewis lung carcinoma-based model, our laboratory has previously shown that the IGF-I receptor (IGF-IR) plays the key role in liver metastasis by regulating matrix metalloproteinase (MMP) expression and by increasing tumor cells survival and proliferation in the liver. The objectives of my project were to further analyze IGF-mediated regulation of MMP expression and investigate the crosstalk between the IGF axis and mediators of inflammation, particularly the TNF-alpha/NF-kappaB axis. My results revealed the following: A. In M-27 cells with ectopic IGF-IR overexpression (M-27IGFIR) that have acquired a liver-metastasizing potential but lost the ability to colonize the lung, PKC-alpha was found to be transcriptionally down-regulated and this resulted in decreased expression of the PKC-regulated MMPs- MMP-9, MMP-3 and MMP-13. This altered MMP expression could account for the changes in site-specificity of metastasis observed in these cells. B.  In M-27IGFIR, but not in wild type M-27 cells, TNF-alpha was found to induce IL-6 production and autocrine IL-6/gp130/STAT3 signalling and thereby provide a mechanism of escape from the pro-apoptotic effects of this inflammatory cytokine. When this escape mechanism was abrogated by the use of siRNA or neutralizing antibodies, the cells re-acquired their sensitivity to apoptosis and their metastatic ability was reduced, indicating that it played a critical role in liver-metastasis in vivo. C. A mechanism of synergistic crosstalk between IGF and TNF signalling was identified in cells with high IGF-IR expression levels. In these cells, NF-kappaB activation in response to TNF-alpha was found to be accelerated in a PI3-K/Akt –dependent manner, identifying IGF-IR as an enhancer of NF-kappaB signalling and suggesting that cytokine expression, in particular IL-6 production may be regulated by the kinetics of NF-kappaB activation. Together, these results identify novel molecular mechanisms that mediate the diverse effects of IGF-IR on the tumor microenvironment and on metastasis and may be targeted for anti-cancer therapy. </description><description>Les métastases hépatiques sont souvent mortelles dans les patients atteint du cancer. Une meilleure compréhension de la biologie des métastases hépatiques nous aiderais a amélioré le taux de survie des ces patients. Cela fait plus de vingt ans que la contribution de IGF-IR dans la progression du cancer est reconnue, mais nous ne savons pas encore exactement comment. Utilisant le modèle de carcinome pulmonaire de Lewis, nous avons déjà démontré que le IGF-IR régularise l'expression des métalloprotéinases matricielles (MMP) et ainsi joue un rôle important dans les métastases hépatiques. Les objectifs de mon projet étaient d'analyser le mécanisme de régulation des MMPs par IGF et d'examiner la diaphonie de signaux entre l'axe IGF et les médiateurs d'inflammations, en particulier TNF-α et NF-κB. Mes résultats démontrent ceci: A. Dans les cellules M27 transfectées avec le IGF-IR (M-27IGFIR) et qui ont acquis l' habileté de métastasier au foie mais on perdu leur potentiel de coloniser les poumons, l'expression transcriptionnelle de PKC-α était diminuée, résultant en une diminution de l'expression des MMPs qui sont régularisées par PKC-α: MMP-1, MMP-3 et MMP-13. La variation de profil de MMP de ces cellules pourrait expliquer le changement de site de métastases de ces cellules. B. Dans les cellules  M-27IGFIR, mais pas dans les cellules sauvages M27, TNF-α peut induire la production de IL-6 et des signaux autocrines via la voie de transduction IL-6/gp-130/STAT3. De cette façon, les cellules peuvent évader les effets pro-apoptotiques de IL-6. Quand nous avons inhibé cette voie de signalisation en utilisant un siRNA et des anticorps, les cellules ont re-acquis leur habileté d'induire l'apoptose et leur habilité de métastasier a été réduit. Ces résultats démontrent que cette voie de signalisation est importante pour les métastases hépatiques des cellules  M-27IGFIR. C. Dans les cellules avec une haute expression de IGF-IR, j'ai identifié un échange de signaux entre les voies de signalisation de IGF et TNF. Dans ces cellules, l'activation de NF-κB, suivant la stimulation avec TNF-α, a été accélérée d'une manière dépendante de la voie de signalisation PI3K/Akt. Ces résultats démontrent que IGF-IR augmente la signalisation de l'agent de transcription NF-κB et suggère que l'expression des cytokines, IL-6 en particulier, peut être régulée par l'activation de NF-κB. Conjointement, mes résultats identifient de nouveaux mécanismes, dont IGF-IR, jouant un rôle dans le microenvironment des tumeurs, dans la métastase et introduit des cibles pour la thérapie.</description><creator>Li, Shun</creator><contributor>Penina Brodt (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Crosstalk between mediators of inflammation and the IGF axis in liver metastasis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66347641.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rj58n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zn00h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'obésité est devenue une des plus grandes menaces dans la santé publique, étant donné qu'elle est fréquemment co-reliée avec des facteurs de risque du diabète de type 2 (T2D) et de la maladie cardiovasculaire (CVD), et est donc associée à une mortalité accrue. Les facteurs génétiques représentent une partie substantielle de la variation phénotypique de l'obésité, ainsi que des facteurs de risque des maladies vasculaires qui y sont associés. Dans cette thèse, je décris l'identification de plusieurs variants génétiques communs qui prédisposent les porteurs aux complications associées à l'obésité. D'abord, je décris l'identification d'une variation commune dans le gène d'une protéine sécrétée par le tissu adipeux viscéral, visfatin, et démontre l'influence de ces variants sur la variation interindividuelle d'une insulinémie à jeun. Deuxièmement, je décris l'identification d'une interaction entre l'utilisation des thiazolidinediones une classe de médicaments anti-hyperglycémiques, et une variation génétique dans le gène nuclear factor of activated T-cells cytoplasmic component 2 (NFATC2) qui aboutit à l'œdème et potentiellement à l'insuffisance cardiaque congestive. Ensuite, en utilisant un échantillon de la population asiatique du Sud dans la découverte de gènes, j'identifie une nouvelle association entre la variation du gène dipeptidyl peptidase 4 (DPP4), une cible de la médication anti-hyperglycémique basée sur l'incretin, et les niveaux de l'apolipoprotéine B (apoB), un facteur de risque du CVD et un marqueur de la dyslipidémie associée à l'obésité. De plus, en utilisant des différences observées entre les Européens et les Asiatiques du Sud, j'ai pu identifier l'hétérogénéité dans l'association entre DPP4 et apoB causé par l'adiposité. Finalement, je décris une association entre la variation du gène sterol regulatory element binding protein 1 (SREBF1) et l'indice de masse corporelle (BMI) et démontre sa contribution potentielle aux différences de BMI observées parmi différentes ethnicités dans le monde entier. Je présente aussi des données qui suggèrent fortement que ces différences peuvent être dues à une récente sélection positive à ce locus dans des populations humaines. Les découvertes de cette thèse illustrent l'importance des variants génétiques communs dans la pathogenèse de l'obésité, ainsi que les complications qui s'y rattachent et mettent en évidence la régulation de glucose par le tissu adipeux comme étant une caractéristique sous-jacente importante.</description><description>Obesity has become one of the biggest threats to global health, as it frequently co-occurs with a constellation of type 2 diabetes (T2D) and cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk factors and is associated with increased mortality. Genetic factors account for a substantial portion of the phenotypic variance in obesity and each of the correlated vascular disease risk factors. In this thesis, I describe the identification of several common genetic variants that predispose carriers to the complications associated with obesity. First, I report the identification of common variation within the gene of a protein secreted by visceral adipose tissue, visfatin, and demonstrate the influence of these variants on the inter-individual variation in fasting insulin levels. Second, I describe the identification of an interaction between the use of thiazolidinediones (TZDs), a class of anti-hyperglycemic medication, and variation in the nuclear factor of activated T-cells cytoplasmic component 2 (NFATC2) gene that results in edema and potentially congestive heart failure (CHF). Next, using a South Asian population sample for gene discovery, I identify a novel association between variation in the dipeptidyl peptidase 4 (DPP4) gene, a target of incretin-based anti-hyperglycemic medication, and apolipoprotein B (apoB) levels, a CVD risk factor and marker of the dyslipidemia associated with obesity. In addition, using observed differences between the Europeans and South Asians I was able to identify heterogeneity in the association between DPP4 and apoB caused by adiposity. Finally, I report an association between variation in the sterol regulatory element binding protein 1 (SREBF1) gene and body mass index (BMI) and demonstrate its potential contribution to observed differences in BMI among different ethnicities around the world. I also present data that strongly suggest that these differences may have been due to recent positive selection at this locus in human populations. The findings in this thesis illustrate the importance of common genetic variants in the pathogenesis of obesity, as well as its associated complications and highlight the regulation of glucose by adipose tissue as an important underlying feature.</description><creator>Bailey, Swneke</creator><contributor>James Engert (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Genetic insights into obesity and its associated metabolic complications: a multiethnic perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pm31x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zn00h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53x101z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Higgs boson is the only elementary particle predicted by the Standard Model (SM) that has not yet been observed experimentally. If it exists, it explains the spontaneous electroweak symmetry breaking and the origin of mass for gauge bosons and fermions. We test the validity of the SM by performing a search for the associated production of a Higgs boson and a  W  boson in the channel where the Higgs boson decays to a bottom-antibottom quark pair and the W boson decays to a charged lepton and a neutrino (the WH channel). We study a dataset of proton-antiproton collisions at a centre-of-mass energy  of 1.96 TeV  provided by the Tevatron accelerator, corresponding to an integrated luminosity of 5.7 inverse femtobarns , and recorded using the Collider Detector at Fermilab (CDF). We select events consistent with the signature of exactly one charged lepton (electron or muon), missing transverse energy due to the undetected neutrino (MET) and two collimated streams of particles (jets), at least one of which is required to be identified as originating from a bottom quark. We improve the discrimination of Higgs signal from backgrounds through the use of an artificial neural network. Using a Bayesian statistical inference approach, we set for each hypothetical Higgs boson mass in the range 100 - 150  GeV/c^2  with 5 GeV/c^2  increments a  95%  credibility level (CL) upper limit on the ratio between the Higgs production cross section times branching fraction and the SM prediction.Our main original contributions are the addition of a novel charged lepton reconstruction algorithm with looser requirements (ISOTRK) with respect the electron or muon tight criteria (TIGHT), as well as the introduction of a novel trigger-combination method that allows to maximize the event yield while avoiding trigger correlations and that is used for the ISOTRK category. The ISOTRK candidate is a high-transverse-momentum good-quality track isolated from other activity in the tracking system and not required to match a calorimeter cluster, as for a tight electron candidate, or an energy deposit in the muon detector, as for a tight muon candidate. The ISOTRK category recovers real charged leptons that otherwise would be lost in the non-instrumented regions of the detector. This allows the reconstruction of more  W  boson candidates, which in turn increases the number of reconstructed  WH  signal candidate events, and therefore improves the sensitivity of the  WH  search. Since there is no ISOTRK-dedicated trigger at CDF, for the ISOTRK charged lepton category we employ three MET-plus-jets-based triggers using a novel method, which allows the combination of any number of triggers in order to maximize the event yield while avoiding trigger correlations. On an event-by-event basis, only the trigger with the largest efficiency is used. By avoiding a logical "OR" between triggers, the loss in the yield of events accepted by the trigger combination is compensated by a smaller and easier-to-compute corresponding systematic uncertainty. The addition of the ISOTRK charged lepton category to the TIGHT category produces an increase of 33% in the WH signal yield and a decrease of 15.5 % to 19.0 % in the median expected 95 % CL cross-section upper limits across the entire studied Higgs mass interval. The observed (median expected) 95 % CL SM Higgs upper limits on cross section times branching ratio vary between 2.39  x SM (2.73  x SM) for a Higgs mass of 100  GeV/c^2  to 31.1  x SM (31.2  x SM) for a Higgs mass of 150 GeV/c^2, while the value for a 115 GeV/c^2 Higgs boson is that of 5.08  x SM (3.79  x SM).The novel trigger combination method is already in use by several CDF analyses. It is applicable to any analysis that uses triggers based on MET and jets, such as supersymmetry searches at the ATLAS and CMS experiments at the Large Hadron Collider. In its most general form, the method can be used by any analysis that combines any number of different triggers.</description><description>Le boson de Higgs est la seule particule elementaire predite par le Modele Standard qui n'a jamais ete observee experimentalement. S'il existe, il explique la brisure spontanee de la symetrie electrofaible, ainsi que la masse des bosons W et Z et de tous les fermions. On verifie la validite du Modele standard en effectuant une recherche sur la production associee d'un boson de Higgs et d'un boson W dans le cas ou le boson de Higgs se desintegre en une paire de quarks bottom-antibottom et le boson W se desintegre en un lepton charge et un neutrino (le mode WH). Nos donnees furent accumulees en etudiant  des collisions proton-antiproton a une energie au centre de masse de 1.96 Tev produites par l'accelerateur Tevatron, a une luminosite integree de 5.7 femtobarns inverses et collectees par le detecteur Collider Detector at Fermilab (CDF). On selectionne des evenements avec une signature correspondante a exactement un lepton charge (electron ou muon), de l'energie manquante transversale a cause du neutrino qui s'echappe du detecteur (MET) et deux jets de particules, dont au moins un doit provenir d'un quark bottom. On ameliore la discrimination entre le signal Higgs et le bruit de fond a l'aide d'un reseau de neurones artificiels. En utilisant une inference statistique bayesienne, on calcule pour chaque masse hypothetique du boson de Higgs dans l'intervalle 100-150 GeV/c^2, avec des increments de 5 GeV/c^2, une limite superieure de 95% d'intervalle de credibilite (CL), sur le rapport entre la section efficace multipliee par le rapport d'embranchement et celle predite par le Modele Standard. Notre contribution principale est l'introduction d'un nouvel algorithme de reconstruction d'un lepton charge avec des criteres plus laches (ISOTRK) par rapport aux criteres stricts de reconstruction des candidats d'electrons et de muons (TIGHT). La deuxieme contribution majeure consiste en l'introduction d'une nouvelle methode pour combiner des declencheurs differents permetant de maximiser le nombre d'evenements selectionnes et en meme temps que d'eviter les correlations entre les declencheurs.Un candidat de ISOTRK est une trajectoire qui correspond aux criteres de qualite, qui a une large quantite de mouvement transverse, qui est isolee d'autres activites dans le detecteur de trajectoires et qui ne doit pas se prolonger dans une zone active du calorimetre (detecteur de muons), comme pour un candidat d'electron (muon). Les candidats de ISOTRK recuperent de vrais leptons charges qui seraient autrement perdus dans les zones non instrumentees du detecteur. L'ajout de la categorie ISOTRK a la categorie TIGHT permet de reconstruire plusieurs bosons W reels et par la suite de recuperer plusieurs evenements WH, ce qui ameliore la sensitivite de la recherche de WH.Comme a CDF il n'y a pas de declencheurs dedies au leptons charges ISOTRK, on utilise pour la categorie ISOTRK trois declencheurs bases sur MET et jets avec une nouvelle methode qui permet de maximiser le nombre d'evenements accumules tout en evitant les correlations des declencheurs. Pour chaque evenement, ce n'est que le declencheur avec la plus grande efficacite qui est utilise. Le nombre d'evenements ramasses est legerement inferieur a celui d'un "OR" logique entre les declencheurs, mais cela est compense par une erreur systematique qui est a la fois moins importante et plus facile a evaluer. Dans sa forme la plus generale, la methode peut etre utilisee par toute analyse qui utilise un nombre variable de declencheurs differents.  L'utilisation de la categorie ISOTRK en plus de la categorie TIGHT augmente de 33% le nombre d'evenements WH selectionnes et decroit de 15.5% a 19.0% la limite superieure mediane attendue. La limite superieure observee (attendue) varie entre 2.39 x SM(2.73 x SM) pour un boson de Higgs de 100 GeV/c^2 jusqu'a 31.1 x SM(31.2 x SM) pour un boson de Higgs de 150 GeV/c^2. En meme temps, pour un boson de Higgs de 115 GeV/c^2, la valeur est 5.08 x SM(3.79 x SM).</description><creator>Buzatu, Adrian</creator><contributor>Andreas Warburton (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Physics - Elementary Particles and High Energy</subject><title>Search for the standard model Higgs Boson produced in association with a W Boson in the isolated-track charged-lepton channel using the collider detector at Fermilab</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d570165j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x101z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xn80v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines whether transitioning from current co-management approaches to an adaptive co-management approach would resolve some of the problems experienced in current treaty negotiations contexts between Canadian First Nations and the state government. It first identifies how adaptive co-management would be an improvement on existing treaty processes. Secondly, it examines how the co-existence of different knowledge systems and cultural change can be addressed in an adaptive co-management process. Finally, the thesis identifies the preconditions needed in order to build organisations for adaptive treaties. The case of the Atikamekw First Nation (central Quebec, Canada) treaty negotiations serves as a case study to meet these research objectives. Research results identify adaptive co-management as a suitable approach for creating treaties that are closer to First Nations' needs by focusing on learning and the on-going renewal of a people-to-people relationship. This approach departs from current static and bureaucratic models of treaty making, which concentrate on structural aspects of co-management and the extinguishment of Aboriginal rights. The research identifies adaptive co-management as a potential catalyst for the revitalization of Aboriginal cultures by reporting on the current transformation of the Atikamekw First Nation traditional institutions of governance in order to increase their participation in natural resource management decision-making processes. It also conveys that the Atikamekw aim towards having a decision-making system rooted in the past, with the territorial chief at its core, but yet future-oriented, not fixed in time, and departing from its original form, therefore highlighting the need for flexible and adaptive organisations for the co-management of the land.</description><description>Cette thèse détermine si une approche de cogestion adaptative peut ou non résoudre quelques uns des problèmes actuellement rencontrés lors de négociations de traités entre premières nations du Canada et l'état. La thèse identifie dans un premier lieu la façon dont la cogestion adaptative présenterait une amélioration par rapport aux traités actuels. Deuxièmement, elle examine la façon dont la coexistence de différents systèmes de savoir et le changement culturel peuvent être pris en compte dans un processus de cogestion adaptative. Finalement, la thèse identifie les préconditions requises pour la mise sur pied d'organisations de cogestion dans un contexte de traité adaptatif. Pour atteindre ces objectifs, c'est le cas de la négociation territoriale de la nation atikamekw (Quebec, Canada) qui est étudié. Les résultats de recherche indiquent que la cogestion adaptative est une approche appropriée afin d'en arriver à des traités qui sont plus près des besoins des premières nations en valorisant l'apprentissage en continu et le renouvellement continuel d'une relation de peuple-à-peuple. Cette approche se distingue des modèles actuels de traités, qui tendent à être statiques et bureaucratiques, se concentrant sur les aspects structuraux de la cogestion et l'extinction des droits ancestraux. La recherche souligne qu'une approche adaptative de la cogestion a un potentiel de catalyseur pour la revitalisation des cultures autochtones. Ceci est illustré par le processus de transformation des institutions de gouvernance territoriale ayant présentement cours chez les Atikamekw. La thèse démontre que les Atikamekw désirent construire un système décisionnel ancré dans le passé, centré sur le chef de territoire et la famille, mais tourné vers l'avenir, évolutif et différent de sa forme originale.</description><creator>Houde, Nicolas</creator><contributor>George Wenzel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Social Sciences - Geography </subject><title>"Experimenting with what will become our traditions": adaptive co-management as a bridge to an Atikamekw Nehirowisiw post-treaty world in Nitaskinan, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cp95m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xn80v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n5287</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse présente une analyse théorique et expérimentale du couplage des microsphères anisotropes en verre de chalcogénure. Les modes de galerie résonants (WGMS) de microsphères isotrope sont aussi présentés et la relation de dispersion TE et TM des WGMS est dérivée à partir des équations vectorielles électromagnétiques en coordonnées sphériques. Les équations de Maxwell peuvent être résolues en 2D pour la résolution en 3D de microsphères axisymétriques ou a symétrie rotationnelle isotrope. Les quatre premiers WGMS TE et TM sont simulés dans le modèle 2D en utilisant la méthode des éléments finis. La capacité de liaison, le volume modal V et facteur de qualité Q dépendent de l'indice de réfraction et de la taille de la microsphère. On décompose une onde lumineuse en multiples fronts d'onde plan à l'intérieur de la microsphère; le coefficient de couplage entre une microsphère et un microfil est déterminé par le nombre de WGMS et la distance entre la microsphère et microfil. Le facteur de qualité Q est analysé; le couplage TE &amp; TM de microsphères non linéaire est introduit à partir de simulations Matlab. Des expériences de couplage pour la transmission, la réflexion et le port à fonction «drop» sont conduites. Les ondes lumineuses pour le couplage proviennent d'une source de lumière à large bande incohérent et d'une source laser étroite accordable à bande étroite. La lumière à large bande a donné des résultats à haute sensibilité tandis que le laser cohérent facilite la mesure de couplage.En dernier lieu, les microsphères de chalcogénure ont été utilisées comme élément de rétroaction pour un milieu amplificateur. En comparaison avec des microsphères de silice, les microsphères de chalcogénure génèrent une réponse qui est plus instable due à la perturbation par les porteurs libres et l'activité thermique.</description><description>Anisotropic chalcogenide microsphere is introduced for coupling theoretical analyzing and coupling experiment. Whispering Gallery Modes (WGMs) of isotropic microsphere is introduced and the TE &amp; TM WGMs dispersion relationship is derived from electromagnetic vector equations in the spherical coordinate. The Maxwell equations can be solved in 2D model for the 3D model of axisymmetric or Rotational symmetry isotropic microsphere. First 4 TE&amp;TM WGMs are simulated in 2D model using finite-element weak method. The binding capability, mode volume V and quality factor Q depend on the refractive index and size of the microsphere. Plane wavefront light wave is assumed to propagate inside the microsphere; coupling coefficient is determined by WGMs numbers and the distance between the microsphere and the micro-taper. Coupling related Q factor is analyzed; TE &amp; TM nonlinear microsphere coupling is introduced with Matlab simulation. Chalcogenide coupling experiments for transmission, reflection and drop-port function are conducted. The light waves for coupling are broadband incoherent light source and narrowband tunable laser. Broadband light gave sensitive results while the coherent laser gave easy coupling capability.The chalcogenide microsphere was used as a feedback element of an amplifying medium. Comparing with silica microsphere, chalcogenide microsphere?s response is more unstable due to free carriers perturbation and thermal activity.</description><creator>Yue, HongQuan</creator><contributor>Martin Rochette (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Optical whispering gallery modes in chalcogenide As2Se3 microspheres</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63t092f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n5287</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z5023</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During neural development a wide variety of neuronal and glial cells are produced from neural precursor cells. The regulation of the transition from proliferation to differentiation, migration and final functional integration into neural circuits is a highly elaborate process requiring complex and tightly regulated interactions of various extrinsic and intrinsic factors present in the developing central nervous system. Disturbance of one or more of these processes may result in severe perturbations of normal development and function of the brain. The NF-κB signaling pathway is important for several brain functions such as neuronal survival, plasticity, learning, memory consolidation and neurodegeneration. Although it has been recently shown that NF-κB is activated during development of the forebrain, virtually nothing is known about its possible involvement in neurogenesis. This work aimed at characterizing the pattern of NF-κB activation during telencephalic neurogenesis in developing mouse embryos. It is shown here that NF-κB signaling is activated in neural progenitor cells in the dorsal telencephalon, as well as in post-mitotic neurons of the cortical plate throughout the period of neurogenesis. The possible role of NF-κB in neural progenitor cell proliferation and maintenance is discussed. </description><description>Au cours du développement neuronal, une grande variété de cellules neuronales et gliales sont produites à partir de cellules précurseurs neurales. Le contrôle de la transition de la phase proliférative vers la différenciation cellulaire, de même que la migration et l'intégration fonctionnelle finale à l'intérieur de circuits neuronaux sont des processus hautement complexes nécessitant des interactions complexes et étroitement contrôlées de divers facteurs extrinsèques et intrinsèques présents dans le système nerveux central en développement. Des perturbations d'un ou de plusieurs de ces processus peuvent entraîner des troubles graves du développement et du fonctionnement normal du cerveau. Il a été démontré que la voie de signalisation NF-kB est importante pour plusieurs fonctions cérébrales telles que la survie neuronale, la plasticité, l'apprentissage, la consolidation de la mémoire et la neurodégénérescence. Bien qu'il ait été récemment montré que la voie NF-kB est activé au cours du développement du cerveau antérieur, son éventuelle implication dans la neurogenèse n'est pas connue. Ce travail vise à caractériser le modèle de l'activation de la voie NF-kB cours de la neurogenèse télencéphalique d'embryons de souris en développement. Cette etude démontre que la signalisation NF-kB est activée dans les cellules progénitrices neurales du télencéphale dorsal, ainsi que dans les neurones post-mitotiques de la plaque corticale pendant toute la durée de la neurogenèse. Le rôle presumé de la voie NF-kB au cours de la prolifération et du maintient des cellules progénitrices neurales seront discutés.</description><creator>Al-Jehani, Hosam</creator><contributor>David Stewart Sinclair (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Stefano Stifani (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Activation of the NF-kB pathway during Neocortical Development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021k26t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z5023</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z709185q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Exhalation / Expiration (Expiration / Trépas), œuvre composée pour un ensemble à vent de trente-quatre instrumentistes, poursuit une série d'hommages musicaux par la compositrice à la mémoire de son père, Alexander Fol. La composition réunit différentes techniques musicales afin d'accomplir métaphoriquement un « mappage » où l'infection d'un corps en bonne santé subit une grave maladie, suivie progressivement par la mort de l'organisme. La durée de l'œuvre est 21 minutes et demie.La conception du matériau, notamment la forme, l'harmonie, le rythme et l'orchestration, inclut l'application d'une approche à la sémiotique musicale informée par l'Orphisme, doctrine philosophique et orale de la Thrace, ainsi que la recherche médicale sur des patients ayant le cancer en phase terminale. L'auteur définit deux types de signes musicaux, le type-événement et le type-processus, et décide sur une réalisation musicale de ces deux types aux niveaux formel et structurel. Dans la composition, les signes sont organisés comme symboles musicaux afin de décrire la transition graduelle entre le type de musique qui symbolise la santé – 'A' – et la musique qui symbolise la maladie – 'B', – le tout représenté par une collection d'occurrences et de traitement dominants de l'harmonie, du rythme et de l'orchestration.</description><description>Exhalation / Expiration, a composition for a wind ensemble of thirty-four players, continues a series of musical homages by the composer honouring her father, Alexander Fol. The composition unites different musical devices to accomplish a metaphorical mapping of the infection of a healthy body with a mortal sickness, followed by the organism's gradual demise. The work's duration is twenty-one-and-a-half minutes.The design of these materials, which incorporates the form, harmony, rhythm and orchestration, applies an approach to musical semiotics informed by the philosophical doctrine of Thracian Oral Orphism, as well as by medical research on terminally ill cancer patients. The author defines two types of musical signs, the event-type and the process-type, and decides upon a musical realization thereof at the formal and structural levels. In the composition, the signs are organized as musical symbols that portray the gradual transition between the types of music symbolizing health – 'A' – and sickness – 'B' – represented by types of harmonic, rhythmic and orchestrational treatment.</description><creator>Fol, Alexandra</creator><contributor>John Rea (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</subject><title>Exhalation/expiration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tt33h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z709185q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bz554</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La contribution précise de récompense et de motivation de la neurotransmission  de la dopamine (DA) n'est pas entièrement comprise. La meilleure hypothèse citée propose que la DA forme un trait d'union des effets agréables d'une variété de récompenses naturelles et narcotiques. Cette hypothèse « anhédoniste » a reçu l'appui de quelques modèles précliniques de récompense et de quelques études chez l'humain mettant la drogue en question. Cependant, l'évaluation directe du rôle de la DA sur la disposition et autres états subjectifs chez l'humain en santé a été principalement limitée à l'utilisation de drogues psychostimulantes, ce qui élève le niveau de neurotransmetteurs multiples en plus de la DA dans le cerveau.  La présente thèse comprend une étude qui examine l'effet d'une neurotransmission sélectivement plus élevée de la DA, produite par l'administration du précurseur immédiat de la DA, L-DOPA, chez des volontaires en santé. L-DOPA n'a modifié ni disposition ni autres états subjectifs. Ces résultats s'ajoutent à l'évidence la neurotransmission de DA n'influence pas directement la disposition chez l'humain en santé.</description><description>A large body of evidence indicates that dopamine (DA) neurotransmission regulates approach toward rewards and reward-related cues. The best-cited hypothesis proposes that DA accomplishes this by mediating the pleasurable effects of a variety of natural and drug rewards. This "anhedonia hypothesis" has received support from some pre-clinical models of reward and a few drug challenge studies in humans. However, direct assessment of DA's role in mood and other subjective states in healthy humans has been largely limited to the use of psychostimulant drugs, which elevate brain levels of multiple neurotransmitters in addition to DA. This thesis is comprised of one study which examined the effect of more selectively elevated DA neurotransmission, as produced by administration of the immediate DA precursor, L-DOPA, in healthy human volunteers. L-DOPA failed to alter mood and other subjective states. These results add to the evidence that DA neurotransmission does not directly influence mood in healthy humans.</description><creator>Liggins, John</creator><contributor>Marco Leyton (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Robert O Pihl (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Psychology - Physiological </subject><title>The involvement of dopamine neurotransmission in mood in humans: Administration of L-3,4-dihydroxyphenylalanine to healthy volunteers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fr03f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bz554</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j316k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les étudiants avec troubles d'apprentisages (TA) au niveau collégial vont souventindiquer que l'école est un défi car ils n'ont pas toujours les compétences nécessaire pour réussir à ce niveau. Ce mémoire examine comment les stratégies d'apprentissages stratégiques sont affecter par les services spécialisés constructivist pour les étudiants au niveau collégial avec TA. Au début de l'année scolaire les étudiants avec TA qui recevaient les services spécialisés utilisaient les stratégies pour la motivation et pour gérer le temps plus que les étudiants avec des TA qui ne recevaient pas les services spécialisés. Les étudiants avec les TA qui recevaient les services spécialisés n'ont pas utiliser les stratégies pour gérer l'anxieté différemment que les étudiants avec des TA qui ne recevaient pas les services spécialisés. Ni l'histoire des services spécialisés reçus, les TA, ou une combinaison des deux facteurs a été considérablement différent pour les trois domaines de stratégies (motivation, anxiété, gérer le temps). Les étudiants avec les TA qui recevaient des services spécialisés ont reçu des notes comparables aux étudiants sans TA qui ne recevaient pas des services spécialisés. L'utilisation des domaines de stratégies n'ont pas changé considérablement dès le début de l'année scolaire.</description><description>College students with learning disabilitities (LDs) find college especially challenging as they often do not have the skills necessary to be successful in higher education. This thesis examined how strategic learning strategies are affected by constructivist support services for postsecondary students with LDs studying at a postsecondary institution. At Time 1 students with LDs who received support used motivation and time management strategies significantly more than students with LDs who did not receive support. Students with LDs who received support did not differ significantly in their use of anxiety strategies from students with LDs who did not receive support. Neither support history, presence of a LD nor an interaction of support and LD were significant for any of the three areas of strategy use (motivation, anxiety and time management) at Time 1. Students with LDs who received support received grades comparable to their peers without LDs and no support. The strategy use of students with LDs who received support did not change significantly from Time 1 to Time 2.</description><creator>Weil, Brigitte</creator><contributor>Ingrid Sladeczek (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Education - Higher</subject><title>Supporting college students with learning disabilities to become strategic learners</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430882t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j316k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pv55c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Abstract</description><description>A hallmark of HIV infection is the gradual decline in CD4 T cells leading to AIDS and failure of the immune system. Depletion of CD4 T cells has been attributed to direct viral cytopathogenicity and hyperimmune activation which all lead to accelerated apoptosis. More recently, impaired thymic function has been shown to contribute to the numerical decline of CD4 T cells. The thymus is the primary source of de novo T cells that bear a broadly diverse T cell receptor (TCR) repertoire. In adults, the thymus produces every day approximately 50 million new T cells termed recent thymic emigrants (RTEs). Following their exit from the thymus, RTEs join the naive T cell compartment and upon antigen encounter differentiate into effector and memory T cells.</description><creator>Zeidan, Joumana</creator><contributor>Amit Bar-Or (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Rafick-Pierre Sekaly (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Virology</subject><title>Novel findings on the impact of HIV infection: Interplay between T cell development and peripheral T cell homeostasis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2774064d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pv55c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935714c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La majorité des problèmes de croissance dans les pays en développement ont lieu au cours des deux premières années de la vie, c'est pourquoi il existe un besoin d'identifier les interventions améliorant la croissance infantile et qui ciblent les communautés vulnérables  durant cette période critique. L'objectif principal de cette recherche était d'évaluer l'efficacité d'une intervention communautaire de Deviance Positive (DP)/ foyer du nourrison et du jeune enfant afin d'améliorer la croissance et la nutrition des nourrissons et des enfants en bas-âge dans les hautes terres équatoriennes. La premiere etude a été Afin avec des mères des communautés rurales des Andes équatoriales qui en 2008 avaient participé à l'intervention DP/foyer avec leurs enfants de 2-5 ans (n=168). Les pratiques d'alimentation du nourrisson et du jeune enfant et les prédicteurs du retard de croissance des communautés des hautes terres équatoriennes ont été évaluées pour guider le développement de la nouvelle intervention de 2009. Il a été nécessaire de développer une procédure pour ajuster les mesures anthropométriques pour le poids des nourrissons et des jeunes enfants (n=293) étant donné les températures faibles et les infrastructures limitées. Une étude avec conception non randomisée quasi-expérimentale a été utilisée pour comparer la croissance et la nutrition des nourrissons et des jeunes enfants au sein de 6 communautés d'intervention (n=80) à ceux des 9 communautés sans intervention (n=184). Dans le groupe d'intervention, les mères et leurs enfants agés de moins de 2 ans ont participé à l'intervention communautaire participative DP/Foyer de 12 jours. Les données démographiques, nutritionnelles et anthropométriques ont été récoltées au début et après 6 mois de suivi. Les résultats étaient les suivants: 1) selon les mères, leur estime de soi et le soutien social se sont améliorés grâce à l'intervention de 2008, mais elles ont donné plus d'importance aux changements sociaux qu'une amélioration de la croissance. 2). Au début de l'étude 56.2% de la populatin avaient un retard de croissance. Un âge plus élevé, des infections respiratoires et le sexe masculin étaient des prédicteurs d'un score Z du rapport 'Taille pour Age' plus faible alors que le début précoce de l'allaitement maternel, un statut socio-économique plus élevé, la consommation d'aliments riches en fer et une densité élevée en protéines étaient des éléments protecteurs. 3) Le modèle a montré que jusqu'à 24% des enfants avaient été classés en score Z du rapport 'Poids pour l'Age' et 13% pour le score Z du rapport 'Poids pour Taille' lorsque le poids des vêtements avait été ajusté. 4) Six mois après l'intervention de 2009, les mères avaient 1.6 à 5.7 fois plus de chances de nourrir leurs enfants avec des aliments promus par l'intervention que les mères du groupe de comparaison (p &lt; 0.05). Au cours du suivi, les enfants du groupe d'intervention consommaient plus de fer, de zinc, de vitamine A, de protéines et d'énergie, lorsque les covariantes ont été controlées (p &lt; 0.05). Les enfants du groupe d'intervention avaient une plus grande amélioration du score Z  du rapport 'Poids pour Age ' (aβ=0.16; 95% CI: 0.01, 0.32), mais pas du score Z du rapport 'Taille pour Age' (aβ= 0.00; 95% CI: -0.21, 0.17). L'intervention a été bénéfique en éliminant le risque d'insuffisance pondérale sévère (aOR=0.00; 95% CI: 0.00, 0.08). Les mères  de l'Equateur rural ont amélioré le régime alimentaire et le poids de leurs enfants grâce au soutien par les pairs, aux connaissances autochtones et à leurs aliments locaux, mais ne pouvaient pas améliorer la croissance linéaire. Le soutien des groupes de mères à travers des interventions communautaires de Deviance Positive/Foyer est un moyen efficace pour réduire la charge globale de l'insuffisance pondérale des nourrissons et des jeunes enfants.</description><description>Most growth faltering in developing countries occurs in the first two years of life; therefore, there is a need to identify interventions for vulnerable communities which improve child growth during this critical period. The purpose of this research was to evaluate the effectiveness of a community-based Positive Deviance (PD)/hearth infant and young child feeding intervention to improve growth and nutrition in infants and young children in the Ecuadorian highlands. The first study was with experiences of mothers in rural communities in the Ecuadorian Andes who had previously (2008) participated in a PD/hearth intervention (n=168). Infant and young child feeding practices and predictors of stunting in the Ecuadorian highlands communities were assessed to guide the development of the 2009 intervention. In this cold environment with limited health infrastructure, it was necessary to develop a procedure for adjusting anthropometric measures for clothing weight of infants and young children (n=293).  This study used a quasi-experimental non-randomized study design to compare growth and diet of infants and young children in six intervention communities (n=80) to those in nine non-intervention communities (n=184).  Intervention mothers and their children participated in a 12-day PD/hearth nutrition intervention. Demographic, nutritional, and anthropometric data were collected at baseline and at six months follow-up. The results were as follows. 1) Mothers credited the 2008 intervention with increasing self-esteem and social support, yet greater importance was placed on social changes than on growth. 2) Stunting was found in 56.2% of the study population at baseline. Older age, respiratory infections, and being male were predictors of lower height-for-age z-score (HAZ), whereas early initiation of breastfeeding, higher socioeconomic status, consumption of iron-rich foods, and higher dietary protein density were protective. 3) Modeling showed that without adjusting for clothing weight 24% of children were misclassified for weight-for-age z-score (WAZ), and 13% for weight-for-height z-score (WHZ).  4) Six months after the 2009 intervention, participants were 1.6 to 5.7 times more likely than comparison children to consume the foods promoted in the intervention. Intervention children consumed more iron, zinc, vitamin A, protein, and energy (p &lt; 0.05). Compared to non-intervention children, intervention children had greater improvement in WAZ (β=0.16; 95% CI: 0.01, 0.32), but not HAZ (β= 0.00; 95% CI: -0.21, 0.17). The intervention was beneficial in eliminating the risk of severe underweight (OR=0.00; 95% CI: 0.00, 0.08). In rural Ecuador, mothers improved their children's diet and weight with peer support, indigenous knowledge, and local foods. Supporting mothers' groups through community PD/hearth nutrition interventions is an effective way to reduce the global burden of underweight in infants and young children.</description><creator>Roche, Marion</creator><contributor>Grace Marquis (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Harriet V Kuhnlein (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>A community-based positive deviance/hearth intervention to improve infant and young child nutrition in the Ecuadorian Andes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666897p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935714c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53k221s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'hippocampe est une des structures clés du cerveau dans les processus de mémorisation. Les altérations du fonctionnement de cette structure chez les patients schizophrènes pourraient expliquer en partie les troubles cognitifs associés à la maladie. Même si les causes exactes de la schizophrénie font encore l'objet de nombreux débats, plusieurs études ont pu mettre en évidence une augmentation de l'incidence de cette maladie chez les enfants des mères exposées à une infection bactérienne ou virale durant la grossesse. Afin de mieux comprendre les changements intervenant au sein des réseaux hippocampiques lors de la schizophrénie, nous avons utilisé un modèle d'infection prénatale chez le rongeur. Ce modèle animal, largement validé, a permis de caractériser les changements anatomiques survenant dans l'hippocampe. Cependant, soulignons qu'aucune étude n'a pour le moment étudié les altérations possibles de l'activité électrophysiologique, tant au niveau de la synapse que du réseau, occasionnées dans l'hippocampe par une infection prénatale. La caractérisation de ces altérations nous permettra par conséquent de mieux saisir d'une part les changements d'activité observés dans l'hippocampe suite à une infection prénatale et de cerner d'autre part leurs rôles possibles dans les troubles comportementaux communément décrits dans la schizophrénie.La première partie de notre étude porte ainsi sur les altérations de la transmission synaptique dans l'hippocampe de jeunes rats provenant de mères exposées à une infection bactérienne (en utilisant le lipopolysacharide ou LPS comme modèle d'infection) vers la fin de la grossesse, soit le quinzième et seizième jours de gestation chez le rat. Dans ce modèle d'infection prénatale, nous avons observé une diminution de la transmission excitatrice vers l'aire CA1 de l'hippocampe (altérations présynaptique) accompagnée d'une augmentation compensatoire au niveau postsynaptique. Ces changements semblent spécifiques à l'aire CA1 puisqu'ils ne sont pas présents dans l'aire CA3 ou le gyrus dentelé. Finalement, nous avons également mis en évidence une augmentation de l'excitabilité des cellules pyramidales de l'aire CA1.Ces résultats couplés aux nombreuses études mettant en évidence une perturbation de la transmission excitatrice et inhibitrice dans l'hippocampe suite à une infection prénatale, suggèrent que l'activité de réseau de l'hippocampe pourrait être altérée. Afin de tester cette hypothèse, nous avons étudié l'effet d'une infection prénatale au poly I:C sur l'activité oscillatoire de l'hippocampe et ce en utilisant une nouvelle approche expérimentale récemment développée au laboratoire, l'hippocampe intact isolé in vitro. Bien qu'aucune altération des rythmes thêta et gamma nà été observée, nous avons mis en évidence une plus grande sensibilité du rythme thêta aux récepteurs NMDA (N-methyl D-aspartate) exclusivement dans le subiculum. Dans cette region de l'hippocampe nous avons de plus observé une augmentation du couplage des oscillations gamma et theta. En conclusion, l'infection prénatale induit des changements neurodéveloppementaux qui affectent profondément la transmission synaptique et l'activité de réseau de façon précoce dans l'hippocampe. Ces changements, spécifiques au subiculum et à l'aire CA1, pourraient fortement compromettre le transfert d'information entre l'hippocampe et différentes structures corticales et sous-corticales et pourraient de ce fait contribuer aux déficits cognitifs observés dans la schizophrénie.</description><description>The hippocampus, which plays a crucial role in cognitive processes, is a brain region that has been repeatedly shown to be disrupted in schizophrenia, which likely contributes to some of the cognitive impairments associated with the disease. Although the aetiology of schizophrenia remains unknown, mounting evidence from epidemiological studies have implicated exposure to infection during pregnancy as a potent risk factor for schizophrenia in the offspring. Using rodent models to mimic maternal infection during gestation, we sought to examine in the offspring changes that may be occurring in the hippocampus. While anatomical and behavioural alterations have been reported in the hippocampus in rodent models of prenatal maternal infection, it remains unknown as to how hippocampal synaptic transmission is affected. Understanding what is occurring at the synaptic level will help to understand the consequences of maternal infection during pregnancy on hippocampal function in the offspring.Study 1 investigated synaptic transmission in the hippocampus of the juvenile offspring from rat mothers that were exposed to infection near-term. Lipopolysaccharide (LPS) was used to mimic bacterial infection and was administered to rats on embryonic days 15 and 16. A significantly attenuated presynaptic excitatory input and a compensatory increase in transmission postsynaptically were uncovered in the CA1 region after prenatal maternal infection. Although synaptic transmission was assessed in the dentate gyrus and CA3 areas, the marked changes were only found in CA1, an important hippocampal output region. In addition, prenatal maternal infection led to heightened excitability of CA1 pyramidal cells.Based on the findings from Study 1 and the existing reports suggesting that excitatory and inhibitory synaptic transmission may be affected by prenatal maternal infection, Study 2 examined whether network-generated activity in the hippocampus might also be disrupted. Using a mouse model of prenatal maternal infection with polyriboinosinic:polyribocytidilic acid (poly I:C), we measured spontaneously generated oscillations in areas CA3, CA1 and the subiculum from in vitro, whole hippocampal preparations of the juvenile offspring. Although no significant alterations in theta and gamma rhythms were found in the 3 hippocampal subfields, a greater contribution of NMDA (N-methyl D-aspartate) transmission to the generation of theta oscillations was uncovered exclusively in the subiculum, a major output of the hippocampus. Furthermore, the modulation of gamma amplitudes by the underlying theta was abnormally greater in the subiculum after prenatal maternal poly I:C treatment. Taken together, neurodevelopmental disruption triggered by prenatal maternal infection can have profound effects on hippocampal synaptic transmission and hippocampal networks that are already evident in early life. We revealed changes exclusively occurring in the CA1 and subiculum, suggesting that the outflow of information from the hippocampus is severely disrupted. These results strongly indicate that prenatal maternal infection leads to impaired information processing in the hippocampus that probably contributes to the cognitive deficits in schizophrenia.</description><creator>Lowe, Germaine</creator><contributor>Sylvain Williams (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Prenatal maternal infection and synaptic transmission in the hippocampus: from single cells to neural networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204320d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k221s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dt537</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette dissertation se compose de trois modèles originaux concernant des aspets variés du problème de détermination du niveau de l'application des droits de propriété dans des contextes différents. Le premier chapitre est un aperçu de la littérature sur l'importance de la propriété et des droits de propriété, depuis le régime physiocratique jusquà la littérature récente sur différents aspects des droits de propriété imparfaits. Le deuxième chapitre considère un modèle aux générations imbriquées dans lequel les ménages accumulent de la richesse and influencent le processus de détermination du régime optimal de droits de propriété, en maximisant leur bien-être par rapport au taux de taxation qui nance l'application des droits de propriété. On étudie le cas des ménages homogènes ainsi que le cas des ménages hétérogènes. On calcule le niveau de revenue à l'équilibre stationnaire, et détermine la stabilité de l'équilibre. On démontre que le niveau optimal de l'application des droits de propriété évolu au fil de temps et dépend des facteurs tels que le taux d'actualisation et le partage de capital dans le revenu. Le troisième chapitre utilise l'approache principal-agent pour modéliser un joint venture dans le quel une entreprise multinationale transfère la technologie à une entreprise locale. Celle-ci a l'intérêt d'annuler le contrat de joint venture quand elle a accumulé un savoir suffisant, pour devenir un monopole. L'entreprise multinationale, anticipant l'incitation à la defection de son partenaire, décide de transférer un niveau réduit de technologie dans l'objectif de préempter la défection, en tenant compte du taux de compensation dans le cas de défection. Le niveau optimal de la protection des droits de propriété, représenté par le taux optimal de compensation, est déterminé par la maximisation du bien-être du pays domestique. On montre que le taux optimal de compensation est plus élevé dans le cas où l'output est vendu au marché domestique que dans le cas où est destiné au marché étranger. Le quatrième chapitre cherche la fondation pour la détermination de la longueur optimale des brevets de l'industrie pharmaceutique. On étudie un modèle Nord-Sud, dans lequel une entreprise du Nord effectue de la recherche et les entreprises du Sud font la rétro-ingénierie. S'il n'y a pas d'obstacles juridiques, les entreprises du Sud produisent des antibiotiques répliqués, ce qui érode le pouvoir de monopole de l'entreprise du Nord. Cela n'encourage pas la recherche dans le pays Nord. Par contre, la prohibition de la rétro-ingénierie implique des prix élevés du monopole. La longeur optimale des brevets balances les deux forces opposantes. Pour les horizons de temps raisonables, on montre que la longeur optimale des brevets est une fonction croissante du paramètre de coût et une fonction décroissante du paramètre de mark-up des coûts de production dans le pays Sud.</description><description>This dissertation formulates and analyzes three original models dealing with aspects of optimal property rights protection, in varying contexts. Chaper 1 is a survey of the literature on the importance of property and property rights in economic thought beginning from the Physiocratic regime up to the recent literature which deals with implications of imperfect property rights. Chapter 2 considers an overlapping generations model where households accumulate wealth and inuence the political process of determing the optimal property rights regime through maximization of the household welfare function with respect to the tax rate which yields revenue to nance the cost of enforcement of property rights. Both the cases of homogeneous and heterogeneous households are considered. The long run equilibrium levels of income are calculated and stability properties analyzed. It is shown that the optimally determined levels of property rights enforcement evolves over time, and depends on a number of factors, such as the discount rate and the share of capital in output. Chapter 3 uses a principal-agent approach to model a joint venture, where a multinational rm transfers technological knowledge to a local rm during their partnership. The local firm may defect on acquiring adequate knowledge to operate as a monopolist. Anticipating this, the multinational chooses to transfer an amount of technology just sufficient to pre-empt defection, given the rate of compensation earned. The optimal level of enforcement of property rights, represented by the optimal rate of compensation, is determined by maximizing the social welfare of the home country. It is found that the optimal rate of compensation is higher when the goods are produced solely for the home market than in the case where the goods are produced only for the export market. Chapter 4 finds a basis for the determination of an optimal patent length in the pharmaceutical industry, in a North South model, where the Northundertakes R&amp;D and the South carries out reverse engineering. In absence of a legal barrier, the Southern rms can produce replicated antibiotics that erode the monopoly power of the Northern rm. This works against the Norths R&amp;D incentives. However, a ban on reverse engineering implies the prevalence of high Northern monopoly prices. An optimal patent length must balance the two opposing forces. It is demonstrated that, for plausible lengths of the Souths planning horizon, the optimal patent length varies positively with the R&amp;D cost parameter and negatively with the parameter for production cost mark-up of the South.</description><creator>Sen Choudhury, Eesha</creator><contributor>Ngo Van Long (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Economics - Theory </subject><title>Three essays on the optimal degree of enforcement of property rights:determination and impact</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547w57t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dt537</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80j075c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> La voie de signalisation EGFR/Ras/MAPK est impliquée dans la régulation de la prolifération cellulaire, la migration et l'apoptose. Les mutations qui activent l'EGFR ou les composants qui sont en aval dans la voie de signalisation ainsi que la perte d'un régulateur négatif de l'EGFR / Ras / MAPK ont été impliquées dans le cancer. L'endocytose et le trafic de l'EGFR vers le lysosome est un important mécanisme de régulation négative du signal. La GTPase Rab7 régule le trafic vésiculaire et la dégradation de l'EGFR qui est un mécanisme important d'atténuation du signal. Toutefois, les effets de Rab7 sur la voie de signalisation EGFR/Ras/MAPK ne sont pas encore connus. La voie de signalisation EGFR/Ras/MAPK qui est très conservée chez C. elegans, est responsable pour la spécification de l'identité cellulaire de la vulve.  Nous avons constaté que RAB-7 antagonise la signalisation de LET-23 EGFR pendant l'induction vulvaire, ce qui suggère un rôle possible de Rab7 comme un suppresseur de tumeur chez les mammifères. Ici, je montre que la perte de fonction du mutant de rab-7, rab-7(ok511), régule la localisation du récepteur LET-23 dans les cellules précurseurs vulvaires (CPV). En outre, mes données suggèrent que le récepteur LET-23 (comparable au EGFR chez les mammifères) transitent des corps multivésiculaires (CMVs) vers les lysosomes puisque la réduction d'expression des components du complexe ESCRT-0 et ESCRT-I, HGRS-1 et VPS-28, par ARN interférence supprime la sévérité du phénotype Vul de lin-2(e1309), la mutation qui provoque une mauvaise localisation du LET-23.  J'ai mené un projet pilote génétique pour trouver les suppresseurs du phénotype Vul de lin-2(1309) afin d'identifier d'autres gènes qui pourraient aussi réguler le trafic vésiculaire du récepteur LET-23 EGFR. Deux suppresseurs, vh4 et vh22, ont été identifiés. Ils montrent un phénotype de létalité embryonnaire partiel et d'autres phénotypes suggérant un défaut du trafic vésiculaire. J'ai cartographié vh4 et vh22 à des régions distinctes du chromosome I dépourvues de régulateurs du récepteur LET-23 EGFR identifiés précédemment, ce qui suggère que ses mutations sont des nouveaux régulateurs de la voie de signalisation de l'EGFR. En outre, vh4 peut améliorer le phénotype Muv du let-60(n1046), la mutation qui active Ras en permanence, ce qui implique vh4 comme un régulateur négatif de l'EGFR/Ras/MAPK. Des expériences d'ARN interférence ainsi que de la complémentation génétique ont identifié AGEF-1, une Arf1-GEF, comme un candidat potentiel pour vh4. Bien que je n'ai pas pu trouver une mutation correspondante au gène agef-1, je trouve que les mutants vh4 ont des phénotypes cohérente d'un défaut dans une voie de sécrétion et affectant AGEF-1.  En conclusion, vh4 et vh22 sont éventuellement des mutations de nouveaux régulateurs négatifs de la voie de signalisation de EGFR/Ras/MAPK qui moduleraient aussi le trafic vésiculaire du récepteur LET-23 EGFR.</description><description> Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor (EGFR)/Ras/Mitogen Activated Protein Kinase (MAPK) signaling is involved in regulation of cell proliferation, migration and apoptosis. Activating mutations in EGFR or downstream components of the signaling pathway as well as a loss of a negative regulator of EGFR/Ras/MAPK signaling have been implicated in cancer.  EGFR endocytosis and trafficking to the lysosome is an important mechanism of signal downregulation. A small GTPase Rab7 regulates EGFR trafficking and degradation, however its effects on signaling are not known.  In C. elegans a highly conserved EGFR/Ras/MAPK signaling pathway is required for vulval cell fate specification. We found that RAB-7 antagonizes LET-23 EGFR signaling during vulval induction suggesting a possible role as a tumor suppressor in mammals. Here I show that a rab-7(ok511) deletion mutant regulates LET-23 localization in the Vulval Precursor Cells (VPCs). Additionally, my data suggest that LET-23 EGFR, similar to mammalian EGFR, traffics through multivesicular bodies (MVBs) en route to lysosome as RNAi knock-down of ESCRT-0 and –I components, HGRS-1 and VPS-28, can suppress the severity of the Vulvaless (Vul) phenotype of a LET-23 mislocalization mutant lin-2(e1309). To identify additional genes that might regulate LET-23 EGFR trafficking and signaling, I conducted a pilot forward genetic screen for suppressors of the lin-2(e1309) Vul phenotype. I identified two suppressor mutants, vh4 and vh22, that are partial embryonic lethal and display phenotypes suggestive of vesicular trafficking defects. I mapped vh4 and vh22 to distinct regions of chromosome I, devoid of previously identified regulators of LET-23 EGFR signaling, suggesting that they are mutations in novel regulators. Additionally, vh4 can enhance the Multivulva (Muv) phenotype of a Ras gain-of-function mutant let-60(n1046) further implicating vh4 as a negative regulator of EGFR/Ras/MAPK signaling. RNAi and genetic complementation data identified AGEF-1, an Arf-GEF, as a potential candidate for vh4. Although I have been unable to identify a corresponding mutation in agef-1, I find that vh4 mutants have phenotypes consistent of a defect in a secretory pathway and affecting AGEF-1 activity. Thus, vh4 and vh22 might represent mutations in novel negative regulators of LET-23 EGFR signaling and possibly regulate trafficking of the receptor. </description><creator>Skorobogata, Olga</creator><contributor>Christian Rocheleau (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>A screen for endocytic regulators of epidermal growth factor receptor signaling in «Caenorhabditis elegans»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881r226.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80j075c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848v51h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tandis que la plupart des études  sur l'Afrique de l'ouest ont concentré sur l'étendu et le caractère de l'Islam soufi, il y a eu une transformation dramatique récente dans son influence politique et sociale. Les forces de la globalisation et de changement social et  économique ont abouti dans des transformations parallèles en Afrique de l'ouest et ailleurs et partout dans le monde islamique. Dans le Ghana du nord, ou l'Islam soufi a été longtemps la forme dominante de la pratique religieuse et la politique, un nouveau forme de l'Islam plus orthodoxe a surgi qui n'a pas encore reçu suffisamment d'attention,. Une explication pour cette désaccord est le fait que l'étude de l'Islam africain a été dominé par les notions orientalistes et réductives d'un Islam africain statique, dépourvu d'histoire et décontextualisé des changements sociales et économiques importantes.qui ont eu un impact sur l'Afrique de l'ouest. En plus, le biais envers l'étude de l'Islam politique dans le Moyen Orient et l'Asie du sud a eu pour résultat que de rares chercheurs ont abordés les transformations importantes dans l'Islam ouest-africain qui sont enracinées localement mais liées sans doute  au monde islamique en générale.    Ma thèse vise à combler cette lacune dans la littérature sur le sujet par une examen des facteurs qui ont contribué au déclin de la soufisme et l'essor d'une vision nouvelle Wahhabie de l'islamisation dans deux domaines clefs -- l'éducation et la politique --  au niveau de l'état.Dans le Ghana du nord, les soufis ont traditionnellement représenté la classe religieuse ou dominante, comme ailleurs dans l'Afrique musulmane. Néanmoins, pendant les trois dernières décades, il y avait une réduction distincte dans le pouvoir politique et l'influence sociale du soufisme et une influence élargie correspondante sur la part de l'Islam Wahhabi. Malgré la manque d'attention, le soufisme en Ghana du nord a été éclipse par ce dernier, particulièrement dans les domaines de l'éducation et  la politique – les deux champs d'intérêt capital pour le présent travail.Quels sont donc les facteurs qui peuvent expliquer cette transformation évidente dans le Ghana du nord? Ceci est la question de recherche principale de la présente thèse. Afin de répondre à la question, j'ai entrepris des investigations approfondies sur le terrain en Ghana du nord pour juger entre un bon nombre d'explications alternatives. Cela m'a permis d'analyser empiriquement les raisons et les concours de facteurs qui ont mené à cette transformation religieuse et sociale surprenante en Ghana du nord. Naturellement, ces explications ne s'exclurent pas forcément. Néanmoins, ma thèse  scrute  l'évidence pour chaque ligne d'argument et fait un choix entre les facteurs les plus  importants qui ont contribué à la montée du « nouveau Islam » en Ghana du nord. Je soutiens que l'ascension du Wahhabisme là bas est en grande partie le résultat de changements politiques et socio-économiques qui sont spécifiques au lieu. C'est-à-dire, tout en admettant le rôle de liens internationaux dans la popularité courante de l'activisme Wahhabie, je montre dans ce mémoire que le rôle de la politique des partis et la contestation électorale dans les décades récentes étaient déterminants au succès du Wahhabisme en Ghana du nord. De plus, en bâtissant sur des recherches originales entreprises sur le terrain, je montre empiriquement que cette tendance vers une notion plus orthodoxe d'identification islamique et de pratique politique est décisivement enraciné dans les manières dans lesquelles les adeptes du Wahhabisme ont influencé, voire dominé, les institutions éducatrices nouvelles dans le Ghana du nord</description><description>While most studies of Islam in West Africa have focused on the spread and nature of Sufi Islam, there has been a recent dramatic transformation in the political and social influence of Sufi Islam long-believed to characterize "African Islam." The forces of globalization and social and economic changes in West Africa and beyond have resulted in parallel transformations across the Islamic world. In northern Ghana, where Sufi Islam has long been the dominant form of religious practice and politics, the advent of a new, more orthodox, form of Islamicization has taken place that has not yet been adequately studied. One reason for this discrepancy is the fact that the study of Islam in Africa has been dominated by Orientalist and reductive notions of a static form of "Islam" in Africa shorn of any history and decontextualized from the important social and economic changes that have impacted West Africa. Moreover, the bias towards the study of political Islam in the Middle East and South Asia has meant that few scholars have focused on the important transformations in West African Islam that are locally rooted, but clearly linked to the global world of Islam. My thesis seeks to make up for the dearth in the literature on the topic by examining some of the factors that have contributed to the decline of Sufism and the rise of a new Wahhabist version of Islamicization in two key fields: education and politics at the level of the state. In northern Ghana, Sufis have traditionally represented the dominant religious and political class, similar to many other regions in Muslim Africa. However, during the last three decades, there has been a distinct transformation in the political power and social influence of Sufism and an increasing influence of the Wahhabist forms of Islam. While it has not been adequately analyzed, Sufism in northern Ghana has been eclipsed by the conservative, Wahhabist influence in the fields of education and politics which represent the two arenas of inquiry in my research. What then are the factors that can account for this clear transformation of Islam in northern Ghana? This is the primary research question of this thesis. In order to answer this question, I conducted extensive research in northern Ghana in order to adjudicate between a number of alternative explanations with the objective of analyzing empirically the reasons, and combinations of factors, that have led to this seemingly surprising religious and social transformation in northern Ghana. Naturally, these alternative explanations do not need to be mutually exclusive. However, my thesis explores the evidence for each line of argument, and prioritizes some of the most important factors that contributed to the rise of the "new Islam" in Northern Ghana. I argue that the rise of Wahha&gt;bism in northern Ghana is in great part a result of political and socio-economic changes that are locally specific. That is, while I acknowledge the role of international linkages in the current popularity in Wahhabist activism, I demonstrate in this work that the role of political party politics and electoral contestation in recent decades has played a great role in the recent success of Wahha&gt;bism in northern Ghana. Moreover, building on original field research, I further show empirically that this emerging trend of a more orthodox notion of Islamic identification and political practice is crucially rooted in the ways in which adherents of Wahha&gt;bism have influenced and often dominated new and influential educational institutions in northern Ghana. </description><creator>Ibrahim, Mohammad Saani</creator><contributor>Khalid Medani (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Religion - Religion General</subject><title>The decline of Sufism and the rise of a new Islam: some factors contributing to the political and social ascendancy of Wahhabist Islam in Northern Ghana</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t54b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848v51h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085q212</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work undertaken in this dissertation was motivated by the pressing need to enlighten the intricate relationship between cerebral metabolic and haemodynamic changes underlying blood oxygenation level-dependent (BOLD) signals, all three widely employed in functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) as surrogate markers of neuronal activity. To this end, a methodology was developed to improve the calibration procedure essential to a BOLD biophysical model in quantifying cerebral metabolic rate of oxygen (CMRO2) responses to brain activation. A computerized gas delivery and rebreathing circuit was implemented in the magnetic resonance (MR) environment of a 3 T scanner to achieve precise and independent manipulation of end-tidal (i.e., end-exhaled) partial pressures in oxygen and carbon dioxide (PETO2 and PETCO2). The improvement in cerebrovascular responses (CVR) attainable via end-tidal control was investigated in a comparative fMRI study involving healthy young adults where the novel system was applied along side the traditional hypercapnic (HC) calibration technique of fixed increases in inspired concentration of carbon dioxide (FICO2) via a nonrebreathing face mask. Rapid near square-wave changes in PETCO2 and constrained PETO2 (i.e., baseline iso-oxic state) translated to reduced methodological and physiological uncertainties for greater predictability and stability in the induced BOLD and cerebral blood flow (CBF) signals. These findings indicated that while the common fixed inspired maneuver suffers from inconsistencies between administered gas concentrations and measured MR signal responses, prospective end-tidal targeting generates precise iso-oxic HC stimulation, invaluable in the regulation of cerebral haemodynamics in BOLD calibrated fMRI studies. Based on the progress made with the new modality, the subsequent study aimed at demonstrating the reduction of uncertainties in the calibration constant (M) achievable under the fine control of graded iso-oxic HC as well as isocapnic (i.e., baseline PETCO2) hyperoxic (HO) challenges. The results illustrated impressively smaller M-value variability than typically reported under the fixed inspired methods (FICO2 and FIO2, respectively), with HO showing a factor of 0.3-0.5 further improvement over HC, suggesting the appropriateness of this alternate procedure for increased precision of per-subject and per-brain-region calibration. Finally, the last manuscript examined and established that diminished M-variability translates to more accurate estimations of CMRO2 changes in the activated visual and sensorimotor cortices. Together, the performed studies represent the first experimental demonstration that rigorous prospective end-tidal targeting and HO challenges, both, independently, provide remarkably reduced variability in estimates of M, CMRO2 and CMRO2-CBF coupling, vital in diminishing biases currently encountered in the field of quantitative BOLD calibrated fMRI.</description><description>Le travail entrepris dans cette dissertation a été motivé par la nécessité d'éclaircir les relations complexes entre les changements métaboliques et hémodynamiques cérébraux sous-jacents à l'effet BOLD (signal qui dépend du taux d'oxygénation sanguin), les trois étant fréquemment employés en imagerie par résonance magnétique fonctionnelle (IRMf) comme marqueurs d'activité neuronale. À cette fin, une méthodologie a été développée pour améliorer la procédure de calibration essentielle à un modèle BOLD biophysique pour estimer la consommation métabolique cérébrale en oxygène (CMRO2) en réponse à l'activité neuronale. Un système automatisé d'apport de gaz couplé d'un circuit de réinspiration ont été installés dans l'environnement d'un appareil de résonance magnétique (RM) de 3 T afin de permettre une manipulation précise et indépendente des pressions partielles en oxygène et dioxide de carbone en fin d'expiration (PETO2 et PETCO2). L'amélioration des réponses cérébrovasculaires (RCV) réalisable par ce contrôle de pression a été examinée lors d'une étude d'IRMf sur de jeunes adultes sains en comparant le nouveau système à la technique traditionnelle de calibration hypercapnique (HC), consistant en des augmentations fixes de concentration inspirée en dioxide de carbone (FICO2) par l'entremise d'un masque facial ne permettant pas la réinspiration. En offrant des transitions rapides entre niveaux de PETCO2, tout en gardant la PETO2 constante (i.e., état de référence iso-oxique), le nouveau système a réduit les incertitudes méthodologiques ainsi que physiologiques, engendrant une prévisibilité et une stabilité accrue des signaux produits en BOLD et en débit sanguin cérébral (CBF). Ces conclusions indiquent que, tandis que la manoeuvre commune d'inspiration fixe souffre de désaccord entre les concentrations de gaz administrées et les réponses de signaux RM mesurées, le ciblage en perspective de fin d'expiration génère une stimulation précise en HC iso-oxique, de valeur inappréciable dans la régulation hémodynamique cérébrale employée par les études d'IRMf-BOLD calibrées. En employant les progrès réalisés à travers la nouvelle modalité, l'étude ultérieure a visé à déterminer la réduction réalisable dans l'incertitude de la constante de calibration (M) par le contrôle étroit d'un étalonnage de défis HC iso-oxiques ainsi qu'hyperoxiques (HO) isocapniques (i.e., états de références PETCO2). Les résultats ont démontré une impressionnante diminution de la variabilité des valeurs M par rapport à celles généralement rapportées sous les méthodes d'inspiration fixe (respectivement, FICO2 et FIO2), l'HO démontrant une amélioration additionnelle d'un facteur de 0.3-0.5 sur l'HC, suggérant la pertinence de cette procédure alternative pour une calibration par sujet et par region du cerveau de plus grande précision. Enfin, le dernier manuscrit a examiné et établi que l'atténuation de variabilité en M se traduit par des estimations plus précises des changements en CMRO2 dans les cortex visuel et sensorimoteur activés. Conjointement, les études réalisées représentent la première démonstration expérimentale que le ciblage rigoureux en perspective de fin d'expiration et les défis d'HO, à la fois, indépendamment, fournissent de remarquables réductions de variabilités dans l'estimation de M, CMRO2 et couplage CMRO2-CBF, vitales dans la diminution des biais actuellement rencontrés dans le domaine de l'IRMf-BOLD calibrée.</description><creator>Mark, Clarisse</creator><contributor>Gilbert Bruce Pike (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Biophysical modeling of human brain physiology in functional magnetic resonance imaging</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50h153z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085q212</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128g18m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Émanant de la recherche sur les deux economies Nord-Américaines, l'étude a investigué la composition de plusieurs projets de stimule fiscal de ces deux nations en réponse à la crise financière récente. Plus précisement, la recherche a visé les industries et secteurs économiques les plus affectés par les offres de stimule des gouvernments Canadien et Americain.  L'histoire des disputes précédentes à l'Organisation Mondiale du Commerce (OMC) du Canada et des États-Unis à été investigué afin de pouvior identifier des parallèles entre les bénéficiers des stimules contemporains et des tendances de protéctionisme chez ces deux economies dans le passé. Des preuves signifiantes de nouvelles sources de protection des industries nationaux ont été découvertes. Plusieures disputes dans l'OMC contre les industries Américaines qui ont réçu des niveau de stimule importantes pendants la crise ont soulignés le charactère protectioniste des project fiscaux proposés par ce pays. La dévaluation en valeur du Dollar Américain est presumée d'être la cause des réactions négatives internationals. Le stimule Canadien n'a pas crée une reaction internationale aussi marquée mais l'appréciation soulignée du Dollar Canadien pendants les deux dernières années est presumée d'être la raison de ce restraint des partenaires d'échange international du Canada. L'application des stimules économiques en conjunction avec une chute de valeur de la monnaie nationale n'a pas donc été acceptée au même niveau que les stimules seulements. Néamoins, et au centre de cette invéstigation, les projects de stimules fiscaux proposés part les deux économies ont été démasquées pour être des nouvelles sources de protéction pour des récipients historiquement protéctionistes.</description><description>Deriving from research of the two North American economies, the study investigated the nature and makeup of various stimulus policies enacted by the respective governments in response to the recent financial crisis. Specific attention was given to identifying the most significant industry recipients of stimulus offerings. World Trade Organization (WTO) dispute histories for the American and Canadian economies were investigated to find parallels between recent fiscal stimulus offerings amongst various industry beneficiaries and past instances of international trade disputes. Evidence of national stimulus packages being new sources of protection for traditional recipients was discovered. American WTO disputes targeting important stimulus recipients during the crisis period underlined international identification of that country's fiscal policies as protectionist in several economic sectors. Periods of American Dollar depreciation are thought to have exacerbated recent international reactions. No such marked parallel in recent disputes was found for Canada, though it is believed that clear Canadian Dollar appreciation over the past two years is the explanatory factor for this reserved international reaction. Stimulus in conjunction with depreciation, it would seem have been accepted to a lesser degree than stimulus alone. Central, however, is the finding that stimulus packages for both nations were found to focus on industries historically inclined on protectionism.</description><creator>Kozinski, Lukasz</creator><contributor>Mark R Brawley (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>Constant protectionism in the financial meltdown: are national stimulas packages new forms of protection alongside currency devaluation?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fs81s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128g18m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jq714</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study deals with the perspective of Indonesian parents of children with disabilities concerning the inclusion of their children in mainstream schools.  It explores the extent to which these parents believe in inclusion and what they identify as challenges and opportunities in the current inclusion of their children. Employing a case study approach, the main data for this qualitative  study was collected through  interview with seven parents of elementary school children with various disabilities in two cities in Indonesia, namely Jakarta and Yogyakarta.From their personal narratives, we learn that despite cultural differences, parents in Indonesia shared common opinions—with regard to various aspects of inclusion—with parents who lived in other parts of the world shown by previous studies. They, for instance, believed that the practices of inclusion cast positive impacts upon children's social and academic development. Parents also believe that inclusion is a better way to prepare children for the “real” world.     However, cultural differences   yielded different perspectives. Unlike previous studies, the Indonesian parents put greater emphasis on academic achievement instead of social ones.  Parents in Indonesia also demonstrate distinct ways in facilitating and supporting their children inclusion. These subjective perspectives of parents can perhaps be interpreted as a cultural production of inclusion.</description><description>Cette étude porte sur le point de vue des parents indonésiens d'enfants présentant un handicap au sujet de l'inclusion de leurs enfants dans des écoles ordinaires. Particulièrement, elle explore dans quelle mesure ces parents croient en ce concept et ce qu'ils identifient comme des défis et des opportunités dans l'inclusion actuelle de leurs enfants. Utilisant une approche de type étude de cas, les principales données de cette étude qualitative ont été recueillies par des entrevues dans des écoles primaires. Sept parents d' élèves ayant divers handicapés provenant de deux villes indonésiennes (e.g. Jakarta et Yogyakarta) ont participé.Nous apprenons dans leurs récits personnels que les parents en Indonésie partagent des opinions communes en ce qui concerne divers aspects de l'inclusion avec des parents provenant d'autres parties du monde, tel que montré dans des études précédentes. Par exemple, ils croient que les pratiques de l'inclusion produisent des effets positifs sur le développement social et scolaire de leurs enfants. Les parents estiment également que l'inclusion est de meilleure façon de préparer leurs enfants pour le monde «réel». Toutefois, certaines différences culturelles ont donné des perspectives dissemblables. Contrairement aux études antérieures, les parents indonésiens mettent davantage l'accent sur la réussite scolaire plutôt que sur la réussite sociale. Les participants ont aussi démontré une façon distincte pour faciliter et soutenir l'inclusion de leurs enfants. Les perspectives subjectives des parents peuvent être interprétées comme une production culturelle de l'inclusion.</description><creator>Mudzakir, Ro'fah</creator><contributor>Wendy Ann Thomson (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Claudia A Mitchell (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Social Sciences - Social Work</subject><title>Grateful voices and greater expectations: parents' perspective on inclusive education in Indonesia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vc82p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jq714</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289p10p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the ways in which the janissaries were part of civic society in early seventeenth-century Istanbul. It is based on the premise that investigation of the relationship between military cadres and civilians in Ottoman cities will reveal how hitherto unnoticed or underestimated aspects of urban life was during the early modern era. Making use of the Istanbul court records (şer'iye sicils), probate registers (tereke defters), conscription (eşkal defters) and salary registers (mevacib defters) of the janissaries, and registers of central state decrees (mühimme defters), the study focuses on the economic and social roles of the janissaries in Istanbul, as they entered into an enhanced urbanization process due to the social and political transformations of the Ottoman Empire in the seventeenth century.By studying various aspects of janissaries' lives this dissertation reveals the extent of their involvement in seventeenth century Istanbul's civic society. First, the methods of becoming a janissary are investigated and how these methods changed during the early seventeenth century are laid out. The profiles of janissaries in seventeenth-century Istanbul became much different than those of previous centuries as a result of changes in the conscription methods. These profiles are looked at more closely in the following sections of the dissertation. An examination of the janissaries' residential patterns in Istanbul reveals that the urban topography of the capital was directly influenced by an increase in the number of janissaries who were not living in the barracks and therefore were not segregated from the civic population. Solidarities and antagonisms that emerged thanks to the intertwinement of the janissaries with the city is another important concentration of this dissertation. A two-way movement between the janissaries and the artisans as well as solidarity among them emerged, which was reflected in janissary-led urban protests. These are all important dimensions of the newly emerged urban dynamics in Istanbul. Another one is the enhanced janissary solidarity through the economic bonding among the same regiment members through the strengthening of the regiment waqfs. This study reveals that the urbanization process of the janissaries in seventeenth-century Istanbul and their economic activities was a reflection of the general trends of increased capital accumulation and growth of a credit economy in Ottoman society.</description><description>La présente étude vise à examiner les moyens dans lesquelles les Janissaires faisaient partie de la société civile d'Istanbul au début du 17e siècle. Il se fonde sur la prémisse qu'une investigation des rapports entre cadres militaires et civiles dans les villes ottomanes révélera  des aspects de la vie urbaine, jusqu'ici inaperçus ou sous-estimés, dans la période moderne.  En exploitant  les documents de la cour de justice d'Istanbul (şer'iye sicils), les registres de testament (tereke defters), les registres de conscription (eşkal defters) et des salaires (mevacib defters) des Janissaires, et les registres des décrets de l'état centrale (mühimme defters), l'étude concentre sur les rôles économiques et sociales des Janissaires en Istanbul au moment où ils se sont embarqués dans un processus d'urbanisation rehaussée dû à la transformation sociale et politique de l'empire ottoman au 17e siècle.Par une étude des différents aspects de la vie des Janissaires, cette dissertation découvre l'étendu de leur implication dans la société civile d'Istanbul dans cette période. D'abord, il est question d'examiner les moyens de devenir janissaire et comment ces moyens ont changé dans les premières décades du 17e siècle. Les janissaires d'Istanbul ont subis en ce temps un grand changement de profil à la différence des siècles précédents suite aux changements dans les méthodes de conscription. Ces profils sont examinés de plus près dans les sections qui suivent. Une étude des dispositions résidentielles des Janissaires en Istanbul révèle que la topographie urbaine de la capitale a été directement liée au surcroit dans le nombre de Janissaires qui ne résidaient plus dans les casernes et qui n'étaient donc pas isolés de la population civile. Les solidarités et les antagonismes qui s'ensuivaient, dus aux entrelacements des Janissaires avec la ville, font un autre focus de cette dissertation. Le va-et-vient entre les janissaires et les artisans, ainsi que la solidarité qui se formait entre ces deux groupes, est reflété dans les protestations menées par les janissaires. Ce sont tous des dimensions signifiantes d'une nouvelle dynamique urbaine à Istanbul. Un autre, c'est la solidarité rehaussée parmi les Janissaires qui découlait de la rapprochement économique à l'intérieur des régiments causée par la renforcement des waqfs régimentaires.  L'étude révèle aussi que le processus d'urbanisation des Janissaires dans l'Istanbul du 17e siècle ainsi que leurs activités économiques reflétaient les tendances générales d'accumulation accrue du capital et l'essor d'une économie de crédit dans la société ottomane.</description><creator>Yilmaz, Gulay</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Victor Ostapchuk (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>History - Middle Eastern</subject><title>The economic and social roles of janissaries in a seventeenth century Ottoman city: the case of Istanbul</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924g83j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289p10p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q847z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les  équilibres de phase hydrate-liquide-vapeur pour les systèmes à gaz binaires formant des hydrates ont été étudiés. La règle des phases de Gibbs a été appliquée pour  établir le nombre de variables nécessaires pour préciser les systèmes d'intérêt ainsi qu'une variable supplémentaire intensive pour justifier l'équilibre. Une nouvelle méthode a été utilisée pour cartographier les plans d'équilibre pour l'azote+dioxyde de carbone+eau et du méthane+éthane+eau sous l'équilibre entre hydrate-liquide- vapeur. Pour le système d'azote+dioxyde de carbone+eau, il a été constaté que peu importe l'isotherme, la pression d'équilibre augmente avec la fraction molaire d'azote dans la phase vapeur. Le système de méthane+éthane+eau forme à la fois les hydrates de structure I et II, composant ainsi deux plans de phase. La transition de la structure I à la structure II a lieu autour d'un ratio de 3 à 1 de méthane à l'éthane en phase vapeur. Un diagramme 3D du système est présenté, contenant à la fois les sections de la structure I et II. Pour toute donnée d'isotherme et d'isobare dans les régions de structure I et II, il a été constaté que la pression d'équilibre a augmenté et la température d'équilibre a diminué, respectivement, avec l'augmentation de la fraction molaire d'éthane dans la phase gazeuse. La pression d'équilibre de la structure I se trouve à être moins sensible aux changements de température et de composition que la structure II.La solubilité du méthane et du dioxyde de carbone dans le système de méthane+ dioxyde de carbone+eau en équilibre sous hydrate-liquide-vapeur a été déterminée. La solubilité du méthane augmente avec la pression et diminue avec la température. La solubilité du dioxyde de carbone montre un comportement inverse : elle augmente avec la diminution de pression et l'augmentation de la température. Les compositions d'équilibre en phase vapeur ont également été mesurées et sont en accordance avec les données de littérature disponibles. Le système a été complètement modélisé en utilisant une technique de base qui calcule la vaporisation instantanée, où les pressions d'équilibre et les compositions de phase respectives ont été d ́eterminées à des isothermes différentes. Le modèle prédictif est basé sur l'équation d'état Trebble- Bishnoi, ainsi que les modèles van der Waals &amp; Platteeuw et Holder. Les prédictions conformes aux données et tous les paramètres modèles ont été indépendamment optimisés. C'est la première fois que la solubilité des formateurs d'hydrates est mesurée et comparée aux valeurs prévues dans un système binaire de formation d'hydrates et dans des conditions d'équilibre d'hydrates. Les données d'équilibre dans le développement une composante essentielle dans représentent d'un modèle de croissance d'hydrates, des formateurs d'hydrates de gaz simples aux formateurs multiples. Un modèle cinétique de croissance pour des systèmes avec des mélanges de formateurs d'hydrates de gaz a été développé et proposé.</description><description>Hydrate-liquid-vapor phase equilibria for systems with binary gas hydrate formers was investigated. The Gibbs phase rule was applied to establish the number of variables needed to specify the systems of interest as well as one additional intensive variable to justify the equilibrium. A novel method was used to map the equilibrium planes for nitrogen+carbon dioxide+water and methane+ethane+water under hydrate-liquid-vapor equilibrium. For the nitrogen+carbon dioxide+water system it was found that along any given isotherm the equilibrium pressure increases with an increased mole fraction of nitrogen in the vapor phase. The methane+ethane+water system forms both structure I and structure II hydrates and hence consists of two phase planes. The transition from structure I to structure II takes place around a 3 to 1 ratio of methane to ethane in the vapor phase. A 3D phase diagram of the system is presented, containing both the structure I and a structure II sections. Along any given isotherm and isobar in the structure I and II regions, it was found that the equilibrium pressure increased and the equilibrium temperature decreased respectively, with increasing mole fraction of methane in the gas phase. The equilibrium pressure of structure I is found to be less sensitive to temperature and composition changes than structure II.The solubility of methane and carbon dioxide in the methane+carbon dioxide+water system under hydrate-liquid-vapor equilibrium was determined. The solubility of methane increases with increasing pressures and decreasing temperatures and the solubility of carbon dioxide increases with decreasing pressures and increasing temperatures. Equilibrium vapor phase compositions were also measured and found to agree with other reported literature data. The system was also completely modelled using a flash based technique where equilibrium pressures and respective phase compositions were determined at various isotherms. The predictive model is based on the Trebble-Bishnoi equation of state and the van der Waals &amp; Platteeuw and Holder models. The predictions were found to fit the data well and all model parameters were independently optimized. This is the first time that the solubility of hydrate formers in a binary hydrate forming system under hydrate equilibrium conditions have been experimentally measured and compared to predicted values. The equilibrium data is an essential component in the expansion of a hydrate growth model from single to multiple gas hydrate formers. A kinetic growth model for systems with mixtures of gas hydrate formers was developed and is proposed.</description><creator>Bruusgaard, Hallvard</creator><contributor>Phillip Servio (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>H-Lw-V equilibrium for systems formed with binary gas mixtures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cp96w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q847z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63t0940</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse porte sur l'aide médicale internationale dans le nord d'Haïti.  L'aide Cette thèse a pour objet d'étudier et d'analyser l'assistance médicale internationale déployée dans le nord d'Haïti. Dans ce contexte, l'assistance médicale englobe un large éventail de biens et de services, notamment les fournitures pharmaceutiques et les équipements médicaux, les procédures médicales, le soutien aux projets d'infrastructures ainsi que la formation du personnel médical. Fondée sur des recherches ethnographiques menées de 2007 à 2009 auprès de fournisseurs, de metteurs en oeuvre et de bénéficiaires d'assistance médicale, la présente étude examine les différentes relations de collaboration et les tensions qui découlent de la prestation de services de santé dans un milieu caractérisé par des inégalités sociales et économiques marquées. Après une discussion sur l'héroïsme humanitaire, qui est ici illustré par la vie et les travaux des médecins Albert Schweitzer et de Paul Farmer, cette thèse examinera les activités d'une ONG de santé laïque des États-Unis. Le troisième chapitre est consacré aux expériences et aux points de vue de médecins haïtiens résidents qui oeuvrent dans un grand hôpital public, situant la vie et le travail de ces derniers dans le cadre de grands débats sur les obligations et l'émigration. Le quatrième chapitre examine les facteurs qui entravent la collaboration, pourtant réclamée de toutes parts, entre les différents intervenants des services d'assistance médicale. Le dernier chapitre propose des théories fondées sur l'économie morale et le ressentiment en tant que cadres conceptuels pour comprendre les échanges, les valeurs et les émotions de nature variée qui constituent et influencent les rencontres entre les intervenants de l'assistance médicale, et qui naissent de celles-ci. Plutôt que d'exposer les faiblesses ou les défaillances de l'assistance médicale internationale en Haïti, cette thèse vise à mettre en lumière l'ambivalence et les contradictions vécues par les divers acteurs engagés dans ce processus complexe.</description><description>This dissertation examines and analyzes the provision of international medical aid in northern Haiti.  Medical aid in this setting comprises a wide range of goods and services, including pharmaceutical supplies and medical equipment, clinical procedures, support for infrastructure projects and training for Haitian medical staff.  Based on ethnographic research conducted from 2007 to 2009 among the providers, implementors and recipients of medical aid, this study examines the various collaborations and tensions that result from the provision of health resources across marked social and economic inequalities.  Beginning with a discussion of humanitarian heroism as exemplified by the lives and work of Drs. Albert Schweitzer and Paul Farmer, the dissertation goes on to describe the activities of a secular U.S.-based health NGO.  The third chapter is devoted to the experiences and perspectives of Haitian medical residents at a large, public hospital, situating their lives and work within larger debates about obligation and emigration.  The fourth chapter focuses on the issue of coordination, and examines the factors that impede coordination among the diverse actors involved in medical aid, despite unanimous calls for it.  The final chapter proposes theories of moral economy, resentment and "ressentiment" as frameworks for understanding the diverse exchanges, values and emotions that constitute, influence and result from medical aid encounters.  Rather than expose the shortcomings or failures of international medical aid in Haiti, this dissertation aims to highlight the ambivalence and contradictions experienced by the diverse actors involved in this complex process.       </description><creator>Minn, Pierre Hong</creator><contributor>Allan Young (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Anthropology - Cultural</subject><title>"Where they need me": the moral economy of international medical aid in Haiti</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70n046p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63t0940</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd376186t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis consists of two different topics: In part 1, the design of an optical system testbed for long haul transmission using a re-circulating loop, is presented. The testbed operates at 40 Gb/s, it simulates an 1800 km link, with optical amplifiers every 80 km, and 16-32 DWDM channels. The theoretical elements involved in the testbed design are reviewed. The optical components are described and selected. The optical system design parameters are presented as well as design targets and optimization parameters. The final implementation is presented and propagation simulations are performed with RZ/NRZ DPSK, QPSK modulation formats to demonstrate the testbed functionality. In part 2 of the thesis, The BER penalty due to PDf in a DPSK demodulator is analyzed and its effect mitigated. A readily available technique is developed that allows measuring the individual contributions of PDf and PDL on BER and calibrate the demodulator in order to reduce the effective PDf by a factor of two which represents an almost 40% reduction in BER penalty due to PDf. The BER penalty due to PDf is measured for 10- vs. 40-GHz, RZ vs. NRZ DPSK demodulators. Finally, PDf mitigation is demonstrated using a PDL emulator, allowing a 75% reduction in polarization sensitivity.</description><description>La thèse se compose de deux sujets différents: Dans la partie 1, la conception d'un banc d'essai pour simuler un système optique pour la transmission longue distance à l'aide d'une boucle de recirculation, est présentée. Le banc d'essai fonctionne à 40 Gb/s, il simule un lien de 1800 km, avec des amplificateurs optiques à tous les  80km, et 16-32 canaux DWDM. Les éléments théoriques impliqués dans la conception du banc d'essai sont passés en revue. Les composantes optiques sont décrites et sélectionnées. Les paramètres de conception de systèmes optiques sont présentés ainsi que des objectifs de conception et d'optimisation. La mise en œuvre finale est présentée et des simulations de propagation sont réalisées avec les formats de modulation OOK, DPSK, QPSK RZ / NRZ pour démontrer la fonctionnalité du banc d'essai. Dans la partie 2 de la thèse, la pénalité due au PDf dans un démodulateur DPSK est analysée et ses effets réduits. Une technique facilement disponible est développée qui permet de mesurer les contributions individuelles du PDf et PDL sur le BER et de calibrer le démodulateur afin de réduire par un facteur de deux le PDf effectif, ce qui représente une réduction de près de 40% de la pénalité due au PDf sur le BER. La  pénalité due au PDf sur le BER est mesurée pour les 10 - 40-GHz  vs RZ NRZ dans les démodulateurs DPSK. Enfin, la réduction de la pénalité due au PDF est démontrée en utilisant un émulateur de PDL, ce qui permet une réduction de 75% de la sensibilité à la  polarisation.</description><creator>Cotruta, Dragos</creator><contributor>David V Plant (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Odile Liboiron-Ladouceur (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Ultra High Data-Rate Optical Transmission Networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795c922.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd376186t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644w814</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The way humans visualize and interact with visual data affects how that data is processed.  The current most prevalent paradigm for displaying visual content is a two dimensional display that suffers from a number of shortcomings.  One shortcoming is that the display is a flat 2D display.  As such, displaying collections of images that have been acquired from widely differing viewpoints becomes a challenge.  With the pervasiveness of cameras, there is an abundance of these collections of images.  These images are mostly stored and displayed as disparate images, and the information that they share and how the images relate is lost.  Another shortcoming of the current display paradigm is that the display can only act as a peephole into a much larger visual space, thereby filtering out a lot of the visual information.  This particular shortcoming is especially pronounced with displays on mobile devices, which are relatively small in size.  On mobile device displays, even 2D visual spaces, such as maps, a lot of information is filtered out, since only a small portion of the 2D space can be seen at any given time.  Each of these small portions becomes like an individual view of the map, and in exploring the visual space, the views of the space change; information of how these views relate is therefore lost.  In this thesis, we examine the ways in which we can relate seemingly disparate views in order to improve scene understanding and spatial awareness.We present two approaches to relating views: a passive and an active approach.  In the passive approach, users do not interact with the display; rather, we integrate images such that images from widely differing viewpoints can be displayed in a natural way that maintains their spatial relationships.  Our approach is called Virtual Mirroring because we place virtual mirrors on the scene and overlay images onto them.  For example, if we had a picture of both the front and the back of a person, we can assume that a virtual mirror is behind the person, and overlay onto it the image of the back of the person.  In so doing, we can see both the front view and the back view, by way of a virtual mirror.  Subsequently, we present a psychophysical experiment that we performed, which validates our belief that by presenting users with integrated images of a scene rather than non-integrated images, the users are better able to understand that scene.   Our active approach involves users interacting with the display.  We tie user motor actions to display changes, such that the display scrolls in the direction that the mobile device has been tilted.  We then perform a psychophysical experiment to investigate whether such a coupling between user motor actions and display changes can result in better learning of the visual space.  Our findings support such an active approach to the learning of visual information.  Finally, we present an application for our work.  One activity, in which better spatial understanding is crucial, is navigation.  We create a system, MirrorMap, that incorporates the Virtual Mirroring technique to provide users of the system with alternate views of the environment they are navigating.  For examples, video feeds from traffic cameras with better views of an intersection, can be overlaid onto virtual mirrors and then displayed to the user in a manner that preserves the spatial relationship between the camera and the user's locations.</description><description>La façon dont les humains visualisent et interagissent avec les données visuelles affecte la manière dont elles sont traitées.  Le paradigme le plus courant présentement utilisé pour représenter du contenu visuel est un affichage en deux dimensions qui possède de nombreux désavantages.  L'un de ces désavantages est que l'affichage est plat et en 2D.  Ainsi, l'affichage de collections d'images acquises de points de vue grandement différents devient un défi.  Avec l'omniprésence des appareils photos, il y a abondance de ces collections d'images.  Ces images sont surtout emmagasinées et affichées en images disparates, et l'information qu'elles partagent et les rapports entre les images sont perdus.  Un autre désavantage du paradigme d'affichage courant est que l'affichage peut seulement agir comme une petite ouverture vers un espace visuel beaucoup plus grand, ce qui a pour effet de filtrer beaucoup d'information visuelle.  Ce désavantage est particulièrement prononcé sur des appareils portatifs, qui sont relativement de petite taille.  Sur des appareils portatifs, même des espaces visuels en 2D comme des cartes filtrent beaucoup d'information, puisqu'une petite partie seulement peut être vue à tout moment.  Chacune de ces petites parties devient comme une vue individuelle de la carte.  Dans l'exploration de l'espace visuel, les vues de l'espace changent ce qui fait en sorte que la façon dont ces vues se rapportent l'une à l'autre est perdu.  Dans cette thèse, nous examinons comment nous pouvons rapporter l'une à  l'autre des vues disparates pour améliorer la compréhension de la scène et la sensibilisation à l'espace.Nous présentons deux approches pour rapporter les images : l'une passive et l'autre active.  Dans l'approche passive, les utilisateurs n'interagissent pas avec l'affichage; nous intégrons plutôt des images de façon à ce que les images de points de vue grandement différents puissent être affichées d'une manière naturelle qui maintient leurs points communs dans l'espace.  Notre approche se nomme Réflexion Virtuelle parce que nous plaçons des miroirs virtuels  sur la scène et transposons des images sur eux.  Par exemple, si nous avions une photographie du devant et du dos d'une personne, nous pouvons penser qu'un miroir virtuel est derrière la personne et y superposer l'image du dos de la personne.  De cette façon, nous pouvons voir la vue de face et celle de dos, avec l'aide d'un miroir virtuel.  Ensuite, nous présentons une expérience psychologique que nous avons effectuée qui valide notre hypothèse que la présentation d'images intégrées d'une scène aux utilisateurs -plutôt que des images non intégrées- facilite la compréhension de la scène.  Notre approche active implique que les utilisateurs interagissent avec l'affichage.  Nous lions les actions motrices de l'utilisateur pour démontrer les changements de façon à ce que l'affichage défile dans la direction où l'appareil portatif a été incliné.  Nous effectuons ensuite une expérience psychologique  pour vérifier si la combinaison des actions motrices avec le changement d'affichage peut amener à un meilleur apprentissage de l'information visuelle.  Finalement, nous présentons une application pour notre travail.  Une activité pour laquelle une meilleure compréhension de l'espace est cruciale est la navigation.  Nous créons un système, MirrorMap, qui incorpore la technique de Réflexion Virtuelle pour fournir aux utilisateurs du système des points de vue alternatifs de l'environnement qu'ils naviguent.  Par exemple, des vidéos de caméras de trafic routier avec de meilleures vues de l'intersection peuvent être superposées sur des miroirs virtuels et ensuite exposés à l'utilisateur de façon à préserver la relation spatiale entre la caméra et la location de l'utilisateur. </description><creator>Au, Carmen E</creator><contributor>James J Clark (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Integrating multiple views to improve scene understanding and spatial awareness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mv115.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644w814</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h377p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The isostructural R3T4X4 (R: rare earth, T:Mn,Pd,Cu,Ag, X:Si,Ge,Sn) family of compounds have been extensively studied recently due to the rich variety of magnetic behaviour exhibited: the two rare earth sublattices often order with quite different moment values and distinct magnetic structures. In some cases the rare earth sites will also have quite different ordering temperatures. Several of the series, R3Cu4Sn4, R3Ag4Sn4 and R3Cu4Ge4, appear not to follow the expected de Gennes scaling law of transition temperatures despite the structural uniformity of the system. Moreover, the system suffers from a common problem in rare earth intermetallic systems: an important lack of data and understanding of the Sm and Gd members.Capitalizing on the presence of Sn in many of these compounds, we have used 119Sn Mossbauer spectroscopy as a probe of local magnetism at the Sn sites in the structure. Although Sn carries no magnetic moment, a transferred field from the rare earth neighbours is observed, as both Sn sites in the structure have nearest neighbours from both rare earth sublattices. We also performed 155Gd Mossbauer spectroscopy on three Gd compounds, probing the local magnetism at the 155Gd nuclei directly. Using the newly developed flat plate mounting for highly absorbing samples, we performed neutron diffraction on several Sm and Gd compounds to probe the long range spatial symmetry of the rare earth magnetic moments. The Mossbauer spectroscopy and neutron scattering results were then combined as verification of consistency, but more importantly as complementary sources of magnetic information allowing us to draw conclusions that otherwise could not be drawn with either of the experimental techniques alone.We find that a simple isotropic hyperfine field transfer model successfully describes the 119Sn Mossbauer spectra of several R3T4Sn4 (T:Cu,Ag) compounds. 119Sn Mossbauer spectroscopy also reveals important magnetic interactions previously missed: Nd3Cu4Sn4 data exhibits a clear magnetic contribution at temperatures at which neutron diffraction data did not, while Ho3Cu4Sn4 exhibited magnetic interactions above the ordering temperature determined by neutron diffraction. The Sm3Ag4Sn4 and Sm3Cu4Sn4 compounds proved to behave entirely differently than previously thought: the former undergoes magnetic ordering at 26K rather than 9K, and shows evidence of anisotropic field transfer, while Sm3Cu4Sn4 fails to order and instead exhibits slow moment dynamics. The Gd compounds also yield surprising results as Gd3Cu4Ge4 and Gd3Ag4Sn4 order at far higher temperature than previously thought, while Gd3Cu4Sn4 exhibits the most complex 119Sn Mossbauer spectrum due only to the moments at the Gd-2d site. The R3T4X4 system remains highly magnetically complex and diverse, however the magnetic landscape has been significantly altered. The flat plate mounting technique for neutron diffraction, especially when combined with Mossbauer spectroscopy data, allows for the determination of the magnetic structures of Sm3Ag4Sn4 as well as Gd3Ag4Sn4 and partially of Gd3Cu4Sn4, showing great promise as an important new experimental tool.</description><description>La famille de composés R3T4X4 (R: terre rare, T: Mn, Pd, Cu, Ag, X: Si, Ge,Sn) adopte uniformément la structure orthorhombique de type Gd3Cu4Ge4 (groupe d'espace Immm, # 71). Ces composés ont été étudiés récemment en raison de la riche variété de comportements magnétiques observés: chaque sous-réseau de terre rare s'ordonne avec des valeurs de moment magnétique très différentes et adoptent des structures magnétiques distinctes. Dans certains cas, les deux sites de terres rares auront également des températures d'ordre magnétique très différentes. Plusieurs membres de la série, R3Cu4Sn4, R3Ag4Sn4 et R3Cu4Ge4, ne semblent pas suivre la loi d'échelle de de Gennes des températures de transition magnétique, malgré l'uniformité structurelle du système. De plus, le système souffre d'un problème commun parmi les systèmes intermétalliques de terre rare: un manque important de mesures et compréhension des membres Sm et Gd du système.Capitalisant sur la présence de Sn dans plusieurs de ces composés, nous avons effectué des mesures de spectroscopie Mossbauer 119Sn comme une sonde locale du magnétisme aux sites Sn dans la structure. Bien que le Sn ne comporte pas de moment magnétique, un champ transféré des terres rares voisines est observé, vu que les deux sites Sn dans la structure ont des voisins proches des deux sous-réseaux de terres rares. Nous avons également effectué des mesures de spectroscopie Mossbauer 155Gd sur trois composés de Gd, pour sonder le magnétisme local aux noyaux 155Gd directement. En utilisant la plaque de montage nouvellement mise au point pour des échantillons hautement absorbants, nous avons procédé à la diffusion neutronique sur plusieurs composés de Sm et Gd pour sonder la symétrie spatiale à longue portée des moments magnétiques des terres rares. La spectroscopie Mossbauer et les résultatsde diffusion neutronique ont ensuite été combinés premièrement pour une vérification de cohérence, mais avant tout comme des sources complémentaires d'information magnétique qui nous permettent de tirer des conclusions qui ne pourraient autrement pas être établies avec l'une ou l'autre de ces techniques à elles seule.Nous constatons qu'un simple modèle de transfer isotropique de champ magnétique hyperfin décrit avec succès les spectres Mossbauer 119Sn de plusieurs composés R3T4Sn4 (T: Cu, Ag). La spectroscopie Mossbauer 119Sn révèle aussi d'importantes interactions magnétiques inconnues auparavant: la présence d'une contribution magnétique claire de Nd3Cu4Sn4 à des temp ératures auxquelles la diffusion neutronique n'en detecte aucune, tandis que Ho3Cu4Sn4 exhibe des interactions magnétiques au dessus de la température d'ordre magnétique déterminée par diffusion neutronique. Il s'avère que les composés Sm3Ag4Sn4 et Sm3Cu4Sn4 ont un comportement très différent de ce qui était cru auparavant: le premier subit un ordonnement magnétique à 26K au lieu de 9K, et montre des signes de transfert de champ magnétique hyperfin anisotrope, alors que le deuxième ne parvient pas à l'ordre magnétique mais exhibe une dynamique de moment magnétique lente. Les composés de Gd révèlent aussi des résultats surprenants alors que Gd3Cu4Ge4 et Gd3Ag4Sn4 ont une température d'ordonnement magnétique beaucoup plus élevée qu'on ne le pensait, et que Gd3Cu4Sn4 exhibe lesspectres Mossbauer 119Sn les plus complexes du uniquement aux moments magnétiques du site Gd-2d.Le système R3T4X4 reste très complexe et diversifié d'un point de vue magnétique, mais le paysage magnétique a été significativement modifié. La technique de plaque de montage pour la diffusion neutronique, en particulier lorsqu'elle est combiné avec les données de spectroscopie Mossbauer, permet la détermination des structures magnétiques des composés Sm3Ag4Sn4 et Gd3Ag4Sn4, et partiellement du composé Gd3Cu4Sn4, et reste prometteuse comme un nouvel outil expérimental important.</description><creator>Voyer, Christian</creator><contributor>Dominic Ryan (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Physics - Solid State</subject><title>A 119Sn and 155 Gd Mossbauer spectroscopy and neutron diffraction study of R3T4X4 (R=rare-earth, T=Cu,Ag, X=Sn, Ge) compounds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687n36f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h377p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38000</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>