<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:05:13Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):16350" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hg70n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dissertation examines four historical definitions of Western architecture: architecture as a techne in ancient Greece, as a mechanical art in the Middle Ages, as an art of disegno in Renaissance Italy, and as a fine art in the eighteenth century. These definitions situated architecture within larger classifications of knowledge. They established alliances between architecture and other disciplines. They also influenced elements of architectural practice: what we would associate conventionally with the designer, builder, dweller, material, drawing, and building. The dissertation reviews writings in each historical period and focuses on the practical implications of several texts: Hugh of St. Victor, Didascalicon; Leon Battista Alberti, De re aedificatoria, Book 1; and Etienne-Louis Boullee, Essai sur l'art. As a series, the four historical definitions show how the concept of architecture and the elements of architectural practice have been open to change. Even the word "architecture" has ambiguous roots.</description><creator>Parcell, Stephen.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Architecture -- Western influences.</subject><subject>Architecture -- History.</subject><title>Four historical definitions of architecture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956k60r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hg70n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591c71z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Waveform Relaxation methods are very efficient and reliable methods. They have been widely used in several fields, including circuit theory, for solving large systems of ordinary differential equations and solving partial differential equations. A new approach called optimized waveform relaxation algorithms was recently introduced which greatly improved convergence by using new transmission conditions. These conditions are responsible for the exchange of information between subsystems. In this thesis, we demonstrate that the transmission conditions have a tremendous influence on the convergence of the waveform relaxation algorithms for circuit simulations. We first derive new waveform relaxation methods for a general circuit and its associated system of ordinary differential equations, and give transmission conditions with optimal performance. These optimal transmission conditions are however not convenient to use and thus we introduce approximations for them. We then determine numerically the approximate transmission conditions with the best performance of the new waveform relaxation algorithms for two model problems, and we show how much the convergence can be improved compared to the classical waveform relaxation algorithm. We then start a detailed study of optimized waveform relaxation algorithms for RC type circuits. We first analyze RC circuits of any finite size, and give optimal transmission conditions. We again propose approximations for the optimal transmission conditions which are optimized based on numerical insight. Then we choose a very small RC circuit which has only one cell and a small RC circuit which has three cells to further study the quality of the approximations. For the very small RC circuit we show that the optimal transmission conditions are indeed local operators in time, they are first degree time derivatives which are convenient to use. However; we also propose a constant approximation of the optimal transmission conditions which is simpler to use and we prove the optimality of this approximation. For the small RC circuit we also prove the optimality of the proposed constant approximation, and find asymptotically an optimized first order approximation. We then study an infinitely large RC circuit to demonstrate that the size of the circuit does not have a major impact on the convergence of the optimized waveform relaxation methods. We recall the optimality proof for the constant approximation given in [1], and we give an asymptotic result for an optimized first order approximation. We show that results found for the infinitely large RC circuit are indeed limits of those found for the finite size RC circuit as the size of the circuit goes to infinity. We next start a detailed study of optimized waveform relaxation algorithms for transmission line type circuits. We give optimal transmission conditions which we approximate by constants. We analyze very small and small transmission line circuits, which have one cell and two cells respectively, and we find asymptotically optimized constant transmission conditions for both. We consider also an infinitely large transmission line circuit, and we give an optimized constant approximation based on an asymptotic analysis. We finally show that the systems representing the circuits considered are semi-discretizations of particular partial differential equations, and in addition, we show that the new transmission conditions introduced for the circuit problems imply the ones associated with the partial differential equations at the continuous level. We also show that the convergence factors and the solutions obtained by applying the new waveform relaxation algorithms to the partial differential equations converge to those obtained by applying the algorithms to the circuit systems. In order to demonstrate the practicality and the efficiency of the optimized waveform relaxation methods; we give numerical experiments that show the drastically improved convergence behavior.</description><creator>Al-Khaleel, Mohammad D.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Differential equations -- Numerical solutions.</subject><subject>Electronic circuits -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Optimized waveform relaxation methods for circuit simulations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tg662.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c71z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f965f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Scopulariopsis brevicaulis (Saccardo) Bainier is a member of the Fungi Imperfecti. It is a mould which, like many species of Fungi Imperfecti, is widely distributed throughout the world. Of the many species in the genus Scopulariopsis, this organism has attracted the most attention. A review of the literature shows that it is important not only as a saprophyte but also as a parasite. As a human parasite it is most commonly encountered as a dermatophyte. Reviews by Dodge (1935), Raper and Thom (1949), Conant et al. (1954) and more recent reports such as Fischer's review of clinical cases (1960) and a report from Poland by Kapica (1960) indicate that S. brevicaulis is isolated from clinical material more frequently than any other recognized species belonging to this genus.</description><creator>Van Walbeek, Wilhelmina.</creator><contributor>Blank, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Bacteriology and Immunology.</subject><title>Further studies of the keratinolytic activities of scopulariopsis brevicaulis.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gr89b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f965f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514np90n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The signing of the Anglo-German Naval Agreement by Sir Samuel Hoare on June 18, 1935, after only ten days as foreign Secretary, was really an outcome of negotiations begun by his predecessor. Sir John Simon. Nevertheless, the agreement was sanctioned during the foreign Office of Hoare and therefore must be examined in some detail within the scope of this thesis. The agreement was signed at the conclusion of talks which began in London on June 4, 1935, under the chairmanship of Sir John Simon. The proposal to hold naval talks in London was first made by Simon during the course of his visit to Berlin, in March of the same year.</description><creator>Vallely, Lois. M.</creator><contributor>Fieldhouse, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>History.</subject><title>The foreign secretaryship of Sir Samuel Hoare (later Lord Templewood).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010t594.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np90n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827g333</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experimental study of supersonic combustion bas been performed using the McGill University pebble bed heated wind tunnel. Supersonic combustion was achieved in a stainless steel combustion tube and in a free jet issuing from the tube. Due to fuel mixing delay time, the combustion efficiency was very low. The total heat addition was limited to a small value by friction in the combustion tube. Computer programmes were written for the I.B.M. 650 digital computer to calculate test conditions and to compute Mach Number and total pressure profiles in the tube, with and without combustion. Because of the low combustion efficiency, the calculated profiles do not agree with the experimental values for cases with combustion.</description><creator>Valenti, Anthony. M.</creator><contributor>Swithenbank, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering.</subject><title>Supersonic combustion studies.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q5207.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827g333</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bj49x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The importance of tile adrenal cortex in influencing sodium and potassium metabolism is well established. The adrenal cortex secretes a number of steroid hormones which affect sodium and potassium excretion to varying degrees. The hormone which is the most potent in its sodium retaining effect is aldosterone. It promotes the sodium reabsorption for the exchange of potassium or hydrogen ion in the distal tubules of the kidney. There are several problems which are not well understood, e.g. the physiological importance of the rate of secretion of various steroids, the synergistic or antagonistic action of various adrenal cortical hormones on the absorption, distribution and excretion of electrolyte and their interplay with each other.</description><creator>Uete, Tetsuo.</creator><contributor>Venning, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>The effect of adrenal cortical hormones on electrolyte excretion.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89db031.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bj49x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Health Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c184n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The future development of the natural resources of the Canadian North definitely includes agriculture and agriculture in that area is not a novelty but a reality, as stated by Nowosad (1959). The importance of agriculture and its possible development in the Yukon Territory was discussed in the debate of the House of Commons by Nielson (1960). The soil survey in the Yukon, conducted by Day in 1957-58 reveals that the soil in general is low in organic matter, nitrogen and phosphorus. Marked advantages resulted from application of manure and commercial fertilizers on grain crops and favorable results were also obtained by the application of nitrogen fertilizer on pasture crops as reported by the Whitehorse Experimental Farm (1958).</description><creator>Tsukamoto, Yoshikazu.</creator><contributor>Steppler, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Agronomy.</subject><title>The influence of environmental conditions upon alfalfa growth in the Yukon.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xd270.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c184n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agriculture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn1072684</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cover of a recent issue of a leading Canadian magazine drew a comic parallel between the children of today and the children of' the parental generation. The children of the past were depicted as happy carefree lads and lassies engaging in such active games as hoop rolling, skipping, scrub baseball, apple stealing and the like. The modern child appeared in a darkened room blankly staring at a television screen. This idea appears too common now that television has become a part of life and it is not always expressed in a humourous vein. In fact many people are concerned about this new medium and the attraction it has for children.</description><creator>Thorsteinson, William. E.</creator><contributor>Elkin, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Sociology.</subject><title>The reaction of nursery school children to television.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m540z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1072684</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752m50d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Some copper sulphide minerals recrystallized when heated in a temperature gradient in an argon-sulphur atmosphere, and acicular and lenticular crystals grew down gradient. The crystal composition was determined by the composition of the starting material, temperature, and the sulphur vapour pressure. The purpose of these experiments was to determine: (i) what effect the texture of the surface over which the copper sulphide migrated had upon the diffusing mineral, (ii) what relationship existed between temperature and the weight of the mineral transferred under a constant temperature gradient, (iii) what were the critical factors causing the migration, and, (iv) whether chalcopyrite (CuFeS2) and bornite (Cu5FeS4) would migrate to the same degree under similar conditions.</description><creator>Thorniley, Brian. H.</creator><contributor>Gill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Experiments with copper minerals at high temperatures.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vv48b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752m50d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w588j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The hippocampal formation is interesting because of the wide range of functions that have been attributed to it. The older anatomists, impressed by its close relation to the pre-pyriform or entorhinal cortex, attributed to it a role in olfaction. Comparative anatomists have noticed, however, that in anosmic animals such as the porpoise, which have no peripheral olfactory apparatus, the hippocampal cortex is well differentiated. Furthermore, Swann (1934) and Allen (1940, 1941) have shown that ablation of the hippocampus and fornix does not interfere with the retention of conditioned responses to olfactory stimuli, or olfactory discrimination performance.</description><creator>Teitelbaum, Herman.</creator><contributor>Milner, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Psychology.</subject><title>A study of hippocampal function in the rat.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827g34c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w588j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gr903</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Measurements on the swelling pressure of oriented samples of Na-montmorillonite at dialysate concentrations of 10^-4 and 10^-2 M NaCl were made at temperatures ranging from 0°C to 25°0 in a specially designed temperature - swelling apparatus. The results indicate that at a dialysate concentration of 10^-4 M NaCl, the swelling pressure predicted from the combined Poisson-Boltzmann equation agreed closely with the measured pressures at the temperatures considered – swelling pressure decreased with decreasing temperature as predicted from the equation. Measured pressures were in all cases slightly smaller than the predicted pressures. </description><creator>Taylor, Leon. O.</creator><contributor>Yong, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>The effect of depressed temperatures on the swelling pressure of sodium montmorillonite.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sk84g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gr903</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x7480</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Petroleum is a hydrocarbon known in its liquid state as oil and in its gaseous state as natural gas. It is usually found in the sedimentary basins which make up about one-third of the earth's land surface. Well over a century ago, it came into increasingly general use as a lubricant, and through one of its many derivitives, kerosene, as an energy source. This latter use has since been enhanced powerfully by the rapid industrialization of the western world, the invention of the combustion engine, the decline of coal, and numerous other developments that have characterized the twentieth century.</description><creator>Tarasofsky, Abraham.</creator><contributor>Asimakopulos, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Economics and Political Science.</subject><title>Canada’s national oil policy and the emerging world oil market.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t03v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x7480</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics and Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p840g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chemical changes involve the breaking of bonds in the reacting molecules and the formation of bonds in the products; they are usually accompanied by energy changes. Although the stability of a molecule or a radical, as expressed in terms of bond strengths, and its reactivity do not necessarily go hand in hand, a knowledge of the former is essential for the full understanding of the other factors which influence the source of chemical processes. In consequence, it is evident that the magnitudes of bond dissociation energies are of fundamental importance for both chemical kinetics and chemical equilibria.</description><creator>Tan, Ah-Ti. C-H.</creator><contributor>Sehon, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The pyrolysis of phenylmercaptoacetic acid.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903360r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p840g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149t241</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the early period of microbiology, little attention was paid to marine microorganisms. In spite of the knowledge that life originated in the sea which covers the greater part of the earth's surface, little or no attempt was made to study the nature and activity of bacteria in the oceans. It was the end of the 19th century when Ehrenberg, Certes, Fischer and Russel, pioneer workers of marine bacteriology, published their studies in this field. Although marine bacteriology received more and more attention following the days of the pioneers, the research was mostly limited to general observations such as taxonomy, distribution, cultural characteristics, enumeration, etc., consequently very little information became available on the biochemistry of marine bacteria.</description><creator>Takacs, Frank. Paul.</creator><contributor>MacLeod, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Agricultural Bacteriology.</subject><title>Inorganic ion uptake by marine bacteria.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rc569.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149t241</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agriculture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p3915</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alicyclic spiranes, like spiro [5.5] undecane, and azaspiranes, like 3-azaspiro [5.5] undecane, the alternate name “piperidine-4-spirocyclohexane”; formula and 1-azaspiro [5.5] undecane, the alternate name "piperidine-2-spirocycohexane"; formula are representatives of an unusual combination of ring structures and they involve several important sterochemical – configurational and conformational-problems. It is not true, as is often stated, that the two alicyclic six-membered rings in these spiranes lie in planes perpendicular to each other.</description><creator>Szalay, Paul. J.</creator><contributor>Taurins, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The synthesis and infrared spectra of piperidinespiranes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xq24n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p3915</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h524t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Penicillium cyaneo-fulvum, which was found growing as a contaminant on a Lowenstein slope in the Clinical Laboratories of the Department of Bacteriology, McGill University, by Denton (1947), has been shown to produce at least three distinct substances. The mould produces an antibiotic, probably penicillin, a toxin neutralizing substance, noxiversin (Diena, 1954, 1956; Murray, Denton, Stevenson and Diena, 1958) and an antiviral factor (Diena, 1956; Cooke, 1958, 1960). Noxiversin, studied in some detail by Diena and others (Ajemian, 1957; Diena, 1954, 1956; Murray et al., 1958; Tanner, 1956, 1957), was found to possess, in addition to its antitoxic properties, some activity against influenza virus (Diena, 1956).</description><creator>Syeklocha, Delfa.</creator><contributor>Stevenson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Bacteriology and Immunology.</subject><title>Biological activities of an antiviral substance from Penicillium cyaneo-fulvum.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343w591.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h524t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967722z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Attention has been drawn to the complex problem of the neurogenic bladder by the increased incidence of spinal cord trauma in civilian and war casualties. Improvement in the immediate care of the injuries has resulted in a greater initial salvage rate. The increased population of patients with neurogenic bladders suggests a need for re-evaluating the fundamental aspects of this problem. The physiology and pathology of the normal and neurogenic bladder have been studied. The utilization of substitute bladders in these cases has not been fully explored.</description><creator>Susset, Jacques. G.</creator><contributor>MacKinnon, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Experimental study on the therapeutic indications of intestino-cystoplasty in neurogenic vesical dysfunctions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v210p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967722z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Health Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tz83p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this study we shall deal with the great affirmation of the Bible that the purpose of God which is manifested in the history of Israel is the same purpose on which the entire creation is founded. Being a redemptive purpose, it is conceived not as an abstract, immovable design, but as effective in itself, identical with the creator's word striving for fulfillment in the world. Jesus fulfills this all-inclusive purpose as the Messiah of Israel, bringing the chosen people of God, and in principle the entire cosmos, to a final crisis wherein divine judgment is enacted on human sin and the new humanity is brought into being. The new humanity, inaugurated in Christ's fulfillment of the creator's purpose, is an eschatological concept and offers man the possibility of becoming a complete man in Jesus Christ. Man's response to this offer involves the recognition of human solidarity, even cosmic solidarity, for, by divine intent, he lives not in isolation, but in a network of relationships to the rest of creation.</description><creator>Suld, Henry.</creator><contributor>Frost, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Divinity.</subject><title>The relation of the doctrine of creation to the person of Jesus Christ in New Testament theology.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk87k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tz83p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Religion</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gp56p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Composite concrete-steel beams are widely used for highway bridge structures and to a lesser extent for building floors. These structures are made from steel beams which support a concrete slab. The concrete slab serves a dual purpose: It provides a deck or working surface and it acts as the top flange of the supporting beam. The compressive forces are resisted by the concrete slab; the tensile forces are resisted by the steel beam; and the horizontal shear between these two elements is resisted by shear connectors which are welded to the steel beam and embedded in the concrete slab. The resulting structure has greater stiffness, shallower construction, greater live load factor of safety and often greater economy than a non-composite structure designed for the same loads.</description><creator>Stonehewer, John.</creator><contributor>De Stein, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>A study of composite concrete-aluminum beams.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602455j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gp56p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544bs986</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The structure and reactivity of aza-aromatic nitramines has been under study in this laboratory for several years. Since the chemical properties of phenazine place it between aromatic hydrocarbons and strongly electron-deficient aza-aromatics, the compound is especially interesting from the point of view of the behaviour of its nitramine derivatives. An investigation of the latter would bridge the gap between nitramines of the two groups of compounds. 2-Nitraminophenazine was prepared and was found to behave similarly to the known aza-aromatic compounds of this type. 1-Nitraminophenazine could not be isolated under the reaction conditions.</description><creator>Stammer, Chaim.</creator><contributor>Taurins, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Synthesis and infrared spectra of phenazines.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fm770.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bs986</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214s81s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phenomenon of selective permeation of certain substances across tissue membranes and into cells has long been recognized as a function of fundamental and essential importance. The composition of the intracellular fluid is, under normal physiological conditions, quite different from that of the extracellular fluid and it is the role of the external membrane surrounding the cytoplasm of each cell to maintain this state. The mechanisms which come into play in this process are still far from completely understood, although a great deal of work has been devoted to their study.</description><creator>Stachiewicz, Eva. T.</creator><contributor>Quastel, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Transport phenomena in yeast.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/794081677.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214s81s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rs490</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Disagreement among teachers on major and minor issues saps the strength of the educational system; undermines and enfeebles the purpose of the school; and destroys the unity of thought and action needed to realize great achievements in public education. All teachers cannot be expected to accept one specified code of beliefs. The pruning of superfluous ideas, and the effecting of greater unanimity, however, is sure to create a more fruitful theory of education. The tenacity with which most teachers hold to their beliefs based on a fragmentary knowledge of popular philosophies prevents agreement on the answers to many problems. Their blind acceptance of the dictates of common sense blocks the path of advance.</description><creator>Smith, George. W.</creator><contributor>Nash, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Education.</subject><title>Peirce’s philosophy: some educational implications with particular reference to the teaching of science.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v6353.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rs490</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451n21k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Finance and administration are not merely interwoven, but finance is an integral part of administration itself. In the words of Durell, “the administrator is always working with both factors, he is cutting a coat according to his cloth, and the quantity of cloth is just as vital a factor as the pattern of the future coat in his mind”. Canada's financial administration, like that of Great Britain, is based on a budgetary rather than a non-budgetary system. The distinction between these two systems has been described by Villard and Willoughby in the following words.</description><creator>Singh, Sant. P.</creator><contributor>Mallory, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Political Science.</subject><title>The Canadian committee on estimates.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246w55p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451n21k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395wc16p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Melville Peninsula is the largest and most easterly of several peninsulas which extend northward from the eastern mainland portion of the Northwest Territories in the Canadian Arctic. It has a maximum. north-south length of approximately 250 miles (66° 10’N. to 69°52'N.) and a. maximum width at its widest point of approximately 140 miles (81°15’W. to 86°36’W.). The peninsula, itself within the District of Franklin, is joined to the northeastern corner of the District of Keewatin by Rae Isthmus. It forms the western shore of Foxe Basin (map 1) and is separated from Baffin Island to the north by Fury and Hecla Strait and from Southampton Island to the south by Frozen Strait. The region covered by this study includes Wales, Amherst and Igloolik Islands. It does not include several smaller islands off the extreme southern tip of the peninsula.</description><creator>Sim, Victor W.</creator><contributor>Bird, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Geography.</subject><title>The physiography of Melville Penisula, N. W. T.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053k822.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wc16p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sx49v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study proposes a detailed examination of the Irish migration to Montreal between 1847 and 1867, that is to say between the Famine and Confederation. For vast numbers of Irish, Quebec and Montreal were of course merely staging-points in a weary journey whose end lay in Upper Canada or, more often, in the United States of America. [...]</description><creator>Keep, George Rex Crowley, 1902-</creator><contributor>Copper, J.I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948</date><subject>Irish Canadians -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><subject>Canada -- Emigration and immigration.</subject><subject>Ireland -- Emigration and immigration.</subject><subject>History, Canadian.</subject><title>The Irish migration to Montreal, 1847-1867</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d770k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sx49v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History and Classical Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):16375</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>