<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:02:28Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):3250" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892d19h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The analysis of musical signals to extract audio descriptors that can potentially characterize their timbre has been disparate and often too focused on a particular small set of sounds. The Timbre Toolbox provides a comprehensive set of descriptors that can be useful in perceptualresearch, as well as in music information retrieval and machinelearning approaches to content-based retrieval in large sound databases. Sound events are first analyzed in terms of various input representations (short-term Fourier transform, harmonic sinusoidal components, an auditorymodel based on the equivalent rectangular bandwidth concept, the energy envelope). A large number of audio descriptors are then derived from each of these representations to capture temporal, spectral, spectrotemporal and energetic properties of the sound events. Somedescriptors are global, providing a single value for the whole sound event, whereas others are time-varying. Robust descriptive statistics are used to characterize the time-varying descriptors. To examine the information redundancy across audio descriptors, correlational analysisfollowed by hierarchical clustering is performed. This analysis suggests ten classes of relatively independent audio descriptors, showing that the Timbre Toolbox is a multidimensional instrument for the measurement of the acoustical structure of complex sound signals. </description><creator>Peeters, Geoffroy</creator><creator>Giordano, Bruno L.</creator><creator>Susini, Patrick</creator><creator>McAdams, Stephen</creator><date>2011</date><subject></subject><subject>Audio Descriptors</subject><title>The Timbre Toolbox: Extracting audio descriptors from musical signals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s4704.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892d19h</identifier><degree><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150m25w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sounds convey information about the materials composing an object. Stimuli were synthesized using a computer model of impacted plates that varied their material properties: viscoelastic and thermoelastic damping and wave velocity (related to elasticity and mass density). The range of damping properties represented a continuum betweenmaterials with predominant viscoelastic and thermoelastic damping (glass and aluminum, respectively). The perceptual structure of the sounds was inferred from multidimensional scaling of dissimilarity judgments and from their categorization as glass or aluminum. Dissimilarity ratings revealed dimensions that were closely relatedto mechanical properties: a wave-velocity-related dimension associated with pitch and a damping-related dimension associated with timbre and duration. When asked to categorize sounds, however, listeners ignored the cues related to wave velocity and focused on cues related to damping. In both dissimilarity-rating and identificationexperiments, the results were independent of the material of the mallet striking the plate (rubber or wood). Listeners thus appear to select acoustical information that is reliable for a given perceptual task. Because the frequency changes responsible for detecting changes in wave velocity can also be due to changes in geometry, they are not as reliable for material identification as are damping cues.  </description><creator>McAdams, Stephen</creator><creator>Roussarie, Vincent</creator><creator>Chaigne, Antoine</creator><creator>Giordano, Bruno L.</creator><date>2010</date><subject>Impact sounds</subject><subject>Damping</subject><title>The psychomechanics of simulated sound sources: Material properties of impacted thin plates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074x34p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m25w</identifier><degree><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wq021</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>En droit international, les décideurs ont remplacé les interventions militaires par des sanctions économiques au cours des dernières décennies. Cependant, l'imposition de sanctions a ses propres coûts et des résultats imprévus, y compris des problèmes humanitaires dans les pays sanctionnés et des coûts économiques pour les États qui les sanctionnent. Cette étude proposée se concentre sur un autre résultat indésirable des sanctions: elle fait valoir que les sanctions économiques augmentent le niveau de corruption dans les pays sanctionnés et dans d'autres pays.Le premier chapitre commence par un contexte conceptuel et passe brièvement en revue les sanctions économiques et les débats sur la corruption dans le droit et dans d'autres domaines. Le deuxième chapitre utilise une étude de cas sur l'Iran pour mieux comprendre la relation entre les sanctions économiques et la corruption. Cette étude conclut que l'imposition de sanctions économiques affecte les pays ayant des conséquences spécifiques, entraînant une augmentation du niveau de corruption dans les pays sanctionnés et les pays tiers. Il propose en outre que les pays qui ont été soumis à des sanctions économiques semblent confrontés au problème de la corruption même après la levée des sanctions. Enfin, cette étude soulève des implications qui pourraient être utiles aux décideurs politiques pour choisir la bonne combinaison d'instruments de politique étrangère pour les futurs cas de sanctions économiques.</description><description>In international law, policymakers have replaced military interventions with economic sanctions over recent decades. However, the imposition of sanctions has its own costs and unintended results, including humanitarian issues in sanctioned countries and economic costs for sanctioning states. This proposed study concentrates on another undesirable outcome of sanctions: it argues that economic sanctions increase the level of corruption in sanctioned countries and other countries.The first chapter begins with a conceptual background and briefly reviews economic sanctions and corruption debates in the law and other fields. The second chapter uses a case study of Iran to obtain a better understanding between the relationship of economic sanctions and corruption. This study concludes the imposition of economic sanctions affects countries with specific consequences, leading to a rise in the level of corruption in sanctioned and third countries. It further proposes that countries that have undergone economic sanctions appear to deal with the issue of corruption even after sanctions are lifted. Finally, this study raises implications that could be useful for policymakers to choose the right combination of foreign policy tools for future cases of economic sanctions. </description><creator>Mahmoudi, Azar</creator><contributor>Evan Fox-Decent (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Law</subject><title>The proliferation of corruption in sanctions regimes: The case of Iran</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tb63p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wq021</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579v53d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans cette thèse, on s'intéresse à l'espace de modules des connexions plates sur une surface avec groupe de structure SU(n), ainsi qu'aux espaces associés qui aparaissent quand on permet à la surface d'avoir une frontière. Les propriétées de ces espaces et la relation entre eux nous sert a construire un système intégrable sur l'espace de modules sur une surface fermée qui généalise l'application moment torique de Jeffrey et Weitsman [10].</description><description>In this thesis we treat the moduli space of flat SU(n) connections over a surface, as well as the various related spaces that appear when the surface is allowed to have boundary. The properties of these spaces and the relationships between them are used to construct an integrable system on the moduli space over a closed surface which generalizes the toric moment map of Jeffrey and Weitsman [10].</description><creator>Artymowicz, Adam</creator><contributor>Jacques Claude Hurtubise (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Mathematics and Statistics</subject><title>Integrable systems on the moduli space of flat connections</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000229c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v53d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150m265</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>My PhD thesis aims to improve our understanding of the assembly process of the bacterial ribosome and the overarching goal of my research is to identify steps in this pathway that can be targeted with new molecular probes. Ribosome assembly in actively growing Escherichia Coli involves multiple events including synthesis of 54 ribosomal-proteins and their binding to ribosomal RNAs in a hierarchical manner. Many of these events are assisted by a number of accessory proteins known as assembly factors, making the process extremely fast and efficient. My PhD thesis contributes new knowledge on the precise mechanism by which YjeQ and Era assist the ribosome assembly process. Recent work indicates that both factors assist the late stages of the 30S subunit assembly. To reveal the precise role of YjeQ in the context of the mature 30S subunit, we solved the structure of the 30S subunit in complex with YjeQ by cryo-electron microscopy (Cryo-EM). Our data suggested that in addition to work as a maturation factor, YjeQ also functions as a checkpoint protein testing the proofreading ability of the ribosomal subunit prior to the particle's release into the pool of actively translating ribosomes. This work provides the first example of a bacterial assembly factor that tests a specific translation mechanism of the 30S subunit. To investigate the role of Era, we used quantitative mass spectrometry (qMS), microscale thermophoresis (MST) and cryo-EM techniques. We first determined using cryo-EM the structures of the assembly intermediate that accumulated in E. coli upon depletion of Era at 3.8Å resolution. In addition, we also solved the structure of the mature 30S subunit in complex with Era. We found that Era-depleted cells accumulated three assembly intermediates at different stages of maturation ranging from early stage of maturation to the late stage of 30S subunit with missing density both in the central and 3' minor domains of the 30S subunit. Densities for ribosomal proteins (r-proteins) bS21, bS1, uS3 and uS2 bound to the central domain were also missing from the late stage of 30S subunit. The structure of the 30S subunit in complex with Era demonstrated that binding of this factor reverts the mature subunit to an immature state lacking density for the motifs integrating the decoding center. These results suggest that Era facilitates the proper folding of the platform region of the 30S subunit. In addition, Era may work as a placeholder for some of the late ribosomal proteins and prevent premature association of the 30S subunit with the 50S subunit. Finally, we tested whether YjeQ and Era exert their function in conjunction rather than independently. To this end, we obtained the cryo-EM structure of the 30S subunit in complex with Era and YjeQ at 3.5Å resolution. However, we couldn't observe any density for YjeQ in this structure. Moreover, we demonstrated Era binds to the cavity between head and platform and reverts the structure of the 30S subunit to its immature state. These results suggest that Era and YjeQ works subsequently during assembly. Era binds first to the assembling subunit and assists the folding of the platform region at the same time that it prevents the binding of YjeQ. Once Era is released, YjeQ binds assisting the maturation of the decoding center and testing the fidelity of the subunit before releasing it to the pool of fully active ribosomes. Overall, this thesis provides novel insights into the function of two important GTPases dedicated to the assembly process of the bacterial ribosome.</description><description>Ma thèse de doctorat vise à améliorer notre compréhension des processus d'assemblage du ribosome bactérien et l'objectif global de mon travail de recherche est d'identifier les étapes de cette voie, qui peut être une cible potentielle pour de nouvelles molécules thérapeutiques. L'assemblage de ribosomes chez Escherichia coli en croissance active implique plusieurs évènements, dont la synthèse de 54 protéines ribosomales, et leur liaison aux ARN ribosomiques de façon hiérarchique. Plusieurs de ces évènements sont assistés par certain nombre de protéines accessoires, les facteurs d'assemblage, qui rendent le processus extrêmement rapide et efficace. Ma thèse de doctorat contribue aux nouvelles connaissances sur le mécanisme précis par lequel YjeQ et Era assistent le processus d'assemblage du ribosome. Des travaux récents indiquent que ces deux facteurs aident les dernières étapes de l'assemblage de la sous-unité 30S. Pour révéler le rôle précis de YjeQ dans le contexte de la sous-unité mature 30S, nous avons résolu la structure de la sous-unité 30S en complexe avec YjeQ, par Cryo-microscopie électronique (Cryo-EM). Nos données révèlent qu'en plus de fonctionner comme un facteur de maturation, YjeQ fonctionne également comme une protéine de contrôle qui teste la capacité de relecture de la sous-unité ribosomale, avant la libération de la particule dans le pool des ribosomes actifs. Ce travail fournit le premier exemple d'unfacteur d'assemblage bactérien qui teste un mécanisme de traduction spécifique de la sous-unité 30S. Pour examiner le rôle d'Era, nous avons utilisé la spectrométrie de masse quantitative (qSM), la thermophorèse à l'échelle microscopique (MST) et la technique de la cryo-EM. Nous avons d'abord déterminé, en utilisant la cryo-EM, les structures de l'intermédiaire d'assemblage accumulées dans E. Coli lors de la déplétion d'Era, à une résolution de 3.8Å. En outre, nous avons également résolu la structure de la sous-unité 30S mature dans le complexe avec l'Era. Nous avons trouvé que les bactéries déplétée en Era accumulaient principalement un intermédiaire d'assemblage avec des densités manquantes à la fois dans les domaines central et 3' mineur de la sous-unité 30S. Les densités des protéines ribosomiques bS21, bS1, uS3 et uS2 liées au domaine central étaient également manquantes. La structure de la sous-unité 30S en complexe avec Era a démontré que la liaison de ce facteur ramène la sous-unité mature à un état immature auquel manquent les densités des motifs intégrant le centre de décodage. Ces résultats suggèrent qu'Era facilite le repliement correct de la région de la plateforme de la sous-unité 30S. En outre, Era peut agir comme un espace réservé pour certaines des protéines ribosomales tardives et empêcher l'association prématurée de la sous-unité 30S avec la sous-unité 50S. Enfin, nous avons testé si YjeQ et Era exerçaient leur fonction en conjonction plutôt qu'indépendamment. À cette fin, nous avons obtenu la structure en Cryo-EM de la sous-unité 30S dans le complexe avec Era et YjeQ à une résolution de 3.8Å.  Cependant, nous n'avons pas pu observer de densité pour YjeQ dans cette structure. De plus, nous avons démontré qu'Era se lie à la cavité entre la tête et la plateforme et ramène la structure de la sous-unité 30S à son état immature. Ces résultats suggèrent qu'Era et YjeQ fonctionnent successivement pendant l'assemblage. Era se lie d'abord à la sous-unité d'assemblage et aide au repliement de la région de la plateforme en même temps qu'elle empêche la liaison de YjeQ. Une fois qu'Era est libérée, YjeQ se lie pour aider à la maturation du centre de décodage et tester l'efficacité de la sous-unité avant de la relâcher dans le pool de ribosomes actifs. Dans l'ensemble, cette thèse fournit de nouvelles pistes sur la compréhension de la fonction de deux GTPases importantes impliquées dans le processus d'assemblage du ribosome bactérien.</description><creator>Razi, Aida</creator><contributor>Joaquin Ortega (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Anatomy and Cell Biology</subject><title>Role of GTPases in assembly of the bacterial 30S subunit</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc786.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m265</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278w46m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: Food security, health and well-being for all are the second and third Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) of the 2030 Agenda set by the United Nations. Although global efforts have resulted in improvements in food security, health and well-being across the world, studies have shown that economic and political crises can rapidly undermine achievements in these areas and prevent countries from reaching both SDGs. However, the literature lacks continuous monitoring of food security, health, and well-being in affected countries; and despite Brazil's food security policies and universal healthcare system are recognized as a model for developing countries, no one has yet investigated the effects of the country's current financial and political crisis on its food security, health, and well-being. Objectives: To fill these gaps, this study aimed to assess the changes in food security status, health, and well-being before and during Brazil's current crisis, as well as to explore their associations with individual, economic, psychosocial and environmental factors. Methods: This is a cross-sectional study based on population-representative data (n= 356,667) from two different sources: the Brazilian National Household Sample Survey and the Gallup World Poll. Household food security status was measured by a shorter version of the Brazilian Food Insecurity Scale, consisting of the first 8 questions of the original scale.  Health and well-being were measured by the Personal Life Index and the Life Evaluation Index. Descriptive analyses and logistic regression models were performed to assess the changes in food security, health status, and well-being and to investigate the factors associated with these changes. All tests were performed using the Statistical Package for the Social Sciences (SPSS), version 23, and evaluated at the 0.05 significance level. Results: There was deterioration in food security and well-being during the crisis. The percentage of households classified as food secure declined by 36% (76% in 2013 to 49% in 2017), severe food insecurity tripled (4% in 2013 to 12% in 2017) and the prevalence of respondents classified as "thriving" declined by almost 30% (63% in 2013 to 44% in 2017). This deterioration of food security status disproportionately affected the poor, increasing by six times the chances of being food insecure among the poorest strata. In addition, those who reported a low job climate, lack of social support and low level of education were twice more likely to be food insecure. Rather than income, health status and well-being were most associated with food insecurity, increased age and lack of social support, followed by the low level of education, poor community environment and dissatisfaction with the healthcare system. Conclusions: Despite its noteworthy social policy framework, during the crisis, Brazil suffered from a great deterioration of food security and well-being. These findings indicate the need for emergency policies, which should focus on strengthening access to food, healthcare, and education, improving community environment (quality of air, water, and infrastructure), and fostering social support.</description><description>Contexte: La sécurité alimentaire, la santé et le bien-être pour tous constituent les 2e et 3e Objectifs de Développement Durable (SDGs) étant fixés par les Nations Unies et devant être atteints avant 2030. Bien que les efforts mondiaux aient abouti à des améliorations de la sécurité alimentaire, de la santé et du bien-être dans le monde, des études ont montré que les crises économiques et politiques peuvent à la fois compromettre les prouesses accomplies dans ces domaines, ainsi qu'empêcher les pays d'atteindre ces deux SDGs. Cependant, il existe un manque d'information dans la littérature sur la surveillance continue de la sécurité alimentaire, de la santé et du bien-être dans les pays affectés par des crises économiques et politiques. Au Brésil, les politiques de sécurité alimentaire et le système de santé universel implémentés sont utilisés comme modèle de base, à l'échelle globale, pour les pays en voie de développement. Cependant, jusqu'à maintenant, aucune étude n'a été réalisée afin d'étudier les effets de la crise financière et politique actuelle du Brésil sur la sécurité alimentaire, la santé et le bien-être du pays. Objectifs: Afin de combler ces lacunes, cette étude visait à évaluer les changements intervenus dans la sécurité alimentaire, la santé et le bien-être avant et durant la crise brésilienne, ainsi qu'à explorer leurs associations avec des facteurs individuels, économiques, psychosociaux et environnementaux. Méthodes: Il s'agit d'une étude transversale basée sur des données représentatives de la population (n= 356 667) provenant de deux sources différentes: «l'Enquête Nationale Brésilienne» et le «Gallup World Poll». L'état de la sécurité alimentaire des ménages a été mesuré par le biais d'une version réduite de l'échelle Brésilienne d'Insécurité Alimentaire comprenant les huit premières questions de l'échelle originale. La santé et le bien-être ont été mesurés à l'aide de «l 'Indice de Santé Personnelle» et de «l'Indice d'Évaluation de la Vie». Des analyses descriptives et des modèles de régression logistique ont été réalisés afin d'évaluer les changements intervenus dans la sécurité alimentaire, l'état de santé et le bien-être ainsi que d'examiner les facteurs reliés à ces changements. Tous les tests ont été effectués à l'aide du Progiciel Statistique pour les Sciences Sociales (SPSS), version 23, et ont été évalués utilisant un seuil de signification de 0,05. Résultats: La sécurité alimentaire et le bien-être se sont détériorés au courant de la crise. Le pourcentage de sécurité alimentaire dans les ménages a diminué de 36% (76% en 2013 à 49% en 2017), l'insécurité alimentaire sévère a triplée (4% en 2013 à 12% en 2017) et la prévalence des répondants classés comme «prospères» a été réduite de près de 30% (63% en 2013 à 44% en 2017). Cette détérioration de la sécurité alimentaire a touché les pauvres de manière disproportionnée, multipliant par six les risques d'être en situation d'insécurité alimentaire au sein des ménages pauvres. En outre, les personnes ayant déclaré avoir de faibles perspectives économiques et professionnelles, un manque de soutien social et un faible niveau d'éducation étaient deux fois plus susceptibles d'être en situation d'insécurité alimentaire. De plus, l'état de santé et le bien-être étaient davantage liés à l'insécurité alimentaire, au vieillissement et au manque de soutien social, comparés au revenu, et étaient suivis par un faible niveau d'éducation, un environnement communautaire précaire et le mécontentement par rapport au système de santé. Conclusions: Malgré ses politiques sociales notables, le Brésil a connu une grave détérioration de la sécurité alimentaire et du bien-être durant la crise. Ces résultats indiquent la nécessité de mettre en place des politiques d'urgence axées sur le renforcement de l'accès à l'alimentation, au système de santé et à l'éducation, ainsi que sur l'amélioration de l'environnement communautaire et sur la favorisation du soutien social.</description><creator>Rezende Machado de Sousa, Luna</creator><contributor>Hugo Melgar-Quiñonez (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Human Nutrition</subject><title>Food security, health and well-being in times of financial and political crisis in Brazil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r067z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278w46m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225d30q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Depuis le commencement de l'exploration spatiale, l'usage et les applications militaires ont toujours occupés une place importante dans l'espace. Aujourd'hui, les technologies spatiales continuent d'avantager grandement les forces armées des puissances spatiales, tant au niveau des communications et de la navigation, qu'à celui de la reconnaissance. Malgré le fait que ces satellites fournissent des services essentiels lors de combats terrestres, ils ont rarement été la cible d'attaque directe.  Néanmoins, même en l'absence d'attaque, le développement et les tests d'armes antisatellites (ASATs) existe depuis de nombreuses années. La technologie principale, les systèmes à ascension directe, généralement constitués de missiles balistiques, ont la capacité de détruire un satellite en orbite lorsque celui-ci passe dans un cadran sus-jacent au lanceur. Cependant, ces dernières années ont vues le développement d'un nouveau type d'ASAT : les armes coorbitales. Cette nouvelle technologie, aussi destructrice qu'un missile balistique, a le net avantage de pouvoir se camoufler parmi les autres satellites jusqu'au moment de l'attaque. Cette nouvelle menace soulève maintes questions pour les puissances spatiales, entre autre sur la possible légalité et l'étendue des obligations encourues par l'État ciblé lors d'une frappe préventive contre une telle arme. La présente recherche étudiera un tel scénario et analysera l'habileté de l'État ciblé à utiliser la force dans un contexte de légitime défense, sous le cadre légal actuellement applicable dans l'espace. L'introduction de cette thèse présentera les informations relatives à la problématique, l'objectif visé ainsi que la terminologie et la méthodologie formant la base de cette recherche. La première partie couvrira la menace des armes ASAT coorbitales, en contextualisant les caractéristiques de celles-ci face aux menaces historiques. Ensuite, la seconde partie analysera les lois et traités applicables, d'une part quant à l'utilisation de la force dans l'espace et d'autre part sur ceux spécifiques aux ASATs coorbitaux. Finalement, la troisième partie présentera une prémisse qui, selon le droit international actuel, permettraient à un État ciblé d'utiliser la force, de manière préventive, contre un ASAT coorbital.</description><description>From the beginning of humankind's quest into outer space, military application and utilization has been at the forefront.  Today, assets in space continue to provide militaries of spacefaring States with numerous advantages in areas such as communication, navigation and reconnaissance.  While satellites that deliver these services provide benefits for terrestrial battles, they have remained relatively outside the crosshairs of a direct attack.    Despite remaining free from an actual attack, the development and testing of antisatellite weapons (ASATs) has existed for decades.  Primarily, the focus has been on direct-ascent ASATs, or ground to space missiles, capable of destroying an orbital satellite as it passes overhead.  However, in recent years the development of a new type of ASAT has emerged.  Co-orbital ASATs provide similar lethal results as direct-ascent ASATs, but with the ability to camouflage amongst other satellites until attacking quickly and simultaneously.  This new threat poses questions for spacefaring States, among which are whether and to what extent a target State whose satellites are being followed by such ASATs, could legally strike first to save its space assets.  This thesis explores such a scenario and analyzes the target State's ability to use force in self-defense under the current legal structure in outer space. The introduction to this thesis provides information on the issue itself, the objectives of the thesis, terminology to be used, as well as the confines and methodology in which the thesis will operate.  Part I addresses the threat from co-orbital ASATs against a historical backdrop to contextualize the uniqueness of this emerging danger.  Part II discusses the law that applies to the issue, first to the use of force in outer space and then to the specific space systems of co-orbital ASATs.  Finally, Part III sets forth a legal justification under current international law that it is argued would permit a State to use force against co-orbital ASATs before its own space assets suffered harm.           </description><creator>Fox, David</creator><contributor>Brian Havel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Air and Space Law</subject><title>Defensive strike: International law and the use of force in self-defense against co-orbital antisatellite weapons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qc03p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d30q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m633f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'année 2018 a marqué les 50 ans depuis la première Conférence des Nations-Unies sur l'exploration et les utilisations pacifiques de l'espace extra-atmosphérique. L'année passera et le monde aura continué de changer comme toujours, avec pour seule constante, ce changement et la capacité dynamique du droit à s'adapter et prévaloir. Le droit international, et plus particulièrement, le droit relatif à l'espace extra-atmosphérique est bien au fait de l'évolution technologique, géopolitique et géoéconomique, et a su s'adapter à ces conditions changeantes.Ce qui reste à voir, toutefois, est sa pertinence pour les temps futurs. En effet, le changement de paradigme quant au nombre, à la variété des acteurs et problèmes touchant au droit aérospatial et au rôle de ce droit international dans l'adaptation aux changements est marquant.  Le droit de l'espace, sous la forme des normes découlant du Traité de l'espace de 1967, a vu le jour afin de traiter du problème central de l'époque, soit la prévention de l'expansion des conflits terrestres vers l'espace extra-atmosphérique. Le traité aura bien atteint son objectif, considérant qu'aucun conflit n'ait migré vers l'espace dans les 50 dernières années, malgré l'intensité des tensions sur terre.Toutefois, pour le futur, bien que le rôle du droit international dans le maintient de la paix dans l'espace soit important, son rôle risque de devenir d'autant plus important pour favoriser l'usage pacifique de cet espace extra-atmosphérique. En effet, l'usage pacifique ne se limite pas à la prévention des conflits armés, mais à la plus large conduite des affaires civiles pacifiques, sans crainte des problèmes posés par de potentielles collisions avec des débris spatiaux, par la dégradation environnementale ou encore par l'usage commercial inéquitable de l'espace. À cette fin, ce mémoire de recherche proposera de dépasser les termes traditionnellement étroits de l'interprétation donnée à l'expression « usage pacifique de l'espace », pour aller vers une conception plus large, contextuelle et pragmatique. Ainsi, le projet proposera une analyse de la capacité des normes existantes à répondre à l'augmentation fulgurante du nombre de petits satellites. De plus, il sera discuté des possibilités de convergence des acteurs impliqués dans l'usage de l'espace pour faire face à ces difficultés dans une logique de développement durable. Ce projet de recherche visera donc à identifier des opportunités pour la coopération internationale dans un contexte d'intensification de l'usage commercial de l'espace, et sur les pistes à suivre pour cette convergence d'intérêts vers un développement harmonieux du droit international. Vraisemblablement, l'augmentation du nombre de petits satellites s'intensifiera dans les années à venir, et le droit international devra s'adapter. Ainsi, ce problème pratique est d'une grande importance pour le maintient des relations entre les acteurs impliqués dans le développement de l'espace extra-atmosphérique.</description><description>The year 2018 marks 50 years since the first United Nations Conference on the Exploration and Peaceful Use of Outer Space. The year shall pass and the world would change as it always has. The only constant would be change and the dynamism of law to respond to change and prevail. International law, particularly, the law related to outer space has been alive to the shifting patterns of technology, geo-politics, geo-economics and has evolved to remain relevant. What remains to be seen is whether it would continue to be as relevant in the times to come. There has been a paradigm shift in the number and variety of actors and issues in space and the role of international law in absorbing and adapting to change has been significant. Space Law, in particular, the Outer Space Treaty, came about in 1967 to address the prime concerns of those times-of preventing terrestrial conflict from spiraling into outer space. International law has evidently served its purpose, considering that there has been no conflict in space in the past 50 years despite intense tensions on earth. As we move into the future, the role of law in maintaining peace in space continues to be relevant, but equally relevant is the role of law in enabling peaceful use of space as is ordinarily understood. A peaceful use not just restricted to conflict prevention, but the wider expanse of conducting affairs in space 'peaceably', without fear of debris collisions, environmental degradation and unfair commercial gain, competition among other things. Towards this end, this thesis seeks to go beyond the traditional narrow confines of the treaty interpretation of 'peaceful use of space' to a broader, more contextual and pragmatic interpretation. Thereafter, it analyses the ability of existing international law to address common vulnerabilities arising out of the surge in small satellites and how convergence on vulnerabilities can pave the way to sustainable development of space. Additionally, it seeks to identify opportunities in international cooperation arising out of the rising commercialization of space and how best this convergence of interests can be harnessed by international law for harmonious development. The surge in small satellites will continue into the future as also international cooperation in space, the topic is hence extremely significant and addresses a practical problem.</description><creator>Nair, Kiran</creator><contributor>Ram S Jakhu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Air and Space Law</subject><title>Conflict to convergence: role of international law in fostering international cooperation and sustainable development in space</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s1618425.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m633f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225d310</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the EU, the recent entry into the force of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is expected to inspire a greater number of private enforcement claims arising from the infringement of data protection laws.  Social networking services (SNS) such as Facebook, Twitter or Instagram carry a significant risk of being faced with such claims due to the services they offer and their business model, both of which have the processing of personal data at their center. This being said, although a regulation, the GDPR still allows for many instances where the Member States may enact divergent data protection laws, while providing no solution for conflict of laws issues. This Thesis analyzes the possibility and the extent of resort to Rome I in determining the applicable law to those claims raised against SNSs by their users. It concludes that the protective connecting factor found under Art. 6(2) of Rome I should be effectively implemented to ensure that the users enjoy maximum protection while providing legal certainty for SNSs.</description><description>Le Règlement Général sur la Protection des Données (RGPD) est récemment entré en vigueur et il devrait susciter, au sein de l'UE, de nombreux recours privés pour la violation des lois sur la protection des données. Les services des réseaux sociaux (SNS) tels que Facebook, Twitter ou Instagram présentent un risque important d'être confrontés à de telles réclamations en raison des services qu'ils proposent et de leur modèle économique, les deux étant centré sur le traitement des données personnelles. En revanche, même s'il s'agit d'un règlement, le RGPD permet, dans de nombreux cas, l'adoption par des États membres de règles divergentes en matière de protection des données alors qu'il ne propose aucune solution aux problèmes de conflits de lois. Ce mémoire analyse la possibilité et l'étendue de l'application du Règlement Rome I pour déterminer le droit applicable aux réclamations formulées contre les SNS par leurs utilisateurs. Il conclut que le facteur de rattachement de protection prévu à l'article 6 (2) de Rome I devrait être mis en œuvre de manière efficace pour garantir aux utilisateurs une protection maximale tout en assurant la sécurité juridique des SNS.</description><creator>Uludere, Eda</creator><contributor>Genevieve Saumier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Law</subject><title>Where all roads lead: private enforcement of data protection laws against social networking services under Rome I</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx673.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d310</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795993x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Concerns over environmental sustainability in Canada have increased in recent years leading to changes to the discharge limits of certain contaminants like biological oxygen demand (25 mg/L), ammonia (1.25 mg NH3-N/L), and total suspended solids (25 mg/L) in effluent from wastewater treatment facilities collecting an average daily influent volume of 100 m3 or more. Contaminants of emerging concern (CECs) like pharmaceuticals, hormones, pesticides, herbicides, and other natural and synthetic compounds found in effluent from wastewater treatment facilities remain unregulated in Canada but may persist in the environment and lead to negative environmental outcomes. Given the number of Canadians who rely upon lagoons for their wastewater treatment in small, rural, and remote communities, there is a need to investigate and develop new, cost-effective strategies to improve the quality of wastewater treated in lagoons. Ozonation has been shown to improve the removal of a variety of wastewater contaminants (including CECs) from real wastewater through direct means (oxidation of compounds) and indirect means (increased dissolved oxygen, enhanced biodegradability) and was investigated in the present thesis as a potential strategy to improve wastewater treatment in lagoons. Two pilot tests were conducted to investigate the effects of ozonation on contaminant removal in lagoons. Samples of wastewater were collected from several locations in each lagoon prior to ozonation, during ozonation, and after ozonation and analyzed to determine the effect of ozonation on the removal of conventional contaminants and CECs. The samples were analyzed for biological oxygen demand (BOD), chemical oxygen demand (COD), total ammonia, unionized ammonia, total dissolved solids (TDS), total suspended solids (TSS), nitrite, nitrate, toxicity to Vibrio fischeri, and for the presence of fifteen CECs. For the first pilot test at New Credit First Nation, there were reductions in the BOD and total ammonia during the ozonation period. There was a decrease in toxicity to Vibrio fischeri and a further decrease in total ammonia during the post-ozonation period. The concentrations of three CECs (carbamazepine, gemfibrozil, and ibuprofen) decreased during the ozonation period, and the gemfibrozil concentration continued to decrease during the post-ozonation period. For the second pilot test at Rainy River First Nation, there were reductions in BOD, total ammonia, and unionized ammonia in the post-ozonation period. There was also a reduction in time from ice-off at the lagoon until compliance with the Wastewater System Effluent Regulations (WSERs) in 2018 compared to 2017 and 2016, but this time was still longer than in 2015 or 2014. Laboratory experiments with synthetic wastewater showed no improvements in removal of contaminants due to ozonation in a subsequent biodegradation process by Bacillus, Pseudomonas, and Rhodococcus species, and an increase in the formation nitrate at one of the dose tested. Direct removal of two indicator compounds (caffeine and sulfamethoxazole) by ozone was observed. The optimal dosing strategy for the removal of caffeine was different than for the removal of sulfamethoxazole. Overall, it is unclear if the pilot tests led to improvements in each lagoon and laboratory experiments with synthetic wastewater did provide evidence of an optimal ozone dosing strategy to improve the removal of contaminants. Monitoring at New Credit First Nation and Rainy River First Nation may provide further insight on the impact of ozonation on contaminant removal processes in lagoons. Further laboratory experiments using a more complex synthetic wastewater or real lagoon wastewater may also help determine the impact of ozonation on contaminant removal and the optimal dosing strategy to minimize costs associated with ozone production.</description><description>Les préoccupations environnementales au Canada ont augmenté au cours des dernières années, ce qui a entraîné des changements aux limites de rejet concernant la demande biochimique en oxygène (25 mg/L), de l'ammoniac (1,25 mg NH3-N), et des matières en suspension (25 mg/L) pour les effluent des stations de traitement dont le volume moyen quotidien est de 100 m3 ou plus. Les contaminants d'intérêt émergent (CIE) présents dans les eaux usées ne sont pas réglementés au Canada, peuvent persister dans l'environnement et entraîner des effets sur l'environnement. Étant donné le nombre de Canadiens qui dépendent d'étangs pour le traitement de leurs eaux usées, surtout dans les petites communautés rurales et éloignées, il est nécessaire d'étudier et de développer de nouvelles stratégies peu couteuses pour améliorer la qualité des eaux usées traitées dans ces étangs. Il a été démontré que l'ozonation améliore l'élimination d'une variété de contaminants (y compris les CIEs) des eaux usées réelles par des moyens directs (oxydation des composés) et indirects (augmentation de l'oxygène dissous, biodégradabilité accrue) et a été étudiée dans la présente thèse comme une stratégie possible pour améliorer le traitement d'eau usée dans les étangs. Deux essais pilotes ont été réalisés pour étudier les effets de l'ozonation dans les étangs. Des échantillons d'eaux usées ont été prélevés à plusieurs endroits dans chaque étang avant, pendant et après l'ozonation et analysés pour déterminer l'effet de l'ozonation sur l'élimination des contaminants classiques et des CIE. Les échantillons ont été analysés pour la demande biochimique en oxygène (DBO), la demande chimique en oxygène (DCO), l'ammoniac total, l'ammoniac non ionisé, les matières dissous totales (MDT), les matières en suspension totales (MST), le nitrite, le nitrate, la toxicité envers Vibrio fischeri et la présence de quinze CIEs. Pour l'essai pilote à la Première nation de New Credit, des réductions de la DBO et de l'ammoniac total ont été observées pendant la période d'ozonation. La toxicité envers Vibrio fischeri et la concentration en ammoniac total ont diminué pendant la période suivant l'ozonation. Les concentrations de trois CIEs (carbamazépine, gemfibrozil et ibuprofène) ont diminué pendant la période d'ozonation, et la concentration de gemfibrozil a continué de diminuer pendant la période suivant l'ozonation. Pour l'essai pilote à la Première nation de Rainy River, des réductions de la DBO, de l'ammoniac total et de l'ammoniac non ionisé ont été observées au cours de la période suivant l'ozonation. Il y a eu une réduction du temps entre la fonte du couvert de glace de l'étang et la conformité aux limites imposées par le Règlement sur les effluents des systèmes d'assainissement des eaux usées en 2018 par rapport à 2017 et 2016, mais ce temps était plus long qu'en 2015 ou 2014. Des expériences de laboratoire avec des eaux usées synthétiques n'ont montré aucune amélioration de l'élimination des contaminants par l'ozonation dans un subséquent processus de biodégradation par trois espèces de bactérie Bacillus, Pseudomonas et Rhodococcus, mais une augmentation de formation du nitrate a été observée à une des doses étudiées. L'élimination directe de deux CIEs (caféine et sulfaméthoxazole) par l'ozone a été observée. La stratégie optimale pour l'élimination de la caféine était différente de celle du sulfaméthoxazole. L'absence d'essais de contrôle ne permet pas de conclure si les essais pilotes ont mené à des améliorations dans chaque étang et les expériences en laboratoire avec l'eau usée synthétique n'ont pas permis d'identifier une stratégie optimale de dosage de l'ozone pour améliorer l'élimination des contaminants. La surveillance aux Premières nations de New Credit et de Rainy River pourrait permettre de mieux comprendre l'effet de l'ozonation sur les processus d'élimination des contaminants dans les étangs des eaux usées en fournissant un point de comparaison des résultats. </description><creator>Schlageter, Beauregard</creator><contributor>Viviane Yargeau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Chemical Engineering</subject><title>Ozonation for the improvement of wastewater quality in lagoons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z0607.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795993x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rk31v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'assemblage des ribosomes bactériens est un mécanisme robuste pouvant suivre des voies parallèles. Plusieurs facteurs d'assemblage facilitent ce processus, notamment la GTPase RgbA impliquée dans l'assemblage de la grande sous-unité 50S chez les Bacillus subtilis. Les particules intermédiaires immatures appelés 45S s'accumulent quand RbgA est déplétée ou mutée sur son site catalytique (RbgA-F6A). En présence de RbgA, les particules 45S sont capables d'évoluer vers une sous-unité 50S chez les bactéries de type sauvage mais ils sont incapables de le faire efficacement chez les mutants pour qui la croissance est considérablement réduite. Les mutations suppressives dans le gène codant pour la protéine ribosomique uL6 corrigent partiellement le défaut de croissance causée par RbgA-F6A. Le processus de suppression implique l'accumulation de particules immatures dites 44S, capables de devenir des sous-unité 50S dans le contexte de mutation RbgA-F6A. Ici, nous élucidons ce mécanisme de suppression. En analysant la structures de la particule 45S résolue grâce à la cryo-microscopie électronique, nous avons constaté que RbgA induit le positionnement correct des hélices 42, 43 et 44 (h42-44) au sein de la particule. L'incorporation de la protéine de liaison tardive uL16 au niveau de l'hélice h42 peut solliciter cette position pour diriger la maturation de la sous-unité ribosomique. Les hélices h42-44 sont hautement flexibles au sein des particules 44S ayant une mutation uL6-R3C ce qui peut permettre l'incorporation de uL16 sans requérir une RbgA fonctionnel. Dans la sous-unité 50S mature, les protéines ribosomique uL14 et uL19 se fixent près du site potentiel de liaison de RbgA-F6A et elles sont absentes dans les particules 44S purifiées à de forte concentration de sels. Ces données indiquent que uL14 et uL19 se lient faiblement aux sous-unités immatures pouvant, de ce fait, affecter l'interaction de RbgA-F6A aux particules 44S. En effet, l'analyse en microscale thermophoresis confirme que l'affinité de liaison de RbgA-F6A pour les particules 44S est inférieure à l'affinité de liaison de RbgA pour les particules 45S. Ainsi, une liaison de faible affinité peut permettre à RbgA-F6A de se dissocier de la particule ribosomale après son action et, par conséquent, de compenser son activité GTPasique très réduite. Cette étude donne un aperçu du rôle fonctionnel de RbgA durant l'assemblage de la sous-unité 50S et souligne son importance dans la création d'un site de liaison pour la protéine ribosomique uL16.</description><description>Bacterial ribosome assembly is a robust mechanism that can proceed in parallel pathways. Several assembly factors assist this process, including the GTPase RbgA that plays a role in the assembly of the large 50S subunit in Bacillus subtilis. Immature intermediates called 45S particles accumulate upon the depletion of RbgA or the expression of RbgA-F6A that has reduced GTPase activity. The 45S particles are able to mature to the 50S subunit in the presence of RbgA in the wild type bacteria, but unable to do so efficiently in the RbgA-F6A background that results in reduced growth rate of bacteria. Suppressor mutations in the large ribosomal protein uL6 partially corrects the growth defect caused by RbgA-F6A. The suppression process involves the accumulation of 44S particles, which are able to efficiently mature to the 50S subunit in a RbgA-F6A background. Here, we elucidate this suppression mechanism. Cryo-electron microscopy structures show that RbgA induces the correct positioning of the helices 42 to 44 (h42-44) in the 45S structure. Incorporation of the late binding protein uL16 that binds to h42 may require this correct position in order to drive 50S subunit maturation. The h42-44 are highly flexible in the 44S particles with uL6-R3C mutation, which may allow the incorporation of uL16 without requiring functional RbgA. Dissociation of two proteins, uL14 and uL19, from the high salt purified 44S particles show that these proteins are weakly bound to the 44S particles near the potential binding site of RbgA-F6A, and therefore may affect the interaction of RbgA-F6A with 44S particles. Indeed, binding affinity measured by microscale thermophoresis confirmed that RbgA-F6A binds to the 44S particles with lower affinity compared to the binding of RbgA and 45S particles. Low affinity binding may allow RbgA-F6A to dissociate from the ribosomal particle upon its action, and therefore compensate for its reduced GTPase activity. This study provides insight into the functional role of RbgA in the 50S subunit assembly and highlights its importance in forming the binding site for uL16.</description><creator>Wasi, Tanzila</creator><contributor>Joaquin Ortega (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Anatomy and Cell Biology</subject><title>Function of the GTPase RbgA in prokaryotic ribosome assembly</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gq48w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rk31v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cw364</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La technologie de l'aile delta inversée, autrefois été conçue par l'allemand Alexander Lippisch, est utilisée de nos jours par certains fabricants pour la conception d'une nouvelle génération de véhicules à effet de sol. Malgré le regain en popularité de ce moyen de transport économique et écologique, peu d'articles scientifiques sont actuellement disponibles. Cette thèse, destinée à l'étude des tourbillons générées par différentes configurations d'aile delta inversée (l'angle de flèche = 65˚) dans un écoulement libre, permettra d'améliorer les connaissances sur ce type d'aile et d'établir une référence pour des futures études en effet de sol. Des mesures d'écoulement de la traînée à proximité de l'aile ont été obtenues en utilisant une sonde de pression à sept trous, à des vitesses subsoniques et un nombre de Reynolds fixé à 3.3x10^5, plus particulièrement sur l'évolution et les caractéristiques des tourbillons en bout d'aile à un angle d'attaque sélectionné de 16˚. Les différents modèles d'ailes ont été configurés avec le recadrage d'apex traînant, le dièdre négatif, et des winglets, séparément et ensemble. Des bandes latérales, communément appelé «Gurney Flap», ont également été utilisées en tant que dispositif passif d'augmentation de portance. Les mesures de portance et de traînée ont été obtenues pour supporter les mesures d'écoulement. Le recadrage d'apex traînant a eu un impact négligeable sur la vorticité mais important sur les coefficients aérodynamiques de l'aile. Par ailleurs, la modification du dièdre négatif, en anglais «Anhedral angle», a engendrée des vitesses tangentielles plus grandes et une traînée minimisée. Les bandes latérales ont augmenté la force du tourbillon, la portance et la traînée des différentes configurations. Les winglets ont générés une paire de tourbillons co-rotatifs et une circulation inchangée. La portance, calculée théoriquement à l'aide de la circulation du tourbillon, a été sous-estimé analytiquement par rapport aux valeurs expérimentales de 1.5 à 11.3%. Cela suggère que la force du tourbillon d'une aile delta inversée peut représenter la majorité de la portance réelle. Pour conclure, à partir des mesures de vorticité, la traînée induite a été calculée et estimée à environ 17.6 à 27.5% de la traînée totale.</description><description>The reverse delta wing (RDW) planform is uniquely seen on the Lippisch-type wing-in-ground effect vehicles that have emerged as a new and sustainable mode of commercial sea travel in the last decade, yet public archives of RDWs are rarely seen and relevant academic studies are scarce. This study investigates wingtip vortices generated by different RDW configurations outside ground effect (GE) as to expand knowledge about RDWs and to establish potential benchmark data for future studies in GE. Flow measurements of 16" in chord 65˚-sweep RDW models were obtained using a seven-hole pressure probe at low subsonic speeds and a Reynolds number of 3.3x10^5. Major attention was paid to the streamwise evolution and characteristics of the tip vortices at the angle of attack of 16˚. The various wing models were configured with, separately and jointly, trailing-apex cropping, anhedral and winglets. Gurney flaplike strips were also examined as a lift augmentation and passive flow control device. In addition, the lift and drag forces of each configuration were measured via a force balance to supplement the flow-field data. The cropping had a minimal impact on the RDW vortices and aerodynamic forces while the anhedral engendered faster-rotating vortices and minimized lift-induced drag. The side-edge strips enhanced the vortex strength and wing lift, but also drag. The winglets generated a co-rotating vortex pair but kept the vortex strength mostly intact. Lift based on the total vortex circulation underestimated the experimental values by 1.5-11.3%, suggesting that the RDW vortex strength can represent majority of the actual lift. Lastly, induced drag computed using the vorticity flow field constituted 17.6-27.5% of the total drag.</description><creator>He, Mengyizhe</creator><contributor>Timothy Lee (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>An experimental investigation of wingtip vortices generated by a reverse delta wing of different wing configurations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k7333.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cw364</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g236n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les troubles de la voix résultent en une altération de production vocale ce qui interfère avec la communication parlée. Le trouble le plus fréquent survient dans la couche superficielle de la lamina propria des cordes vocales. L'injection de substances telles que le gras ou un hydrogel est la stratégie la plus communément utilisée pour permettre la régénération de cette zone. Cependant, de travaux récents ont montré. Qu'après injection, ces matériaux peuvent être rapidement éliminés par le système phagocytaire mononucléaire, stoppant leur fonction régénérative. Il a notamment déjà été montré que l'encapsulation dans des microsphères d'un diamètre de 500 µm supprimer la réponse immunitaire. Ces microsphères ont une longue durée de vie. De plus, leurs favorise la diffusion excellente des cellules. Le but de la présente étude est d'évaluer l'efficacité des microsphères contenant des fibroblastes de cordes vocales pour induire la régénération de la lamina propria des cordes vocales humaines. La fabrication et la caractérisation in vitro de microsphères est l'objet premier de cette recherche. L'électrodéposition a été utilisé afin de fabriquer des microsphères en alginate. Exploitant la surface électronégative de l'alginate, la technique d'assemblage de poly-électrolytes couche par couche a permis d'obtenir différentes conformations, incluant de l'alginate-poly-L-lysine-alginate (APA) et alginate-chitosane (Al-Cs). Des microsphères réparties de manière homogènes, ayant une forme sphérique ainsi qu'un diamètre de 552.74 ±7.72 µm ont été obtenues. La concentration optimale de cellules insérées dans les microsphères a été estimée en utilisant un microscope. Pour les microsphères d'alginate et Al-Cs, une grande concentration cellulaire cause un grand nombre de malformation. Au contraire, les microsphères APA ont moins tendance à se déformer lorsqu'elles sont chargées avec une grande concentration de cellules. Dans tous les cas, les microsphères remplies de 10x105 cellules se gonflent et se déchirent. Leurs propriétés mécaniques ont été mesurées, entre autres: 1) la stabilité mécanique à 37°C et 2) la pression osmotique. La rigidité des matériaux a été évaluée à l'aide d'un rhéomètre à torsion et d'un microscope à force atomique. Les tests de stabilité mécanique et de pression osmotique ont montré que la microsphère d'alginate est la plus stable et est la moins fragile après implantation. La microsphère APA est moins stable dans le temps que les autres types de microsphères. Le module d'Young de l'hydrogel d'alginate pur réticulé avec CaCl2 est de 3 kPa. La modification avec une couche supplémentaire de PLL et d'alginate dilué a diminué la rigidité jusqu'à 1,92 kPa. La couche supplémentaire de chitosane a augmenté la rigidité locale jusqu'à 12,23 kPa. Les résultats indiquent que tous les hydrogels conviennent à la régénération VF-LP.Les propriétés de gonflement ont été évaluées en mesurant les changements de diamètre des microsphères lorsque celles-ci sont stockés dans du PBS. Les microsphères d'alginate, APA et Al-Cs ont respectivement un pourcentage de gonflement de 33,67%, 2,32% et 52,76%. L'épaisseur de la membrane de chitosane et PLL a été caractérisée en utilisant la génipine comme marqueur fluorogène et un microscope confocal à balayage laser. La membrane PLL est plus épaisse et plus uniforme que la membrane de chitosane. En termes de cytotoxicité, nulle des trois configurations de microsphères n'ont compromis la viabilité des fibroblastes. Toutes ont induit la prolifération des cellules après 24 h et 48 h d'incubation.Dans l'ensemble, les propriétés des microsphères d'alginate semblent des plus propices, c'est aussi le type de microsphère le plus facile à fabriquer. Les microsphères d'alginates semblent être un outil stable et fonctionnel de transport de cellules. Même si les microsphères sont souvent utilisées, leur emploi pour induire la régénération de la lamina propria des cordes vocales est originale à cette étude.</description><description>Voice disorders can be defined as the absence of normal voice production which interferes with speech communication. It is estimated that these problems cost in the United States a total of $2.5 billion annually. The most common disorders occur in the vocal fold Lamina Propria (VF-LP), specifically in the superficial layer. Material injection is the most frequently used strategy to regenerate the injured VF-LP. But recent work has shown that commonly used materials may be rapidly cleared by the mononuclear phagocyte system after injection, hampering their regeneration function. Microspheres (Ms) with a diameter of 500 µm are able to reduce the immune response. Thus, Ms can remain in the body for a longer time period. Ms are considered ideal substrates for cell delivery due to their optimal diffusion properties. The aim of the present study was to evaluate the feasibility of using Ms containing human vocal fold fibroblasts to induce VF-LP regeneration. This evaluation was done through the fabrication and in vitro characterization of Ms. Electrospraying was used to fabricate alginate Ms. Taking advantage of the electronegative surface of alginate, layer-by-layer assembly of polyelectrolytes was used to fabricate different Ms configurations, including Alginate-Poly-L-Lysine-Alginate (APA) and Alginate-Chitosan (Al-Cs). Homogeneous size distribution, and a spherical morphology with a diameter of 552.74±7.72 µm were obtained. The optimal load cell concentration, 4x105 cells/ml, of the Ms was determined based on the morphology and integrity of the Ms using optical microscope. In the case of Al Ms and Al-Cs Ms, excessive cell concentration caused many Ms to be deformed. Conversely, APA Ms were less prone to deformation upon high cell concentration. In all cases, the Ms swelled and ruptured when 10x105 cells/ml were loaded into the Ms. The results indicate that cells were randomly distributed within the Ms. The mechanical stability at 37°C was determined. Alginate-Ms and Al-Cs Ms were stable. Only 7% and 6% of the Ms, respectively, were found to be broken after 10 days of testing. In contrast 28% of APA Ms broke on day 10. Osmotic pressure test showed that Al Ms were the toughest. The stiffness of the materials was evaluated using a torsional rheometer and an atomic force microscope (AFM).  The Young's modulus of pure alginate hydrogel crosslinked with CaCl2 was 3 kPa. The modification with an additional layer of PLL and additional diluted alginate decreased the stiffness to 1.92 kPa. The addition of one Cs layer increased the local stiffness to 12.23 kPa. The results indicate that all hydrogels stiffness was matched with native tissue. Swelling properties were evaluated by measuring the diameter changes of the Ms when stored in PBS. In the present study, alginate, APA, and Al-Cs Ms had swelling percentages of 33.67%, 2.32%, and 52.76%, respectively. The thickness of the Cs and PLL membrane was characterized using genipin as a fluorogenic marker, and confocal laser scanning microscopy. It was found that the PLL membrane was thicker, 21.55±1.88 µm, and more uniform than that of Cs membrane, 10.625 ± 0.88 µm. In terms of cytotoxicity, none of the three configurations of Ms compromised the viability of fibroblasts. All of them indicated proliferation of the cells after 24h and 48h of incubation. Alginate and Al-Cs Ms doubled the initial cell concentration, while APA Ms increased the initial cell population by up to 72%.Overall, the best balance of desirable properties was obtained for the alginate Ms, which also were the easiest group to fabricate. These results thus represent a first step in Ms design and fabrication to promote the regeneration of the VF. As such, alginate Ms were found to be a stable and functional cell delivery tool. Although Ms are extensively used for other organs, this is the first time that they are used and characterized with the purpose to induce the regeneration of the VF-LP, to the author's knowledge.</description><creator>Reyes, Alicia</creator><contributor>Satya Prakash (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Luc Mongeau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>In vitro analysis of polymeric microspheres containing human vocal fold fibroblasts for regeneration of vocal fold lamina propria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nt20g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g236n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Biological and Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483m375</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Approximately 10% of individuals claim penicillin allergy based on vague or remote histories and are permanently labeled β-lactam allergic. These individuals receive suboptimal non-β-lactams for intraoperative prophylaxis prolonging operations and experience negative clinical outcomes. Clarifying penicillin allergic status is thus of major importance. This thesis examines  pre-operative allergy assessments including drug allergic history, penicillin skin testing and/or oral challenge on selection of perioperative antibiotics. It also examines the effectiveness of communicating the drug allergy patient de-labeling status to the surgical team. Patients referred from April 1st, 2015 to March 31st, 2017 for suspected β-lactam hypersensitivity were studied. Those having pre-operative allergy assessments within 6 months of surgery were analysed. Data collected included age, gender, drug allergy history, drug allergy skin testing, oral challenges along with the type of surgery, time of operating room entry, incision start time and intraoperative antibiotics.. Of the 194 patients evaluated, four were β-lactam allergic on skin testing. Among the remaining 190 skin test negative patients, 146 were β-lactam challenged. Only 5% of these reacted and considered β-lactam allergic. Cefazolin became the perioperative antibiotic of choice for the remaining 77% of non-allergic patients requiring antibiotic prophylaxis. Only 5 of the confirmed β-lactam allergic patients received intraoperative vancomycin. Patients not prescribed vancomycin saved on average  22 minutes in operative time. Among all 194 evaluated patients, 35 were given suboptimal alternative antibiotics perioperatively. These included 16 that tested negative for β-lactam allergy yet prescribed vancomycin and 17 that received clindamycin. The 2 remaining tested positive for β-lactam allergy and were erroneously given cefazolin. The suboptimal antibiotic use stemmed from poor reporting of the allergy evaluations. Factors included delays in transmitting the results from the allergy clinic in 12 patients, 15 patients reported being β-lactam allergic to the surgical team at the time of surgery despite having tested negative and the remaining 8 had no clear reason for being prescribed an alternative antibiotic. To identify causes of miscommunication, a questionnaire survey was sent to allergists, surgeons and anesthesiologists.. Results of the survey revealed that surgeons and anesthesiologists prefer direct and clear statements like "the patient is not allergic to penicillin" or "can be administered cefazolin"; while allergists preferred qualifying statements such as "at this time the patient is not allergic to penicillin, based on skin testing, oral challenge and clinical assessment". In summary, comprehensive penicillin allergy evaluation successfully de-labeled 94.3% of patients referred for pre-operative β-lactam allergy evaluation. Vancomycin was used only in five surgeries (3%) (those truly penicillin allergic) and cefazolin was subsequently prescribed for 120/155 (77.4%) of the de-labeled patients given antibiotics.. The reduced use of vancomycin minimized delays in initiation of incision time, thus improving operative efficiency. Multiple issues indicating poor communication were identified partially explaining the suboptimal antibiotic use and signifying a need for consensus statements in drug allergy reporting. The main limitation of the study was that pre-operative allergy referrals were not mandatory, thus not all pre-operative patients claiming to be β-lactam allergic were captured.</description><description>Approximativement 10% de la population se dit allergique à la pénicilline, basée sur un historique vague et nébuleux et est étiquetée allergique aux β-lactames de façon permanente.  Ces patients reçoivent une prophylaxie intra opératoire sub-optimale  prolongeant la chirurgie avec des effets négatifs. Une clarification du statut des allergies est importante. Cette thèse examine l'impact d'une vérification des allergies préopératoire  sur le choix de l'antibiothérapie. Elle examine aussi  la communication du statut des allergies à l'équipe chirurgicale. Les patients étudiés furent référés pour une hypersensibilité possible aux β-lactames entre  Avril 1, 2015 et Mars 31, 2017, incluant ceux ayant eu une vérification des allergies préopératoires 6 mois précédent la chirurgie. Les données obtenues comprenaient: sexe, historique de l'allergie, résultats des évaluations cutanées et orales,  type de chirurgie,  heure d'arrivée au bloc opératoire, heure du début de l'incision et les antibiotiques utilisés.Parmi 194 patients évalués, 4 patients furent considérés allergiques aux β-lactames suite au test cutané. Parmi les  190 autres patients, 146 ont reçu une provocation. Cinq % ont réagi et sont considérés allergiques. Cefazolin a été  l'antibiotique prophylactique  de choix pour  77% des patients non allergiques. Cinq patients, confirmés allergiques, ont reçu de la vancomycine. Le temps opératoire a été  réduit de 22 minutes chez les patients n'ayant pas reçu de vancomycine.   Des 194 patients évalués, 35 ont reçu une alternative non-optimale. Seize ont reçu de la vancomycine, 17 autres, de la clindamycine.  Deux patients positifs aux β-lactames ont reçu du cefazolin. Les problèmes de communications, sont à l'origine de l'utilisation sub-optimale des antibiotiques. Les résultats  de 12 ont été déposés dans le dossier médical électronique suite à la chirurgie Au moment de la chirurgie 15 patients se sont identifiés, allergiques aux β-lactames, en dépit des résultats  négatifs. Pour les 8 autres patients, aucune raison n'a pu être identifiée. Un questionnaire pour identifier les causes de mis-communication fut envoyé aux allergologues, chirurgiens et anesthésistes.Il révèle que les chirurgiens et les anesthésistes préfèrent une déclaration directe et claire. Ils optent pour des déclarations simple : «le patient n'est pas allergique à la pénicilline»,  «le patient peut recevoir de la pénicilline». Les allergologues préfèrent des déclarations telles que «à ce moment, le patient n'est pas allergique à la pénicilline en se basant sur le test cutané, la provocation orale et l'évaluation clinique».   En résumé, une évaluation complète des allergies à la pénicilline a permis de lever l'étiquette d'allergie chez 94.3% des patients référés à la clinique préopératoire. La vancomycine n'a été utilisée  que lors de  5 chirurgies (3%) alors que le cefazolin fut prescrit chez 120/155 (74%) patients. L'usage réduit de la vancomycine a permis de minimiser les délais du début d'incision. Des problèmes de communication identifiés expliquent en partie l'utilisation sous optimale des antibiotiques. Un consensus lors du rapport des résultats des tests est nécessaire.  La limite principale de l'étude est reliée au fait que les consultations préopératoires ne sont pas obligatoires ; seulement un partie des patient se disant allergiques aux β-lactames ont été capturés.</description><creator>Moussa, Yara</creator><contributor>Christos M Tsoukas (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Improving antibiotic stewardship: β-lactam allergy evaluation in the pre-operative setting and identifying barriers in communicating the results</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f796.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483m375</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988n335</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: Thalamocortical EEG rhythms in gamma (30–80Hz) and high-gamma (80–200Hz) ranges have been linked to arousal and conscious processing. We have recently shown that isoflurane and propofol cause a concentration dependent attenuation of the power of these fast (50¬–200Hz) rhythms in the ventroposteromedial nucleus (VPM) of the thalamus. It has been proposed that general anesthetics may exert a stronger effect on the central medial thalamus (CMT) and the thalamic reticular nucleus (TRN) as the afferents to both structures are likely to be more sensitive to general anesthetics when compared to the Ventral Posteromedial Nucleus (VPM) whose afferents are either not affected (spinal) or minimally affected (cortico-thalamic recurrent projections). Recent studies have showed that the earliest correlate of propofol-induced unconsciousness in rats (loss of righting reflex) occurs in the Central Medial Thalamus (CMT) as a shift to a lower dominant frequency in the gamma (20-40 Hz) range with a concomitant increase in power. Additionally, solid motives for the study of the TRN include its pivotal role in regulation of thalamocortical function and arousal, as well as the GABAergic nature of its efferents – since potentiation of the GABA receptor is the most common molecular mechanism through which general anesthetics act. The aim of this study was to compare the effect of isoflurane on fast rhythms observed from the VPM, CMT and TRN.Methods: Local field potentials (LFPs) were recorded from the VPM, TRN and CMT in 10 chronically implanted rats to measure spectral power in the gamma/high-gamma range (30–200 Hz) range. Rats were placed in an airtight chamber and isoflurane was administered at 0.5%, 0.75%, 1.0% and 1.25%. Spectral power was assessed during baseline, at the 4 isoflurane concentrations, and during emergence and recovery. The analysis was carried out over four bands (30–50, 51–75, 76–125 and 126–200 Hz). The state of unconsciousness was defined as a sustained loss of righting reflex. Multiple linear regression was used to model the change in power (after logarithmic transformation) as a function of concentration and recording site. P values were corrected for multiple comparisons. Results: Loss of consciousness occurred at 1.0% in all animals. A significant attenuation of the gamma and high-gamma oscillations in the 51–200 Hz range was observed with no significant differences between structures under observation. There was no effect observed on the 30–50Hz range.Conclusion: There is an attenuation of gamma and high-gamma oscillations (30–80 Hz and 80–200 Hz respectively) at the level of the CMT, TRN and VPM when exposed to isoflurane and the effect is uniform across all structures under observation. </description><description>Introduction: Les rythmes d'EEG thalamocorticaux dans les bandes de fréquence gamma (30-80 Hz) et haut-gamma (80-200 Hz) sont liés avec l'éveil et les processus conscients. Nous avons récemment démontré que l'isoflurane et le propofol causent une atténuation, en fonction de la concentration, de l'amplitude de ces rythmes rapides (50-200 Hz) du noyau ventropostéromédial du thalamus (VPM). Il fût proposé que les anesthésiques généraux pourraient avoir un effet important sur le thalamus centromédial (CMT) et le noyau réticulaire thalamique (TRN) puisque les structures afférents de ces dernières sont susceptibles d'être plus sensibles aux anesthésiant généraux lorsque comparés au VPM dont les structures afférentes ne sont soit pas affectées (spinales) ou minimalement affectées (projections récurrentes cortico-thalamiques). Des études récentes ont démontré que les corrélats les plus tôt de l'inconscience due au propofol chez les rats (la perte du réflexe de redressement) ont lieu dans le CMT en tant que changement vers une fréquence dominante plus basse dans la bande d'ondes gamma (20-40 Hz) avec une augmentation concomitante de puissance. De plus, les raisons centrales d'étudier le TRN incluent son rôle clé dans la régulation de la fonction thalamocorticale, dans l'éveil, ainsi que dans la nature GABAergique de ses structures efférentes puisque la potentialisation des récepteurs GABA est le mécanisme moléculaire par lequel les anesthésiants généraux font effet. Le but de cette étude est de comparer l'effet de l'isoflurane sur les rythmes rapides observés aux VPM, CMT et TRN.Méthode: Les potentiels de champs locaux (LFPs) furent enregistré aux VPM, TRN et CMT dans 10 rats chroniquement instrumentés pour mesurer la puissance spectrale dans les bandes d'ondes gamma et haut gamma (30-200 Hz). Les rats furent placés dans une chambre hermétique et de l'isoflurane leur fût administré à 0.5%, 0.75%, 1.0% et 1.25%. La puissance spectrale fût mesurée au un point de référence, aux quatre concentrations d'isoflurane et durant l'émergence et la convalescence. L'analyse fût poussée sur quatre bandes de fréquence (30-50, 51-75, 76-125 et 126-200 Hz) L'état de conscience a été défini comme étant une perte continue du réflexe de redressement. La régression linéaire multiple a été utilisé pour modéliser les changements de puissance (après une transformation logarithmique) comme étant une fonction de la concentration et du site d'enregistrement. Les valeurs P furent corrigées pour comparaisons multiples.Résultats: La perte de conscience a eu lieu à 1.0% pour tous les animaux. Une atténuation significative des oscillations dans les bandes de fréquences gamma et haut-gamma fût observée sans différence significative entre les structures observées.Conclusion: Il existe une atténuation des oscillations des bandes de fréquences gamma et haut-gamma (30-80 Hz et 80-200 Hz respectivement) au niveau du CMT, du TRN et du VPM lorsque exposé à l'isoflurane et les effets sont uniformes dans toutes les structures observées.</description><creator>Malhotra, Sidharth</creator><contributor>Gilles Plourde (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Comparison of the effect of isoflurane on high-frequency (30-200 Hz) ryythms recorded in central medial, reticular, and ventroposteromedial thalmic nuclei</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515q71q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988n335</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tx35t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A key limitation for bulk tissue engineered scaffold development is the inability to deliver oxygen to cells found within scaffolds – which can result in hypoxia and tissue necrosis. The objective of this study was to determine the necessary requirements for anoxic MSC survival up to 13 days.  Initially, unmodified and Erythropoietin (Epo) gene-modified mouse bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells (Epo-MSCs) were cultured for 7 days in normoxic (21%) and anoxic (&lt;1%) oxygen conditions. In the second set of experiments, unmodified MSCs were cultured in anoxia for up to 13 days in high (4.5g/L) and regular (1g/L) glucose media. Cell viabilities were determined for up to 13 days. We observed from our oxygen experiments, that while both groups of MSCs showed similar viabilities (78-88%) when compared to normoxic controls (85-91%), Epo-MSCs showed a significantly higher cell count (10.1x104±4.5) compared to unmodified MSCs (7x104±3.8) when cultured in anoxia. In anoxia, addition of high glucose media to unmodified MSCs led to a significant increase in cell viability percentage when compared to regular glucose media at 13 days. Our results indicate that both groups of MSCs can survive for up to 13 days in the absence of oxygen, with higher cell counts seen for Epo-MSCs. Protein production was unaffected by the absence of oxygen compared to normoxic controls. Additional glucose allowed for a 37% increase in MSC survival in anoxia. These results may lead to future research in scaffold designs that do not require vasculature to maintain cell survival for extended periods of time.</description><description>Incapacité à fournir de l'oxygène aux cellules constituant les matrices tissulaires constitue aujourd'hui l'une des principales limitations au développement de l'ingénierie tissulaire. Cette difficulté peut mener à une hypoxie et à une nécrose des tissus. L'objectif de notre étude était de déterminer quelles conditions sont favorables à la survie des cellules souches mésenchymateuses (CSM) anoxiques durant 13 jours de culture. Une première expérience a consisté à mettre des CSMs issues de la moëlle osseuse de souris contrôle ou modifiées pour le gène codant pour l'Erythropoietin (Epo) en culture durant 7 jours en conditions normoxiques (21% O2) ou anoxiques (&lt;1% O¬2). Dans un second groupe d'expériences, des CSMs non-modifiées ont été cultivées en conditions anoxiques pendant 13 jours dans un milieu fortement ou faiblement concentré en glucose (4.5g/L et 1g/L, respectivement). La viabilité cellulaire a ensuite été déterminée. Nous avons observé que les deux groupes de CSMs cultivées en conditions anoxiques présentent un taux de survie similaire (78-88%) à celui des cellules cultivées en conditions normoxiques (85-91%). Cependant, nous avons constaté que les cultures de CSMs modifiées pour Epo possédaient un nombre de cellules plus important (10.1x104±4.5) que les CSMs non-modifiées (7x104±3.8) en conditions anoxiques. De plus, une augmentation significative de la viabilité des CSMs non-modifiées en anoxie a été observée lorsque celles-ci étaient cultivé dans un milieu riche en glucose. Ainsi, nos résultats montrent que les deux groupes de CSMs peuvent survivre jusqu'à 13 jours en absence d'oxygène, et que les cultures de CSMs modifiées pour Epo présentent un nombre plus important de cellules. Une forte concentration de glucose dans le milieu de culture permet de plus une augmentation de 37% de la survie des CSMs en anoxie. La production de protéines demeure inchangée en absence ou en présence d'oxygène. Ces résultats pourraient permettre une avancée significative dans la conception de nouvelles matrices tissulaires, pour lesquelles la vascularisation ne serait pas nécessaire à la survie à long terme des cellules.</description><creator>Lau, Fiona</creator><contributor>Nicoletta Eliopoulos (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jake Barralet (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Surgery</subject><title>The effects of oxygen and glucose culture on mouse bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r0687.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tx35t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000002304</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La grippe ou l'influenza est une infection respiratoire causée par les virus grippaux. La façon la plus efficace de prévenir cette maladie est par la vaccination. Malgré leur accessibilité, les vaccins contre l'influenza ont encore quelques limites causant une efficacité variable à chaque année, puisque les virus de la grippe mutent et de nouvelles souches de la maladie sont générées apportant ainsi une faible protection aux groupes les plus vulnérables de la société tels que les personnes âgées. Ainsi, à chaque année, l'influenza demeure un problème social, économique et sanitaire causant un nombre élevé de malades sévères et de morts partout sur la planète. Pour enrayer la maladie, de nouvelles approches sont sous investigation.Un candidat prometteur dans le secteur vaccins grippaux sont les particules pseudovirales (PPV) présentant l'hémagglutinine fabriquées par Medicago Inc. Les particules ne sont pas réplicatives faute de matériel génétique mais elles récapitulent les interactions virales avec le système immunitaire. Qui plus est, ces particules stimulent de fortes réponses humorales et à médiation cellulaire immunitaire croisées lors d'essais cliniques. Toutefois, la puissante et unique réponse immunitaire induite par les PPV de Medicago ne sont pas entièrement compris.Dans cette étude, nous utilisons des PPV présentant l'hémagglutinine dérivée d'une souche H1N1 et des macrophages dérivés de monocytes humains afin d'analyser les interactions des PPV avec des cellules présentatrices d'antigènes. Nous avons démontré que ces particules sont d'abord intériorisées par une endocytose médiée par la clathrine, une endocytose dépendante de la cavéoline et la macropinocytose, puis transportées aux endosomes précoces. De ce compartiment, l'hémagglutinine véhiculée par ces particules peut se diriger vers les compartiments lysosomaux et de recyclage pour la dégradation des protéines. À la fois les différents mécanismes d'internalisation de ces PPV ainsi que leurs possibles voies intracellulaires différentes indiquent que l'hémagglutinine véhiculée par ces particules peut éventuellement se dégrader dans des compartiments associés à la présentation d'antigène via les CMH I et CMH II.Ces résultats suggèrent que les diverses manières dont les PPV sont traitées par les cellules présentatrices d'antigènes peuvent avoir pour résultat, à la fois, les présentations de CMH I et de CMH II, qui provoquent respectivement la réponse des cellules T CD8 + et CD4 +, qui coordonnent la réponse immunitaire et générer une mémoire immunitaire. Nos résultats aident à expliquer en quoi les PPV de Medicago sont un candidat puissant pour la vaccination antigrippale, car elles induisent des réponses immunitaires variées, contrairement aux autres vaccins disponibles.</description><description>Influenza is a respiratory tract infection caused by influenza viruses. The most effective way to prevent this disease is through vaccination. Despite their availability, licensed influenza vaccines still have several limitations that cause inconsistent vaccine efficacy every year, as the influenza viruses mutate and generate new viral strains, and these vaccines provide poor protection to more susceptible population groups such as the elderly. Thus, influenza remains a social, economic, and health burden every year, causing substantial numbers of severe illness cases and deaths, worldwide. To overcome these limitations, new vaccination approaches are being currently researched. A promising candidate for influenza vaccination are virus-like particles (VLPs) bearing hemagglutinin developed by Medicago Inc. These particles are not replicative as they lack genetic material, and they have been shown to recapitulate viral interactions with the immune system. More importantly, these particles have been shown to elicit strong and cross-reactive humoral and cell-mediated immune response in clinical studies. However, the unique and potent immune responses generated by Medicago's VLPs are still not completely understood. In this study, we used VLPs bearing hemagglutinin derived from an H1N1 strain and human monocyte-derived macrophages to study the VLPs interactions with antigen presenting cells. We demonstrate that these particles are first internalized via clathrin-mediated endocytosis, caveolin-dependent endocytosis, and micropinocytosis, and then they are delivered to early endosomes. From this compartment, hemagglutinin can be directed to both lysosomal and recycling compartments for protein degradation. Both the diverse mechanisms of internalization of these VLPs and their different possible intracellular pathways indicate that the hemagglutinin carried by these particles may end up being degraded in compartments associated with MHC I and MHC II antigen presentation.These results suggest that the diverse way in which the VLPs are handled by antigen presenting cells may results in both MHC I and MHC II presentation that elicit the response of CD8+ and CD4+ T cells, respectively, which are in charge of coordinating the immune response and generating immune memory. Our results help explain how Medicago's VLPs are a powerful candidate for influenza vaccination as they elicit a varied immune responses, in contrast with other available vaccines.</description><creator>Costas Cancelas, Ian Noel</creator><contributor>Isabelle Rouiller (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>John Presley (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Anatomy and Cell Biology</subject><title>Internalization and endosomal trafficking of hemagglutinin-bearing virus-like particles favors antigen presentation in human macrophages</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096949z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000002304</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r7813</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The stem and bulb nematode, Ditylenchus dipsaci, is a plant-parasitic nematode responsible for major economic loss worldwide. A wide host range, reaching more than 500 plants species and the presence of more than 30 biological races defined by their host preference, make this species one of the most difficult nematodes to manage. Since 2011, garlic producers from Ontario and Quebec have been particularly affected with economic losses caused by this pest. An appropriate extraction method is essential for the detection of the nematode. However, the extraction efficacy will be influenced by many factors such as the nematode species (size and motility), the material to be diagnosed (soil or plants tissues) and the type of soil or plants tissues. Therefore, many different methods exist, each with their own advantages and disadvantages. Three extraction methods (Baermann pan, Baermann funnel and sonication) were compared for the extraction of nematodes from garlic bulbs, stems and leaves. Three methods (Baermann pan, Baermann funnel andsugar flotation) were also tested on four types of soil sample. This study confirmed the efficiency of the Baermann pan with D. dipsaci, both with soil and plant tissue samples. Reproduction of D. dipsaci on a particular host depends on its biological race, which was unknown for the populations of eastern Canada. In this study, the host range of four populations of D. dipsaci from Quebec and Ontario was determined in a greenhouse test on 11 crops. Garlic, onion and green onion showed great susceptibility to the nematode while reproduction on potato was poor. No development was observed on corn, soybean, barley, alfalfa, mustard, carrot, and lettuce. These plants could therefore be used in rotation crops in a control program. Finally, thirty-two populations of D. dipsaci were genetically characterized using genotyping-by-sequencing. Comparison of allele frequencies at 481 SNPs showed that most of the populations had a genotype similar to a reference population from northern Ontario. However, a sample from eastern Quebec exhibited a very distinct genotype and will require further phenotyping in the greenhouse to preclude the possibility of a different race.</description><description>Le nématode des tiges et des bulbes, Ditylenchus dipsaci, est un nématode phytoparasite responsable de pertes économiques majeures dans le monde entier. Une vaste gamme d'hôtes, atteignant plus de 500 espèces végétales et la présence de plus de 30 races biologiques définie par la préférence de l'hôte font de Ditylenchus dipsaci l'une des espèces de nématodes phytoparasites les plus difficile à gérer. Depuis 2011, les producteurs d'ail de l'Ontario et du Québec ont été sévèrement touchés par ce problème. Une méthode d'extraction appropriée est essentielle à la détection du nématode dans un échantillon. L'efficacité de l'extraction dépend de nombreux facteurs tels que l'espèce de nématode (taille et mobilité), le matériel à diagnostiquer (sol ou tissus) et le type de sol ou de plante. De nombreuses méthodes sont disponibles avec leurs avantages et leurs inconvénients. Trois méthodes d'extraction (Assiette de Baermann, entonnoir deBaermann et sonication) ont été comparées pour l'extraction des nématodes dans les bulbes, les tiges et les feuilles d'ail. De plus, trois méthodes (Assiette de Baermann, entonnoir Baermann et flottaison au sucre) ont été comparées pour l'extraction des nématodes dans quatre types de sol. Cette étude a confirmé l'efficacité de l'assiette de Baermann avec D. dipsaci, à la fois avec des échantillons de sol que des tissus végétaux. La reproduction de D. dipsaci sur un hôte particulier dépend de sa race biologique. Dans cette étude, le spectre d'hôte de quatre populations de D. dipsaci du Québec et de l'Ontario a été déterminé à l'aide d'un essai en serre sur 11 cultures. L'ail, l'oignon et l'oignon vert ont montré une grande sensibilité au nématode alors que la reproduction sur pomme de terre était faible. Aucun développement n'a été observé sur le maïs, le soja, l'orge, la luzerne, la moutarde, la carotte, et la laitue. Ces plantes pourraient donc être utilisées comme cultures de rotation dans un programme de lutte. Finalement, trente-deux populations de D. dipsaci ont été caractérisées génétiquement enutilisant le génotypage par séquençage. La comparaison des fréquences alléliques de 481 polymorphismes nucléotidiques simples (SNP) a montré que la plupart des populations du Québec et de l'Ontario avaient un génotype similaire. Par contre, une population duQuébec a démontré un génotype très différent et exigera des phénotypages supplémentaires afin de confirmer s'il s'agit d'une race différente.</description><creator>Poirier, Sandra</creator><contributor>Valérie Gravel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Benjamin Mimee (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Plant Science</subject><title>Host range and genetic characterization of the stem and bulb nematode, «Ditylenchus dipsaci», from Eastern Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xv02w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r7813</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c958v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Laser Powder Bed Fusion (LPBF) is an Additive Manufacturing (AM) process that offers superior versatility and direct part manufacturing from Computer Aided Design (CAD) model. It provides nearly unrestricted freedom to design in order to optimize part functionality producing shapes that would be impossible with conventional manufacturing such as moulding or machining. Moreover, it has a very low buy-to-fly ratio offering savings in material usage and lower waste from machining.Despite all the ground-breaking benefits mentioned, porosity is currently an inevitable process-induced defect commonly found in as-fabricated LPBF components. Porosity level as low as 0.5% contained in manufactured parts can still render them unfit for large-scale structural applications, such as in aerospace, due to its negative effects on mechanical properties. As an effective time and cost saving approach for assessing different types of pores for quality control and catastrophic failure prevention, the use of Finite Element Analysis (FEA) was proposed. By modelling the pores found in the parts' microstructure, a threshold is expected to be determined on the tolerable defect amount to be allowed while still preserving the minimum mechanical property required for a given application.The results found in this thesis presents a methodology for assessing the types of pores and pore clusters found in LPBF Ti-6Al-4V manufactured parts. The concept of stress triaxiality was used as a parameter and failure criteria for pore evaluation and damage initiation, respectively. This parameter enabled so far to obtain a trend with respect to the pore morphology and describe the dominant mechanism of failure pertaining this type of defect found in LPBF parts. Moreover, pore morphology and directionality simulated in FEA were found to significantly influence strain limit to fracture initiation showing a more premature failure mode for pores with smaller radius of curvature and directionally perpendicular to tensile load direction.</description><description>La technologie LPBF (Laser Powder Bed Fusion) est un procédé de fabrication additive qui offre une polyvalence supérieure et une fabrication directe de pièces à partir du modèle de conception assistée par ordinateur (CAO). Il offre une liberté de conception quasi illimitée afin d'optimiser la fonctionnalité des pièces en produisant des formes impossibles avec une fabrication classique telle que le moulage ou l'usinage. De plus, son ratio achat / envoi est très faible, ce qui permet de réduire l'utilisation de matériaux et de réduire les déchets d'usinage.En dépit de tous les avantages novateurs mentionnés, la porosité est actuellement un défaut inévitable induit par le procédé que l'on trouve couramment dans les composants LPBF fabriqués. Un niveau de porosité aussi faible que 0,5% contenu dans les pièces fabriquées peut encore les rendre impropres à des applications structurelles à grande échelle, telles que l'aérospatiale, en raison de ses effets négatifs sur les propriétés mécaniques.En tant que méthode efficace d'économie de temps et de coût pour évaluer différents types de pores en vue du contrôle de la qualité et de la prévention des défaillances catastrophiques, l'utilisation de l'analyse par éléments finis a été proposée. En modélisant les pores présents dans la microstructure des pièces, un seuil devrait être déterminé sur la quantité de défaut tolérable à tolérer tout en préservant la propriété mécanique minimale requise pour une application donnée.Les résultats trouvés dans cette thèse présentent une méthodologie pour évaluer les types de pores et de groupes de pores trouvés dans les pièces fabriquées par LPBF Ti-6Al-4V. Le concept de triaxialité sous contrainte a été utilisé comme paramètre et critère de défaillance pour l'évaluation des pores et l'initiation des dommages, respectivement. Ce paramètre a permis jusqu'à présent d'obtenir une tendance en ce qui concerne la morphologie des pores et de décrire le mécanisme de défaillance dominant concernant ce type de défaut trouvé dans les parties de LPBF. En outre, la morphologie des pores et la directionnalité simulées dans la FEA influençaient significativement la limite de déformation à la rupture, montrant un mode de défaillance plus prématuré pour les pores de rayon de courbure inférieur.</description><creator>Weinstein Silva, Flavio</creator><contributor>Mathieu Brochu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Mining and Materials</subject><title>Relationship between porosity and mechanical properties in laser powder bed fusion fabricated Ti6Al4V alloy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q6425.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c958v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602322s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DLBCL is the most common Non-Hodgkin lymphoma of B and T cell lineages. It is curable by R-CHOP in 60% of patients in which is the first line of regimen. Therapeutic resistance is the major cause of death in patients with relapse (30-40% of the patients). Salvage chemotherapy followed by autologous stem cell transplantation is the treatment regimen for relapsed-refractory DLBCL (rrDLBCL), however this treatment is not tolerated in older or frail patients and ultimately &gt;90% of patients with rrDLBCL die from their disease. Recent whole exome sequencing of 38 DLBCL samples taken at the time of relapse revealed that 18% of the cases had mutations in the FAS gene. FAS receptor is a type I transmembrane protein belonging to the tumor necrosis factor superfamily. FAS receptor initiates extrinsic apoptosis upon binding of FAS ligand by surrounding cells. FAS-FASL interaction plays an important role in maintaining immune homeostasis.We hypothesized that FAS mutations may favour lymphoma growth in vivo by impairing FAS-mediated apoptosis by surrounding immune cells.  We transduced an Eμ-Myc/Arf-null chemo-sensitive lymphoma line with either Fas(Y224*) (murine equivalent of FAS(Y232*)), Fas wildtype (WT) or empty vector control. We then injected these lymphoma cells into C57BL/6 syngeneic mice and monitored lymphoma growth before and after chemotherapy. We observed that the Fas mutant cells grew faster and had a delayed response to therapy when compared to controls or FasWT lymphomas. However, introduction of Fas into the cells triggered apoptosis and resulted in poor viability and transduction efficiency. To circumvent this problem, we bred mice that have germline mutations in Fas (lpr mice) with Eμ-Myc mice that develop spontaneous lymphomas by 3-6 months of age, thus generating primary Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt, EμMyc/Faswt/wt and Faslpr/wt lymphomas, all on an immune competent C57BL/6 background. The goal was to study the effect of Fas mutations in lymphoma development, lymphoma growth rate and response to chemotherapy. We bred Eμ-Myc and lpr mice, generating 10 Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt and 21 Eμ-Myc/Faswt/wt lymphomas. Mice without the Eμ-Myc transgene (90 Faslpr/wt) did not develop lymphoma. The median time to lymphoma development in the primary mice generated from breeding was not significantly different between Fas genotypes: 164 days in Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt and 161 days in EμMyc/Faswt/wt (p=0.943). However, when these primary lymphomas were injected into C57BL/6 mice, lymphoma engraftment was higher in the Fas mutant group, where, 8/10 Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt and 8/18 Eμ-Myc/Faswt/wt lymphomas generated lymphomas in recipient mice. Secondary Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt developed aggressive lymphomas faster (49 days) compared to the Eμ-Myc/Faswt/wt group (95 days), p=0.045. To study the response to chemotherapy, secondary Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt and Eμ-Myc/Faswt/wt lymphomas were injected into C57BL/6 mice and treated with doxorubicin, cyclophosphamide, and vincristine. There was no significant difference in the overall survival between treated and untreated control mice in both the groups (15 days in the Faslpr/wt group compared to 20 days in the Faswt/wt group), p=0.181. Relapse was a common phenomenon. Time to remission/relapse was shorter in the Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt cohort compared to the Eμ-Myc/Faswt/wt cohort for mice treated with doxorubicin and cyclophosphamide (p=0.047 for doxorubicin and p=0.058 for cyclophosphamide treatments). Fas mutation does favour lymphoma growth when injected in C57BL/6 mice and may contribute to therapeutic resistance. There is great heterogeneity in lymphoma growth within each Fas genotype, which may be related to other factors not yet measured in this project (selection for secondary mutations (e.g.Tp53), expression of Bcl2). Understanding the differences in immune responses and the interactions in microenvironment in these two Fas genotypes will provide a better insight into the novel therapeutic targets and their clinical significance.</description><description>Nous avons émis l'hypothèse que les mutations FAS pourraient favoriser la croissance des lymphomes in vivo en altérant l'apoptose médiée par le FAS par les cellules immunitaires environnantes. Nous avons transduit une lignée de lymphome chimio-sensible Eμ-Myc / Arf-null avec soit Fas (Y224*) (équivalent murin de FAS (Y232*)), FasWT ou le contrôle du vecteur vide. Nous avons ensuite injecté ces cellules de lymphome dans des souris syngéniques C57BL/6 et surveillé la croissance du lymphome avant et après la chimiothérapie. Nous avons observé que les cellules mutantes de Fas se développaient plus rapidement et avaient une réponse retardée à la thérapie que les contrôles ou les lymphomes de type FasWT. Cependant, l'introduction de Fas dans les cellules a déclenché l'apoptose et a entraîné une mauvaise viabilité et une efficacité de transduction. Pour contourner ce problème, nous avons développé des souris qui ont des mutations germinales chez des souris Fas (lpr) avec des souris Eμ-Myc qui développent des lymphomes spontanés vers 3-6 mois, générant Eμ-Myc / Faslpr/wt primaire, Eμ-Myc / Faswt/wt et les lymphomes de Faslpr/wt, tous avec des souris immunocompétentes. Le but de ce projet était d'étudier l'effet des mutations Fas dans le développement du lymphome, le taux de croissance des lymphomes et la réponse à la chimiothérapie. Nous avons élevé des souris Eμ-Myc et lpr, en générant 10 lymphomes Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt et 21 EμMyc/Faswt/wt. Des souris sans le transgène Eμ-Myc(90 Fasmut) n'ont pas développé de lymphome. Le temps de développement du lymphome chez les souris primaires n'était pas significativement différent entre les génotypes Fas:164 jours chez Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt et 161 jours chez Eμ-Myc/ Faswt/wt(p=0,943). Cependant, lorsque ces lymphomes primaires ont été injectés dans des souris C57BL/6, la prise de greffe de lymphome était plus élevée dans le groupe mutant Fas, où les lymphomes 8/10 Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt et 8/18 Eμ-Myc/ Faswt/wt ont généré des lymphomes chez des souris receveuses. Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt secondaire a développé un lymphome agressif plus rapidement(49 jours) que le groupe Eμ-Myc / Faswt/wt(93 jours),p=0,045. Pour étudier la réponse à la chimiothérapie, des lymphomes secondaires Eμ-Myc / Faslpr/wt et Eμ-Myc / Faswt/wt ont été injectés dans des souris C57BL/6 et traités avec de la doxorubicine, du cyclophosphamide et de la vincristine. Il n'y avait pas de différence significative dans la survie globale des souris témoins non traitées dans les deux groupes(15 jours dans le groupe Faslpr/wt par rapport à 20 jours dans le groupe Faswt/wt), p=0,181. La rechute était un phénomène commun. Cependant, la survie posttraitement (délai de rémission / rechute) était plus courte dans la cohorte Eμ-Myc/Faslpr/wt comparée à la cohorte Eμ-Myc/Faswt/wt pour les souris traitées à la doxorubicine et au cyclophosphamide (p=0,047 pour la doxorubicine et p=0,058 pour la cyclophosphamide). traitements). La mutation FAS favorise la croissance du lymphome lorsqu'elle est injectée chez la souris C57BL/6 et peut contribuer à la résistance thérapeutique. Il y a une grande hétérogénéité dans la croissance des lymphomes dans chaque génotype Fas, qui peut être liée à d'autres facteurs non-encore mesurés dans ce projet (par exemple sélection pour des mutations secondaires (par exemple Tp53), expression de Bcl2). Comprendre les différences dans les réponses immunitaires et les interactions dans le microenvironnement dans ces deux génotypes Fas permettra de mieux comprendre les nouvelles cibles thérapeutiques et leur signification clinique. </description><creator>Venkataraman, Maanasa</creator><contributor>Nathalie Johnson (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Understanding the role of FAS mutations in DLBCL</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn77w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602322s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676z01h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electric vehicles have started to make their appearance in the transportation industry. At Quebec's scale especially, since electricity is already sustained by an extensive network of dams and reservoir, Hydro-Quebec puts a lot of focus towards green gas emission reduction via transportation electrification. To be widely accepted, batteries used in electric vehicles must have high ranges, long durability, be safe and an economical choice in the long run for its user to abandon gasoline-powered automobiles. In that matter, the company's Center of Excellence in Transportation Electrification and Energy Storage works tirelessly on the development of new generation battery materials using elements available in large quantities, with high performance chemistry. Materials characterization with Scanning Electron Microscopy is one of the most important steps in developing new materials, since it links the microstructure of the material to its fabrication process and properties down to the nanometer scale. This study focuses on the development of quantitative techniques for lithium in battery materials since this light element is the key element in the operation of a battery. In this work energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS), electron energy-loss spectroscopy (EELS) and secondary ion mass spectrometry are evaluated in relation to their capabilities to both detect and quantify lithium atoms in battery materials. A portable time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometer (TOF-SIMS) that can attach to a standard dual beam microscope(FIB-SEM) was found to fulfill both aspects while allowing high resolution imaging andchemical analysis of the samples. An experimental calibration curve of lithium content in standard nickel cobalt manganese oxide cathodes was built using TOF-SIMS detector. The calibration curve allows identification of lithium content in cathodes with different state of charge and according to different charging rates. TOF-SIMS allows visualization of ionic distributions in material. Furthermore, it can help observe differences in crystallographic orientation with respect to the beam in between primary particles and permits identification of chemical hotspots of lithium.</description><description>De plus en plus, les voitures électriques font leur apparition sur le marché de l'automobile. À l'échelle du Québec plus particulièrement, comme la majorité de l'électricité utilisée de façon domestique et industrielle provient d'un vaste réseaux hydroélectrique, le focus d'Hydro-Québec envers la réduction des émissions de gaz à effet de serres se tourne vers l'électrification des transports. Pour que le grand public délaisse la voiture à essence au profit de la voiture électrique, les batteries proposées dans ces véhicules doivent permettre une grande autonomie, être durables en plus d'être sécuritaires et se révéler un choix économique à long terme pour l'acheteur. Selon cette perspective, le Centre d'Excellence en Électrification des transports et Stockage d'Énergie d'Hydro-Québec s'acharne à développer des matériaux de batteries utilisant des éléments disponibles en grandes quantités et économiques en plus de d'une chimie de haute performance. La caractérisation des matériaux à l'aide d'un microscope électronique à balayage est l'une des étapes les plus importantes dans la recherche et développement, puisqu'elle peut nous indiquer à chaque étape de la vie utile d'une batterie les liens entre la microstructure, les processus de fabrication et ses propriétés et ce, jusqu'au nanomètre. Ce travail porte sur le développement de techniques quantitatives pour le lithium dans le smatériaux de batteries puisque celui-ci est l'élément clé de leur fonctionnement. Dans cette étude, les techniques de spectroscopie des rayons X par dispersion d'énergie (EDS), de spectroscopie des pertes d'énergie des électrons (EELS) et la spectrométrie de masse à ionisation secondaire (SIMS) seront évaluées par rapport à leur capacité à détecter et à quantifier le lithium dans les matériaux de batteries. Un détecteur portable d'ion secondaires par temps de vol (TOF-SIMS) s'est révélé le meilleur choix parmi ces techniques en permettant l'imagerie haute résolution du lithium et son analyse chimique et quantitative. Une courbe de calibration expérimentale du contenu en lithium dans des cathodes standard d'oxide de nickel cobalt manganese a pu être construite grâce au TOF-SIMS. Cette courbe de calibration permet l'identification de la concentration de lithium dans l'échantillon en fonction de l'état decharge de la cathode et selon différent taux de charge. Le TOF-SIMS permet de surcroît la visualisation des distributions des ions dans le matériaux. Il a permis de voir des différences dans l'orientation cristalline des grains primaires et l'identification de points chaud ou "hotspots" de lithium.</description><creator>Bessette, Stéphanie</creator><contributor>Karim Zaghib (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Raynald Gauvin (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Mining and Materials</subject><title>Development of quantitative techniques for lithium compounds for next generation batteries with focused ion beam scanning electron microscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05ff13p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676z01h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr80q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il y a eu des développements en plein essor dans la recherche sur les nanoparticules (NP) pour les applications biomédicales et la nanomédecine. Cependant, très peu d'IP ont réussi à faire des essais cliniques, et encore moins ont atteint la pratique clinique. Cette grande disparité entre les découvertes au banc et leur traduction clinique efficace est principalement due à une connaissance insuffisante de l'interface nanobio. Nous pensons que plusieurs facteurs de l'environnement in vitro sont ignorés, ce qui conduit à une mauvaise interprétation des données collectées. Récemment, plusieurs études ont été réalisées pour réduire l'écart susmentionné visant à mieux comprendre l'identité biologique des NP et leurs propriétés cytotoxiques inhérentes. Cependant, les recherches importantes dans ce domaine sont encore insuffisantes. Par conséquent, l'objectif principal de ma thèse est d'étudier les facteurs qui affectent l'absorption cellulaire des nanoparticules (NP), notamment les influences physiques et biologiques. Les tendances de l'absorption et les facteurs associés ont été étudiés dans les fibroblastes primaires dérivés des glandes salivaires de donneurs humains mâles et femelles adultes et les tumeurs primitives et les cellules stromales des patients à différents stades de la progression du cancer. Nous visons à documenter les rôles joués par le sexe, la progression de la maladie et d'autres facteurs dans l'interface nanobio dans l'endocytose des NP et donc leurs effets sur les applications cliniques potentielles des NP et de la médecine personnalisée.</description><description>There have been burgeoning developments in nanoparticle (NP) research for biomedical applications and nanomedicine. However, very few NPs have made it to clinical trials, and even fewer have reached clinical practice. This wide disparity between bench discoveries and their effective clinical translation is mainly due to insufficient knowledge of the nano-bio interface. We believe that there are multiple factors in the in vitro environment that are overlooked leading to misinterpretation of data that is collected. Recently, several studies have been performed to diminish the aforementioned gap aimed at achieving a more in-depth understanding of the biological identity of NPs and their inherent cytotoxic properties. However, there is still a dearth in significant research in this field. Therefore, the main objective of my thesis is to study the factors that affect the cellular uptake of nanoparticles (NPs) which include both physical and biological influences. Uptake trends and the associated factors were studied in primary fibroblasts derived from the salivary glands of adult male and female human donors and primary tumor and stromal cells of patients from different stages of cancer progression. We aim to document the roles played by gender, disease progression and other factors in the nanobio interface in NP endocytosis and thus their effects on potential clinical applications of NPs and personalized medicine.</description><creator>Pushparaj, Pooja</creator><contributor>Joseph Kinsella (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>The analysis of factors influencing nanoparticle uptake in primary cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wz05g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr80q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Biological and Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fn973</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce projet de maîtrise avait pour but d'explorer les effets de l'expertise sportive sur les patrons de fatigue musculaire dans la région du cou et de l'épaule pendant une tâche répétitive et fatigante, comparés aux mesures subjectives de fatigue. Une population de femmes ont été recrutées pour former trois groupes: les contrôles, les joueuses de water polo expertes, et les nageuses expertes. Les participantes ont effectué une tâche qui mesure les performances de l'épaule avant et après un protocole de rotation internes sous-maximal (50%) et répétitive, effectuées jusqu'à l'atteinte de fatigue. Le protocole fatigant a été exécuté jusqu'à l'atteinte de 8 sur l'échelle modifiée de Borg CR10, et les données d'électromyographie (EMG) et les valeurs de l'effort perçu (RPE) était enregistrées à chaque minute.  Les résultats illustrent que les joueuses de water polo on atteint les critères de fatigue plus rapidement, probablement en raison de leur torque significativement plus élevé, causant une tâche fatigante a 50% de maximum plus difficile à réaliser. L'amplitude EMG (RMS) et les fréquences médianes de puissance (MdPF) ont été calculées avec les donnés acquises, et les changements de ces variables pendant le protocole fatiguant ont indiqué la fatigue musculaire dans les trois groupes. Les contrôles ont montré une fatigue significative dans leur latissimus dorsi (LAT), et des corrélations entre le grand pectoral, le deltoïde antérieur, et le subscapularis avec le RPE. Elles ont aussi montré un abaissement des RMS dans leurs stabilisateurs scapulaires, illustrant que ces muscles devenaient moins actifs. Le groupe water polo a démontré une fatigue musculaire significative dans leur trapèze supérieur et le LAT, et aussi des corrélations entre leur deltoïde antérieur, supraspinatus, trapèze supérieur, et le trapèze médian avec le RPE. Elles ont aussi démontré des stratégies de protection des muscles responsables de l'action de lancer un ballon. Le groupe de nageuses a indiqué des associations entre la fatigue de leurs stabilisateurs scapulaires et le RPE, et aussi une tendance à protéger leur LAT de la fatigue supplémentaire. Nos résultats supportent les études passées sur la fatigue musculaire localisée spécifique aux sports, et démontre l'utilisation des muscles de la région du cou et de l'épaule selon l'expertise. Ils dénotent aussi dans les groupes experts des stratégies proactives spécifiques au sport pour prévenir les blessures des épaules. </description><description>The aim of this Master's project was to explore the effects of sport expertise on neuromuscular activation in the neck/shoulder region during a repetitive fatiguing task, in comparison to subjective measures of fatigue. A convenience sample of female participants was recruited in three groups: controls, expert water polo players, and expert competitive swimmers. Participants completed tasks measuring shoulder performance before and after a repetitive submaximal (~50%) internal rotation protocol to fatigue. The fatiguing protocol was performed until a score of 8 on the Borg CR10 scale was reached, and electromyographical (EMG) data and ratings of perceived exertion (RPE) were recorded each minute throughout the task. Results indicate that water polo players had the shortest time to reach termination criteria, likely due to their considerably higher maximum torque output from the shoulder performance measures, making the relative 50% fatiguing task much more difficult to achieve. EMG root mean square (RMS) and median power frequency (MdPF) measures were calculated from the acquired data, and changes in these variables throughout the fatiguing protocol indicated fatigue in all three expertise-groups. Controls showed significant fatigue in the latissimus dorsi (LAT), and strong correlations between pectoralis major, anterior deltoid, and subscpularis activity and RPE.  They also showed a decrease in RMS for the scapular stabilizers indicating those muscles were becoming less active. The water polo group displayed significant fatigue in the upper trapezius, and latissimus dorsi, as well as correlations between their deltoid muscles, supraspinatus, upper trapezius and middle trapezius activity and RPE. They also showed signs of protecting their muscles responsible for the throwing action from further fatigue. The swimming group showed correlations between fatigue of their scapular stabilizers and RPE, as well as a tendency to protect their latissimus dorsi from further fatigue. These results support past literature on sport-specific localized fatigue, and show expertise-dependent in the utilization of muscles of the shoulder/neck, as well as sport-specific proactive injury-prevention tactics in the expert groups. </description><creator>King, Savannah</creator><contributor>Julie Cote (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>The effects of expertise on the relationship between perceived exertion and outcome measures throughout a shoulder-fatiguing task</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df83r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn973</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558g42d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Acute pain is a protective mechanism guiding the organism away from a potentially harmful stimulus. Contrarily, the pathophysiology of chronic pain manifests in ways which are not advantageous for survival and are rather debilitating. The development and maintenance of chronic pain rely on new gene expression which is in turn responsible for the morphological and biochemical alterations in different components of the pain pathway. Translational control of gene expression has emerged as a key mechanism in regulating different forms of long-lasting neuronal hypersensitivity. Recent studies showed that signaling pathways upstream of mRNA translation, such as mTORC1 and ERK, are upregulated in chronic pain conditions, and their inhibition effectively alleviates pain in several animal models. Translation is primarily regulated at the initiation stage via the coordinated activity of translation initiation factors. The mRNA cap-binding protein, eIF4E integrates inputs from the mTOR and ERK signaling pathways. However, mRNAs whose translation is altered in chronic pain conditions remain largely unknown. Here, we performed genome-wide translational profiling of dorsal root ganglion (DRG) and spinal cord dorsal horn tissues in a mouse model of neuropathic pain, spared nerve injury (SNI), using the ribosome profiling technique. We identified distinct subsets of mRNAs that are differentially translated in response to nerve injury in both tissues. We also discovered key converging upstream regulators and pathways linked to mRNA translational control and neuropathic pain. Our data are crucial for the understanding of mechanisms by which mRNA translation promotes persistent hypersensitivity after nerve injury.</description><description>La douleur aiguë est un mécanisme protecteur guidant l'organisme hors de stimulus potentiellement dangereux. En revanche, la physiopathologie de la douleur chronique n'offre pas d'avantages pour la survie et reste plutôt débilitant. Le développement et le maintien de la douleur chronique reposent sur une nouvelle expression génétique à son tour responsable des changements morphologiques et biochimiques de différentes composantes de la voie de la douleur. Le contrôle translationnel de l'expression génétique s'est révélé être un mécanisme essentiel dans la régulation des différentes formes d'hypersensibilité neuronale de longue durée. Des études récentes ont montré que des voies de signalisation en amont de la traduction de l'ARNm, telles que mTORC1 et ERK, sont régulées positivement dans les douleurs chroniques et que dans plusieurs modèles animal leur inhibition diminue la douleur. La traduction est principalement régulée au stade d'initiation grâce à l'activité coordonnée de facteurs d'initiation de la traduction. La protéine de liaison à l'ARNm, eIF4E, intègre les entrées des voies de signalisation mTOR et ERK. Cependant, les ARNm dont la traduction est altérée dans les conditions de douleur chronique restent en grande partie inconnus. Dans le cadre de cette présente recherche nous avons effectué un profilage d'expression du génome entier des ganglions dorsaux (DRG) et de la corne dorsale de la moelle épinière dans un modèle de douleur neuropathique chez la souris impliquant la lésion nerveuse de type SNI au moyen de la technique de profilage de ribosomes. Nous avons identifié des sous-ensembles distincts d'ARNm traduits différentiellement en réponse à une lésion nerveuse dans les deux tissus. Nous avons également découvert des régulateurs clés convergents en amont ainsi que des voies liées au contrôle translationnel de l'ARNm et à la douleur neuropathique. Nos données sont essentielles pour comprendre les mécanismes par lesquels la traduction de l'ARNm favorise l'hypersensibilité persistante suivant une lésion nerveuse. </description><creator>Uttam, Sonali</creator><contributor>Arkady Khoutorsky (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Luda Diatchenko (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Genome-wide translational profiling in a mouse model of neuropathic pain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h1824.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558g42d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227ms14k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:58:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La paralysie faciale (PF) est un état clinique résultant de dommages au nerf facial, entraînant la paralysie des muscles faciaux qui peuvent affecter la parole, la vision et les interactions sociales des patients. Nous émettons l'hypothèse que l'activité peut être restaurée dans la moitié du visage atteinte au moyen de la stimulation électrique de ses muscles, en utilisant l'activité des muscles de la moitié saine du visage comme une entrée de contrôle. Pour explorer cette hypothèse, nous utilisons un modèle de rat de PF, qui traite le clignotement des yeux et le mouvement des moustaches comme étant les caractéristiques de l'intérêt dans le mouvement facial. Cette thèse décrit le développement d'un système expérimental et d'une méthodologie de mesure automatique du déplacement des paupières et de la détection des clignotements dans les enregistrements vidéo du rat. Plus précisément, nous avons utilisé une approche de mesure aux contours actifs pour localiser et suivre les yeux du rat dans une vidéo à tête fixe. L'algorithme est initialisé en marquant manuellement le contour des yeux dans la première image du vidéo; les images suivantes sont analysées automatiquement sur la base d'une fonction d'énergie qui dépend des caractéristiques de l'image dans la région d'intérêt. Nos résultats démontrent que cette technique détecte des clignotements dans des enregistrements vidéo avec un taux de réussite de 100% et une forte corrélation entre le résultat de l'algorithme et la décrivant manuelle.</description><description>Facial palsy (FP) is a clinical condition caused by damage to the facial nerve, resulting in paralysis of facial muscles that may affect patients' speech, eyesight and social interactions. We hypothesize that activity can be restored in the injured hemiface, by electrical stimulation of its muscles, using the activity of muscles on the healthy hemiface as a control input. To explore this hypothesis, our group uses a rat model of FP, which treats blinking and whisking as the features of interest in facial movement. This thesis describes the development of an experimental system and a methodology for the automatic measurement of eyelid displacement and detection of blinks in video recordings of the rat. Specifically, we used an active-contour approach to localize and track rodent eyes in a head-fixed video. The algorithm is initialized by manually marking the eye contour in the first frame of the video; subsequent frames are analyzed automatically based on an energy function that depends on image features in the region of interest. Our results demonstrate that this technique detects blinks in video recordings with 100% success rate, and that there is a high correlation between algorithm output and manual outlining.</description><creator>Tsror, Guy</creator><contributor>Robert E Kearney (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Human Genetics</subject><title>Eyelid and blink tracking in an animal model of facial palsy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qf27d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227ms14k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Biological and Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):3275</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>