<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:22:40Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33475" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mk642</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the professional musical stage of Montreal in the decade following the First World War. Throughout the 1920s, almost all of the city's musical theatre attractions were foreign in origin, and were staged by American, French, and British roadshow companies, arriving mainly from New York City. Analysis of Montreal's musical theatre entertainment and satellite relationship with Broadway highlights the growing cultural influence of the United States upon Quebec society in the interwar period. As a northern outpost of Broadway, Montreal was directly affected by the profound transformation of the entertainment industry of the United States. After peaking in the second half of the decade, the musical stage of Montreal was gradually supplanted by the decline of the roadshow system, the advent of the sound film, the onset of the Great Depression, and the resurgence of local stock theatre companies. The northern extension of Broadway into Montreal heightened divisions within Montreal society between a growing middle class of businessmen, managers, and other professionals who embraced modernity and cultural change, and more conservative forces who favoured the traditional Quebec based on religious and nationalist values. While the musical attractions sent northwards from Broadway were a popular divertissement for a large proportion of Montrealers from all social classes and linguistic backgrounds, they were abhorred by the province's clerical and nationalist elites and their supporters who regarded them as a threat to the survival of traditional French Canadian values and culture.</description><creator>Charpentier, Marc, 1965-</creator><contributor>Zucchi, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Musical theater -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History -- 20th century.</subject><title>Broadway north : musical theatre in Montreal in the 1920s</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm60v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk642</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042v62j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new methodology using simple acid-base hydrolysis of aminosilanes with molecules containing terminal hydroxyl groups, has been developed for the preparation of supports for heterogenized homogeneous catalysis. The flexibility of this approach has allowed the build-up of new materials ranging from simple organometallic thin films to complex organometallic-inorganic sol-gel networks, and organophosphine and metallodendrimers. The acid-base hydrolytic route to construct thin films containing phosphine and amine donor ligands on glass surfaces, eliminates the problems of the traditional surface functionalization techniques. Surface modification involves the reaction of SiCl4 with the surface hydroxyl groups of glass, quartz and single crystal silicon, followed by the addition of NEt2H, resulting in the formation of [Si]-NEt2 sites on the surface, which can undergo acid-base hydrolysis with phosphine and amine ligands containing terminal OH groups, to afford thin films of various long alkane chains containing terminal donor ligands. Bridge-splitting and ligand displacement reactions were used to anchor the organometallic complexes of Ni(0), Rh(I), Ru(II) and Pd(0). A detailed analysis of their characterization is reported. The catalytic efficiencies were examined for the cyclooligomerization of phenylacetylene using the thin film, [Si]-O-(CH 2)3PPh2Ni(CO)2PPh3, and the hydrogenation of diphenylacetylene with the long alkane chain thin film, [Si]-O-(CH2)nPPh2Rh(1,5-C8H 12)(Cl) (n = 10--12). Both anchored catalysts were highly active and selective, resulting in product distributions that differed from similar reactions with solution complexes. In an attempt to prepare solution analogs to the surface-bound species, an interesting class of Rh(I) complexes of the type, Rh(CO)(Cl)(PPh3 )(NRR'R′) were synthesized, of which Rh(CO)(Cl)(PPh3)(HNEt2) and Rh(CO)(Cl)(PPh 3)(H2NCy) were crystallographically characterized. Reactivity of the complex, Rh(CO)(Cl)(PPh3)(HNEt2) towards haloalkanes was also explored, resulting in Rh(III) amine anionic complexes of the type, [RhX4(CO)(PPh3)]-(H2NEt 2)+. X-ray structural characterization of the Rh(III) complexes are discussed. The catalytic reactivity of Rh(CO)(Cl)(PPh3 )(HNEt2) in the hydrosilation of 1-hexene, shows higher activity than both Rh(CO)(Cl)(PPh3)2 and RhCl(PPh3) 3. In the presence of CCl4, Rh(CO)(Cl)(PPh3)(HNEt 2), was able to polymerize styrene and methyl methacrylate. An alternative approach to sol-gel processing, based on acid-base hydrolysis, was used to develop organometallic network supports. The organometallic-inorganic sol-gel was prepared in an non-aqueous medium, under mild reaction conditions, using commercially available reagents, eliminating many of the problems related to the traditional sol-gel technique. The organometallic-inorganic hybrid network catalyzed tolan hydrogenation with selectivities for the fully hydrogenated product, bibenzyl. In the final part of the study on supported catalysis, tri-branched organophosphine and metallo-dendrimers are prepared in excellent yields via acid-base hydrolytic chemistry. The organophosphine dendrimers are used to subsequently bind the Rh(I)(COD)(Cl) complex. An examination of the 31P NMR and MALDI data suggests dendrimer growth. The Rh(I) dendrimers were employed as catalysts for decene hydrogenation resulting in activities similar to the monomeric adduct.</description><creator>Petrucci, Maria G. L.</creator><contributor>Kakkar, Ashok K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><title>New routes to heterogenized homogeneous catalysis via simple acid-base hydrolytic chemistry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j497.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042v62j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj1393733</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The advent of the ep collider HERA at the DESY research center has opened a wide kinematical window for the study of the Deep Inelastic Scattering (DIS) processes e+p→ e+X. Recent measurements of the structure function F2 of the proton have confirmed the fact that the Bjorken scaling which arises from the naive Quark-Parton Model is broken in the limit where the scaling variable, x-Bjorken, is small. It also revealed that F2 grows exponentially with x-Bjorken, at low x. The standard picture of parton evolution, based on the DGLAP equations, reproduces this steep rise if it is used with an appropriate set of F2 parametrizations. However these parametrizations include "ad-hoc" assumptions on the non-perturbative behaviour of the structure functions and depend on a large set of phenomenological parameters. The steep rise can also be reproduced by using a different perturbative treatment for the parton evolution. This treatment, based on the BFKL evolution equations, differs from the standard DGLAP picture by the lack of ordering in the transverse energy of the emitted partons. Unlike DGLAP, the BFKL picture reproduces the steep rise of F2 without assuming any particular shape of the structure function in the non-perturbative domain. In order to gain an insight on parton dynamics in DIS at low x and discriminate between these two pictures, jet observables are used as they are expected to be closely related to the hard scattering and depend only slightly on the hadronization effects. Two jet observables are studied here in more details: the azimuthal correlation between the two leading-order jets and the cross section of the forward jet production. The measured cross sections are corrected for detector effects and compared to several DIS Monte Carlo models and next-to-leading order simulations over a wide kinematic range. The results are evaluated in the light of the BFKL and the DGLAP pictures. The experimental results are compared to other models of parton evolution as well, like the Colour Dipole Model (CDM), the Linked Dipole Chain (LDC) and the resolved photon model in DIS.</description><creator>Riveline, Michael.</creator><contributor>Corriveau, Francois (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Probing the parton evolution in DIS at low xBJ using jet observables</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q322c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1393733</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r36d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of catchment hydrology and biogeochemistry in the production and transport of methylmercury (MeHg) was studied in a headwater catchment in the low boreal forest zone of the Precambrian Shield. A simple, catchment-scale model found that peatlands were large sources of MeHg, and lakes were large sinks. Sensitivity analysis revealed that the volume of runoff delivered to the peatland by the upland, peatland size, and pore water MeHg concentration in the peatland are important controls on catchment MeHg yield. Contemporary atmospheric deposition of MeHg was found to be insignificant compared to the sources of MeHg within the catchment. Sulfate addition experiments were undertaken to examine the controls on MeHg production in peatlands, and it was found that the in situ addition of sulfate to peat and peat pore water resulted in an increase in pore water MeHg concentrations by a factor of 3 to 4. A supporting hydrological study found that the annual catchment hydrologic regime is strongly influenced by the volume and timing of precipitation inputs. For example, a 19% smaller than average snowpack and a dry April in 1995 resulted in the absence of a spring melt runoff event. This finding, coupled with 30% less summer rainfall in 1995 than in 1996, produced low antecedent moisture conditions in the upland soils, 68% less total runoff and reversals of hydraulic gradients. Concentrations of MeHg in pore water were variable across the catchment, with the highest found in the peatland (up to 3.02 ng/l). The delivery of sulfate, carbon quality and temperature appear to influence the production of MeHg at a variety of scales. The mass flux of MeHg within and from the catchment is dependent upon the mass flux of water and the placement of landscape units in the catchment hydrologic cascade. In the two study years, the total mass flux of MeHg over the study period was 8.65 mg and 25.9 mg in 1995 and 1996 respectively.</description><creator>Branfireun, Brian A.</creator><contributor>Roulet, N. T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Methymercury.</subject><title>Catchment-scale hydrology and methylmercury biogeochemistry in the low boreal forest zone of the Precambrian Shield</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806159b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r36d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655j308</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A finite element p-method controls the precision of the solution solely by manipulating the richness of the approximation within each element. In contrast, the h-method uses elements supporting a constant low polynomial order approximation, and subdivides its elements to increase its overall precision. The goal of this thesis is to improve the p-method's procedures in order to the cost of its application. This cost arises from the increased effort due to the use of high order finite element basis, and the added complexity involved in managing high precision local approximations. Specifically, the high order polynomial basis used by p-methods makes the calculation of local matrices time-consuming. This same use of high precision local basis promotes minimally tessellated meshes, increasing the likelihood that p-elements have curved boundaries. Consequently, the precision of their basis is more prone to be affected by curved boundaries. As the finite element basis order of a p-system is increased, the sparsity of the global p-matrix will decrease by no more than one order of magnitude. Hence, the standard h-solvers, which assume a linearly decreasing sparsity with successive refinement, perform poorly. To overcome these difficulties, a curvilinear p-element a proposed that can fit arbitrary boundary shapes exactly without unduly affecting the finite element basis precision. The workload per element of the p-method is reduced by resorting to a new integration procedure capable of producing a local matrix at a constant cost per matrix entry. Finally, an efficient procedure for solving the global matrix system is proposed. It is able to solve p-problems in an amount of computer work that grows no faster than n1.5 over a range of polynomial orders from 1 to 10, n being the total number of degrees of freedom employed.</description><creator>Villeneuve, Donald.</creator><contributor>Webb, Jonathan P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A p-type finite element method for devices with nonlinear materials and curved boundaries /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074w97r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655j308</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vs66v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is characterized by the progressive loss of upper and lower motor neurons. A subset of familial ALS cases (20%; FALS-1) are linked to mutations in the Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase (SOD-1). In order to study the mechanisms of mutant SOD-1 (mSOD-1) toxicity and preferential vulnerability of motor neurons, human wild type and seven different mSOD-1 were expressed in motor neurons or dorsal root ganglion neurons of dissociated cultures of murine spinal cord-dorsal root ganglia, or in cultured hippocampal neurons. Expression was obtained by intranuclear microinjection of plasmid expression vectors. Many features of the motor neuron disease observed in humans with ALS and in mSOD-1 transgenic mice were reproduced in this new culture model, including preferential vulnerability of motor neurons and abnormal distribution of hyperphosphorylated neurofilament proteins. A novel observation was the formation of cytoplasmic SOD-1 aggregates in motor neurons expressing mSOD-1 followed by evidence of apoptotic cell death. Both formation of aggregates and motoneuronal death were reduced by coexpression of the stress-inducible heat shock protein, HSP70, indicating that insufficiency of molecular chaperones may be involved in FALS-1. Using specific antagonists of glutamate receptor subtypes, we have demonstrated that normally nontoxic glutamatergic input, particularly via calcium-permeable AMPA/kainate receptors, is a major factor in the vulnerability of motor neurons to the toxicity of mSOD-1. Partial protection was obtained by blockade of L-type voltage-gated calcium channels, implicating Ca2+ entry through these channels in the toxicity of mSOD-1. Dramatic neuroprotection was obtained by coexpressing the calcium-binding protein calbindin-D28k indicating that the toxicity of mSOD-1 is calcium-dependent. However, increasing intracellular glutathione levels or treatment with N-tert-butyl-alpha-phenylnitrone (PBN) had no significant effect on motone</description><creator>Roy, Josée, 1970.</creator><contributor>Durham, Heather D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Mechanisms of preferential vulnerability of motor neurons in a familial form of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m831s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vs66v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418p91r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous studies suggest that IL-12, the potent Th1-inducing cytokine, IFN-gamma, TNF-alpha and nitric oxide (NO) contribute to resistance against blood-stage malaria. Early Th1 responses correlate with resistance, whereas predominantly Th2 responses are associated with susceptibility. In the present studies, the requirements for endogenous IL-12 and its role in host defense against blood-stage P. chabaudi AS malaria were investigated. Our results reveal, for the first time, significant differences in the kinetics of endogenous IL-12 p70 synthesis and splenic IL-12R beta1 and beta2 mRNA expression between resistant B6 and susceptible A/J mice that correlate with the polarization of Th responses observed in these hosts during early blood-stage malaria. The spleen was found to be the major source of systemic IL-12 in infected B6 hosts. In addition, significant differences were observed between acutely infected B6 and A/J hosts, on a per cell basis, in IL-12 p70 release by splenic macrophages in vitro. Importantly, these differences correlated with greater malaria parasite-induced IFN-gamma synthesis in vitro by spleen cells from infected B6 mice. Furthermore, systemic IL-12 production and Th1 responses were found to be unimpaired in P. chabaudi AS infected mice deficient in TNFR compared to wild type controls. However, LPS, but not PRBC, -induced NO synthesis by splenic macrophages, was significantly reduced in infected TNFR deficient hosts. Finally, compared to controls receiving chloroquine (CQ) alone, the mechanism(s) of combined low dose IL-12 and CQ therapy for malaria-infected A/J mice was found to involve increased splenocyte expression of IL-12R beta1 and beta2 and IFN-gamma mRNA, together with enhanced parasite antigen-induced synthesis of IFN-gamma by spleen cells in vitro. This novel IL-12 and CQ therapeutic strategy resulted in significantly reduced parasitemia, enhanced survival, and was effective against established blood-stage malaria. Taken together</description><creator>Sam, Hakeem.</creator><contributor>Stevenson, M. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Mechanism(s) of interleukin-12-induced protection against early murine blood-stage P. Chabaudi AS malaria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p641b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418p91r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Centre for the Study of Host Resistance</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hd87d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The eighteenth century public sphere has been defined by Habermas in terms of its rational, critical style of debate and egalitarian ideals. In eighteenth century America the public sphere comprised mainly elite merchants. This group mediated between civil society and the state in order to influence government decisions. Motivated largely by commercial interests, they nevertheless claimed to represent the entire society. But around the mid-nineteenth century, the American public sphere began to expand, mainly due to the emergence of a middle class. Debate over Shakespearean drama had a profound effect on the ways in which 19th century civil society presented and considered arguments related to public issues. Increasingly, the credibility of an individual's public utterance, rather than his or her social or intellectual status, was of primary import in determining the merit of an argument. The discursive behaviour adopted in discussion of Shakespeare plays in numerous clubs and societies helped to form habits of rational critical debate which characterized public decision-making in the latter part of the century. Those largely excluded from public debate, such as blacks and women, began to publicly argue for rights previously extended only to white males. The major spread of mass entertainment and its perceived ills toward the end of the century, however, rendered Shakespeare the chief weapon in the resistance to modern vulgarity and commercialism. The wedge which developed in Shakespeare discussion between amateurs and academics at this time may be partly explained by a developing mass consumption mentality which Habermas contends segmented the public into protective, specialized minorities and an often uncritical mass of consumers.</description><creator>Rowland, Hilary.</creator><contributor>Bristol, Michael D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>United States -- Intellectual life.</subject><subject>Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 -- Appreciation -- United States.</subject><subject>Theater and society -- United States.</subject><title>Shakespeare and the public sphere in nineteenth century America</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dt80v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hd87d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mp00v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work has focused on understanding in vivo aspects of ASP metabolism particularly postprandially. I showed that ASP was produced directly from human adipose tissue, a process that increased postprandially and was correlated with increased plasma triglyceride clearance and increased fatty acid incorporation into adipose tissue "FIAT". The target of ASP is adipose tissue. Binding studies in freshly obtained adipose tissue demonstrated specific binding to high affinity receptor sites. ASP binding to subcutaneous tissue from obese females demonstrated the greatest binding and highest receptor affinity. In contrast omental tissue particularly from males showed the lowest specific binding and affinity. This suggests an important role for ASP in maintaining regional adipose tissue mass in females and males, hence providing possible explanations for the metabolic complications seen in abdominal obesity. The strongest evidence for a physiological role of ASP on triglyceride clearance for ASP in vivo was obtained when exogenous intraperitonial hASP was administered to genetically obese mice. Normolipidemic ob /ob mice demonstrated accelerated postprandial TG clearance in the presence of ASP. The effect in the hyperlipidemic: db/db mice, however was markedly greater (2 to 8 times). These findings strongly support the hypothesis that ASP is an important factor in postprandial lipid metabolism and may be a significant factor in determining the pathophysiology of obesity and related dyslipidemias.</description><creator>Saleh, Jumana.</creator><contributor>Cianflone, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Acylation stimulating protein : production, receptor interaction and role in vivo in humans and mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096881h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp00v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wk99k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary objective of this study was to investigate the use of water table management (WTM) as a microbial delivery system for in-situ bioaugmentation of contaminated soils. In addition, the use of Rhizobium ( R.) for PCB degradation in soils was evaluated. First, the presence and isolation of a variety of strains of Rhizobium meliloti was demonstrated using plant nodulation tests on alfalfa plants in soils that were contaminated for over 15 years with PCBs, PAHs and heavy metals. Next, R. meliloti, strain A-025, was selected based on its membrane (hydrophobicity, adhesion) characteristics and its potential to transform PCBs. This strain was delivered and implanted in sod columns, 200 mm in diameter x 1000 mm in length, packed with a sandy loam soil, using surface and subirrigation. The results of this study showed that subirrigation led to a higher number and a more uniform distribution of the bacterial cells in the soil at 60, 300, 500, and 700 mm depths, than surface irrigation. In a different setup, similar column were packed with a PCB contaminated soil. These soil columns were bioaugmented with three bacterial cultures, i.e., R. meliloti (strain A-025), Comomonas testosteroni (strain B-356) and an indigenous bacterial consortium using subirrigation. The results indicated that bioaugmentation of the PCB contaminated soil was possible by using subirrigation. Bioaugmentation with the indigenous culture was observed to be more effective in the biodegradation of PCBs than with A-025 and B-356 cultures at 140 and 340 mm depths. However, at 590 mm depth, bioaugmentation with strain A-025 was observed to be better than the other treatments. Sequential aerobic and anaerobic cycles appear to be of significance for effective dechlorination of PCB congeners to lower chlorinated congeners. In a separate exploratory study, the rhizospheric effects of alfalfa plants on R. meliloti for PCB depletion were investigated. The results suggest that the growth of alfalfa plants and bioaugmentation of soil with R. meliloti, strain A-025, increased the depletion of PCB congeners in the soil as compared to bioaugmentation alone. In other preliminary studies, the results showed that the presence of PCBs in a sandy loam soil increases the filtration of bacterial cells. Also, soil type and the presence of PCBs affected water infiltration, moisture, and hardness of the soil. Furthermore, water table management system along with bioaugmentation of soil columns with R. meliloti, strain A-025, decreased the concentration of atrazine by 31% during anaerobic and aerobic cycles and reduced the concentration of nitrate by 87% and 78% in the absence and presence of atrazine, respectively, in the drainage water. The overall results of this work indicate that water table management (subirrigation) can be used for bioaugmentation of contaminated soils. Also, use of R. meliloti may prove to be an interesting option for soils contaminated with PCBs, atrazine and nitrate.</description><creator>Mehmannavaz, Reza.</creator><contributor>Ahmad, Darakhshan (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Prasher, Shiv O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>In situ bioremediation.</subject><subject>Rhizobium meliloti.</subject><subject>Subirrigation.</subject><subject>Polychlorinated biphenyls -- Biodegradation.</subject><subject>Soil remediation.</subject><title>A laboratory study on the development and testing of a bioaugmentation system for contaminated soils /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp82r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wk99k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wf504</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, the association between the neurokinin substance P (SP) with both its receptor (the NK-1r) and neurokinin B (NKB) was investigated in order to improve our understanding of the synaptic circuitry involving the neurokinins in the sensory spinal cord. In the rat spinal dorsal horn under normal physiological conditions, our immunocytochemical studies demonstrated that the distribution of SP and NK-1r immunoreactivities correlated well. Quantitative analysis at the ultrastructural level revealed that SP-immunoreactive (IR) boutons were more frequently presynaptic to dendritic and cell body profiles expressing the NK-1r than to those profiles not expressing the NK-1r. This indicates that SP preferentially innervates profiles expressing the NK-1r. This preferential innervation of SP on NK-1r-IR profiles was maintained even in conditions in which the SP fibres were ectopically located. In transgenic mice over-expressing SP fibres in the white matter of the spinal cord, SP-IR boutons were often presynaptic to NK-1r-IR dendrites in the white matter. However, in control mice, NK-1r-IR dendrites were rarely apposed by SP-IR boutons in the same area. The physiological relevance of the ectopic SP fibres in the transgenic mice was studied and it was demonstrated that these ectopic fibres were functional. In fact, the transgenic mice displayed both hyperalgesia and allodynia in the tail-withdrawal test. These nociceptive responses were reversed by both NK-1 and NMDA receptor antagonists indicating that both NK-1 and NMDA receptors contributed to the altered nociceptive responses in these mice. In addition, the transgenic mice displayed an increased antinociceptive response following a noxious stimulation when pre-treated with morphine suggesting that morphine treatment uncovers a different response to a mechanical stimulus in transgenic mice as compared to control mice. Finally, NKB-like immunoreactivity was observed in both axonal boutons and dendrites in the ra</description><creator>McLeod, Amber L.</creator><contributor>Ribeiro-da-Silva, Alfredo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Synaptic organization of the neurokinin system in the sensory spinal cord</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz264.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wf504</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt45g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Coastal eutrophication, defined as an increase in algal biomass (as chlorophyll (Chl)) is of increasing international concern. Although coastal eutrophication will likely increase as coastal populations grow, few models exist to support its management. Lake eutrophication has also long been recognized as an important environmental concern. However, effective lake eutrophication management exists, supported by regression and mass-balance models. Traditionally, these "Vollenweider" models link land-use to Chl via total phosphorus (TP), the nutrient considered to be limiting Chl. However, based on a data set of 63 lakes, Chl was more accurately predicted by models based on land-use than by those based on TP. This result provided the rationale to build Chl:land-use models for estuaries where the Chl:nutrient relations are unclear. Chl:land-use models were developed for 15 estuaries in PEI, 19 estuaries in Finland and 26 US estuaries. Land-use models predicted Chl more accurately than TP in the US estuaries and in some of the Finnish estuaries. In the Finnish estuaries, Chl was best predicted by a land-use model in estuaries dominated by nonpoint source loading whereas Chl was most accurately predicted by the Vollenweider approach in estuaries dominated by point-source loading. In the PEI estuaries, the accuracy of the land-use model was comparable to the accuracy of the TP model. The PEI estuaries had much lower yields of Chl per unit nutrient than lakes suggesting differences among systems. This Chl deficit (expected-observed Chl) was accounted for by herbivory and turbidity, neither of which factors are exclusive to estuaries. The comparison of Chl response to nutrients and land-use across lakes and estuaries demonstrated no systematic differences as a function of tidal energy, openness or salinity. The regression models based on the combined data accurately predicted Chl as a function of TP and percentage of the catchment forested and mean depth. These results sug</description><creator>Meeuwig, Jessica Jane.</creator><contributor>Peters, Robert Henry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Land use.</subject><subject>Marine eutrophication -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Eutrophication -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>All water is wet : predicting eutrophication in lakes and estuaries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pv32h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt45g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sh98d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Space manipulators mounted on a free-floating base are structurally flexible mechanical systems. For some applications, it is necessary to control the attitude of the base by the use of on-off thrusters. However, thruster operation produces a rather broad frequency spectrum that can excite sensitive modes of the flexible system. This situation is likely to occur especially when the manipulator is moving a big payload. The excitation of these modes can introduce further disturbances to the attitude control system; therefore, undesirable fuel replenishing limit cycles may develop. To investigate these dynamic interactions, the dynamics model of an N-flexible-joint space manipulator is developed and used to describe a three-flexible-joint manipulator mounted on a six-degree-of-freedom spacecraft dubbed in this thesis "spatial system". Since the attitude controller assumes the use of on-off thrusters, which are nonlinear devices, the describing-function technique, an approximate method for the analysis of nonlinear systems, is used to analyze four different control systems using an approximate two-mass system. This technique is adapted to be used in conjunction with the root-locus concept, thus providing a different picture of the problem and helping in the control system design. A parametric study is performed to compare the control schemes using those analytical tools, which is validated with simulations using the spatial system. It is shown that the three proposed variations of a classical control scheme are very effective to minimize such undesirable dynamic interactions. Finally, Mecano, a commercial mechanical-system modelling and analysis software tool, is adapted for the study of control systems and used to study the effect of link elasticity on the robustness of the proposed control schemes.</description><creator>Martin, Eric, 1969 Feb. 26-</creator><contributor>Angeles, Jorge (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Papadopoulos, Evangelos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>Dynamic interaction of a space manipulator with its base attitude controller</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm168.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sh98d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042v63t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the relationship of George Villiers, First Duke of Buckingham (1592--1628) to the art and aesthetic ideas of his era. As the intimate and all-powerful favourite of two successive kings, James I and Charles 1, Buckingham profoundly influenced the course of English politics, both at home and abroad, and it is as a political force that he is generally viewed. But, as a major patron of many artists and the builder of one of the largest art collections of the time, his influence in the cultural sphere must have been equally significant. Yet no modern study of this aspect of Buckingham's persona exists. After a review of the general historiographical material on Buckingham as well as his evaluation by art historians over the years, Chapter I presents an analysis of the concept and role of Favourite in social and cultural terms. It goes on to detail Buckingham's personal position within early Stuart court culture, and argues that while this culture formed and defined him, he simultaneously re-formed and redefined it through his choices and actions. Chapter II examines the dynamics of art patronage and Buckingham's activity as a patron, beginning with his early dealings with the native English painter, William Larkin. The relationship of Buckingham and the young Anthony Van Dyck is discussed, with parlicular attention to the artist's brief visit to England in 1620--21, and it is suggested that Buckingham was instrumental in bringing about this event. The Duke's dealings with the controversial polymath, Balthazar Gerbier, are explored, as are his many-layered connections with the premier painter of the day, Peter Paul Rubens. In Chapter III the traditions of art collecting, especially in England are discussed, as is Buckingham's reputation as a collector compared to some of his rivals in the field. The extant documentation of his collection is examined, along with the chronology and methodology of its formation. Particular attention is given to gifts of art to Buckingham by King Charles, the Earl of Arundel and others; the art-buying by Buckingham's agents like Balthazar Gerbier; and the incorporation by the Duke into his own inventory of parts of other collections such as that of the Duke of Hamilton and, more importantly, that of Rubens. Both in the realm of court culture and in the world of art patronage and art collecting, it was Buckingham more than anyone else who supplied the energy and set the fashion. And he continued to do so even after his premature death: the Duke's image remained bright in the memory of King Charles, whose subsequent expanded relationships with Rubens and Van Dyck owe much of their intensity to both artists' previous connections with Buckingham.</description><creator>Harvie, Ron.</creator><contributor>Glen, T. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Art patronage -- England -- History -- 17th century.</subject><subject>Art -- Collectors and collecting -- England -- History -- 17th century.</subject><subject>Buckingham, George Villiers, Duke of, 1592-1628.</subject><title>The spectre of Buckingham : art patronage and collecting in early Stuart England</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pp710.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042v63t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cc590</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis seeks to identify the mosaic, rather than the monolithic, nature of culture contact by integrating historical and archaeological sources relating to the concept of gender roles, as they influence response within a contact situation. Specifically, I examine how the Inuit gender system structured artifact patterning in Inuit-European contact situations through the investigation of three Inuit sites in Frobisher Bay, Baffin Island. These date from the 16th, 19th and early 20th centuries and represent a variety of seasonal occupations and dwelling forms. The ethnographic data suggest that Inuit gender relations were egalitarian and complementary. On this basis I hypothesize that European goods and materials were used equally by men and women. Within each gendered set of tasks, European goods and materials were differently used, according to empirically functional criteria such as the nature of the tasks. Opportunities for and responses to European contact differed depending on the types of tasks in which Inuit women and men engaged and the social roles they played. Seasonality of occupation bears upon the archaeological visibility of gender activities. Sixteenth-century Elizabethan contact did not alter Nugumiut gender roles, tasks, authority or status but served primarily as a source of raw material, namely wood and iron. Based on the analysis of slotted tools I suggest a refinement to take account of the overlap in blade thickness that occurs for metal and slate, and which depends on the function of the tool. I conclude that there was much more metal use by Thule Inuit than previously believed. However, during Elizabethan contact and shortly afterwards there was actually less metal use by the Nugumiut than in the prehistoric era. Little archaeological evidence was recovered for 19th-century commercial whaling contact, (suggesting geographic marginality to European influence), or for 19th century Inuit occupation in the area. This is partly because of immigration to Cumberland Sound and because of subsequent structural remodelling of the dwellings by later occupants. By the early 20th century, the archaeological record showed not only equal use of European material across gender but a near-ubiquitous distribution across most activity classes, even though commercial trapping never replaced traditional subsistence pursuits but only supplemented them.</description><creator>Gullason, Lynda.</creator><contributor>Fitzhugh, William (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Morantz, Toby (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Inuit -- Nunavut -- Iqaluit -- Antiquities.</subject><subject>Sexual division of labor -- Nunavut -- Iqaluit -- History.</subject><subject>Inuit -- Material culture -- Nunavut -- Iqaluit.</subject><subject>Iqaluit (Nunavut) -- Antiquities.</subject><title>Engendering interaction : Inuit-European contact in Frobisher Bay, Baffin Island</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r068.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc590</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t3721</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation describes both methodological developments in quantitative functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) of cerebral oxygen consumption, and the results of experiments using these techniques to elucidate the mechanisms linking focal changes in blood flow and oxygen metabolism. Technical contributions presented include a novel MRI pulse sequence for simultaneously monitoring cerebral blood flow and tissue oxygenation with high signal-to-noise ratio, as well as an experiment automation system permitting complex multiparametric studies to be carried out efficiently in large numbers of subjects. These tools enabled us to make a number of significant neurophysiological discoveries with important implications for the design and interpretation of fMRI experiments. In particular, relative changes in cerebral perfusion and oxygen consumption were found to be coupled in a consistent linear ratio of approximately 2:1, respectively, in human visual cortex. A quantitative model predicting that oxygenation-sensitive MRI signals must be extremely sensitive to departures from this coupling ratio was also introduced, revealing that combined perfusion/oxygenation measurement during graded activation is a powerful tool for studying regulatory relationships between these parameters. Predictions based on this model were in excellent agreement with experimental results, supporting model-derived estimates of oxygen consumption and suggesting that the ~2:1 coupling discovered in visual cortex is likely to apply in most cortical systems. Finally, important non-linear characteristics of fMRI signal dynamics in human visual cortex were revealed, challenging current models of fMRI transient response.</description><creator>Hoge, Richard D.</creator><contributor>Pike, G. Bruce (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Magnetic resonance imaging of cerebral oxygen consumption and perfusion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx128.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t3721</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s650g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Abnormal heart rhythms are often associated with serious illness and sometimes cause death. A new strategy to control cardiac arrhythmias involves precisely-timed electrical stimulation of the heart in an attempt to restore normal dynamics. In the first part of this thesis, I demonstrate that a particular abnormal heart rhythm is caused by a period-doubling bifurcation. I describe a new control technique that suppresses the abnormal rhythm by directing the timing of electrical stimuli according to a simple feedback algorithm. Subsequent analysis of the feedback controller revealed a rich structure of stability zones that can be used for automatic adaptation of the previously fixed feedback gain parameter. While electrical stimulation of the heart guided by feedback control is a promising new treatment, the standard means of controlling an abnormal heart rhythm involves accurate diagnosis of the arrhythmia mechanism followed by appropriate medical or surgical intervention. Since different arrhythmia mechanism often have very different treatments, accurate diagnosis is crucial. In the second part of this thesis, I describe a new diagnostic technique that identifies the different spatio-temporal symmetry properties of electrical wave patterns underlying different mechanisms of cardiac arrhythmia. For one of the arrhythmia mechanisms, the surgical treatment involves locating and destroying an abnormal region of the heart that generates unwanted electrical oscillations. I present new techniques for locating these abnormal regions and I suggest a procedure to confirm when the correct location has been found.</description><creator>Hall, Kevin.</creator><contributor>Glass, Leon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Control of abnormal heart rhythms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956h59k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s650g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc17g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is the first major study of censorship of and in English Canadian literature. While there are several reasons scholars have focused on censorship in Europe and the United States, it is the ascendancy in quality and quantity of Canadian writing leading to its further use in institutions where censorship takes place---such as schools and libraries---that necessitates a study of censorship in Canadian literature now. This rise in censorship has prompted Canadian authors increasingly to write about the subject. In this thesis I study censorship issues raised both explicitly md implicitly by Timothy Findley, Margaret Atwood, Margaret Laurence, Beatrice Culleton and Marlene Nourbese Philip. All of these writers have been subjected to censorship attacks and have responded to these attacks and grappled with the philosophical implications of censorship in their fiction and non-fiction. My investigation of censorship in these texts sheds new light on the works of literature themselves, but the literary texts also suggest a new way of looking at censorship. Each of my chapters offers arguments challenging the traditional Enlightenment model of censorship as an oppressive government practice against its citizens, a definition resulting in the mistaken views that censorship has been largely eradicated in the West and that, when it does surface, it is to be condemned on principle. This view can be contrasted with a "constructivist" model of censorship as the delegitimation of expression by social forces. My findings support a definition which draws on both models wherein censorship is the exclusion of some discourse as the result of a judgment by an authoritative agent based on some ideological predisposition. The key word in this definition is "judgment" which, when recognized as the primary activity in censorship, must change the way we approach censorship controversies. For if censorship is the exercise of judgment, and judgment is enmeshed in the fabric of huma</description><creator>Cohen, Mark, 1966-</creator><contributor>Cooke, Nathalie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Censorship -- Canada.</subject><subject>Canadian literature -- Censorship.</subject><title>Just judgment : censorship of and in Canadian literature</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35696130.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc17g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vv92m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Src family protein tyrosine kinases are involved in the regulation of a large number of cellular processes in response to extracellular stimuli. Their crucial role in the initiation of cellular activation of T-lymphocytes following stimulation of the T-cell receptor by an antigen has sparked great interest in better understanding the regulation of their catalytic activity and function. The protein tyrosine kinase Csk is the major negative regulator of Src-related kinases through its ability to phosphorylate a negative regulatory tyrosine, in their carboxy-terminal region. By virtue of its negative impact on Src-like enzymes, Csk is capable of down-regulating T-cell activation. Nevertheless, the mechanisms regulating the inhibition of T-cell receptor signalling by Csk are still poorly understood. The experiments presented in this thesis were aimed at improving our understanding of the regulation of Csk in T-lymphocytes. I have demonstrated that the SH3 and SH2 domains of Csk, which can mediate protein-protein interactions, are essential for its capacity to down-regulate T-cell activation. This observation led me to the identification of the first known ligand for the SH3 domain of Csk, the protein tyrosine phosphatase, PEP. Functional analysis of the Csk-PEP complex revealed that these two enzymes cooperate to inhibit signals generated by Src-related enzymes, thereby acting as potent negative regulators of T-cell activation. Taken together, the results obtained suggest that the inhibitory function of Csk is not only dependent on its ability to phosphorylate the carboxy-terminal tyrosine of Src-related enzymes, but also relates to its ability to associate with the protein tyrosine phosphatase PEP.* *Originally published in DAI Vol. 61, No. 6. Reprinted here with corrected author name.</description><creator>Cloutier, Jean-Francois, 1971-</creator><contributor>Veillette, Andre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>The association between an inhibitory kinase and a phosphatase : a novel facet in the regulation of Src-related enzymes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q62x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vv92m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rg188</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we applied both numerical methods and artificial intelligence techniques to NMR data processing and analysis. First, a comprehensive study of the Iterative Quadratic Maximum Likelihood (IQML) method applied to NMR spectral parameter estimation is reported. The IQML is compared to other conventional time domain data analysis methods. Extensive simulations demonstrate the superior performance of the IQML method. We also develop a new technique, which uses genetic algorithm with a priori knowledge, to improve the quantification of NMR spectral parameters. The new proposed method outperforms the other conventional methods, especially in the situations that there are signals close in frequencies and the signal-to-noise ratio of the FID is low. The usefulness of Singular Value Decomposition (SVD) method in NMR data processing is further exploited. A new two dimensional spectral processing scheme based on SVD is proposed for suppressing strong diagonal peaks. The superior performance of this method is demonstrated on an experimental phase-sensitive COSY spectrum. Finally, we studied the feasibility of using neural network predicted secondary structure information in the NMR data analysis. Protein chemical shift databases are compiled and are used with the neural network predicted protein secondary structure information to improve the accuracy of protein chemical shift prediction. The potential of this strategy for amino acid classification in NMR resonance assignment is explored.</description><creator>Choy, Wing Yiu, 1969-</creator><contributor>Sanctuary, Bryan C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><subject>Artificial Intelligence.</subject><title>Using numerical methods and artificial intelligence in NMR data processing and analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg24b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rg188</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032470c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis I have retrieved the modern language of the law of nature between the period 1625--1672. I have reconstructed this language as a response to the seventeenth century breakdown of society in Europe. In Chapters 1, 2 and 3, I lay out Hugo Grotius' moral and political theory grounded in three irreducible principles of self-preservation, the primacy of society and consent. These principles lead Grotius to develop a rich and pluralistic theory. Thomas Hobbes's theory calls into question the complex Grotian social and political arrangement and in its place provides an absolutist and homogeneous conception of the state. This is treated in Chapter 4. In Chapters 5 and 6, I lay out Samuel Pufendorf's moral and political theory. Pufendorf accepts Grotius's and Hobbes' initial premises but argues for a 'regular' or homogeneous state. The retrieval of the law of nature proposed in this thesis is important, for it radically calls into question the conventional manner in which we understand the seventeenth century. Among other things, this work illuminates the common foundation shared by contemporary liberals, communitarians and more radical theories.</description><creator>Chimni, Ravinder Singh.</creator><contributor>Taylor, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Tully, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Pufendorf, Samuel, Freiherr von, 1632-1694 -- Contributions in natural law.</subject><subject>Natural law -- History -- 17th century.</subject><subject>Hobbes, Thomas, 1588-1679 -- Contributions in natural law.</subject><subject>Grotius, Hugo, 1583-1645 -- Contributions in natural law.</subject><title>The modern language of the law of nature : rights, duties and sociality in Grotius, Hobbes and Pufendorf</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k8871.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032470c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268685n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The contemporary study in the philosophy of language concentrates extensively on a cluster of questions defining the problem of linguistic knowledge (Evans 1981, Davies 1989, Dummett 1991). What explains a speaker's language mastery? Is it knowledge that underwrites our linguistic abilities, and if so, what is the nature of this knowledge? Is rationality an intrinsic feature of language mastery, and if so, how does an account of linguistic knowledge accommodate the connection between language and rationality? While philosophers emphasize the importance of such questions for an account of language, the only systematic response to them has been based almost exclusively on research in psycho-linguistics, and in cognitive science, generally. And prominent cognitivists, such as Chomsky, use their view of linguistic knowledge to promote fervently the naturalistic ideal that the language researcher adhere faithfully to the methodology of the natural scientist, and to provide a thorough critique of any alternative (i.e., non-naturalistic or dualist) approach to language (Chomsky 1995a). In the thesis, I respond to the negative side of cognitivism, and defend a non-naturalistic approach to linguistic knowledge which I call interpretivism. I argue that when applied to interpretivism the cognitivist's critique is rather inconclusive. And, by itself, the cognitivist's explanation of language does not imply that interpretivism is invalid, but rather leaves room for it. The cognitivist explicates linguistic knowledge either as a system of computational states (Stich 1975) or as a set of intentional states (Dwyer and Pietroski 1996). And while under the computationalist construal the cognitivist cannot address the rationality of language, under the intentionalist construal he does not do full justice to it. The interest of interpretivism lies thus in its emphasis on the rational aspects of language, and on the related idea that linguistic knowledge is multifarious: not only intentional or computational, but also similar in kind to the capacity for thought. Following Sellars [1960/1963], I introduce a broad view of explanations of human behaviour within which both the cognitivist and the interpretivist model of explanation are tenable. I conclude that there is room and a need for a non-naturalistic approach to linguistic knowledge, and that naturalism cannot be the only defensible strategy in the study of language.</description><creator>Ungureanu, Manuela L.</creator><contributor>Pietroski, Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Dwyer, Susan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Language and languages -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Dualism.</subject><subject>Naturalism.</subject><title>Naturalism and dualism in the study of language and mind</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333404c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268685n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qk475</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is about the professionalization of nursing. Nursing leaders at the national level and in New Brunswick initiated a new education policy requiring the baccalaureate degree as entry to practice. The new education policy would eliminate the diploma programs which are two to three years in length in favour of the baccalaureate degree which is four years in length. This study demonstrates that the case of upgrading nurse education was a carefully planned event requiring the acceptance of groups within nursing and the government, and was not part of the occupation's natural evolution. Publicly, nursing leaders argued that the increase in work complexity necessitates a more qualified and educated workforce. Less publicized reasons for the change were the desire to be perceived as a profession, the hope for more respect from other occupations, increased autonomy, and increased financial rewards. There was, as well, the desire to expand nursing tasks which would address the belief that traditional, valued nursing tasks were being taken on by other health care workers. Four competing theoretical perspectives were used to interpret the education change in nursing: functionalist, human capital theory, the interactionist perspective, and conflict theory. The findings from this study support the explanatory power of both the interactionist perspective and conflict theory. The interactionist perspective, focusing on intra-occupational processes, suggests that the conflict between the professional nursing association in New Brunswick, who initiated the education policy change, and the provincial nursing union, who vehemently opposed the policy change, stems partially from differences in organizational memberships, beliefs about nursing roles and broader occupational goals. Conflict theory (in particular closure theory), describes how occupations pursuing a 'professional project' may define membership in such a way to exclude other subordinate groups (e.g. the use of credentials). Thus, the baccalaureate entry to practice may be interpreted as an exclusionary strategy which will close off opportunities to diploma nurses in an attempt to enhance nursing's status. In order to achieve this goal, nursing leaders needed the support of the provincial government.</description><creator>Rhéaume, Ann.</creator><contributor>Smith, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Nursing -- Study and teaching -- New Brunswick -- History.</subject><subject>Professions -- Sociological aspects.</subject><title>The professionalization of nursing : a study of the changing entry to practice requirements in New Brunswick</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj30g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk475</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff365694v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation provides a cultural history of the first North American film archive, the Film Library of the Museum of Modern Art (New York), established in 1935. It asks a seemingly simple question: How was it that small, popular, debased, ephemeral objects like films came to be treated as precious, complex and valuable historical objects? It therefore explores how ideas about archiving (seeing and saving films) intersect with practices of collection and exhibition, by mapping the evolution of key institutional discourses and cultural trends from the birth of the medium to the Film Library. It considers links between the archive and longstanding concepts in film culture---utopianism, cinematic knowledge and art. It attends to the more specific convergence of interests---public and private, national and international---which impacted on the Film Library's institutional shape and on the debates in which it was embroiled. This dissertation shows that despite the Film Library's home within an institution of modern art, film's archival value was associated more with the urgency of recovering a history that had been lost and less with an art that had been neglected. This contention is further supported by an examination of the Film Library's first circulating film programs and their public reception. This dissertation postulates that the library's development of an unprecedented and broad acquisition policy as well as an active exhibition program made it more than a mere reflection of the uniquely historical and modern attributes of the cinema: a meeting of aesthetic ferment, technology, commercialism, propaganda, popularity and information. It concludes that the library was an important intervention into these discourses marking with institutional certainty the contested nature of film as a cultural object as well as the ongoing project to understand it.</description><creator>Wasson, Haidee.</creator><contributor>Burnett, Ron (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Szanto, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.). Film Library -- History.</subject><subject>Motion pictures -- United States -- History.</subject><title>Modern ideas about old films : the Museum of Modern Art's Film Library and film culture, 1935-39</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9354703.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365694v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zc87j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work, the Nature and Value of Scepticism, shows that the metaphilosopby arising from what David Hume calls "true scepticism," is of use and value, refuting three standard objections to sceptical philosophy: the charges of unlivability, of idleness and of being dangerous and destructive. The unlivability charge is refuted with an examination of the work of a self-proclaimed extreme sceptic, Sextus Empiricus. The idleness charge is answered by questioning its assumption that if scepticism does not lead to an extreme conclusion, it must be idle and without philosophical interest. The destructive charge, that the acceptance of scepticism would result in the death of rationality, is countered in reviewing the work of Hume and Ludwig Wittgenstein, showing that their outlook is not against philosophy but only a particular type of philosophy, namely dogmatic philosophy. Chapter 1 argues that two reasonable interpretations of Sextus's writings yield a scepticism that is livable and philosophically important. Chapter 2 shows Hume's philosophy is livable and not destructive. Chapter 3 examines the connection between Hume's philosophy and his sceptical approach, arguing that his true scepticism informs his philosophical outlook. Chapter 4 argues that Wittgenstein shares much with Hume's "true scepticism," and that his work is not anti-philosophical as widely supposed. Chapter 5 provides examples of how a sceptically informed metaphilosophy can help address questions in epistemology and metaethics.</description><creator>McCormick, Miriam.</creator><contributor>Norton, David (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Stroud, Sarah (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Hume, David, 1711-1776</subject><subject>Skepticism.</subject><subject>Sextus, Empiricus. Pyrrōneioi hypotypōseis.</subject><subject>Wittgenstein, Ludwig, 1889-1951 -- Views on skepticism.</subject><title>The nature and value of scepticism /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731566d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc87j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33500</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>