<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:19:54Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):47775" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g456j</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:35:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The current research evaluated the influence of various media (BG11, MN8, MZM, MBBM) including simulated dairy wastewater (10D, 10D+Y) on the growth, biomass productivity and lutein content of an under-examined algal strain Chlorella variabilis. The study demonstrated that the algal strain performed better in 10D with a biomass productivity of 0.037 g/L/day and enhanced lutein content to 9.6 mg/g. The results from this study also proved that 10D could be used as a cultivation medium for the large scale production of the alga with huge economic benefits. In order to overcome the problems associated with culture crashes, it was decided to employ a microalgal consortia for further studies. The effect of light wavelengths (blue, red, amber, amber+blue and cool-fluorescent) on the growth, biomass productivity, and lutein content of the microalgal consortia composed of Chlorella variabilis and Scenedesmus obliquus cultivated on simulated dairy wastewater was evaluated and the results showed that cool fluorescent light was the best choice with a biomass productivity of 0.042 g/L/day and lutein content of 7.22 mg/g when compared to other light treatments. A Central Composite design was employed to optimize the biomass productivity, lutein content and pollutant removal capability of the microalgal consortia with respect to inoculum concentration, light intensity and time. It was found that at optimal conditions of 40% inoculum concentration,                             25 µmol m-2s-1 and time of 10 days, the microalgal consortia had a biomass productivity of 29.13 mg/L/day and lutein content of 12.59 mg/g. The lutein content exhibited in this study is the highest ever reported for any microalgal consortia studied so far and could be a commercial source of lutein in the future. Finally, based on the results obtained from the optimization study, the effect of the microalgal consortia as a biofertilizer on the plant growth of corn and soybean was also evaluated. The results demonstrated that 40% algal concentration showed better plant growth in both corn and soybean with improved secondary characteristics when compared to other treatments. Overall, the thesis showed that the microalgal consortia of Chlorella variabilis and Scenedesmus obliquus could be the first of its kind with the potentiel of being incorporated into a biorefinery concept with huge multifaceted benefits</description><description>La recherche actuelle a évalué l'influence de divers milieux (BG11, MN8, MZM, MBBM), y compris les eaux usées laitières simulées (10D, 10D + Y) sur la croissance, la productivité de la biomasse et la teneur en lutéine d'une souche d'algue sous-examinée Chlorella variabilis. L'étude a démontré que la souche d'algues fonctionnait mieux en 10D avec une productivité de la biomasse de 0,037 g / L / jour et une teneur en lutéine augmentée à 9,6 mg / g. Les résultats de cette étude ont également prouvé que le 10D pouvait être utilisé comme milieu de culture pour la production à grande échelle de l'algue avec d'énormes avantages économiques. Afin de surmonter les problèmes liés aux accidents de culture, il a été décidé d'employer des consortiums de microalgues pour des études complémentaires. L'effet des longueurs d'onde lumineuses (bleu, rouge, ambre, ambre + bleu et fluorescent froid) sur la croissance, la productivité de la biomasse et la teneur en lutéine des consortiums de microalgues composés de Chlorella variabilis et Scenedesmus obliquus cultivés sur des eaux usées laitières simulées a été évalué et le les résultats ont montré que la lumière fluorescente froide était le meilleur choix avec une productivité de biomasse de 0,042 g / l / jour et une teneur en lutéine de 7,22 mg / g par rapport à d'autres traitements légers. Une conception composite centrale a été utilisée pour optimiser la productivité de la biomasse, la teneur en lutéine et la capacité d'élimination des polluants des consortiums de microalgues en ce qui concerne la concentration de l'inoculum, l'intensité lumineuse et le temps. Il a été constaté que dans des conditions optimales de concentration d'inoculum de 40%, de 25 µmol m-2s-1 et de 10 jours, les consortiums de microalgues avaient une productivité en biomasse de 29,13 mg / L / jour et une teneur en lutéine de 12,59 mg / g. La teneur en lutéine présentée dans cette étude est la plus élevée jamais rapportée pour tous les consortiums de microalgues étudiés jusqu'à présent et pourrait être une source commerciale de lutéine à l'avenir. Enfin, sur la base des résultats de l'étude d'optimisation, l'effet des consortiums de microalgues comme biofertilisant sur la croissance végétale du maïs et du soja a également été évalué. Les résultats ont démontré qu'une concentration d'algues de 40% a montré une meilleure croissance des plantes dans le maïs et le soja avec des caractéristiques secondaires améliorées par rapport à d'autres traitements. Dans l'ensemble, la thèse a montré que les consortiums de microalgues de Chlorella variabilis et Scenedesmus obliquus pourraient être les premiers du genre avec le potentiel d'être incorporés dans un concept de bioraffinerie avec d'énormes avantages à multiples facettes</description><creator>Gatamaneni Loganathan, Bhalamurugan</creator><contributor>Valerie Orsat (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Mark Lefsrud (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>Micro-algae assisted bioremediation of simulated dairy effluent and valorization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nq75r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g456j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nn50q</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:35:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les hétérostructures bidimensionnelles (2D) de van der Waals (vdW) ont attiré l’attention dans les dernières années. En empilant différents matériaux 2D liés faiblement par la force de vdW, on obtient des bicouches ou des multicouches artificielles qui créent autant de sujets recherche fondamentale et d’avenues de développement technologique. Une caractéristique presque commune à toutes les hétérostructures de vdW est le moiré provoqué par le mésappariement des structures cristallines ou la rotation relative des couches, ce qui crée une modulation latérale périodique du potentiel électronique dans l’hétérostructure. Un tel moiré peut ainsi former une super-structure cristalline 1D ou 2D produisant d’intéressants phénomènes physiques.Dans cette thèse, nous proposons et étudions théoriquement la notion de vallétronique topologique dans les hétérostructures 2D de vdW, selon laquelle les moirés induisent des mosaïques de canaux de conductions topologiques pour les états électroniques des vallées. Des calculs systématiques à partir de principes premiers sont effectuées sur des systems graphène/hBN pour établir une compréhension de base de la formation de canaux topologiques de moiré, et les nouveaux phénomènes topologiques des moirés se retrouvent également dans une vaste gamme de matériaux 2D de vdW. En effet, en raison de la robustesse structurelle, la physique topologique des moirés peut aussi être observée en 1D: où les matériaux graphène/hBN 2D sont enroulés de sorte à former des structures tubulaires qu’on nomme des hétéronanotubes topologiques (THT). à cause des possibilités infinies de l’indice des tubes, des états de vallée topologiques intéressants sont présents en 1D et modulés par les moirés avec diverses périodes et orientations chirales. Nous montrons également que la nouvelle physique des points de Dirac provenant des moirés se manifeste sous d’autres formes, y compris en induisant des cônes de Dirac secondaires dans les super-structures cristallines graphène/hBN en nid d’abeille. L’ordre topologique des moirés 2D est analysé en calculant le nombre Chern de vallée des bandes électroniques. Pour les nanotubes de carbone 1D (CNT), la classification topologique peut être établie en calculant la phase topologique de Zak. Fait intéressant, nous découvrons que la phase de Zak des CNT orientés zigzag est quantifiée et prend une valeur de 0 ou π, ce qui suggère la présence de différentes topologies parmi les phases isolantes des CNT orientés zigzag, et une règle 2N qui classe topologiquement les phases isolantes est établie à la fois analytiquement et numériquement.Nous concluons que les moirés qui apparaissent naturellement dans les matériaux bicouches 2D de vdW et les structures de carbone tubulaires 1D mènent à des états topologiques de vallée nouveaux et variés qui sont protégés par certains ordres topologiques, et qui peuvent donc resister à de grandes perturbations. Les recherches exposées dans cette thèse fournissent un aperçu général, robuste et expérimentalement faisable permettant d’étudier la science fondamentale de la topologie de dimension réduite et les applications pratiques que sont les nanodispositifs à base de carbone et la nanoélectronique fiables de faible puissance</description><description>Two-dimensional (2D) van der Waals (vdW) heterostructures have attracted great attentions in recent years. By stacking different 2D materials to weakly bond via the vdW force, the resulting artificial bilayers and/or multi-layers create novel material platforms for fundamental as well as technological exploration. A nearly ubiquitous feature of the vdW heterostructures is the moiré pattern caused by lattice mismatch or relative rotation of the two stacking lattices which creates a periodic lateral modulation on the electronic potential in the heterostructure. Such moiré modulation can form large-scale 2D and 1D superlattice leading to interesting new physics. In this thesis, we propose and theoretically investigate the notion of topological valleytronics in 2D vdW heterostructures where moiré patterns are predicted to induce arrays of topologically protected pathways of valley electronic states. Systematic and first-principles calculations on the graphene/hBN systems are carried out to establish a basic understanding of the formation of topological moiré edges, and the novel moiré topological physics is also found in a broad range of other 2D vdW materials. Importantly, due to the structural robustness, the moiré topological physics can be extended to 1D: where the 2D graphene/hBN materials are rolled up into tubular structures to form topological heteronanotubes (THT). Due to essentially infinite possibilities of the tube index, interesting valley topological states are found and modulated by various 1D moiré patterns with different moiré periods and chiral orientations. We also show that the novel valley-Dirac physics resulted from moiré patterns show up in other aspects, including the appearance of secondary Dirac cones induced by the large-scale honeycomb graphene/hBN moiré superlattice. The topological order of the 2D moiré systems are analyzed by calculating the valley Chern number of the electronic bands. For 1D carbon nanotube (CNT) systems, the topological classification can be built by calculating the topological Zak phase. Interestingly, we discover that the Zak phase of zigzag CNTs can be quantized to take 0 or π, suggesting topological differences in the insulating phases of the zigzag CNT, and a 2N-rule is established both analytically and numerically that topologically classifies the insulating phases.We conclude that moiré patterns which appear naturally on 2D vdW double-layer materials and/or 1D tubular carbon structures lead to very rich and novel valley topological states which are protected by certain topological orders and thus can sustain large external perturbations. Our researches in this thesis provide a general, robust and experimentally feasible platform for both investigating fundamental science of low-dimensional topological physics and practical applications in reliable low-power carbon-based nanodevices and nanoelectronics</description><creator>Hu, Chen</creator><contributor>Hong Guo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>Novel topological valleytronics in moiré heterostructures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zs78z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nn50q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042z693</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:35:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: The Muslim people are the second-largest religious group in Canada and represent approximately 3.2 per cent of the population. Since the Bouchard-Taylor commission on ''reasonable accommodation'' of minorities in Quebec, Muslim people have been at the forefront of the debate on religious signs and symbols. They have also faced discrimination and even violence; the Quebec City mosque shooting in 2017 being an example. While there is a large body of research on the impact of racial and ethnic discrimination on physical and mental health, very little is known about the impact of religious discrimination. In particular, we know very little about how experiencing religious discrimination may affect people's oral health and oral health-related behaviors.Research Question: How does religious discrimination affect the oral health care of Muslim people?Methodology: We conducted a qualitative exploratory study within the Muslim people of Montreal, Quebec. We adopted a maximum variation sampling strategy regarding age, sex, education level, marital status, and employment status. We collected our data through face-to-face, in-depth, semi-structured interviews of 11 participants practicing Islam. The interviews were audio - recorded and transcribed verbatim to be analyzed. Data analysis was carried out by using a thematic analysis approach, which allowed us to provide a detailed description of the phenomenon.Results: The participants experienced religious discrimination in three different settings, most commonly in daily life but also in the healthcare and the dental healthcare systems. The participants experienced discrimination in the form of verbal, non-verbal, physical aggression related to Islamic clothing and prayer rituals in public places (metro station, streets, bus, etc.). These experiences had a major impact on their life, including stress and anxiety, feelings of insecurity, and, in some cases, emigration to escape discrimination. Some participants experienced negative behaviors and disinterest from healthcare and non-healthcare professionals (receptionists), which generated a lack of trust in healthcare professionals in general. Three participants had similar experiences during their dental visits that led them to lose trust in dentists and, ultimately, avoid dental visits.Conclusion: In sum, our findings showed that religious discrimination had an impact on the mental health of the Muslim people through stress and anxiety. It may have an impact on the use of dental care services and access to care. And this, in turn, may negatively impact oral health. We were unable to determine the impact of psychological stress and anxiety on oral health-related behaviors such as diet and oral hygiene</description><description>Contexte: Les musulmans constituent le deuxième groupe religieux en importance au Canada et représentent environ 3,2% de la population. Depuis la commission Bouchard-Taylor sur les accommodements raisonnables des minorités au Québec, les musulmans sont au premier plan du débat sur les signes et symboles religieux. Ils ont également été victimes de discrimination et même de violence, comme ce fut le cas lors d'une fusillade dans une mosquée de la ville de Québec en 2017.Il existe de nombreuses recherches sur l'impact de la discrimination raciale et ethnique sur la santé physique et mentale, mais l'impact de la discrimination religieuse est très mal connu. En particulier, nous savons très peu comment la discrimination religieuse pourrait affecter la santé bucco-dentaire et les comportements liés à celle-ci.Question de recherche: Comment la discrimination religieuse affecte-t-elle les soins de santé bucco-dentaire des musulmans?Méthodologie: Nous avons mené une recherche exploratoire qualitative au sein de la communauté musulmane de Montréal, au Québec. Nous avons adopté une stratégie d'échantillonnage à variation maximale en ce qui concerne l'âge, le genre, le niveau de scolarité, l'état matrimonial et le statut professionnel. Notre méthode de collecte de données était basée sur des entretiens semi-structurés et approfondis avec 11 participants pratiquant l'islam. Les entretiens ont été enregistrés et transcrits pour être analysés. L'analyse des données a été réalisée en utilisant une approche d'analyse thématique, ce qui nous a permis de fournir une description détaillée du phénomène.Résultats: Les participants ont rapporté être victimes de discrimination religieuse dans trois contextes différents, le plus souvent dans la vie quotidienne, mais également dans le système de soins et le système de soins dentaires. Cette discrimination prenait la forme d'agressions verbales, non verbales, et même physiques, et était liée aux vêtements et signes religieux dans les lieux publics (station de métro, rues, bus, etc.). Ces expériences avaient un impact significatif sur la vie des participants, causant notamment du stress et de l’anxiété, un sentiment d’insécurité et, dans certains cas, une émigration pour échapper à la discrimination. Certains participants ont également rapporté des comportements négatifs et un désintérêt de la part des professionnels de la santé et de leur staff (notamment les réceptionnistes), ce qui engendrait un manque de confiance envers les professionnels de la santé en général. Trois participants ont vécu des expériences similaires lors de visites chez le dentiste, ce qui les avait amenés à perdre confiance en leur dentiste et, finalement, à éviter de consulter.Conclusion: Nos résultats ont montré que la discrimination religieuse avait un impact sur la santé mentale de la population musulmane, causant du stress et de l'anxiété. Cela pourrait avoir un impact sur l'utilisation des services de soins dentaires et l'accès aux soins et, ultimement, affecter négativement la santé buccodentaire. Nous n'avons toutefois pas observé d'impact de ce stress et de cette anxiété sur les comportements liés à la santé buccodentaire tels que le régime alimentaire et l'hygiène buccale</description><creator>Tandale, Madhura</creator><contributor>Christophe Bedos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Dentistry</subject><title>We are what we are: Religious discrimination and oral health care among Muslim people in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q146s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042z693</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sj28g</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:35:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bien que le Canada soit officiellement un pays multiculturel et reconnaisse les contributions culturelles de ses diverses minorités ethniques, les fonds publics ne sont pas alloués aux langues minoritaires ou aux langues d’origine (LO), comme ils le sont pour les deux langues officielles du Canada, l’anglais et le français (Haque, 2012). Les efforts de préservation des LO sont donc principalement organisés par les communautés minoritaires respectives, qui sont particulièrement préoccupées par le potentiel de changement et de perte de la langue, en particulier après la troisième génération. Dans le contexte de l’enseignement de LO grecque au Canada, il est essentiel de renforcer le lien des apprenants avec leur LO, car il existe à présent de nombreux apprenants de la LO grecque de la troisième et quatrième générations qui possèdent une connaissance minimale du grec et dont la seule possibilité d'apprendre et pratiquer leur LO est dans les écoles grecques (Aravossitas, 2016). Il est donc essentiel de trouver des moyens d'améliorer l'enseignement de la LO grecque afin de s'assurer que les générations actuelles et futures de Grecs au Canada puissent conserver ce lien avec leur LO. Il est indéniable que les acteurs les plus importants dans le contexte de l'enseignement d'une LO grecque sont les apprenants, car ils représentent l'avenir des communautés grecques hors de la Grèce. Néanmoins, cette étude s’attache plutôt aux enseignants de langue grecque, car leurs attitudes et leurs pratiques façonnent en grande partie les expériences des apprenants dans les écoles grecques et peuvent les engager ou les aliéner. Le but de cette étude était de déterminer comment les professeurs de LO grecque inscrits aux programmes de grec à la fois primaires et secondaires de la grande région métropolitaine de Montréal et de Toronto s'identifiaient et comment leur identification et leurs idéologies affectaient leurs attitudes envers leurs élèves et leurs pratiques pédagogiques. Ma compréhension du processus de « langager » et des identités linguistiques est éclairée par une sociolinguistique poststructuraliste critique, selon laquelle les pratiques et les identités linguistiques sont conçues comme étant interdépendantes, socialement construites et constamment (re)négociées dans de l’interaction. Lors de la conception de cette étude, l’hypothèse de base était que l’identification et les idéologies des enseignants façonnaient en grande partie leurs attitudes à l’égard des élèves et, finalement, leurs pratiques pédagogiques ; ces facteurs devaient donc tous être examinés ensemble. Je me suis engagé dans une enquête narrative qualitative visant à fournir des descriptions nuancées des expériences et des perceptions individuelles des participants et à éclairer des questions liées aux idéologies du pouvoir et de la langue. Les résultats de l’étude suggèrent que les enseignants de LO grecque assument la responsabilité d’aider leurs étudiants à conserver un lien avec la langue et la culture grecques, mais ne sont parfois pas équipés pour répondre à tous les besoins de leurs élèves. Les résultats suggèrent également que les idéologies linguistiques des enseignants de LO grecque jouent de rôle à la manière dont ils voient leurs élèves et les pratiques pédagogiques qu'ils utilisent. Les professeurs de LO grecque préfèrent les méthodes et stratégies d'enseignement conventionnelles, mais lorsqu'ils rencontrent le désengagement des étudiants, ils optent intuitivement pour des méthodes non conventionnelles et des stratégies de translanguaging, car elles sont plus efficaces pour convaincre leurs élèves. En effet, cette étude a montré qu’il y a du mérite à utiliser le translanguaging dans la classe de LO. La thèse se termine par une discussion sur les implications de l’étude, avec des recommandations pour l’amélioration de l’enseignement de la LO grecque au Canada, et avec des suggestions pour des recherches futures</description><description>While Canada is officially a multicultural country, and recognizes the cultural contributions of its various ethnic minorities, public funds are not allocated to minority languages, or heritage languages, in the same way that they are to Canada’s two official languages, English and French (Haque, 2012). Efforts to preserve heritage languages are thus mainly organized by the respective minority communities, which are particularly concerned about the potential of language shift and language loss, especially after the third generation. In the context of Greek Heritage Language Education in Canada, strengthening the learners’ connection to their heritage language is crucial, as there are now many third-and-fourth-generation Greek heritage language learners who have minimal knowledge of Greek, and whose only opportunity to learn and practice their heritage language is in the Greek schools (Aravossitas, 2016). It is therefore essential to find ways to enhance Greek heritage language education to ensure that the current and subsequent generations of Greeks in Canada can maintain a connection to their heritage language. It is undeniable that the most important stakeholders in the context of Greek heritage language education are the heritage language learners, as they represent the future of the Greek communities outside Greece. Nevertheless, this study focuses on Greek heritage language teachers instead, because their attitudes and practices largely shape the learners’ experiences in the Greek schools, and can either engage or alienate them. The aim of this study was to investigate how Greek heritage language teachers teaching in primary and secondary Greek programs in the greater Montreal and Toronto areas self-identify, and how their identification and ideologies affect their attitudes towards their students and their instructional practices. My understanding of languaging and identities is informed by critical poststructuralist sociolinguistics, according to which people’s language practices and identities are seen as interrelated, socially constructed, and constantly (re)negotiated in people’s interactions. A basic assumption when designing this study was that the teachers’ identification and ideologies largely shape their attitudes towards students and ultimately their instructional practices, and thus these factors must all be examined together. I engaged in a qualitative narrative inquiry, aiming to provide nuanced descriptions of the participants’ individual experiences and perceptions, and to shed light on issues related to power and language ideologies. The study’s findings suggest that Greek heritage language teachers assume the responsibility to help their students maintain a connection to the Greek language and culture, but sometimes are unequipped to accommodate all their students’ needs. The findings also suggest that Greek heritage language teachers’ language ideologies do play a role in how they view their students and what instructional practices they use. The Greek heritage language teachers prefer conventional teaching methods and strategies, but when met with student disengagement, they intuitively opt for unconventional methods and translanguaging strategies, as these are more effective in winning over their students. Indeed, this study showed that there is merit in using translanguaging in the heritage language classroom. The thesis closes with a discussion of the study’s implications, with recommendations for the enhancement of Greek heritage language education in Canada, and with suggestions for future research</description><creator>Tisizi, Emmanouela</creator><contributor>Caroline Joan Riches (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Mekhala Sarkar (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Education</subject><title>Exploring Heritage Language (HL) teachers’ identities and their perceptions about HL pedagogy: a narrative study of Greek HL teachers in Montreal and Toronto</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jg864.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sj28g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m3897</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:36:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we explore the use of Inverse Reinforcement Learning (IRL) in image-based dialogue systems. Visually-grounded dialogue systems are still in their infancy. Their success hinges on an efficient feature extraction method and the training mechanism used for learning the language model. At present, dialogue systems trained using maximum likelihood estimation tend to produce deflective or uninformative responses. We propose to tackle this issue by formulating the dialogue generation problem in the IRL setup. To that end, we adapt the IRL framework for processing complex high- dimensional inputs by leveraging a connection between deep learning, min-max optimisation and energy-based models. We also propose a neural network architecture for generating state representation by combining signals from text and image modalities. Finally, we show that subject to the availability “enough” training data; our proposed method can mitigate the issue of bland or deflective responses</description><description>Dans cette thèse, nous explorons l’utilisation de l’apprentissage par reinforcement in- verse (IRL) dans les systèmes de dialogue basés sur les images. Les systèmes de dia- logue visuellement fondés n’en sont encore qu’à leurs débuts. Leur succès repose sur une méthode efficace d’extraction des caractéristiques et sur le mécanisme de formation utilisé pour apprendre le modèle linguistique. De plus, les systèmes de dialogue formés à l’aide de l’estimation du maximum de vraisemblance tendent à produire des réponses défléchies ou non informatives. Nous proposons d’aborder cette question en formulant le problème de la génération de dialogue dans la configuration IRL. Pour ce faire, nous adaptons le cadre IRL pour le traitement d’entrées complexes de grande dimension en tirant parti d’une connexion entre l’apprentissage approfondi, l’optimisation min-max et les modèles énergétiques. Nous proposons également une architecture de réseau neu- ronal pour générer une représentation d’état en combinant des signaux provenant de modalités texte et image. Enfin, nous montrons que, sous réserve de la disponibilité de données " suffisantes " sur la formation, la méthode que nous proposons peut atténuer le problème des réponses fades ou défectives</description><creator>Patil, Gandharv</creator><contributor>Doina Precup (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jeremy Cooperstock (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Min-max inverse reinforcement learning for learning bi-modal dialogue policies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jz839.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m3897</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t650m</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:36:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Natural language processing is a discipline rooted in both linguistics and computer science. It incorporates syntactic problems (grammatical category, word segmentation, name entity recognition, etc.), semantics (sentiments analysis, texts categorization, translation, questions answering, etc.), vocal signals generation from texts or texts generation from vocal signals, etc. In the last few years, some scientists and companies have been able to create algorithms capable of achieving very high levels of performance for some of these tasks such as translation or sentiment classification, in part, by using big data. The fact that some algorithms perform so well with such a large amount of data gives a significant business advantage to large companies with large databases over smaller businesses or start-ups. The purpose of this thesis is to find algorithms or methods that can be effective in solving some natural language processing problems on small databases. For our research, we built a content-based recommendation system. We tested similarity measures such as Latent Dirichlet Allocation, cosine similarity, long-short term memory neural network, and the RV coefficient. We also compared the efficiency of the term frequency-inverse document frequency versus the mutual information to give a weighting scheme for the cosine similarity. We also compared the effectiveness of mutual information versus using raw word count as thresholds to remove words from a dictionary for the other similarity measures. We also used external databases, one containing documents related to our problem and another having Wikipedia documents. We also used a pre-trained GLOVE word embedding vector for our neural networks and the RV coefficient. We concluded that the simplest algorithms generally work best when there is little data. We also proposed several possible solutions to improve the algorithms we tested</description><description>Le traitement du langage naturel est une discipline ayant racine autant dans la linguistique que dans les sciences informatiques. Elle incorpore un bon nombre de problèmes syntaxiques (catégorie grammaticale, segmentation de mots, détection de noms propres, etc), sémantiques (classification de sentiments, catégorisation de textes, traduction, répondre à des questions, etc), transformation de signaux vocaux en textes ou textes en signaux vocaux, etc. Dans les dernières années certains scientifiques et compagnies ont été capable de créer des algorithmes capable d'atteindre de très haut niveaux de performances pour certaines de ces tâches tel que la traduction ou la classification de sentiment, en partie, grâce aux mégadonnées. Le fait que certains algorithmes performent aussi bien avec une aussi grande quantité de données donne un avantage commercial significatif aux grandes compagnies ayant de grande base de données sur les plus petits commerçants ou les entreprises en démarrages. Le but de cette thèse est du trouvé des algorithmes ou méthodes qui peuvent être efficaces pour résoudre certains problèmes de traitement du langage naturel sur de petites base de données. Pour notre recherche, nous avons construit un système de recommandation à base de contenus. Nous avons testé des mesures de similarités tel que le Latent Dirichlet Allocation, la similarité du cosinus, un réseau de neurones profond long-short term memory, et le coefficient RV. Nous avons aussi comparé l'efficacité du term frequency-inverse document frequency versus l'information mutuelle pour donnée un poids aux mots pour la similarité du cosinus. Nous avons aussi comparé l'efficacité de l'information mutuelle versus utilisé le nombre de mots comme seuil d'épuration de dictionnaires dans l'application des autres mesures de similarités. Nous avons aussi utilisé des bases de données externes, une contenant des documents reliés à notre problème et une autre ayant des documents de wikipedia. Nous avons aussi utilisé un vecteur de prolongement de mot GLOVE pré entraîné pour notre réseaux de neurones et le coefficient RV. Nous avons conclu que les algorithmes les plus simple fonctionne généralement mieux lorsqu'il y a peu de données. Nous avons aussi proposé plusieurs piste de solution pour amélioré les algorithmes que nous avons testés</description><creator>Perreault-Jenkins, Matthew</creator><contributor>Ioannis Psaromiligkos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>A study of similarity measures for natural language processing as applied to candidate-project matching</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cn08k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t650m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qh69b</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:37:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many studies have shown that international students are likely to be affected by foreign language anxiety. In recent years, the number of Chinese international secondary school students in Montreal is increasing greatly, yet the literature on this group of students’ experiences related to foreign language anxiety is limited. This thesis aims to investigate whether Chinese international secondary school students in Montreal are impacted by foreign language anxiety, focusing on their reactions to it and the factors that increase or decrease foreign language anxiety in this group. This study gathered qualitative data from seven participants using semi-structured interviews. This study also reveals the challenges and coping strategies that are mentioned by the participants. Finally, some different features between the educational systems of Canada and China are presented and discussed. The findings of this research enrich the understanding of the influence of foreign language anxiety in Chinese international secondary school students in Montreal and provide some insights for the development of helpful measures which are beneficial for the students’ successful integration into their studies and daily life in Montreal.Keywords: foreign language anxiety, Chinese international secondary school students, qualitative study</description><description>De nombreuses études ont montré que les étudiants internationaux sont susceptibles de s’affecter par l'anxiété langagière. Au cours des dernières années, le nombre des étudiants chinois internationaux du secondaire à Montréal augmente considérablement, pourtant, la littérature sur ce groupe d’étudiants et leurs expériences liés à l'anxiété langagière est limité. Cette thèse vise à déterminer si les étudiants chinois internationaux du secondaire à Montréal sont affectés par l'anxiété langagière, se concentrant sur leurs réactions et les facteurs qui augmentent ou diminuent l'anxiété langagière chez eux. Cette étude rassemble des données qualitatives de sept participants à l'aide d'entrevues semi-structurées. Ce qui ressort également de cette étude, ce sont les défis et les stratégies d'adaptation mentionnés par les participants. Enfin, certaines caractéristiques différentes entre les systèmes éducatifs du Canada et de la Chine sont présentées et discutées. Les résultats de cette recherche enrichissent la compréhension de l'influence de l'anxiété langagière chez les étudiants chinois internationaux du secondaire à Montréal et fournissent des idées pour l'élaboration de mesures utiles pour l'intégration réussie des étudiants dans leurs études et leur vie quotidienne à Montréal.Mots-clés: l'anxiété langagière, étudiants chinois internationaux du secondaire, étude qualitative</description><creator>Xu, Shengwen</creator><contributor>Mekhala Sarkar (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Education</subject><title>How Chinese international secondary students in Montreal are affected by foreign language anxiety: A qualitative study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t92r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qh69b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289p51x</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:37:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This qualitative self-study explores three different educational change processes as experienced by a secondary school science teacher in an urban setting in the province of Quebec, Canada.  Through reflecting on the teacher’s own experiences in three different contexts of educational change, the teacher provides insight into how issues of agency, group size, collegial relationships, hierarchy and politics impacted the teacher’s decision-making and affective domain as a participant and their perceptions of self-efficacy.  High levels of agency, small group sizes, trusting pre-existing relationships, lack of hierarchy and low levels of political involvement in the change initiatives all increased the teacher’s engagement and self-efficacy in the reforms. Suggestions are provided for participants and change leaders in designing future change initiatives to increase participant engagement and achieve more successful outcomes in educational reform</description><description>Cette auto-étude qualitative explore trois différents processus de changement pédagogique tel qu’expérimenté par un enseignant de science au niveau secondaire dans un milieu urbain au Québec au Canada. En se penchant sur les propres expériences de l’enseignant dans trois différents contextes de changement éducatif, l’enseignant nous éclaire comment les questions dans la façon d’agir, de la grosseur du groupe, de relations collégiales, de hiérarchie et de politique ont influencés la prise de décision et le domaine affectif de l’enseignant en tant que participant et leurs perceptions d’auto-efficacité. La facilité d’adaptation, de petits groupes, faire confiance aux relations préexistantes, le manque de hiérarchie et un bas niveau d’implication politique dans les initiatives de changement ont tous augmentés l’engagement et l’auto-efficacité de l’enseignant dans les réformes. Des suggestions sont proposées aux participants et aux responsables du changement pédagogique dans la création d’initiatives de changements futures afin d’accroître l’engagement des participants et d’atteindre de meilleurs résultats dans la réforme de l’éducation</description><creator>Clark, Melanie</creator><contributor>Lisa Starr (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Caroline Joan Riches (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Education</subject><title>A teacher's perspective on experiences of educational change: A qualitative self-study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sg17v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289p51x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920g212c</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:38:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Apart from providing basic nutrients, foods also impact additional health benefits such as antioxidative, anti-cancer and antidiabetic effects due to the presence of functional molecules such as phenolic compounds. Over the years, manipulation of phenolic biosynthesis has been achieved with techniques such as plant tissue cultures and genetic engineering. However, these techniques have limitations such as low consumer acceptance, low yield, and genetic instability. Thus, there is need for appropriate and consumer acceptable techniques to enhance the yield of phenolic compounds in foods. For the first time, this study investigated the influence of chemical, ultrasonication and thermal elicitations of the phenylpropanoid pathway at different sprouting stages of common bean (Phaseolus vulgaris). With each elicitation, accumulation of stress markers, phenylpropanoid triggering enzymes, phenolic compounds, antioxidant capacities and sprout morphological characteristics were monitored at different sprouting stages. Among chemical elicitors, 7 mM glutamic acid elicited the highest levels of H2O2 (0.12 mol/g) at 96 h of sprouting time, whereas the maximum activities of catalase (23.2 U/mg protein) and peroxidase (3.48 U/mg protein) were elicited with 5 mM glutamic acid compared to control. The 5 mM glutamic acid most significantly enhanced the activities of phenylalanine ammonia-lyase and tyrosine ammonia-lyase leading to 65% enhancements of total phenolic acids and 2.97 fold total flavonoids, and significantly enhanced antioxidant capacities. The chemical elicitors did not inhibit sprout’s morphological characteristics.   Ultrasonication studies indicated the highest levels of H2O2 (0.35 mol/g), catalase (26.04 U/mg protein) and guaiacol peroxidase (8.80 U/mg protein) with 360 W (60 min) at 96 h of sprouting. Elevated stress markers observed with ultrasonic treatments enhanced activities of phenylalanine ammonia-lyase and tyrosine ammonia-lyase, resulting in enhanced total contents of phenolic acids, flavonoids and anthocyanins by 11.7, 6.6 and 11.5 folds, respectively, compared to the control. Additionally, phenolic compounds elicited with ultrasonic treatments significantly improved all tested antioxidant capacities. Furthermore, elevated stress markers stimulated with 360 W (60 min) ultrasonic treatment reduced sprouting time by 60 h, compared to control treatments. Also, thermal treatments significantly enhanced biosynthesis of phenolic compounds. The highest accumulations of H2O2 and malondialdehyde were elicited with 40°C, whereas activities of catalase and guaiacol peroxidase were maximally elicited with 30°C at 96 h. Phenylalanine ammonia-lyase was optimally elicited with 30°C (11 folds higher than control), whereas tyrosine ammonia-lyase showed a 97.4 % increase. Total phenolic acids were enhanced by 7.75 times, total flavonoids by 69.3 % and total anthocyanins content by 2.29 folds, compared to control. In addition, elevated stress markers associated with 30°C treatments were non-lethal against morphological characteristics of sprouts. For kinetic studies, accumulation rates, k (h^(-1)), estimated for H2O2 and malondialdehyde showed an increasing trend with temperature rise. However, activation rates observed for catalase, guaiacol peroxidase and phenylpropanoid triggering enzymes were highest at 30°C. Furthermore, activation energy (Ea-kJ/mol) values estimated for total phenolic acids, flavonoids and anthocyanins were 30.40, 63.98 and 208.63 kJ/mol, respectively, with this result synchronizing with the high accumulation rates, k (h^(-1)), estimated for phenolic acids and flavonoids, compared to anthocyanins. In conclusion, ultrasonic treatment of 360 W (60 min) at 96 h of sprouting elicited phenolic compounds with maximum antioxidant capacities, when compared with other investigated treatments. Thus, controlled elicitation can serve as alternative techniques for production of natural functional foods</description><description>En plus de fournir des nutriments de base, les aliments ont également un impact sur d’autres avantages pour la santé tels que les effets antioxydants, anticancéreux et antidiabétiques dus à la présence de molécules fonctionnelles comme les composés phénoliques. Au fil des ans, la manipulation de la biosynthèse phénolique a été réalisée à l’aide de techniques telles que les cultures de tissus végétaux et le génie génétique. Cependant, ces techniques ont des limites telles que la faible acceptation par le consommateur, le faible rendement, et l’instabilité génétique. Il faut donc des techniques appropriées et acceptables pour le consommateur afin d’améliorer le rendement des composés phénoliques dans les aliments.  Pour la première fois, cette étude a examiné l’influence de l’élicitation chimique, ultrasonique et thermique de la voie phénylpropanoïde à différents stades de germination du haricot commun (Phaseolus vulgaris). Avec chaque élicitation, accumulation de marqueurs de stress, phénylpropanoïde déclenchant des enzymes, les composés phénoliques, les capacités antioxydantes et les caractéristiques morphologiques du germe ont été surveillées à différents stades de germination.Parmi éliciteurs chimiques, l'acide glutamique 7 mM a provoqué les niveaux les plus élevés de H2O2 (0.12 mol/g) à 96 h de temps de germination, tandis que les activités maximales de catalase (23.2 U/mg de protéine) et de peroxydase (3.48 U/mg de protéine) ont été provoqués avec de l’acide glutamique 5 mM comparativement au témoin. L’acide glutamique de 5 mM a plus fortement amélioré les activités de la phénylalanine ammoniac-lyase et tyrosine ammoniac-lyase, ce qui a entraîné des améliorations de 65% des acides phénoliques totaux et de 2.97 fois les flavonoïdes totaux, et a considérablement amélioré les capacités de antioxydants. Les élicitateurs chimiques n’ont pas inhibé les caractéristiques morphologiques du germe. Les études par ultrasons ont indiqué les concentrations les plus élevées de H2O2 (0.35 mol/g), de catalase (26.04 U/mg de protéines) et de peroxydase de guaiacol (8.80 U/mg de protéines) avec 360 W (60 min) à 96 h de germination. Les marqueurs de stress élevés observés avec les traitements ultrasoniques ont amélioré les activités de phénylalanine ammoniac-lyase et tyrosine ammoniac-lyase, ce qui a entraîné une augmentation des teneurs totales en acides phénoliques, en flavonoïdes et en anthocyanes de 11.7, 6.6 et 11.5 plis, respectivement, par rapport au témoin. En outre, les composés phénoliques induits par les traitements ultrasonores ont considérablement amélioré toutes les capacités antioxydantes testées. De plus, les marqueurs de stress élevés stimulés par un traitement ultrasonique de 360 W (60 min) ont réduit le temps de germination de 60 h, par rapport aux traitements témoins. De plus, les traitements thermiques ont considérablement amélioré la biosynthèse des composés phénoliques. Les accumulations les plus élevées de H2O2 et de malondialdéhyde ont été obtenues avec 40 °C, tandis que les activités de catalase et de peroxydase de guaiacol ont été le plus souvent provoquées avec 30 °C à 96 h. La phénylalanine ammoniac-lyase a été extrapolée de façon optimale à 30 °C (11 plis de plus que le témoin), tandis que la tyrosine ammoniac-lyase a affiché une augmentation de 97.4%.  Les acides phénoliques totaux ont été multipliés par 7.75, les flavonoïdes totaux par 69.3% et la teneur totale en anthocyanes par 2.29 plis, comparativement aux témoins. De plus, les marqueurs de stress élevés associés aux traitements à 30 °C étaient non létaux par rapport aux caractéristiques morphologiques des germes. Pour les études cinétiques, k (h^(-1)) estimés pour le H2O2 et le malondialdéhyde, ont montré une tendance à la hausse avec l’augmentation de la température. Toutefois, les taux d’activation observés pour les enzymes déclenchant la catalase, la peroxydase de guaiacol et la phénylpropanoïde étaient les plus élevés à 30 °C</description><creator>Ampofo, Josephine</creator><contributor>Michael O Ngadi (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Hosahalli Ramaswamy (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</subject><title>Elicitation of phenolic biosynthesis and antioxidative capacities in common bean «(phaseolus vulgaris)» sprouts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h6152.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920g212c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cq190</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:38:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: The ability to detect objects of interest in the environment is essential to activities of daily living. Such an ability can be dramatically altered after a central nervous system lesion, especially after a right hemisphere stroke leading to post-stroke unilateral spatial neglect (USN). In this population, deficits in object detection are modulated as a function of object location and environment complexity, yet the mechanisms for such modulation remain unclear. As a first step, we examined in this study the healthy patterns of brain activation involved in a virtual reality-based object detection task performed in an ecological environment representing a grocery shopping scene. Objectives: to estimate the extent to which (1) scene complexity impacts on the amplitude and latency of event-related potential (ERP) components and; (2) the amplitude and latency of ERP components are modulated as a function of object location along the horizontal plane. Methods: Fifteen healthy adults (45-70 years) were assessed using an immersive virtual reality set-up as they detected a target object (shopping item) located at five possible locations (0°, ±20°, ±40°) in an uncluttered (UCE; item appearing in isolation) or a cluttered virtual environment (CE; item appearing amongst others). Response time was recorded and ERPs components P1, N1 and P3 were extracted from electroencephalography recordings over electrode sites corresponding to bilateral posterior parietal cortex (RPPC, LPPC) and extrastriate cortex (RESC, LESC). Results: Larger amplitude of P1 and N1 in PPC clusters as well as larger P3 amplitude in extrastriate cortex clusters were observed for CE vs UCE.  Object location has significant effects on amplitude of N1 and P3 only: N1 amplitude (in absolute value) peaked at center and decreased with target eccentricity whereas P3 amplitude is enhanced in the contralateral to hemisphere. Latency of P1, N1, and P3 was longer for UCE vs CE, due to longer latencies in the peripheral (left or right) vs. centered target location in UCE but not in the CE. Conclusions: Present findings indicate that brain activation in the PPC and/or extrastriate cortex during an object detection task performed in an ecological virtual environment vary according to scene complexity and target location. The increase in amplitude for P1 and P3 with the more complex (cluttered) environment may reflect top-down influences on early sensory information processing, whereas the enhancement of N1 for the same condition may reflect the role of this area in the discrimination process itself, which was needed for the complex but not the simple scene. In the simple scene, the bilateral effects of target location of N1 observed in the right hemisphere is in line with presumed involvement of N1 in the orientation of attention to the relevant location, while the enhancement of P3 in response to contralateral target appearances may result from a compound of premotor cortex activation. Significance: The results obtained provide fundamental knowledge on brain activation patterns involved in object detection in an ecological environment, as required in activities of daily living. While serving as a basis for comparison to determine defective patterns of brain activation in populations such as individuals with post-stroke USN, the present findings constitute a first step towards the development of optimal brain stimulation paradigms to promote USN recovery</description><description>Contexte: La capacité à détecter des objets d'intérêt dans l'environnement est essentielle aux activités de la vie quotidienne. Une telle capacité peut être considérablement altérée après une lésion du système nerveux central, en particulier après un accident vasculaire cérébral de l'hémisphère droit conduisant à une négligence spatiale unilatérale. Dans cette population, les déficits de détection des objets sont modulés en fonction de la localisation de l'objet et de la complexité de l'environnement, mais les mécanismes de cette modulation restent méconnus. Dans cette étude, nous avons dans un premier temps examiné les patrons d'activation cérébrale impliqués dans une tâche de détection d'objets effectuée dans un environnement virtuel écologique représentant une scène d'épicerie chez des individus sains. Les objectifs étaient d’estimer dans quelle mesure: (1) la complexité de la scène influe sur l'amplitude et la latence des composantes du potentiel évoqué et (2) l'amplitude et la latence des composantes du potentiel évoqué sont modulées en fonction de la position de l'objet dans le plan horizontal. Méthodes: Quinze adultes en bonne santé (45 à 70 ans) ont été évalués à l'aide d'un casque immersif de réalité virtuelle alors qu’ils détectaient un objet cible (item) situé à cinq endroits possibles (0°, ±20°, ±40°) dans un environnement simple (objet apparaissant isolément) ou dans un environnement virtuel complexe (objet apparaissant parmi d’autres). Le temps de réponse a été enregistré et les composantes P1, N1 et P3 du potentiel évoqué ont été extraites des enregistrements d’électroencéphalographie aux sites d'électrodes correspondant au cortex pariétal postérieur bilatéralement (RPPC, LPPC) et au cortex extrastrié (RESC, LESC). Résultats : Une plus grande amplitude de P1 et N1 dans l’aire du PPC ainsi qu'une plus grande amplitude de P3 dans le cortex extrastrié ont été observées pour l'environnement complexe vs. plus simple.  La localisation de l'objet a des effets significatifs sur l'amplitude de N1 et P3 seulement : L'amplitude N1 (en valeur absolue) a culminé au centre et a diminué avec l'excentricité de la cible tandis que l'amplitude P3 est augmentée dans la partie controlatérale de l'hémisphère. La latence de P1, N1 et P3 était plus longue pour l'environnement simple que pour l'environnement complexe, en raison de latences plus longues lorsque la cible était décentrée (à gauche ou droite) vs. centrée dans l'environnement simple exclusivement. Conclusions: Les résultats de cette étude indiquent que l'activation cérébrale dans le PPC et/ou le cortex extrastrié au cours d'une tâche de détection d'objet effectuée dans un environnement virtuel écologique varie selon la complexité de la scène et la localisation de l’objet cible. L'augmentation de l'amplitude des composantes P1 et P3 enregistrées dans un environnement plus complexe (encombré) peut refléter des influences descendantes sur le traitement précoce de l'information sensorielle, tandis que l'augmentation de N1 enregistrées lors la même condition peut refléter le rôle de N1 dans le processus de discrimination lui-même, nécessaire dans le contexte d’une scène complexe mais non pas d’une scène plus simple. Dans le cas d’une scène simple, les effets bilatéraux de l'emplacement de la cible sur l’amplitude de N1 dans l'hémisphère droit correspondent à l'implication présumée de cette aire dans l'orientation de l'attention vers l'emplacement pertinent, tandis que l'augmentation de P3 en réponse aux cibles décentrées du côté controlatéral peut résulter de l’'activation du cortex pré-moteur. Implication : Les résultats de cette étude contribuent à l’amélioration des connaissances fondamentales sur les patrons d'activation cérébrale impliqués dans la détection d'objets dans un environnement écologique, tel que requis dans les activités de la vie quotidienne</description><creator>Li, Youlin</creator><contributor>Anouk Lamontagne (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Marie-Helene Boudrias (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Physical and Occupational Therapy</subject><title>Neural correlates of object detection in in a simple and complex ecological virtual reality environment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731846j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cq190</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644x136</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:38:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les évaluations génétiques pour le mois d’avril 2018, calculées par le Réseau laitier canadien, et l’information sur les troupeaux laitiers et les relevés de lactation des vaches Holstein provenant de Lactanet, ont été utilisés pour (i) calculer les écarts de sélection génétique (ÉSG) réalisés pour les traits économiquement importants pour les troupeaux Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey et Suisse Brune au Canada, (ii) étudier les intervalles de générations dans quatre populations de vaches laitières, (iii) estimer les paramètres génétiques de la production laitière, du poids des vaches en lactation, de la cote de cellules somatiques (CCS) et des traits indicateurs de profit chez les vaches Holstein au Québec, et (iv) développer un prototype d’outil et un modèle de visualisation pour surveiller la sélection réalisée dans les troupeaux laitiers individuels. Une nouvelle approche qui serait plus pertinente pour les producteurs laitiers a été utilisée pour calculer les ÉSG des traits d’importance économique. D'importants ÉSG ont été obtenus pour la production, la durabilité, la santé, les traits de fertilité et l'indice de performance à vie (IPV). De plus grandes sélections ont été réalisées dans les méthodes de sélection femelle à mâle (DB) et mâle à mâle (SB) comparativement à d'autres méthodes; peu ou pas de sélection a été réalisée pour la production, la durabilité et les traits de santé dans la méthode femelle à femelle (DC) dans les quatre races de bovins laitiers. Mis à part l’année de conception (YOC), les autres facteurs non génétiques n'avaient majoritairement pas d'importance sur l’ÉSG réalisé pour les traits économiquement importants alors qu'il existait des variations significatives entre les troupeaux dans leur ÉSG réalisé. Les intervalles de génération (L) dans les quatre méthodes de sélection ont diminué de 1980 à 2016. Il y a eu des réductions de 55 %, 41 %, 46 % et 38 % du L total dans les populations de Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey et Suisse Brune entre 1980 et 2016, respectivement. Une proportion importante des réductions de L s'est produite au cours des huit dernières années (2009 à 2016). Le troupeau et l'interaction entre l’année de naissance et le troupeau expliquent une proportion significative des variations de L. Cette étude a démontré que les troupeaux qui utilisent de jeunes taureaux d’insémination artificielle pour la reproduction augmentent leur progrès génétique annuel à un rythme plus rapide.Les données de la première à la quatrième lactation des vaches Holstein au Québec ont été utilisées pour estimer les paramètres génétiques et phénotypiques de la production laitière, de la CCS, du poids des vaches en lactation (BWT), de la valeur cumulative du lait (MV), du coût cumulatif des aliments (FC) et de la marge sur le coût des aliments (MOFC). Les estimations de l'héritabilité pour les traits de production laitière, BWT, MV et MOFC étaient modérées tandis que l'héritabilité pour le CCS et FC était faible. On a tenté d'illustrer qu'il est possible de ralentir ou d'arrêter les tendances génétiques croissantes du poids des vaches en incorporant les traits de la production laitière en utilisant un indice de sélection simple.Finalement, un prototype d'outil et de modèle de visualisation ont été mis au point pour aider les producteurs laitiers et les conseillers à surveiller l’ÉSG dans leurs troupeaux et à comparer leur sélection à certains repères. Le concept de ce prototype d'outil est applicable à toutes les espèces animales pour lesquelles des évaluations génétiques sont régulièrement calculées et publiées. Nous nous attendons à ce que les producteurs utilisent cet outil logiciel pour surveiller la sélection qu'ils font dans leurs troupeaux et apporter des changements s'ils vont dans une direction non voulue</description><description>Genetic evaluations for April 2018, which were computed by Canadian Dairy Network, dairy herd information, and lactation records of Holstein cows from Lactanet, were used to (i) compute realized genetic selection differentials (GSD) for economically important traits in Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Brown Swiss herds in Canada, (ii) investigate generation intervals in four dairy cattle populations, (iii) estimate genetic parameters for milk production, lactation body weight, SCS, and profit indicator traits in Holstein cows in Québec, and (iv) develop a prototype tool and visualization model to monitor selection realized in individual dairy herds. A new approach that would be more relevant to dairy producers has been used to compute realized GSD of traits of economic importance in four dairy cattle breeds in Canada. Significant GSDs were being realized for production, durability, health, fertility traits, and lifetime performance index (LPI). Greater selections were realized in the dam-to-bull (DB) and sire-to-bull (SB) pathways of selection compared with selection realized in the sire-to-cow (SC) and dam-to-cow (DC) pathways; little to no selection was realized for production, durability, and health traits in the DC path in the four dairy cattle breeds. Apart from year of conception, other non-genetic factors were mostly unimportant on the realized GSD for economically important traits while significant variations existed among herds in their realized GSD.Generation intervals (L) in all four paths of selection have been decreasing from 1980 to 2016. There have been 55%, 41%, 46%, and 38% reductions in total L in the Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Brown Swiss populations between 1980 and 2016, respectively. A significant proportion of the reductions in L occurred in the last 8 years (2009 to 2016). Herd and herd*year of birth explained significant proportion of the variations in L. This study has demonstrated that herds that used younger Artificial Insemination bulls for breeding increased their annual genetic progress at a faster rate.First to fourth lactation records of Holstein cows in Québec were used to estimate genetic and phenotypic parameters of milk production, somatic cell score (SCS), lactation body weight (BWT), cumulative milk value (MV), cumulative feed cost (FC), and margin over feed cost (MOFC). Heritability estimates for milk production traits, BWT, MV, and MOFC were moderate whereas heritability estimates for SCS and FC were low. Genetic correlations among the traits studied ranged from low to high. Strong genetic correlations existed between the same traits in different lactations with the greatest correlations found between adjacent lactations. An attempt has been made to illustrate that it is possible to slow or halt the positive genetic trends in cow body weight by incorporating BWT and milk production traits into a simple selection index.Finally, a prototype software tool and visualization model were developed to help dairy producers and advisors monitor GSD in their herds, and compare the selection they are making with a number of benchmarks. The concept of this prototype software tool is applicable to all livestock species for which genetic evaluations are routinely computed and published. It is expected that producers would use this software tool to monitor what selection they are making in their herds and make changes if they are moving in an unintended direction</description><creator>Hagan, Bernard</creator><contributor>Roger I Cue (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Animal Science</subject><title>Genetic selection in Canadian dairy cattle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k685w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644x136</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mv39v</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:38:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bien que la résection totale d’une tumeur soit fortement corrélée à la survie, une mauvaise détection des limites tumorales signifie que jusqu’à 82% des cas de glioblastome réséqués entraînent une résection incomplète. La segmentation et l’étiquetage précis des tissus pathologiques sont essentiels pour la réussite chirurgicale et peuvent aider à préserver la les tissues sains. En plus de la planification chirurgicale, un étiquetage précis des tissus en navigation neuronale est important pour les techniques d’enregistrement et de visualisation d’images. Alors que les techniques de segmentation automatique et semi-automatique ont été explorées dans des contextes de recherche, la pratique standard actuelle en neurochirurgie consiste à segmenter à la main le tissu pathologique dans des images IRM préopératoires. Même lorsqu’elle est effectuée par un expert, la segmentation manuelle est un processus difficile, qui entraîne toujours des limites de segmentation sujettes aux erreurs. Autrement, la vision par ordinateur et les stratégies d’apprentissage automatique offrent la possibilité d’étudier des méthodes de segmentation multimodale entièrement automatisées qui peuvent segmenter et annoter efficacement les grands volumes d’images IRM préopératoires utilisées dans les applications cliniques. Le but de cette recherche est de valider des techniques d’apprentissage profond à des fins de segmentation des tumeurs cérébrales. La validation est effectuée sur un réseau convolutionnel codeur-décodeur généralisé (UNet) et comparée à deux réseaux de segmentation de tumeurs cérébrales optimisés et les plus performants : un modèle de codeur-décodeur nnUNet amélioré et un réseau entièrement convolutionnel à double voie DeepMedic. La segmentation doit être robuste, précise et efficace sur le plan informatique pour l’IRM multicontraste et doit fournir des étiquettes pour l’œdème, la tumeur centrale et la tumeur active. La formation et la validation sont effectuées sur l’ensemble de données BRATS 2018 existant avec des étiquettes manuelles d’experts, et les prédictions sont évaluées à l’aide de Dice Coefficient et distance Hausdorff pour chaque étiquette. nnUNet a obtenu les meilleurs résultats globaux et a pu atteindre un score moyen de DICE de tumeurs entières de 94,9 %---une amélioration statistiquement significative (p &lt; 0,001) par rapport aux autres modèles</description><description>Although gross total resection of a tumour is highly correlated to survival, poor tumour boundary detection means that as many as 82% of easily resected glioblastoma cases result in an incomplete resection. Accurate segmentation and labelling of pathological and healthy tissues are key for successful tumour resection and may additionally give surgeons perspective on critical cortex regions to preserve. In addition to surgical planning, accurate tissue labelling in neuronavigation is important for image registration and visualization techniques. While automatic and semi-automatic segmentation techniques have been explored in research contexts, the present standard practice in neurosurgery is to segment pathological tissue in preoperative MR images by hand. Even when performed by an expert, manual segmentation is a difficult and time-consuming process, which still results in error-prone segmentation boundaries. Alternatively, computer vision and machine learning strategies provide the opportunity to investigate fully automated, multimodal segmentation methods that can efficiently segment and annotate the large volumes of preoperative MR images used in clinical applications. The purpose of this investigation is to validate state-of-the-art deep learning techniques applied to multicontrast-MRI brain tumour segmentation. Validation is performed on a generalized encoder-decoder convolutional network (UNet) and compared to two optimized and top-performing brain tumour segmentation networks: an improved encoder-decoder model nnUNet, and a dual-pathway fully-convolutional network DeepMedic. Segmentation should be robust, accurate, and computationally efficient for multicontrast-MRI and should provide labels for edema, core tumour, and active tumour. Training and validation are performed on the existing BRATS 2018 dataset with expert manual labels, and predictions are assessed using Dice Coefficient and Hausdorff Distance metrics across each label. nnUNet performed the best overall, and achieved a mean whole tumour Dice score of 94.9%---a statistically significant improvement (p&lt;0.001) over the other models</description><creator>Hebel, Jai</creator><contributor>Louis Collins (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Bioengineering and Biomedical Engineering</subject><title>Current state-of-the-art for glioblastoma segmentation using deep convolutional networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jd26j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mv39v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Bioengineering and Biomedical Engineering Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827h364</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:39:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: Up to 80% of patients with primary tumors of the breast, prostate or lung will develop spine metastases. Spine metastases cause pain, functional deficit and severely diminished health related quality of life through fracture, vertebral instability and spinal cord and nerve-root compression. This is associated with high socioeconomic and healthcare costs. With advancements in medical, radiation and surgical oncology, these patients are living longer thereby increasing the disease burden. Surgical bone resection of metastatic tumors leads to large bone defects that cannot self-repair, and treatment with antiresorptive bisphosphonates such as Zoledronate, is being explored for tissue repair. However, bone loss, instability and poor repair following tumor resection remains an unmet clinical need in this population. This leads to the possibility of exploring nanotechnology to delivery drugs locally and at therapeutic to help with the management of spine tumor patients.Methods: We first investigated the proliferation of various prostate cancer cell lines; LAPC4, 22RV1 and PC3 with different doses of Zoledronate using Alamarblue® kit and MTT assays. Following this we performed migration assays on similar cell lines using Boyden chambers and scratch assays. Once the action of various Zoledronate doses were established we worked to coat silica nanobeads with this drug and assess its release. The silica nanobeads were first prepared and tested using fluorescently labelled Zoledronate. Once a reproducible protocol was established, we tested the release of nanobeads coated in Zoledronate in a 3D bioprinted in-vitro model using a prostate cancer cell line (C42B). The coated nanobeads were placed in the middle of the 3D construct surrounded by the prostate cancer cell. The proliferation of these cells was then assessed to determine the local release and activity of Zoledronate coated nanobeads.Results: The highest dose of Zoledronate (100 μM) was found to reduce the proliferation of the prostate cancer cell lines LAPC4 and PC3 over 48 hours (0.711 ± 0.180 p value = 0.0497 and 0.575 ± 0.212, p=0.02571 respectively). No significant effect was found on the 22RV1 cell line over 48 hours with all Zoledronate concentrations tested. Proliferation of osteoblast cells were also reduced at Zoledronate 100 μM concentration (0.698 ± 0.0.52, p value = 0.0145). Cell migration was reduced with 10 μM for LAPC4 cells using the Boyden chamber (22.8% ± 8.1, p value = 0.04) and with 100 μM for PC3 cells performed using scratch assay over 24 and 48 hours (ratio 0.443 ± 0.024, p value = 0.047 and 0.375 ± 0.003, p value = 0.002 respectively).The nanobeads were tested firstly using fluorescently labelled Zoledronate and it was found that chitosan coated nanobeads retain and deliver more of the drug per day for a total of 8 days (302.1 μM cumulatively). Following this, we found that Zoledronate coated nanobeads placed in a 3D bioprinted construct with C42B prostate cancer cell lines shows a reducing trend in the proliferation of that cell line over 7 days.Conclusion: Our experiments showed extremely promising results in using nanobeads as an inexpensive drug delivery system, both locally and at therapeutic levels. We elaborated on the action of Zoledronate on the activity of various prostate cancer cell lines. In addition to this, we devised a successful protocol enabling us to coat silica nanobeads with Zoledronate and show its local delivery and therapeutic action in a 3D bioprinted construct with a prostate cancer cell line. We feel this will be the steppingstone for our future vision in relation to the local delivery of bisphosphonates to tumor cells.  We foresee the future to involve spinal metastasis mice models and the integration of these coated nanobeads in a structurally stable construct such as bone cement to fill the void following spine tumor resection</description><description>Contexte: Jusqu'à 80% des patients atteints de tumeurs primitives du sein, de la prostate ou du poumon développeront des métastases de la colonne vertébrale. Ceci est associé à des coûts socio-économiques et de santé élevés. Avec les progrès réalisés en oncologie médicale, radiologique et chirurgicale, ces patients vivent plus longtemps, augmentant ainsi le fardeau de la maladie. La résection osseuse chirurgicale des tumeurs métastatiques conduit à des défauts osseux importants qui ne peuvent pas s'auto-réparer, et un traitement par des bisphosphonates antirésorptifs, tels que le zolédronate, est actuellement à l'étude pour la réparation des tissus. Cependant, la perte osseuse, l'instabilité et la mauvaise réparation après la résection de la tumeur restent un besoin clinique non satisfait dans cette population. Cela conduit à la possibilité d'utiliser des nanotechnologies pour administrer des médicaments localement et de manière thérapeutique afin de faciliter la gestion des patients atteints de tumeur à la colonne vertébrale.Méthodes: Nous avons initialement effectué des expériences montrant la prolifération de différentes lignées cellulaires du cancer de la prostate; LAPC4, 22RV1 et PC3 avec différentes doses de zolédronate en utilisant le kit Alamarblue® et les tests MTT. Après cela, nous avons effectué des tests de migration sur des lignées cellulaires similaires en utilisant des chambres de Boyden et des tests de grattage.Une fois que l’action de diverses doses de zolédronate a été établie, nous avons travaillé pour recouvrir ce médicament de nanobilles de silice et évaluer sa libération. Les nanobilles de silice ont d'abord été préparées et testées à l'aide de zolédronate marqué par une fluorescence. Une fois que le protocole établi a été mis au point, nous avons commencé à tester la libération de nanobilles enrobées de zolédronate dans un modèle in vitro bioimprimé en 3D fabriqué à partir d’une lignée cellulaire du cancer de la prostate.Résultats: La dose la plus élevée de zolédronate (100 μM) s'est avérée réduire la prolifération des cellules cancéreuses de la prostate LAPC4 et PC3 en 48 heures (0,711 ± 0,180 valeur p = 0,0497 et 0,575 ± 0,212, p = 0,02571 respectivement). Aucun effet significatif n'a été observé sur la lignée cellulaire 22RV1 sur une période de 48 heures avec toutes les concentrations de zolédronate testées. La prolifération des cellules d'ostéoblastes a également été réduite à une concentration de Zolédronate de 100 µM (0,698 ± 0,0,52, valeur p = 0,0145). La migration cellulaire a été réduite avec 10 µM pour les cellules LAPC4 à l’aide de la chambre de Boyden (22,8% ± 8,1, valeur p = 0,04) et avec 100 µM pour les cellules PC3 réalisées par test de scratch sur 24 et 48 heures (rapport 0,443 ± 0,024, valeur p 0,047 et 0,375 ± 0,003, p = 0,002 respectivement).Les nanobilles ont tout d'abord été testées avec du zolédronate marqué par une fluorescence et il a été constaté que les nanobilles enrobées de chitosane retiennent et délivrent un total de 8 jours (302,1 µM de façon cumulée). Suite à cela, nous avons constaté que les nanobilles enrobées de zolédronate placées dans une construction 3D imprimée avec une lignée cellulaire de cancer de la prostate C42B réduisaient la prolifération de cette lignée cellulaire en 7 jours.Conclusion: Nous avons détaillé l'activité du zolédronate sur l'activité de diverses lignées cellulaires du cancer de la prostate. En outre, nous avons mis au point un protocole efficace nous permettant de revêtir Zoledroante de nanophares de silice et d’en montrer la distribution locale dans une construction bioprintée 3D avec une lignée de cellules cancéreuses de la prostate. Nous prévoyons que l'avenir impliquera des modèles de souris atteintes de métastases vertébrales et l'intégration de ces nanobilles enrobées dans une construction structurellement stable telle que le ciment osseux pour combler le vide après la résection tumorale de la colonne vertébrale</description><creator>Barimani, Bardia</creator><contributor>Lisbet Haglund (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Michael Weber (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Surgery</subject><title>The use of nanobead technology to deliver zoledronic acid to prostate cancer cell lines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913v27s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827h364</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547w92d</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:39:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Netrin-1 and the netrin receptor deleted in colorectal cancer (DCC) have been demonstrated to functionally contribute to multiple stages in oligodendrocyte development and maturation in the central nervous system. Both are required for appropriate oligodendrocyte precursor cell (OPC) migration, as well as oligodendrocyte process extension, branching, and membrane elaboration. Another netrin receptor, UNC5B, is also highly expressed by OPCs and oligodendrocytes, but in contrast to netrin-1 and DCC, its functional contribution to oligodendrocyte maturation and myelination has not been studied. We have recently determined that UNC5B is enriched at the paranodal junctions that terminate the compact myelin internode. UNC5B null mice are embryonic lethal at ~E14. Thus, in order to study the contribution of UNC5B to myelination, we developed conditional knock-out (cKO) mice that selectively delete UNC5B from the oligodendrocyte lineage. Olig2 cre – UNC5Bflox/flox mice exhibit disruption of paranodal organization and an age dependent disruption of axonal subdomains. In this thesis, we further investigated the impact of UNC5B deletion on the length of myelin internodes, reporting shorter internodes in 9-month old UNC5B cKO mice compared to their wild type littermates. These findings reveal that UNC5B expression by mature myelinating oligodendrocytes is required to maintain and organize paranodal junctions. However, little is known regarding the proteins that interact with UNC5B and the signaling pathways associated with this protein. We therefore conducted a screen for UNC5B candidate interacting proteins that may function downstream of UNC5B using the biotin identification (BioID) proximity labeling assay. Our findings suggest previously unknown interaction of UNC5B with proteins associated with the cytoskeleton and with key regulators of cell polarity and vesicle trafficking</description><description>La protéine nétrine-1 et son récepteur DCC (deleted in colorectal cancer) contribuent de façon fonctionnelle au développement et à la maturation des oligodendrocytes dans le system nerveux central. Ces deux protéines sont nécessaires à la migration des précurseurs oligodendrocytaires (OPCs), ainsi qu’à l’extension de la membrane et des ramifications des oligodendrocytes lors de la myelinisation. Un autre récepteur à la nétrine, UNC5B, est également exprimé par les OPCs et les oligodendrocytes. Cependant, sa contribution à la maturation des oligodendrocytes et à la myélinisation n’a jusqu’à présent, pas été étudiée. Nous avons récemment démontré un enrichissement de la protéine UNC5B au niveau des jonctions paranodales, qui constituent les extrémités des internoeuds de myéline compactée. La suppression totale de UNC5B provoque une léthalité embryonnaire au jour 14 (E14). Nous avons donc développé une lignée de souris où UNC5B est invalidé de façon conditionnelle dans les cellules de la lignée oligodendrocytaire afin d’étudier sa contribution à la myélinisation. Cette lignée de souris, Olig2 cre – UNC5Bflox/flox, présente une désorganisation progressive des paranoeuds, associée à une perturbation des sous-domaines axonaux à proximité des noeuds de Ranvier. Dans ce mémoire, nous étudions également l’impact de la suppression de UNC5B sur la longueur des internoeuds, révélant des intenoeuds plus courts chez les souris UNC5B cKO âgées de 9 mois que chez les souris contrôle. Ces résultats montrent que l’expression de UNC5B est nécéssaire à la préservation des jonctions paranodales. Cependant, peu d’information sont disponibles quant aux protéines interagissant avec UNC5B et aux voies de signalisation associées. Nous avons ainsi réalisé une expérience d’identification de protéine biotinylée (BioID) à proximité de UNC5B afin d’identifier des protéines candidates pouvant interagir avec UNC5B au sein des jonctions paranodales. Nos résultats suggèrent une interaction de UNC5B avec des protéines du cytosquelette, ainsi qu’avec des régulateurs clés de la polarisation cellulaire et du trafic de vésicule</description><creator>Clemot-DuPont, Samuel</creator><contributor>Timothy E Kennedy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Identifying novel UNC5B interacting partners to understand its function in CNS white matter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623h98t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547w92d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sm79t</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:40:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The internal relocation principle (IRP), also known as the internal relocation/protection/flight alternative, refers to the norm in international refugee and human rights law that permits the refusal of protection status (such as refugee status or subsidiary protection status) to the applicant who can find sufficient protection against the risks of harm by relocating to an alternative area in the country of origin. Invented by certain State parties to the 1951 Convention relating to the Status of Refugees (“1951 Convention”) and the 1967 Protocol relating to the Status of Refugees (“1967 Protocol”) in the late 1970s and the early 1980s, IRP has become well-accepted today as an applicable norm under the 1951 Convention and the 1967 Protocol. It has also been “transplanted” into international human rights law on some occasions to interpret certain human rights treaties.Despite the acceptance of IRP under the 1951 Convention and the 1967 Protocol, many controversies and ambiguities continue to revolve around IRP’s conceptualization, interpretation and application. State parties, UNHCR and academic commentators do not seem to agree upon IRP’s scope of applicability, formulation or legal standards under refugee and human rights treaties. This thesis aims to address these ambiguities and controversies around IRP’s puzzled existence in international law.This thesis contends that the failure to find a plausible legal basis for IRP in international law is the underlying cause leading to most controversies and ambiguities about IRP’s conceptualization, interpretation and application. Although most theorists presume IRP’s existence as the result of treaty interpretation of Article 1(A)(2) of the 1951 Convention, a critical analysis about IRP and the rules of treaty interpretation reveals that treaty interpretation cannot plausibly provide a legal basis for IRP in international law. Therefore, an alternative theory is needed to account for IRP’s legal basis.Based on Louis Henkin’s theory of constitutional international law, this thesis proposes an alternative approach to legitimizing IRP’s applicability under refugee and human rights treaties. Based on the inter-State structure – which is a structural necessity of the international legal system – constitutional international law on territorial allocation, by allocating the primary responsibility of protecting individuals to the country of origin, provides the legal basis for IRP’s application as a default limitation to the receiving State’s obligations under international refugee and human rights law. In this way, constitutional international law legitimizes IRP as a common (as opposed to treaty-specific) and permissive (as opposed to mandatory) norm under refugee and human rights treaties.Based on constitutional international law as IRP’s legal basis, this thesis constructs a new normative framework for IRP that not only clarifies IRP’s applicability but also emphasizes the harmonized requirements for IRP’s interpretation and application across different treaty regimes. Unless a specific treaty text or the collective subsequent practice clearly indicates otherwise, IRP has default applicability under refugee and human rights treaties regarding both the inclusion and cessation of protection status. In addition, IRP is applicable only when truly sufficient protection is indeed available within the country of origin, which requires not only the elimination of real risks of harm but also additional protection to ensure a relatively normal life for the applicant upon internal relocation</description><description>Le principe d’alternative de protection interne (API) renvoie à la norme en droit international des réfugiés et en droit international des droits de l’homme, qui permet de refuser d’accorder un statut de protection (comme le statut de réfugié ou le statut de protection subsidiaire) à un étranger qui pourrait trouver une protection suffisante contre tout danger en se déplaçant dans une autre région de son propre pays.Inventé par certains États parties à la Convention de 1951 relative au statut des réfugiés (« Convention de 1951 ») et au Protocole de 1967 relatif au statut des réfugiés (« Protocole de 1967 ») vers la fin des années ’70, l’API est devenue une norme reconnue dans la mise en œuvre de ces textes. Il a aussi été « transplanté » dans l’interprétation de certains traités de droit international des droits de l’homme.Malgré la reconnaissance du principe, de nombreuses controverses et ambiguïtés traversent encore la conceptualisation, l’interprétation et la mise en œuvre de l’API. Les États, le HCR et les universitaires sont en désaccord sur l’aire d’application du principe, sur sa formulation et sur son interaction avec d’autres règles conventionnelles du droit international des réfugiés et du droit international des droits de l’homme. La présente thèse vise à clarifier ces ambiguïtés et répondre à ces controverses.L’incapacité de déterminer un fondement juridique plausible pour l’API en droit international est la cause de la plupart des controverses et ambiguïtés dans la conceptualisation, l’interprétation et la mise en œuvre de l’API. La plupart des auteurs présument que l’existence de l’API résulte d’une interprétation de l’article 1(A)(2) de la Convention de 1951. Une analyse critique des règles de l’interprétation conventionnelle révèle que celles-ci ne peuvent servir de fondement plausible à l’API en droit international. Une théorie alternative est nécessaire.La théorie du Pr Louis Henkin sur le droit international constitutionnel permet de légitimer l’applicabilité de l’API en droit international des réfugiés comme en droit international des droits de l’homme. Fondé sur la structure interétatique – comme nécessité structurelle du système juridique international –, le droit international constitutionnel justifie l’allocation de territoires aux États et leur impose la responsabilité primaire de protéger les individus sur leur territoire. Cela fournit le fondement juridique de l’API comme limitation par défaut des obligations de l’État d’accueil en droit international des réfugiés et en droit international des droits de l’homme. Ainsi, le droit international constitutionnel légitime l’API comme une norme commune (non spécifique à un traité particulier) et permissive (non obligatoire), applicable aux dispositions conventionnelles tant du droit international des réfugiés que du droit international des droits de l’homme.La présente thèse propose donc de placer l’API dans un nouveau cadre normatif, qui non seulement clarifie ses conditions de mise en œuvre, mais encore offre des conditions harmonisées d’interprétation, quel que soit le régime conventionnel en cause. À moins qu’un texte conventionnel ou une pratique collective subséquente ne suggère autrement, l’API est applicable par défaut aux clauses de protection et de cessation des traités du droit international des réfugiés et du droit international des droits de l’homme. De plus, l’API n’est applicable que dans les cas où une protection véritablement suffisante est possible sur le territoire du pays d’origine : cela requiert non seulement l’élimination des risques de préjudice, mais aussi une protection additionnelle nécessaire à assurer à l’individu une vie relativement normale au lieu de sa nouvelle résidence</description><creator>Chao, Yi</creator><contributor>François Crépeau (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Law</subject><title>A legitimate norm gets misunderstood: Finding a plausible place for the internal relocation principle in international refugee and human rights law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mk73k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sm79t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78th59v</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:40:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L’indice aurifère et cuprifère Black Dog est situé sur une zone d’altération à tourmaline longuede deux kilomètres dans une séquence volcanique de la ceinture de roches vertes d’Urban-Barry,Abitibi, Québec. Cette zone mesure de deux à trois mètres d’épaisseur sur la majorité de salongueur mais atteint plus de 30 mètres d’épaisseur à Black Dog où la tourmaline est présente àla fois en tant que minéral d’altération et ciment d’une brèche à tourmaline magmatiquehydrothermal.Cette brèche à tourmaline comporte des proportions environ équivalentes dematrice de tourmaline et de clastes altérés à tourmaline et quartz. La minéralisation aurifère etcuprifère se présente dans une brèche à sulfures qui recoupe la brèche à tourmaline. En ordredécroissant d’abondance, les sulfures principaux sont la pyrite, la chalcopyrite, la sphalérite, lacobaltite, l’arsénopyrite et la pyrrhotite. L’or est présent principalement sous la forme d’électrumet est associé avec de la hessite, de la matildite, de l’argent natif et des des tellurures de bismuth.Cette minéralisation est généralement présente en intercroissance à l’intérieur des grains dechalcopyrite et aux contacts avec la pyrite ou d’arsénopyrite.La minéralisation aurifère est contenue dans des roches basaltiques faiblement foliées altéréesprincipalement à tourmaline, quartz et séricite. La tourmaline précoce (de Type A) estprincipalement dravitique alors que les épisodes subséquents (de Types B et C) appartiennent àla famille du schorl. La tourmaline tardive (de Type C) contient des proportions élevéesd’éléments reliés au minerai et incluent le cobalt, le zinc, le cuivre, l’argent et le bismuth. Uneanalyse en composante principale a démontré que la concentration de ces éléments sontfortement corrélés avec l’or.vPlusieurs caractéristiques de Black Dog sont inusuelles pour la ceinture de roches vertes del’Abitbi, où la vaste majorité des gisements appartiennent aux catégories de l’or orogénique etdes sulfures massifs volcanogènes. Contrairement à Black Dog, les gisements de type orogéniquesont caractérisés par une abondance limitée de sulfures, ne présentent pas de brècheshydrothermales et le minerai est habituellement relié à des veinules de quartz et carbonate et plusrarement de tourmaline.Les températures de dépositions estimées d’après la composition isotopique de la pyrite, lachalcopyrite et la sphalérite à Black Dog ont donné une fenêtre allant de 400 à 600 ºC (± ~50°C)et une moyenne de 496 ºC pour six paires d’échantillons (±26°). Ces températures de formationrelativement élevées et l’intervalle étroit des compositions isotopiques (δ34S de +1.7 à +3.6 ‰sur les sulfures, correspondant à +1.4 à +2.4‰ H2S) suggèrent que les fluides ayant mené à laminéralisation était majoritairement magmatiques. Les gisements orogéniques typiques sontgénéralement pauvres en cuivre et présente un plus large intervalle de compositions isotopiques,possiblement dû à de multiples sources de soufre. Ils présentent également des températures deformation plus basses.Les relations temporelles à Black Dog indiquent que l’altération à tourmaline et la minéralisationont été mises en place après le début de l’épisode de déformation principal. Les veines detourmaline qui recoupent la foliation, les clastes foliés dans la brèche et l’orientation subverticalede la cheminée de brèche qui recoupe également la foliation régionale sont des preuvestangibles d’une origine tardi-tectonique de la tourmaline.Il est suggéré que des fluides magmatiques émanant d’une intrusion calc-alcaline en profondeurfurent responsables pour l’altération et la minéralisation observée à Black Dog. Ce modèle devidéposition est analogue à ceux présentés pour les brèches à tourmaline aurifères et cuprifèresassociées aux porphyres de cuivre communs dans les roches phanérozoïques</description><description>The Black Dog Au-Cu prospect occurs in a two km-long tourmaline alteration zone in a maficvolcanic sequence of the Urban-Barry greenstone belt, Abitibi region, Québec. This zone is twoto three meters thick for most of its length but reaches over 30 meters in thickness at Black Dog,where tourmaline is present both as an alteration phase and as the cement of a magmatichydrothermalbreccia. The tourmaline breccia has roughly equivalent proportions of tourmalinematrix and quartz and tourmaline-altered clasts. The Au-Cu mineralization occurs in a sulfidebreccia that cuts the tourmaline breccia. In decreasing order of abundance, the main sulfideminerals are pyrite, chalcopyrite, sphalerite, cobaltite, arsenopyrite and pyrrhotite. Gold occursmainly as electrum and is associated with hessite, matildite, native silver and Bi-tellurideminerals. This mineralization is generally intergrown with chalcopyrite and occurs in contactwith pyrite and arsenopyrite grains in the sulfide veins.The gold mineralization is hosted by weakly foliated, basaltic rocks that have been alteredmainly to tourmaline, quartz and sericite. The early tourmaline (Type A tourmaline) isdominantly dravite, whereas in the subsequent stages (Types B and C), schorl is predominant.Late stage tourmaline (type C) has elevated concentrations of ore-related elements, including Co,Zn, Cu, Ag and Bi. Principal component analyses applied to bulk rock compositions demonstratethat concentrations of these metals correlate strongly with that of gold.Many features of the Black Dog prospect are unusual for the Abitibi greenstone belt, where thevast majority of the ore deposits belong to the orogenic gold and volcanogenic massive sulfideclasses. In contrast to Black Dog, the orogenic deposits are characterized by limited abundancesiiiof sulfide minerals, magmatic-hydrothermal breccias are absent, and the ores are usuallyassociated with quartz/carbonate (and more rarely tourmaline) veins.Temperatures estimated from sulfur isotope compositions of pyrite, chalcopyrite and sphaleriterange between 400 and 600°C (± ~50°C) and average 496°C for six sample pairs (±26°). Thisrelatively high temperature of formation and the narrow range of sulfur isotope compositions(δ34S from +1.7 to +3.6 ‰ on sulfide minerals, corresponding to +1.4 to +2.4‰ H2S) suggestthat the fluids, which produced the mineralization, were dominantly magmatic. Typical orogenicAu deposits generally are depleted in Cu and have a wider range of sulfur isotope values,possibly reflecting multiple sources of sulfur. They also display lower mineralizationtemperatures.The timing relationships indicate that tourmaline alteration and mineralization took place afterthe main deformation event had started. Tourmaline veins cutting foliation, foliated clasts in thebreccia, and the sub-vertical orientation of the breccia pipe, which also cuts the regionalfoliation, are strong evidence for the crystallization of tourmaline during the late stages ofregional deformation.It is proposed that magmatic fluids emanating from a calc-alkaline intrusion at depth wereresponsible for the alteration and mineralization observed at Black Dog. This depositional modelis analogous to that postulated for the Au-Cu-bearing tourmaline breccias associated withporphyry copper deposits in Phanerozoic rocks</description><creator>Drouin, Philippe</creator><contributor>Anthony E Williams-Jones (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Earth and Planetary Sciences</subject><title>The Black Dog Prospect, Québec, Canada: a Rare Example of Archean Tourmaline Breccia-Hosted Au-Cu Mineralization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pz04z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78th59v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pv84t</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:40:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Résumé:Contexte: Les individus co-infectés par le VIH et le VHC sont plus souvent dans une situation de vie précaire que la population générale. Ces facteurs peuvent mener ces idividus à être privés de soins. Cependant, la privation est difficile à mesurer. De telle mesures sont souvent basées sur des données agrégées qui ne saisissent pas l'hétérogénéité des individus. Nous avons développé un indice de privation au niveau individuel pour les personnes co-infectées par le VIH et le VHC qui englobe les facteurs sociaux, matériels et de style de vie.Méthodes: Nous avons estimé un indice de privation au niveau individuel avec les données de la cohorte canadienne de co-infection, une étude prospective de cohorte nationale. Nous avons utilisé plusieurs analyses de correspondance et analyses de données exploratoires pour sélectionner 9 variables dichotomiques lors de la visite de référence: revenu &gt; 1 500 $ / mois; éducation &gt; école secondaire; emploi; s'identifier comme gai ou bisexuel; Statut autochtone; utilisation de drogues injectables au cours des 6 derniers mois; n’avoir jamais fait usage de drogues injectables; incarcération antérieure et hospitalisation psychiatrique antérieure. Nous avons développé un model théorie de la réponse d'item à un élément avec: des paramètres de gravité (quelle est la probabilité qu'un élément ait été signalé), des paramètres discriminatoires (dans quelle mesure une variable distingue les niveaux d'index) et un paramètre individuel (l'indice). Nous avons considéré deux modèles: un simple sans variation provinciale et un modèle hiérarchique par province. Le critère d'information largement applicable (WAIC) a été utilisé pour comparer les modèles ajustés. Enfin, nous avons évalué l'association de l'indice avec la non-fréquentation à une deuxième visite à la clinique (comme mesure de désengagement) en utilisant la régression logistique.Résultats: Nous avons analysé 1547 cas complets de 1842 participants inscrits. 457 (30%) n'ont pas assisté à une deuxième visite. Le modèle hiérarchique s'est révélé le mieux adapté. Les valeurs de l'indice étaient réparties de façon similaire entre les provinces. Dans l'ensemble, les incarcérations, l’éducation et le chômage avaient les paramètres discriminatoires les plus élevés. Cependant, dans chaque province, différentes composantes de l'indice étaient associées à une privation reflétant l'épidémiologie locale. Par exemple, la Saskatchewan avait le paramètre de gravité le plus élevé pour le statut autochtone, tandis que le Québec était le plus faible. Une augmentation d'une unité de l'indice était associée à 17% de chances (intervalle crédible de 95%, 2% à 34%) de ne pas assister à une deuxième visite.Conclusion: Nous avons estimé un indice de privation au niveau individuel avec des poids de variables variant par province. L'indice était associé au désengagement des soins. Cet indice et cette méthodologie peuvent être utiles pour étudier les résultats en matière de santé et de traitement qui sont influencés par les disparités sociales chez les Canadiens co-infectés</description><description>Abstract:Background: HIV-HCV co-infected individuals are often more deprived than the general population. These factors may lead to disengagement from care. However, deprivation is difficult to measure, and often relies on aggregate data which don’t capture individual heterogeneity. We developed an individual-level deprivation index for HIV-HCV co-infected persons that encapsulated social, material, and lifestyle factors. Methods: We estimated an individual-level deprivation index with data from the Canadian Co-infection Cohort, a national prospective cohort study. We used multiple correspondence analyses and exploratory data analyses to select 9 dichotomous variables at baseline visit: income &gt;$1500/month; education &gt;high school; employment; identifying as gay or bisexual; Indigenous status; injection drug use in last 6 months; injection drug use ever; past incarceration, and past psychiatric hospitalization. We fitted an item response theory model with: severity parameters (how likely an item was reported), discriminatory parameters, (how well a variable distinguished index levels), and an individual parameter (the index). We considered two models: a simple one with no provincial variation and a hierarchical model by province. The Widely Applicable Information Criterion was used to compare the models. Finally, we evaluated the association of the index with non-attendance to a second clinic visit (as a measure of disengagement) using logistic regression. Results: We analyzed 1547 complete cases of 1842 enrolled participants; 457 (30%) failed to attend a second visit. The hierarchical model was found to have the best fit. Values of the index were similarly distributed across the provinces. Overall, past incarceration, education, and unemployment had the greatest discriminatory parameters. However, in each province different components of the index were associated with being deprived reflecting local epidemiology.  For example, Saskatchewan had the highest severity parameter for Indigenous status while Quebec the lowest. A one-unit increase in the index was associated with 17% odds (95% credible interval, 2% to 34%) of not attending a second visit.Conclusion: We estimated an individual-level deprivation index with weights of variables varying by province. The index was associated with disengagement from care. This index and methodology may be useful in studying health and treatment outcomes that are influenced by social disparities in co-infected Canadians</description><creator>Palayew, Adam</creator><contributor>Marina B Klein (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Alexandra Schmidt (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</subject><title>Estimation of an individual-level deprivation index in a cohort of HIV-HCV co-infected Canadians and its relationship with health outcomes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cj907.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pv84t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zz67n</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:41:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les jeux basés sur du texte sont un domaine intéressant à l'intersection du traitement du langage naturel et de l'apprentissage par renforcement. Du point de vue de l'apprentissage par renforcement, ils posent divers défis: état combinatoire et espace d'action, récompenses clairsemées et observabilité partielle, c'est-à-dire que l'agent est informé des conséquences de ses actions par un retour textuel. En mettant l'accent sur le dernier point, nous concevons des algorithmes d'apprentissage par renforcement profond qui apprennent uniquement à partir des commentaires. Nous profitons des caractéristiques structurelles communes à ces jeux et proposons deux améliorations algorithmiques dans l'application de Deep RL pour jouer à ces jeux. Nous proposons d'abord un mécanisme de contextualisation, basé sur la récompense accumulée, qui simplifie le problème d'apprentissage et atténue l'observabilité partielle. Nous étudions ensuite différentes méthodes qui reposent sur la notion que la plupart des actions sont inefficaces dans une situation donnée, en suivant l'idée de Zahavy et al. D'une action admissible. Nous évaluons ces techniques dans une série de jeux textuels de difficulté croissante basés sur le framework TextWorld, ainsi que le jeu iconique Zork. Empiriquement, nous constatons que ces techniques améliorent les performances d'un agent d'apprentissage de renforcement profond de base appliqué aux jeux basés sur du texte</description><description>Text-based games are an interesting domain at the intersection of natural language processing and reinforcement learning. From reinforcement learning perspective, they pose various challenges: combinatorial state and action space, sparse rewards and partial observability, i.e., the agent is informed of the consequences of its actions through textual feedback. Emphasising the later point, we design deep reinforcement learning algorithms which learn from feedback alone. We take advantage of the structural characteristics common to these games and propose two algorithmic improvements in applying Deep RL to play these games. We first propose a contextualisation mechanism, based on accumulated reward, which simplifies the learning problem and mitigates partial observability. We then study different methods that rely on the notion that most actions are ineffectual in any given situation, following Zahavy et al.'s idea of an admissible action. We evaluate these techniques in a series of text-based games of increasing difficulty based on the TextWorld framework, as well as the iconic game Zork. Empirically, we find that these techniques improve the performance of a baseline deep reinforcement learning agent applied to text-based games</description><creator>Jain, Vishal Vijay Kumar</creator><contributor>Marc G. Bellemare (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Doina Precup (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Deep reinforcement learning algorithms for playing text-based games from feedback</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vz32s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zz67n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78th60m</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:41:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Food environments with high fast food access may increase risk for poor diet. As much as 62% of the Canadian diet consists of highly processed convenience foods, including food consumed at so-called ‘fast food’ outlets (Ogilvie &amp; Eggleton, 2016). These types of limited service restaurants offer convenience foods, which are typically both calorically dense and high in fat, salt, and sugar. This thesis contributes a new measure of fast food access for Canadian neighbourhoods and examines whether neighbourhood fast food access is associated with increased fast food consumption. Fast food retail outlets were extracted from the Statistics Canada Business Register and mapped in a geographic information system (ArcGIS) by their geocoded location. Absolute and relative fast food access measures were created using 1000m and 3000m network buffers in the neighbourhoods of respondents of the 2015 Canadian Community Health Survey-Nutrition (N = 10,182). Fast food consumption was measured using a question from the survey’s 24-hour dietary recall. 12.7% of adult Canadians reported eating in a fast food restaurant the previous day, with this number varying by province and city. Despite significant variation in Canadian adults’ reporting of fast food consumption across provinces and cities, there was no conclusive influence of the neighbourhood food environment (at either 1000m or 3000m) on fast food consumption. Factors associated with fast food consumption in multivariate analyses were young age (18-24), being male, single, and in the workforce. Results speak to the scale at which fast food consumption cultures may be created. Neighbourhood access may matter less than the surrounding urban environment as a whole in determining fast food consumption</description><description>Les environnements alimentaires ayant une densité élevée de restauration rapide augmentent le risque de mauvaises habitudes alimentaires. Des études suggèrent qu’au moins 62% des nourritures que les canadiens consomment quotidiennement sont de la restauration rapide (Ogilvie &amp; Eggleton, 2016). Des régressions logistiques binomiales furent utilisées afin d’examiner le lien entre l’accessibilité géographique de la restauration rapide dans le quartier et la consomption de restauration rapide par niveau d’éducation dans un échantillon représentatif de la population canadienne. Les commerces de restauration rapide furent extraits du Registre des Commerces du Statistiques Canada et cartographiés dans un système d’information géographique (ArcGIS) par leurs locations géocodées. Les mesures absolues et relatives de l’accessibilité de la restauration rapide furent créées en utilisant des zones tampons de 1000m et à 3000m dans les quartiers des sondés de l’enquête sur la santé dans les collectivités canadiennes-nutrition (2015).  La consomption de restauration rapide fut mesurée d’après une question du sondage sur le rappel alimentaire des dernières 24 heures. 12.7% des adultes canadiens ont déclaré avoir mangé dans un commerce de restauration rapide durant le dernier jour, avec variation par province et par région métropolitaine de recensement. Malgré la variation significative dans la consomption de restauration rapide parmi les provinces et les villes, aucune influence de l’environnement alimentaire du quartier (à 1000m ou à 3000m) sur la consomption de restauration rapide n’a été notée. Les variables explicatives associées à la consomption de restauration rapide furent le groupe d’âge (18-24), le sexe (les hommes), le statut marital (célibataire), et le statut de travail (employé). Les résultats indiquent l’ampleur à laquelle les cultures de restauration rapide sont créées. Il est possible que l’accessibilité géographique aux aliments dans le quartier soit moins importante que l’environnement urbain environnant dans son ensemble à déterminer la consomption de restauration rapide</description><creator>Kaufmann, Clara</creator><contributor>Nancy Ross (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Geography</subject><title>Neighbourhood fast food access and fast food consumption in Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515s668.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78th60m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w674d</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:42:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Heritage language maintenance is a very important problem for immigrant families. Out of varied considerations, more and more Chinese immigrant parents pay attention to their children’s heritage language maintenance. In order to explore Chinese immigrant parents’ and children’s attitudes toward heritage language maintenance, and how age plays a role in children’s heritage language development, this qualitative study recruited participants from a heritage language school in Montreal and collected data through interviews. Findings indicate that most Chinese immigrant parents believe that learning Chinese is important and they hold positive attitudes towards Chinese learning. However, they placed greater importance on speaking and listening skills and have higher expectations on the two skills. The children’s different attitudes toward the four skills were consistent with their parents. Besides, the parents gradually handed the responsibility of heritage language learning to their children over time and the children presented growth autonomy of their Chinese learning. In addition, both parents and children preferred for school support. The parents decided to enroll their children in the Chinese weekend school instead of teaching their children themselves at home</description><description>Le maintien de la langue d’héritage constitue un problème très important pour les familles immigrantes. Pour des raisons diverses, de plus en plus de parents immigrants d’origine chinoise prêtent attention au maintien de la langue d’héritage chez leurs enfants. Dans le but d’explorer les attitudes des parents et des enfants immigrants chinois envers le maintien de leur langue d’héritage, et comment l’âge joue un rôle dans le développement de la langue d’héritage chez les enfants, nous avons recruté des participants à une école de langue en enseignement du chinois à Montréal et recueilli des données en menant des entrevues. Les résultats indiquent que la plupart des parents immigrants chinois trouvent l’apprentissage du chinois important et qu’ils adoptent une attitude positive à l’égard de l’apprentissage de la langue. Cependant, ils accordaient une plus grande importance aux compétences de l’expression et la comprehension orales et attendent plus de ces deux compétences. Différentes attitudes de la part des enfants à l’égard des quatre compétences étaient conformes à celles de leurs parents. En outre, au fil du temps, les parents ont progressivement laissé la responsabilité d’apprendre la langue d’origine à leurs enfants, tandis que les enfants ont développé une autonomie de leur apprentissage de cette langue en grandissant. De plus, les parents et les enfants préféraient demander de l’aide à l’école. Les parents ont décidé d’inscrire leurs enfants à des cours de fin de semaine du chinois au lieu de leur enseigner eux-mêmes à la maison</description><creator>Zhang, Junping</creator><contributor>Susan Gail Ballinger (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Mekhala Sarkar (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Education</subject><title>Family and heritage language maintenance: Parents' and children's attitudes over the years</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cn09v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w674d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pm636</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:42:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ovarian and endometrial cancers are among the leading causes of death for women over 45 years of age in developed countries, and the deadliest of gynecological cancers with an overall survival rate of 46.5%. Every year, 15,000 women die in the US and Canada of this disease. Currently there is no screening program in place, and the diagnostic tools available are neither specific nor sensitive enough for early detection. The standard of care is relevant in assessing and staging previously diagnosed cancer but has not proven effective for early detection. Dr. Gilbert’s research group at the McGill University Health Centre (MUHC) has developed a test to detect these cancers early, based on the identification of genetic tumoral markers from intrauterine samples; however, the tools they had available for procuring these samples were not ideal; For this, we set out to design a collector for liquid biopsies from the uterine cavity. Design methodologies for manufacturability were used to obtain the first generation of the intrauterine liquid biopsy sampler. Verification and validation in vitro tests were performed throughout the process for structural stability, volumetric collection performance and ease of use. The new designs showed an increase in volume collection of 1.3 times when compared to the control and transferred 1.4 times as much sample to the preservation vial. The devices were structurally sound and safe to use under normal conditions</description><description>Les cancers de l'ovaire et de l'endomètre sont parmi les principales causes de décès des femmes de plus de 45 ans dans les pays développés et les plus meurtriers des cancers gynécologiques avec un taux de survie global de 46,5%. Chaque année, 15 000 femmes meurent aux États-Unis et au Canada de cette maladie.Actuellement, aucun programme de dépistage n'est en place et les outils de diagnostic disponibles ne sont ni spécifiques ni suffisamment sensibles pour une détection précoce. Les soins standards permettent d’évaluer et d’établir le stade d’un cancer précédemment diagnostiqué, mais n'a pas été prouvé efficace pour la détection précoce.Le groupe de recherche du Dr Gilbert du Centre Universitaire de Santé McGill (CUSM) a mis au point un test de détection précoce de ces cancers, basé sur l'identification de marqueurs tumoraux génétiques à partir d'échantillons intra-utérins. Cependant, les outils dont il disposa pour se procurer ces échantillons n'étaient pas idéaux, nous avons donc décidé de concevoir un échantillonneur pour biopsies liquides de la cavité utérine.Des méthodologies de conception pour la fabricabilité ont été utilisées pour obtenir la première génération de l'échantillonneur de biopsie liquide intra-utérine. Des tests de vérification et de validation in vitro ont été effectués tout au long du processus pour la stabilité structurelle, les performances de collecte volumétrique et la facilité d'utilisation.Les nouveaux concepts ont montré une augmentation du volume de collecte de 1,3 fois par rapport au contrôle et ont transféré 1,4 échantillons de plus dans le flacon de conservation. Les appareils sont structurellement solides et sûrs à utiliser dans des conditions normales</description><creator>Ulacia Flores, Paola</creator><contributor>Rosaire Mongrain (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Lucy Gilbert (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Design and optimization of a liquid biopsy collector for ovarian and endometrial cancer screening</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859k96w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pm636</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b794z</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:42:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Abusive language in online discourse negatively affects a large number of social media users. Many computational methods have been proposed by the Natural Language Processing (NLP) community to address this issue of online abuse. The existing studies, however, have been limited in that they focus on detecting the more explicit forms of abuse leaving the subtler forms of abuse largely untouched. This is problematic since subtle abuse can be just as damaging as overt abuse. This thesis makes three core contributions to address this gap in the literature. First, we propose a novel task of detecting a subtler form of abuse, namely unpalatable questions, inspired from the theory of impoliteness. Second, we collect, annotate, and make publicly available a context-rich dataset for the task using data from a diverse set of online communities on Reddit. A notable characteristic of our dataset is that the conversational context was explicitly considered during annotation. Third, we implement a wide array of machine learning and deep learning models using state-of-the-art NLP techniques to detect unpalatable questions. We also investigate the benefits of incorporating conversational context into the computational models. Our results show that modelling subtle abuse is feasible but difficult due to the language involved being highly nuanced and context-sensitive. We hope that future research in the field will also account for subtler forms of abuse since they do their harm passing unnoticed through existing detection systems. Detecting abuse -- both overt and subtle -- on the Internet would help enhance the user's online experience and facilitate civil and productive discussions</description><description>Le langage abusif utilisé sur les plateformes virtuelles a des impacts négatifs sur un grand nombre d’usagers des média sociaux. Plusieurs méthodes de calcul ont été proposées par la communauté Natural Language Processing (NLP) pour résoudre la problématique de l’abus virtuel. La recherche sur ce sujet est toutefois limitée et se concentre majoritairement sur la détection de formes explicites d’abus alors que les formes plus subtiles d’abus passent inaperçues. Cette problématique est inquiétante sachant que les formes d’abus plus subtiles peuvent être tout aussi dommageable que les formes d’abus explicite. Pour combler cette lacune, cette thèse contribue au domaine de recherche de trois manières différentes. Premièrement, nous proposons une nouvelle technique inspirée de la théorie linguistique de l’impolitesse afin de détecter les formes subtiles d’abus, notamment les questions déplaisantes. Deuxièmement, nous collectons, annotons et rendons public une banque de donnée qui comprend l’information contextuelle associé aux formes d’abus subtiles. Cette base de données est construite est à l'aide de données provenant d'un ensemble diversifié de communautés en ligne sur Reddit et se démarque car elle inclut le contexte de la conversation qui a donné lieu à l’abus. Troisièmement, nous avons implémenté plusieurs modèles d’apprentissage automatique et d’apprentissage approfondi à l’aide de techniques NLP de pointe pour détecter les questions déplaisantes. Nous étudions également les avantages qui découlent de l’intégration du contexte de la conversation qui a donné lieu à l’abus dans l’analyse dans des modèles informatiques. Nos résultats démontrent qu’il est possible de modéliser les abus subtils est réalisable mais cette tâche reste incroyablement difficile en raison du langage très nuancé et dépendant du contexte qui est utilisé. Nous espérons que les recherches futures dans le domaine incluront également les formes d’abus subtiles, car elles causent des dommages qui ne sont pas détectées par les systèmes de détection existants. Détecter les abus - à la fois explicites et implicites - sur Internet contribuerait à améliorer l’expérience virtuelle des usagers et faciliterait des discussions saines et civiles</description><creator>Bagga, Sunyam</creator><contributor>Derek Ruths (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Andrew Piper (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Detecting abuse on the internet: It's subtle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000447q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b794z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vz332</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:42:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The field of fan studies has gone through several transformations in semantics and dialectics since its conception in the latter half of the 20th century. However, it is overdue for a complete revolution in the way that scholars conceptualize fans and fandoms. Matt Hills (2017) introduces the theoretical concept of fan worlds to expand our thinking on what constitutes a fan or fan community. The author builds on Hills’ concept of fan worlds to introduce it as a way of mapping and orienting space using the practices that form an affective bond between a fan subject and fan object. This mapping of space is visualized through social media, which renders legible the relationships that form between fans, fan objects, and media institutions. Using social media, issues of accessibility, anonymity, economy, and transcultural contact zones can be identified and mapped into the fan world. In turn, social media also forms infrastructure that connects spaces within the fan world to one another and the world as a whole to other fan worlds. Scholars of fan studies should adopt the concept of fan worlds within their own projects and continue to map out the world systems that exist around fan objects</description><description>Le domaine des études de fans a connu plusieurs transformations en sémantique et dialectique depuis sa conception dans la seconde moitié du XXe siècle. Cependant, il est trop tard pour une révolution complète dans la façon dont les érudits conceptualisent les fans et les fandoms. Matt Hills (2017) présente le concept théorique des mondes de fans pour élargir notre réflexion sur ce qui constitue un fan ou une communauté de fans. L’auteur s’appuie sur le concept de Hills des mondes de fans pour l’introduire comme un moyen de cartographier et d’orienter l’espace en utilisant les pratiques qui forment un lien affectif entre un sujet fan et un objet fan. Cette cartographie de l'espace est visualisée à travers les médias sociaux, ce qui rend lisibles les relations qui se forment entre les fans, les objets de fans et les institutions médiatiques. En utilisant les médias sociaux, les problèmes d'accessibilité, d'anonymat, d'économie et de zones de contact transculturelles peuvent être identifiés et cartographiés dans le monde des fans. De plus, les médias sociaux forment également une infrastructure qui relie les espaces du monde des fans les uns aux autres et le monde dans son ensemble aux autres mondes des fans. Les spécialistes des études de fans devraient adopter le concept de mondes de fans dans leurs propres projets et continuer à cartographier les systèmes mondiaux qui existent autour des objets de fans</description><creator>Taylor, Leslie</creator><contributor>Thomas Lamarre (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Gal Gvili (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>East Asian Studies</subject><title>Fan Worlds: Expanding the Horizons of Fandoms and Fan Studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827h37d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vz332</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vq358</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:43:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Biodiversity-Ecosystem Function (BEF) research in forests lacks a solid foundation of below-ground studies that consider coarse roots, and documented analyses that include both crown and root system are sparser still. This thesis seeks to fill this knowledge gap by assessing the influence of the tree neighbourhood (e.g. size and species identity of neighbouring trees) and abiotic characteristics (e.g. soil nitrogen content, depth to water table), first on coarse root traits such as length, diameter and number of coarse lateral roots, and second on the extent and shape of crowns and root systems. We used mixtures of tree species (monoculture, two- or three-, and five-species mixtures) planted in 2001 at the Sardinilla experiment in Panamá. In 2017, 128 trees of 13.27 ± 4.73 m mean height were destructively harvested above-ground, and their root systems up to 0.5m radius and 0.2 m depth from the stem were excavated from the soil to expose the core of their root systems. In addition, a primary lateral root was chosen randomly and fully excavated; species-specific allometries were used to predict the length of all unexcavated primary roots. Terrestrial laser scans taken in 2017 were used to calculate the 128 trees’ two-dimensional crown shapes. With these data, seven root traits were described, including four observed (primary root number, diameter and length, and number of secondary roots per meter of primary root) and 3 predicted traits (root system extent, total length of roots per focal tree, and coarse root biomass), as well as crown and root system area and an index of compactness of these systems. Focal tree biomass was plotted against the Hegyi distance-dependent competition index at three distinct neighbourhood extents (nearest neighbours, above- and below-ground neighbours) to identify the neighbourhood scale that best explained focal tree growth. Canonical correspondence analysis was used to identify which aspects of neighbourhood composition and environmental characteristics explained a majority of variation in the tested root and crown traits.Larger trees tended to have more extensive and numerous primary roots, and the 128 focal trees’ root systems were on average 2.6 ± 1.1 (standard deviation) times wider than their crowns. The size and species identity of near neighbours explained more variation than environmental characteristics: compare 63.0% versus 30.4% variation in the seven coarse root traits explained, and 65.8% versus 26.0% variation explained in crown and root extent and morphological traits. The nearest neighbourhood best predicted focal tree biomass (R2 of 0.46), suggesting the paramount importance of competition with near neighbours for the biomass and above- and below-ground architecture of two-decade-old tropical trees. However, certain trends in root architecture were observed in response to biotic and abiotic variables: trees growing with conspecific neighbours, in nitrogen-rich plots or in soil with a lower mean water table height tended to have more and shorter primary roots. These findings further our understanding of how tropical tree roots and crowns respond to their local biotic and abiotic environments, plastically altering architecture and morphology to better cope with competing neighbours and nutrient or water supply</description><description>La recherche sur la biodiversité et les fonctions des écosystèmes (BEF, en anglais) dans les forêts manque encore d'études qui prenant en compte les grosses racines, ainsi que d’analyses documentées considèrant la couronne et le système racinaire. Par conséquent, cette thèse étudie l’influence du voisinage des arbres (par ex. la taille et l’identité des espèces des arbres voisins) et des caractéristiques abiotiques (par ex. la concentration d'azote du sol ou le niveau piézométrique), même pour les traits racinaires tels que la longueur, diamètre et nombre de racines latérales primaires, comme pour l’étendue et la forme des couronnes et des systèmes racinaires. Nous avons utilisé des parcelles d'arbres (monoculture, mélanges de deux, trois ou cinq espèces) plantés en 2001 à Sardinilla, en Panamá. En 2017, 128 d'arbres ont été exploités de manière destructive et dans un rayon de 0,5 m et d'une hauteur de 0,2 m ont été extraits du sol pour exposer le noyau du système racinaire. De plus, une racine latérale primaire a été choisie au hasard et entièrement excavée; des allométries spécifiques aux espèces ont été utilisées pour prédire la longueur de toutes les racines primaires non excavées. Les balayages laser terrestres effectués en 2017 ont été utilisés pour calculer les formes de cimes bidimensionnelles des 128 arbres. Avec ces données, sept traits racinaires ont été décrits, dont quatre observés (le nombre, diamètre et longueur des racines primaires, et le nombre de racines secondaires par mètre de racine primaire) et trois traits prédits (l'étendue du système racinaire, la longueur totale des racines, et la biomasse racinaire primaires), ainsi que de la couronne et du système racinaire et un indice de compacité de ces systèmes. La biomasse des arbres focaux a été comparée à l'indice de compétition de Hegyi en fonction de trois étendues de voisinage distinctes (les voisins les plus proches, les voisins au-dessus et au-dessous du sol) pour identifier l'échelle spatiale qui explique le mieux la croissance des arbres focaux. Une 'analyse de correspondance cononique a été utilisée pour identifier les aspects de la composition spatiale et des caractéristiques environnementales expliquant la majorité de la variation des caractères de racine et de couronne testés. Les grands arbres ont tendance à avoir des racines primaires plus étendues et plus nombreuses que les petits, et le système racinaire de les 128 arbres exploitées est en moyenne 2,6 ± 1,1 (l’écart type) plus large que leur cime. La taille et l'identité de l'espèce des voisins proches expliquent plus la variation que les caractéristiques environnementales: 63,0% contre 30,4% de la variation des sept caractères des grosses racines expliqués, et 65,8% contre 26,0% variation expliqué pour l'étendue de la couronne et des racines et les traits morphologiques. La biomasse des arbres focaux a été mieux prédite par le voisinage le plus proche (R2 de 0,46), ce qui suggère que la compétition avec des voisins proches détermine la biomasse d'arbre ainsi que l’architecture aérienne et souterraine. Cependant, certaines réponses de l’architecture racinaire ont été observées en réponse à des variables biotiques et abiotiques: les arbres poussant avec des voisins conspécifiques, dans des parcelles riches en azote ou dans un sol où le niveau piézométrique était plus bas, avaient des racines primaires plus nombreuses et plus courtes. Ces résultats permettent de mieux comprendre comment les racines et les couronnes des arbres tropicaux réagissent à leurs environnements biotiques et abiotiques en modifiant l'architecture et la morphologie de manière plastique afin de mieux atteindre de la lumière, les nutriments ou l'eau en sol en compétition avec des voisins</description><creator>Madsen, Chris</creator><contributor>Catherine Potvin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Biology</subject><title>Local neighbourhood affects the crowns and root systems of five tropical tree species</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806459z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vq358</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816s06c</identifier><datestamp>2020-07-14T19:43:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La chiralité, soit l’incapacité d’une structure à se superposer par rapport à son image miroir, se manifeste dans presque tous les systèmes biologiques. Les cristaux de vatérite(carbonate  de  calcium) se trouvent dans divers organismes dans lesquels se produit la biominéralisation, allant des squelettes d’organismes marins aux oreilles internes des humains. Les cristaux sont constitués de structures nano pseudo-hexagonales et la présence d’acides aminés chiraux spécifiques induisent une chiralité, qui est droitière ou gauchière, par le biais d’un mécanisme de croissance inclinable des nanoparticules. Cependant, en l’absence d’acides aminés, les particules forment une structure cristalline tassée. Cette thèse porte sur la simulation et la modélisation des mécanismes de basculement qui donnent lieu à la chiralité, dans le but de mieux comprendre ce phénomène tel qu’il se produit dans la nature.Deux mécanismes de chiralité proposés dans la littérature sur la croissance des cristaux ont été explorés en particulier, soient ceux qui portent sur des rotations inter-particulaires entre une particule existante et une nouvelle particule fille  ainsi que ceux traitant des inclinaisons interplaquettaires. Nous avons développé des algorithmes pour simuler les rotations qui jouent un rôle central dans l’évolution de la croissance des cristaux au fil du temps, de la surface du substrat jusqu’à son point culminant en une structure hiérarchique de couches sur couches de nanoparticules. Nous avons étudié l’attachement des particules filles aux sommets d’une particule mère ou fille existante et déterminé que l’attachement des particules de sommet sélectif ou restreint est essentiel pour les modèles réguliers qui sont compatibles avec les expériences réelles de croissance cristalline. Nous avons soulevé des questions fondamentales concernant les emplacements et les fréquences de nucléation des particules mères qui déterminent le résultat de la simulation, car ces questions n’ont pas été élaborées en profondeur dans la littérature scientifique. Nous avons trouvé des solutions justes telles que la modélisation de la diffusion ionique qui pourrait être utilisée au niveau informatique pour conduire le processus de nucléation</description><description>Chirality, the inability of a structure to be superimposed onto its mirror image, is exhibited in almost all biological systems. Vaterite (calcium carbonate) crystals are found in various organisms in which biomineralization occurs, ranging from skeletons of marine organisms to the inner ears of humans. The crystals are made up of nano pseudo-hexagonal structures and the presence of specific chiral amino acids induces chirality, which is either right-handed or left-handed, due to a nano-particle tilting growth mechanism. In the absence of amino acids, however, the particles form a packed crystalline structure. This thesis looks at simulating and modeling the tilting mechanisms that give rise to chirality, to better understand this phenomenon as it occurs in nature. Two mechanisms for chirality proposed in the crystal growth literature have been explored in particular, which are inter-particle rotations between an existing particle and a new daughter particle and inter-platelet tilts. We have developed algorithms to simulate these rotations that play a key role in the crystal growth evolution over time, from the initial substrate surface to their final culmination to a hierarchical structure of layers upon layers of nano-particles. We have studied the attachment of daughter particles to the vertices of a mother or existing daughter particle and determined that selective or restricted vertex particle attachment is critical for regular patterns that are consistent with the actual experiments in crystal growth. We have raised fundamental questions regarding locations and frequencies of nucleation of mother particles which determine the result of the simulation, since these issues have not been explored in detail in the existing literature. We have provided feasible solutions such as ion diffusion modeling, that could potentially be used to computationally drive the nucleation process</description><creator>Singh, Aashima</creator><contributor>Kaleem Siddiqi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Modeling chirality in vaterite crystals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591d60n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816s06c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):47800</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>