<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:29:01Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34925" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bw15r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Degenerating spinal motor neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) are characterized by a reduced expression of neurofilament light (NF-L) mRNA and by the presence of inclusions composed of peripherin and neurofilament (NF) proteins. This thesis examines questions related to the formation and toxicity of inclusions containing peripherin. Transfection studies demonstrated that the organization of the penpherin network is disrupted by the larger NF proteins NF-M and NF-H in context of NF-L deficiency. To further investigate the in vivo assembly of peripherin, transgenic mice overexpressing the mouse peripherin gene were generated and then bred with NF-L null mice. Mice overexpressing peripherin developed a late onset motor neuron disease characterized by the formation of peripherin inclusions and by the degeneration of motor axons in two years old mice. Remarkably, a deficiency of the NF-L protein enhanced the formation of inclusions and accelerated the onset of the peripherin-mediated disease by about 15 months. Transgenic mice overexpressing the human NF-H protein in the absence of NF-L (hH;L-/- mice) were then generated to further examine the impact of a NF-L deficiency upon the formation and toxicity of protein inclusions. These mice were characterized by the formation of large perikaryal inclusions containing peripherin and NF-H. Unlike the axonal and perikaryal inclusions formed in peripherin transgenic mice, the inclusions of hH;L-/- mice were not associated with loss spinal motor neuron, thus suggesting that the toxicity of inclusions in peripherin transgenic mice may be related to their axonal localization. Finally, a last series of experiments demonstrated that stab injuries and ischemia can also trigger the formation of peripherin inclusions in brain neurons that are normally silent for peripherin expression. The combined results suggest that peripherin inclusions may participate to the pathology of ALS and perhaps to neurodegeneration in other dis</description><creator>Beaulieu, Jean Martin.</creator><contributor>Julien, Jean-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Formation and toxicity of neuronal peripherin inclusions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xw66c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw15r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494b112</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the projected increase in global population, unprecedented increases in crop production will be needed and legume crops are one of the primary means of achieving these increases. The legume-Rhizobium symbiosis is the single most important source of biologically fixed nitrogen in agricultural systems but, as a biological system it is complex, and very sensitive to environmental effects, such as available soil nitrogen, soil pH (both high and low), soil salinity and extremes of soil temperature. Each of these may affect the delicate signal exchange process that occurs during symbiosis establishment. To better understand the effect of environmental factors on signal exchange and nodulation, we conducted four experiments, under controlled-environment conditions, with pea (Pisum sativum) as the model legume. The first experiment studied the effects of available nitrogen, the second the effects of low soil pH, the third the effect of soil salinity and the fourth the effects of low soil temperature. In all experiments the plants were inoculated with Rhizobium leguminosarum bv. viceae cells previously treated with 10 x 10-3 M of hesperitin or naringenin, or not treated (control). In all experiments plants were destructively sampled at 10, 20, 30 and 40 days after inoculation (in two experiments samplings were also conducted at 15 DAI), and data on plant and nodule variables were collected. To allow for a better understanding of the effects of flavonoids on nodule development an image analysis technique was developed that permitted us to measure every individual nodule at each sampling. This provided a more precise picture of nodule development over time than would have been possible with previous methods. Our results indicated that addition of flavonoids had positive effects on nodulation, both in number and size of nodules produced, and that the positive effects were greatest at the most inhibitory levels of the environmental factors tested, and at earlier sampling</description><creator>Lira Junior, Mario de Andrade.</creator><contributor>Smith, Donald L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Rhizobium leguminosarum.</subject><subject>Peas -- Roots -- Anatomy.</subject><subject>Flavonoids.</subject><subject>Plant cellular signal transduction.</subject><subject>Root-tubercles.</subject><title>Environmental factors and plant-to-bacteria signals effects on nodulation and nodule development of pea</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k790.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494b112</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440v24z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sry on the Y-chromosome triggers the fetal gonad to begin differentiation into testis in mammals. Mutation or absence of Sry results in development of ovaries and the female phenotype. However, XY sex reversal in the presence of wild-type Sry exists in mice and man. One such example is the B6-YTIR mouse, whose autosomes and X-chromosome are of the C57BL6/J mouse (Mus musculus molossinus) whereas the Y-chromosome is from a mouse originating in Tirano, Italy (Mus musculus domesticus). B6-YTIR mice develop only ovaries or ovotestes in fetal life. The objective of my thesis was to identify the mechanism of sex reversal in the B6-YTIR mouse. The results indicate that onset of Sry transcription in B6-YTIR gonads is comparable to control B6 XY gonads. On the other hand, onset of Mis, 17alpha-HA, 3beta-HSD (testicular cell products), p450arom as well as inactivation of Sry transcription are delayed or absent in the sex reversed gonads. It has been suggested that low levels of Sry transcription may account for aberrant testis differentiation in B6-YTIR mice. We observed relatively low levels of Sry transcripts not only in B6-YTIR but also in B6 mice. However, levels in normal B6-YSJL mice were significantly greater. On the SJLB6F1 background, where no sex reversal occurs, Sry transcript levels of the TIR allele increased while those of B6 and SJL alleles remained the same as in the B6 background. Thus, low levels of Sry transcript from the B6 allele are sufficient whereas the levels from TIR and SJL alleles (both DOM type) appear to be critical for testis determination. We then compared the levels of endogenous Sry proteins. A combination of immunoprecipitation and immunoblotting succeeded in detecting a protein band whose expression profile and molecular size are consistent with those of the predicted Sry. Sry protein levels in B6-Y TIR gonads were roughly two fold greater than in B6 XY gonads. We hypothesize that the Sry protein of the TIR/SJL alleles is less efficient</description><creator>Lee, Chung-Hae, 1966-</creator><contributor>Taketo, Teruko (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Sex differentiation disorders</subject><subject>Mice -- Molecular genetics</subject><subject>Sex determination, Genetic</subject><title>Mechanism of sex determination and reversal in an XY mouse strain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r01w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v24z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67js842</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An individual faced with intergroup conflict must choose from a vast array of possible actions, ranging from grumbling among ingroup friends to voting and demonstrating to rioting and revolution. The present thesis proposes a model of decision-making in intergroup contexts oriented towards understanding how group members choose among these behavioural alternatives. Intergroup decisions are conceptualized as rationally shaped by perceptions of the benefits and costs associated with the action (expectancy-value processes). In intergroup contexts, group-level costs and benefits may play a critical role in individuals' decision-making. Perception of the dynamic between ingroup and outgroup norms is thought to be a key determinant of the group-level benefits and costs associated with individualistic or collective actions. Four studies explore the predictive value of this model for understanding decision-making in the context of English-French conflict in Quebec. Studies 1 and 2 provide evidence that group-level costs and benefits influence individuals' decision-making, in intergroup contexts. Contrary to the predictions of individualistic models of decision-making such as the theory of planned behaviour (Ajzen, 1985), the individual level of analysis was not observed to mediate the group level of analysis. Moreover, contrary to recent social identity theorizing (Kelly, 1993; Simon et al., 1998), perceived group-level costs and benefits were implicated in the relationship between social identity and intentions to engage in collective action. Studies 3 and 4 provide evidence that outgroup and ingroup norms may interact to influence decision-making. Thus, contrary to the referent informational influence model (Terry &amp; Hogg, 1996; Turner, 1991), ingroup norms alone did not determine group members' actions. Moreover, Study 4 provides evidence that the dynamic between ingroup and outgroup norms influences evaluations of the costs and benefits of intergroup behaviours, both</description><creator>Louis, Winnifred R.</creator><contributor>Taylor, Donald M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Québec (Province) -- Ethnic relations.</subject><subject>Group decision making.</subject><title>Grumbling, voting, demonstrating, and rioting : a model of social identity and decision-making in intergroup contexts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j7149.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67js842</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418p86w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Because of the concern for the environment and the search for the synthetic efficiency, the metal-mediated aqueous carbon-carbon bond formation reactions were studied. By employing sulfonimines, the scope of the metal-mediated aqueous Barbier-type allylation reactions was expanded to C=N electrophiles and the regio- and stereoselectivities of these reactions were examined. The stereochemical factors in the indium-mediated aqueous Barbier-type allylation reactions of sulfonimines were investigated, and chelation control was observed and applied in the stereoselective crotylation reactions. By using chiral-modified sulfonimines or sulfinimines, the asymmetric aqueous Barbier-type allylation reaction of C=N electrophiles was also studied. Highly regioselective propargylation reactions of sulfonimines mediated by zinc were discovered through the coupling of propargylic bromides with sulfonimines in aqueous media. Beyond the allylation transformations, zinc was also found as the metal of choice for the mediation of the Barbier-type benzylation reaction of sulfonimines and the coupling reaction of aldehydes with alpha-bromoacetonitriles in aqueous media. The indium-mediated aqueous coupling reaction of 1,4-dibromobut-2-yne with aldehydes was demonstrated to be a concise way for the synthesis of 1,3-dien-ol compounds. Further synthetic applications of this reaction including the intro-molecular Diels-Alder reactions were preliminarily studied.</description><creator>Lu, Wenshuo, 1971-</creator><contributor>Chan, Tak Hang (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Organometallic reactions in aqueous media : reactivity, selectivity and synthetic applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx08x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418p86w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418p875</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We study the interaction between dislocations and smooth elastic strains in thin film growth. In the first part of the thesis, a continuum model is introduced which, for the first time, includes nucleation, interaction, and dynamics of dislocations in an external stress field in two spatial dimensions. The model implicitly includes the presence of boundaries and their coupling to the elastic strains in the system. In particular, it naturally gives rise to the two well-known strain relaxation modes in thin films: the Asaro-Tiller-Grinfeld (ATG) morphological instability, leading to a grooved morphology of the film-vapor interface, and the nucleation of misfit dislocations for films thicker than the Matthews-Blakeslee critical thickness. The novelty of the model resides in the fact that both of these mechanisms are explicitly incorporated within a unified approach. Therefore, this is a generic model for dislocations in strained heterogeneous systems. In the second part of the thesis, this model is applied to thin film growth with dislocations. It is shown that the film undergoes an ATG instability. However, the accumulation of dislocations at the film-substrate interface leads to an effectively screened stress in the film, and hence buckling occurs at longer wavelengths. In particular, it is shown that the film remains planar for sufficiently effective screening. Furthermore, the effect of dislocations depends very strongly on their equilibrium density and mobility. It is also shown that, in the late-time regime, dislocations interact strongly with the stress enhancement at the bottom of the grooves. In particular, this leads to a buildup of localized dislocations around the stress concentrations, in addition to dislocations at the film-substrate interface. This in turn leads to very complicated film morphologies, in qualitative agreement with experiments. In the last part of the thesis, the dynamics of a single groove is studied in a strip geometry, both with and without dislocations. In the absence of dislocations, it is argued theoretically and shown numerically, that the groove attains a steady-state. A theoretical argument is given for the shape of the groove, and good agreement with numerics is found. Upon including noise in the dynamics, a morphological transition from straight to oscillatory propagation is found. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Haataja, Mikko.</creator><contributor>Grant, Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Model of elastic effects and dislocations in strained heteroepitaxial films</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333396w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418p875</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wr92v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present thesis and series of studies explores the underlying cognitive and neuropsychological processes that underlies propensity for aggressive response in adult men and women, both sober and intoxicated. Previous research demonstrated that poor executive functioning, either pre-existing (idiopathic) or induced by alcohol-intoxication, was associated with heightened aggressive responses. The first study demonstrates that although cognitively impaired when alcohol intoxicated, men with above average pre-alcohol Executive Cognitive Functioning (ECF) do not act aggressively if they are properly motivated to remain non-aggressive, suggesting some ability to use residual executive function. The second study directly compares the aggression-eliciting effects of alcohol in both men and women, an under-investigated issue. Results indicate that aggression levels in the women are not significantly less than those of men, and that alcohol-intoxication is not as predictive a factor in women as in men. The third study, a post-hoc analysis of the second, indicates that like for men, executive function level in women is highly related to propensity for aggressive response, in fact far more predictive than acute alcohol-intoxication. The fourth study was intended to investigate a possible behavioural explanation for the ECF-aggression relationship. Specifically, this study was designed to assess whether the aggression manifested by individuals with poor ECF was rapid or impulsive, i.e. due to a disinhibition process. Contrary to this popular contention, this study demonstrates that when faced with complex, social interactions, low-ECF individuals act aggressively, but only after a somewhat slow period of apparent contemplation. These findings and others conducted by the author are discussed in a speculative model of the ECF-aggression relationship. Means by which to test this model are proposed, as are other theoretical implications of the work.</description><creator>Hoaken, Peter Neil Spencer.</creator><contributor>Pihl, R. O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Aggressiveness.</subject><subject>Alcohol -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Cognitive psychology.</subject><title>Executive cognitive function, alcohol intoxication, and aggressive behaviour in adult men and women</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666618m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wr92v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494b12b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The human progranulin gene encodes a 593 amino acid secreted glycoprotein, progranulin (also called PC cell-derived growth factor, acrogranin or granulin/epithelin precursor). The biological activities of this protein were poorly defined at the beginning of the project. Here, we determined that the progranulin gene is widely expressed in vivo and strongly associated with immune, neuronal and highly proliferative epithelial cells. It is not expressed in fibroblasts and endothelial cells in vivo unless these cells are stimulated by, for example, tissue damage and this expression correlates temporally with the healing process. Thus progranuhn is induclbly expressed in mesenchymal cells but is a constitutive product in proliferative epithelial cells. These studies defined a physiological context for investigating the roles of progranulin in the body. To correlate the expression studies with function, we assessed the ability of progranulin to regulate wound repair and epithelial growth. Progranulin enhances the growth and motility of fibroblasts and endothelial cells, and promotes the formation of tubule-like structures by endothelial cells on Matrigel, suggesting that progranulin may accelerate fibroplasia and serve as a pro-angiogenic factor in the proper environment. These effects are mediated through the activation of the p44/42 MAP kinase, PI-3 kinase and focal adhesion kinase (FAK) pathways, as inlubition of the MAP kinase and PI-3 kinase pathways by PD98059 and wortmannin blocked progranulin-induced cell migration, and progranulin was found to hyper-phosphorylate FAK in endothelial cells. The association of strong progranulin expression with highly proliferative epithelial cells suggests that progranulin may take part in epithelial homeostasis. To investigate this hypothesis, we either overexpressed or downregulated the progranulin gene in SW-13 and MDCK cells. SW-13 cells are derived from human adrenal cancer, but their growth resembles non-transformed epithel</description><creator>He, Zhiheng, 1971-</creator><contributor>Bateman, Andrew (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Functional characterization of progranulin in wound healing and tumorigenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2686787.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494b12b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qt63w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study incorporates archival and historical research on women poets and editors and their roles in the production of modernist and/or leftist little-magazine cultures in Canada. Where the first three chapters investigate women poets who were also magazine editors and/or members of magazine groups, the fourth chapter takes account of women magazine editors who were not themselves poets. Within this framework, the dissertation relates women's editorial work and poetry to a series of crises and transitions in Canada's leftist and modernist little-magazine cultures between 1926 and 1956. This historical pattern of crisis and transition pertains at once to the poetry of Dorothy Livesay, Anne Marriott, P. K. Page, and Miriam Waddington and to the little-magazine groups in which they and other women were active as editors and/or contributing members. Chapter 1 deals with Livesay's editorial activities and poetry in the context of two magazines of the cultural left, Masses and New Frontier, between 1932 and 1937. Chapter 2 concerns Livesay, Marriott, their involvement in poetry groups in Victoria and Vancouver, and their publications in Contemporary Verse and Canadian Poetry Magazine, between 1935 and 1956. Chapter 3 addresses the poetry of Page and Waddington published in Preview and First Statement from 1942 to 1945, their poetry appearing in Contemporary Verse from 1941 to 1952--53, and their editorial activities in and/or relationships to these Montreal and Victoria - Vancouver magazine groups between 1941 and 1956. Chapter 4 documents the histories of some often forgotten women who edited modernist or leftist little magazines in Canada between 1926 and 1956. These core chapters are prefaced and concluded by histories of the antecedents to and descendants of Canadian modernist and leftist magazine cultures.</description><creator>Irvine, Dean J. (Dean Jay)</creator><contributor>Trehearne, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Little magazines -- Canada -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Women editors -- Canada.</subject><subject>Women poets -- Canada.</subject><title>Little histories : modernist and leftist women poets and magazine editors in Canada, 1926-56</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c18v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt63w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806152d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many bacteria accumulate carbon stores as poly-3-hydroxybutyrate (PHB) when growth is limited but carbon availability is not. This stored carbon can then be utilized during conditions of limited carbon availability. The net PHB accumulation in the cell is dependent on the balance between PHB synthesis and degradation. Sinorhizobium meliloti accumulates PHB in the free-living stage but not in the symbiotic stage. The physiological role of the PHB cycle in S. meliloti is unknown. As a first step to understand the genetics of PHB degradation, transposon-generated mutants that were not able to use PHB degradation intermediates, such as 3-hydroxybutyrate and acetoacetate, as a sole carbon source, were isolated. Genetic mapping revealed that there were at least three chromosomal loci involved in acetoacetate metabolism. Identification of these three loci determined that in S. meliloti: (1) acetoacetyl-CoA synthetase (AcsA), encoded by acsA2 gene, rather than the enzyme acetoacetate:succinyl-CoA transferase, is the enzyme that catalyzes activation of acetoacetate to acetoacetyl-CoA; (2) PHB synthase, encoded by phbC, is required for acetoacetate utilization; (3) a putative transporter protein encoding gene, aau-3, may also be involved in acetoacetate metabolism. acsA2 and aau-3 were 78% linked in co-transduction, while phbC was mapped to somewhere else on the chromosome. Biochemical analysis revealed that acsA2::Tn5 mutants lacked AcsA activity but not acetoacetate:succinyl-CoA transferase activity, while phbC::Tn5 maintained similar level of AcsA activity as wild type in vitro. PHB was absent in the phbC mutant. One transposon-generated mutant, age-1, showed enhanced growth rate on acetoacetate medium. Genetic mapping and transductional analysis indicated that the location of the mutation in age-1 is tightly linked to acsA2. Fine mapping with PCR and DNA sequence techniques showed that Tn5 in age-1 was located at 132 by upstream of the putative translation start site of acsA2. Gene expression analysis indicated that age-1 insertion results in elevated transcription of acsA2. Thus enhanced growth rate on acetoacetate was due to the increased gene expression. acsA2 transcription was induced by acetoacetate and 3-hydroxybutyrate, and repressed by glucose and acetate. All mutants formed root nodules that fixed nitrogen with varying decrease of impairment. Acetoacetate metabolism and the PHB degradation are not essential for symbiosis.</description><creator>Cai, Guo Qin, 1966-</creator><contributor>Charles, Trevor (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Acetoacetates -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Rhizobium meliloti -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Ketonic acids -- Metabolism -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Acetates -- Metabolism -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Rhizobium meliloti -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Sinorhizobium meliloti -- genetics.</subject><title>Molecular genetic analysis of acetoacetate metabolism in Sinorhizobium meliloti</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085m96h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806152d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z007q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hyperhomocysteinemia is a risk factor for cardiovascular disease and stroke. Nutritional and/or genetic disruptions in homocysteine metabolism can cause hyperhomocysteinemia. Mild methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR) deficiency due to the 677C → T mutation in the MTHFR gene is the most common genetic cause of hyperhomocysteinemia. The 677C → T variant is associated with an increased risk for neural tube defects, pregnancy complications, schizophrenia and Down syndrome, and with a decreased risk for colon cancer and leukemia. This variant is also a potential risk factor for vascular disease. Severe MTHFR deficiency results in homocystinuria, an inborn error of metabolism with neurological and vascular complications. We have generated mice with a knockout of the Mthfr gene. The Mthfr-deficient mice exhibit hyperhomocysteinemia and decreased methylation capacity. The Mthfr+/- mice appear normal, whereas the Mthfr-/- mice are smaller and have reduced survival. Abnormal external granule neuron development associated with increased cell death in the cerebellum was observed in the Mthfr-/- mice. Evidence for cardiovascular pathology was obtained in several ways. Impaired aortic relaxation response to acetylcholine was seen in the Mthfr +/- mice fed a high methionine diet. Both Mthfr+/- and Mthfr-/- mice fed a low folate high methionine diet developed myocardial fibrosis in the left ventricle. Abnormal lipid deposition in the proximal portion of the aorta was observed in older Mthfr+/- and Mthfr-/- mice. After crossing Mthfr -deficient mice with apoE-null mice, we demonstrated that MTHFR deficiency promoted atherogenesis and its progression in the apoE-null mice. Gene expression in brain of Mthfr-deficient mice was investigated via microarray analysis. Five genes with altered expression in the brain of Mthfr-/- mouse were validated by RT-PCR. In biochemical studies of human MTHFR, both FAD and folate were shown to stabilize the purified recombinant wild type and mutant MTHFRs from the baculovirus expression system against heat inactivation. The effect of folate appeared to be secondary to that of FAD, and S-adenosylmethionine (SAM) inhibited purified wild type and mutant MTHFRs with similar efficiency. This dissertation will significantly contribute to our understanding of the role of MTHFR in human disease.</description><creator>Chen, Zhoutao, 1972-</creator><contributor>Rozen, Rima (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Homocysteine -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Hyperhomocysteinemia -- etiology.</subject><subject>Mice -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Folic acid deficiency.</subject><subject>Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase</subject><subject>Cardiovascular system -- Diseases -- Etiology.</subject><title>A mouse model for methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase deficiency and biochemical studies of the recombinant human enzyme /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526d97p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z007q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb3979844</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The major objective of this project was to evaluate the feasibility of artificial neural networks (ANNs) and genetic algorithms (GAs) for modeling and optimization of food thermal processing. The specific objectives were: (1) to develop a comprehensive computer simulation program for thermal processing, (2) to apply ANNs and GAs for modeling and optimization of constant retort temperature (CRT) thermal processing and variable retort temperature (VRT) thermal processing, (3) to develop dynamic models for thermal processing using ANNs, and (4) to explore ANN-model-based analysis of critical control points for deviant thermal processes. As a preliminary research, neural network models were successfully developed for modeling of residence time distribution (RTD) under aseptic processing conditions. The main configuration parameters of neural networks such as the number of hidden layers and their neurons, learning runs, choice of transfer functions and learning rules were optimized. In order to provide experimental data needed for developing and testing of ANN models and GA optimization, a comprehensive finite difference computer simulation program for thermal processing was first developed in MS Visual Basic language, which could be used for simulating different thermal processes such as constant retort temperature (CRT) and variable retort temperature (VRT) thermal processing. The second objective was focused on developing modeling and optimization methods for CRT thermal processing using ANNs and GAs. The ANN models were developed for predicting process time, average quality retention, surface cook value, final temperature difference, lethality ratio, and equivalent energy consumption. Using this optimization program, the effects of process variables on the optimal retort temperature and the maximum average quality retention were investigated. The final part of the thesis research was focused on applying ANN methods for the analysis of critical control points (CCPs) for deviant thermal processes, one of the important steps required for developing hazard analysis of critical control points (HACCP) program. The results indicated that ANN models could be efficiently used for the analysis of CCPs of thermal processing. Such a concept can be expanded for developing an ANN based HACCP expert system for thermal processing. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Chen, Cuiren, 1962-</creator><contributor>Ramaswamy, H. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Food -- Packaging.</subject><subject>Food -- Effect of heat on.</subject><subject>Food -- Preservation.</subject><subject>Neural networks (Computer science)</subject><subject>Genetic algorithms.</subject><title>Application of computer simulation and artificial intelligence technologies for modeling and optimization of food thermal processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s1617879.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb3979844</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb007</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We attempt to answer the following key questions: What are the revaluation effects and the impacts on the cost of capital, volatility, and correlation with world market returns from stock market liberalization in emerging market countries? These questions have been studied extensively at the market-level, i.e. using country indices, but not at the firm level. In the market-level analysis, there is increasing concern whether the country indices are proper means to answer those questions, for example they may not represent the real holdings of foreign portfolio investors after liberalization. Indeed, foreign portfolio investors are known to prefer investment in large and well-known firms. Hence, the opening of capital markets should have a differential impact across securities depending on foreign investors' demand. In order to take into account the potentially different impacts caused by foreign investors' demand, we use individual firm data as well as market-level indices. Our analysis is based on the cross-sectional and time-series panel regression method. Our test results using country indices show statistically and economically significant revaluation effects, and increases in the cost of capital. While the stock market volatility increases, its correlation with world market return does not change after stock market liberalization. More important than these market-level findings, we report significantly different impacts of stock market liberalization, based on firm size, which is used as a proxy for foreign investors' demand. Large firms tend to exhibit large revaluation effects, insignificant change in the cost of capital, small increases in volatility, and increases in correlation with the world market from liberalization. Small firms show small revaluation effects, increases in the cost of capital, large increases in volatility and decreases in correlation with world market returns after liberalization. Our results have important implications for international investors seeking to manage their global exposure as well as for policy makers considering capital market liberalization.</description><creator>Chung, Hyunchul, 1965-</creator><contributor>Christoffersen, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Errunza, Vihang (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Investments, Developing country.</subject><subject>Economic indicators.</subject><subject>Capital costs.</subject><subject>Corporations -- Valuation.</subject><title>The impacts of stock market liberalization in emerging markets : looking beyond country indices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v955c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb007</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386m06x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Quebec, bacterial leaf spot of lettuce was observed for the first time in 1994. Since this first mention, the disease has been observed each year and the severity varied with environmental conditions. Little information was available on this disease because until recently it was only sporadically observed around the world following the first mention in 1918. In this project, we found that two groups of Xanthomonas caused the bacterial leaf spot of lettuce according to the BIOLOG profiles. From the results of strain characterization, a semi-selective medium has been developed to detect and quantify X. campestris pv. vitians. This medium is made of maltose, tryptone, methyl green, phosphate salts, amoxicillin, cephalothin, cycloheximide and trace elements. It allowed us to carry out studies on the ecology of the pathogen and on the disease epidemiology. The effect of weather conditions on bacterial population size and the bacterial leaf spot development has been studied. Weather parameters influencing the bacterial population were the number of hours with temperature higher than 28°C, the number of hours with wind velocity lower than 1 km per hour, the number of hours with relative humidity lower than 45% and the minimum relative humidity. The weather parameters that significantly discriminated between disease increase categories were the mean solar radiation, the number of hours with relative humidity higher than 90%, the mean relative humidity and the maximum temperature. Looking at the relationship between X. campestris pv. vitians population size and host plant development, it was shown that both bacterial population size and disease severity increased with leaf age. Mathematical models were developed to show these relationships. This information will be useful in disease management to decide when to apply bactericides and when to harvest. Finally, an exploratory study was conducted looking at the effects of nutrients on the size of saprophytic bacterial</description><creator>Toussaint, Vicky.</creator><contributor>Paulitz, Tim C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Lettuce -- Diseases and pests -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Leaf spots -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Xanthomonas campestris -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Ecology of Xanthomonas campestris pv. vitians in relation to development of bacterial leaf spot of lettuce by Vicky Toussaint.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xw68x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m06x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wr95p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Arbuscular mycorrhizal (AM) fungi have been living in association with land plants for at least 400 million years. Because they are obligate symbionts, the study of AM symbiosis has focused primarily on its plant host and progress in the molecular biology of AM fungi has been very slow. Using two different approaches, library screening and direct PCR-based assays, genetic information of AM fungi was compared across isolates and species. This allowed the study of novel DNA regions previously unexplored in AM fungi. The following species were investigated: Glomus intraradices, Glomus mosseae, Gigaspora margarita, Scutellospora calospora, Acaulospora scrobiculata and Entrophosphora colombiana. In the first approach, using in vitro grown G. intraradices, a DNA extraction protocol was developed for the construction of a partial genomic library. This library was screened for the presence of microsatellite-containing loci. PCR primers were designed based on five identified loci. Two of these loci were monomorphic for all isolates and species. The second approach used a combination of degenerate and specific primers for fungal chitin synthase genes to explore the variability of this gene family in AM fungi. A total of 21 AM sequences were isolated and sequenced, covering class I and II chitin synthases. RT-PCR with G. intraradices revealed differential expression of chitin synthases in spores and mycelium, as compared to mycorrhized roots. In addition, using primers designed from a highly conserved sequence for plant resistance genes, classical PCR and RT-PCR allowed the detection of a genomic sequence and its cDNA counterpart encoding a putative serine/lysine rich protein in G. intraradices. We have thus investigated genetic variability in AM fungi in functional genes as well as in repetitive DNA regions. Study of gene expression was also possible using in-vitro grown G. intraradices.</description><creator>Ubalijoro, Eliane.</creator><contributor>Smith, Donald L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Vesicular-arbuscular mycorrhizas -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Glomus intraradices -- Molecular genetics.</subject><title>Study of the arbuscular mycorrhizal fungus Glomus intraradices at the molecular level</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3656890.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wr95p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cf97j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Conventional transmission Mossbauer, selective excitation double Mossbauer (SEDM), and zero-field muon spin relaxation (ZF-muSR) spectroscopy were used to identify static and dynamic magnetic disorder. With the construction of an efficient SEDM spectrometer, a consistent description of static magnetic disorder in an amorphous alloy (a-Fe80B 20) was developed using transmission Mossbauer and SEDM spectroscopy. Both methods measure the effects of the random static distribution of local magnetic environments around the Mossbauer nuclei. Magnetic fine particle systems (Fe3O4 ferrofluids, polysaccharide iron complex) were examined using transmission Mossbauer spectroscopy, and a model was developed that describes the entire range of dynamic magnetic behavior, from blocked moments on towards collective excitations and superparamagnetic moments. SEDM has measured 180° moment flips in the ferrofluids, determining a model independent relaxation rate of superparamagnetic moments. With the spectral signatures of static and dynamic magnetic phenomena identified, SEDM spectroscopy has been used to unambiguously verify the existence (a-Fe 92Zr8) and absence (Fe65Ni35) of magnetic relaxation in chemically disordered alloys. Additionally, the static and dynamic disorder in a magnetic fine particle system (a polysaccharide iron complex) and a frustrated magnet system (a-FexZr100- x), have been measured with ZF-muSR spectroscopy. The effects of collective excitations have been independently verified with ZF-muSR and moment fluctuation rates are in agreement with transmission Mossbauer spectra fit results. Two magnetic transitions have been identified with ZF-muSR in the a-FexZr100- x system, one at TC and another at Txy corresponding to transverse spin freezing, in both static and fluctuating magnetic components of muSR spectra. SEDM has been used to verify the existence of a fluctuation peak at T xy, and the time-dependent hyperfine interactions due to transverse spin freezin</description><creator>Van Lierop, Johan.</creator><contributor>Ryan, D. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Separation of static and dynamic disorder in magnetic materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b04w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cf97j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02870x62h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Canada, the control of relative humidity is a key issue in greenhouse production as it has a direct and significant effect on dehumidification cost, crop quality and yield. Experiments were carried out to measure plant transpiration rate and fruit yield under four different ambient water vapour pressure deficits. Four identical greenhouses were used to produce tomatoes (Lycopersicon esculentum Mill.) under four different regimes of water vapour pressure deficit (VPD). Dehumidification costs were highly correlated to VPD: low VPD produced low transpiration requiring little dehumidification. Thus, managing plant transpiration can lead to a more efficient use of transpiration for crop production. A model was developed to optimise greenhouse climatic conditions to maximize net profit. The present project validated this model, and compared measured values with those calculated from the transpiration and condensation sub-models and from the entire model itself. The sub-models and entire model proved to be accurate within 3% when used to simulate ideal climatic conditions for periods of one week or longer. Model sensitivity was greatest for exterior temperature because this factor affects heating costs without increasing yields. Using winter climatic conditions typical of Quebec City, Canada, three greenhouse climate control strategies were simulated and compared with respect to energy consumption and yield of a tomato crop. The merit and drawback of each strategy are discussed.</description><creator>Trigui, Maher.</creator><contributor>Barrington, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Greenhouses -- Environmental engineering -- Computer simulation.</subject><subject>Tomatoes -- Climatic factors.</subject><title>Strategy for the optimal climate control of greenhouse tomatoes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j052t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870x62h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fq579</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Epithelial (E)-cadherin is a calcium-dependent cell adhesion molecule. As a crucial component of epithelial cell adherens junctions, E-cadherin is responsible for the establishment of cell polarity and the maintenance of tissue integrity. Appropriately regulated E-cadherin expression is essential for morphogenesis and its misregulation is an important factor in the progression of cancer. The regulation of E-cadherin expression by 17beta-estradiol was analyzed in human breast carcinoma MCF-7 cells. These cells are well-differentiated and display many epithelial characteristics. MCF-7 cell E-cadherin mRNA and protein levels were increased in response to 17beta-estradiol, but levels of the E-cadherin associated cytoplasmic proteins alpha-catenin, beta-catenin and plakoglobin were unchanged. Culture of MCF-7 cells in estrogen-deprived conditions, or in the presence of anti-estrogens led to an altered morphology, reminiscent of a decreased polarization. This was evidenced by changes in the subcellular localization of E-cadherin, beta-catenin and plakoglobin, as well as rearrangement of the actin-based cytoskeleton. Futhermore, the packing of the MCF-7 monolayer was less ordered under these conditions. The cells reverted to a well organized phenotype upon treatment with 17beta-estradiol. These data show that E-cadherin expression in a mammary epithelial-derived cell line is estrogen-responsive, and that changes in the estrogenic environment have consequences upon cell shape and monolayer packing. These findings suggest a novel role for estrogens in the regulation of mammary gland cadherins which has not previously been appreciated. The mechanism of E-cadherin gene regulation by 17beta-estradiol was studied using promoter-reporter assays and electrophoretic mobility shift assays. A 380 by fragment of the E-cadherin gene promoter was found to be sufficient to drive estrogen-responsive expression in MCF-7 cells. Mutagenesis studies revealed a non-consensus estrogen response element (ERE) within this fragment to be important for regulation by estrogen. Furthermore, the E-cadherin ERE specifically interacted with purified recombinant estrogen receptor (ER) alpha and beta in vitro, supporting the hypothesis that regulation of E-cadherin gene expression by estrogen occurs by direct interaction of the ER and the incomplete ERE in the gene promoter. The involvement of the ER in E-cadherin gene expression provides a functional explanation for the concomitant loss of both ER and E-cadherin expression manifested in aggressive breast cancers. The activity of the 380 by fragment of the E-cadherin promoter and its stimulation by 17beta-estradiol were compromised by overexpression of ErbB2 tyrosine kinase receptor in MCF-7 cells. The ErbB2 receptor is frequently overexpressed in advanced stage breast cancer, and signalling via this tyrosine kinase is implicated in the progression of the disease. The suppression of 17beta-estradiol's effect on E-cadherin promoter activity by ErbB2 may represent a functional intersection between the ErbB2 and estrogen-dependent signalling pathways. In summary, these studies demonstrate that alterations in estrogen levels can have profound consequences on E-cadherin expression and cell morphology. Furthermore, the expression of E-cadherin appears to be under the direct control of estrogens by virtue of the presence of a non-consensus ERE in the gene promoter.</description><creator>Rowlands, Tracey Michelle.</creator><contributor>Farookhi, Riaz (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Meterissian, Sarkis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Mechanism and consequences of E-cadherin induction by estrogen</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161788k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fq579</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547t122</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation analyses the convergence of primitivism and nationalism in late-nineteenth and early-twentieth century French and Russian art. The discourse of primitivism has yielded a number of critical studies focusing on the artistic appropriation of aesthetics derived from "tribal" arts, Asian arts, medieval icons, outsider art, and peasant arts and crafts. Within that scholarship, modern European art that appropriates the aesthetics of folk arts and themes of the peasantry is frequently considered to be representative of national identity and myth. The artistic elucidation of the peasantry as emblematic of national identity combined with their incorporation into primitivism produces a tension that complicates the conventional, binary structure of the discourse. It is therefore necessary to examine artistic expressions of national myth and the peasantry's absorption into the primitivist discourse, as this indicates a critical point at which issues of nationalism and primitivism converge. In the cultural realm, that juncture is located in the artistic idealisation of peasant cultures, which is indicative of a mythical state of being from which national identity could be rearticulated. The myth of the peasantry as developed in nineteenth century European thought centres around the premise that rural populations were an unchanging element of society whose traditional customs, religious beliefs, and modes of production contrasted sharply with the accelerated changes in urban culture. A critical examination of selected paintings by the French artist Paul Gauguin (1848--1903), the Russian Neoprimitivist Natalia Goncharova (1881--1962), and the French Fauve painter Othon Friesz (1879--1949) within their specific, social contexts reveals the ways in which the modern, artistic maintenance of the rural myth elucidates current political and social issues of nationalism. This underscores the peasantry's symbolism within the nation as representative of a national, collective consciousness and ancestry. The peasantry's incorporation into the primitivist discourse and the cultural articulation of the rural myth are revealed in the paintings The Vision After the Sermon (1888), Yellow Christ (1889), Fruit Harvest (1909), and Autumn Work (1908). The paintings and their respective social contexts situate the peasantry both as constructions within the primitivist discourse and symbols of national identity, thereby disrupting the structure of alterity upon which primitivism is predicated.</description><creator>Roy, Nina Tamara.</creator><contributor>Ross, Christine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Primitivism in art -- France.</subject><subject>Nationalism and art -- Russia.</subject><subject>Primitivism in art -- Russia.</subject><subject>Nationalism and art -- France.</subject><subject>Art, French -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Art, Russian -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Art, French -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Art, Russian -- 19th century.</subject><title>Harvest of memories : national identity and primitivism in French and Russian art, 1888-1909</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074w88s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547t122</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q318s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The comprehension of illustrations and text was studied from a cognitive discourse processing perspective. Typically, learners must construct conceptual knowledge representations that integrate different types of information from diverse sources and modalities (e.g., text and illustrations). Currently, little is known about how such integrative processing works in "multimedia" learning situations. This study focused on the semantic representations that low prior knowledge learners constructed as they read from text and static illustrations presenting multiple types of information (structural, functional, and energy) describing a functional system. Both the text and the illustrations were modified so that structural information would be highlighted over other information types. Participants were twenty-four undergraduate engineering students who had little prior knowledge of the target domain (the human visual system), but were experienced in learning about functional systems using texts and illustrations. Six students were randomly assigned to each of four presentation conditions: (a) text only, (b) illustrations only, (c) text with controlled access to illustrations, or (d) text with free access to illustrations. The materials were presented individually in a computer environment which recorded and timed all information accessed. Participants provided on-line interpretations as they read, post-input verbal and visual free recalls of the materials, and responses to integrative comprehension questions. Planned comparisons were used to contrast: (a) the two text with illustrations groups, (b) the combined text with illustrations groups to the text only group, (c) the text with illustrations groups to the illustrations only group, and (d) the processing of information which was privileged (structure) to other information. The results indicated that the text and illustrations each provided mutually constraining information that functioned together to support comprehension. Illustrations aided the construction and elaboration of mental models by providing an external context that supported more active conceptual processing and integration of information. Text aided both literal and high level comprehension by communicating the meaning of illustrations and signaling what information was important. These results support perspectives on situated learning which emphasize the role that discourse plays in comprehending knowledge in environments involving more than one external information source. Future research is recommended to extend such findings to other populations of learners and materials.</description><creator>Roy, Marguerite Claire.</creator><contributor>Frederiksen, Carl H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Integration (Theory of knowledge)</subject><subject>Multimedia systems.</subject><subject>Visual education.</subject><title>Comprehension and learning through multimedia : integrative processing of text and illustrations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr65r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q318s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wr96z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation looks at the way in which the shifting configurations of nation, gender and future in Micah might affect readers' positioning as subjects---that is their positioning as agents of speech and action---in a way that might engender resistance to oppression. It is suggested that if readers of Micah identify with the ambiguous and shifting national and gendered identities, within the context of the book's visions for the future, they are urged to recognize contradictions within their own subjectivity. This has the possible effect of shifting the reader's pre-formed subject position, or at least interrogating it, a process which may allow for resistance to oppression. The theoretical problematic for this approach originates within recent discussions of textual determinacy in biblical and literary criticism: "is it the text or the reader that controls meaning?" The work of theorist Homi K. Bhabha on the negotiation of cultural difference in colonial and post-colonial contexts is used to engage the position---common to much contemporary literary and cultural criticism---that the reader comes to the text already formed as a subject within ideology, and that this will necessarily affect or control the way she reads the text. Zizek's reading of Althusser through Lacan is taken as a starting point for an understanding of "subject formation" thus conceived. This position, which tends toward the fixity of the subject, can be seen as analogous to Bhabha's discussion of the role of "pedagogical objects and discourses" (cultural icons, stereotypes, formative events) within the construction of national identity. By way of contrast, Bhabha's key concepts---hybridity, third space, outside the sentence, liminal identification, time-lag, agency in indeterminacy; in short performative practice---envision an identification with difference in a way that allows for the subject to be repositioned and for meaning to be reinscribed. Bhabha's notions of pedagogical object and</description><creator>Runions, Erin.</creator><contributor>Culley, Robert C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Bhabha, Homi K., 1949-</subject><title>Reading gender, nation and future vision in Micah : reconfiguring the reader as subject</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc333.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wr96z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547t14m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The chemical evolution of peridotites and felsic rocks included in or adjacent to them, and fluids during the hydrothermal alteration of these rocks is the subject of this study. Experiments using a flow-through hydrothermal apparatus, and studies of natural samples from the JM Asbestos chrysotile deposit in the Asbestos ophiolite, Quebec, were the means by which the various topics of this thesis were investigated. Open-system fluid-rock interaction was studied by flowing deionized water or a 0.1 m CaCl2 solution through olivine (Fo91) and lherzolite at a temperature of 300°C and a pressure of 300 bars. During these experiments, the original minerals (olivine, orthopyroxene and clinopyroxene) were altered to an assemblage, which consisted of serpentine-group minerals (conical, polygonal, and cylindrical fibers, and plates), brucite and magnetite. Reaction of lherzolite with deionized water and thermodynamic modelling indicate that the highest pH and calcium concentration are attained when pyroxenes are present in the unaltered rock, and that these parameters are at maximum in the presence of the buffering assemblage serpentine + brucite + diopside. Alteration of olivine by 0.1 m CaCl2 aqueous solution does not lead to the formation of secondary calcium phases. These results, supported by thermodynamic calculations, suggest that calcium-rich fluids can circulate through forsteritic olivine-rich lithologies without inducing calcium metasomatism. In the JM Asbestos mine, these Si-Al lithologies are largely felsic dykes, which, based on geological relationships, are interpreted to have been emplaced after serpentinization of the host peridotites began, but before obduction of the Asbestos ophiolite onto the Laurentian continental margin. Slates underlying and in thrust contact with serpentinite are also locally rodingitized. Mass balance calculations suggest that the calcium responsible for the rodingitization of the slates may have been derived locally, whereas the calcium responsible for the rodingitization of the felsic dykes was most probably derived from a source remote from the dykes. The strong dilution in rodingites and nephrites of the low-solubility minor and traces elements P, Cr and Zr suggests that very large amounts of fluids were involved in calc-silicate metasomatism of the felsic dykes and adjacent serpentinites. The absence of CO2 and presence of hydrocarbons (alkanes from methane to pentane) in the fluid inclusions of both episodes is an indication that the fluids responsible for calc-silicate alteration were derived from the serpentinites. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Normand, Charles, 1963-</creator><contributor>Williams-Jones, Anthony E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>Experimental and field investigations of serpentinization and rodingitization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b495m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547t14m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708z412</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Evidence to date remains equivocal regarding the association between tattooing and various transfusion-transmitted diseases (TTDs). Objectives. To determine whether there is an association between the presence or specific characteristics of ornamental tattoos and one or more of the following infections: HBV, HCV, HIV, Chagas' disease, and syphilis. Methods. Type of study: Hospital-based cross-sectional pair-matched study. Setting: Teaching hospital and blood bank in a Brazilian town. Study population: Adults 18 years of age and over who were admitted to the hospital, attended the outpatient clinic or volunteered to donate blood. Exclusion criteria: medical conditions causing transitory or permanent intellectual impairment; physical impossibility to provide blood specimens or information. Exposure of interest: Having at least one permanent ornamental tattoo. Covariates: Several socio-demographic and behavioral characteristics. Outcomes of interest: Presence of serological markers for one or more of the following infections: HIV, HBV, HCV, Chagas' disease and syphilis. Matching variables: Individuals with tattoos (exposed group) were pair-matched to individuals without tattoos (unexposed group) on age, sex, and main clinical complaint. Assessment of the exposure: Interview and inspection of the tattoo(s). Assessment of the outcomes: Positive or negative laboratory findings as follows for each infection: HBV - HBsAg and anti-HBc (ELISA); HCV - anti-HCV (ELISA); HIV - anti-HIV (ELISA); Chagas' disease - anti-Trypanosoma cruzi (IFA, ELISA and/or IHA); syphilis - VDRL. Results. 345 subjects were included in the study, 182 with tattoos and 163 without tattoos. Having a tattoo was associated with HCV (adjusted OR: 6.41; 95% CI: 1.29, 31.84), and with having at least one positive test for any TTD (adjusted OR: 2.05; 95% CI: 1.11, 3.81). Among the subjects with tattoos associations were found between an increasing number of tattoos and HBV infection (adjusted OR: 2.04 (95% CI: 1.80, 9.97) for two tattoos and 3.48 (95% CI: 1.41, 8.58) for three or more tattoos), having a nonprofessional tattoo and testing positive for at least one TTD (adjusted OR: 3.25; 95% CI: 1.39, 7.59), and having three or more tattoos and testing positive for at least one TTD (adjusted OR: 2.98; 1.03, 8.64). Conclusion. The presence of tattoo(s) may be useful in certain settings for the screening of blood donors, mostly because tattoos are associated with good indicators of TTD such as intravenous drug use.</description><creator>Nishioka, Sergio de Andrade.</creator><contributor>Gyorkos, Theresa W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Tattoos as indicators of transfusion-transmitted diseases in Brazil : a matched hospital-based cross-sectional study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng312.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z412</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jw28t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Taking as a case study the Theatre-Italien, here considered both as a particular theatrical practice and as a specific stage in Paris---one of the most popular at the time---this dissertation asks what role this theatre played in the novel competition of discourses which characterized political culture in the era of Revolutions. All too often, historians have overestimated print culture as the main medium through which discourses were produced in the eighteenth century, and this despite the fact that theatre played a fundamental role in the public life of this period. Furthermore, when theatre is studied, historians emphasize too often the written form of the plays. The dissertation's structure seeks to underline the specificity of the cultural practice represented by the theatre. The discrepancies between the meaning of a play written by a particular author and the same play as it is performed on stage are emphasized. Political messages emerge out of the language of the actors and actresses without any possibility to control them, so that the players become, in effect, co-authors of the play. Similarly, the variety of the nature of the audience and the way in which it becomes at once judge, co-author and co-actor make the public, neither intangible nor invisible, but simply gathered, a crucial feature of this cultural practice which allows us to argue that theatre was actually a very bad instrument of propaganda. Instead, theatre can be seen at the time to be a public scene of immediate political debate. The conflicting opinions expressed there turn theatre not into the minor of political reality intended by various regimes confronted to the diversity of the polity---what some people have called "a school for the people"---but rather as the mirror of the reality experienced by a large number of Parisians at the time. It is in this sense that we relate the theatrical practices studied with the concept of public spirit, expressing the people's understanding of the general interest, instead of that of public opinion, expressing the unified message imposed by a dominant political group.</description><creator>Nadeau, Martin.</creator><contributor>Boulle, Pierre H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Theater and society -- France -- History -- 18th century.</subject><subject>Theater -- France -- History -- 18th century.</subject><title>Theatre et esprit public : le role du Theatre-Italien dans la culture politique parisienne a l'ere des revolutions (1770-1799)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hk827.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jw28t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s409x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A comprehensive methodology to physically and numerically model upsetting in cold heading was developed. The physical model was a Drop Weight Test with a guided pocket-die set capable of approximating industrial cold heading conditions. The results show that the test is sensitive to the critical parameters for cold heading. These include surface quality, residual element level, nitrogen content, microstructure, decarburization, and specimen geometry. The test is capable of assessing the fracture behavior of cold heading materials. One goal of the study was to reveal differences in fracture behavior with varying steel sources. Accordingly, the matrix of test materials consisted of grade 1038 steels from three different steel sources. Material preparation and conditioning of test materials approximated industrial procedures for cold heading materials. These procedures included hot rolling, controlled rod cooling, descaling, straightening, lime coating and lubricating, and wire drawing. Spheroidization of test specimens was performed in an industrial batch furnace using an industrial heat treatment cycle. A finite element program (FEM) enabled the simulation of upsetting in cold heading. The inputs required to model the cold heading process include flow stress behavior and friction conditions representative of cold heading. These inputs were obtained using the CANMET Cam Plastometer and the Friction Ring Test. The Cockcroft and Latham fracture constants for an as-rolled and a spheroidize annealed 1038 material were computed by FEM modeling and the critical values were calibrated using the Drop Weight Test. The fracture criterion constant was found to be independent of strain path for upsetting in cold heading and thus is material-related.</description><creator>Nickoletopoulos, Nicholas.</creator><contributor>Yue, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Jonas, J. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Nemes, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Physical and numerical modeling of steel wire rod fracture during upsetting for cold heading operations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p874q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s409x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34950</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>