<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:04:04Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):44550" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w37637271</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The coming into force in March 2006 of the Convention on International Interests in Mobile Equipment ("Cape Town Convention") and its protocol related to aircraft equipment ("Aircraft Protocol") established a new international legal regime to facilitate the cross boarder financing of mobile equipment in general and aircraft frames and engines in particular. The implementation of a new legal regime invevitably brings with it a transitional period of uncertainty. Legal and business actors need time and experience to fully assimilate the new framework. The transitional challenge is magnified exponentially when the vehicle of reform is an international convention intended to have global scope. The wide diversity of legal traditions and business practices among States make the assimilation process particularly challenging. The challenge is even more acute in the case of the Cape Town Convention and Aircraft Protocol. These instruments straddle property, civil procedure, creditor and insolvency laws, areas of private law which traditionally have been particularly resistant to global harmonization efforts. In addition, the Convention establishes a new global institution - an international property rights registry - the first such attempt in private law. This thesis has three intertwined goals. The first is to show that the Cape Town Convention and Aircraft Protocol are not neutral to legal tradition. Rather, they are primarily rooted in the statutory regimes adopted by the common law states and provinces of the United States and Canada over the latter half of the twentieth century. Secondly, this thesis seeks to ease the transition challenge this presents for civil law lawyers by giving a comparative overview of the Convention and Protocol which takes into account those aspects which civil law jurists may have difficulties in understanding. The third and final goal of this thesis is to contribute a deeper substantive understanding of the Convention and Protocol to the existing literature, much of which to date has been concerned - understandably - with general or preliminary implementation issues.</description><description>L'entrée en vigueur en mars 2006 de la Convention relative aux garanties internationales portant sur des matériels d'équipement mobiles ("Convention du Cap") et de son Protocole relatif aux matériels d'équipement aéronautiques ("Protocole") en a établi un nouveau cadre juridique international simplifiant le financement transfrontalier d'équipement mobiles en général et des aéronefs et moteurs d'avion en particulier. La mise en oevre d'un nouveau cadre juridique apporte inévitablement une période passagère d'incertitude. Les acteurs juridiques et économiques ont besoin de temps et d'expérience afin de s'adapter à ce nouveau cadre, en particulier lorsque celui-ci a un impact mondial, les différences entre systèmes juridiques rendant plus compliqué cette mise en oevre. Dans le cas de la Convention du Cap et de son Protocole l'ajustement est encore plus difficile. Ces textes concernent les droits mobiliers, des créanciers, des procédures civiles et des procédures d'insolvabilité, des domaines juridiques qui, dans le passé, ont été résistantes à une harmonisation globale. En outre, la Convention du Cap établit une nouvelle institution globale - un registre international pour les biens aéronautiques - la première dans le droit international privé. Cette thèse a trois objectifs interconnectés. Le premier est de montrer que la Convention du Cap et son Protocole ne sont pas neutres en termes de traditions légales. Ils prennent leurs racines dans les codifications de droit adoptées par les pays du "Common Law" et les provinces des Etats-Unis et du Canada durant la deuxième moitié du 20ème siècle. Le second cherche à faciliter la compréhension pour les juristes en droit civil en leur donnant un aperçu comparatif de la Convention du Cap et de son Protocole qui reposent sur des principes du "Common Law". Le dernier objectif de la thèse est de contribuer à approfondir la compréhension de la Convention du Cap et de son Protocole par rapport à la littérature existante, qui s'est - à bon droit - concentrée sur des questions relatives à leur mise en oevre.</description><creator>von Planta, Niclas</creator><contributor>Paul Stephen Dempsey (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>The aircraft protocol to the Cape Town Convention on Aircraft Financing: a civil lawyer's perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rk777.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w37637271</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gd417</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to investigate the interactional dynamics that occur when health-care professionals collaborate on a medical case. Social exchange theory and the literature on collaboration and teamwork provided the theoretical basis from which interaction was investigated. The participants in the study were 13 health-care professionals and one patient. They participated in two workshops during which they collaborated on an interprofessional care plan. Their interactions were audio-and video-taped. The recordings were transcribed and analyzed using the Roter Interaction Analysis System (RIAS), a widely used method developed for analyzing the dynamics of physician-patient interactions. The data were analyzed using chi-square standardized residuals. The study concluded that while the RIAS format was useful, the original RIAS categories needed to be extensively supplemented with items that specifically addressed the interprofessional interaction. An examination of the categories with variability indicated that the majority of the interactions were task-related and that the response patterns varied depending on whether the categories were grouped according to participant, workshop group, or profession. This study demonstrated that it is possible to assess the degree of interprofessionalism in interactions using a scenario that is more ecologically valid than that offered by attitude questionnaires completed individually. The study offers a methodology by which it might be possible to chart the growth of interprofessionalism in communication among medical and other professionals in the course their work.</description><description>Le but de la présente thèse est d'investiguer la dynamique interactive se produisant lorsque des professionnels de la santé collaborent dans un dossier médical. La théorie de l'échange social et la littérature sur la collaboration et le travail en équipe a servi de base théorique à partir de laquelle l'interaction a été investiguée. Treize professionnels de la santé ainsi qu'un patient ont participé à cette étude. Ces participants ont collaboré à établir un programme de soins interprofessionnels durant deux séances de travail. Leur interaction a été filmée et enregistrée. Les enregistrements vidéos et audio ont été retranscrits et analysés à l'aide du système d'analyse des interactions de Roter (RIAS), une méthode très usitée afin de développer une méthode pour analyser la dynamique des relations entre patient et docteur. Les données ont été analysées grâce à la méthode standardisée khi carré. La recherche a montré que, même si le RIAS demeure utile, les catégories initiales du RIAS exigeaient de vastes suppléments avec des items répondant spécifiquement à l'interaction interprofessionnelle. Un examen des catégories comportant des variables indique que la majorité des interactions était liée aux tâches et que les schémas des réponses variaient selon que les catégories étaient groupées en fonction du participant, des ateliers de groupes, ou de la profession. Cette étude a démontré qu'il est possible de déterminer le niveau d'interprofessionnalisme dans les interactions en utilisant un scénario qui est plus valide écologiquement que celui offert dans des questionnaires d'attitude  complétés individuellement. La thèse offre une méthodologie permettant de tenir compte de la croissance de l'interprofessionnalisme dans la communication entre professionnels de la santé ou d'autres secteurs dans le cadre de leur travail.</description><creator>Margison, Judith</creator><contributor>Bruce M Shore (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Education - Psychology</subject><title>Interactional dynamics of interprofessional collaboration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mj42t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gd417</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634411c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les déficits cognitifs contribuent de façon importante à l'handicap relié à la sclérose en plaque (SP), une des conditions neurologiques chroniques les plus communes chez les jeunes adultes. La présentation clinique des changements cognitifs chez les personnes atteintes de SP est unique en raison de la nature progressive de la maladie et de l'interaction entre les déficits cognitifs et les autres symptômes de la SP. Une évaluation adéquate des changements cognitifs est donc importante dans l'évaluation des personnes atteintes de la SP. L'objectif principal de cette étude est d'évaluer la stabilité, l'unidimensionalité et la hiérarchie des items de la mesure de perception du fonctionnement cognitif (Questionnaire sur les Déficits Perçus, PDQ), ainsi que d'explorer les différences de gendre dans les associations entre l'humeur, la fatigue et le fonctionnement cognitif chez les personnes atteintes de la SP. La perception du fonctionnement cognitif, le fonctionnement cognitif, ainsi que d'autres aspects cliniques ont été mesurés sur un échantillon, stratifié par centre, de 185 personnes atteintes de la SP.  L'analyse Rasch a été effectuée d'identifier la hierarchie des items du PDQ, de confirmer la structure factorielle, la  redondance des items, l'unidimensionalité, ainsi que pour examiner la stabilité des items. Un questionnaire de 11 items, le PDQ-Rasch, a été développé. Des modèles de régression linéaire ont servis à  identifier les corrélations entre les habilités cognitives perçues (PDQ) et les habiletés cognitives mesurées (par le PASAT). Les résultats du PDQ ont été expliqués par une humeur dépressive, la fatigue, le sexe féminin, et la douleur. De plus, l'humeur avait un effet plus fort sur les femmes que sur les hommes, dans les résultats du PDQ.  Les résultats du PASAT ont été prédits par le fonctionnement physique et la douleur.</description><description>Cognitive impairment is an important contributor to disability in multiple sclerosis (MS), one of the most common chronic neurological condition affecting young adults. The clinical presentation of cognitive changes in MS is unique given the progressive nature of the disease and the interaction between cognitive impairments and other MS symptoms. Appropriate evaluation of cognitive deficits is an important issue in assessment for persons with MS. The main objectives of this study are to provide a modern approach to assess stability, unidimentionality and item hierarchy of the Perceived Deficits Questionnaire (PDQ) for persons with MS and to estimate the extend to which there are gender differences in the associations of mood and fatigue with perceived cognitive function and with tested cognitive capacity in persons diagnosed with MS. A center-stratified sample of 185 persons with MS was assembled and participants were evaluated on both perceived and measured cognitive function, as well as other clinical aspects of the disease. To develop an interval-like measure, Rasch analysis was performed, which helped to identify the item hierarchy of PDQ, to confirm the factor structure, item fit and redundancy, unidimensionality, as well as to examine item stability. As a result, an 11-item questionnaire, the PDQ-Rasch was developed. Cognitive function was measured in two ways. The PDQ was used to assess self- perceptions and the PASAT was used to measure processing speed. Multiple linear regression models were used to identify correlates of perceived cognition and measured cognition. PDQ was explained by depressed mood, fatigue, female gender and pain. Furthermore, mood had a stronger effect among women than men on PDQ. PASAT was predicted by physical function and pain.</description><creator>Teng, Shang Yuan</creator><contributor>Nancy Mayo (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Susan Bartlett (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Occupational Health and Therapy</subject><title>Assessing cognitive impairment in Multiple Sclerosis: effect of gender, mood and time</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx46n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634411c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354f67q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> Mon projet situe le poème Apirāmi Antāti à la croisée entre la dévotion populaire Tamoule (bhakti), une forme de Tantra d'Inde du Sud connu sous le nom de Śrīvidyā, et le monde social, culturel et rituel de la caste supérieure (Brahmane) qui ont engendré le texte. En reliant une analyse intertextuelle et ethnographique, je démontre que l'apparition simultanée de thèmes Tantrique avec des thèmes de la vie familiale Brahmanique dans le texte tend vers la Śrīvidyā, une pratique qui intègre des pratiques Tantriques ésotériques avec un comportement social de la caste supérieure Brahmanique. Mon association entre Apirāmi Antāti et Śrīvidyā est justifié par une historisation critique du Apirāmi Antāti qui situe le texte dans le milieu Tamoul Brahmane Tantrique émergent à la court de Tanjavur au début du dix-huitième siècle. Finalement, il se passe quelque chose au sujet de ce milieu, le tombeau de la déesse, et son époux à Tirukkadaiyur qui a eu une valeur durable pour le plus grand groupe de Tamouls Brahmanes appelé Smārthas. En utilisant des données ethnographiques, la dernière partie de cette thèse examine le rappel contemporain de ce poème pour les fidèles de la caste supérieure dévoués à la déesse. Je discute du rite de passage (samskāra), nommé śatābhiekam, qui se déroule à Tirukkadaiyur, et qui permet au poème et à sa déesse d'être identifié aux valeurs culturelles Smārtha Brahmanes</description><description> My project locates the 18th century Tamil poem Apirāmi Antāti at the interstices of popular Tamil devotion (bhakti), a form of South Indian Tantra known as Śrīvidyā, and the upper-caste (Brahmin) social, cultural, and ritual worlds that engender the text. Bringing together inter-textual, and ethnographic analysis, I argue that the simultaneous appearance of Tantric themes, alongside themes of Brahmanic domesticity in the text point towards Śrīvidyā, a practice that integrates esoteric Tantric practice with uppercaste Brahmanic social behaviour. My linkage of the Apirāmi Antāti with Śrīvidyā is substantiated by a critical historcization of the Apirāmi Antāti that locates the text in the emergent Tamil Brahmin Tantric milieu at the Tanjavur court in the early eighteenth century. Finally, there is something about this milieu, the shrine of the goddess, and her consort at Tirukkadaiyur that has had an enduring value for the largest group of Tamil Brahmins known as Smārtas. Using ethnographic data the later part of this thesis examines the contemporary appeal of this poem to upper-caste devotees of the goddess. I discuss a rite-of-passage (samskāra), known as śatābhisekam, which is performed at Tirukkadaiyur, and allows the poem and its goddess to become identified with Smārta Brahmin cultural values.</description><creator>Figlarz, Marissa</creator><contributor>Davesh Soneji (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Religion, General</subject><title>A song to "The beautiful Goddess": Text, ritual, and devotion in the «Apirami Antati»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hf952.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f67q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xj123</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une terre acide pauvre en éléments nutritifs provenents de Resolution Island, Nunavut, a été contaminé par des hydrocarbures pétroliers durant les opérations d'une ancienne base de radar entre 1954 - 1973. Deux réservoirs mésocosmes contenant ~200 kg de terre de Resolution Island contaminée par des hydrocarbures ont été sujet à un profil saisonnier de gel et dégel conçu pour simuler les conditions du sol in situ après la saison estivale d'exploitation. La terre dans un réservoir a été traite avec 100.0 mg N kg-1 de terre et  2.0 g CaCO3 kg-1 de terre, tandis que le deuxième réservoir n'a reçu aucun traitement. La biodégradation d'hydrocarbures aliphatiques (nC10 à nC16) a été stimulée par l'ajout d'éléments nutritifs après une période initiale d'acclimatisation, qui correspondait à une croissance des populations Actinomycetales et Rhodanobacter de 2.4ºC à -2.1ºC. Ces populations Actinomycetales et Rhodanobacter ont probablement représenté des K-stratégistes hydrocarbonoclastes et des r-stratégistes utilisant des métabolites d'hydrocarbures, respectivement. De plus, la communauté originale indigène d'archaea était apparentée aux oxydeurs d'ammoniac Thaumachaeota, mais n'était pas associée avec la biodégradation d'hydrocarbures. Deux isolats Burkholderia diazotrophiques de la terre ont aussi dégradé du 14C-naphtalène et/ou du 14C-phénanthrène à -5°C.</description><description>Nutrient-deficient, acidic soil from Resolution Island, Nunavut was contaminated with petroleum hydrocarbons during operations from 1954-1973 at a former radar station. Two mesocosm tanks containing ~200 kg hydrocarbon-contaminated Resolution Island soil each were exposed to a seasonal freezing profile designed to simulate in situ ground conditions after the summer landfarming season. Soil from one tank was treated with 100.0 mg N kg-1 soil and 2.0 g CaCO3 kg-1 soil, while the second mesocosm remained untreated. Aliphatic nC10-nC16 hydrocarbon biodegradation was enhanced by soil treatments after an initial acclimation period, which corresponded to Actinomycetales and Rhodanobacter population growth from 2.4ºC to -2.1ºC. These Actinomycetales and Rhodanobacter populations probably represented hydrocarbonoclastic K-strategists and hydrocarbon metabolite-utilizing r-strategists, respectively. Additionally, a novel indigenous archaeal community was related to Thaumachaeota ammonia oxidizers but not associated with hydrocarbon biodegradation. Two diazotrophic Burkholderia isolates from the soil also degraded 14C-naphthalene and/or 14C-phenanthrene at -5°C.</description><creator>Klemm, Sara</creator><contributor>Lyle Whyte (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Subhasis Ghoshal (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>Microbial responses to the biostimulation of Subartic hydrocarbon-contaminated soil under seasonal freeze-thaw conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gt135.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xj123</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g317d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: Les immigrants adultes sont peut-être sous-immunisés dans leurs pays d'origine.  Nous avons effectué une étude de la prévalence de la susceptibilité au tétanos et à la diphtérie et nous avons examiné les indicateurs potentiels de cette susceptibilité. Méthodes: 1480 adultes ayant immigré récemment ont été recrutés à Montréal entre 2002 et 2004. Nous avons obtenus des informations sociodémographiques et l'histoire de vaccination et nous avons mesuré les anticorps sériques contre le tétanos et la diphtérie avec le test EIA; la susceptibilité était définie comme ≤0.15 IU/ml et  ≤0.10 IU/ml, respectivement. Résultats: Quarante-cinq pour cent (95% IC, 42%-48%) des immigrants, avec un âge moyen de 31 +/- 8.6 ans, n'étaient pas immuns soit contre le tétanos ou la diphtérie, avec des variations selon la région d'origine (23%-79%). Trente-deux pour cent (95% IC, 30%-34%) étaient susceptibles au tétanos et la susceptibilité augmentait avec l'âge.  La susceptibilité à la diphtérie était moins prévalente [26% (95% IC, 24%-28%)] et diminuait avec l'âge. Conclusions: Plusieurs immigrants adultes bénéficieraient du vaccin contre le tétanos et la diphtérie.  La susceptibilité au tétanos suggère la présence de sous-vaccination, tandis que la susceptibilité à la diphtérie, qui diminue avec l'âge, suggère que l'immunité a été stimulée par la transmission continue de l'infection dans certains pays d'origine.</description><description>Background:  Adult immigrants may have been under-immunized in their countries of origin.  We estimated the seroprevalence and examined risk factors for susceptibility to diphtheria and tetanus. Methods: 1480 newly-arrived adult immigrants were recruited in Montreal, 2002-2004. We collected socio-demographic information and vaccination history, and measured serum antibodies to tetanus and diphtheria by EIA to identify susceptibility, defined as ≤0.15 IU/ml and ≤0.10 IU/ml, respectively. Results: 45% (95% CI, 42%-48%) of immigrants, mean age 31 +/- 8.6 years, lacked immunity to either tetanus or diphtheria, ranging by region of origin (23%-79%). 32% (95% CI, 30%-34%) were susceptible to tetanus and susceptibility increased with age.  Susceptibility to diphtheria was less prevalent [26% (95% CI, 24%-28%)] and decreased with age. Conclusions: Many adult immigrants would benefit from diphtheria/tetanus vaccine.  Susceptibility to tetanus suggests under-vaccination, while decreasing susceptibility to diphtheria with age suggests that immunity has been boosted from ongoing transmission in some countries of origin.</description><creator>Gingrich, Penny</creator><contributor>Kevin Schwartzman (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Christina Greenaway (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Susceptibility to tetanus and diphtheria in recently arrived adult immigrants and refugees to Montreal, Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494895p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g317d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741s23v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis aims to determine whether international gestational surrogacy contracts are exploitative, and whether they should be prohibited. I chose a group of women working as surrogates at Kaival Maternity Home and Surgical Hospital, in Anand, Gujarat, India as a study group.  After examining their life circumstances, I argue that these women live in unjust circumstances caused by institutional sexism and poverty. I critically assess arguments launched against surrogacy, organ trade, and prostitution and find that none of these are sufficient for demonstrating that contracts involving the sale of the body are necessarily exploitative.  I find that surrogacy is exploitative because of a complex set of social conditions.  Further, the contracts are beneficial to both the woman acting as surrogate and to the couple hiring her. I conclude that international gestational surrogacy is exploitative yet mutually beneficial, and prohibiting surrogacy would be harmful unless accompanied by drastic social change.</description><description>Cette thèse vise à savoir si les contrats internationaux de maternité de substitution sont une forme d'exploitation et s'ils devraient être interdits. La population étudiée est un groupe de femmes travaillant comme mères de substitution au Kaival Maternity Home and Surgical Hospital à Anand (Gujarat) en Inde. Après examen de leurs conditions de vie, je soutiens que ces femmes vivent dans des conditions injustes causées à la fois par la pauvreté et par une forme de sexisme institutionnalisé. Puis, j'ai étudié et évalué les arguments critiquant cette pratique ainsi que ceux relatifs au commerce d'organes et à la prostitution. J'en ai conclu qu'aucun d'entre eux n'est cependant suffisant pour démontrer que des contrats impliquant la mise en vente du corps sont nécessairement et par essence des outils d'exploitation. La maternité de substitution est une forme d'exploitation parce qu'elle met en jeu un ensemble complexe de conditions sociales inégalitaires. Cependant, ce type de contrat profite à la fois à la mère de substitution et au couple qui l'emploie. Les contrats internationaux de maternité de substitution sont une forme d'exploitation mais ils apportent un bénéfice mutuel. Dès lors, interdire la maternité de substitution serait préjudiciable à moins qu'une telle mesure ne soit accompagnée d'un changement social drastique.</description><creator>MacKay, Kathryn</creator><contributor>Marguerite Deslauriers (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Jennifer Fishman (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Philosophy</subject><title>An examination of exploitation in international gestational surrogacy contracts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qj11k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741s23v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pq769</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nous avons étudié deux applications basées sur l'utilisation de nanotubes de carbone.  Nous avons tout d'abord réalisé des couches conductives et transparentes de nanotubes servant de substrat pour le dépôt électrochimique d'une couche mince de poly(éthylenedioxythiophene). Une telle électrode, ayant les propriétés des nanotubes ainsi que du polymère, devrait être bénéfique pour divers dispositifs organiques.  Les électrodes polymère-nanotubes ont été fabriquées avec les SWNTs HipCO et à l'arc électrique sur du verre et sur du plastique; le gain obtenu rapport aux couches déposées par enduction centrifuge en terme de résistance va jusqu'à 100 Ω/sq.  Quelques DEL organiques fonctionnelles ont été fabriquées avec succès en utilisant ces électrodes.  Ensuite, nous avons synthétisé des couches auto-assemblées de SWNTs sur du silicium, afin d'étudier les propriétés électriques des SWNTs alignés verticalement.  Les surfaces de silicium fonctionnalisées avec des groupes hydroxyles ont été liées aux nanotubes par estérification. Les substrats obtenus ont des nanotubes liés à la surface qui sont désordonnés.</description><description>The viability of two independent electronic applications of single-walled carbon nanotubes was studied.  Firstly, the use of a transparent, conductive, nanotube film as an electrode on which to electrochemically synthesise a thin film of poly(ethylenedioxythiophene).  Such an electrode, possessing advantageous properties of both the nanotube and polymer film, should prove useful for numerous organic devices.  Polymer-nanotube electrodes were made with HipCO and arc-discharge CNTs, on glass and flexible substrates; showing up to 100 Ω/sq. improvement in sheet resistance over conventional spin-coated films was demonstrated on glass.  Preliminary organic LED devices were fabricated and successfully tested.  Secondly, covalently bound monolayers of SWNTs on silicon were synthesised with a view to exploring the electronic properties of vertically aligned SWNT arrays.  Silicon surfaces with hydroxyl functionality were prepared by a radical reaction with hydroxyl terminated 1-alkenes, which were then ester couple to oxidised carbon nanotubes.  The resulting substrates showed bound, but disordered nanotube films.</description><creator>Lockwood, Tobias</creator><contributor>Dmytro Perepichka (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Chemistry - Physical</subject><title>Electronic applications of single-walled carbon nanotubes: Electropolymerised transparent electrodes and CNT monolayers on silicon</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x4405.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pq769</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qq024</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In many normal and pathologic calcified tissues, osteopontin (OPN) is a prominent protein intimately associated with biominerals.  This work aims to elucidate how OPN regulates crystal growth in two biosystems: calcitic avian eggshell during growth and resorption, and in vitro calcium oxalate dihydrate (COD) growth related to pathologic urolithiasis (kidney stones). To understand how OPN and other proteins participate in calcite growth and organization in avian eggshell, ultrastructural matrix-mineral relationships of unfertilized, unincubated chicken eggshell were examined using scanning and transmission electron microscopy (SEM and TEM).  OPN was localized in situ in eggshell with high resolution colloidal-gold immunolabeling, and the effects of this protein on calcite growth were assessed in vitro.  The detailed ultrastructures described here reconcile, for the first time, how an extensive organic matrix coexists with the calcitic mineral phase in eggshell. OPN preferentially binds to the {104} crystallographic face and subsequently occludes into the mineral, and thus directs calcite orientation by influencing crystal growth and morphology in eggshell.  Moreover, OPN accumulates at interfacial boundaries between various eggshell compartments, maintaining the structure of eggshell compartments and the patency of eggshell pores by inhibition of mineralization at these interfaces. Once constructed, the eggshell can serve as a calcium source for skeletal mineralization in the growing embryonic chick.  Ultrastructural changes within the eggshell mammillae during shell resorption by chick embryo were examined systematically by SEM. The results suggest that the extensive mineral-occluded matrix network in mammillae may regulate dissolution of shell mineral by providing channels facilitating calcium release. To investigate OPN related to COD formation common in urolithiasis, the effects of full-length OPN, and a poly-aspartic acid-rich peptide of OPN (DDLDDDDD, poly-Asp86-93), were examined in COD crystal growth studies.  By combining SEM, light and confocal microscopy using fluorescently tagged poly-Asp86-93, together with computational modeling, it was observed that OPN and poly-Asp86-93 similarly inhibit (and thus enhance) the {110} faces of COD, and that the peptide is occluded into the COD crystals - this identifies an important motif involved in OPN binding to COD. Collectively, these data provide new insights into how OPN and its peptides (and likely other proteins) bind to, and are occluded within, various biominerals to regulate crystal growth, and in some cases, to facilitate mineral dissolution.</description><description>Dans beaucoup de tissus calcifiés normaux et pathologiques, l'ostéopontine est une protéine de premier plan qui est intimement associée aux biominéraux. Cette étude vise à déterminer comment l'ostéopontine controlle la croissance cristalline dans deux biosystèmes : la calcite de coquilles d'oeuf aviaire durant sa croissance et sa résorption, et la formation in vitro d'oxalate de calcium dihydraté associé à l'urolithiase (calculs rénaux) pathologique. Pour comprendre comment l'ostéopontine et d'autres protéines participent à la croissance et à l'organisation de la calcite dans la coquille d'oeuf aviaire, on a étudié, à l'aide d'un microscope électronique à balayage (MEB) et d'un microscope électronique à transmission (MET), les relations ultrastructuralles entre les matrices organique et minérale de coquilles d'oeuf de poule non fertilisé et non incubé. L'ostéopontine a été localisée in situ dans la coquille d'oeuf par immunomarquage à haute résolution à l'aide d'or colloïdal et les effets de cette protéine sur la croissance de la calcite ont été évalués in vitro. Les ultrastructures détaillées décrites ici montrent pour la première fois la coexistence d'une matrice organique étendue et de la phase calcitique minérale dans la coquille d'oeuf. L'ostéopontine se lie de préférence à la face cristallographique {104}, pour ensuite s'occlure dans le minéral et diriger ainsi l'orientation des cristaux de calcite en influençant la croissance et la morphologie cristalline dans la coquille d'oeuf. Qui plus est, l'ostéopontine s'accumule au niveau des joints interfaciaux entre les différents compartiments de la coquille d'oeuf, maintenant la structure de ces compartiments et la perméabilité des pores de la coquille en inhibant la minéralisation sur ces joints interfaciaux. Une fois construite, la coquille d'oeuf peut servir de source de calcium pour la minéralisation du squelette de l'embryon lors de son développement. Les changements ultrastructuraux dans les mamelons qui se forment sur la coquille lors de sa résorption par l'embryon ont été systématiquement examinés au microscope électronique à balayage. Les résultats permettent de penser que l'important réseau matriciel minéral occlus présent dans ces mamelons pourrait réguler la dissolution des minéraux de la coquille en fournissant des voies favorisant la libération du calcium. Pour étudier l'ostéopontine associée à la formation d'oxalate de calcium dihydraté lors de l'urolithiase, on s'est penché sur les effets de l'ostéopontine pleine longueur et d'un peptide d'ostéopontine riche en acide polyaspartique (DDLDDDDD, poly-Asp86-93) dans des études de la croissance de cristaux d'oxalate de calcium dihydraté. En combinant la microscopie électronique à balayage, la microscopie  optique et la microscopie confocale utilisant du poly-Asp86-93 marqué par fluorescence, ainsi que la modélisation assistée par ordinateur, on a observé que l'ostéopontine et le poly-Asp86-93 inhibent de façon similaire (et donc renforcent) les faces {110} de l'oxalate de calcium dihydraté et que le peptide est occlus dans les cristaux de ce dernier - ce qui identifie un important motif impliqué dans la liaison de l'ostéopontine à l'oxalate de calcium dihydraté. Collectivement, ces résultats donnent un nouvel aperçu de la façon dont se lient l'ostéopontine et ses peptides (de même que d'autres protéines, probablement) et leur occlusion au sein divers biominéraux afin de réguler la croissance cristalline et, dans certains cas, de faciliter la dissolution minérale.</description><creator>Chien, Yung-Ching</creator><contributor>Marc D McKee (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Hojatollah Vali (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Dentistry</subject><title>Matrix protein-mineral interactions in avian eggshell and during calcium carbonate and calcium oxalate crystal growth in vitro</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b303.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qq024</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j143r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse de doctorat propose une analyse des multiples facettes que comportent les devoirs et obligations des médecins chercheurs et fait valoir que l'on devrait étendre la responsabilité fiduciaire aux médecins qui mènent des recherches cliniques avec des humains. Les allégations de malhonnêteté et de fraude scientifique ont entaché l'intégrité des chercheurs. Certains médecins chercheurs ont succombé aux pressions de publier dans le but d'accroître leur renommée scientifique, alors que d'autres ont été séduits par l'appât du gain. En tant que fiduciaires, les médecins chercheurs doivent éviter de se placer dans des situations de conflit d'intérêts potentiel. La recherche financée par l'industrie pharmaceutique peut donner lieu à de tels conflits lorsque le médecin chercheur a des intérêts financiers dans la société qui commandite une recherche à laquelle il participe. Je déconstruis la doctrine des fiducies et identifie trois modèles analytiques : le modèle de l'approche catégorique, le modèle de l'analyse des principes sous-jacents et le modèle du droit acquis. Les principes fiduciaires - la confiance, la bonne foi et la loyauté - sont à la base du construct normatif qui sert à l'analyse des instruments juridiques et des ordonnances judiciaires établissant la norme de conduite relative à la recherche clinique. L'analyse démontre que le principe fiduciaire - primordial - de loyauté est commensurable avec le devoir de bénéficience du médecin, c'est-à-dire le devoir d'agir dans le meilleur intérêt du patient. Mon analyse utilisée dans cette thèse de doctorat font appel au test de l'attente raisonnable de P.D. Finn. Le devoir de bénéficience, soit le devoir d'agir dans le meilleur intérêt du patient-sujet de recherche, la législation internationale et les ordonnances judiciaires établissant la norme de conduite relative à la recherche clinique sont autant de circonstances qui justifient une attente raisonnable de loyauté fiduciaire de la part des médecins chercheurs. L'analyse fait valoir que l'on devrait accorder deux droits importants aux patients-sujets de recherche : L'attente raisonnable qu'un mobile approprié motive les actions du médecin chercheur; La non-spéculation quant à la confiance que l'on peut accorder au mobile du médecin chercheur. L'analyse est influencée par le traité de Lionel Smith sur le devoir de fiduciaire et l'examen du mobile; le mobile du fiduciaire est sujet à révision judiciaire, car le facteur déterminant de l'infidélité fiduciaire est le mobile et non le préjudice subi. Je considère finalement comme base de recherches futures la notion de droits fiduciaires en tant que théorie cohésive des devoirs des médecins chercheurs qui unirait les approches déontologiques, fondée sur les conséquences et fondée sur les droits.</description><description>This dissertation analyzes the multiple layers of physician scientists' obligations and argues for extending fiduciary liability to physicians conducting clinical research with human participants. Allegations of scientific dishonesty and fraud have cast a shadow on the integrity of medical researchers. Some physician scientists have succumbed to pressure to publish for professional renown, while others have been seduced by the temptation to yield greater pecuniary gains. As fiduciaries, physician scientists must avoid potential conflicts of interest. In industry-funded research, such conflicts arise when the physician scientist has a pecuniary interest in the sponsoring pharmaceutical company. My examination begins by deconstructing fiduciary doctrine and identifying three theoretical models: the categorical approach, the underlying principles analysis, and the prophylaxis, motive and entitlement model. The fiduciary principles of trust and confidence, good faith, and loyalty form the normative construct for analysis of legal instruments and judicial prescriptions regarding clinical research standard of care. The overarching fiduciary principle of loyalty is determined to be commensurable with the physician's duty of beneficence: the duty to act in the patient's best interest. My analysis uses P.D. Finn's reasonable expectation test. The actual circumstances justifying a reasonable expectation of physician scientists' fiduciary loyalty would be the duty of beneficence, i.e. to act in the interests of the research patient, international legislation and judicial prescriptions on the duty of care in clinical research. The analysis extends two important entitlements to research patients: The reasonable expectation that the physician scientist will act with the proper motive and non-speculation on the trustworthiness of the physician scientist's motive. The analysis is influenced by Lionel Smith's treatise on fiduciary obligation and scrutiny of motive: a fiduciary's motive to act (or not act) is subject to judicial review because motive not harm determines fiduciary disloyalty. The notion of fiduciary entitlements as a cohesive theory uniting deontological, consequentialist and rights-based approaches to physician scientist obligations will be considered as a basis for future study.</description><creator>Motta, Madeline Marie</creator><contributor>Richard Gold (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Fiduciary obligations of the physician scientist in a post Hippocratic era</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r136v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j143r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j67314402</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les récepteurs tyrosine kinase aux facteurs de croissance sont des initiateurs critiques des voies de signalisation nécessaires à la croissance, la différentiation, la migration et la survie cellulaire. Beaucoup de ces signaux sont coordonnés par des protéines d'échafaudage qui sont phosphorylées au cours de leur recrutement au complexe de récepteurs activés. Ceci fournit des sites de liaison à de multiples protéines permettant l'activation et la génération de différentes réponses biologiques. L'amplitude et la durée d'un signal est régulée via la déphosphorylation et la dégradation des protéines cibles. De cette façon, la régulation du signal agit pour promouvoir la formation et le désassemblage de complexes protéiques et pour diversifier et localiser les signaux en aval des récepteurs tyrosine kinase. Le récepteur Met et son ligand HGF (Hepatocyte Growth Factor) sont des régulateurs de la morphogenèse, la dispersion et la survie des cellules épithéliales. Toutefois, peu d'informations sont disponibles sur les protéines responsables de l'extinction des signaux issus du récepteur Met. Dans le chapitre II, je démontre que le récepteur Met est hyperphosphorylé dans les souris knock-out pour PTP1B en réponse aux dommages induits par Fas. L'inhibition par le composé PHA665752 de la signalisation par Met, relève la protection contre  les crises hépatiques dans les souris KO pour PTP1B. Ceci démontre que PTP1B est un régulateur négatif de Met et son retrait permet la survie cellulaire contre les crises hépatiques induites par Fas. En réponse à la stimulation du récepteur Met, la protéine d'échafaudage Gab1 est la plus importante des protéines recrutées et phosphorylées en aval de Met et cette protéine est critique dans la médiation des réponses biologiques dépendantes de Met. Dans les chapitres III et IV, j'ai identifié la kinase Ser/Thr Pak4 et le facteur d'échange de guanine lié aux microtubules (GEF-H1) en tant que nouvelles protéines recrutées à Gab1 suite à l'activation de Met. Je démontre que Gab1 et Pak4 agissent de façon synergique pour promouvoir la migration et l'invasion suite à la stimulation par HGF. De plus, le recrutement de Pak4 à Gab1 est important pour sa localisation cellulaire dans les lamellipodes et est critique pour la dispersion et la morphogenèse des cellules épithéliales en aval de Met. En outre, GEF-H1 est important pour la formation et le roulement des points d'adhésion focaux ce qui est en corrélation avec la capacité de GEF-H1 de promouvoir la migration et l'invasion épithéliale en aval de Met. Ces études ont pour but d'investiguer les mécanismes moléculaires régulant les signaux dépendants de Met et démontrent pour la première fois que le récepteur Met est un substrat pour PTP1B. Finalement, Pak4 et GEF-H1 sont identifiés comme des intégrateurs clés de la migration et l'invasion cellulaire dépendante de Met.</description><description>Growth factor receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs) are critical initiators of signal transduction pathways necessary for cell growth, differentiation, migration and survival.  Many of these signals are coordinated through scaffold proteins that are phosphorylated upon their recruitment to the activated receptor complex.  This provides binding sites for multiple proteins to activate and generate distinct biological responses.  The amplitude and duration of a signal is regulated via dephosphorylation and degradation of target proteins.  Signal regulation in this manner acts to promote the formation and disassembly of multi-protein complexes and diversify and localize signals downstream from RTKs. The Met RTK and its ligand, hepatocyte growth factor (HGF), are positive regulators of epithelial morphogenesis, scatter, and survival.  However little was known regarding the proteins responsible for attenuating Met receptor activation.  In Chapter II, I demonstrated that the Met receptor was hyperphopshorylated in PTP1B-null mice in response to Fas-induced liver damage.   Inhibition of Met signaling with PHA665752, removed protection from liver failure in PTP1B-null hepatocytes, demonstrating that PTP1B was a negative regulator of the Met RTK and its removal promoted cell survival against Fas-induced hepatic failure. In response to Met receptor stimulation, the Gab1 scaffold protein is the prominent protein recruited and phosphorylated downstream from Met and is critical in mediating Met-dependent biological responses.  In chapters III and IV, I identified the serine/threonine kinase Pak4 and the microtubule-bound guanine nucleotide exchange factor GEF-H1 as novel proteins recruited to Gab1 following Met receptor activation. I demonstrate that Gab1 and Pak4 synergize to enhance migration and invasion following HGF stimulation. Furthermore, the recruitment of Pak4 to Gab1 is important for its subcellular localization to lamellipodia and critical for epithelial cell dispersal and morphogenesis downstream from Met.   In addition, GEF-H1 is important in focal adhesion formation and turnover and this correlates with the ability of GEF-H1 to promote epithelial migration and invasion downstream from Met. Overall, these studies investigate molecular mechanisms regulating Met-dependent signals and demonstrate for the first time that the Met receptor is a substrate for PTP1B and identify Pak4 and GEF-H1 as key integrators of Met dependent cellular migration and invasion.</description><creator>Paliouras, Grigorios</creator><contributor>Morag Park (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Regulation of met receptor tyrosine kinase signalling and biology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dw029.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67314402</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02870w33v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mon sujet est l‟éthique de la lecture chez Nietzsche. J‟y soutiens que ses stratégies narratives - métaphores, ironie, et parodie, entre autres - doivent être interprétées en tenant compte de ses déclarations sur la lecture et de ses remarques adressées au lecteur. Ces stratégies sont des outils pédagogiques pour éduquer un lecteur conscient de la responsabilité qu‟il a de s‟émanciper des (méta) récits. L‟éthique de la lecture chez Nietzsche se base sur des principes découlant de son intérêt pour l‟agonistique : scepticisme, compétition, et performance. Le lecteur doit être conscient de la nature construite des textes et être sceptique quant aux affirmations textuelles; lire est la réponse du lecteur aux affirmations et défis d‟un texte. Cette étude contribue à la recherche sur Nietzsche car elle démontre l‟importance de l‟agonistique dans son éthique de la lecture, elle relie cette dernière à la promotion d‟une transvaluation des valeurs, et elle révèle que toutes deux construisent un même récit de l‟émancipation. L‟éthique de la lecture chez Nietzsche est interprétée ici comme sa réponse à l‟éthique de la lecture du Platonisme, du Christianisme, et de la philosophie kantienne. Pour démontrer cela, j‟utilise le chapitre « Der Genesende, » d‟Also sprach Zarathustra comme étude de cas. « Der Genesende » est un récit qui s‟oppose aux récits de la chute chez Platon (Phaedrus; l‟allégorie de la caverne), dans la Genèse, et chez Kant (Mutmasslicher Anfang der Menschengeschichte). Nietzsche mine la téléologie et le dualisme de ces récits, et leurs utilisations de la dialectique, d‟interdictions, et d‟impératifs, pour démontrer que ces récits limitent la liberté de mouvement (de pensée) du lecteur. À l‟opposé, le style de Nietzsche (l‟interdépendance des enseignements de Zarathustra, par exemple) est interprété ici comme une stratégie qui encourage le mouvement. Cette thèse se termine par des lectures de textes du jeune Nietzsche sur l‟éducation, la langue, et l‟agonistique - préoccupations que l‟on retrouve dans Ecce Homo, un soi-disant texte autobiographique qui, en raison de son genre indéfinissable, de ses questions et déclarations provocantes, et de son style agonistique ne sert pas tant la construction de l‟identité de Nietzsche que celle du lecteur.</description><description>This dissertation explores Nietzsche‟s ethics of reading. I argue that narrative strategies such as metaphors, irony, and parody, amongst others, must be interpreted against the backdrop of Nietzsche‟s utterances on reading and statements addressed to the reader. These strategies are interpreted as pedagogical tools which serve the education of an emancipated reader - a reader aware of the responsibility to emancipate himself from (meta)narratives. Nietzsche‟s ethics of reading consists in principles deriving from his preoccupation with agonistics: suspicion, contest, and performance. The reader must be aware of the constructed nature of texts and suspicious of textual assertions; the act of reading also consists in the reader‟s response to textual assertions and challenges. This dissertation thus contributes to Nietzsche scholarship by investigating the significance of agonistics for Nietzsche‟s ethics of reading, by linking this ethics of reading to his call for a revaluation of values, and by showing that both partake in the same narrative of emancipation Nietzsche‟s ethics of reading is interpreted here as his response to the ethics of reading which arose out of the Platonic, Christian, and Kantian traditions. In order to show this, I use the chapter "Der Genesende," from Also sprach Zarathustra as case study. I show that "Der Genesende" is Nietzsche‟s counternarrative to fall narratives found in Plato (Phaedrus; the parable of the cave), Christianity (Genesis 3), and Kant (Mutmasslicher Anfang der Menschengeschichte). Nietzsche undermines the teleological and dualistic worldviews of these narratives as well as their use of dialectics, prohibitions, and imperatives, to show that these narratives restrict the freedom of movement (of thought) of the individual and reader. In contrast, Nietzsche‟s style in Also sprach Zarathustra (the entwinement of Zarathustra‟s teachings, for example, which underpin and undermine one another) is interpreted as his way to promote movement in
the reader‟s mind.
The study ends with readings of Nietzsche‟s early writings on education,
language, and agonistics. These preoccupations coalesce in Ecce Homo, a text which,
because of its confusion of genres, provocative questions and statements, and agonistic
style reveals itself to be not so much about Nietzsche‟s own identity construction but
about the reader‟s. </description><creator>Lachance, Nathalie</creator><contributor>Karin Bauer (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Literature - Germanic</subject><title>'Thou shalt not believe (me)': Nietzsche's ethics of reading and the movement for emancipation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nf235.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870w33v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784m27h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Distraction osteogenesis (DO) is a prevalent surgical technique for the correction of congenital orthopaedic deformities and craniofacial developmental conditions. Yet, clinical benefits continue to be limited by a number of complications mainly as a result of the protracted treatment time during which the fixator has to be kept in situ until the newly-formed bone in the distracted zone consolidates (or hardens), thus exacerbating significant medical, psychological and socio-economical problems on patients, their families and caregivers. On the other hand, protein therapy particularly with the use of potent osteoinductive cytokines from the TGF-B superfamily has been hailed as the most promising alternative to conventional bone grafts. Currently, rhBMP-2 and rhBMP-7/OP-1 have been approved for their "restricted" clinical use in long bone healing and spinal fusion. Prospective clinical trials have reported variability in results ranging from full bone bridging to no bone union and to optimize the therapeutical outcome, the incorporated high and unsafe dosages of the growth factors, timing of release and their application systems necessitate further development. Thus far, loading the protein solution into collagen sponges prior to surgical implantation has shown poor retention and rapid clearance of BMPs within a much shorter period than bone healing requires, especially in humans. Also, such carriers do not provide controlled or customizable release and can comprise outcome by foreign body reactions due to their nature, composition and incomplete degradation. Hence, biocompatible delivery systems that release the bioactive load locally and continuously over proper periods of time for the regeneration of native bone using lower and safer drug concentrations are needed. This doctoral dissertation describes the development and evaluation of a novel hybrid nanoparticulate rhOP-1 delivery system demonstrating characteristics suitable for enhancing de novo bone regenera</description><description>L'ostéogenèse par distraction osseuse (OD) est une technique chirurgicale répandue pour la correction de difformités orthopédiques congénitales et craniofaciales. Pourtant, les avantages cliniques continuent d'être limités par de complications comme à la suite d'un traitement de longue durée pendant lequel le fixateur doit être gardé in situ jusqu'à ce que l'os nouvellement formé dans la zone distraite se consolide; pouvant significativement engendrer voire aggraver certains problèmes médicaux, psychologiques et socio-économiques. D'un autre côté, l'utilisation de puissantes cytokines de la superfamille TGF-B a été considérée comme l'alternative la plus prometteuse à la greffe conventionnelle d'os. Actuellement, BMP-2 et BMP-7/OP-1 ont été approuvés pour leur utilisation clinique "restreinte" dans la longue guérison osseuse et la fusion spinale. Pourtant, certaines études ont rapporté une certaine variabilité dans les résultats, allant du pontage osseux complet jusqu'à l'absence d'unification osseuse. Et pour optimiser le résultat thérapeutique, le haut dosage incertain des facteurs de croissance, le choix du temps de relargage et de leurs systèmes d'application requièrent des développements supplémentaires et approfondis. Donc, le développement d'un système de délivrance qui relargue le chargement bioactif localement et continuellement sur des périodes de temps appropriées pour faciliter la régénération de l'os natif à des concentrations plus basses et moins dangereuses est nécessaire. Cette thèse décrit le développement et l'évaluation d'un système de délivrance hybride, combinant nanoparticules et rhOP-1, qui démontre des caractéristiques convenables pour l'accélération d'OD. Le travail présenté dans cette thèse est divisé en deux phases principales : (1) La formulation de nanoparticules à structure coeur-coquille biocompatible, biodégradable, monodisperse, physiquement stable et chargée positiv</description><creator>Haidar, Ziyad</creator><contributor>C Reggie Hamdy (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Maryam Tabrizian (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Dentistry</subject><title>A hybrid core-shell rhOP-1 nanoparticulate delivery system for enhanced new bone regeneration in distraction osteogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415p986g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784m27h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9997145</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La croissance et la plasticité synaptiques sont des éléments critiques pour le bon fonctionnement du cerveau, et participent aux processus de la mémoire et l'apprentissage. Le but de nos recherches est d'identifier et de caractériser les mécanismes moléculaires qui sous-tendent le règlement de la plasticité synaptique morphologique ainsi que fonctionnelle. À cette fin, nous avons élaboré un crible d'augmentation-de-fonction génétique dont le but était d'identifier de nouveaux régulateurs de croissance synaptique, en utilisant la jonction neuromusculaire (JNM) larvaire de la mouche drosophile (Drosophila melanogaster) comme synapse modèle. Grâce à ce crible, nous avons identifié un groupe de microARN (miARN) bien conservé au niveau évolutionnaire, miR-310-313, dont l'expression affecte la plasticité synaptique à la JNM de la drosophile. Nous avons produit une délétion de ce groupe de miARN par l'excision imprecise d'un élément génétique mobile (P-element). Nos résultats démontrent que la perte de miR-310-313 entraîne une augmentation significative du courant post-synaptique évoqué et du contenu quantique, une mesure de l'efficacité de la libération de neurotransmetteur présynaptique. Ce phénotype peut être rescapé en surexprimant miR-310-313 pendant le stade larvaire du système nerveux, suggérant une exigence d'expression génétique temporelle et spatiale spécifique pour ce groupe de miARN. Les miARN répriment l'expression de leurs cibles par appariement de bases avec le 3'UTR de leur mARN. Des algorithmes quantificatifs ont prédit Khc-73, un membre de la superfamille des protéines Kinesin (KIFs), comme une des cibles les plus plausibles pour miR-310-313. Nous émettons l'hypothèse que le groupe miR-310-313 régule la fonction synaptique en réprimant l'expression de Khc-73. Dans le soutien de notre hypothèse, nous démontrons que la surexpression de Khc-73 dans les neurones moteurs de la drosophile améliore la fo</description><description>Proper synaptic growth and plasticity are critical for higher brain functions including memory and learning. We are interested in identifying and characterizing mechanisms that underlie the regulation of morphological and functional synaptic plasticity. To that end, we conducted a forward genetic gain-of-function screen aimed at identifying novel regulators of synaptic growth, using Drosophila larval neuromuscular junction (NMJ) as a model synapse. From this screen, we identified a well-conserved microRNA cluster, miR-310-313, whose expression affects synaptic plasticity at Drosophila NMJ. We generated a deletion of this miRNA cluster by imprecise excision of a P-element. Our results show that lack of miR-310-313 leads to a significant increase in evoked post-synaptic current and in quantal content, a measure of the efficiency of presynaptic neurotransmitter release. This phenotype can be rescued by overexpressing miR-310-313 during larval stage in nervous system, suggesting the temporal and tissue-specific requirement of this miR-310-313 cluster.   miRNAs repress expression of their targets via base-pairing with the 3'UTR of their mRNAs. Computational algorithms predicted Khc-73, a member of Kinesin Superfamily proteins (KIFs), as one of the highest-scoring targets for miR-310-313. We hypothesize that miR-310-313 cluster regulates synaptic function by downregulating Khc-73. In support of our hypothesis, overexpressing Khc-73 in Drosophila motoneurons enhances synaptic function, a phenotype resembling miR-310-313 deletion. Further evidence shows that genetic removal of Khc-73, by using Khc-73 RNAi or by a deficiency uncovering Khc-73 genomic region, is sufficient to restore normal synaptic function in miR-310-313 deletion. Taken together, our data present a novel pathway by which synaptic plasticity is regulated.</description><creator>Tsang, Ka Wai Karen</creator><contributor>Ali Haghighi (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience</subject><title>A microRNA cluster negatively regulates synaptic function at «Drosophila» larval neuromuscular junction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gk227.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9997145</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bb969</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study situates the National Action Committee on the Status of Women's [NAC] activism and media strategies in relation to the emergence of neoliberal policy and political discourse at the federal level in Canada. The rise of neoliberal policies and political language during the 1980s and early 1990s in Canada created a new terrain on which political debates about women's issues entered into public culture. Consequently, women's organizations had to change advocacy strategies in order to participate in national political discourse and contest the terms on which women's issues were being framed. While this story has primarily been told as the beginning of the end of Canadian second wave feminism, my dissertation investigates how Canadian feminism did not decline or die, as news media reported, but instead was forced to change strategies and, in the process, re-organize the movement's shape, objectives and practice. My study uses qualitative, historical and discursive analysis to examine two sets of representations occurring around the NAC-sponsored federal leadership debates. The first set is drawn from representations of the organization's interests and strategies produced through their own materials, policies and media tactics. This approach facilitates analysis of the internal dynamics informing NAC's media strategy, so as to fully evince the organization's keen awareness of the potential opportunities and constraints for Canadian women presented by a shift to a neoliberal federal framework. The second set is constructed in the English-language news media around NAC's strategic media events in order to determine the ways in which the Canadian women's movement was being discussed and historicized in the mainstream news media.</description><description>La présente recherche fait le point sur l'activité militante et les stratégies médiatiques du comité canadien d'action sur le statut de la femme (CCASF), en relation avec l'émergence d'une politique et d'un discours néolibéraux au niveau fédéral.  Le développement des politiques néolibérales et du langage politique au cours des années 1980 et au début des années 1990, au Canada, a créé une nouvelle réalité dans laquelle les débats politiques sur les questions féminines sont entrés dans la culture populaire.  Par conséquent, les organisations féminines ont été forcées de modifier leurs stratégies en matière de représentation des femmes, afin d'être en mesure de participer au discours politique canadien et de contester les modalités servant à formuler les questions relatives à la condition féminine.  Même si ce sujet a été présenté principalement comme le commencement de la fin de la deuxième vague féministe au Canada, ma thèse explique pourquoi le féminisme n'est pas mort,  comme l'avaient annoncé les médias, mais qu'il a dû  modifier ses stratégies, et par la même occasion, restructurer la forme, les objectifs et les pratiques du mouvement.  Ma recherche utilise l'analyse qualitative, historique et discursive pour examiner deux groupes de représentations qui ont eu lieu autour des débats parrainés par le CCASF.  Le premier groupe est tiré de représentations relatives aux intérêts et aux stratégies de l'organisation, effectuées à l'aide de son propre matériel, de ses politiques et de ses tactiques médiatiques.  Cette approche facilite l'analyse de la dynamique interne qui a influencé les stratégies médiatiques du CCASF, afin de démontrer pleinement que l'organisation était consciente des perspectives et des contraintes éventuelles qu'un changement vers une structure néolibérale fédérale créerait pour les Canadiennes.  Le deuxième groupe est constitué à partir des informations provenant des</description><creator>Thrift, Samantha</creator><contributor>Rentschler, Carrie (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Mass Communications</subject><title>NAC, the news, and the neoliberal state 1984-1993</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vt79v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bb969</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096751k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dystroglycan (DG) is a cell surface receptor that interacts both with the extracellular matrix (ECM) and the intracellular cytoskeleton.  DG serves as the core protein of the dystrophin associated complex (DGC) linked to muscular dystrophies (MDs).  A subset of MDs called Dystroglycanopathies, are associated with mutations which reduce DG's ability to interact with the ECM.  In addition to muscle degeneration, Dystroglycanopathies have central nervous system defects including eye anomalies, lissencephaly and mental retardation.  DG is conserved in D. melanogaster, where its deficiency in muscle leads to muscle degeneration, demonstrating that D. melanogaster serves as a model for MDs.  Deficiency in DG during D. melanogaster eye development was studied to gain insights into the function of DG in the nervous system.  Once the expression and localisation of DG was established, the eye development of two series of Dg mutant alleles was characterised using: immunofluorescence, histology, scanning electron microscopy and cell death assays.  During photoreceptor (R cell) specification, DG concentrates to the apical surface and this location is maintained through early pupal development.  The first Dg allele series tested, exemplified by Dg248, also contains a deletion in the mitochondrial ribosomal protein L34 (mRpL34).  However, due to the mitochondrial dysfunction, Dg248 may serve as a model for the function of DG during metabolic stress.  The severe disruption of eye development observed in eyes mosaic for Dg248 is significantly rescued by the transgenic expression of mRpL34.  Dg248 eyes develop progressive loss of R cell morphology beginning during early pupa.  Dg248 R cell pupal development is associated with the migration of R cell nuclei into their axons.  Cell death levels are high during early Dg248 eye development and inhibition of this cell death, using the baculovirus caspase inhibitor p35, is detrimental to Dg248 eye development, suggesting a defect in com</description><description>La dystroglycan (DG) est une réceptrice cellulaire qui interagit à la fois avec la matrice extracellulaire (MEC) et le squelette intracellulaire.  La DG est le noyau du complexe associé à la dystrophine, lié à la dystrophie musculaire (DM).  Un groupe de DMs, nommé les Dystroglycanopathies, est associé aux mutations qui réduisent la capacité de la DG à interagir avec la MEC.  Les Dystroglycanopathies ont, en plus de la dégénération musculaire, des défauts du system nerveux central (SNC) qui inclut des anomalies des yeux, la lissencephaly et des déficiences mentales.  Conserver dans la D. melanogaster, la déficience de DG dans les muscles produit une dégénération indiquant que la D. melanogaster peut être un model pour les DMs.  Une déficience de DG pendant le développement de l'oeil de la D. melanogaster a été produite pour gagner des connaissances de la fonction sur la DG dans le SNC.  Une foi que l'expression et la localisation de la DG ont été établies, le développement de l'oeil de deux séries d'allèles du Dg fut déterminée en utilisant plusieurs outils incluant l'immunofluorescence, l'histologie, la microscopie électronique à balayage et des analyses de morts cellulaires.  Pendant la spécification des photorécepteurs (R), la DG est concentrée à leur surface apicale et cette localisation est maintenue pendant le début du développement de la pupe.  Le premier allèle de Dg testé, Dg248, contient aussi une délétion du gène de la protéine ribosomale de la mitochondrie L34 (mRpL34).  La disruption sévère de l'oeil mosaic Dg248 est sauvée de façon significative par un transgene du mRpL34.  Cependant, due à la dysfonction de la mitochondrie, Dg248 peux servir comme model du rôle du DG pendant le stress métabolique.  Les yeux Dg248 ont une perte de morphologie progressive pendant le développement de la pupe.  Le développement des cellules R Dg248 est associé avec la migration de leur noyau dans leur axone.  La$</description><creator>Melian, Nadia Yolaine</creator><contributor>Salvatore T Carbonetto (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience</subject><title>A genetic study of Dystroglycan in the «Drosophila melanogaster» eye</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wg423.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096751k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f1596</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Metastatic disease remains the main cause of death from cancer. Few therapeutic options for patients have demonstrated potential in curing metastatic disease.  The molecular mechanisms underlying site-specific metastasis and the factors mediating tumor cell homing remain largely unknown.  Based on a murine Lewis lung carcinoma tumour model of site-specific metastasis mediated by the expression of the insulin-like growth factor - I receptor (IGF-IR), we identified ECM components that show particular promise in regulating metastasis to a specific site.  Specifically, we identified collagen IVα1 and α2 as differentially expressed in liver- and lung-colonizing cells. The overexpression of these genes caused major changes to cell structure and function including differences in cellular morphology, anchorage-independent growth, and resulted in a switch from a lung- to a liver-metastasizing phenotype.  These changes were at least in part due to α2-integrin-mediated activation of focal adhesion kinase (FAK) and protection from anoikis. Collagen IV α1 suppression resulted in increased anoikis and decreased tumour cell colonization of the liver, making it an essential and sufficient gene in liver metastasis in our model. Moreover, type IV collagen overexpression resulted in major changes to ECM and ECM-degradation genes decreasing MMP-3, MMP-9, MMP-13, and collagen type III. Uveal melanoma cells with distinct metastatic phenotypes also showed major changes to these genes. Finally, by analyzing human specimens of metastatic disease, collagen IV was shown to be expressed only in metastatic and specifically hepatic metastases when compared to primary tumours and metastases to other organs.  Collectively, these findings implicate collagen IV as a clinically relevant marker and potential target against site-specific metastasis to the liver.</description><description>Le cancer métastatique ne présente que peu d'options thérapeutiques et de ce fait constitue la cause principale de décès chez les patients qui en sont atteints. Par ailleurs, les mécanismes moléculaires responsables de l'atteinte d'organes-cibles de la métastase par les cellules cancéreuses demeurent largement méconnus. La thèse qui suit présente l'identification d'un marqueur moléculaire qui apparait comme étant un facteur crucial dans l'atteinte des organes-cibles par les cellules métastatiques. En effet, la constituante de la matrice extracellulaire collagene IVα1 et α2, semble être exprimée de manière distinctive chez les cellules colonisant le foie et les poumons.  Nous basant sur un modèle murin de métastase provenant de carcinome pulmonaire et véhiculée par l'expression de IGF-IR, nous avons identifié des changements majeurs quant à la structure et à la fonction des cellules cancéreuses, suite à la surexpression des gènes du Collagene IVα1 et α2.  Ces changements comprennent, entre autre, des différences au niveau de la morphologie  et la croissance cellulaire et ont aussi pour résultat la mutation du phénotype métastatique de pulmonaire à hépatique. Ces changements sont en partie conséquence de l'activation de la kinase d'adhésion focale (FAK) et de la protection de l'anoikis. Par contre, la suppression de l'expression du Collagène IV accroit l'anoikis et diminue la colonisation du foie par les cellules cancéreuses. En outre, la surexpression du Collagène IV apporte des changements majeurs au niveau de la matrice extracellulaire et aux gènes de dégradation de celle-ci, diminuant MMP-3, MMP-9, MMP-13 et le collagène III. Les cellules de mélanome uvéale à phénotype métastatique distinct présentent aussi des changements importants quant à l'expression ces gènes. Finalement, après analyse de spécimens humains, le collagène IV semble être exprimé exclusivement au niveau des tumeurs métastatiques et en</description><creator>Burnier, Julia</creator><contributor>Penina Brodt (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Regulation of site-specific liver metastasis by extracellular matrix proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494898h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f1596</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p0844</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La régulation de la croissance cellulaire, de l'apoptose et de la différentiation cellulaire  sont essentielles pour le développement rénal. L'expression et l'activation de la protéine  kinase SLK (« Ste20-like kinase ») sont augmentés durant le développement rénal et la  récupération d'une ischémie suite a un dommage rénal, qui en fait récapitule certains  aspects du développement rénal. La kinase SLK peut promouvoir la mort cellulaire et  pourrait être impliquée dans la régulation de la croissance durant le développement et le  processus de guérison. Nous proposons que l'activation de la kinase SLK soit due à  l'augmentation de son expression favorisant ainsi son homodimérisation et/ou le  déblocage de son auto-inhibition. Pour tester cette hypothèse l'ADN complémentaire  (ADNc) codant pour le domaine catalytique de SLK (acides aminés 1-373) a été fusionné  avec un ADNc codant pour une version modifiée de la protéine de liaison FK506,  appelée Fv2E. La construction résultante, Fv2E-SLK (1-373), a été transfectée dans des  cellules COS-1 pour exprimer la protéine fusion résultante. L'addition d'AP20187 (un  analogue de FK506) peut ensuite induire la dimérisation de Fv2E-SLK (1-373). In vitro,  le dimère Fv2E-SLK (1-373) montre une augmentation de son activité de 1.7 fois par  rapport à la version monomère. Des cellules épithéliales glomérulaires ont ensuite été  transfectées transitoirement avec la construction Fv2E-SLK (1-373) et traitées ou non  avec l'AP20187. Comparée au monomère, la forme dimérique du Fv2E-SLK (1-373)  augmente la phosphorylation de c-Jun N-terminal kinase et de la kinase p38 de 1.5 à 2.1  fois respectivement, reflétant ainsi une activation qui semble liée au stress. Dans une  autre expérience visant à mesurer l'activité de SLK nous avons mesuré la transactivation  de p53 suite a une transfection transitoire d'un plasmide rapporteur contenant l'élément  de réponse cis de p53.$</description><description>Strict regulation of cell growth, apoptosis and differentiation is essential for normal  kidney development. The expression and activation of the Ste20-like kinase, SLK, is  increased during renal development and recovery from ischemic acute renal failure,  which recapitulates certain aspects of kidney development. SLK promotes apoptosis and  may, therefore, regulate cell growth during development and healing. We propose that  activation of SLK may be due to upregulation of expression, which may then favor  homodimerization and/or reversal of autoinhibition. To test this hypothesis, the cDNA  encoding the SLK catalytic domain (amino acids 1-373) was fused with a cDNA for a  modified FK506 binding protein, Fv2E (Fv2E-SLK(1-373)). The plasmid was transfected  into COS-1 cells, and a fusion protein of the expected molecular mass was expressed.  Addition of AP20187 (an analog of FK506) induced dimerization of Fv2E-SLK(1-373).  In an in vitro immune complex kinase assay, the dimeric Fv2E-SLK(1-373) displayed 1.7  fold greater activity, compared with the monomer. Glomerular epithelial cells were  transiently transfected with Fv2E-SLK(1-373) and were treated with or without  AP20187. Compared with the monomer, dimeric SLK(1-373) increased activation-  specific phosphorylation of c-Jun N-terminal kinase and p38 kinase (1.5-2.1 fold)  reflecting enhanced signaling via stress kinase pathways. In a second assay of SLK  signaling, we monitored p53 transactivation following transient transfection of a  luciferase reporter plasmid that contains a p53 cis-acting enhancer element. Addition of  AP20187 to cells transfected with Fv2E-SLK(1-373) enhanced p53 reporter activity,  compared with untreated. Finally, we monitored the effect of SLK dimerization on the  activation of the proapoptotic protein, Bax. Cells were cotransfected with Fv2E-SLK(1-  373) and Bax-luciferase reporter cDNAs. Stimulation of the Bax reporter by SLK was 2.5  fold in the presence of AP20187 and 1.8 fold in</description><creator>Delarosa, Sierra</creator><contributor>Andrey V E Cybulsky (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</subject><title>Regulation of the Ste20-like kinase, SLK</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cg98q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p0844</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj2362513</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A series of empirical studies is presented that examine the  contribution of Fragile X Mental Retardation 1 (FMR1) gene expression to the  structure and function of the visual system. This contribution is documented using a  histological approach in human and nonhuman primate tissue in conjunction with  psychophysical testing of Fragile X Syndrome affected patients who are lacking FMR1  expression. In the first set of experiments, immunohistological studies of  unaffected human and primate brain tissue were carried out to reveal the staining  pattern for Fragile X Mental Retardation Protein (FMRP), the protein product of the  FMR1 gene, within the two main subcortical pathways at the level of the lateral  geniculate nucleus (LGN). FMRP is expressed in significantly greater quantity within  the magnocellular (M) neurons of the LGN when compared to levels obtained from the  parvocellular (P) neurons. This finding suggests that M neurons depend on FMRP to  greater extent than P neurons for determining their normal structure and function. A  subsequent histological analysis of the LGN from a FXS affected individual revealed  atypical LGN composed of small-sized neurons that were more P- than M-like. This  result supports the notion that with the lack of FMR1 expression as occurs in FXS,  the impact is greatest to M neuron morphology. A second set of experiments explored the idea that the M neuron  pathology in FXS results in a functional deficit for processing of visual  information carried by this pathway. Detection thresholds for stimuli known to probe  either M or P-pathway integrity were obtained from individuals affected by FXS as  well as age- and developmental-matched control participants. In support of this  hypothesis, FXS affected individuals displayed significantly elevated thresholds for  M-but not P-specific achromatic visual stimuli. The selectivity of this deficit was  verified in a consequent experiment that evaluated colour vision, a visual attribute  known to be exclusively processed by the P-pathway. Affected individuals did not  differ significantly from developmental-matched control participants in their  ability to detect chromatic stimuli. Finally, the effect of the M pathway deficit on  cortical visual function was assessed. Results of these experiments reveal that the  thresholds for detection of coherent motion, but not form, are significantly  elevated in the FXS group. This finding suggests that the parietal (dorsal) visual  stream, the major cortical recipient of input from the M pathway, is detrimentally  affected in FXS. A third experiment examines the extent to which the M pathway  deficit impacts on cortical visual functioning by employing stimuli of varying  complexity that probe the parietal (dorsal) and temporal (ventral) visual streams  separately. Results suggest that FXS affected individuals have a pervasive deficit  in their ability to detect both simple and more complex forms of motion. In  contrast, these same individuals have normal detection thresholds for simple form  stimuli. However, with more complex form stimuli affected individuals have  significant elevations in threshold. Taken together these results support the notion  that the M pathway deficit is amplified at higher levels of visual processing and  further, that FXS affected individuals have difficulties integrating all early  visual information.</description><creator>Kogan, Cary Samuel</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Vision disorders.</subject><subject>Fragile X syndrome.</subject><title>Visual processing deficits in the Fragile X Syndrome</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731445f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj2362513</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w777k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse offre une traduction et une translittération d'un texte datant de la fin de l'ère Meiji sur les arts martiaux, Moral Instruction in Budo (1912), ainsi qu'une étude sur l'auteur, Chiba Chosaku (1861-1935).  L'objectif visé consiste à conceptualiser la pensée de Chiba dans la perspective des événements historiques et des courants idéologiques de son époque, en vue de faciliter une meilleure compréhension de sa véritable contribution. Chiba défendait l'idée que la pratique des arts martiaux (budo) soit la manière de maintenir et de transmettre l'éthique religieuse martiale (bushido) dans la condition moderne du Japon occidentalisé. L'oeuvre de Chiba prend toute son importance lorsqu'il affirme que le bushido ne découle pas d'un héritage issu de la classe des samouraïs médiévaux, mais plutôt d'une foi récompense basée sur la loyauté en l'Empereur et sur le patriotisme envers la nation japonaise, laquelle fournit les fondements de la pratique du budo. Chiba soumet l'idée que la mise en application de l'enseignement du budo au niveau de l'éducation nationale préviendrait contre le relâchement de la morale et contribuerait au renforcement du caractère national japonais et de l'institution militaire. La carrière et les écrits de Chiba démontrent que la tendance militariste de l'idéologie budo n'a pas fait son apparition dans les années 1930, comme il est généralement accepté, mais qu'elle a débuté au moins deux décennies plus tôt. Comme il s'agit du tout premier exemple d'une narration fusionnant les idéologies budo et bushido, Moral Instruction in Budo ne laisse pas d'être un texte crucial dans la compréhension de l'impact historique des arts martiaux au Japon.</description><description>This thesis provides a translation and transliteration of a late Meiji period martial arts text, Moral Instruction in Budo (1912), together with a study of its author, Chiba Chosaku (1861-1935).  The aim is to contextualize Chiba's thinking in the framework of historical events and ideological currents of his time, in order to facilitate better understanding of his contribution. Chiba argued that martial arts practice (budo) is the way to maintain and transmit martial religious ethics (bushido) in the modern condition of Westernized Japan. The importance of Chiba's study lies in his claim that bushido is not a legacy of the medieval samurai class, but a due faith based on loyalty to the Emperor and patriotism toward the Japanese nation, which provides the foundation for budo practice. Chiba submits that the implementation of budo instruction at the level of national education would prevent the slackening of morals and contribute to strengthening of the Japanese national character and military institution. Chiba's career and writings demonstrate that the militarist slant in the budo ideology of Japan did not occur in the 1930s, as is generally accepted, but began at least two decades earlier. As the earliest example of a narrative that blends budo and bushido ideologies, Moral Instruction in Budō remains a crucial text for understanding the historical impact of martial arts in Japan.</description><creator>Shooklyn, Samuel</creator><contributor>Thomas Lamarre (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>History - Asia, Australia and Oceania</subject><title>Moral instruction in budo: a study of Chiba Chosaku with a translation of his major work</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx507.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w777k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903040n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chemotherapy is used in the treatment of cancer. Unfortunately,  drugs often fail due to multidrug resistance (MDR) caused by P-glycoprotein (P-gp1or  ABCB1) and the multidrug resistance-associated protein (MRP1 or ABCC1). These  proteins bind and transport drugs out of cancer cells, thereby conferring  MDR. The second chapter of this thesis addresses an unexplained  phenomenon that accompanies P-gp1 expression, collaterally sensitive to verapamil.  The collective results of this work demonstrated that treatment of cells that  over-express P-gp1 with verapamil induces apoptosis. Furthermore, the findings show  that the ATPase activity of P-gp1 was activated by verapamil. The degree of ATPase  activation was proportional to the level of apoptosis and the increased demand for  ATP resulted in the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS). Finally, the  production of ROS led to cell death mediated by apoptosis in that experimental model  system. Chapters three and four are devoted to understanding the binding  characteristics of MRP1 with two of its physiological substrates, glutathione (GSH)  and leucotriene C4(LTC4). Photoreactive derivatives of these substrates were  synthesised to address this objective, IAAGSH and IAALTC4. Photolabelling and  transport studies showed that these derivatives have similar binding characteristics  as the native compounds. In addition, photolabelling of MRP1 occurred with a high  specificity with both compounds. IAAGSH and IAALTC 4 were also used to determine the  locations of GSH and LTC4 binding sites. This was accomplished using MRP1-variants  containing hemagglutinin (HA) epitopes at specific locations in the amino acid  sequence. Through photoaffinity labelling, immunoprecipitation, and trypsin  digestion, a map of binding sites for IAAGSH or IAALTC4 was obtained. Both LTC4 and  GSH bound to transmembrane (TM) regions 10-11 and 16-17 which have been previously  implicated in drug binding. Furthermore, novel binding sites for both substrates  were discovered. IAALTC4 photolabelled a novel site within the first five TMs (TMD0)  of MRP1, whereas IAAGSH labelled two cytoplasmic regions (L1 and L0). These may  represent specific binding sites for LTC4 and GSH. The work within this thesis explores some of the biochemical  characteristics of Pgp1 and MRP1 that are not directly related to drug resistance  and may lead to new strategies in cancer treatment.</description><creator>Karwatsky, Joel Michael</creator><date>2005</date><subject>ATP-binding cassette transporters.</subject><subject>P-glycoprotein.</subject><subject>Multidrug resistance.</subject><subject>Verapamil.</subject><title>The biochemical and drug binding characteristics of two ABC transporters /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cw76h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903040n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p762q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA replication initiates at origins with the origin recognition  complex (ORC) binding and activating initiation. Although ORC specifically binds  origins in vivo, it possesses no sequence specific DNA binding activity in vitro.  Thus, it is thought to interact with another protein that recruits it to the origin.  The heterodimeric Ku (Ku70/Ku80) protein is one candidate. Ku is an abundant nuclear  protein that has recently been implicated in the initiation of DNA replication, but  the mechanism by which it performs this function is yet unknown. Here, using  haploinsufficient human HCT116 Ku80 +/- cells that express 25-40% Ku80 protein, the  origin activity and origin-association of other replication proteins were examined  in a Ku80-deficient environment. Ku80 was not found to influence the expression of  replication proteins, except for Ku70, its partner, which displayed a reduction of  its protein expression to 64% of wildtype cells. Ku80+/- cells displayed a  prolongation of G1 phase by 2 hours, but normal progression through S-phase.  Furthermore, the activity of the early-activated replication origins of the lamin  B2, beta-globin and c-myc loci decreased by 4.5-, 3.4-, and 4.3-fold, respectively.  This was associated with a 2.1-, 1.5- and 1.7-fold decrease in the association of  Ku80 with these origins, respectively, and a 1.5-, 2.3- and 2.5-fold decrease in  that of Ku70, respectively. Moreover, the origin-association of three of the six  subunits of the ORC complex, Orc-3, -4, and -6 was significantly decreased in Ku80  +/- cells, indicating decreased ORC complex formation at the origins. In contrast,  the association of Orc-2 was not influenced by Ku80 deficiency, nor was the  association of Ku80 with origins affected by Orc2 deficiency. Overall, these results  suggest that Ku binds origins to allow assembly of the ORC complex, which is  necessary for origin licensing and activation. Ku80-/- murine embryonic fibroblasts (MEFs) are viable but  display a prolonged doubling time of 43 hours vs. 23 hours for wildtype cells. To  analyze the effect of Ku80 absence on DNA replication, the late-firing murine  adenosine deaminase origin was fine-mapped by nascent strand abundance analysis. Two  origins were identified, mAdA-1 and mAdA-C, with 34- and 29-fold greater nascent  strand abundance relative to non-origin DNA. These origins were able to replicate  episomally when transiently transfected into MEF cells. In Ku80-/- cells, in situ  and episomal DNA replication assay of both origins indicated that Ku80 did not  influence their DNA replication activity.</description><creator>Sibani, Sahar</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of initiation of DNA replication in HCT116 Ku80+- Cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vp04s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p762q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731442m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pathology of asthma is a multicellular process that includes  leukocyte recruitment, of which the eosinophil is prominent. Tissue eosinophilia  results from the combined effects of chemoattractants, cytokines and adhesion  molecules. Lipid mediators are a major class of endogenous chemoattractants, among  which 5-oxo-6,8,11,14-eicosatetraenoic acid (5-oxo-ETE) is the most potent for human  eosinophils. To further elucidate its potential role in airway inflammation, the  purpose of these studies was to investigate its proinflammatory effects on different  cell types, including eosinophils, monocytes, and the endothelial cells  (ECs). We found that 5-oxo-ETE is a potent survival factor for human  eosinophils. LTD4 and LTB4 also have this effect, but are much less potent. The  effect of 5-oxo-ETE is indirect and is dependent on the presence of small numbers of  contaminating monocytes. Incubation of highly purified monocytes with 5-oxo-ETE led  to the release of an eosinophil survival factor, the effect of which was completely  blocked by an antibody to GM-CSF. Furthermore, 5-oxo-ETE stimulated the release of  GM-CSF in amounts compatible with eosinophil survival activity. At low  concentrations 5-oxo-ETE and LTB4 stimulated release of similar amounts of GM-CSF,  but at concentrations of 10 nM or higher 5-oxo-ETE induced a much stronger response.  5-Oxo-ETE also stimulated monocytes to release TNF-alpha, IL-1beta, IL-6 and IL-8 in  a time- and concentration-dependent manner. Although, 5-oxo-ETE and LTB4 were  equally effective in stimulating release of IL-8, 5-oxo-ETE was more effective in  inducing release of IL-6, and more potent in stimulating release of  IL-1beta. 5-Oxo-ETE also has potent effects on human ECs, stimulating the  release of soluble forms of the adhesion molecules ICAM-1 and VCAM-1, as well as the  cytokine IL-6. These effects are time- and dose-dependent and significant within the  nanomolar range. 5-Oxo-ETE also promotes actin polymerization in these cells,  suggesting that it may be involved in processes such as vascular permeability and  angiogenesis. These novel insights into the biological effects of 5-oxo-ETE  indicate that it has broad and potent bioactions of physiological relevance to  diseases such as asthma and atherosclerosis.</description><creator>Stamatiou, Panagiota</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Physiology.</subject><title>The proinflammatory effects of 5-oxo-ete on leukocytes and endothelial cells /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bp651.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731442m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fc049</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The winter watermass properties and circulation of the Gulf of  St. Lawrence and St. Lawrence Estuary are examined using a combination of new  wintertime observations and numerical modelling. Ten moorings were deployed over the  winter 2002/3, providing the first continuous observations of the upper 200m of the  water column in winter. A harmonic analysis of current data in the estuary confirms  the existence of a semi-diurnal internal Poincare wave. The analysis also provides  strong evidence of a neap-tide intensification of the estuarine circulation. The  cold intermediate layer (CIL) in the estuary is seen to be renewed abruptly in late  March, with the advection of a wedge of near-freezing water from the  gulf. An eddy-permitting sea ice-ocean model is used with the  observations to quantify the formation and circulation of the CIL. As a first step,  a two-equation second moment turbulence closure parameterization is implemented to  better account for vertical mixing processes. The model sensitivity to this  parameterization is tested and differences of several salinity units are found in  the surface layer throughout the southern half of the gulf. The model reproduces the  strong spring renewal event of the CIL into the estuary, and helps to explain the  role of local dynamics, including the coupled circulation in the northwest gulf, in  controlling the exchange processes at depth. The model results suggest the existence  of a separated Gaspe Current that persists for more than a month. A significant  correlation is found between the inflow through the Strait of Belle Isle and outflow  through Cabot Strait. In order to isolate the effects of this inflow on the CIL heat  content, we examine a sensitivity experiment in which the Strait of Belle Isle is  closed. This simulation shows that the inflow has a relatively small effect on the  total CIL heat budget. With the Strait of Belle Isle closed, the outflow of CIL  through Cabot Strait is reduced by 61%. It is estimated that only 64% of CIL inflow  through the Strait of Belle Isle in fall and winter contributes directly to the heat  content of CIL present in the gulf.</description><creator>Smith, Gregory C.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>The Gulf of St. Lawrence in winter : tides, mixing and watermass transformation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x73k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fc049</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558d76t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:30:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Methylmercury (MeHg) is a neurotoxic global pollutant that  accumulates at high levels in predatory fish and marine mammals. The dietary intake  of these animals is the main source of MeHg exposure in humans. At high levels, MeHg  is known to damage the sensory and motor systems in both adults and children. Due to  the complexity and inaccessibility of the central nervous system (CNS), early  dysfunction is difficult to detect. Biochemical markers in the CNS have been used to  identify MeHg neurotoxicity in animal models. Analogues of these biochemical targets  are also present in peripheral blood tissue and may reflect early CNS dysfunction in  human populations. The proposed peripheral biomarkers include (1) lymphocyte  muscarinic acetylcholine (mACh) receptor, (2) serum cholinesterase (ChE) and (3)  platelet monoamine oxidase (MAO). This thesis evaluates the effects of mercury (Hg)  compounds on these CNS and peripheral biochemical markers in laboratory and  epidemiological studies. In vitro studies showed that inorganic Hg (HgCl2) and MeHg  inhibited mACh receptor binding in human, rat, and mouse brain tissue. Additionally,  studies demonstrated that a low-level gestational exposure to MeHg reduced MAO  activity in the developing embryo and in adult female offspring. Combined, these  studies provide a framework for the assessment of biochemical targets of Hg  compounds in humans. A cross sectional study was conducted to evaluate the  association between peripheral biochemical markers and MeHg exposure in fish-eating  adults (n=129) from Lac St-Pierre, Quebec. Blood-Hg concentrations were used as a  marker of exposure and ranged from 0.2 to 17.0 mug/L. Multiple linear regression  analysis demonstrated that both blood-Hg (p=0.011) and heavy smoking (p=0.001) were  associated with reduced platelet-MAO activity. However, neither lymphocyte mACh  receptor nor serum ChE was related to blood-Hg. These results suggest that exposure  to MeHg may result in reduced plat</description><creator>Stamler, Christopher John</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biochemical markers.</subject><subject>Methylmercury -- Bioaccumulation.</subject><subject>Central nervous system -- Diseases.</subject><subject>Neurotoxicology.</subject><title>Mercury neurotoxicity and the development of peripheral biochemical markers of central nervous system function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hv79g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558d76t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):44575</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>