<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:48:06Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41200" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333301b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new method for the acetalization of carbonyl compounds using chlorotrimethylsilane under mild conditions is described. Carbonyl compounds are acetalized by ethylene glycol with chlorotrimethylsilane. Two isomeric methyl olivetolates were synthesised by the condensation of 1,3-bis(trimethylsiloxy)-1-methoxybutadiene with the corresponding electrophilic components. This reaction has clearly indicated the discriminative behaviour of 1,3-bis(trimethylsiloxy)-1-methoxybutadiene towards different electrophilic sites thus leading to regio-selectivity. A new method for the synthesis of olivetol is described. This method provides a shorter route to olivetol from acyclic precursors. A new synthesis of (DELTA)('1)-tetrahydrocannabinol is described. The synthesis is patterned after biogenetic considerations. A new method for the synthesis of poly (beta)-carbonyl compounds using diketene and enol silyl ethers is described. The possibility of synthesising gossypol by the cyclo-aromatization procedure was investigated.</description><creator>Chaly, Thomas.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Phenols.</subject><subject>Carbonyl compounds.</subject><title>Synthesis of phenolic natural products</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tm78v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333301b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cb64n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vector interpolation functions which approximate electromagnetic vector fields are constructed in this thesis. These vector functions are to be used when the solution of Maxwell's equations involves an irrotational or solenoidal vector field. In addition the functions are chosen so that they can easily be used in the implementation of a finite element method. Four bases are constructed. The first two span the spaces of solenoidal or irrotational two component vector polynomials of order one in two variables whereas the other two span the spaces of solenoidal or irrotational three component vector polynomials of order one in three variables. The vector polynomials are then used within the finite element method to approximate the two component current density J and electric field E over a conducting plate and the three component current density in a three dimensional wire.</description><creator>Nassif, Nevine.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Vector valued functions.</subject><subject>Finite element method.</subject><subject>Vector fields.</subject><title>Vector interpolation polynomials over finite elements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zh57t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cb64n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w8048</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A comprehensive model of particle collection in flotation is developed from a rigorous analysis of the relative motion between a particle and a bubble prior to and during particle-bubble contact. Collection efficiency E(,K) is derived as a product of collision efficiency E(,C) and attachment efficiency E(,A). From trajectory calculations E(,C) is correlated to the bubble Reynolds number and the Stokes number, a dimensionless inertia term. E(,A) is calculated as the fraction of particles which reside on the bubble for a time greater than the induction time. As a result of the velocity gradient are the bubble surface E(,A) decreases with increasing particle size. The model explains the peak in size-by-size recovery data that is often observed at intermediate particle sizes. The peak location is shown to shift to smaller sizes as induction time increases. A scale-up model for flotation columns is also developed. The model uses measured values of collection rate constants and an experimental correlation of plant column mixing parameters to calculate collection zone recovery R(,K). R(,K) is interfaced with a variable cleaning zone recovery to yield a grade-recovery relationship for the plant column. The onset of bubble loading is accounted for.</description><creator>Dobby, G. S. (Glenn Stephen), 1952-</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Separation (Technology) -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Flotation -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>A fundamental flotation model and flotation column scale-up /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386k03w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w8048</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945r557</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>High, intermediate and low virulent strains of Xanthomonas campestris pv. manihotis were isolated from cassava fields in Nigeria. Resistance to cassava bacterial blight (CBB) increased with age. CBB was established by as little as 10('4) CFU/mL inoculum, but general symptom severity and lesion length differences between resistant, intermediate and susceptible cultivars were greatest with 10('6) CFU/mL and leaf wilting with 10('8) CFU/mL. CBB increased shoot dry weight and foliar ion leakage; this increase was greater for potassium and magnesium than for sodium and calcium. Pathogen multiplication in leaves was least in the resistant cultivar and it spread to the stem only in the susceptible one. CBB reduced liquid flow in stem of resistant, intermediate and susceptible cultivars by 43, 35 and 96%, respectively. Flow in the healthy susceptible cultivar was double that in the more resistant cultivars. The number of non-functional vascular bundles in diseased plants was negatively correlated with liquid absorption and translocation.</description><creator>Asiedu, Samuel Kwaku.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Host-parasite relationships.</subject><subject>Cassava -- Diseases and pests.</subject><subject>Xanthomonas manihotis.</subject><subject>Phytopathogenic bacteria -- Host plants.</subject><title>Interactions between Xanthomonas campestris pv. manihotis (ISPP list 1980) and cassava (Manihot esculenta Crantz)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b419s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945r557</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nr733</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A system was developed to study membrane transport in isolated human fibroblast plasma membrane vesicles, avoiding potential complications of intracellular binding and metabolism in the intact cell. Ten-fold enrichment of plasma membranes after subcellular fractionation was confirmed with appropriate markers. Transport competence was established by the following criteria: osmotic sensitivity, stereospecificity, temperature dependence, sodium gradient stimulation, response to ions and ionophores, saturability, and exchange properties. Methotrexate uptake was osmotically sensitive, temperature sensitive, saturable, and inhibited by folinic acid and phosphate. Measurement of lysine uptake was complicated by binding and lack of sodium dependence, but was stimulated by an interior-negative membrane potential, and intravesicular lysine or arginine. Exchange properties of the lysine carrier were exploited to assess its function in fibroblasts from patients with the Mendelian phenotype, lysinuric protein intolerance (LPI). LPI vesicles were not different from controls in their lysine transport phenotype.</description><creator>Buchanan, Janet Ann.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Cells -- Permeability.</subject><subject>Biological transport.</subject><subject>Fibroblasts.</subject><subject>Cell membranes.</subject><title>Fibroblast plasma membrane vesicles to study inborn errors of transport</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cf00f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nr733</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn009z62f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study indicates a need for further research in the diagnosis of language deficits in beginning readers to prevent reading problems.</description><description>A quantitative analysis between groups revealed differences at the level of linguistic competence. A qualitative analysis of the dyslexic group revealed the existence of three subgroups: a morphological subgroup, a Cloze grammatical subgroup, and a Cloze lexical subgroup.</description><description>Two groups, a control group of normal readers and an experimental group of dyslexic readers, were compased using a series of reading tasks that measured certain components of linguistic competence.</description><description>The purpose of the study was to investigate the role of linguistic competence in developmental dyslexia. This was done to determine whether there existed subgroups of dyslexics classified according to linguistic criteria.</description><creator>Théberge, Raymond.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Cloze procedure.</subject><subject>Language disorders.</subject><subject>Reading disability.</subject><title>Discriminating linguistic factors in reading disability</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289j79s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z62f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440t12z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The need for the development of a rigorous analytical model of the lumbar spine to clarify the role of mechanical factors in low-back disorders has long been recognized. In response to this need, a general three dimensional nonlinear finite element program has been developed as part of this work and has been applied to the analysis of a lumbar L(,2-3) joint including the posterior elements. The analysis accounts for both the material and geometric nonlinearities and is based on a representation of the nucleus as an incompressible inviscid fluid and of the annulus as a composite of collagenous fibres embedded in a matrix of ground substance. The facet articulation has been accounted for by treating it as a general moving contact problem. The ligaments have been modelled as a collection of nonlinear axial elements. The geometry of the finite element model is based on in-vitro measurements. The response of the joint under single compression, single flexion, single extension and also under flexion or extension combined with compression and sagittal shear has been analyzed for both the normal and degenerated states of the nucleus. Validity of the model has then been established by a comparison of those predictions which are also amenable to direct measurements. The states of strain and stress in different components of the lumbar joint have been thoroughly studied under all the foregoing loading conditions. Those elements of the joint predicted to be vulnerable to mechanical failure or damage under the above types of loading have been identified. These results have been correlated with the lumbar joint injuries reported clinically. Furthermore, some joint injury mechanisms and degeneration processes have been proposed and the supporting clinical evidences have been presented.</description><creator>Shirazi-Adl, Aboulfazl</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Strains and stresses -- Testing.</subject><subject>Joints -- Models.</subject><subject>Intervertebral disk.</subject><subject>Lumbar vertebrae.</subject><subject>Spine.</subject><title>Three dimensional nonlinear finite element stress analysis of a lumbar intervertebral joint</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483k08h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440t12z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:707958516</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mice bearing the mutant gene Cat:Fr have dominantly inherited congenital cataracts, which are more extensive in the mutant homozygote than in the heterozygote. The biochemical and ultrastructural properties of these lenses were examined and compared with those of lenses in which cataracts were induced with acetaminophen and bleomycin. The Cat mutation induces a dominant, by inheritance, loss of beta-H crystallins, but this change is also seen in the bleomycin cataracts, and in the presence of 1 M sucrose, or at 4(DEGREES)C. There are codominantly inherited alterations in the relative proportions of crystallin and albuminoid components in the inherited cataracts, and in the presence of 1 M sucrose. Changes in amino acid composition of the lens proteins are dominantly inherited in the Cat mutation. There are also abnormalities of amino acid composition in the proteins from the acetaminophen cataracts, but these are different from those caused by the mutation. As to the ultrastructural changes, the inherited cataracts have a relatively normal anterior epithelium, but show marked degeneration of nuclear and deep cortical fibres. The bleomycin cataracts also show extensive nuclear destruction, but in addition, appear to be completely devoid of capsule, and have degenerating anterior epithelium cells, which are not seen in the inherited cataract. The acetaminophen cataracts, by contrast, retain normal overall structural architecture, but the individual fibres become swollen and flaky, and develop an increased number of interdigitating processes. These abnormal biochemical properties not unique to the Cat:Fr mouse are unlikely to be proximal effects of the mutant gene, and may be general consequences of the presence of a cataract, from whatever cause. The differences between ultrastructural abnormalities seen in the drug induced and inherited cataracts suggest that these etiological agents induce cataracts by different mechanisms, a fact that is not always apparent from</description><creator>Stirk, Linda J. (Linda Joyce)</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Cataract.</subject><subject>Rodents -- Diseases -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Mice -- Diseases -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Ocular pharmacology.</subject><subject>Eye -- Diseases -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Biochemical and ultrastructural studies of dominantly inherited and drug induced cataracts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bv33g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/707958516</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g832p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Following recent developments in philosophy of education, this thesis attempts to relate work done in analytic philosophy of education to work done in normative philosophy of education. The first part of the thesis focuses on the analysis of the concept Curriculum. The aim of this analysis is to attempt to clarify Curriculum and show that it is an essentially normative concept. An examination of the nature of this concept raises serious moral issues, e.g. that of the justification of the content of the Curriculum. This issue is dealt with in the second part of the thesis where I investigate two major philosophical attempts to justify the content of the Curriculum (that of R. S. Peters--an approach couched essentially in terms of the intrinsic value of certain activities--and that of P. S. Wilson--an approach couched essentially in terms of the notion of 'what interests someone') and show that the arguments adduced by Peters and Wilson do not satisfactorily resolve the issue, either in their own terms or in terms of the extent to which they speak to practical considerations. Mary Warnock attempts to merge the double rift, between Peters and Wilson, and between theoretical and practical considerations, by arguing that imagination and work are the criteria (equally important) by which decisions as to the content of the Curriculum should be made. This moderate position, although more adequate, is not devoid of problems, especially with regard to the relationship between imagination and work. It is my belief that a fundamental change in the understanding of theory and practice in the field of education must occur before serious advances can be made with regard to the justificatory issue.</description><creator>Portelli, John P. (John Peter)</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Peters, R. S. (Richard Stanley), 1919-</subject><subject>Peters, R. S. (Richard Stanley), 1919- Ethics and education.</subject><subject>Education -- Philosophy</subject><subject>Wilson, Patrick Seymour.</subject><title>Philosophical approaches to the justification of the curriculum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b592.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g832p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:00000077m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The "modified triester" and phosphodichloridite procedures for oligoribonucleotide synthesis, using 2'- silylated nucleosides, were compared. Phosphodichloridite reagents were faster and more efficient than the arylsulphonyl reagents for both dinucleotide and mononucleotide phosphotriester synthesis. The trichloroethyl group was better than tribromoethyl, p-nitrophenethyl or methyl protecting groups for solution-phase synthesis. Trichloroethyl dichlorophosphite was used in block condensations to prepare CCCGA and UCAUAA. An automated RNA synthesizer was developed. Nucleoside methyl chlorophosphites were used with silica gel supports. Polystyrene, polyacryloylmorpholide and controlled pore glass supports were also used but were not as satisfactory. Oligoribonucleotides, up to 17 units long, were rapidly prepared in high overall yield. The sequences were purified by TLC and gel electrophoresis. Enzymatic degradations and HPLC confirmed the composition of the products.</description><creator>Pon, Richard T. (Richard Timothy)</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Organic compounds -- Synthesis.</subject><subject>Oligoribonucleotides.</subject><subject>Chemical tests and reagents.</subject><subject>Phosphodichloridite.</subject><title>Phosphodichloridite reagents in the solution and solid phase synthesis of oligoribonucleotides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jv43q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000077m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f1995</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Characterization of the most frequently isolated virus found during a survey of eastern Ontario red clover fields, which was designated as the Ottawa isolate, was undertaken. Determination of the biological and physico-chemical properties of the virus showed that the virus studied differed in some respects from other WCMV isolates. An ultrastructural examination of virus localization of cytopathological changes in infected red clover and pea plants revealed various types of viral inclusions, including a membrane-bound mass of tubules, not usually associated with infection by potexviruses, in red clover leaves, and severe organelle disorganization within pea leaf tissues. WCMV infection significantly reduced several processes relevant to symbiotic nitrogen fixation, including plant growth, nodulation, nitrogenase activity, leghemoglobin content, and Rhizobium population, but nitrate reductase and acid phosphatase specific activities were increased. The correlation between leghemoglobin content and nitrogenase activity shown at ten-leaf and pre-blooming stages was absent during the flowering and senescence stages. Infectivity assays, immunosorbent electron microscopy, and an ultrastructural examination showed the presence of the virus in nodular tissues; the cytopathological changes seen in bacteroids suggested that virus infection accelerated nodule senescence. Application of a cytochemical technique using diaminobenzidine showed that the leghemoglobin was located in the peribacteroidal space.</description><creator>Khadhair, A. H. (A. Hameed)</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Red clover vein mosaic virus.</subject><subject>White clover -- Diseases and pests.</subject><subject>White clover -- Ontario, Eastern -- Diseases and pests.</subject><subject>Mosaic diseases.</subject><subject>Red clover -- Ontario, Eastern -- Diseases and pests.</subject><title>Studies on an eastern Ontario isolate of white clover mosaic virus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x4758.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f1995</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623d43m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mesidotea entomon inhabiting Pauline Cove, YT, is larger in total body length at sexual maturity than M. entomon inhabiting Dolomite Lake, NWT. The sex ratio, diet, habitat distributions, size frequency distributions, and fecundity in the two populations are compared. Total carbohydrate, protein, lipid, chitin, and ash contents of both isopods' life stages are compared. Isopods in the cove show reduced carbohydrate and elevated lipid levels. In the 1975, 1978, and 1979 summers, isopods in the cove were internally infected with an extracellular protozoan parasite; those in the lake were uninfected. The infection is systemic. The prevalence of the protozoan infection increases with increasing host size. The host response involved phagocytosis and encapsulation. Transmission may be transovarially and/or by ingestion of the infective stage. The protozoan also infected Mesidotea sibirica. The infection is related to growth, abundance, habitat, reproduction, and biochemical variables.</description><creator>Korczynski, Rita E.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Crustacea -- Yukon -- Pauline Cove.</subject><subject>Isopoda -- Yukon -- Pauline Cove.</subject><subject>Isopoda -- Northwest Territories -- Dolomite Lake.</subject><subject>Crustacea -- Northwest Territories -- Dolomite Lake.</subject><title>Comparison of freshwater and saltwater populations of the isopod Mesidotea entomon from Dolomite Lake, Northwest Territories, and Pauline Cove, Yukon Territory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784m577.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623d43m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Oceanography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qm758</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the forms of utopianism which developed in U.S. fiction after the Civil War, from Mark Twain to Jack London. It covers the genres and subgenres of the utopia of reform, the fiction of occult utopianism, the lost-race romance, the post-catastrophe utopia, and the dystopia. Its central argument is that utopianism provides a means of developing alternative horizons of historiosophy and of building images of otherness, as it is also an argumentative apparatus which allows utopists to comment on their empirical society, as the other side of otherness. Nineteenth-century U.S. utopian fiction conveyed, through an increasing deconstruction of the utopian genre, conflicting interpretations of such elements of American myth-history as the stock image of America as a new Eden and paradise of abundance, the American Dream, and Manifest Destiny. This helps explain the fragmentation of the utopian genre within literary discourse and its cooptation by modern science fiction as it developed after the first decade of the twentieth century.</description><creator>Khouri, Nadia, 1943-</creator><date>1983</date><subject>American fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Utopias in literature.</subject><subject>American fiction -- 19th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>The other side of otherness : forms of fictional utopianism in the U.S.A. from Mark Twain to Jack London</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25x937m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qm758</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tm794</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this thesis is to examine the nature and role of the relation which exists between the revelation of God to man, and ethics. Within Protestant Christianity two major schools of thought are involved in active debate over the issue. We have selected Reinhold Niebuhr of the neo-orthodox wing and Carl F. H. Henry as the evangelical spokesman, in view of comparing their concepts of revelation to their ethics. We proceed by asking whether the ethical systems of both Niebuhr and Henry are dependent, interdependent, or independent in relation to revelation. We find the answer by observing the parallel movement of differences in the form and content of revelation with the differences in the form and content of their ethics. We discover dependence. Furthermore, we consider the ways in which the revealed content is related to ethics. Thus we measure the relevance of revelation to ethics and discover again the same relatedness and dependence.</description><creator>Kis, Miroslav M.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1892-1971.</subject><subject>Ethics.</subject><subject>Henry, Carl F. H.</subject><subject>Revelation.</subject><title>Revelation and ethics : dependence, interdependence, independence? :</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000078w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm794</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77sq92f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The adaptability of the respiratory muscles to training and/or emphysema was investigated. The diaphragmatic (DIA) length-tension curve of the emphysematous animals shifted significantly towards the left; maximal tetanic tensions were generated at shorter absolute DIA lengths. This decrease in DIA length occurred in proportion to the hyperinflation and mainly occurred due to a loss in the number of sarcomeres. In states of acute DIA shortening, were no adaptations in length occurred, we noted marked alterations in the twitch characteristics and in the shape of the force-frequency curve; at acutely shorter DIA lengths, a disproportionately greater excitability was required in order to reach a given submaximal tension. In the chronically shortened DIA, however, the re-establishment of a new shorter length allowed for the twitch characteristics, the force frequency curve and the maximal tetanic tension to remain unchanged. Therefore, the dropping out of sarcomeres in the chronic condition appears to maintain normal DIA function. Training produced no effects on the contractile or structure properties of the DIA. The acutely shortened DIA fatigued at a faster rate when initial tensions were comparable as to the optimal length. In emphysematous animals, however, the DIA showed a significantly greater resistance to fatigue. The mechanisms responsible for the enhanced DIA endurance were biochemical increases in the oxidative capacity with a concomitant decrease in the glycolytic capacity. Histochemically, the DIA from sedentary emphysematous animals revealed a selective fast fiber atrophy which was prevented by endurance training. The intercostal muscles revealed histochemical and biochemical evidence of adaptations consistent with a greater resistance to fatigue.</description><creator>Farkas, Gaspar Andrew.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Adaptations of the respiratory muscles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505128s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sq92f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903074g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The conditions by which the production, in liquid media, of hemolytic activity by growing cells of T. hyodysenteriae and T. innocens are described. From a ribonucleic acid added culture broth of T. hyodysenteriae, two hemolysins are shown in the supernatant. For each of them, a purification scheme allowing the obtention of an homogeneous hemolytic preparation by gel filtration and electrophoresis, is proposed. One hemolysin is associated with ribonucleic acid (HN) while the later is associated with bovine serum albumin (HP). They share some properties: their synthesis is blocked by chloramphenicol, they do not have proteolytic or phospholipasic activities, they are insensitive to oxygen and their activity does not require bivalent cations or is sensitive to EDTA's action; they are lytic to all red blood cell's type tested. They differ by the size of their apparent molecular weight, their mode of action, the stability of their activity to temperature and different pH and, their pattern of sensitivity to proteolytic enzymes. The isolation of a non-hemolytic mutant strain of T. hyodysenteriae and its use in a ligated ileal loop model in rabbit has shown that there is a relation between the loss of the hemolytic activity and the loss of the enterotoxic activity.</description><creator>Picard, Benoit</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Treponema innocens.</subject><subject>Pathogenic bacteria.</subject><subject>Hemolysis and hemolysins.</subject><subject>Treponema hyodysenteriae.</subject><title>Production, purification et caracterisation d'hemolysines de Treponema hyodysenteriae</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t77z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903074g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zb88m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The transmembrane potential changes ((DELTA)(PSI)) induced by the sensitizing cancer extract in leukocytes from patients with cancer were measured as part of their transmembrane signalling. Cancer extracts induce (DELTA)(PSI) changes in sensitized leukocytes, initiating the cascade of reactions that lead to leukocyte nonadherence to glass. Monocytes armed with cytophilic antitumor antibodies recognized the organ-specific cancer neoantigen (OSN) in extracts of allogeneic cancer and released leukotriene mediators that affected themselves and bystander leukocytes. Whereas the monocyte response is not MHC restricted, the T-cell response in the LAI and (DELTA)(PSI) assay is limited to extracts of autologous cancer and restricted by class I MHC antigens. (DELTA)(PSI) changes are seldom observed in leukocytes from patients with advanced cancer to either OSN or leukotrienes. The evidence suggests that these leukocytes are activated in vivo and are therefore refractory to a second in vitro stimulus. Increasing intracellular cyclic AMP restores transmembrane signalling and LAI.</description><creator>Shenouda, George.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Transmembrane signalling and leukocyte nonadherence induced in leukocyte subpopulations by sensitizing cancer extract</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tg18v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zb88m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dn126</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This investigation was primarily concerned with the interaction of the ('125)I-labeled human gonadotropins with testicular tissue from the human and from nonhuman primate species. The binding of the ('125)I-hFSH and ('125)I-hCG (or ('125)I-hLH) to a particulate fraction (P1) of the primate testis was highly specific. Gonadotropin binding was competitively displaced by the synthetic estrogens and an inhibitory factor present in testicular extracts (140,000 x g supernatant). The biochemical properties of the gonadotropin receptor (testicular) interaction of the different primate species were similar in most respects. All tissues had a greater FSH than LH binding capacity with an apparent dissociation constant in the range of 10('-10)-10('-11)M. An FSH responsive adenylyl cyclase was characterized in human testicular membranes. In the presence of a chemically deglycosylated derivative of FSH it was possible to uncouple the FSH responsive adenylate cyclase system. The synthetic estrogens were also effective inhibitors of the human testicular adenylyl cyclase.</description><creator>Berman, Marvin.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Primate testicular gonadotropin receptors : characterization and functional studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623d44w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dn126</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010q78q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates the reading processes used by nine sixteen-year-old, adolescent reluctant readers as they read and interpret poetry. The study also considers how these reading processes are affected by the students' participation in a one-month study of reading and independently discussing poetry in small groups. Each student's responding-aloud interpretation of poetry gathered before the study (pre-test protocol) is compared with his or her responding-aloud interpretation of poetry gathered after the study (post-test protocol). This is done by analyzing each protocol according to a reading scale which identifies five key-reading processes each of which is qualitatively differentiated across five categories. This reading scale, designed by the researcher, is based on the analysis of over one hundred and twenty responding-aloud protocols of adolescent reluctant readers. Six of the nine readers refine the processes through which they read and interpret poetry. The most likely cause of this improvement is their having been involved in independent small-group discussion of poetry. The analysis of students' pre-test and post-test protocols reveal the (differing) extents to which each of them use the five key-reading processes.</description><creator>Sullivan, M. Alayne</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Reader-response criticism</subject><subject>Reading</subject><subject>Poetry -- Study and teaching</subject><title>Reading poetry in non-directive settings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375x07c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010q78q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mm925</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first part of this research concerns gelation in reversible gels. On the basis of calorimetric, viscometric, and spectroscopic results, a novel mechanism of gelation is described. It is proposed that the formation of the gel network leads to an increase in entropy which is sufficient to overcome the unfavorable gelation enthalpy. Gelation is, therefore, said to be entropy driven. The role of the solvent in the gelation process is also discussed. The second part of the research is a study of spherulitic growth rate in blends of isotactic polypropylene (iPP) and a compatibilizer. Using time-lapse photomicroscopy it was found that addition of small amount of compatibilizer can enhance the growth rate of iPP. Similar results were obtained with chemically modified compatibilizers. The enhancement is explained in terms of partial miscibility between iPP and compatibilizers. A mathematical model of the kinetics of spherulitic growth rate in partially miscible blends is described.</description><creator>St-Jean, Guylaine</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Physical properties of polymers : I. Gelation of poly-4-methylpentene-1. II. Growth rate of isotactic polypropylene spherulites in immiscible blends</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q221w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mm925</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558f01z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human newborns' response to decreased sound pressure level (SPL) was investigated with a localized headturning habituation procedure. Following criterion orientation (three headturns toward the sound out of four consecutive trials) and habituation (three consecutive trials with no headturns or headturns away from the sound), study 1 and 2 assessed newborn female infants' (M age = 41 hrs.) responses to lower-volume sounds immediately following habituation and following a 55-sec delay, respectively. Generalization of habituation to decreased volume following delay with recovery immediately following habituation was observed. Immediate recovery to decreased SPL contradicts a selective receptor adaptation view because a lower-intensity stimulus does not engage a separate set of receptor cells. It is proposed that generalization of habituation following delay involves recognition of the sound as familiar despite variations in volume.</description><creator>Tarquinio, Nancy</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Hearing</subject><subject>Sound pressure.</subject><subject>Newborn infants.</subject><title>Newborn response to decreased sound pressure level</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vv083.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558f01z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074v861</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The distribution of neuropeptide Y (NPY) receptor sites was investigated in certain mammalian species using receptor autoradiography and membrane binding assay techniques. NPY receptor sites are discretely distributed throughout the central nervous systems of hamster, rat, guinea pig and monkey but are particularly concentrated in cortex and hippocampus. NPY receptor autoradiography techniques also revealed important labelling of numerous thalamic nuclei while most hypothalamic nuclei showed surprisingly low densities of NPY receptor sites, considering the high levels of NPY-like immunoreactivity in this brain area. The widespread distribution of NPY receptor sites suggests that this peptidergic system must have important roles in mammalian central nervous system. In particular, the possible involvement of NPY in cognitive function deserves further investigation since we observed that ($ sp3$H) NPY receptor site densities are decreased in temporal cortex and hippocampus of individuals decreased with Alzheimer's disease. The possible existence of NPY/peptide YY (PYY) receptor subtypes was investigated in the rat brain. Overall, the similar autoradiographic distribution of ($ sp{125}$I) BH-NPY and ($ sp{125}$I) PYY in most areas suggests that these two receptor probes most likely interact with the same population of NPY/PYY receptor sites. ($ sp{125}$I) PYY may recognize both a high and low affinity state/subtype of NPY/PYY receptors while ($ sp{125}$I) BH-NPY recognize a single affinity state of receptor having the binding characteristics of the low affinity ($ sp{125}$I) PYY receptor state/subtype. The exact nature of this high affinity receptor state/subtype remains to be established. Finally, the structural requirements of NPY receptors in central (CNS) and peripheral (PNS) nervous systems were also examined with a binding assay on rat brain membrane preparation and with the rat vas deferens bioassay preparation. The amino acid residues responsible for the activation of NPY receptors in the rat vas deferens preparation lie in the C-terminal half of the NPY molecule as revealed by the loss of potency, but not of biological activity with C-terminal fragments up to NPY$ sb{18-36}$. The N-terminal portion of the NPY molecule appears to be mostly important to insure adequate affinity for central and peripheral NPY receptors. Moreover, a series of NPY analogs revealed that the two tyrosine residues in position 20 and 21 are not directly involved in NPY receptor activation in this bioassay preparation, although they appear relatively important for the maintenance of adequate affinity for the receptors. Interestingly, modifications of the tyrosine residue in position 20 led to the development of two analogs demonstrating a certain degree of selectivity for the PNS receptors while other modifications of tyrosine residues in position 21 may provide some selectivity for CNS receptor sites. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Martel, Jean-Claude</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Autoradiographic and pharmacological studies of neuropeptide Y receptors in central and peripheral nervous systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mg17m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074v861</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g5809</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work describes the neuromodulatory effects of norepinephrine (NE) on single neurons isolated in the somatosensory cortex of halothane-anaesthetized cats. In 46 animals, a sample of 465 isolated neurons were characterized according to the presence or absence of peripheral input, of spontaneous activity and sensitivity to glutamate. The effects of NE were examined in 117 cases using two different paradigms; either the receptive fields of neurons displaying peripheral inputs were stimulated mechanically during NE administration or the effects of NE were studied on the response to iontophoretically-administered glutamate on neurons lacking a receptive field. In the presence of NE, 54% (63/117) of the neurons were inhibited. 36% (42/117) displayed some increase in neuronal activity and 10% (12/117) were unaffected. Often, the inhibitory effects of NE were more important on the spontaneous activity than on the induced activity producing an increase in the signal-to-noise ratio in 74% (28/38) of neurons. In contrast, when NE produced some excitation, the signal-to-noise ratio was increased in only 38% (11/29) of those cases. Inhibited neurons were located predominantly in the middle layers of the cortex while excited neurons were found in upper and lower layers. These results suggest that NE has different functions in different layers of the somatosensory cortex. After the cessation of NE administration, the response to a peripheral stimulus was increased for more than 5 min in 22% (2/9) of neurons. In contrast, long-lasting increases in the response to glutamate followed NE administration in 70% (31/44) of cases. In this latter group, NE also produced long-lasting decreases in the ongoing activity in 39% (9/23) of neurons and long-lasting increases in the signal-to-noise ratio in 59% (13/23). Pharmacological evidence suggests that the inhibitions were mediated by $ alpha sb{2}$- and $ beta$-receptors while the excitations and the long-lasting increases in neuronal activity were mediated by $ alpha sb1$-receptors.</description><creator>Warren, Richard</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Effects of iontophoretically administered norepinephrine in cat somatosensory cortex : modulation of neuronal responses to cutaneous input and prolonged increases of glutamate-induced excitations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62f897x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g5809</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kt539</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alpha-fetoprotein (AFP) is a tumor-associated embryonic serum glycoprotein, existing in the circulation as a heterogeneous population of closely related molecular variants. The biological function(s) of AFP is not known, but the precisely regulated expression of AFP molecules during ontogenetic development and in certain diseases is consistent with an immunoregulatory function. The present thesis examines the functional significance of murine AFP microheterogeneity. In the initial phase of this study, seven individual AFP isoforms were purified with a novel separation protocol developed on Mono Q anion-exchange columns linked to an FPLC system. All seven subspecies were further characterized by isoelectric focusing gels, immunoblot analysis, molecular weight determination, and sialic acid composition studies. When all seven variants were tested in several AFP sensitive immune assays, we determined that all the immunosuppressive activity of native AFP was localized to a single distinct molecular variant. This isoform, AFP-1, exhibited an isoelectric point of pH = 5.1, contained 1 mol of sialic acid/mol of protein, and represented approximately 6% of the total population of naturally occurring AFP isoforms isolated from the amniotic fluid at days 15-19 of murine gestation. Further studies indicated that sialic acid expression on the carbohydrate portion of the AFP molecules was unlikely to be involved in the suppressor function. Since it has been reported that the polyunsaturated fatty acids arachidonic acid and docosahexaenoic acid complexed to AFP molecules may be necessary for the expression of AFP-mediated immunoregulatory activity, we also examined the potential contribution of these polyunsaturated fatty acids to the immunoregulative function of the active isoform. Gas liquid chromatographic analyses, delipidation procedures and fatty acid reassociation experiments indicated that these fatty acids are unlikely to contribute to AFP-mediated immunosuppressive activity. We also determined that MAF-derived AFP from different gestational time points including days 10.5, 12.5, 14.5, 16.5, and 18.5 exhibits immunosuppressive activity in vitro. All the above results are the first direct demonstration that individual molecular variants of murine AFP have distinct immunoregulatory properties. This should facilitate a better comprehension of the relationship of molecular structure to biological function of AFP molecules during fetal development.</description><creator>Van Oers, Nicolai S. C. (Nicolai Stanislas Cyrille)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><title>Biochemical and immunoregulatory properties of a distincte murine alpha-fetoprotein isoform</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494918s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kt539</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708x30b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Constant true strain rate (2 s$ sp{-1})$ compression tests with one or two interruptions were carried out on a series of steels over the temperature range 900-1050$ sp circ$C. Based on a 0.07% C, 1.25% Mn and 0.006% N reference steel, the three microalloyed steels contained the following: (i) 0.08% Al, (ii) 0.04% Nb, or (iii) 0.045% Nb and 0.08% Al. The degree of fractional softening during the interpass was used to assess recrystallization start (R$ sb{ rm s})$ and finish (R$ sb{ rm f})$ times as well as those for the onset (P$ sb{ rm s})$ and termination (P$ sb{ rm f})$ of precipitation. Relative to a plain C steel, the static recrystallization kinetics show that the single solute retarding effect of Al is small but measurable while that of Nb is substantially larger. The influence of each element is enhanced when they are present jointly. The retardation effects observed at 1000$ sp circ$C are due solely to the presence of these elements in solution. Additional delays observed at or below 950$ sp circ$C in the two Nb bearing steels are ascribed to strain induced precipitation of Nb(CN). The P$ sb{ rm s}$ times were estimated from the fractional softening data as well as from stress relaxation type tests. The presence of high levels of Al retarded the onset of Nb(CN) precipitation while it accelerated its progress. The Nb precipitates were cube shaped and heterogeneously distributed, suggesting that they were formed on dislocation networks. A thermodynamic model was developed for the alloy system studied. The calculations indicated that there is a higher chemical driving force for precipitation in the Nb steel than in the Nb-Al steel at a given temperature. Consequently, this produces a higher equilibrium mole fraction of Nb(CN) in the former. The P$ sb{ rm s}$ times calculated based on the classical nucleation theory are in good agreement with the values observed. Three hit test results further showed that increased hold times between the first two hits decrease the rate of softening between the second and third hits. Residual strain in the partially recrystallized structure is more effectively accumulated at lower temperature due to slower softening rates. These data enabled the development of a model for calculation of residual strains following a hold in a partially recrystallized structure. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Wang, Ganlin</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Static recrystallization and precipitation in Nb-Al HSLA steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343s87k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708x30b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41225</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>