<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:22:36Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33450" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214q846</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alzheimer's disease (AD) is the most common neurodegenerative disease affecting the elderly. One of the main pathological hallmarks of AD is abundant senile plaques found in brain parenchyma and in the meningovasculature. The core of these senile plaques is predominantly composed of the 40--43 amino acid beta-amyloid (Abeta) peptide which arises from proteolytic cleavage of the beta-amyloid precursor protein (betaAPP), a glycoprotein with a predicted structure of a transmembrane protein. Most studies of betaAPP expression and processing have focused on cultured cell systems. Previously, our laboratory reported that immediately ex vivo human peripheral blood lymphocytes did not express cell surface betaAPP. Here, we investigated expression of betaAPP in various immediately ex vivo cell types from rodent and human species to determine whether or not our previous findings extended to different cell types and species. Cell surface expression of betaAPP was detected on immediately ex vivo rodent and human adult brain cells, and human peripheral blood monocytes by using various anti-betaAPP antibodies and flow cytometry; however, peripheral cells such as rodent lymphoid cells, hepatocytes, and kidney cells or human lymphoid cells did not display cell surface immunoreactivity, although all cells expressed abundant betaAPP intracellularly. This suggests cell-specific processing of the betaAPP molecule. We extended our studies with human peripheral blood monocytes to examine any differences between different age groups and AD patients. We demonstrate that cell surface betaAPP decreases with aging; however, it is significantly increased in AD patients compared to healthy age-matched controls. Our data suggest that a proportion of peripheral Abeta may be derived from monocyte/macrophages, and that defects in brain cell processing of betaAPP in AD may be shared by this readily accessible peripheral cell. Investigation of immediately ex vivo human adult brain cells demonstrat</description><creator>Jung, Sonia Sun-Yung, 1968-</creator><contributor>Cashman, Neil R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Expression and processing of the Alzheimer's beta-amyloid precursor protein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505220s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214q846</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hh21p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes an experimental investigation of semileptonic B meson decays with a D and pi mesons in the final state: B- → D+pi -e-nu e. The data for the analysis were collected with the CLEO II detector at the Cornell Electron-positron Storage Ring. The D meson is reconstructed in the D+ → K-pi+pi+ channel. The advantage of using this particular B decay mode is that there is no contribution from the D* due to phase space exclusion. This analysis is the first attempt at measuring non-resonant decays semileptonic decays with the CLEO II detector. Even though we do not distinguish between higher order D resonances and the so called non-resonant decays, measuring this decay channel reveals useful information about the deficit observed in inclusive charm semileptonic B decays. We present the full neutrino reconstruction method used in extracting this decay channel from our data sample. The main difficulty comes in understanding combinatoric backgrounds and we develop two methods to solve this problem. After extensive study, no statistically significant signal is observed. So an upper limit is extracted. The result we obtain is B (B- → D +pi-e- nue) &lt; 0.71% at 90% C.L. This is consistent with the expected amount of B - → D+pi- e-nu e events predicted by the current models.</description><creator>Janicek, René.</creator><contributor>Patel, Popat M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Search for charmed meson-Pion continuum production in Semileptonic B decays at CLEO II</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns61h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh21p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc14n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Botho Strauss a writer of prose, essays and plays, belongs to the most interesting and controversial authors of the last thirty years. Like a seismograph he picks up numerous discourses, the most important one being Memoria . His peculiar and eccentric way of representing and reflecting on memory, in the early texts, is innovative, critical, self reflective, but in the later texts becomes neo-conservative, elitist and patriarchal. This later discourse sparked off a discussion, involving writers such as Peter Handke, Martin Walser and Peter Sloterdijk, about the role of the intellectual in German society. I begin by examining how cultural studies approaches the topic of Memoria. I then apply to the texts of Strauss a 'mnemonic reading,' meaning, to explore and discover topographies of memory. Literature and the arts in general are perceived as places of memory, or as archives where cultural memory is kept alive. Quoting, or rewriting selections from texts, as described in theories of intertextuality, changes and keeps alive a tradition of literature within literature. A text becomes a palimpsest in which fragments of foreign texts suddenly become visible and can enter the readers memory. In Strauss, to form a memory from the fragments is not without major problems. The pieces move in all directions to form a paradoxical body of text. In his early texts the narrator laments the impossibility of creating an identity based on personal memories and so he concentrates on the problem of how to represent memory within the context of increasing amnesia. The seemingly dead subject moves about within the texts where he hopes to build himself a place for his identity to survive. In reaction to loss of memory and identity, a calculated game appears in which the representation and experience of the past plays only a minor role. The author turns towards the models of aesthetic memory, adapting, for example, the romantic mode of writing. The metamorphosis of texts, such as those from the romantic period, occurs as a backdrop against which the writer projects his erotically inspired allegorical "memory theater." Dramatization of the memory process leads him to conclude that memories only exist within the aesthetic world of literature, where they manifest themselves beyond a historical and social reality. At the end of his writing project, Strauss creates an aesthetic refuge of personal memories by turning himself into a "diarist." The male voice regresses to an aggressive and melancholic mode of limited perception, which the author knows cannot be more than an artificial construction.</description><creator>Fürhoff, Irena E.</creator><contributor>Bauer, Karin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Strauss, Botho, 1944- -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Erinnerungs-Inszenierungen in Botho Strauss' Prosawerken</title><language>ger</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q60c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc14n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mr60g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rising awareness in the need for environmental protection has brought into question the adequacy of conventional hazardous waste treatment operations. Regulatory standards are increasingly strict, and there is growing concern over the safety of incineration facilities. This research project examines the technoeconomic potential of thermal plasma technology in this context. Adaptive Plasma-Assisted Incineration (APAI) is a novel concept for secondary gas treatment in hazardous waste incineration. As an energy source for waste destruction, a thermal plasma can provide conditions far higher in temperature and in reactivity than those obtained using a combustion flame. Thus, the plasma is more effective at destroying hazardous materials, albeit at a higher cost. APAI features a thermal plasma afterburner with continual on-line optical monitoring of the gas product and feedback optimization of the plasma conditions. This approach allows complete destruction of persistent organic compounds and cost-effective response to feed load variations. The process supplements conventional incineration techniques with the effectiveness and flexibility of thermal plasma treatment. The main objectives are to reduce the risk of harmful emissions during hazardous waste incineration and to facilitate compliance with new environmental regulations. In this project, the technical feasibility of APAI was demonstrated experimentally using a laboratory-scale plasma afterburner model. The work focused on the development of a spectroscopic monitoring procedure and on the application of optimization techniques for cost-effective operation of the model system. The techno-economic potential and limitations of APAI were addressed in a conceptual study. Preliminary designs and cost estimates were developed for specific applications. The costs of plasma-assisted and conventional methods were compared for contaminated soil remediation (by incineration and desorption) and for organic liquid waste destruction. Economically, APAI appears uncompetitive at the present time. However, it remains a promising alternative in view of ongoing environmental policy changes and developments in plasma technology.</description><creator>Filion, Julie.</creator><contributor>Munz, Richard J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Salin, Eric D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Physics, Fluid and Plasma.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>A feasibility study of adaptive plasma-assisted incineration /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21th12d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mr60g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87ps08k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is found experimentally that total cross sections increase with energy. Partonic total cross sections can be calculated in perturbative QCD provided the coupling constant is small, though multiloop diagrams must be included at high energies. Such calculations are difficult and can usually be carried out only in the leading-log approximation. The resulting BFKL Pomeron violates the Froissart bound, which forbids total cross sections asymptotically to grow faster than the square of the logarithm of energy. To restore unitarity and the Froissart bound, subleading contributions of all orders must be included. Unfortunately existing techniques for computing Feynman diagrams prove to be inadequate for this difficult task. The purpose of this thesis is to develop new techniques capable of solving this problem. Since factorization in the impact-parameter space is a main ingredient needed to reach unitarity, such a technique must be capable of implementing factorization in an efficient way. We introduce the non-abelian cut diagrams for that purpose. We use it to compute quark-quark scattering amplitude to the two-loop order and show how the new technique can overcome the inadequacies of the existing method. We are also able to use this method to prove factorization of a class of Feynman diagrams, which we shall refer to as 's-channel ladder diagrams', though the proof of general factorization is not attempted in this thesis. We have also developed a more efficient method to calculate the high-energy dependences of individual Feynman and non-abelian cut diagrams. This method relies on a systematic study of the paths used by momenta to flow through the diagram, and will thus be referred to as the path method for flow diagrams. These new techniques can be used to implement unitarity and to restore the Froissart bound, but this final goal is not carried out here.</description><creator>Feng, Yongjian, 1969-</creator><date>1999</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>New techniques for computing and factorizing Feynman diagrams</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n287s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87ps08k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78td839</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the last few years the field of computer speech recognition has come into its own as a practical technology. These advances have been due primarily to a steady, step-wise refinement of existing techniques, and the availability of ever more powerful computers on which to implement them. However, many problems remain partially unsolved or entirely open. For example, the current methods continue to fail in cases of small, highly confusable vocabularies. New acoustic modeling techniques and search methods are proposed in the area of robust, speaker-independent continuous speech recognition. Randomized search techniques are used to refine and improve the topologies and clustered training of allophone hidden Markov models. A new approach for word hypothesization and pronunciation modeling is proposed, based on pseudo-syllabic units. Algorithms are described for transforming a lattice of syllables into words, and learning the phonotactics of syllables automatically in a statistical framework. Next, a multi-grammar method for generating alternative hypotheses is presented, together with the method's experimental evaluation in a telephone-based spelled word recognition system. A blueprint is given for building time and memory-optimized speech decoders. Finally, analysis and recognition techniques are applied to the problem of enhancing the intelligibility of speech produced by alaryngeal speakers.</description><creator>Galler, Michael.</creator><contributor>De Mori, Renato (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Methods for more efficient, effective and robust speech recognition Michael Galler.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f30r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td839</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042v618</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In an interdisciplinary study, I argue that narrative fiction centred around old women, through its appeal to readers' imaginations, can challenge the ageism which currently governs how old women are scripted and depicted. Chapter one situates media broadcasts amidst other discourses, such as academic theory, medical language, gerontology, and popular feminism, which confront---or avoid confronting---old women. To counter common, negative cultural depictions, chapter two examines Margaret Lock and Simone de Beauvoir's engagements with narratives of aging. I combine de Beauvoir's constructivist La Vieillesse and midlife fiction with Jean-Paul Sartre's What is Literature?, Martha Nussbaum's Poetic Justice, and Mieke Bal's Narratology to articulate how narrative fiction can compel what I call a committed reader to reimagine social possibilities for old women. Chapter three foregrounds old age as a new category of analysis for Margaret Laurence's The Stone Angel, sifting through her metaphors of decrepitude to set up a model for studying three potential, late life, female social roles. Chapter four connects Joan Barfoot's Duet for Three with Hiromi Goto's Chorus of Mushrooms, which both depart from the previous age-as-decrepitude convention, to propose that the role of grandmother offers old women opportunities to give freely and benefit from non-possessive love, in a family context. In chapter five, I examine how gerontological nursing textbooks theorize institutional care to illuminate how Edna Alford's A Sleep Full of Dreams and Shani Mootoo's Cereus Blooms at Night facilitate an intergenerational bond within nursing homes. Caregivers' communicative strategies in each text exemplify how readers' imaginative engagement could begin to counter negative cultural attitudes. In chapter six, I explore how female friendship, as depicted in Barfoot's Charlotte and Claudia Keeping in Touch and Cynthia Scott's The Company of Strangers, offers old women an interdependence which enables the self sufficiency they often (are considered to) lack, eschewing a old age versus youth binary opposition. I conclude that narrative fiction provides opportunities to shift cultural meanings of the conventionally negative term old, so that committed reading can transform imagined possibilities and lead to new perceptions of old women.</description><creator>Chivers, Sally.</creator><contributor>Westphal, Sarah (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Women in literature.</subject><subject>Old age in literature.</subject><title>The literary potential of old age in Simone de Beauvoir, The stone angel, and new Canadian narratives /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741t517.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042v618</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n498f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>5-Oxo-L-prolinase (5-OPase) is involved in the synthesis and metabolism of glutathione (GSH) in the gamma-glutamyl cycle. The present project is to investigate (1) the level and distribution of 5-OPase in human tissues, (2) the potential application of a 5-OPase modulator, L-2-oxothiazolidine-4-carboxylate (OTZ), in selective modulation of GSH in normal versus tumor cells in cancer chemotherapy, and (3) the role of 5-OPase in cellular GSH modulation. First, Compared to rat tissues, 5-OPase activity was found to be generally low in human tissues and no specific distribution pattern was observed. A polyclonal rabbit anti-rat 5-OPase antibody was produced with high affinity and specificity and it was shown to crossreact with human 5-OPase. Immunohistochemistry analysis revealed that 5-OPase was localized in the structures that have typical absorptive or secretary function. By Western blot, normal human lung and stomach tissues showed significantly higher 5-OPase levels than their paired tumors, while the other tissues examined showed case-dependent patterns. Second, OTZ, a 5-oxo-L-proline analog that is metabolized to cysteine by 5-OPase, was shown in vivo to increase the GSH level in normal bone marrow cells while paradoxically decreasing it in rat mammary tumors and sensitizing the tumors to the alkylating agent melphalan. When the human breast cancer cell line MCF7 was treated with OTZ in combination with melphalan, the cytotoxicity of melphalan was increased relative to that of melphalan alone, and this effect was reversed by the addition of glutamate or 5-oxo-L-proline. OTZ treatment decreased the GSH levels in MCF7 cells but increased the GSH levels in normal human breast MCF10A cells. Therefore, in tumor cells where glutamate is limited in GSH synthesis, OTZ increases melphalan toxicity by limiting glutamate production from 5-OPase for GSH synthesis. Third, the expression of transfected 5-OPase in MCF7 cells decreased the cellular GSH level, sensitized the Cells to melphalan toxicity, and diminished the sensitizing effect of OTZ on melphalan toxicity; while exposure of both normal and cancerous human cells to GSH depleting agents led to an increased expression of 5-OPase both in vitro and in vivo. These results indicate a critical interaction between cellular GSH levels and 5-OPase activity that could be important in GSH modulation in therapeutic settings.</description><creator>Chen, Xiang, 1968-</creator><contributor>Batist, Gerald (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Characteriization of 5-Oxo-L-prolinase in glutathione modulation and cancer chemotherapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx12h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n498f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xn379</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lamina I neurons constitute a major output pathway from the dorsal horn of the spinal cord, relaying sensory information to the brain. Investigating how the excitability of these neurons is controlled is important for the understanding of nociceptive processing. The extensive co-localization of the major inhibitory neurotransmitters GABA (gamma-aminobutyric acid) and glycine in the marginal zone of the rat spinal cord, raises the issue of their respective role in this spinal area. Therefore, I developed a spinal cord slice preparation that allowed us to clearly delineate lamina I neurons for in vitro studies. I used whole cell patch clamp recording in identified lamina I neurons to study spontaneously occurring inhibitory postsynaptic currents (IPSCs), and stimulus evoked IPSCs. In particular, spontaneous miniature (action potential independent) IPSCs (mIPSCs) were studied as they are thought to reflect transmitter release from single vesicles. An important initial finding was that lamina I neurons were almost exclusively bombarded by glycine receptor (GlyR)-mediated mIPSCs. However, all cells appeared to express both GABA A receptors (GABAARs) and GlyRs. Moreover, recording of mIPSCs in the presence of a benzodiazepine revealed GABAAR-mediated mIPSCs with kinetic properties consistent with the interpretation that GABA ARs are likely located at extrasynaptic sites in lamina I neurons. Thus, GABA and glycine appeared to be co-released from the same synaptic vesicles. Together with IPSCs evoked from low- and high-intensity electrical stimulations, the results indicated that glycine is responsible for most tonic inhibitory control in lamina I, while GABAAR-mediated inhibition may be more relevant for the control of evoked input. Paired-pulse stimulations indicated that tonically released GABA appeared to first serve to activate presynaptic GABAB autoreceptors. To test the plasticity of GABAergic and glycinergic systems in lamina I, I have investigated their possible</description><creator>Chéry, Nadège.</creator><contributor>de Koninck, Yves (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Inhibitory control of neurons in the marginal zone (lamina I) of the rat spinal cord</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng37q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xn379</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97ks14z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The GSG (G&amp;barbelow;RP33, S&amp;barbelow;am68, G&amp;barbelow;LD-1) domain is a tripartite protein module of ~200 amino acids. It consists of an hnRNP K homology (KH) domain and two flanking regions N- and C-terminal to the KH domain Called the NK region and CK region, respectively. The KH domain embedded in the GSG domain has longer loops 1 and 4 compared to other KH domains. The physiological significance of the GSG domain is demonstrated by the fact that genetic mutations in the GSG domain result in developmental defects in various species. The primary goal of this thesis is to characterize the biochemical properties and functions of the GSG domain. We demonstrated that the GSG domain proteins Sam68, Qk1, GRP33, and GLD-1 are RNA-binding proteins that self-associate into multimers. Sam68 complexes bound homopolymeric RNA and the SH3 domains of p59fyn and phospholipase Cgamma1 in vitro, indicating that Sam68 associates with RNA and signaling molecules as a multimer. The formation of Sam68 complex was inhibited by p59fyn, suggesting that Sam68 oligomerization is regulated by tyrosine phosphorylation. Deletion studies in Sam68 and Qk1 demonstrated that the GSG domain is required for both self-association and RNA binding. Sam68 oligomerization requires the extended loops 1 and 4 of the KH domain and the Qk1 dimerization domain is mapped to the NK region. A Qk1 lethal point mutation, altering glutamic acid 48 to a glycine in the NK region, abolishes Qk1 self-association but has no effect on its ability to bind total cellular RNA. The mutant Qk1 protein is more potent than wild-type Qk1 in inducing apoptosis when expressed in NIH 3T3 cells, suggesting that failure to dimerize may be the molecular mechanism for the embryonic lethality. In addition to mediating self-association and RNA binding, the Sam68 GSG domain plays a role in protein localization. We demonstrated by indirect immunofluorescence studies that Sam68 is concentrated in novel nuclear structures, termed Sam</description><creator>Chen, Taiping, 1963-</creator><contributor>Richard, Stephane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Biochemical and functional characterization of the GSG (GRP33, Sam68, GLD-1) domain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579t95q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks14z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343t814</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The convective fluid-to-particle heat transfer coefficient (hfp ) is one of the critical factors influencing the process design for multi phase food products, in continuous tubeflow systems. Determination of hfp associated with moving particles poses a unique challenge to investigators because of the difficulty in monitoring the temperature of moving particles without interfering with the particle motion. Two different techniques involving particle motion were developed to evaluate hfp and to study the effects of factors influencing hfp, associated with spherical particles under tube-flow conditions. Spherical Nylon particles with centrally located fine-wire flexible thermocouples, were suspended from the upper mid-section of a curved glass tube in order to provide lateral movement of the particle as the tube was subjected to oscillatory motion. A full factorial experimental design was studied involving spherical particles made of Aluminum epoxy and Nylon of different diameters (12.7 to 17.5 mm), particle linear velocities (0.06 to 0.21 m/s), heating medium viscosities (0 to 1% Carboxymethyl cellulose, CMC) and fluid temperatures (60 to 80°C). The above factors had a significant (p &lt; 0.001) effect on hfp. Depending on experimental conditions the values of h fp varied from 350 to 2000 W/m2K. Overall, hfp values associated with the aluminum epoxy particle were about 30% higher than that for the Nylon particle. A calorimetric method was developed to evaluate hfp associated with a freely moving particle. The calorimetric method was used to evaluate the effect of fluid flow rate, viscosity and temperature, as well as particle size on the associated hfp under tube-flow conditions. Experiments were carried out using different flow rates (9 to 19 L/min), fluid viscosity (0 to 1% CMC solution) and fluid temperature (50 to 70°C) as well as Aluminum spherical particles of different sizes (19 to 25.4 mm). Values of hfp varied from 650 to 2660 W/m2K, and increased significantly (p &lt; 0.001) with an increase in fluid flow rate and particle size, whereas a decrease was observed with CMC concentration and temperature. Several correlations were developed in the form of Nusselt number as a function of other influencing dimensionless numbers. Nusselt numbers estimated from the developed equations showed good agreement with the experimental data (0.88 &lt; R2 &lt; 0.99). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Zareifard, Mohammad Reza.</creator><contributor>Ramaswamy, H. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Food -- Preservation.</subject><subject>Heat -- Transmission.</subject><subject>Nusselt number.</subject><title>Evaluation of fluid-to-particle heat transfer coefficient under tube-flow conditions involving particle motion with relevance to aseptic processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n92c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343t814</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bn44b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis studies the issues on sustainability with nonrenewable resources and on practical problem with environment: regulation to control pollution. The first essay proves the converse of Hartwick's rule with general production function. Hartwick's rule shows that if one reinvests all the rents from nonrenewable resource, then constant sustainable consumption can be maintained. This ensures intergenerational equity. The converse of Hartwick's rule is proved by directly solving ordinary differential equations. It means the constant consumption must imply the total reinvesting of the rents from the exhaustible resource, and so the Hartwick's rule prescribes the unique sustainable policy. In the second essay, Rawls' "just saving principle" is fonnulated with a model for constant utility in an intergenerational allocation framework. A term comparing consumption of adjacent generations is added to the utility function. The model is analyzed in the context of optimal control theory. In a two-sector economy, consumption growth is incorporated with equity. This property removes the disadvantage that a society starting out poor will be in such poverty forever, which is inherent in the model of constant consumption with nonrenewable resources. Different forms of generalized Hartwick's Rule are obtained. Optimal consumption path is characterized to achieve the highest utility. The third essay investigates the optimal emission tax schemes for oligopolistic firms with differentiated goods. In the model, pollution stock creates disutility on social welfare. Firms play dynamic games against themselves, trying to maximize the long-run profit given the tax rules and their opponents' behavior. Open-loop and Markov Nash Equilibria are studied. The model is analyzed with optimal control theory and differential game theory. Time-independent tax rules are shown to exist that guide polluting oligopolists to produce along socially optimum path. For linear market demand and quadratic damage function, the tax rules are shown to be linear in the pollution stock. Numerical examples show that even the polluting firm can receive subsidy at the periods when initial pollution stock is low. The optimal tax in general is dependent on the current pollutant stock. The results shed a light on policy making of the related market structure.</description><creator>Yang, Zhao, 1965-</creator><contributor>Cairns, R. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Pollution.</subject><subject>Sustainable development.</subject><title>Three essays on sustainable growth and environmental control</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s414s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn44b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d159m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cover of the ericaceous shrub Kalmia angustifolia L. (sheep's laurel or lamb's kill) expands rapidly on many clear-cut sites through central Newfoundland and northern Quebec. Previous laboratory and greenhouse studies on the effect of Kalmia on black spruce (Picea mariana (Mill.) B.S.P.) germinants and seedlings have demonstrated that extracts of Kalmia leaves and soil can reduce the germination rate and early root and shoot growth of black spruce. Observations in the field have suggested that Kalmia leaves and soil can reduce the germination rate and early rot and shoot growth of black spruce. Observations in the field have suggested that Kalmia reduces the growth of planted spruce seedlings. The experiments presented in this thesis were designed to determine the importance of Kalmia in controlling spruce growth and nutrition, and to document how the importance of Kalmia varies from site to site. Spruce seedlings growing in close proximity to Kalmia were found to be shorter and had lower foliar concentrations of N and P, and the roots of these seedlings had lower rates of mycorrhization and a more frequent occurrence of the pseudo-mycorrhizal/pathogenic fungus Phialocephala dimorphospora Kendrick. Results suggest that Kalmia impedes the N nutrition of spruce seedlings through the reduction of N mineralization rates and N availability. The results of path analysis further suggest that Kalmia had a direct effect on both spruce foliar N concentration and spruce growth. These findings do not demonstrate, though they are consistent with the suggestion, that Kalmia can affect spruce through allelopathic processes. Although we could not demonstrate that the reduction of rates of mycorrhization were due to indirect effects of Kalmia on spruce nutrition, we demonstrated that improving spruce nutrition in close proximity to Kalmia increased, though not significantly, the occurrence of mycorrhizae on spruce roots. Mycorrhizal symbiosis was shown to play a key role in t</description><creator>Yamasaki, Stephen H.</creator><contributor>Fyles, James W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Black spruce -- Ecology -- Newfoundland and Labrador.</subject><subject>Taiga ecology.</subject><subject>Sheep laurel.</subject><subject>Black spruce -- Ecology -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Influences of Kalmia angustifolia on black spruce in eastern Canada's boreal forest</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qt72v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d159m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784n39h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work studies supermanifolds and some of their applications, the goal being to study Hamiltonian systems, in particular the idea of complete integrability and some systems associated to coadjoint orbits. The approach taken here is that of Jadczyk and Pilch [21] where the anticommuting quantities enter at the "point" or coordinate level. This is in contrast with the approach that enters them at the function level by modifying the sheaf of functions (Kostant [24]). The basic definitions are given, such as supernumbers, superspaces, concepts of analysis and finally the notion of a supermanifold. Once the groundwork is established, questions relating to coadjoint orbits and differential equations will be considered. We can then proceed on to Hamiltonian systems and complete integrability, proving some of the staple theorems such as the Darboux theorem and Arnold's theorem and giving many examples of completely integrable systems. The structure of coadjoint orbits will also be discussed. We will determine when a coadjoint orbit is a supermanifold and also describe orbits in (duals) of loop algebras using associated line bundles.</description><creator>Jetzer, Frédéric.</creator><contributor>Hurtubise, Jacques (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Completely integrable systems on supermanifolds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w745.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784n39h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cc54m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the central nervous system, oligodendrocytes (OLs) form myelin that facilitates conduction of impulses along axons. An individual OL has the unique capability to myelinate up to 50 axons and to produce dramatic quantities of myelin proteins and lipids. The importance of myelin is well reflected in a number of neurological pathologies such as multiple sclerosis, a human demyelinating disease, where severe damage/loss of myelin and OLs are apparent. Although numerous studies have provided evidence of the possibility of remyelination in experimental models, successful remyelination in the demyelinated lesions has not been achieved. One approach to enhance the remyelinating capability of OLs may be to stimulate OL process outgrowth, a prerequisite event for myelin formation. In this thesis, I have tested three hypotheses to elucidate the mechanisms of process outgrowth by OLs. The first hypothesis is that other glial cell types provide stimulatory factors to promote process outgrowth by OLs. In this regard, I have found that astrocytes promote OL process outgrowth through the interaction between bFGF and astrocyte extracellular matrix (ECM). The second hypothesis that I tested is that protein kinase C activation in OLs is involved in mediating the promoting effects of astrocytes. My results describe that the inhibition of PKC activity attenuates the promoting action of bFGF and astrocyte ECM on process outgrowth by OLs. The final hypothesis that I tested is that matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) are utilized in OL process outgrowth, since the advancement of OL processes would require proteases to remodel the pericellular microenvironment. My results suggest that the production of MMP-9 by OLs, downstream of PKC activation, allows process outgrowth by OLs. Overall this thesis has addressed the mechanism of process outgrowth by OLs. I propose that astrocytes in close contact to OLs in vivo produce the proper stimuli (i.e. bFGF and ECM molecules) to OLs for PKC activation and that this leads to upregulation of MMPs, particularly MMP-9. This latter effector molecule is then utilized by OLs to advance their processes across a matrix to reach target axons. Although many questions still remain to be resolved to achieve satisfactory remyelination, the current portrait of the mechanism of OL process outgrowth should lead to a better appreciation of OL biology and myelin formation.</description><creator>Oh, Luke Yun Suk, 1969-</creator><contributor>Yong, V. W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Mechanisms of process outgrowth by oligodendrocytes : astrocytes, protein kinase C and matric metalloproteinase-9</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171z875.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc54m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f7651</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although radio-frequency (RF) methods have been used for decades in many heating and drying processes, there is still a need for more engineering design data related to the design of the applicators and the performance of these systems before costly prototypes are built. Energy, temperature, and the effect produced by the high frequency field parameters on biological materials need to be examined with regard to their effects on the resulting processing requirements. Wheat-seed infection by a fungus such as Fusarium graminearum can considerably lower the seed germination and the quality of the harvest. A study was thus conducted to determine the combined effect of different levels of RF power, temperature, and moisture content on the quality of seed-grade wheat and fungus inactivation. Similar treatment combinations were studied with seed-grade soybean in view on improving germination. With higher power, higher temperature (90°C) and higher moisture content (14%), the fungus mortality significantly increased, with a fungal vigour of less than 0.1, and the germination quality of the seeds decreased to a germination vigour below 0.3. For soybean seeds, only treatments of low RF intensity (60°C) were successful in improving germination vigour especially at lowest moisture content typically found in stored seeds. RF treated wheat was studied to identify the relationship between heating conditions and grain quality categorized in terms of kernel viability and structural damage. The potential of an RF thermal treatment to improve and extend the storability of vacuum packaged carrot sticks was investigated. The results have shown that it is possible to treat carrot sticks to 60°C in less than 2 min to reduce the initial microbial load. The RF-treatments maintained colour, the vacuum of the packages, and the excellent taste of the carrot sticks. RF heating was studied for the pasteurization of prepared samples of ham. The ham samples were brought to internal temperatures of 75 and 85°C, by RF heating with a 10 min residence time. The study indicates that radio-frequency heating can improve the storability of re-packed hams by reducing the bacterial load, reducing moisture loss during storage and maintaining an overall greater product quality. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Orsat, Valérie.</creator><contributor>Raghavan, G. S. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Dielectric heating.</subject><subject>Food -- Effect of heat on.</subject><subject>Soybean -- Seeds.</subject><subject>Radiation preservation of food.</subject><subject>Radio frequency.</subject><subject>Wheat -- Seeds.</subject><title>Radio-Frequency thermal treatments for agri-food products</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f297t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f7651</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bw225</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis provides a new approach to the codesign of digital systems. Complex systems tend to have mixed hardware-software components and are often subject to severe cost, performance, and design-time constraints. Our approach is to codesign these systems. The codesign approach allows the hardware and software designs to be tightly coupled throughout the design process. We focus on three key problems of system modeling, system analysis and system hardware-software partitioning. A key contribution of the thesis is to use hierarchy as it is available in modeling tools to handle complex system models but also during the codesign process to provide different modeling alternatives for the same input system. This use of the hierarchy, during the codesign process, allows the extension of the design space explored to find the final implementation. Another key contribution is the analysis of the hierarchical model for any target architecture using automatic estimators and scheduling algorithms. The performance estimation provides information on the performance of each block in the model when it is run on software resources or implemented on hardware. The scheduling algorithm is used to identify critical paths in the system execution and also to identify data dependency between the different model components. The last main contribution is the hardware-software partitioning algorithm. The proposed algorithm is based on a weighted graph partitioning heuristic. The partitioning algorithm performs into two nested loops. The outer loop is used to select the blocks which take a long time to execute in order to move them to hardware. This selection has the main objective of accelerating the system execution. The inner loop is used to select the neighbors of the block selected in the outer loop. The neighbors which have the most data dependency are first selected in order to minimize the hardware-software communication cost. We embody all the above concepts in a framework containing tools for hierarchical modeling, system analysis and partitioning. This new framework provides designers with a list of hardware-software implementations corresponding to the different levels in the system hierarchy. These codesign alternatives are provided with their performance and cost measures to allow the designer selecting the final implementation.</description><creator>Oudghiri, Houria.</creator><contributor>Rajski, Janucz (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A hardware/software partitioning framework for the codesign of digital systems /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pj05w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw225</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr34m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For a general fixed duration endpoint cost optimal control problem, the proximal aiming technique of nonsmooth analysis is employed in order to construct a discontinuous feedback law, all of whose Euler solutions are optimal to within a prescribed tolerance, universally for all initial data in a prescribed bounded set. The technique is adapted in order to construct universal near-saddle points for two-player fixed duration differential games of Krasovskii-Subbotin type.</description><creator>Nobakhtian, Soghra.</creator><contributor>Clarke, F. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Stern, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Near optimal universal feedback law in control and differential games</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v33x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr34m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494b155</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Von Willebrand factor (vWF) is a large multimeric protein found in plasma, intracellular stores of platelets and endothelial cells, as well as in the extracellular matrix. VWF has been implicated in venous and arterial thrombosis. Its importance in the primary adhesion of platelets at sites of vascular injury, and for platelet aggregation at very high shear rates was clearly demonstrated by other investigators. We have investigated the role of vWF in the recruitment of platelets activated with low concentrations of agonist, such as may be found with partial ADP secretion or thrombin generation in vivo, at physiologic shear rates (G) ranging from 100--2000 s--1. In the presence of ristocetin, soluble vWF bound to the glycoprotein Ib receptor (GPIb), and mediated shear-associated aggregation independently of the glycoprotein IIb-IIIa receptor (GPIIb-IIIa), with very few vWF monomer equivalents required to achieve high capture efficiencies (alphaG; reflecting initial rates of aggregation). Activation of washed platelets in the absence of soluble ligands, with low concentrations of the physiologic agonists, ADP or thrombin, resulted in good aggregation. Participation by GPIb was shearrate dependent, with the extent of contribution further varying with activation conditions. Inhibition of vWF-GPIb interactions in ADP and thrombin-induced aggregation, caused 25 and 50% inhibition of alpha G at G = 300 and 1000 s--1 respectively. alpha G's were similar for both agonists, and showed an absolute dependence on activated GPIIb-IIIa in each case. Further investigations using thrombin versus ADP as activator, however, revealed differences in participation by other surface-expressed ligands, in particular Fg. Thus, antibodies against TSP and Fg inhibited aggregation differentially, depending on shear rate and agonist activating conditions. Removal of catalytically-active thrombin from its receptors by antagonists hirudin and PPACK at ≥1 minute following activation, allowed normal secretion to occur from alpha-granules (monitored using P-selectin). However, the thrombin antagonists significantly decreased both platelet aggregation and surface-expression of vWF and TSP for platelets activated at low (0.05 U/ml), but not intermediate (0.2 U/ml) thrombin concentrations. In conclusion, all our studies demonstrated a consistently important cross-bridging role for vWF, but multi-ligand, multi-receptor participation was required for optimal shear-associated aggregation of platelet suspensions activated at very low agonist concentrations.</description><creator>Kasirer-Friede, Ana.</creator><contributor>Frojmovic, Mony M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Dynamics of von Willebrand factor-mediated platelet aggregation in laminar flow : physical and molecular determinants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n2882.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494b155</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655j287</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Clouston hidrotic ectodermal dysplasia (BED) is an autosomal dominant skin disorder that is characterized by nail dystrophy, hair defects and palmoplantar hyperkeratosis. This condition has been described in families of various ethnic origins but is particularly common in the French Canadian population. Using linkage analysis in eight French Canadian families segregating HED, we mapped the HED gene to the pericentromeric region of chromosome 13q with a combined two-point lod score of 8.12 at zero recombination from the marker D13S175. Haplotype analysis allowed us to define D13S143 as the telomeric flanking marker for the HED candidate region. We tested five genes that map to this region, connexin 26, connexin 46, fibroblast growth factor 9, zinc-finger ZNF198 and alpha tubulin TUBA2, for involvement in HED by PCR-SSCP analysis. No mutation specific to HED was found in any of them suggesting that they most likely are not defective in this disease. To facilitate the identification of the HED gene, we constructed a radiation hybrid (RH) map of 48 loci surrounding the HED locus on chromosome 13q. This map integrates 3 genes (TUBA2, GJbeta2 and FGF-9) and 18 ESTs with 27 markers including 19 polymorphic loci. A major inconsistency in order involving a reversed interval of six loci was found between our RH map and a YAC contig established in the region. We used Fiber-FISH and FISH on interphase nuclei to confirm our order. To refine the localization of the HED gene, we isolated eight new chromosome 13q polymorphic (CA)n markers and used seven of them along with three others in genetic analysis of a multiethnic group of 29 HED families. We demonstrated genetic homogeneity in HED in four families of French, Spanish, African and Malaysian origins and showed evidence for a strong founder effect in families of French Canadian origin. Recombination mapping placed the HED gene in a 2.4 cM region flanked by D13S1828 proximally and D13S1830 distally. Multipoint linkage and linkage disequilibrium analyses finely mapped the HED gene at 0--0.08 cM telomeric to D13S1835. These studies will greatly facilitate the physical mapping and positional cloning of the HED gene.</description><creator>Kibar, Zoha D.</creator><contributor>Rouleau, Guy A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Human gene mapping.</subject><subject>Ectodermal dysplasia -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Mapping of clouston hidrotic ectodermal dysplasia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881n732.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655j287</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rq45g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The use of tissue or tumor selective promoters in targeted gene therapy for cancer depends on strong and selective activity. Hexokinase type II (HK II) catalyzes the first committed step of glycolysis and is overexpressed in tumors, where it is no longer responsive to normal physiological inhibitors, e.g. glucagon. I show in a reporter gene assay activation of HK II in non-small cell lung carcinomas NCI-H661 and NCI-H460 at 61% and 40% of the activation observed with a constitutive promoter respectively, while it is only 0.9% in a number of different primary normal human bronchial epithelial cell lines (NHBEC). Similar results were observed in a variety of normal and tumor cells. Moreover, treatment of the transfectants with glucagon did not inhibit promoter/activation in the transformed H661 cells, while endogenous HK II in NHBEC is suppressed by glucagon, H460 and H661 cells infected with a recombinant adenovirus carrying a HK II/LacZ expression cassette, Ad HexLacZ, demonstrated beta-galactosidase activity, which correlated with the level of HK II promoter activation in these cells. Under similar conditions, no enzyme activity was observed in NHBEC. Cells were then infected with AdHexTk and treated with GCV. Our results demonstrate selectivity in toxicity with a 10--100 fold increase in IC 50 between lung cancer cells and NHBEC. There was also a 100-fold increase in IC50 in normal human mammary epithelial cells (NHMEC) relative to breast carcinoma cells MCF-7. This represents a novel use of the hexokinase type II as a selective promoter in cancer gene therapy. Other factors important in suicide gene therapy were explored. Pharmacological modulation of the bystander effect using 8-bromo-cAMP, observed in HSVTk/GCV suicide killing, was demonstrated to enhance killing efficacy by 50% when a small proportion of a target population was gene modified. The phenomenon of cellular resistance to HSVTk/GCV was examined and in a novel finding, we demonstrated dramatic int</description><creator>Katabi, Maha M.</creator><contributor>Batist, Gerald (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Transcriptional targeting of suicide genes in cancer gene therapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935469b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq45g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988m73x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the most critical tasks facing the world in the post-cold war era is to eliminate nuclear proliferation. With the recent nuclear tests by India and Pakistan, the subject of nuclear proliferation has returned to the forefront of international politics. Taking issue with the complacent belief that only a few states unnecessarily jeopardize international peace by acquiring nuclear weapons, I argue that many states in territorial protracted conflict are generally proliferants because of their specific security concerns. Demonstrating how individual and domestic level motivations are not the key determinants of the nuclear choices of the South Asian and Middle Eastern states, I emphasize the role of systemic level motivation, particularly security, in their nuclear decisions. Through a close examination of these states' nuclear weapons choices, I develop a new appraisal of the territorial protracted conflict states' potential to proliferate. While high war-probability has provoked virtually all of these protracted conflict states to seek nuclear deterrent capability and become proliferants, the variations in the type of conflict, regional power structure and geographical proximity have brought about variations in the pace of proliferation among these states. Finally, I expand the implications of this study for IR theory, especially with regard to Realist theory, nuclear deterrence, post-cold war world order, and nuclear arms control treaties. I conclude that the resolution of the roots of regional conflicts will most effectively ensure that more states do not embark on a nuclear weapons program. It is, however, naive to expect the new nuclear states to roll back their weapons programs.</description><creator>Khan, Saira.</creator><contributor>Paul, T. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Nuclear nonproliferation.</subject><subject>Deterrence (Strategy)</subject><subject>Nuclear weapons -- South Asia.</subject><subject>Nuclear weapons -- Middle East.</subject><title>Nuclear proliferation in protracted conflict regions : a comparative study of South Asia and the Middle East</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp050.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988m73x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dt78t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>At low temperature, we have used thermal conductivity as a directional probe of the residual normal fluid in two superconductors, UPd2Al 3 (a heavy fermion) and YBa2Cu3O7-delta (a high-Tc cuprate). By extrapolating our measurements to zero temperature, we can shed light on zero energy quasiparticles and the structure of the superconducting gap. For both superconductors, we review measurements pertaining to the density of states. In the case of the heavy fermion superconductor UPd2Al 3, we have found a finite anisotropy between b axis and c axis heat conduction, which excludes those gap structures with only zeroes along c or in the equatorial plane of a spherical Fermi surface; however, our results are consistent for two line nodes equidistant from the equatorial plane, as in the A 1g gap. Comparisons to theory developed for UPt3 show qualitative agreement with two hybrid gaps with strong spin-orbit coupling, of E2u and E 1g symmetry. For YBa2Cu3O7-delta, because the gap symmetry has been established as dx2-y2 , we can go much further as regards a quantitative analysis. The anisotropy in the thermal conductivity was measured along both high symmetry directions. A residual T-linear term in kappa(T) was observed in both directions. In the CuO2 planes (J∥ a) the magnitude of the residual normal fluid conduction is perfectly consistent with the temperature dependence of the penetration depth, within the theory for a d-wave superconductor. The value for J∥b is slightly larger, yielding an anisotropy ratio of 1.3 +/- 0.3. This is considerably weaker than that observed in the normal state resistivity, pointing to a suppressed heat conduction by quasiparticles in the chains, either due to strong defect scattering or a gapped excitation spectrum. With the application of an external magnetic field (up to 8 T), we can study the effect of vortices on quasiparticle transport. The residual linear term increases with field, directly reflecting the occupation of extended quasiparticle states. A study for different Zn impurity concentrations reveals a good agreement with recent calculations for a d-wave gap. The magnitude of the suppression indicates that Zn impurity scattering needs to be treated in the resonant impurity scattering limit, until now an unverified assumption. Together with specific heat measurements, we obtain a quantitative measure of the gap near the nodes.</description><creator>Chiao, May.</creator><contributor>Taillefer, Louis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Zero energy quasiparticle conduction in unconventional superconductors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r7261.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dt78t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x3112</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>E1B 19kDa protein (19K), a member of Bcl-2 family of protein, is an adenovirus early gene product. It functions to suppress apoptosis of the host cell caused by viral infection. The exact role of E1B 19kDa in regulating apoptosis in response to many different death stimuli has not been investigated. We found that hygromycin B, an aminoglycoside antibiotic that is used to establish stable mammalian cell lines, kill cells by apoptosis. Apoptosis induced by Hygromycin B is p53-independent and can be blocked both by E1B 19kDa and Bcl-2, showing that E1B 19kDa, like Bcl-2, may confer protection against apoptosis in a variety of circumstances. The sequence similarities between E1B 19kDa and Bcl-2 are largely restricted to the BH1 and BH3 domains. Our sequence alignment analysis shows that E1B 19kDa also contains a BH4 region overlapping its BH3 domain. We find that the BH1 domain of E1B 19kDa contributes to its anti-apoptotic function and its ability to interact with Bax. A conserved residue Gly 87 in the BH1 domain of E1B 19kDa that is critical for Bcl-2 and Bax interaction is also important for the E1B 19kDa and Bax interaction. We do not detect an interaction between E1B 19kDa and Bad, suggesting that E1B 19kDa is a structural and functional homolog of Bcl-2 but also has its unique features. Bap31, a 28kDa polytoptic integral protein of the endoplasmic reticulum, is part of an ER protein complex that also includes Bcl-2/Bcl-xL, procaspase-8, and a CED-4-like protein. E1B 19kDa does not interact with Bap31; nor does it interact with Bcl-2/Bcl-xL. We have made a set of chimeric E1B 19kDa proteins carrying different BH domains from Bcl-2 to test their protein-protein interaction properties. We show that the BH3 domain of Bcl-2, when substituted for the homologous region of E1B 19kDa, confers the properties of interaction with Bap31 and Bcl-xL onto 19K. The subcellular distribution and antiapoptotic function of the 19K/Bcl-2BH3 is very similar to that of wild type 19K. These results show that the BH3 domain of Bcl-2/Bcl-xL has an important role in mediating Bcl-2/Bcl-xL and Bap31 interaction.</description><creator>Chen, Gang, 1964-</creator><contributor>Shore, Gordon C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>The anti-apoptotic function of adenovirus E1B 19kDa protein /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924d435.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x3112</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft07d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work is a study of in vivo neuronal injury of the central nervous system (CNS). It investigates the neuropathological sequelae and mechanisms involved in both the response to and recovery from CNS injury. Two animal models are used: traumatic brain injury (TBI) and seizure, both performed in the rat. Using the cortical impact injury model of TBI in the rat, the pathophysiological results of injury and the induction of protracted apoptotic cell death in specific brain regions of traumatically injured animals are addressed. Following TBI, silver stain histological analysis detected the appearance of dystrophic neurons in the hippocampus, cortex, amygdala, thalamus, and hypothalamus. Dystrophic cells were detected for at least 2 weeks following injury, and their location correlated with regions of cell loss. These regions have been shown to be functionally related to the post-injury behavioural deficits observed in this paradigm. These dystrophic cells were demonstrated to be apoptotic by morphological examination using electron microscopy, gel electrophoresis and in situ detection of DNA fragmentation, and nuclear condensation detected using Hoechst stain. Recovery from the behavioural deficits caused by the injury is accompanied by biochemical changes that suggest that regeneration of the affected neuronal systems is occurring. To address this aspect of the neuronal response to injury and to investigate a possible biochemical mechanism, netrin induction following pilocarpine-induced seizure (a model of human temporal lobe epilepsy) was investigated. First, netrin, an embryonically-expressed axonal guidance molecule was shown to be expressed in the adult rat brain, and the distribution of netrin protein and mRNA was mapped. Then, by sampling tissue at successive time points following pilocarpine-induced seizure in rats, netrin and the axon-attracting netrin receptor DCC were demonstrated to be induced in brain regions associated with neuronal cell damage and l</description><creator>Colicos, Michael Adrian.</creator><contributor>Kennedy, T. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>The neuronal response to injury /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731563k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft07d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33475</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>