<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:00:03Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2625" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xk76v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following work is divided in two sections. In the review section, we analyse "La riviere sans repos", a collection of stories by Gabrielle Roy, published in 1970. This analysis explains the impact of the break-up of the social fabric of esquimo traditions on intergenerational interactions among families. For quite some time, the arrival of white culture within the traditional esquimo civilization did not include the brutal and accelerated rhythm, as it has since World War II. Nevertheless, at the time where Roy sets the events in her book, between 1945 and 1968, one can definitely speak of culture shock. Hence, we would like to understand how the esquimo characters in the book react to this brutal culture change, as they are forced to question their identity along with their traditional values. In addition, we explain how these excessively rapid changes influence the interactions between four different generations. The second section of this work, the creative section, is linked to the first by the coming together of members of a single family. " Jamais tu ne m'avais dit", a collection of short stories, includes individuals of different generations (for example, a parent and his child, a grandmother and her granddaughter), who are forced to truly communicate with one another, following an event or a recent discovery.</description><creator>Van Dun, Aïcha.</creator><contributor>Boucher, Jean-Pierre (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Roy, Gabrielle, 1909- Rivière sans repos.</subject><subject>Conflict of generations in literature.</subject><title>Chocs culturels et générationnels chez G. Roy ; Jamais tu ne m'avais dit</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107114m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk76v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676x974</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis offers Plato's readers a different approach to reading the Gorgias. Chief consideration is given to Plato's artistic plan as a rhetorician, rather than a strict moral philosopher. The display of his rhetorical genius works to support his arguments in favour of a certain kind of rhetoric. The usual argument that Plato is attacking rhetoric is rejected here. In its place the reader will see a Plato refuting his contemporaries' spurious form of rhetoric, as the rhetoric Plato represents and displays is a true craft, as genuine as the dialectic. Rhetoric is not without its shortcomings, but neither is the dialectic, and though Socrates says otherwise, it is because Plato is not Socrates. The argument for two Socrates is not advanced here, but his rhetorical tendencies are expressed in three debates whose overall message culminates in his prophetic myth of life after death. Plato introduces a new kind of visionary rhetoric that Socrates does not explicitly defend but which he nonetheless displays within the drama of the dialogue. Plato's views on rhetoric, then, are not merely the sum of Socrates' views on the Gorgias' theme, rather it is within the dramatic presentation of different views on rhetoric that Plato seeks to convey his defence of rhetoric.</description><creator>Tucker, Jiri Arthur Augustine.</creator><contributor>Silverthorne, Michael J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Rhetoric, Ancient.</subject><subject>Plato. Gorgias.</subject><subject>Plato -- Views on rhetoric.</subject><title>A reprise of rhetoric in the Gorgias : is Plato a master rhetorician?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s7021.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676x974</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Classics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k35696572</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The current study was designed to examine characteristics associated with interaction in group versus dyads in middle childhood. Two classes of children in grades one through five participated in the study. Children were identified by their peers as participating in groups or dyads. Teachers then rated the characteristics of these children. Analyses of children interacting in groups versus dyads showed that both boys and girls in groups were perceived to be more competitive, to value their friends more, to receive more attention from peers and to be more emotionally expressive than children interacting in dyads. It was also found that boys in both groups and dyads were perceived to lack more self-control and to be more active and loud than girls. The measures of self-confidence, lack of self-control, emotional difficulties, activity level, and thoughtfulness did not differ for children who interacted in groups versus dyads. Findings are discussed in terms of the functions of group versus dyadic interaction.</description><creator>Tricerri, María F.</creator><contributor>Benenson, Joyce F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Social interaction in children.</subject><subject>Sex differences (Psychology) in children.</subject><title>Characteristics associated with group versus dyadic interaction in boys and girls</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0325172.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k35696572</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zs749</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Scientistic authors in the latter half of the 19 th century and the early 20th century, such as Ernest Renan and H. G. Wells, discounted revealed religion. Yet they believed in the secular myth of an imminent technological Eden and they elevated science itself to the dignity of a religion. In so doing, they shaped bold visions of the future, drawing heavily on a millenary store of Western myth and metaphor. In historical terms, the myth of an imminent technological Eden represents a survival and a fusion of the ancient Greek myth of the Golden Age along with three Judeo-Christian myths: Biblical time, Earthly Paradise and the Apocalypse. Since the Enlightenment, the process of secularization has drained the religious content of such myths, although it does not deprive them of any of their deeply emotional force. This explains why the 19th century myth of an imminent technological Eden has considerable staying-power, in spite of the many events since 1945 which seem to discredit it.</description><creator>Tombs, George, 1956-</creator><contributor>Boss, Valentine (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Technological forecasting.</subject><subject>Prophecies in literature.</subject><subject>Utopias in literature.</subject><title>Paradise, the Apocalypse and science : the myth of an imminent technological Eden</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225d221.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zs749</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vn12j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an examination of the political and educational implications of environmentalism. This movement has been characterized by oversimplifications which have led to confusion about the proper role of humans with respect to the natural world. The modern world system was founded on the concept of human domination of nature, and this led to degradation of both the natural and the social environment. The radical ecological response to this view rejected any role for human subjects other than protection, and called for a rejection of technology and a return to pre-modern conditions. This investigation proposes that citizens in a postmodern world should be characterized by ecological literacy: a comprehensive understanding of the natural and social environment, and the responsibilities of humans in it. It is argued that this will be possible only with political arrangements which are selectively decentralized, preserving local initiative and promoting community resilience.</description><creator>Tittley, Teresa Brewster.</creator><contributor>Morris, Ron (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Environmentalism -- Political aspects.</subject><subject>Environmental education.</subject><title>Ecological literacy as a response to modernism : educational and political implications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v065v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vn12j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xh01n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This examination looks at the contextual and cultural implications of learning, using sources from story-telling traditions. The thesis proposes that perceptions of reality are manipulable fictions. It uses the teachings of the American visionary writer, Lynn Andrews, to illustrate how a person's perceptions can be altered to his or her advantage, and how, when not properly attended to, perceptions can manipulate the person. Andrews' work is compared to that of Carlos Castaneda and other contemporary visionary writers, as well as to very old teachings from an oral tradition. I have set the study of Andrews' insights in the social, environmental and educational contexts of North America in the final years of the 20th century, as I experience those contexts in my private and professional academic life. I conclude that including knowledge such as that which Andrews offers, in the menu of teachings available to and tolerated by North Americans, is essential. The thesis details a set of extra-ordinary teachings proffered by Lynn Andrews, purportedly of native origin. Attention is given both to the techniques used to teach and to the exceptional knowledge imparted. In Part I, I speak of the distinct culture of learning which I come from, and reply to detractors of cross-cultural teaching. I outline the general purposes which I believe these teachings can serve in any culture, and most particularly in the global culture of life on earth. Part II is a detailed exposition of the teachings in the first two books by Lynn Andrews. Part III addresses some of the challenges confronting those who wish to take her teachings to heart and pass them on to others. This section makes it clear that such teachings are not appropriate for everyone, and are not to be instituted in a systemic context.</description><creator>Stephenson, Sandra, 1958-</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Andrews, Lynn V.</subject><subject>Folklore and education.</subject><subject>Indians of North America -- Religion.</subject><title>Seven arrows teaching : extra-ordinary teaching and learning by apprenticeship : a study of teaching techniques described in the works of Lynn V. Andrews</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z3136.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh01n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r556</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the 1910s, there was an increasing concerted effort on the part of Canadian artists to create art and literature which would affirm Canada's sense of nationhood and modernity. Although in agreement that Canada desperately required its own culture, the Canadian artistic community was divided on what Canadian culture ought to be. For the majority of Canadian painters, writers, critics and readers, the future of the Canadian arts, especially poetry and painting, lay in Canada's past. These cultural conservatives championed art which mirrored its European and Canadian predecessors. Their domination of the arts left little room for the progressive minority, who rebelled against prevailing artistic standards. In painting, the Group of Seven was one of the first groups to challenge this stranglehold on Canadian culture. The Group waged a protracted and vocal campaign for the advancement of Canadian approaches and subjects. In literature, A. J. M. Smith and F. R. Scott began a similar movement to modernize Canadian poetry and reform critical standards. By examining the poetry, essays, criticism and archival material of these poets and painters, the thesis establishes strong parallels between the modernist campaigns of these two groups and investigates this cross-fertilization between the modern Canadian arts.</description><creator>Roza, Alexandra M.</creator><contributor>Trehearne, Brian (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Canadian literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Smith, A. J. M. (Arthur James Marshall), 1902- -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Group of Seven (Group of artists)</subject><subject>Scott, F. R. (Francis Reginald), 1899-1985 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Towards a modern Canadian art 1910-1936 : the Group of Seven, A.J.M. Smith and F.R. Scott</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd86g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r556</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j67316197</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose was to examine the effect of shaft stiffness on puck velocity and response characteristics of the stick during performance of a slap shot. Six elite male ice hockey players performed 6 slap shots with 4 sticks of different shaft stiffness designated as medium (13 N/m), stiff (16N/m), extra (17 N/m) and pro stiff (19 N/m). These four levels represent the range in stiffness of sticks available to hockey players. The mechanics of the slap shot were evaluated by recording ground reaction forces and kinematics from high speed filming and a radar gun. Data were analyzed with a 3-way repeated measures ANOVA for 7 dependant variables---puck velocity, peak Z force, peak Y force, time to achieve peak Z force, time to achieve peak Y force, peak deflection and time to peak deflection of the shaft. Results indicated: (1) the stick with shaft stiffness of 13 N/m produced the highest puck velocity, the greatest amount of shaft deflection, the longest time to peak deflection and the lowest peak Z forces; (2) time to obtain peak forces in the Y and Z directions were similar across level of shaft stiffness; (3) puck velocity was influenced by the interaction of subject and stiffness; (4) variability in performance measures across subjects was greater than the variability across stiffness.</description><creator>Rothsching, Norman.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Hockey -- Equipment and supplies.</subject><title>The effect of shaft stiffness on the performance of the ice hockey slap shot /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r318b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67316197</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft62g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study is designed to outline the approaches towards moral development and moral education over the past four decades, and to show how the findings of second-generation cognitive science compel a re-thinking of the role of narrative and narrative thinking in moral education. Examined also, are the psychological and philosophical assumptions that underpin and lend substantiation to these findings. Narrative, as an essential instrument for moral education, is now on the way to being rehabilitated, by virtue of the emerging trend to apply the narrative method of autobiographical mythology, or personal narrative to moral education. Through the increased implementation of this process, it is envisioned that the cognitive-developmental, rationalistic view of moral education will be supplanted by other cognitive models, with their implications for moral development and moral education, of a nature closer to the way human beings make meaning of experience.</description><creator>Pousao-Lopes, Cecilia.</creator><contributor>Morris, R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Moral education.</subject><subject>Fiction -- Moral and ethical aspects.</subject><title>The mind values meaning above knowledge : narrative and moral education</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xh02x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft62g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h172w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the role nineteenth-century women's literary journals, specifically Ladies' Journal (1823--1833), played in the development of Russian literature. The longest-lived and most-circulated of the pre-Soviet women's literary journals, Ladies' Journal was well-positioned to have contributed to the on-going formation of a national literature through its influence on the Russian woman writer and reader. Ladies' Journal served as a forum for new Russian women writers and translators. It also promoted the discussion of women's issues. However, Ladies' Journal had a contradictory editorial policy concerning women and literature. While advocating women stake their own ground as writers, Ladies' Journal modeled the type of writer it wanted. The ideal writer was the inspiration of male poets and did not differ from the Romantic heroine or the ideal Romantic woman. This was a gesture in the spirit of the time, but it had consequences for Russian literature and for the poetics and politics of Russian women's journals to come.</description><creator>Possehl, Suzanne René.</creator><contributor>Austin, Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Literature and society -- Russia -- History -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Russian literature -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Women's periodicals, Russian -- Russia.</subject><title>A women's journal, or, The birth of a Cosmo girl in 19th-century Russia /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dv32d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h172w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483m34b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The number of United Nations interventions in civil conflicts has increased since the end of the Cold War. Traditional peace-keeping has proved ill-suited to deal with them; second-generation, multi-task peace-keeping operations have emerged as a substitute. These new operations have strained UN resources and the willingness of nations to provide troops is not as forthcoming as it used to be. Therefore, the UN has shared in recent years the burden of conflict resolution with regional organisations and ad hoc coalitions. This thesis studies multinational interventions in three conflicts (Somalia, Haiti and Bosnia) and asks what lessons can be drawn with regard to co-operation between the different actors involved on the ground. Moreover, it discusses the problems involved in the transfer of an operation between the UN and non-UN actors.</description><creator>Orsini, Dominique.</creator><contributor>Brynen, Rex (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>United Nations -- Armed Forces -- Bosnia and Hercegovina.</subject><subject>United Nations -- Armed Forces -- Somalia.</subject><subject>United Nations -- Armed Forces -- Haiti.</subject><subject>Intervention (International law) -- International cooperation.</subject><subject>United Nations -- Armed Forces.</subject><title>Multinational operations in Somalia, Haiti and Bosnia : a comparative study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c2838.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483m34b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr172041x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since its publication in 1981, Cronica de una muerte anunciada, has been in general interpreted in terms of tragedy. The death of Santiago Nasar, which is due to the rigid observance of a code of honour concerning women's virginity before marriage, appears to be absurd. Nonetheless, in my opinion, the death of Santiago Nasar acquires meaning the moment the victim is symbolically reborn in the love that eventually will join the disgraced couple. My interpretation, which relies on both historiography and narrative, is supported by an evaluation of the narrator's role in this fictional world. Significantly enough, the narrator is none other than Gabriel Garcia Marquez who, through a self-splitting fictionalisation, appears as one more among the many characters. Thus, Garcia Marquez as the narrator and a character, relates the events and organizes them into a chronicle. In this sense, he assumes the role of "chronicler-narrator." Yet, he also assumes the role of "oracle-narrator," in the sense that he imbues Santiago Nasar's crime with a mythical dimension which reveals the message of love suggested in the novel. Another hermeneutic resource applied to my analysis is the analogy I draw between the novel and the Gospel, and my view of Santiago Nasar as a sort of Christ. In my opinion, the character's death is not meaningless because it appeals to give life to the love of a couple and to open the possibility of love for the other characters.</description><creator>Ochoa Reyes, José Luis.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>García Márquez, Gabriel, 1928- Crónica de una muerte anunciada.</subject><title>Autopsia de una muerte anunciada</title><language>spa</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720g110.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172041x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Hispanic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x353k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this thesis is to analyse the relationship between religion and revolution within the context of Egyptian Islamic culture. The discussion will begin with an investigation into the evolution of revolution as a concept, from its original scientific meaning within the writings of Copernicus to its current political meaning as a radical social break with the past. It will be argued that the revolutionary ideal of escaping fate and rationally constructing the future is the driving force behind the Modern era. Faith in the capacity of humanity for self-redemption could only arise after the scientific discoveries of the Renaissance began to disrupt the static metaphysical universe of the past. The concept of social development then arose in the Enlightenment as a quest for the liberation of reason so as to construct a new society free of myth and mystery. The discussion will then attempt to demonstrate that the culture of Egypt underwent a parallel philosophical development during the nineteenth and twentieth centuries due to the importation of modern technology. In order to prove this, the military reforms of Muhammad `Ali will be compared to Hobbe's concept of the Leviathan, the journalism of Muhammad `Abduh will be placed within the traditional Islamic debate concerning the ethical relationship between reason and revelation; the cult of nationalism will be contrasted with s&amp;dotbelow;ufi mysticism; the social project of the Nasser regime will be interpreted in light of Rousseau's conception of the liberal social contract; and the thesis will conclude with a discussion of the thought of Sayyid Qutb in terms of the failure of Modernity to fulfil the promise of the Enlightenment.</description><creator>Munro, Marc Andrew.</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Egypt -- History -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Islam -- Egypt -- History -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Revolutions -- Egypt.</subject><subject>Revolutions -- Religious aspects -- Islam.</subject><subject>Religion and politics -- Egypt.</subject><title>Religion and revolution in Egypt</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp938.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x353k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hf35v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Much of the success of the Allied Peninsular Army was due to the effectiveness of Wellington's supply system. The ability of Wellington to keep his army supplied presented him with an enormous advantage over the French. This paper examines the role logistics played in deciding the outcome of the war in the Peninsula as well as detailing the needs of the troops. The primary focus of this paper is the procurement, transport, and payment of supplies for the use of the Allied Army during the Peninsular War. Wellington's ability to consistently defeat French forces despite a substantial numerical disadvantage presents the thesis that the efficiency of Wellington's logistical system impacted the strategic situation to a significant degree. While superior logistics alone cannot win a war, their absence can lead to defeat, as the French learned to their detriment.</description><creator>McLauchlan, Tina M.</creator><contributor>Senior, Hereward (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Wellington, Arthur Wellesley, Duke of, 1769-1852.</subject><subject>Peninsular War, 1807-1814 -- Logistics.</subject><title>Wellington's supply system during the Peninsular War, 1809-1814</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j760d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hf35v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zd325</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The church and monastery of Brou, Bourg-en-Bresse were built under the attentive patronage of Margaret of Austria (1480--1530), Duchess of Savoy, Regent of the Netherlands and daughter of Maximilian I and Mary of Burgundy. Brou was intended to symbolically and economically secure the region for the Habsburgs as well as memorialize the glory of its patron. Located in Savoy, a strategic territory in the battle for Italy between the Habsburg Empire and France, Brou's secular and religious references, chosen by the patron herself, reflect her and her family's political needs. This paper explores Margaret of Austria's role as patron and creator of Brou, her political and propagandistic agenda, her pivotal role in its planning and construction, her architectural and stylistic choices and the results of her efforts and their reception.</description><creator>MacDonald, Deanna.</creator><contributor>Boker, Hans (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Margaret, of Austria, Regent of the Netherlands, 1480-1530.</subject><subject>Patronage, Political -- France and Italy -- Savoy.</subject><subject>Notre-Dame de Brou (Church)</subject><title>Margaret of Austria and Brou : Habsburg political patronage in Savoy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r991g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd325</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085n546</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis has explored the implementation of the primary health care strategy in Ghana, focusing on the Maternal Child Health program, one of main components of the strategy and the program that seems to have been most widely implemented in the country. The analysis has been concerned primarily with identifying the obstacles to the implementation of this strategy in rural areas of the country, where levels of utilization and participation have been found to be lower than what was hoped for by the government. It does this by using data collected through in-depth interviews and participant observation in three rural villages of the country. The findings reveal that a complex range of interrelated factors influence or deter women from utilizing and participating in the MCH program.</description><creator>Livingstone, Anne-Marie.</creator><contributor>Von Eschen, Donald (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Primary health care -- Ghana.</subject><subject>Maternal health services -- Ghana.</subject><title>Obstacles to primary health care : a three village study of the Maternal Child Health (MCH) Program in Ghana</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx59d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085n546</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zg674</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Government ownership of airports is inefficient and has led to large financial deficits in Canada. Terminals I and 11 at Pearson Airport are in desperate need of redevelopment. The Pearson Airport Agreements between the Federal Government and the Pearson Development Corporation ("PDC") to redevelop and operate Terminals I and II at Pearson Airport pursuant to a long term lease would have benefitted the Government through the receipt of the proceeds from the sale of the airports while being relieved of the burden of financing airport expansion. The cancellation of the Pearson Airport Agreements based on the faulty reasoning of the Nixon Report was contrary to the public interest. The Canadian Government plans to "commercialize" Airports which involves leasing them to Airport Authorities. The federal government has reached an agreement on terms for transfer of Pearson Airport to the Greater Toronto Airport Authority ("GTAA"). Pearson airport will be one of the first airports to be transferred to local control under the Liberal governments Canadian Airport Authority model. Commercialization amounts to a transfer of Airports from one part of the public sector to another. It is plagued by many of the inefficiencies that characterize Government operated Airports. Pearson Airport has significant market power. Pearson Airports market power can effectively be diffused by separating the airport's airside and groundside functions, and basing airside ownership on slots. Terminals I, II and III will be sold separately and will become the responsibility of several airport companies who will compete for Airlines and Passengers. Runways, taxiways and the apron would be owned and operated by a Corporation made up of investors and third party brokers.</description><creator>Lerner, Stephen, 1966-</creator><contributor>Janda, Richard (advisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Political Science, Public Administration.</subject><subject>Transportation.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Toronto's Pearson International Airport : airport commercialization/privatization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505257f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg674</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547t66c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Attending to the felt quality of experience, this work looks at how a community of Mexican campesinos go about thew life While cultivating coffee, trying to make sense of how villagers feel, know, and understand the world "on their own terms". The aim is to work through (and from) the plane of the body, a narrative strategy that seeks to convey some of the give an take of everyday life; the joy and salubrity that are often bounded in moments of good health, the sorrow and pain that poverty entails. But since "well being" is not "culture five" but guided by moral and aesthetic constraints, I map out the cultural "building blocks" to see how local notions of health and illness tie into feelings of integrity or fragmentation. Last, we look at what social ideals underscore notions of personhood and how these shape local experiences of land.</description><creator>Von Gunten Medleg, Dylan.</creator><contributor>Krohn, Roger (advisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Coffee growers -- Mexico -- Rio Negro.</subject><subject>Chiapas (Mexico) -- Social conditions.</subject><title>Cultivating coffee in the highlands of Chiapas : the aesthetics of health in the Mexican campesinato</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nb011.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547t66c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r56g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When the relative velocity between the different objects in a scene and the camera is relative large---compared with the camera's exposure time---in the resulting image we have a distortion called motion blur. In the past, a lot of algorithms have been proposed for estimating the relative velocity from one or, most of the time, more images. The motion blur is generally considered an extra source of noise and is eliminated, or is assumed nonexistent. Unlike most of these approaches, it is feasible to estimate the Optical Flow map using only the information encoded in the motion blur. This thesis presents an algorithm that estimates the velocity vector of an image patch using the motion blur only, in two steps. The information used for the estimation of the velocity vectors is extracted from the frequency domain, and the most computationally expensive operation is the Fast Fourier Transform that transforms the image from the spatial to the frequency domain. Consequently, the complexity of the algorithm is bound by this operation into O( nlog(n)). The first step consists of using the response of a family of steerable filters applied on the log of the Power Spectrum in order to calculate the orientation of the velocity vector. The second step uses a technique called Cepstral Analysis. More precisely, the log power spectrum is treated as another signal and we examine the Inverse Fourier Transform of it in order to estimate the magnitude of the velocity vector. Experiments have been conducted on artificially blurred images and with real world data, and an error analysis on these results is also presented.</description><creator>Rekleitis, Ioannis.</creator><contributor>Jones, David (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Visual motion estimation based on motion blur interpretation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g479m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r56g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sc56x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Diamonds unrivaled properties generate an enormous potential in industrial applications for thin film diamond coatings. Diamond has the highest values of hardness, thermal conductivity and elastic modules of any known material. Polycrystalline diamond coatings can be produced from thermal plasmas by Chemical Vapor Deposition (CVD). The films created by this process are often very non uniform over the deposition area. The properties of the free flowing plasma above the deposition surface and the plasma chemistry in the boundary layer above the growing film are believed to play fundamental roles in the formation of the diamond film and its uniformity. In this study, an Ar/H2/CH4 plasma (8.65% H 2, 0.25% CH4) was created by a rf inductively coupled plasma torch for the deposition of diamond thin films on a molybdenum substrate probe (5 mm diam.). With the probe surface oriented normal to the plasma flow, growth rates in the order of 70 gm/hr were obtained for highly crystalline continuous films. Temperature and electron density profiles in the plasma free flow were determined from measurements by emission spectroscopy. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Oberste Berghaus, Jürg.</creator><contributor>Meunier, J.-L. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Gitzhofer, F. (advisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Induction plasma deposition of diamond thin films</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225d239.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sc56x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jt45k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Monoculture corn (Zea mays L.) production may result in increased soil degradation through intensive cultivation and N fertilizer use. Intercropping may reduce these negative effects. The objectives of the study were to examine at two sites the effects of monocropping and intercropping corn on soft physical and chemical properties. A sandy loam soil of the Chateaugay series and a sandy loam soft of St Dainase series were used in a field experiment for 1993 and 1994 growing seasons. Soil with corn monoculture planted at 60 and 90 cm row width had lower soil, organic matter than that under intercrops. Soil aggregate stability treatment effects varied with soil. Corn intercropped with perennial rye grass (Lolium perenne L.) showed the highest of aggregate stability. Similar trends were noted with wet-sieved aggregate diameters. Monoculture corn tended to produce higher soil bulk density than intercrops. There was some evidence of compaction after late seeding of intercrops. Monoculture corn resulted in more acidity and lower pH than corn with intercrops. Extractable P and K by Mehlich III were lower in monoculture corn than corn-soybean intercrops. Intercropping tended to reduce residual soil NO3 -- levels but this effect varied with depth. Single and broadcast N application resulted in higher N residues with corn planted at 75 cm row width than split and banded application. Intercropping tended to reduce soil degradation and pollution as measured by aggregate stability and NO3 -- residues.</description><creator>Melkamu, Teshome.</creator><contributor>MacKenzie, A. F. (advisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content.</subject><subject>Ryegrasses.</subject><subject>Companion planting.</subject><subject>Corn -- Soils.</subject><title>Intercropping in corn : soil physical quality and soil inorganic nitrogen levels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537331d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt45k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w66345886</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of temperature on a 58-kDa phosphoprotein (PP58) have been examined in cell-free extracts of two alfalfa (Medicago sativa L.) cultivars, Apica and Trek. In the extracts prepared without the use of Triton X-100, PP58 is present in a 12,000 x g (P12), 28,000 x g (P28) and 100,000 x g (P100) pellets but is enriched in the P28 fraction. In these fractions PP58 is substantially and equally phosphorylated at both 4° and 24°C. When extracts are prepared in the presence Triton X-100, PP58 is present in the 28,000 x g supernatant (TXS fraction) is extensively dephosphorylated at 24°C but highly phosphorylated at 4°C. The phosphorylation of this protein increased sharply as temperature declined below 12°C, and was 15 times greater at 0° than at 24°C. The phosphorylation level doubled between 12° and 8°C and again between 8° and 4°C. Thus temperature effect is not mediated by Q10 effect. Interestingly, temperature-response curve of PP58 phosphorylation is similar to that of the reported cold-induced calcium influx (Plant Cell 7: 321-331). Labeling reactions carried out in the presence of [gamma-35S]thioATP indicated that low temperature inhibited the dephosphorylation reaction. These results were not mimicked at room temperature by the protein phosphatase 1 and 2A inhibitor okadaic acid. In reactions performed at 4°C, addition of calcium caused a 2-fold increase in the phosphorylation of PP58. A decrease in phosphorylation was observed when equimolar amounts of EGTA were added in the presence of MgCl 2 or MnCl2, but not in the presence of CaCl2, suggesting that this protein is phosphorylated by a calcium-dependent protein kinase. These results are consistent with the suggestion that PP58 and its putative kinase are membrane-localized whereas the putative PP58 phosphatase is a loosely-associated membrane peripheral protein lost to the supernatant during fractionation. We suggest that PP58 could be involved in low te</description><creator>Labbé, Etienne.</creator><contributor>Dhindsa, R. S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Phosphoproteins.</subject><subject>Alfalfa -- Effect of cold on.</subject><subject>Phosphorylation.</subject><subject>Cold adaptation.</subject><title>Temperature-modulation of protein phosphorylation in cell-free extracts of alfalfa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bh28z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w66345886</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10ws54n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Haji Agus Salim (1884--1954) was an Indonesian Muslim political figure of the Nationalist Era (1908--1945). He was influential in two important associations; Sarekat Islam (SI-Islamic Union) and the Jong Islamieten Bond (JIB-Young Muslim Union). Salim was born into religious family and had a Western education. In 1915 when he joined the Sarekat Islam it was at the height of its popularity. Salim became so engrossed with its goals, that he devoted most of his life to it. As such, he was soon able to obtain a high-ranking position in it, and to help formulate the movement's strategies. This thesis presents a number of Salim's positions on politics which show his disagreement and criticism of the Dutch Colonial policy and its effects, as well as his advocacy of an Islamic approach to politics rather than "socialism" as advocated by communist members of the SI. These views aimed at the paramount goal of freeing Indonesia from the Dutch colonialism. His views on "Nationalism" can be gleaned from his exchange of polemics with Sukarno, later president of Indonesia. These polemics portrayed Salim as a nationalist who would not depart from a religious viewpoint. Finally, his involvement with JIB was a continuation of his desire to implement and promote Islamic values among Young Indonesian Muslims of Western education, whom he regarded as the future leaders of the country.</description><creator>Kahfi, Erni Haryanti.</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (advisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Indonesia -- Politics and government -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Jong Islamieten Bond.</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Indonesia -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Sarekat Islam.</subject><subject>Salim, Agus, 1884-1954.</subject><title>Haji Agus Salim : his role in nationalist movements in Indonesia during the early twentieth century</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r57r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws54n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w685b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores some of the issues of adjustment of Israeli immigrant high school students in Montreal, including sociocultural, linguistic, and educational issues. It deals with the term adjustment from the theoretical and historical point and with the relationship between adjustment and immigration. It reviews existing research on the adjustment experience of immigrant students, and provides a background about the education of Jewish immigrants in Montreal. The thesis is a qualitative study based on individual and group interviews involving 10 high school students.</description><creator>Gutstadt, Pnina</creator><contributor>Jackson, Nancy S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Immigrants -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Israelis -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>High school students -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Psychology</subject><title>The adjustment of Israeli immigrant students in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz795.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w685b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r992r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis approaches the work of Frederick Viesler as an attempt to resolve many of the issues resulting from the technological circumstances of the late twentieth century. It concerns the problematic caused by the gap existing between the senses and imagination, which causes a break between perceiving the world and the human act of creation. This fact reflects the way that nowadays reality has been "instrumentalized", locating man in a realm in which the human body does not interact according to its inherent capacities. Kiesler, through his theory of "Correalism", searched for underlying continuity, and proposed that man inhabit his world as a participant, where senses and imagination become one for reinterpreting the event of architecture, bringing forward the possibility of "enlivening" space. The relevance of "Correalism" for contemporary architecture becomes more significant when seen through a phenomenological perspective, which suggests that "reality" should be apprehended through the link between the embodied self and its contiguous world. Correal architecture should bring about a "more sensitive" experience of space by creating an interacting dynamic that would reflect man's existence as a whole.</description><creator>Franco, Marta.</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (advisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Kiesler, Frederick.</subject><title>Towards a correal architecture : reflections on Frederick Kiesler</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vw18j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r992r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2650</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>