<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:30:40Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10700" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149s73r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] A departmental interest in the subject or experimental diabetes had been hitherto somewhat discouraged by the usual obstacles. A surgical approach to the problem was known to be impractical in small laboratory animals, because it was technically difficult to excise sufficiently large proportions of the pancreatic tissue, and because the subsequent results were usually uncertain. Nor did the newer endocrine approach using anterior pituitary hermone completely solve the problem because it was known that the smaller laboratory animals such as the rabbit and the rat were refractory to its diabetogenic action. Consequently, when we used Alloxan and found that we could easily produce experimental diabetes in hooded rats, we were greatly stimulated by this ready success, and we decided to conduct many further investigations with this new and powerful diabetogenic agent. Although the basis of the present thesis is this work in experimental alloxan diabetes in hooded rats, an attempt has been made at the same time to survey briefly the entire field of experimental diabetes, including diabetes produced by pancreatectomy, and diabetes produced by injections or anterior pituitary extract, and the thesis has been accordingly divided into sections as listed in the table of contents. However in the case of experimental alloxan diabetes a vast literature has recently accumulated, and numerous contributions have been made since the time our work in hooded rats was originally done. [...]</description><creator>Starr, Harry.</creator><contributor>Duff, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Experimental alloxan diabetes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vb73h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149s73r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tg19p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we study ε-well supported Nash equilibria (ε-WSNE) in two player normal-form games. In an ε-WSNE, every pure strategy that is played with positive probability must have an expected payoff within ε of the best response payoff. These can be viewed as combinatorial relaxations of exact Nash equilibria, and this thesis examines the structure of ε-WSNE via the use of a graphical representation of win-lose games. Our main result states that to obtain ε-WSNE with an approximation guarantee better than ⅔ the players must use mixed strategies whose supports have polylogarithmic cardinality. In addition, we show that, to obtain any non-trivial approximation guarantee requires supports of cardinality at least three. Finally, we use the graphical representation to provide a characterization of when a win-lose game has an ε-WSNE with both good approximation guarantee and small cardinality supports.</description><description>Dans cette thèse, nous étudions les ε-Equilibres de Nash bien supportés (E-ENBS) dans des jeux de forme-normale à deux joueurs. Dans un ε-ENBS, chaque stratégie pure jouée avec probabilité positive doit avoir une récompense attendue à l'intérieur d'un intervalle de E de la meilleure récompense de réponse. Ceux-ci peuvent être considérés comme des relaxations combinatoires d'équilibres de Nash exacts; et cette thèse examine la structure d'ε-ENBS à travers l'utilisation d'une représentation graphique des jeux gagnant-perdant. Notre résultat principal stipule que, pour obtenir des ε-ENBS avec une garantie d 'approximation meilleure que ⅔ les joueurs doivent utiliser des stratégies mixtes dont les supports ont une cardinalité polylogarithmique. En outre, nous montrons que, pour obtenir toute garantie d'approximation non-triviale, nous avons besoin d 'au moins trois supports de cardinalité. Enfin, nous utilisons la représentation graphique pour fournir une caractérisation du cas ou un jeu gagnant-perdant a un ε-ENBS avec à la fois une bonne garantie d'approximation et des petits supports de cardinalité.</description><creator>Anbalagan, Yogesh</creator><contributor>Adrian Roshan Vetta (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Approximate well supported nash equilibria in win-lose bimatrix games</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hz70m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tg19p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505358x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The past decade witnessed a substantial wave of airline mergers in the markets of the European Union and the United States. The present thesis will provide a retrospective comparative assessment of the application of antitrust law in each jurisdiction, and will assess its impact on each domestic market under review. It will explore the historical roots of this common tendency towards consolidation, and will analyze how competition regulators in each jurisdiction responded to the antitrust challenges raised by this common trend. It will contend that the European Commission has adopted a more stringent standard in its assessments of the subject mergers than the Department of Justice. It will substantiate this submission by examining three important parameters involved in any competitive assessment, namely the definition of an antitrust market, the substantive test against which a transaction will be reviewed, and the consideration of the efficiencies (allegedly) induced by a merger. It will contrast the European Commission’s merger-skepticism to the Department’s merger-permissiveness in these three areas. It will subsequently assess the impact of this disparate standard of review on the competitive state of each market. Evidence will be adduced showing that the looser antitrust policy pursued in the United States has produced significant anticompetitive effects in its domestic market. The thesis will conclude by offering a prospective assessment of the ways in which these disparities in antitrust enforcement are liable to affect the future evolution of the industries in the two jurisdictions, and will submit that the European approach is more suited for the preservation of effective competition.</description><description>Au cours de la décennie écoulée, les marchés européens et américains ont vu se dérouler un nombre important de fusions entre compagnies aériennes. Ce mémoire entamera une analyse rétrospective et comparative de l'application du droit de la concurrence dans chaque juridiction et examinera son impact pour chacun des marchés. Nous examinerons les raisons historiques de la consolidation de chaque marché et analyserons de quelle manière les autorités de la concurrence ont répondu aux défis posés par cette tendance. Notre thèse sera que la Commission Européenne s'est montrée plus stricte dans son analyse que le Département de la Justice américain. Cette opinion sera soutenue par l'examen des trois paramètres utilisés pour une analyse concurrentielle, soit la définition du marché, le critère de fond utilisé pour l'examen d'une transaction et l'évaluation des gains d'efficacité générés par une fusion. Nous contrasterons en particulier l'exigence dont fait preuve la Commission Européenne avec la permissivité affichée par le Département de la Justice sur ces trois aspects, puis étudierons l'impact sur chaque marché produit par ces différentes pratiques. Nous montrerons également que la politique anticoncurrentielle américaine, favorable aux fusions, a produit des effets plus importants dans le cadre de son marché intérieur. Enfin, nous conclurons par une prévision sur l'évolution des deux marchés, telle qu'elle peut être prévue en fonction de l'attitude du régulateur. Nous expliquerons alors en quoi nous considérons l'approche européenne mieux appropriée à la préservation d'une saine concurrence.</description><creator>Seretis, Marios</creator><contributor>Richard Janda (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Airline mergers in the European Union and the United States: a retrospective account and the ways forward</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fm27s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505358x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wz96x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>En Suisse, l’assurance-maladie fédérale attribue ses ressources à l’aide de trois critères ; efficacité, opportunité et rentabilité (Art. 32 LAMal). Afin de vérifier si l’application de ces derniers est respectée, la loi fédérale sur l’assurance-maladie et ses règlements imposent plusieurs procédures.Les décisions concernant le remboursement des médicaments (et d’autres traitements) sont prises à différents niveaux. Au niveau « macro », l’office fédéral de la santé publique détermine si un médicament est retrouvé sur une de leur liste de médicaments approuvés pour remboursement. Au niveau « meso », les actionnaires ont établi un système de tarifs selon lequel les médicaments sont également inclus. Finalement, au niveau « micro », les décisions prises aux niveaux macro et meso sont vérifiées au cas par cas par les médecins et les compagnies d’assurance-maladie compétentes.Bien que tous les critères soient les mêmes pour chacun des actionnaires, ils sont interprétés différemment. Certains soulignent donc que l’application de ces critères sur la base des différents niveaux entraine, en pratique, des inégalités et incertitudes. De plus, les actionnaires ont critiqué le manque de transparence quant à l’application des trois critères. Par conséquent, la demande d’amélioration de la compréhension et de l’application de ces facteurs est croissante.Cette étude tente de répondre à la problématique. En premier lieu, les aspects centraux du système de santé et d’assurance-maladie suisse seront présentés. Par la suite, la loi et la jurisprudence sur ces trois critères sera analysée à la lumière des niveaux d’application (macro, meso, micro). Le tout sera suivi par une analyse juridique et éthique. En conclusion, quatre suggestions seront proposées pour améliorer la compréhension des cas de remboursement de l’assurance-maladie.</description><description>The Swiss health care insurance system allocates resources according to three criteria: effectiveness, appropriateness and efficiency (Art. 32 SHIA). To determine whether these three criteria are fulfilled, the Swiss Health Insurance Act and its ordinances define a number of decision-making processes. Coverage decisions for pharmaceuticals (and other treatments) are taken at different levels. On the macro level, the Swiss Federal Office of Public Health determines the general registration of pharmaceuticals according to a list that is a precondition for reimbursement. On a meso level, stakeholders establish a tariff system for treatments, which includes pharmaceuticals. And finally, all of these top-down coverage decisions are double checked on a micro-level by the attending physician and the responsible health insurance company. Although the three criteria are binding for everyone, they are interpreted differently. Critics claim that the different levels and approaches to the three criteria result in legal uncertainty and unequal treatment. In addition, stakeholders repeatedly claim that there is no clear overview of the three criteria. There is a strong demand to increase the understanding and the application of the three criteria by considering different needs at each decision-making level. This study shall address this demand. First, the central aspects of the Swiss health care and insurance system will be presented. Then, the specific regulation and case law regarding the three criteria as well as the different levels of application will be outlined, followed by a legal and ethical analysis. The findings of the analyses resulted in a set of four implications. The author argued that underrepresented philosophical/ethical values should be strengthened, namely by increasing utilitarian values and strengthening the scientific character of the evaluations/coverage decisions. In addition, he also suggests the implementation of ‘self-responsibility’ into the decision making process. Therefore, Article 32 of the SHIA should be revised and a number of measures should be taken to increase the evaluation of the three criteria.</description><creator>Widrig, Daniel</creator><contributor>Nicholas King (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Daniel Weinstock (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Resource allocation of pharmaceuticals within the Swiss health insurance system from a legal and ethical perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jx64w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wz96x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xh90j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le cancer du poumon cause annuellement plus de décès que tout autre type decancers. Un petit sous-groupe de cancers du poumon semble se développer via desmutations du récepteur humain associé au facteur de croissance épidermique à activitétyrosine kinase 2 (HER2). De précédentes études ont démontré que des mutationsd’HER2 dans le cancer du poumon entraînent des effets oncogéniques similaires aurécepteur HER2dEx16, soit une isoforme d’HER2 issue de l’épissage alternatif. Cesrésultats suggèrent donc que cet isoforme devrait potentiellement jouer un rôle crucialdans le cancer du poumon. Dans la présente étude, nous avons généré un modèle desouris transgénique du cancer du poumon utilisant le promoteur de la protéinesécrétrice des cellules de Clara (CCSP) afin d’assurer l’expression spécifique deHER2dEx16 dans les poumons, et ainsi permettre le développement de tumeurs ausein de l’organe ciblé. La progression de la maladie sera observable par imageriemédicale de type ultrason adaptée pour le modèle murin. De plus, nous utiliserons destechniques d’ordre histologique et physique pour des fins de mesures quantitatives dela progression du cancer du poumon. L’hétérogénéité des tumeurs, en plus del’augmentation du recrutement de macrophages dans les alvéoles pulmonaires,suggèrent que les cellules du système immunitaire semblent exercer un rôle dans laprogression de ces tumeurs. Nos résultats proposent que le variant HER2dEx16 dansle cancer du poumon semble agir par un mécanisme similaire aux protéines mutantesdu récepteur HER2. À la lumière de nos résultats, nous démontrons que l’utilisation dumodèle CCSP/HER2dEx16 constitue une approche efficace afin d’élucider le rôle duvariant HER2dEx16 dans le cancer du poumon.</description><description>Lung cancer causes more deaths, annually, than any other cancer. A smallsubset of lung cancers are thought to be driven by mutations in human epidermalgrowth factor receptor 2 (HER2). Previously identified HER2 mutations in lung cancerhave oncogenic effects similar to an alternatively spliced isoform, HER2dEx16,suggesting that this spliced form may also be involved in lung cancer. Here, an induciblemouse model of lung cancer was generated that utilizes a Clara cell secretory protein(CCSP) promoter to localize expression of HER2dEx16 to the lungs, thus causing lungtumors to form. Disease progression could be quantified by histological and pathologicalfeatures, and could be monitored by ultrasound imaging. The heterogeneity of tumorsand an increase in alveolar macrophages in the lungs implies that immune cells mayplay a role in the progression of these tumors. HER2dEx16 in lung cancer wasconfirmed to act by a homodimerization mechanism similar to certain HER2 proteinswith mutations in their extracellular domains. The CCSP/HER2dEx16 mice described inthis study have the potential for use in elucidating further details of the character ofHER2dEx16-driven lung cancers.</description><creator>Walsh, Arlan</creator><contributor>William Joseph Muller (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>A mouse model of HER2deltaEx16-driven lung cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579w39s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh90j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395wb598</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Colon cancer is the fourth most prevalent cause of death in female and male cancer patients and is the third most frequent disease in the developed world. The metastasis of cells from the primary tumor is directly related to poor patient prognosis and accounts for 90% of colon cancer deaths. In the past, research efforts have focused on defining the genetic and molecular mechanisms of tumor cells, however, it is now apparent that host processes are important in determining cancer growth and metastatic outcome. Factors such as the interaction between the tumor and its microenvironment within the host, tumor immune surveillance and configuration of the vasculature play a primary role in determining tumor growth, homing to distant sites and organ specificity of metastasis. Immunoediting of cancer contributes to host resistance and provides selective pressure which ultimately determines the outcome of the disease. Further, the metastatic niche secretes effectors to ready it for cancer cell colonization and metastatic growth and dissemination. Our laboratory has implemented the use of both forward and reverse genetic platforms to address the vast challenge of characterizing the host genetic basis of metastasis resistance. While our candidate gene approach, investigating specific genes with key functions in cell death and/or innate immunity did not yield significant results, our phenotype-driven screening of chemically mutagenized mice, using N-ethyl-N-nitrosourea [ENU] germline mutagenesis, led to the identification of two mouse pedigrees that showed resistance to colorectal cancer metastasis to the lung, as assessed by mouse survival. Whole genome exome sequencing revealed potential mutations in Nbeal1, Cadm3, and Ap1g2, which may be conferring the deviant phenotype. Identifying the mutation underlying metastasis resistance in these pedigrees will lead, not only to a more comprehensive understanding of the pathogenesis of cancer progression, but may also provide opportunities for the development of novel therapeutic avenues for the treatment of cancer metastasis.</description><description>Le cancer du colon est la troisième maladie la plus fréquente dans le monde développé et la quatrième cause la plus fréquente de décès chez les patients atteints de cancer. La métastase des cellules cancéreuses à partir de la tumeur primaire est directement liée à un mauvais pronostic et est responsable de 90% des décès suite à un cancer du côlon. Dans le passé, les efforts de la recherche se sont concentrés à définir les mécanismes génétiques et moléculaires ayant lieu dans les cellules cancéreuses pour leur permettre de migrer et former une tumeur secondaire. Il est cependant maintenant évident que les processus biologiques mis en place par l'hôte jouent un rôle important dans ce processus. Des facteurs tels que l'interaction entre la tumeur et son micro-environnement au sein de l'hôte, la surveillance immunitaire de la tumeur ainsi que la configuration du système vasculaire impactent la croissance tumorale, la prise d'origine à des sites distants et la spécificité organique de métastases. L'immunoediting du cancer contribue à la résistance de l'hôte et fournit une pression sélective qui détermine l'issue de la maladie. En plus, le créneau métastatique sécrète des effecteurs qui le préparent pour la colonisation des cellules cancéreuses et la croissance métastatique. Afin d’identifier de nouveaux gènes de l’hôte contrôlant le processus de métastase, notre laboratoire a mis en place des plates-formes de génétique classique et inverse (forward and reverse genetics).  Avec un criblage de souris ayant subis une mutagénèse aléatoire avec le produit chimique (N-ethyl-N-nitrosourea [ENU] germline mutagenesis), nous avons identifié deux familles de souris résistantes à la métastase. Le séquençage génomique des exons a révélé une liste de gènes mutés candidats, incluant Nbeal1, Cadm3, Ap1g2, qui pourraient être à la cause de cette résistance. L’identification de la mutation à l’origine de ces phénotypes déviants ainsi que leur fonction dans le processus de métastase permettra une meilleure compréhension de la  pathogenèse du cancer et des métastases, et pourrait révéler de nouvelles cibles pour améliorer les traitements du cancer.</description><creator>Kinio, Anna</creator><contributor>Maya Saleh (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</subject><title>Host genetic factors in colorectal cancer metastasis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jf213.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wb598</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f6652</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Though general protein synthesis or mRNA translation has been well described, selective translation of subsets of mRNAs, remains ambiguous. The objective of this thesis was to study the recently described 4EHP-GIGYF2-ZNF598 translational repressor complex. This study sought to characterize the interaction between 4EHP and GIGYF2 using Isothermal Titration Calorimetry. Finally, this study describes the purification of the structured regions of novel ZNF598 protein and shows its interacting region with GIGYF2. Overall, the data supports that 4EHP has a unique and distinct consensus motif that it uses to interact with its binding partners. Although this motif is similar to the eIF4E consensus motif, it relies on peripheral secondary structural contact interactions to dictate its specificity from eIF4E. In conclusion, though 4EHP demonstrates a high sequence and structure similarity to the cap-binding protein eIF4E, its cap-binding function and protein-protein interactions are distinct and play a unique physiological role in eukaryotes.  </description><description>Alors que la synthèse de protéines, ou traduction d’ARNm, en générale soit bien détaillées, la traduction sélective de sous-groupes d’ARNm demeure ambiguë. L’objectif de ce mémoire était d’étudier le complexe inhibiteur de traduction nouvellement identifié 4EHP-GIGYF2-ZNF598. Cette étude visait à caractériser l’interaction entre 4EHP et GIGYF2 par calorimétrie à titrage isotherme. Finalement, cette étude décrit la purification des composantes structurales de la protéine récemment identifiée ZFN598 et identifie sa région d’interaction avec GIGYF2. Globalement, l’information recueillie supporte l’hypothèse que 4EHP possède un motif consensus unique et distinct pour interagir avec ses protéines partenaires. Bien que ce motif soit semblable à celui de son homologue eIF4E, la présence de points de contacts additionnels au niveau de la structure secondaire en périphérie du motif consensus confère à 4EHP une spécificité toute autre que celle d’eIF4E. En conclusion, alors que 4EHP démontre un niveau élevé de similitude avec eIF4E au niveau de la séquence et de la structure, sa fonction d’interaction avec la coiffe des ARNm et ses protéines partenaires sont distinctes, conférant à 4EHP un rôle unique dans la physiologie des eucaryotes. </description><creator>Merkley, Devon</creator><contributor>Nahum Sonenberg (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Characterizing the function of 4EHP: a component of the 4EHP-GIGYF2-ZNF598 translational repressor complex in higher eukaryotes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77st10k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f6652</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wt57p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le virus du papillome humain (VPH) est maintenant reconnu comme un antécédent pour le développement du cancer du col. Au cours des deux dernières décennies, il a été de plus en plus reconnu comme un facteur de risque majeur pour le cancer oro-pharyngé (OPC). Les vingt dernières années ont également montré une augmentation de ce type de cancer dans le monde développé, alors que le cancer cervico-facial lié au tabac et à l’alcool a montré une baisse. La tendance du HPV- OPC peut également avoir une augmentation projetée dans l'avenir, si les rôles de promotion de la santé par les professionnels de la santé dentaire ne sont pas en phase avec ces tendances sérieuses. En fait, l'augmentation de HPV- OPC est relativement récente et la population en général, ainsi que de nombreux professionnels de la santé, pourraient ne pas être conscients de l'ampleur du problème et peuvent donc être lents dans la fourniture de messages de santé publique et de leur inclusion immédiate dans l'enseignement professionnel de la santé. Les dentistes, en tant que membres d'une équipe interdisciplinaire de professionnels de la santé, peuvent jouer un rôle majeur dans la prévention de la propagation des infections au VPH. Grâce aux résultats de cette étude phénoménologique d'interprétation, nous avons tenté d'explorer les perceptions des étudiants en médecine dentaire sur le rôle et la responsabilité du dentiste à faire participer les patients à des discussions sur des facteurs de risque de style de vie sensibles tels que la transmission du VPH, y compris leurs comportements sexuels, avec des discussions pertinentes sur des stratégies efficaces de prévention, comme la vaccination, pour prévenir l'acquisition des infections au VPH. Cette étude a également exploré en détail l’état actuel des connaissances des étudiants en médecine dentaire de l'interaction HPV- OPC, obtenant aussi un aperçu sur leur perception de leur propre rôle professionnel en tant que promoteurs de la santé. Des études ont démontré que les étudiants en médecine dentaire n'ont pas une connaissance suffisante du VPH - OPC pour pouvoir conseiller les patients et qu’ils ne sont pas tout à fait à l’aise de parler de sujets sensibles avec eux. La formation continue, dans ce contexte, est recommandée pour les étudiants en médecine dentaire.</description><description>Human Papilloma Virus (HPV) infection is now recognized as an antecedent for the development of cervical cancer and over the last two decades has been increasingly recognized as a major risk factor for oropharyngeal cancer (OPC). The last twenty years have also shown an increase in this type of cancer in the developed world, while tobacco and alcohol related head and neck cancer (HNC) have shown a decline. The trend of HPV-OPC may also have a projected increase in the future, if health promotion roles by dental health professionals are not in sync with these serious trends. Because the increase in HPV-OPC is relatively recent, the general population including many health professionals might not be aware of the magnitude of the problem and therefore may be slow in providing public health messaging and its immediate inclusion into health professional education. Dentists can play a major role in the prevention of the spread of HPV infections, as members of an interdisciplinary team of healthcare professionals. Through the results of this Interpretive Phenomenological (IP) study we attempted to explore the perceptions of dental students about the role and responsibility of the dentist to engage patients in discussions about sensitive lifestyle risk factors such as HPV transmission, including their sexual behaviours, with purposeful discussions about effective preventive strategies such as vaccinations to prevent acquiring HPV infections.  This study also explored the current knowledge of dental students' understanding of the HPV-OPC interaction, as well as, gaining insight about their perceptions about their own professional role as health promoters. Findings demonstrated dental students did not have adequate knowledge about HPV-OPC to be able to counsel patients, and were not fully confident about talking about sensitive topics with their patients. Further educational training in this context is recommended for the dental students. </description><creator>Amir, Nida</creator><contributor>Richard Hovey (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Belinda Farias Nicolau (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Dentistry</subject><title>Perceptions of dental students about the role of the dentist in the prevention of HPV-OPC</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182p15z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wt57p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v155t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La canne à sucre est l’une des plus importantes cultures de la Guyane, représentant 3.8 % du produit intérieur brut du pays. La canne à sucre est cultivée dans les zones côtières, régions caractérisées par des sols très argileux à haut risque d’engorgement autant que par un climat tropical humide avec une précipitation annuelle de 2300 mm, dont la moitié tombe au cours de la longue saison pluvieuse entre les mois de mai et de juillet. Vu ces conditions, autant que les changements climatiques, l’établissement de systèmes de drainage efficaces et efficients sur les plantations de canne à sucre pose un défi important. Cette étude utilise donc un modèle de bilan hydrique pour analyser la performance des systèmes de drainage préexistants dans les champs de canne à sucre typique. Un champ de 4.2 ha à la bonne intention a été instrumenté en 2013 pour mesurer les variables hydrométéorologiques. En plus de l'étude sur le champ, le modèle DRAINMOD (version 6) a été utilisé pour simuler le drainage et l'hydrologie du champ à l'aide de données climatiques historiques. Les résultats du bilan d’eau pour la période de l’étude (du 16 mars au 26 novembre) donnèrent 170,8 cm pour la précipitation, 129,1 cm pour l’évapotranspiration des cultures, 48,8 cm pour le ruissellement de surface et le drainage souterrain, et 2,06 cm pour le changement net en humidité du sol. Basé sur les simulations DRAINMOD, le taux de drainage simulé (période de 3 jours) pour la période la plus humide (de décembre 2004 à février 2005) culminât à une valeur de 12 cm jour-1. Cette valeur excédât la limite supérieure historique du coefficient de calcul de drainage (5 cm jour-1). Cependant, la période de retour pour un événement tel que la période la plus humide était de 52 ans (calculée selon la distribution de Gumbel de type 1). Généralement, les systèmes de drainage des champs agricoles sont conçus pour des tempêtes de période de retour 1 dans 5 ans (événement 1-jour survenant une fois tous les cinq ans). En conclusion des simulations de DRAINMOD, le coefficient de drainage de conception sont adéquates pour le systèmes de drainage de surface pour les champs de canne à sucre en Guyane.</description><description>Sugarcane is one of Guyana's major agricultural crops, accounting for 3.8% of the country's gross domestic product. The crop is grown in the coastal regions with a characteristic heavy clay soil that is prone to waterlogging. The climate is wet tropical with an annual average precipitation of 2300 mm, of which almost 50% occurs during the long wet season (May-July). Together with climate change, these conditions impose the challenge of providing and maintaining an effective and efficient drainage system for water management on the sugar estates. To this end, a water balance study was conducted to analyse the performance of the existing drainage systems for a typical sugarcane field. A 4.2 ha field at La Bonne Intention was instrumented in 2013 to measure the hydrometeorological variables. In addition to the field study, DRAINMOD ver.6 was used to simulate the drainage and hydrology of the field using historical climate data. The results of the measured field water balance for the study period (16 March to 26 November) were 170.8 cm for precipitation, 129.1 cm for crop evapotranspiration, 48.8 cm for combined sub-surface drainage + surface runoff and 2.06 cm as the net change in soil moisture. Based on the DRAINMOD simulations, the simulated drainage rate (3-day duration) for the wettest period (December 2004 to February 2005) peaked at 12 cm day-1. This exceeded the upper limit of the historical design drainage coefficient of 5 cm day-1. However, the return period for an event such as the wettest period, was 52 years as determined using Gumbel Type 1 distribution. Typically, drainage systems for agricultural lands are designed for a 1 in 5 yr design storm (1-day event occurring once every five years),  and in conclusion from the DRAINMOD simulations, the design drainage coefficient are adequate for surface drainage systems for sugarcane fields in Guyana. </description><creator>Gaj, Naresh</creator><contributor>Chandra A Madramootoo (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>An analysis of the hydrology of a sugarcane field in Guyana</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fc36t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v155t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff365830q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The incidence and prevalence of inflammatory bowel diseases (IBD) have dramatically risen in both developed and developing nations in the last 50 years. While there has been much debate on both the genetic and environmental causes of IBD, it is thought to arise from an abnormal immune response to the commensal intestinal microbiota in susceptible individuals. Recent human and mouse genetic results, as well as functional data from experimental animal models of colitis, have both pointed to a key role of the inflammasome-IL-18 pathway in intestinal homeostasis. The inflammasomes are sensors of microbial/danger signals and are key effectors of the innate inflammatory response. They are scaffolded by intracellular pattern recognition receptors and are required for the activation of caspase-1, an inflammatory protease necessary for the processing of IL-1β and IL-18 into their mature biologically active cytokine forms. We hypothesized that IL-18 is required for the activation and effector functions of specific intestinal cells that initiate downstream epithelial repair and host defense mechanisms. In an experimental model of infectious colitis using Citrobacter rodentium infection, we determined that Il18-/- mice were more susceptible to C. rodentium infection compared to wild-type (WT) mice. However, infections using Rag1-/- and Rag1-/-/Il18-/- mice showed a reverse phenotype; Rag1-/- mice showed increased disease phenotypes compared to Rag1-/-/Il18-/- mice. Bone marrow chimera experiments using WT and Il18r-/- mice further demonstrated that IL-18 signaling in the stromal or radio-resistant compartment is vital for host resistance. Altogether, these results suggest that IL-18 plays a dual role in both the innate and adaptive immune responses during an infection that is crucial to control the severity of the disease. The future identification of IL-18-responsive stromal cells as well as the exploration of the role of IL-18 signaling and downstream effector functions of target cells in intestinal homeostasis will further allow us to assemble a more comprehensive picture of interactions between IL-18 and mucosal stromal cells after injury or infection, and how these pathways are able to affect both the generation and progression of the disease.</description><description>L’incidence et la prévalence des maladies inflammatoires de l’intestin (MII) ont considérablement augmenté dans les pays développés et en voies de développements au cours des 50 dernières années. Bien qu'il y ait eu beaucoup de débats sur les causes génétiques et environnementales des MII, il semble que ces dernières soient dues à une réponse immunitaire anormale contre la flore commensale dans des individus génétiquement prédisposés. De récentes analyses génétiques chez l’homme et la souris, ainsi que des données fonctionnelles issues de modèles expérimentaux de colite, ont souligné le rôle clé de la voie de l’inflammasome-IL-18 dans l'homéostasie intestinale. Les inflammasomes sont des complexes protéiques capables de reconnaître des signaux microbiens/de danger et sont des effecteurs clés de la réponse inflammatoire innée. La reconnaissance de signaux dangers par des récepteurs spécifiques (PRR) permet l ‘activation de la caspase-1, une protéase inflammatoire nécessaire pour le clivage et la maturation des cytokines IL-1β et IL-18. Nous émettons l'hypothèse que IL-18 est nécessaire pour l’activation et les fonctions effectrices de cellules intestinales spécifiques, permettant à ces dernières d’initier des mécanismes de réparation de l'épithélium et de défense de l'hôte. En utilisant un modèle expérimental de colite infectieuse induite par Citrobacter rodentium, nous avons montré que les souris Il-18-/- sont plus sensibles que des souris sauvages (WT) à une infection par C. rodentium. Cependant, l’infection de souris Rag1-/- et Rag1-/-/Il18-/- mène a des phénotype opposés; les souris Rag1-/- présentant des signes d’infection plus sévères que les souris Rag1-/-/Il18-/-. En utilisant des souris chimères dans lesquels la signalisation de l’IL-18 est restreinte aux cellules hématopoïétique ou aux cellules stromales (radiorésistantes), nous avons que la signalisation IL-18 dans les cellules stromales est capitale dans la médiation de la progression de la maladie. Ensemble, ces résultats suggèrent que IL-18 joue un rôle dans la réponse immunitaire innée et adaptative au cours d'une infection, et que ces deux rôles sont cruciaux pour réguler la gravité de la maladie. L'identification des cellules stromales répondant à l’IL-18 ainsi que la compréhension des fonctions de ces cellules dans l'homéostasie intestinale nous permettrons d’établir un mécanisme plus complet des interactions entre l’IL-18 et les cellules de la muqueuse intestinale après une lésion ou une infection. De plus, comprendre ces interactions nous permettra de clarifier la façon dont ces voies sont capables d'affecter l’initiation ainsi que la progression des maladies inflammatoires de l’intestin.</description><creator>Zhong, Yifei</creator><contributor>Maya Saleh (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>The role of the inflammasome and interleukin-18 (IL-18) in enteric infection pathogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zh49d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365830q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430774x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L’enzyme ADN méthyltransférase 3-like (DNMT3L) est essentiel durant l’établissement initial de la méthylation de l’ADN dans les cellules germinales mâles et femelles, ainsi que dans le développement de ces dernières. Chez la souris, une déficience de cet enzyme mène à des troubles au niveau de la reproduction, ainsi qu’à des défaults de méthylation d’ADN dans la lignée germinale. La progéniture de mâles hétérozygotes démontre un taux plus élevé d’aneuploïdies, et les mâles et femelles homozygotes mutants sont infertiles. Ces anomalies reproductives sont liées à une hypométhylation de l’ADN dans la lignée germinale de ces animaux. Donc, en terme de dose de DNMT3L, nous savons qu’une réduction donne lieu à des défauts de méthylation d’ADN ainsi qu’à certains phénotypes. Par contre, nous ne connaissons pas l’effet d’une augmentation de la dose de DNMT3L. Nous avons donc évalué l’issue d’une surexpression de Dnmt3L dans la lignée germinale mâle et femelle chez la souris, en utilisant un transgène, EF1α-Dnmt3L, que nous avons propagé à travers la lignée germinale durant plusieurs générations. Dans l’expérience de transmission du transgène à travers la lignée germinale femelle, 28.8% de tous les descendants à la génération F1 sont morts entre la naissance et l’âge de sevrage, et le taux de transmission du transgène aux descendants qui ont survécu jusqu’au sevrage était de 22.3%. Le manque de descendantes femelles à la génération F1 nous a fait mettre fin à 5 des 7 lignées, tandis que nous avons mis fin aux 2 autres lignées à la génération F2. Dans l’expérience de transmission du transgène à travers la lignée germinale femelle, les mâles issus de la lignée contenant le plus haut nombre de copies du transgène ont démontré une diminution significative du nombre de descendants par portée au sevrage de la génération F1 à F2. Les mâles transgéniques de cette lignée ont aussi démontré un nombre significativement plus élevé de tubes séminifères anormaux dans les coupes transversales de leurs testicules comparativement aux contrôles, ainsi qu’une augmentation significative de tubes séminifères anormaux de la génération F1 à F2. Ces observations nous ont mené à examiner les patrons de méthylation d’ADN dans le sperme de ces mâles, en utilisant le séquençage à l’échelle du génome entier par technique de représentation réduite de séquençage bisulfite (RRBS). Les résultats de l’analyse par RRBS ont révelé que, globalement, les patrons de méthylation d’ADN dans le sperme de mâles transgéniques n’étaient pas différents de ceux du sperme de mâles non-transgéniques ou contrôles. Par contre, certaines régions méthylées différemment (DRMs) ont été découvertes. Les DMRs localisées dans les exons étaient hyperméthylées dans le sperme de mâles transgéniques comparativement aux contrôles, ainsi qu’hyperméthylées dans le sperme de mâles transgéniques à la génération F2 comparativement à F1. Il semble donc que la surexpression transgénique de Dnmt3L dans notre modèle donne lieu à de subtiles anomalies reproductives et défauts de méthylation d’ADN. Quoique préliminaire, il est possible que l’augmentation de ces défauts de F1 à F2 soit dûe à un effet d’héritage épigénétique transgénérationnel.</description><description>The DNA methyltransferase 3-like (DNMT3L) enzyme is critical to proper de novo DNA methylation acquisition in germ cells and to gametogenesis. In mice, Dnmt3L deficiency or haploinsufficiency leads to reproductive abnormalities and germ cell methylation defects. Dnmt3L heterozygous males sire offspring with an increased incidence of aneuploidy, and Dnmt3L-deficient males and females are both infertile. These abnormal reproductive outcomes correlate with hypomethylation in germ cells of these animals. In terms of DNMT3L dosage then, it is known that lack/reduction of this enzyme in germ cells leads to DNA methylation and phenotypic defects. The reproductive effects of increased DNMT3L dosage are not known, however. Therefore we evaluated the outcome of Dnmt3L overexpression in male and female mouse germ cells, using an EF1α-Dnmt3L transgene previously created in our lab, and the effect of propagating the transgene through the male and female germlines for successive generations. In the female germline transmission experiment, 28.8% of all F1 pups died between birth and weaning, and the rate of transgene transmission to surviving pups was only 22.3%. The low number of transgenic pups in F1 led to termination of 5 of the 7 lineages in F1, and the 2 remaining lineages were terminated in F2. In the male germline transmission experiment, males from the lineage with the highest number of transgene copies displayed a significant decrease in average litter size at weaning from F1 to F2. Transgenic males from this lineage showed significantly more abnormal seminiferous tubules in their testis cross sections than controls, and a significant increase in abnormal tubules from F1 to F2. These findings prompted us to examine the DNA methylation patterns in the sperm of these males, using a genome-wide, sequencing method called reduced representation bisulfite sequencing (RRBS). RRBS analysis revealed that, overall, DNA methylation patterns in transgenic sperm were not different from non-transgenic or control sperm. However, some differentially methylated regions (DMRs) between transgenic and control sperm were found. DMRs located in exons were hypermethylated in transgenic versus control sperm, and hypermethylated in F2 vs F1 transgenic sperm. It therefore appears that transgenic overexpression of Dnmt3L in our model leads to subtle reproductive and sperm DNA methylation defects. Although preliminary, it is possible that the worsening of these defects from F1 to F2 is due to transgenerational epigenetic inheritance.</description><creator>Boisvert, Patrick</creator><contributor>Jacquetta M Trasler (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>The effects of overexpression of DNA methyltransferase 3-like (DNMT3L) and transmission through the murine male and female germlines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301450k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430774x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s338d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Observational data from the 2011 Dominica Experiment (DOMEX) and cloud-resolving numerical simulations are exploited in order to acquire a better understanding of controlling parameters of thermally-driven circulation and convection over a mountainous tropical island. Four weak (&lt;4 m/s) background wind days are investigated to obtain a preliminary diagnosis of the conditions favorable for diurnally-forced shallow cumulus convection over the island. The observations suggest that the degree of solar heating before the first cumulus development largely controls the amount of low-level forcing and the vigor of shallow cumulus, rather than the moist stability of the background flow.A “golden” case from DOMEX with a clear diurnal cycle in cumulus convection is studied using quasi-idealized numerical simulations (with full model physics and a realistic terrain profile) to better understand the mechanisms and sensitivities of island thermal circulations and cumulus convection. Simulations at different grid spacings reveal that large-eddy grid spacing (~100 m) provides the most accurate representation of the in-situ measurements from DOMEX and other observations.  Sensitivity tests reveal that mechanical forcing played little role in convection initiation on this day since the Froude number (Fr) was &lt; 1. Surprisingly, even though thermal circulations develop earlier over a mountainous island, they are ultimately weaker than those over a flat island possibly due to their elevated outflows undergo stable descent over a high terrain.  Background wind velocity also has a significant impact on thermal circulations, which tend to weaken as the cross-barrier wind increases.  Cloud shadowing and precipitation both have a negative feedback on thermal circulations, with the former being the stronger mechanism. In addition, cloud latent-heat release over the island strengthens thermal circulations, which also explains why circulations intensify when cumulus vigor is enhanced by greater moist instability.The simulations allow for the evaluation of thermal-circulation-strength predictions from thermodynamic heat engine theory. While the theory predicts the strength of thermal circulations reasonably well over a mountainous terrain, it fails to capture the sensitivity to terrain height likely because its assumption that the entire circulation is confined within the mixed layer is invalid. </description><description>       Des données d'observations de l'expérimentation Dominicaine (DOMEX, 2011) et des simulations de model atmosphérique sont exploités dans le but d'acquérir une meilleur compréhension des paramètres contrôlant la circulation et la convection thermique au dessus d'une ile tropicale montagneuse. Quatre jours de vent faible (&lt;4 m/s) sont analysés afin d'obtenir un diagnostic préliminaire des conditions favorable au développement de cumulus de convection peu profonde généré par forçage thermique diurne au dessus de l'ile. Les observations montrent que l'augmentation de la température dut au radiation solaire précédent le développement du cumulus contrôle largement le forçage de basse altitude ainsi que la vigueur du cumulus. la stabilité du courant global joue un role moins important.Une étude de cas provenant de DOMEX montrant clairement un cycle diurne de formation de cumulus par convection a été spécialement sélectionné pour être étudié avec des simulations numérique quasi-idéalisé (avec l'ensemble des équations atmosphérique du model ainsi qu'une représentation réaliste du profil topographique) afin de mieux comprendre les mécanismes et sensibilités de la circulation thermique générée par l'ile ainsi que la formation de cumulus par convection. Les résultats de simulations utilisant différentes résolutions ont révélé que les représentations les plus fidèle aux observations de DOMEX sont obtenues lors de simulations à haute résolution horizontale (~100m). Des tests de sensibilité réalisés montrent que le forçage mecanique joue un rôle mineur dans l'initiation de la convection lors de ce cas où le nombre de Froude (Fr) était &lt; 1. Etonament, même si la circulation thermique se développe plus tôt au dessus de l'ile montagneuse, Elle est toujours plus faible qu'au dessus de l'ile plate, cela peut être expliqué par le fait que les ecoulements de haute altitude subissent une stable descente au-dessus de terrain élevé. La vitesse du vent global a un impact non négligeable sur les circulations thermique, cette dernière tend a s'affaiblir alors que le courant horizontal au sommet de la topographie accélère.. La couverture nuageuse et les précipitations affaiblisse tous les deux la circulation thermique, bien que le premier mécanisme soit le plus efficace. En plus, le relâchement de chaleur latente par le nuage au dessus de l'ile renforce la circulation thermique, ce qui explique également pourquoi la circulation s'intensifie lorsque l'activité du cumulus s'accélère , qui est dans ce dernier cas généré par une plus grande instabilité de l'air humide. Les simulations permettent la comparaison des prédictions de la puissance de la circulation thermique avec celle réalisé grâce à la théorie de l'engin de chaleur thermodynamique. Alors que la théorie prédit relativement bien la circulation thermique au dessus d'une région montagneuse, elle ne capture pas la sensibilité dut l'élévation de la  topographie, surement car l'hypothèse que la totalité de la circulation est confiné dans la couche homogène est invalide.</description><creator>Wang, Chun-Chih</creator><contributor>Daniel Kirshbaum (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</subject><title>Thermally-driven circulation and convection over a mountainous tropical island</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gp102.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s338d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988p056</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A flexible approach is proposed for risk aggregation. The model consists of a tree structure, bivariate copulas, and marginal distributions. The construction relies on a conditional independence assumption whose implications are studied. A procedure for selecting the tree structure is developed using hierarchical clustering techniques, along with a distance metric based on Kendall's tau. Estimation, simulation, and model validation are also discussed. The approach is illustrated using data from a Canadian property and casualty insurance company.</description><description>On propose une approche flexible pour l'agrégation de risques. Le modèle est constitué d'une arborescence, de copules bivariées et de lois marginales. La construction s'appuie sur un postulat d'indépendance conditionnelle dont les ramifications sont étudiées. On montre comment choisir l'arborescence au moyen de techniques de classication et d'une métrique définie à partir du tau de Kendall. L'estimation, la simulation et l'adéquation du modèle sont aussi abordées. L'approche est illustrée à l'aide de données d'une compagnie canadienne en assurance IARD.</description><creator>Côté, Marie-Pier</creator><contributor>Christian Genest (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Statistics </subject><title>Copula-based risk aggregation modelling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z709086s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988p056</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wq90n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Glioblastoma multiforme (GBM) is the most frequent and aggressive form of malignantprimary brain tumors in adults. Increased proliferation and invasion are the major hallmarks ofGBM. Previous studies reported an inverse correlation between proliferation and invasion inGBM, a phenomenon termed the migration/proliferation dichotomy. This dichotomy may haveconsequences in GBM by triggering a pro-invasive response following treatment with antiproliferativetherapies.The DNA repair protein O6-methylguanine-DNA methyltransferase (MGMT) has beenthe focus of intensive research for its role as a DNA repair protein in GBM. Our laboratory hasestablished for the first time the role of MGMT as a potential negative regulator of GBMangiogenesis and invasion in GBM. Positive immunohistochemical correlation of pro-invasiveand anti-proliferative SPARC with MGMT promoter methylation, as well as other genomicalterations suggests that MGMT could modulate proliferation in GBM as well. Focal adhesionkinase (FAK) has shown a role in invasion and proliferation in GBM, making it a suitable targetto inhibit both proliferation and invasion and potentially bypass the consequences of theproliferation/invasion dichotomy.Using isogenic overexpression (U87/EV, U87MGMT) and knockdown (T98/EV,T98/shRNA) models of MGMT in GBM, we showed that expression of MGMT was associatedwith increased proliferation and decreased invasion. Western blotting analysis of potentialmediators of proliferation and invasion in isogenic cell lines for MGMT and other GBM celllines with different levels of MGMT expression (U138, LN18 and A172) revealed a complexrelationship between their expression and both MGMT and the tumor suppressor gene TP53.In addition, we showed that treatment with the new small molecule inhibitor Y11, whichspecifically inhibits FAK Tyr397 induced a dose-dependent decrease of pFAK and reducedproliferation in GBM cell lines differentially based on MGMT expression. This was accompaniedby decreased colony formation, invasion and migration.The overarching aim of our study was to elucidate the mechanisms regulating theproliferation/migration dichotomy in GBM. This will lead to the identification of new biomarkersof invasion and proliferation and prospective therapies targeting molecular effectors involved inboth invasion and proliferation.</description><description>Le glioblastome multiforme (GBM) est la forme la plus fréquente et la plus agressive detumeurs malignes primitives du cerveau chez les adultes. Une prolifération accrue et uneaugmentation de l'invasion tumorale sont les principales caractéristiques du GBM. Des étudesantérieures ont montré une corrélation inverse entre la prolifération et l'invasion dans le GBM, unphénomène appelé la dichotomie migration / prolifération. Cette dichotomie peut avoir desconséquences dans le GBM en induisant une réponse pro-invasive suite à un traitement antiprolifératif.La protéine de réparation d'ADN O6-méthylguanine ADN-méthyltransférase (MGMT) afait l'objet d'une recherche intensive pour son rôle de protéine de réparation d'ADN dans le GBM.Notre laboratoire a mis en place pour la première fois le rôle de MGMT comme un potentielrégulateur négatif de l’angiogenèse et l'invasion dans le GBM. Positif IHC La corrélation enimmunohistochimie de la protéine pro-invasive et anti-proliférative SPARC avecl’hypermethylation du promoteur de MGMT, ainsi que d'autres altérations génomiques suggèreque MGMT pourrait moduler la prolifération dans le GBM. La Kinase d'adhésion focale (FAK)connu pour son rôle dans l'invasion et la prolifération dans le GBM, a un taux d’expressiondépendant de MGMT; ce qui en fait une cible appropriée pour inhiber à la fois la prolifération etl'invasion et potentiellement contourner les conséquences de la dichotomie prolifération /invasion.La surexpression isogénique de MGMT (U87/EV, U87MGMT) et son knock-down(T98/EV, T98/shRNA) ont montré que l'expression de MGMT est associée à l’augmentation dela prolifération et la diminution de l’invasion. L’analyse par Western Blot de mediateurs de laproliferation et de l’invasion dans des lignées cellulaires isogéniques pour MGMT et d’autreslignées cellulaires avec différents niveaux d'expression de MGMT (U138, LN18 et A172) arévélé une relation complexe entre leur expression et l’expression de MGMT et du genesuppresseur de tumeur TP53.En outre, nous avons montré que le traitement avec l'inhibiteur de petite molécules Y11,qui inhibe spécifiquement FAK Tyr397 induit une diminution dose-dépendante de la proliférationpFAK réduite dans les lignées cellulaires de glioblastome de façon différentielle sur la base del'expression de MGMT. Ceci était accompagné par une baisse de la formation de colonies,l'invasion et la migration.L'objectif premier de notre étude était d'élucider les mécanismes de régulation de ladichotomie prolifération / migration dans GBM. Cela conduira à l'identification de nouveauxbiomarqueurs de l'invasion et la prolifération et des thérapies ciblant les potentiels effecteursmoléculaires impliqués dans l'invasion et la prolifération.</description><creator>Chatoor, Kenny</creator><contributor>Siham Sabri (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Role of O(6)-Methylguanine-DNA Methyltransferase in the proliferation/invasion dichotomy in glioblastoma multiforme</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dd071.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wq90n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cx238</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il y a beaucoup de problèmes qui ne peuvent être résolus par des machines; nous aurons besoin de l'intelligence humaine pour les résoudre. Crowdsourcing est un domaine, qui utilise les compétences des personnes pour travailler sur des problèmes complexes. Dans la dernière décennie, de nombreux systèmes de crowdsourcing ont été développés et il est encore un domaine de recherche par les entreprises et les chercheurs. Malgré les nombreux avantages de crowdsourcing qui existent, ils n'ont toujours pas les mesures appropriées de la qualité des données. Nous énumérons les facteurs qui peuvent diriger vers différents problèmes de qualité des données dans les systèmes de crowdsourcing. Nous présentons un modèle général pour le crowdsourcing et parlons de différents systèmes de crowdsourcing qui utilisent ce modèle général. Cette thèse aborde également la classification des systèmes de crowdsourcing en assimilant différents points de vue de la qualité des données.Pour traiter les problèmes de qualité de données, nous décrivons la structure Useright qui fournit un programme de certification pour des mots et des phrases dans le document. Dans cette structure, un auteur publie des documents en utilisant les informations d'identification obtenues à partir d'un ou plusieurs instituts qui accordent Useright. Un auteur demande l’institut de fournir l'autorisations Useright pour une collection de mots et des phrases que l'auteur a choisie. Pour protéger l'identité de l'auteur et maintenir son identification anonyme lors de la lecture, nous introduisons un système de vérification pas cher. La note de Useright pour institut est utilisée pour augmenter la crédibilité du document. Nous offrons une conception pour une structure de Useright prolongée où l'auteur peut modifier un document d'un autre auteur en utilisant son/ses propres mots et phrases de Useright.Pour évaluer la structure Useright, nous avons réalisé une étude par sondage sur Amazon Mechanical Turk, où on a demandé aux utilisateurs d'évaluer les facteurs de qualité de données pour les différents documents qui ont été présentés de différentes façons.</description><description>There are many problems which cannot be solved by machines, we still need help from people who are intelligent and have skills to solve those problems. Crowdsourcing is the field which uses the skills of people to work on complex problems. In the past decade, many crowdsourcing systems were developed and it is still a growing field among companies and researchers. Though there are many advantages  to crowdsourcing, they still lack proper data quality measures. We enumerate the factors that can lead to different data quality problems in crowdsourcing systems. We present a general model for crowdsourcing and talk about different crowdsourcing systems using that general model. This thesis also discusses the classification of crowdsourcing systems using different data quality perspectives.To tackle the data quality problems, we describe the Useright Framework that provides a certification scheme for words and phrases in the document. In this framework, an author publishes documents using credentials obtained from one or more Useright granting institutes. An author asks an institute to provide Useright permissions for a collection of words and phrases that author has chosen. To keep the author's identity private and to check anonymity of author while reading, we introduce the cheap verification scheme. The Useright score for institute is used to increase the believability of document. We provide a design for an extended Useright Framework where an author can edit another author's document using his/her own Useright words and phrases. To evaluate the Useright Framework, we carried out a survey study on Amazon Mechanical Turk, where users were asked to estimate the data quality factors for different documents that were presented in different ways.</description><creator>Shah, Mohitkumar</creator><contributor>Muthucumaru Maheswaran (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Useright: a framework for data quality management in crowdsourcing systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zh505.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cx238</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kn745</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Failure of homologous synapsis during meiotic prophase triggers transcriptional repression termed meiotic silencing of unsynapsed chromatin (MSUC). In spermatogenesis the X and Y chromosomes incompletely synapse and are thus, silenced by MSUC, while the consequences of asynapsis of autosomes are not fully understood. To establish the dynamics of autosomal asynapsis and the proportion of spermatocytes with meiotic silencing of unsynapsed autosomes, we examined two marks of unsynapsed chromatin, histone variants γH2A.X and H3.3, in the spermatocytes of Robertsonian (Rb) translocation carrier mice using immunolocalization with fluorescent antibodies and chromatin immunoprecipitation (ChIP) assays.  We also tested the hypothesis that MSUC marks were transmitted to embryos by exploring the expression levels of pericentromeric genes.Histone variant H3.3S31 was enriched at autosomal regions in 12% of metaphase I/anaphase I spermatocytes of single Robertsonian translocation carriers, and 31% of spermatocytes from carriers of 3 translocations compared to the 100% of nuclei with H3.3S31 enrichment at sex chromosomes, an observation that suggests that only a small proportion of spermatocytes carry autosomal MSUC marks.ChIP experiments with γH2A.X and H3.3 on testes from the same translocation carrier mouse strains confirmed the enrichment of γH2A.X and H3.3 at the Dnmt3a gene, located on the pericentromeric region of chromosome 12 which is associated with the Rb (8.12) translocation in translocation carriers. Finally, we assessed gene expression levels of Dnmt3a and other genes associated with translocations in embryos sired by translocation carriers to test if MSUC marks or effects thereof, are transmitted to the offspring. We were unable to detect any decrease in expression. We therefore conclude that asynapsis at the pericentromeric region of translocation trivalents is variable across the pachytene stage and results in stable silencing in a proportion of translocation carrier spermatocytes. This silencing spreads to the Dnmt3a locus in spermatocytes, but is not passed on to post-implantation embryos sired by translocation carriers, at least not in the expected proportions.</description><description>L’échec de l’appariement homologue pendant la prophase méiotique provoque une forme de répression transcriptionnelle appelée « inactivation méiotique de la chromatine non-appariée » (meiotic silencing of unsynapsed chromatin – MSUC). Lors de la spermatogénèse, les chromosomes X et Y s’apparient de manière incomplète et sont donc réprimés par MSUC, alors que les conséquences du non-appariement des autosomes demeurent obscures.Notre objectif était donc de mieux comprendre la dynamique du non-appariement autosomique et de déterminer la proportion de spermatocytes caractérisés par une inactivation méiotique des autosomes. À l’aide d’expériences de localisation par immunofluorescence et d’immunoprécipitation de la chromatine (ChIP), nous avons examiné deux marques de chromatine non-appariée, les histones γH2A.X et H3.3, dans les spermatocytes de souris porteuses de la translocation de Robertsonian (Rb). Nous avons également vérifié l’hypothèse selon laquelle les marques de MSUC sont transmises à l’embryon, et ce en explorant les niveaux d’expression de gènes péricentromériques.Nos résultats démontrent que la forme d’histone H3.3S31 est enrichie dans les régions autosomiques lors de la métaphase I/anaphase I chez 12% des spermatocytes de porteurs d’une translocation de Robertsonian unique. Ceci est également le cas dans 31% des spermatocytes de porteurs de 3 translocations, alors que 100% des noyaux démontrent un enrichissement de H3.3S31 sur les chromosomes sexuels. Cette observation suggère que seule une faible proportion de spermatocytes sont porteurs de marques de MSUC autosomiques.Nous avons ensuite réalisé des expériences de ChIP contre γH2A.X et H3.3 dans les testicules des mêmes souches de souris porteuses de la translocation, ce qui a confirmé que γH2A.X et H3.3 sont enrichies au locus du gène Dnmt3a. Celui-ci est localisé dans la région péricentromérique du chromosome 12, qui est associée avec la translocation Rb (8.12) chez les porteurs de la translocation.Enfin, afin de déterminer si les marques de MSUC ou leurs effets sont transmis à la prochaine génération, nous avons évalué les niveaux d’expression génique de Dnmt3a et d’autres gènes associés avec la translocation dans les embryons engendrés par des porteurs de la translocation. Nous n’avons pu détecter aucune diminution de l’expression de ces gènes. Ainsi, ces données nous permettent de conclure que le non-appariement dans la région péricentromérique est variable pendant la phase pachytène chez les porteurs trivalents de la translocation. Ceci mène à une répression stable dans une partie des spermatocytes de porteurs de la translocation. Cette inactivation se propage jusqu’au locus Dnmt3a dans les spermatocytes, mais n’est pas transmise aux embryons générés par les porteurs de la translocation après l’implantation, ou du moins pas dans les proportions attendues.</description><creator>Fayer, Shawn</creator><contributor>Anna Naoumova (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Epigenetic consequences of autosomal asynapsis in carriers of Robertsonian translocations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9032976.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kn745</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd4730539</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce mémoire décrit les propriétés d’uneméthode des moments adaptée à l’estimation duparamètre de dépendance d’un modèle de copule pour données discrètes bivariées. Laméthode consiste à inverser une expression analytique pour le rho de Spearman ou le taude Kendall déduite du modèle de copule paramétrique postulé. Ces expressions font intervenirles marges et la structure de dépendance sous-jacente à travers la copule en damier.On démontre que dans le cas àmarges connues, ces estimateurs sont asymptotiquementsans biais et gaussiens sous de faibles conditions de régularité. On donne en outre desformules permettant le calcul de la variance asymptotique des deux estimateurs. Le cas àmarges inconnues est plus réaliste mais aussi beaucoup plus difficile à traiter. En faisantappel à la théorie desM-estimateurs, on parvient néanmoins à montrer que dans ce cas,l’inversion de rho de Spearman conduit encore à une estimation convergente. Enfin, ladépendance des estimateurs sur le choix demarges est étudiée par voie de simulation. Surla base des résultats présentés ici, les nouveaux estimateurs peuvent être recommandéspour l’évaluation de la dépendance dans desmodèles de copule pour données discrètes.</description><description>This thesis describes the properties of a moment-based technique for estimating the dependence parameter in a copula model for bivariate discrete data. The method consists of inverting an analytical expression for Spearman's rho or Kendall's tau derived from the assumed parametric copula model. These expressions involve the marginal distributions and the underlying dependence structure through the so-called checkerboard copula. It is further shown that when the marginal distributions are known, these estimators are asymptotically unbiased and Gaussian under weak regularity conditions. Moreover, formulas for computing the asymptotic variance of the two estimators are given. The case of unknown margins is more realistic but also much more difficult to analyze. Nevertheless, it is shown through M-estimation theory that the estimator based on the inversion of Spearman's rho remains consistent in this case. Finally, simulation results are used to investigate the dependence of the estimators on the choice of margins. On the basis of the results presented here, the new estimators can be recommended for the assessment of dependence in copula models with discrete data.</description><creator>Grebennikov, Ievgenii</creator><contributor>Christian Genest (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Johanna Neslehova (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Statistics </subject><title>Moment-based estimation of dependence parameters in copula models for discrete data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784p706.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd4730539</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g569k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The use of scaffold materials for reconstructive orthopaedics is a strong candidate for promoting tissue regeneration while addressing both mechanical and biological constraints. A scaffold's microarchitecture can be specifically tailored to locally match specific properties of the host tissue resulting in a biologically fixed implant. As such, the use of an optimized graded scaffold mitigates otherwise present issues causing implant failure, such as bone resorption and shear stress at the implant interface. A 2D hierarchical topology optimization technique has been developed here for the design of a cellular bone tissue scaffold that mimics the stiffness of the surrounding bone while maximizing permeability for bone ingrowth. The procedure involves sequentially optimizing material layout at two scales: 1) the material distribution of the implant, and 2) the cellular material used in its construction. In the first stage, an optimal material distribution is obtained for the implant such that the stiffness of the structure matches that of bone. In the second stage, the optimal relative density distribution from the previous stage is used to interpolate target material properties at each location of the implant domain. Target matching topology optimization is used to obtain unit cells with desired stiffness and maximum permeability throughout the implant. The procedure is currently developed in 2D and can be extended to produce clinically relevant 3D implant models. A 2D bone fracture fixation plate is designed as a demonstration of the proposed methodology, where an in-plane loading scenario is assumed. The plate is optimized at both the material and cellular level to achieve target stiffness and permeability properties based on physiological requirements. It is shown that by integrating multi-objective optimization with multi-scale topology optimization, a bone tissue implant can be created that is both mechanically optimal and conducive to bone tissue regeneration.</description><description>L'utilisation de matériaux d'échafaudage pour l'orthopédie reconstructive est un excellent candidat pour la promotion de la régénération des tissus tout en s’occupant des contraintes mécaniques et biologiques. La microarchitecture de l’échafaudage peut être spécifiquement conçue pour égaliser les propriétés locales spécifiques du tissu de l’hôte résultant en un implant biologique fixe. En tant que tel, l'utilisation d'un échafaudage gradué optimisé atténue les problèmes autrement présents qui provoquent l'échec de l’implant, telles que la résorption osseuse et la contrainte de cisaillement à l'interface de l'implant.Une technique 2D d'optimisation hiérarchique de la topologie a été développée ici pour la conception d'un échafaudage pour tissu osseux qui imite la rigidité de l'os qui l'entoure, tout en maximisant sa perméabilité pour la croissance osseuse. Le procédé consiste à optimiser séquentiellement la disposition de matériau à deux échelles: 1) la distribution de matériel de l'implant, et 2) le matériau cellulaire utilisée dans sa construction. Dans la première étape, une distribution de matériau optimal est obtenue pour l'implant de sorte que la rigidité de la structure correspond à celle de l'os. Dans la deuxième étape, la distribution optimale de densité relative de l'étape précédente est utilisée pour interpoler les propriétés matérielles ciblées à chaque emplacement du domaine de l'implant. Optimisation topologique d'adaptation de cible est utilisée pour obtenir des cellules élémentaires avec rigidité souhaitée et la perméabilité maximale tout au long de l'implant. Le procédé est actuellement développé en 2D et peut être étendu afin de réaliser des modèles d'implants 3D cliniquement pertinentes.Une plaque 2D pour la fixation des fractures de l'os est conçue comme une démonstration de la méthodologie proposée, où un scénario de chargement complètement dans le plan est présumé. La plaque est optimisée à la fois au niveau matériel et au niveau cellulaire pour obtenir la raideur et les propriétés de perméabilité ciblées selon les exigences fonctionnelles. Ainsi, en intégrant l'optimisation multi-objective avec l'optimisation topologique multi-échelle, un implant de tissu osseux peut être créé qui est à la fois mécaniquement optimal et favorable à la régénération des tissus osseux.</description><creator>Gogarty, Emily</creator><contributor>Damiano Pasini (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Hierarchical topology optimization for bone tissue scaffold</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h269s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g569k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059cb50v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Maillard reaction refers to the non-enzymatic interaction of reducing sugars with amino acids, and plays a significant role in determining the flavour sensation of many food products.  Since flavour sensation is dictated by a profile of hundreds of compounds, modification of this profile can be an effective method to control the over-all flavour sensation of foods.  Three important factors affecting the Maillard reaction have been investigated using a simple model system: sugar type, amino acid salts and their ratios. Labelled or unlabeled pure reactants - sugars and amino acid salts- were homogenized and pyrolyzed at 250℃ for 20 seconds, and reaction products were separated by Gas Chromatography and then identified by Mass Spectrometry. Results indicated that the sugar type, the amino acid form (free or salt), and their ratios had a significant influence on the total abundance, total number of components, formation of specific peaks as well as on the intensity changes of the common peaks in the various model systems. The data generated may provide useful information on the modification and optimization conditions of the Maillard reaction profiles using practical solutions.</description><description>Réaction de Maillard est basée sur l’interaction non- enzymatique des sucres réducteurs avec des acides aminés, et joue un rôle important dans la détermination  des saveurs de nombreux produits alimentaires. La saveur est dictée par le profil d’une centaine de composés, et la modification de ce profil peut être une méthode efficace pour contrôler la saveur des aliments dans son ensemble. Trois facteurs importants qui affectent la réaction de Maillard ont été étudiés en utilisant un système de modèle simple: le type de sucre, les sels d'acides aminés et de leurs rapports. Réactifs purs ou non marqués étiquetés - sucres et les acides aminés - ont été homogénéisés et pyrolysés à 250 ℃ pendant 20 secondes ;  et les produits de réaction ont été séparés par chromatographie en phase gazeuse et ensuite identifiés par spectrométrie de masse. Les résultats indiquent que le type de sucre, sous forme d'acides aminés (libre ou de sel), et leurs rapports ont une influence significative sur l'abondance totale, le nombre total de composants, la formation de pics spécifiques, ainsi que sur les changements d'intensité des pics communs aux divers systèmes de modèles. Les données générées peuvent fournir des informations utiles sur les conditions appropriées de modification pour l'optimisation des profils de réaction de Maillard en utilisant des solutions pratiques.</description><creator>Wang, Xi</creator><contributor>Varoujan Yaylayan (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Agriculture - Food Science and Technology</subject><title>Investigation of the role of glycine/sugar ratio, sodium and hydrochloride salts of glycine, glucose or fructose on the profile of the Maillard reaction products</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021j25b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059cb50v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zk77q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte: La danse est une modalité thérapeutique de choix en réadaptation, car elle combine les bénéfices de pratiquer une activité physique, en plus d’être une activité sociale agréable. Malgré les preuves scientifiques supportant l'utilisation de la danse en réadaptation, cette modalité thérapeutique est rarement utilisée dans les établissements de réadaptation. Comme d'autres interventions basées sur les données probantes, l’application des résultats d’articles scientifiques dans la pratique clinique demeure un défi.Objectif: Ce mémoire vise à adresser la question de recherche suivante: Quelle stratégie d’application des connaissances (AC) permettra aux professionnels de la santé travaillant en réadaptation d’implanter une intervention par la danse comme modalité thérapeutique? Pour répondre à cette question, les articles de ce mémoire aborderont les objectifs spécifiques suivants: 1) Identifier les facteurs influençant la mise en œuvre d’une intervention par la danse en réadaptation. 2) Identifier le format idéal pour une stratégie d’AC basé sur les besoins des cliniciens en terme de formation. Méthodes: En utilisant une étude qualitative descriptive, ce projet de recherche a été basé sur le Processus des connaissances à la pratique. Trois groupes focus ont été réalisés avec des professionnels de la santé provenant de trois centres de réadaptation délibérément choisis du Centre de Recherche Interdisciplinaire en Réadaptation du Montréal métropolitain. Les données ont été analysées indépendamment par deux membres de l’équipe de recherche, à l'aide d’une analyse de contenu thématique.Résultats: Quatorze cliniciens (six ergothérapeutes, six physiothérapeutes et deux travailleurs sociaux) provenant de trois centres de réadaptation ont participé à cette étude. Quatre principaux facteurs agissant à titre de barrières et facilitateurs à la mise en œuvre d'une intervention par la danse ont émergé de l'analyse thématique: Connaissances et habiletés, Intérêt et croyances personnelles à utiliser la danse en réadaptation, Support de l’organisation, et Ressources disponibles. Malgré l’unicité de chaque centre de réadaptation, les facteurs personnels et organisationnels influençant sur la mise en œuvre d'une intervention de danse étaient similaires pour les trois centres. De surcroit, les participants ont corroboré la nécessité de développer une stratégie simple et facile d’utilisation conçue pour les cliniciens occupés. Des différences ont été observées au niveau du format idéal pour une stratégie d’AC entre les sites utilisant la danse et ceux n’utilisant pas cette modalité thérapeutique. Dans un établissement où la danse est déjà implantée, le mentorat a été perçu comme le meilleur format de diffusion des connaissances. Dans un établissement où la danse n'est pas utilisée, une banque de stratégies actives comprenant une plateforme web avec des vidéos et de la documentation écrite a été identifiée comme étant le format idéal. Dans les trois groupes focus, la structure d'une classe de danse, les exercices et les habiletés des cliniciens ont été identifiés comme étant des éléments importants à inclure dans une stratégie d’AC.Conclusion: En accord avec le Processus des connaissances à la pratique, ce projet de recherche a accompli les deux actions suivantes: Évaluer les obstacles à l'utilisation des connaissances et Adapter les connaissances au contexte local. L'identification des obstacles à la mise en œuvre d'une intervention par la danse, ainsi que du meilleur format et du contenu d’une stratégie d’AC est un précurseur nécessaire à l'élaboration de stratégies efficaces et adaptées aux besoins des cliniciens travaillant dans les centres de réadaptation.  À terme, le développement d’une stratégie de AC pourra contribuer à faciliter la mise en œuvre d'une intervention de la danse dans un contexte de réadaptation.</description><description>Background: Dance is a modality of choice in rehabilitation, because it combines the benefits of aerobic exercise with an enjoyable social activity. Despite the scientific evidence supporting the use of dance in rehabilitation, this treatment modality is rarely used in rehabilitation settings. As with other evidence-based interventions in rehabilitation, the implementation of scientific results from research to practice remains a challenge. Objective: This thesis aims to answer the following research question: What knowledge translation (KT) strategy will enable professionals working in rehabilitation to implement a specific dance intervention as a therapeutic modality? To answer this question, the two manuscripts presented in this thesis will address the following specific research objectives: 1) To determine the factors influencing the implementation of a dance intervention in a rehabilitation setting, 2) To identify the preferred format for a KT strategy based on clinicians’ perceptions of their needs for specific knowledge. Methods: Using a descriptive qualitative study design, this research project was based on the Knowledge-to-Action Process. Three focus groups were conducted with allied health-care professionals from three purposefully selected rehabilitation centers of the Centre for Interdisciplinary Research in Rehabilitation of the Greater Montreal (CRIR). Two members of the research team independently analyzed the transcripts using thematic content analysis. Results: Fourteen clinicians across three sites (six occupational therapists, six physiotherapists and two social workers) participated in this study. Four main factors supporting or limiting the implementation of a dance intervention emerged from the analysis: Clinician’s knowledge and skills, Interest towards using dance as a potential intervention and personal beliefs, Support from the organization of the institution, and Available resources. Although each site was different, the personal and organizational factors influencing the implementation of a potential dance intervention were similar for all three sites. Moreover, the participants corroborated the need for a simple and user-friendly KT strategy, designed for busy clinicians. Discrepancies were noted on which type of KT strategy would be most useful to ensure the implementation of dance interventions between sites currently using dance or those not using it. In an institution where dance was already implemented, direct mentoring was perceived as the ideal format to disseminate knowledge. In an institution where dance was not used, the best perceived format was a combination of active strategies in various formats: a web-supported platform with videos and written documentation. In all three groups, the structure of a dance class, the dance exercises and the therapists’ skills were described as important components of this multi-component tool.    Conclusion: Consistent with the Knowledge-to-Action Process, this research project accomplished two actions: Assess Barriers to Knowledge Use and Adapt Knowledge to Local Context. The identification of the barriers to implement a dance intervention and the preferred format and content of KT strategy are a necessary precursor to developing effective KT strategies tailored to the need of clinicians working in rehabilitation centers. It can ultimately contribute to facilitate the implementation a dance intervention in rehabilitation settings. </description><creator>Demers, Marika</creator><contributor>Patricia McKinley (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Occupational Health and Therapy</subject><title>Development of a KT intervention to promote the use of dance as a therapeutic modality in rehabilitation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z826r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zk77q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634681g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Public education in Canada is currently undergoing a period of financial restraint and fiscal reform.  In spite of these restraints, schools are still mandated to provide diverse educational services, such as academic support and extensive extra- and co-curricular activities.  This is placing school administration in the challenging position of funding these programs while balancing school budgets.  This qualitative study, conducted with the grounded theory methodology, examined the commercial practices and perspectives of Montreal school administrators.  Although there is an abundance of theoretical literature on commercialism in education, very few studies have examined these practices from the perspective of the administrators themselves. The study focuses on the importance of ethical educational leadership in light of seven commercial practices: fundraising, sponsorship of school programs, exclusive agreements, sponsorship of incentive programs, appropriation of space, sponsorship of supplementary educational materials, and digital marketing.  The findings suggest that current fiscal landscapes combined with budgetary restrictions and increased educational needs and expectations, pressures school administrators to actively seek out additional funding through commercial practices.  When school administrators are faced with these restrictions and expectations they initiate a process of deliberation which takes into account complex ethical considerations.  Administrators tend to rely on their personal values and past-experiences to establish good-judgement in their decision making process.  </description><description>L'éducation publique au Canada connaît actuellement une période de restrictions financières et budgétaires. En dépit de ces restrictions, les écoles ont pour mandat de fournir aux élèves des services éducatifs diversifiés, tels que le soutien scolaire ainsi que de nombreuses activités parascolaires. Cette situation représente des défis importants pour les administrateurs scolaires.  Ils doivent trouver le moyen d’offrir les services exigés tout en équilibrant les budgets des écoles. Cette étude qualitative, menée avec la méthodologie de la théorie ancrée (grounded theory), a examiné les pratiques commerciales d’administrateurs scolaires de Montréal ainsi que leurs perspectives sur ces pratiques. Bien qu'il existe une abondante littérature théorique sur la commercialisation de l’éducation, très peu d'études portent sur les défis et les pratiques des administrateurs eux-mêmes. Cette étude met l'accent sur l'importance du leadership éducatif éthique à la lumière de sept pratiques commerciales: les collectes de fonds, les accords exclusifs, l'appropriation de l'espace, ainsi que le parrainage des programmes scolaires, des programmes d'incitation, de matériel didactique supplémentaire et de marketing numérique. Les résultats de l’étude démontrent que les administrateurs interrogés recherchent activement des fonds supplémentaires par la voie de pratiques commerciales pour combler les besoins éducatifs de l’école. Lorsque les administrateurs sont confrontés à des restrictions budgétaires importantes, ils initient un processus de délibération qui tient compte de considérations éthiques complexes. Les administrateurs ont tendance à se référer à leurs valeurs personnelles ainsi qu’à leurs expériences antérieures dans leur processus de prise de décision.</description><creator>Turnbull, Christopher</creator><contributor>Ronald Morris (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Education - Administration</subject><title>Perspectives and practices on commercialism in education: a study of school administrators in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881q18d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634681g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q929q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The continuous growth in the demand of transmission capacity requires high data rates in today's fiber-optic communication systems. Fiber nonlinearity is considered to be the major obstacle in the development of communication capacity. Optical back propagation is one of the ways to address this problem. This thesis explores the performances of optical back propagation under several practical non-ideal conditions. It compares the results of optical back propagation with other nonlinearity control techniques such as digital back propagation and mid-link optical phase conjugation.Optical back propagation is an all optical process which builds into the optical communication systems to compensate for the phase noise caused by fiber nonlinear effects. Aside from previously established simulation results in the literature of optical back propagation under ideal cases, this thesis demonstrates simulation results of optical back propagation under several non-ideal cases. It demonstrates a 5.7dB of power penalty that occurs with a 5dB of optical signal to noise ratio degradation in the system.For further investigation into the optical back propagation system, advanced modulation formats of the optical signals and higher transmission baud rate effects are studied.      The results demonstrated in this thesis can also be used to determine the optimum operating system parameters under non-ideal conditions in optical back propagation systems.</description><description>La croissance incessante de la demande pour la capacité de transmission crée un besoin pour des taux de transmission de données élevés dans les systèmes de communication par fibres optiques d'aujourd'hui. La non-linéarité de la fibre est considérée comme un obstacle majeur dans le développement de la capacité de communication. La rétro-propagation optique est une des façons de répondre à ce problème. Cette thèse explore les performances de la rétro-propagation optique dans plusieurs conditions pratiques et imparfaites. Les résultats obtenus avec la rétro-propagation optique sont comparés à ceux obtenus avec d'autres techniques de contrôle de la non-linéarité telles que la rétro-propagation numérique et la conjugaison de phase optique à mi-chemin.La rétro-propagation optique est un procédé entièrement optique qui s'introduit dans les systèmes de communication optiques pour compenser le bruit de phase causé par les effets non-linéaires de la fibre. En plus des résultats de simulation institués précédemment dans la documentation pour la rétro-propagation dans des conditions idéales, les résultats de simulation pour la rétro-propagation dans des conditions imparfaites sont présentés dans cette thèse. Il est démontré qu'une perte de puissance de 5.7 dB est obtenue lorsque la dégradation du rapport signal sur bruit optique dans le système est de 5 dB.Pour de plus amples investigations du système de rétro-propagation optique, des formats de modulation avancés pour le signal optique ainsi que l'effet de l'augmentation de la vitesse de transmission en bauds sont étudiés.Les résultats présentés dans cette thèse peuvent aussi être utilisés pour déterminer les paramètres optimaux pour un système de rétro-propagation optique fonctionnant dans des conditions imparfaites.</description><creator>Wang, Guanhui</creator><contributor>Lawrence R Chen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Analysis of optical back propagation under non-ideal optical phase conjugation and amplifier noise</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289n11r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q929q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gr43q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La dystrophie musculaire de Duchenne est une forme de myopathie héréditaire qui mène à une atrophie et une faiblesse musculaire progressive, réduisant ainsi l’espérance de vie des patients à environ 20-30 ans. La dégénérescence est causée par l’absence de dystrophine, une protéine impliquée dans l’intégrité structurale des fibres musculaires. Les cellules satellites sont des cellules souches adultes responsables de la croissance post-natale et de la régénération des muscles squelettiques. Elles sont également une source potentielle de cellules donneuses pour le traitement  de la dystrophie musculaire de Duchenne.  La culture de cellules satellites ex vivo entraine leur différenciation en myoblastes. Lors de la transplantation de myoblastes, ceux-ci peuvent contribuer à rétablir l’expression de la dystrophine, mais ils sont incapables de s’auto-renouveler ou de retourner vers l’état de cellule satellite pour permettre des cycles de régénération supplémentaires. L’objectif de ce projet est d’étudier la voie de signalisation des microARNs afin de réguler le renouvèlement des cellules satellites ex vivo et in vivo.  Le microARN-31 cible l’ARN messager myogenic factor 5 (Myf5) afin de réprimer l’expression de ce facteur de transcription myogénique et de s’opposer à la cascade de différenciation. La transfection du microARN-31 augmente la proportion de cellules satellites en culture exprimant le facteur de transcription PAX7 et n’exprimant pas le facteur myogénique régulateur MYOD. Ces résultats sont caractéristiques d’un phénotype cellulaire associé au renouvèlement des cellules satellites, et non à leur différenciation. L’effet du microARN-31 sur l’expression de MYOD pourrait être modulé par la sous-expression de FXR1, une protéine liant l’ARN impliquée dans la stabilisation de l’expression de MYOD. Au contraire, nos résultats démontrent que miR-31 n’influence pas le taux de prolifération des cellules satellites in vitro. Nous avons effectué une expérience de greffe dans des souris mdx dépourvues de système immunitaire acquis afin de déterminer les effets de miR-31 in vivo. La transfection transitoire de miR-31 dans des cellules satellites donneuses n’a pas d’effet statistiquement significatif sur l’expansion des cellules dérivées de donneuses, tel qu’analysé par imagerie bioluminescente in vivo. Une telle transfection n’a pas non plus d’effet sur la restauration de l’expression de la dystrophine ou sur l'auto-renouvellement in vivo.</description><description>Duchenne muscular dystrophy is a heritable myopathy resulting in progressive muscle weakness and atrophy, reducing life expectancy to 20-30 years. Degeneration is caused by the virtual lack of dystrophin, a protein involved in the structural integrity of muscle fibres. Satellite cells, the adult stem cells responsible for all post-natal growth and regeneration of skeletal muscle, are a possible source of donor cells for treatment of Duchenne muscular dystrophy. Ex-vivo culture of satellite cells causes differentiation into myoblasts. Transplanted myoblasts may contribute to dystrophin restoration, but are not capable of self-renewal and homing to the satellite cell for subsequent rounds of regeneration. This work aims to investigate the role of the microRNA-31 in self-renewal of satellite cells ex vivo and in vivo.  MicroRNA-31 targets the myogenic factor 5 (Myf5) transcript to impede expression of this myogenic regulatory transcription factor, opposing the differentiation cascade. Transfection with microRNA-31 increased the proportion of cultured satellite cells expressing the transcription factor PAX7, and lacking expression of the myogenic regulatory factor MYOD in vitro. This indicates a cell phenotype associated with self-renewal of satellite cells, as opposed to differentiation. Effects of microRNA-31 on accumulation of MYOD may be mediated by downregulation of FXR1, an RNA-binding protein implicated in stabilization of MYOD expression. Conversely, it was demonstrated that miR-31 does not influence the proliferation rate of satellite cells in vitro. An engraftment assay was performed in nude-mdx mice to determine the effects of miR-31 in vivo. Transient transfection of donor-derived satellite cells with miR-31 prior to engraftment did not have a statistically significant effect on their in vivo, analyzed by bioluminescence imaging, restoration of dystrophin expression or their self-renewal of donor-derived satellite cells.</description><creator>Duncan, Heather</creator><contributor>Colin Crist (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Effects of microRNA-31 on skeletal muscle stem cell self- renewal ex vivo and in vivo</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf90p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gr43q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wq91x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis aims to show that the works of Yves Bonnefoy – from the publication of the autobiographical L’Arrière-pays (1972) to his most recent poetry, such as L’Heure présente (2011) – are marked by the central role that the relation to the past plays in the quest for presence. The hypothesis underpinning this study is that via the remembrance of things past, anamnesis makes possible an authentic relation with reality and beings in the present. Evoking the past is thereby the key term in the sense of finitude and the ethics of writing as Bonnefoy’s writing tirelessly seeks to name and reforge the links to beings and places. The first chapter, ‘From Autobiography to Anamnesis’, shows how the poems open the reader to a past that is not simply autobiographical and individual but also universal by a task of naming ‘Great Signifiers’. The second chapter, ‘The Anamnestic Illumination’, examines how anamnesis leads to an awareness of the origins of ‘gnostic illusions’, such as that of the hinterland, paving the way for a poetry capable of seeing its way around them in order to find a path to reality. The third chapter, ‘Anamnestic Ethics’, deals with the ethical awakening produced by the awareness of the vulnerability of beings and places to the effects of time. Contrary to the position that has traditionally been taken by critics, this thesis shows that if the quest for presence is indeed an attempt to rediscover a more genuine relation to a reality lived in its finitude, that quest is also one for the past, which will bring the poet back to the ethical demand of the present.</description><description>Le but de ce mémoire est de montrer qu’à partir de la publication de L’Arrière-pays (1972), écrit à caractère autobiographique, et jusqu’aux plus récents recueils poétiques d’Yves Bonnefoy, tel que L’Heure présente (2011), le rapport au passé joue un rôle central dans la quête de la présence. L’hypothèse qui sous-tend cette étude est que l’anamnèse bonnefoysienne permet de retrouver, grâce à un détour paradoxal par les souvenirs et le passé, un rapport authentique avec la réalité physique et humaine. L’évocation du passé gouverne à la fois le sentiment de la finitude et l’éthique de l’écriture. Chez Bonnefoy, l’œuvre vise sans cesse à nommer et renouer les liens avec les êtres et les choses destinées à disparaître. Le premier chapitre, « De l’autobiographie à l’anamnèse », montre comment, par un jeu de transposition du biographique vers de « grands signifiants », les poèmes ouvrent une quête du passé qui n’est pas simplement autobiographique et particulière, mais universelle et compréhensible pour le lecteur. Le deuxième chapitre, « L’éclaircissement anamnésique », examine comment la prise de conscience des illusions « gnostiques », rendue possible par l’anamnèse, permet une écriture poétique consciente de ses tentations et de sa redirection vers le réel. Le troisième chapitre, « L’éthique anamnésique », aborde le sursaut éthique provoqué par la conscience de la vulnérabilité des êtres et des lieux face au temps. Contrairement à la perspective adoptée traditionnellement par la critique, ce mémoire montre que si la quête de la présence est bien une tentative de redécouverte d’une réalité vécue dans sa finitude, elle est aussi conditionnée par une quête du passé qui ramène le poète vers ses devoirs présents.</description><creator>Huguet, Pierre</creator><contributor>Arnaud Bernadet (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Literature - Romance</subject><title>De «L’Arrière-pays» à «L’Heure présente»: poétique de l’anamnèse chez Yves Bonnefoy</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838365s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wq91x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hv678</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte –Le cancer pédiatrique est la principale cause de mortalité par maladie chez les enfants et les adolescents. Afin de favoriser l’excellence dans les soins de fin de vie chez les enfants en phase terminale, il est nécessaire de comprendre la perception sociale des dimensions complexes de la mort, des mourants et de la vie ainsi que de reconnaître les enfants comme des acteurs moraux et sociaux dans leurs soins de santé.  Alors que la voix des enfants en fin de vie est sous-représentée, ces patients recevant des soins palliatifs font pourtant face à une réalité unique et en constante évolution. Une recherche qualitative auprès d’enfants en fin de vie a été proposée comme puissant véhicule pour engager cette population, pour étudier les diverses dimensions de la qualité de vie liée à la santé, ainsi que pour favoriser l’approche participative dans les soins de fin de vie.  Objectif—L’objectif est d’explorer l'éthique de l'engagement dans l'évaluation de la qualité de vie liée à la santé (QVLS) chez les enfants et les adolescents atteints de cancer, ainsi que d'identifier les domaines où il y a une pénurie de méthodes qualitatives efficaces pour un tel engagement dans la recherche en soins palliatifs pédiatriques.Méthodologie—Cette analyse est basée sur une évaluation critique, fondée sur une revue systématique telle que proposée par Arkey et O’Malley (2005).  L’évaluation critique représente une cartographie des politiques et de la littérature portant sur la psychologie associée au développement de l’enfant, la sociologie de l’enfance et les codes de conduite en éthique de la recherche pédiatrique et en soins palliatifs pédiatriques.  Conclusion—La recherche qualitative pour l’évaluation de la QVLS chez les enfants et adolescents en soins palliatifs requière l’adoption de méthodes innovatrices, accordant une plus grande légitimité aux acteurs moraux et sociaux que représentent les enfants en soins palliatifs. Assurer une qualité de vie liée à la santé (QVLS) est la panacée pour les soins palliatifs pédiatriques. Pour y parvenir, il est impératif que l’éthique se soucie des pratiques et reconnaisse l’expertise des enfants et de l’épistémologie sociale de la maladie en phase terminale. À la lumière de l'évaluation critique qui a été réalisée, il ressort que ces méthodes sont disposées à respecter les droits de participation des enfants en vertu de la nouvelle sociologie de l'enfant et des normes régissant l’éthique de la recherche pédiatrique. L’engagement qualitatif dans les soins palliatifs pédiatriques est à la fois éthiquement défendable et un élément crucial à la prestation de soins complets aux patients.</description><description>Background— Pediatric cancer remains the leading cause of disease-related death in children and adolescents. Promoting excellence in the care of terminally ill children is socially dependent on recognizing the complex dimensions of death, dying and living that emerge from situating the child as an active social and moral agent in their healthcare. The continued underrepresentation of children’s voices at the end of life, however, fails to ground modalities of care in the unique and evolving realities they face as palliative patients. Qualitative health research with terminally ill children has been proposed as a meaningful vehicle for engagement, to investigate the various dimensions of health-related quality of life and to augment their participatory agency in end of life care.Objective—To explore the ethics of qualitative engagement in assessing health-related quality of life (HRQoL) among children and adolescents with cancer, and to identify areas where there is paucity of effective qualitative methods for such engagement in pediatric palliative care research.Methods—This analysis was conducted as a critical assessment—combining policy and literature mapping from developmental child psychology, childhood sociology, jurisdictional codes of ethics for pediatric research and pediatric palliative care research—based on the framework for scoping review by Arksey and O’Malley (2005). Conclusion—Qualitative HRQoL research with terminally ill children demands innovative methods that afford greater legitimacy to children’s moral and social agency in palliative care settings. Because ensuring an optimal health-related quality of life (HRQoL) is the panacea of pediatric palliative care, it is an ethical imperative that care practices become the province of childhood expertise and social epistemologies of terminal illness. What emerges from the critical assessment is that such methods are poised to respect children’s participatory rights pursuant to the new sociology of the child and prevailing ethical norms governing pediatric research. Qualitative engagement in pediatric palliative care is both ethically defensible and a necessary element to delivering comprehensive patient care. </description><creator>Rahimzadeh, Vasiliki</creator><contributor>Carolyn Ells (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Gillian Bartlett-Esquilant (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - General</subject><title>On the ethics of engagement: health-related quality of life in terminally ill children and adolescents</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935603n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hv678</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10725</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>