<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:52:56Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):450" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mx48n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:05:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study surveyed 644 (337 males, 306 females) high school students and found that social groups that were disidentified from schools, when compared to identified groups; (a) were perceived to be more distinctive, (b) were more sensitive to the number of competing outgroups, (c) had more closed and cohesive group structures, (d) were perceived to have more homogeneous memberships, and (e) were perceived to be more likely to enact behavioral sanctions against members who strayed from internal group norms. While members of school-identified groups had better self-esteem on average than members of disidentified (at-risk) groups, members of disidentified groups who felt closely connected to their groups had better self-esteem than those who felt more loosely associated, and, such disidentified group members had self-esteem comparable to even identified group members. The results of the present study suggest that the dominant individualistic paradigm fails to satisfactorily explain, or address the needs of socially connected at-risk students who rely on their anti-normative groups to buoy their self-esteem and define their identities.</description><creator>Weber, J. Mark (Jonathan Mark)</creator><contributor>Taylor, Donald M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Reference groups.</subject><subject>Self-esteem in adolescence.</subject><subject>High school students -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Group identity.</subject><title>Social identity, disidentification, and the at-risk student : an intergroup relations perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq457.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx48n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h378q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:05:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to examine the differences between international certification standards for ice hockey helmets. The American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM), Canadian Standards Association (CSA) and International Organization Standards (ISO) protocols were compared. Only the impact testing methods at ambient temperatures were examined. Four helmet models, currently available to consumers, were used for testing. No significant differences (p $&lt;$ 0.05) were found between the standards in a rank order comparison. Further analysis of differences, with peak linear accelerations separated by impact locations showed significant differences (p $&lt;$ 0.05) between all standards, at five of the six defined impact sites, with no differences being found between standards at the rear site. Post-hoc pairwise multiple comparisons also showed significant performance differences (p $&lt;$ 0.05) between helmet models.</description><creator>Wall, Robert Edward.</creator><date>1996</date><subject>Hockey -- Equipment and supplies -- Standards.</subject><subject>Helmets -- Testing.</subject><subject>Helmets -- Standards.</subject><title>Comparison of international certification standards for ice hockey helmets</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj61g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h378q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m142x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to discover whether the gymnasts' body shape affects the judging of gymnastics. The goal was to discover whether the judges' perceptions of the gymnasts' body shape related to the gymnasts' performance scores. A second goal was to discover whether performance scores differed when given by judges with two levels of experience (experienced and novice). Videotapes of compulsory routines performed by 16 gymnasts on bars, beam and floor were constructed to simulate a competition. Eighteen judges, nine novice and nine experienced, evaluated the routines. They were also required to rate their perception of the aesthetic appeal of the 16 gymnasts' body shape. Each gymnasts' body mass index (BMI) was calculated from their height and weight measurements to quantify body shape. The scores were analyzed using repeated measures analysis of variance. The results showed a significant main effect of BMI on judges' perception of gymnasts' body shape scores, $F(3,48)=9.50, p&lt;.001.$ Gymnasts with a medium-low BMI received significantly higher perception scores than gymnasts with a medium-high BMI and gymnasts with a high BMI. The results also showed a significant main effect $(p&lt;.001)$ of BMI on performance scores. Gymnasts with a high BMI received higher performance scores than those gymnasts with a low BMI, medium-low BMI and medium-high BMI. The effect of judge experience was very close to significant $(p&lt;.059)$ in relation to performance scores. Experienced judges gave lower performance scores than novice judges. Although all judges preferred smaller body shape, this preference did not affect the performance scores award by the judges.</description><creator>Valiquette, Sheri.</creator><contributor>Downey, M. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Gymnastics -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Gymnastics -- Officiating -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Physical-appearance-based bias.</subject><title>The effects of the gymnast's body shape on the judging of gymnastics /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m6058.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m142x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c466s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Philip Roth's parody of autobiography in the Zuckerman series is part of a larger debate concerning the problems of Jewish art. As Roth manipulates personal and personified autobiography, he both underlines and undermines Jewish traditions of reading and writing. To be sure, Zuckerman's struggle for artistic identity articulates a long-standing Jewish concern with the tensions of collective representation. It is from a culture consistently threatened by alienation and extermination that Roth finds his terms of reference. Zuckerman and his creator are subject to a whole discourse of Jewish textuality: to Jewish notions about the relationship between the individual and the group; between fact and fiction and between aesthetics and morality. However, the Zuckerman books are at once part of a continuum of Jewish culture and a unique response to the pressures of contemporary American Judaism. Through his humorous manipulations of autobiographical fiction, Roth finally counter-turns the very compasses by which he has oriented himself. He offers a potent commentary on the fatuity of Jewish "facts" and on the fictitious nature of the collectivized Jewish voice. For Roth, it is not only the Jew's experience, but his/her imagination, his/her individual frame of understanding, that determines ethnic identity. In the end, Roth challenges the cohesion of the Jewish cultural text. He places himself in a house of mirrors, where life and art, self and group, Jewish reverence and Jewish rebellion, endlessly reflect off one another.</description><creator>Traves, Julie.</creator><contributor>Ohlin, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>American fiction -- Jewish authors -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Roth, Philip -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Writing himself and others : Philip Roth and the autobiographical tradition in Jewish-American fiction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j313f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c466s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xk57n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examined instructional strategies and their impacts on preservice teachers' attitude toward multicultural issues and learners. A qualitative phenomenological approach is used for this study because of my philosophical belief in multiple realities. The research site was a classroom of the Multi-Cultured/Multi-Racial course offered by the Faculty of Education in an English University located in the Montreal area. The studied course was a compulsory preservice teacher training course implemented for the first time in response to the requirement of the Ministry of Education in Quebec. The data were gathered through classroom observation, questionnaires distributed to preservice teachers in the classroom, interviews with five preservice teachers enrolled in the studied course, and an interview with the course director. Sessions of cooperative learning and discussions following videos seemed to be effective to deepen preservice teachers' understandings of multicultural issues and teaching. The effects that the studied course had on preservice teachers differed among respondents depending on their previous experience. Preservice teachers with minimal multicultural experience felt that they learned a lot from the course, whereas preservice teachers with more multicultural experience felt that the course fell short of their expectations.</description><creator>Takahashi, Mika.</creator><contributor>Ghosh, Ratna (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Multicultural education.</subject><subject>Student teachers -- Attitudes.</subject><title>Multicultural preservice teacher education</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp28j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk57n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jq77j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For almost 35 years the work carried out by the Brazilian artist Lygia Clark between the 1950s and until her death, in 1988, has attracted the attention of both Brazilian and European scholars and critics. Since special attention has only been given to her post-1969 work, the work carried out until 1969 has been overlooked. In particular, I would argue that through the incorporation of the human body Clark's 1959-1964 Bicho series is the first spatial performative strategy developed by Clark during the 1960s and against which all her subsequent production needs to be read. The present essay is thus an attempt to read as spatial performative strategies Clark's Bicho series with and against the Brazilian reception of Mondrian, reception which, as I would argue has been overlooked in the context of her work. Furthermore, I would argue that in order for us to better understand how the Bicho series unfold as spatial performative strategies the Brazilian reception of Mondrian must be approached through the Brazilian reception of Merleau-Ponty's phenomenology and political and cultural movements of the time. While the role played by Merleau-Ponty's incorporation of the human body in Clark's work has not been closely examined, Clark's engagement with the political and cultural movements of her time has been underestimated. I would argue that any attempt to give an account of Clark's practice needs to take into consideration the role these three aspects played in her engagement with the problem of representation.</description><creator>Suescun Pozas, María del Carmen.</creator><contributor>Ross, Christine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Mondrian, Piet, 1872-1944 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Clark, Lygia, 1920- -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Lygia Clark and the European tradition : tracing the appearance of a different space</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf793.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq77j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418q154</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to describe and interpret cooperative learning in a secondary school physical education program. A multiple-method case study design was used to investigate the physical education environment. One eighth grade girls handball class in its first year of cooperative learning was compared to an eleventh grade girls handball class in its fourth year of cooperative learning. The qualitative inquiry included interviewing the students and the physical education teacher, taking field notes, and analysing relevant documents. A modified version of the task structure observational system (Siedentop, 1994) was used as a quantitative measure of the instructional ecology of the two physical education classes. Data revealed that both classes had low management, transition, and wait times. The grade eleven class spent less time in instruction and more time in engagement than the grade eight class. Both classes showed a similar amount of opportunities to respond during activity, but the eleventh grade class exhibited higher successful student responses. The cognitive engagement was integral to the functioning of both units. This included time used by the students, instead of direct instruction by the teacher, for learning a skill, reviewing material learned, planning a strategy at the beginning of a game, implementing change in activity during the game, and reflecting on activity after the game. The study revealed that both teacher and students understood and could visibly see the benefits that cooperative learning offered to the physical education program. This example of cooperative learning in physical education incorporated the basic elements of positive interdependence, individual accountability, face-to-face interaction, social and interpersonal skills, and group processing, which are germane to effective cooperative learning.</description><creator>Strachan, Kevin.</creator><contributor>Dyson, Ben P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Physical education and training -- Study and teaching (Secondary)</subject><subject>Group work in education.</subject><title>Cooperative learning in a secondary school physical education program</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br44p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418q154</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010s139</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis outlines Nietzsche's view of Socrates in The Birth of Tragedy. Socrates is first argued to be the father of science and then, after having explained the artistic nature of the world and ourselves according to Nietzsche, Socrates' degenerative, nihilistic influence upon the world is detailed. Science is then explained to have originated in a moral perspective on the world, the latter growing out of self-denial, and ultimately illness. The "dying Socrates" is Nietzsche's symbol of science as a negative positing of the artistic forces one is, from whence Nietzsche concludes the impossibility of escaping from oneself by such means.</description><creator>Skilnick, Randall.</creator><contributor>Booth, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Nietzsche, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1844-1900. Geburt der Tragüdie.</subject><subject>Socrates.</subject><title>Nietzsche's view of Socrates in The birth of tragedy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0324957.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010s139</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hh62x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Late nineteenth- and early twentieth-century Montreal witnessed the proliferation of parks and playgrounds. Products of urban capitalist development, these deeply ideological spaces, inscribed with different gender, class, ethnic, and sexual meanings, are the subject of this thesis. Moving from the scenic park to the neighbourhood park to the playground, this study examines the relationship among the power to construct a space, the values inscribed in it, and a system of regulation designed to either bar the less powerful or eject those who challenged these values. It links the uneven development of parks and playgrounds in Montreal to the unequal power of the different classes and ethnic groups. It connects the construction of parks as domestic enclaves for families generally and women specifically to the function of parks, places to uphold female propriety, respectable (hetero)sexuality, and bourgeois domesticity. It traces how those who embodied social unrest, economic disorder, and sexual chaos (the drinking man, the vagabond, and the "promiscuous" young working woman) were subject to a policy of exclusion. It charts the process by which the proponents for playgrounds, the elite anglophone organization the Montreal Parks and Playgrounds Association, manipulated play space as a means to curb male vices and contain male heterosexual urges, as well as train working-class boys to be good citizens and obedient workers in the (Anglo-Saxon) nation. This thesis is a history of how the powerful architects of these gendered spaces helped construct the norm and justified the punishment of the deviant.</description><creator>Schmidt, Sarah (Sarah Trainor), 1971-</creator><contributor>Morton, Suzanne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Social life and customs -- History.</subject><subject>Montreal Parks and Playgrounds Association -- History.</subject><subject>Parks -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><subject>Playgrounds -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><title>Domesticating parks and mastering playgrounds : sexuality, power and place in Montreal, 1870-1930</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng665.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh62x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz56f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Most critical acclaim of William Faulkner has focused on his innovations of narrative technique, and while critics have frequently noted the correlation between form and meaning in his novels, the central focus of these novels--race--has largely been ignored in the criticism. The purpose of this paper is to examine Faulkner's narrative methodology and arrangement of material in order to demonstrate that the structures of his novels, particularly Light in August and Absalom, Absalom!, consistently enhance and dramatize the major subject and themes of the novels. Under careful scrutiny, these structures reveal an effective and dramatic parallel between Faulkner's rhetorical methodology and the complexity of his subject matter--the South, and the issue of race.</description><creator>Rivers, Patricia Ann.</creator><contributor>Cope, Karin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Faulkner, William, 1897-1962 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>The narrative poetics of William Faulkner : an analysis of form and meaning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f3262.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz56f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hb80c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this investigation was to examine whether sports in which boys participated spontaneously (i.e., not organized as a treatment) could be associated with the retrenchment of later adolescent delinquent behaviours. The objectives of this particular investigation were to: (i) observe how this participation might alter a negative behavioural developmental trajectory; and (ii) study the possible effects of transition in sports activity (i.e., increases or decreases in participation in sports from year to year) on current and later risk for delinquency. This investigation utilized data obtained from the Montreal Longitudinal-Experimental Study of Boys which started in 1984 when the boys were six years old. Seven-hundred-eleven of the subjects met the inclusion criteria necessary to participate in the present study. Each year, from 1989 (age 11) to 1995 (age 17) the subjects were asked to complete the Self-Report-Delinquency questionnaire, a 27-item scale detailing their involvement in antisocial behaviour over the previous 12-month period. The scores of four of these years were retained for study; namely, those for 1989 (age 11), 1991 (age 13), 1993 (age 15), 1995 (age 17). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Rapagna, Paul.</creator><contributor>Kurtz, L. Pagani (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Wall, A. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Sports -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Problem youth.</subject><subject>Youth -- Recreation.</subject><subject>Juvenile delinquency.</subject><subject>Teenage boys -- Psychology.</subject><title>Sport and delinquency : effects of participation in sport on the development of adolescent antisocial and delinquent behaviour</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cz57q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb80c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n318k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Master's Thesis studies the theme of the stroll (promenade) and the various metaphors it inspires in a selection of humanist works from the 16th and 17th centuries. Furthermore, it attempts to show that the image of the promenade acts as an emblem to various intellectual trends here united under the concept of openness. The diverses uses of the promenade are each considered to be emblematic of a level of ouverture which, in turn, forms the subject of a section of the thesis: I. Openness to the world, where the theme of the stroll is studied in relation to another great humanist commonplace: that of the "book of the world"; II. Openness to the other, where, with special emphasis on Jacques Tahureau's Dialogues (published in 1565), the promenade is shown to be emblematic of the sociability so highly regarded by humanists; III. Rhetorical openness, where, with particular emphasis on Montaigne's Essays (published between 1580 and 1595) and Etienne Pasquier's Letters (published between 1585 and 1619), are examined the rhetorical meanings of the promenade; and finally IV. Philosophical openness, where, with particular emphasis on Francois La Mothe Le Vayer's La Promenade (published between 1662 and 1664), the emblem of the stroll is shown to be inextricably linked to philosophical skepticism. A brief epilogue points to the literary future of the promenade and links the aesthetics of humanist openness to some contemporary epistemological trends.</description><creator>Prévost, Maxime.</creator><contributor>Doiron, Normand (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Walking in literature.</subject><subject>Humanism in literature.</subject><title>La promenade et l'ouverture du texte humaniste /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh636.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n318k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jq78t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The commitment to community shared by Native American authors such as N. Scott Momaday, James Welch, and Louise Erdrich is partially evinced by each author's readiness to inscribe in novel form the values and traditions of the tribal community or communities with which he/she is closely associated. Many students of the novel will attest to its pliant, sometimes transmutable nature; nevertheless, as this study attempts to make clear, there are some reasons why Native American authors should reconsider using the novel as a means to express their tribal communities' values and traditions. Unambivalent prescriptions, however, seem more suited to the requirements of law or medicine; and so this study also examines some of the reasons why Native American authors should continue to embrace this relatively "new" art form persistently termed the novel.</description><creator>Potts, Henry M.</creator><contributor>Ohlin, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Indians in literature.</subject><subject>Indian authors.</subject><subject>American fiction -- Indian authors -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Native American values and traditions and the novel : ambivalence shall speak the story</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v97n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq78t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214r13f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with Montreal innkeepers and tavern-keepers in the first half of the 18th century. It begins with an analysis of the strict regulations imposed on such traders by colonial authorities and follows with a description of their social profile. This research then draws attention to the French, mainly military, origins of this group, as well as to the important role played by women in such occupations and their close relationship with the artisan class. Finally, the study of the estate and of the way of life of innkeepers and tavern-keepers suceeds in showing similarities in their domestic environment, commercial practices and relation to property.</description><creator>Poliquin, Marie-Claude.</creator><contributor>Dechene, Louise (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Hotelkeepers -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History -- 18th century.</subject><title>Les aubergistes et les cabaretiers montréalais entre 1700 et 1755. /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806187h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r13f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p670s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explains why the prefix maha- in Malagasy (a Western Austronesian language) can have either an abilitive or causative meaning. It is not the case that there is a causative maha- prefix and an abilitive maha- prefix. There is, in fact, only one prefix which is both causative and abilitive. The apparent difference in meaning arises because of a difference in the emphasis placed on what I shall suggest are the two components of this prefix: stativity and causation. Whether maha- receives an abilitive or a causative reading depends on whether it attaches to what I term an "eventive" root or a "non-eventive" root. In the former case, it receives an abilitive reading, in the latter case, a causative reading.</description><creator>Phillips, Vivianne.</creator><contributor>Travis, Lisa (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Malagasy language -- Semantics.</subject><subject>Malagasy language -- Causative.</subject><subject>Malagasy language -- Suffixes and prefixes.</subject><title>Up-rooting the prefix maha- in Malagasy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k0068.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p670s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kc67x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study first provides general background on the public education system of Quebec, and the Canadian and Quebec legal systems. Legal background information includes: the classification of Canadian laws; the Common Law and Civil Law traditions of law, and the definitions of sources of law of each tradition; Quebec's bijurisdictional legal system; the court system of Quebec; Constitutional sources of law; and, the role of the Judiciary in Canadian education. This thesis is a documentary study of the sources of law which establish language of instruction rights in Quebec. Its purpose is to assist educators, students of education, and other lay persons of law to gain understanding of the legal bases upon which the Judiciary formulate decisions in matters of language of instruction. Common Law and Civil Law legislative and case law sources, which are applicable to Quebec, are identified and examined, and relevant sources presented. In addition to providing a summary for Common Law sources, and for Civil Law sources, a chronological summary is given, which reveals six main periods in the development of language of instruction provisions in Quebec. The conclusion is that the primary sources of law for language of instruction in Quebec are: s. 93 of the Constitution Act, 1867, and case law thereunder; and, the judicial interpretation and provisions of s. 23 of the Constitution Act, 1982. Future case law in Quebec may reveal s. 23 of the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms, 1982 to be the most significant source of law for the preservation of minority English language instruction, institutions, and rights of management and control.</description><creator>Peszle, T. L. (Theresa L.)</creator><contributor>Burgess, D. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Educational law and legislation -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Educational law and legislation -- Canada.</subject><subject>Minorities -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>Language rights in Québec education : sources of law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w175w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc67x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87ps524</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study attempts to demonstrate symbolic whale bone patterning within 31 Thule winter houses along the southeast coast of Somerset Island, Northwest Territories, Canada. All visible architectural whale bone incorporated within the dwellings was mapped. Trends towards particular patterns of whale bone distribution were demonstrated using Spearman's Rank-order Correlation Coefficient. The potential symbolic nature of such patternings was determined within the context of north Alaskan ethnographic and oral historical sources. The extensive use of whale bone in some Thule entrances suggests that their builders sought to create a distinction between the entrance tunnel and main room, not unlike the Inupiat dwellings in 19th-century Tikigaq. The significance of this architectural phenomenon is rooted in the Inupiat, and to some extent Inuit, association between women, the house and the bowhead whale. It is also suggested that whaling status may be reflected in differential access to bowhead whale bone.</description><creator>Patton, A. Katherine B. (Anna Katherine Berenice)</creator><contributor>Savelle, J. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Thule culture -- Dwellings.</subject><subject>Decoration and ornament, Prehistoric -- Nunavut -- Somerset Island</subject><subject>Whales -- Nunavut -- Somerset Island -- Mythology.</subject><subject>Dwellings, Prehistoric -- Nunavut -- Somerset Island</subject><title>The ideological dimensions of whale bone use in Thule winter houses /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214r14q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87ps524</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fn71z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This is a study of a Latin American community centre in Montreal based on two years of participant observation. The Centre is one of many locales where immigrants spend their time and come to understand a new city, its history, people, and institutional systems. As such, it is a place where social identity is actively negotiated and frequently reinvented, highlighting the constructed and dynamic qualities of ethnicity in contemporary Western society. The study dialectically considers small- and large-scale influences on the Centre and its members. While structural limits often foster social marginalization which must be recognized and addressed, cultural production and the negotiation of identity occur primarily through the subtle and minute lifeworld experiences that are found in the everyday lives at the Centre.</description><creator>Occhipinti, Joseph.</creator><contributor>Ray, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Ethnic relations.</subject><subject>Latin American Canadians -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Identity, place and community : a latin American locale in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765373037.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn71z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j743r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis constitutes an investigation into contemporary writing--both fictional and philosophical. More specifically, it is a comparative analysis of the work of British novelist Angela Carter, and French philosophers Gilles Deleuze and Felix Guattari, in the light of the concept of synthetic authenticity. It is divided into three chapters, "Becomings", "Events", and "Machines", and each chapter presents the work of both Carter and Deleuze and Guattari, respectively, in light of one of these topics. Chapter Two, however, focuses closely on Angela Carter's first novel, Shadow Dance, as it relates to the concept 'event'. And Chapter Three focuses on Carter's novel The Infernal Desire Machines of Doctor Hoffman, as it relates to and differs from the schizoanalytic notion of desiring machines.</description><creator>Ocaña, Karen Isabel</creator><contributor>Massumi, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996-08</date><subject>Deleuze, Gilles, 1925-1995 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Guattari, Félix, 1930-1992 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Carter, Angela, 1940- -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Synthetic authenticity : the work of Angela Carter, Gilles Deleuze and Félix Guattari</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z854.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j743r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qp050</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the reasons why Walt Whitman has been a "puzzle" to literary critics for well over a century. It shows the correspondence between Walt Whitman's work and the mystical tradition of East as also interpreted by American Transcendentalists. Enquiry into "self" is the central theme of most of Whitman's work. Two aspects of this enquiry have been investigated in this thesis and compared with the Upanishads: the development of self; and the use of contradictions as a means of conveying meaning. Both aspects support the view that Whitman displays a worldview not in accordance with the popular Western view in which God and man are entirely different and can never meet on equal terms. Whitman's view can be compared to that of the American Transcendentalists and Neoplatonists which finds a sympathetic chord in the native European tradition of humanistic values as well as in the Upanishads. Whitman works from a state of consciousness that is different in spirit and structure from the Hegelian dialectical principle which has wielded so much influence over Western thought. Whitman's poetry is remarkably akin to that of the Upanishadic writers in whose consciousness the subject and object have fused into one. Whitman is shown to draw his ideas from a depth of the human psyche that is often associated with Eastern thought but which is also present in the West. Four stances of self in Whitman's work have been identified which are seen to be related to, but not identical with, four states of consciousness in the Upanishads. The thesis concludes that not only is there a remarkable degree of correspondence between Walt Whitman and the Upanishads, both in respect to development of the self and use of contradictions, but that interpreting him in the light of the Upanishads provides another modern opportunity for meeting of the East and the West.</description><creator>Nautiyal, Nandita.</creator><contributor>Gibian, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892 -- Sources.</subject><title>"This self is Brahman" : Whitman in the light of the Upanishads</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v054b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qp050</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mp29t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The patriots depend on the uprising of the people and on popular enthusiasm in general, both for the physical and for the ideological support to achieve the revolution. In order to ensure the progress of the revolution, they will strive to control and direct popular agitation through written discourse. Revolutions de Paris, one of the most popular newspapers of the French Revolution, offers a good example of that: events are interpreted through narratives that distinguish 'good' popular uprisings from 'bad' ones, thus outlining a plan for the contribution of popular enthusiasm to the revolution.</description><creator>Munier, Véronique.</creator><contributor>Angenot, Marc (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>France -- History -- 1789-1793.</subject><subject>Mass media -- Political aspects -- France.</subject><title>Représentation discursive de l'enthousiasme : Révolutions de Paris</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m1436.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp29t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c0215</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The topic of this Master's thesis is "Intercultural 'Landeskunde' in the field of German as a foreign language at Canadian unversities: a documentation of a case study in the Department of German Studies at McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, Canada". In the introduction "Landeskunde" itself will be defined as well as its role in the teaching of a language. The three main approaches to "Landeskunde" will be studied, by which more emphasis will be laid on the intercultural approach, which will then be elucidated through a practical example. In chapters two, three and four the background information leading up to the development and implementation of the new "Landeskunde" course will be explained. In the main chapter of the thesis, chapter five, the structure of the course will be presented and analysed in detail. This chapter will be completed by a documentation of the course materials used, quotes from the students' logbooks as well as a summary of the main ideas and suggestions for improvement. The sixth chapter is a general assessment of the course, demonstrating how it could be used as a model for intercultural learning in Canadian universities and as such offer suggestions for alternative methods in the teaching of German as a foreign language.</description><creator>Mollinger, Karin.</creator><contributor>Goldsmith-Reber, T. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>McGill University. Dept. of German Studies.</subject><subject>German language -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Interkulturelle Landeskunde im Bereich des Deutschen als Fremdsprache an kanadischen Hochschulen : Dokumentation einer Fallstudie am Department of German Studies der McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, Kanada</title><language>ger</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq153.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c0215</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jg832</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first part of this M.A. thesis is comprised of short stories that focus on the theme of essential lack, exploring the process whereby one discovers that something is lacking and the various ways in which one attempts to fill the void. The second part consists of an essay on creative writing which proceeds from two main questions: first, is it possible to write when "nothing is happening"?; and secondly, can "nothing" be meaningful? In discussing these questions, we will refer to works of nouveau roman novelists, as well as those of writers such as Rainer-Maria Rilke, John Gardner, Raymond Carver, Milan Kundera and Peter Handke. Through examining these authors' views and approaches to characterization, plot and description, we will show different ways of writing a text though one is starting "from nothing".</description><creator>Meunier, Stéphanie, 1971-</creator><contributor>Rivard, Yvon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Nothing (Philosophy) in literature.</subject><title>Au bout du chemin ; suivi de, Écrire l'absence</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k4650.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jg832</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87ps53d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dialects have always had a negative reputation, and have been considered beneath the national language. Even the literature composed in the various regional languages has been considered inferior to the Italian one until only a few years ago, because it was thought that this literature had as an exclusive theme the peasant-popular world. This thesis will not only demonstrate that dialects are languages deserving of respect, but also that Lucano dialect literature is not bogged down to the peasant-popular world. In fact, it is capable of expressing any concept that any national language is capable of, even if that concept does not originate in the peasant-popular world.</description><creator>Martino, Nicola.</creator><contributor>Gilardino, Sergio (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Pierro, Albino -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Italian language -- Dialects -- Italy -- Basilicata.</subject><subject>Dialect poetry, Italian -- Italy -- Basilicata -- History and interpretation.</subject><title>Albino Pierro</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f26x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87ps53d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b5343</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:06:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts to demonstrate the importance of the "autobiography of childhood" in Gabrielle Roy's first-person narratives through a narratological analysis of the most representative of these texts--the pseudo-autobiographical Rue Deschambault and La Route d'Altamont as well as the autobiographical texts La Detresse et l'Enchantement, "Ma petite rue qui m'a menee autour du monde", "Mes etudes a Saint-Boniface", "Souvenirs du Manitoba" and "Mon heritage du Manitoba". Our purpose is to identify recurrent structures and to interpret the similarities and differences in the light of contemporary theories on the autobiographical genre. This allows us in turn to examine the functioning and meaning of childhood writing in Gabrielle Roy's first-person narratives.</description><creator>Marcotte, Sophie, 1973-</creator><contributor>Ricard, Francois (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Autobiography in literature.</subject><subject>Roy, Gabrielle, 1909- -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Le récit d'enfance dans l'écriture autobiographique de Gabrielle Roy /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f327b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b5343</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):475</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>