<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:20:07Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):32875" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x297</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Supplementation of a minimal medium with KHCO$ sb3$ and some amino acids reduced the duration of the lag period for the growth of the marine bacterium Deleya aesta 134 at sub-optimal Na$ sp+$ concentrations and decreased the minimal Na$ sp+$ concentration allowing growth, to 8mM. Na$ sp+$ was required for the transport of most metabolites into D. aesta 134, while some compounds were taken up by both a Na$ sp+$-dependent and a Na$ sp+$-independent system. Phosphate transport was not affected by Na$ sp+.$ Na$ sp+$ was also required for the oxidation of exogenous succinate. Evidence for the presence in D. aesta 134 of a Na$ sp+$-activated NADH: quinone acceptor oxidoreductase was obtained. A mutant of D. aesta 134 exhibiting a shorter lag period than its parent strain at 10mM Na$ sp+$ was also examined. Enhanced Na$ sp+$/H$ sp+$ antiport activity was obtained in the mutant strain, but the actual mechanism involved in the adaptation to low Na$ sp+$ concentrations is still obscure. Succinate transport by D. aesta 134 was mediated by a C$ sb4$-dicarboxylate transport system, and exhibited biphasic kinetics, indicating the presence of a high- and a low-affinity transport system. A partial genomic library of D. aesta was prepared, and DNA from D. aesta complemented mutations from Escherichia coli auxotrophs. Successful introduction of the plasmid pRK404 into D. aesta 134 by electroporation was also obtained.</description><creator>Berthelet, Marc</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Marine bacteriaxMetabolism</subject><subject>Sodium -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Deleya aesta</subject><title>The role of sodium in the physiology and metabolism of the marine bacterium Deleya aesta 134</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sh86m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x297</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qb47j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Site-selective laser excitation and emission spectra were obtained with a 20% Eu$ sp{+3}$ exchanged sodium $ beta sp{ prime prime}$-alumina crystal at 77 and 6.4 K. Excitation into the $ rm sp5D sb0$ level (568-579 nm) shows that the trivalent europium ion occupies at least two types of site distributions. The first distribution occurs at the higher energy of the tuning range and has site symmetry C$ sb{ rm 3v}$ or C$ sb3.$ It corresponds to the crystallographic Beevers-Ross position. The other site distribution is observed at lower energy and is associated with the mid-oxygen crystallographic position (site symmetry: C$ sb{ rm 2h}).$ This work shows that the interpretation of the site-selective spectroscopy of Eu$ sp{+3} beta sp{ prime prime}$-alumina must take into account the occurrence of multipole site-to-site energy transfer linked to vibronic coupling phenomena.</description><creator>Laberge, Monique Marie</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>A laser spectroscopic study of the Eu+3 environment and energy transfer in b"-alumina</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df15m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qb47j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gj00h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Clinical and morphological investigations were carried out concerning the osseointegration of dental implants. A clinical evaluation of 1087 implants placed over a seven year time span revealed an osseointegration success rate of 96%. Studies indicated that, on average 8.7 months lapsed between implant insertion and prosthesis delivery. A technique was developed to evaluate the process of osseointegration with the light microscope (LM) and transmission electron microscope (TEM). A rat model was used and threaded implants were fabricated from solid commercially pure titanium. LM demonstrated osseointegration and a preservation of implant surface topography utilizing this technique. TEM analysis revealed an electron dense lamina-limitans like layer covered by an amorphous substance adjacent to the surface of the implant. $ sp3$H-proline was used to label seams of bone formation in order to evaluate the distribution and rate of formation of the new bone next to the metal implant. Bone appeared to grow from the old presurgical bone towards the implant with no apparent direct influence of the metal. A quail embryo model was developed to evaluate the effects of vascular occlusion on the formation of bone and to label epithelial blood vessels with iodinated transforming growth factor-beta 1 applied to the chorioallantoic membrane. These preliminary experiments demonstrated that surgical manipulation of the quail embryo was possible for the purposes of studying the process of osseointegration.</description><creator>Clokie, Cameron M. L. (Cameron Malcolm Lang)</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry.</subject><title>The titanium-bone interface : a clinical and morphological analysis of osseointegration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mk58x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gj00h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df16w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this study is to demonstrate differences between erythroid and nonerythroid iron metabolism. Erythroid specific gene expression for transferrin receptor (TfR) which is a transporter of transferrin-bound iron, and for ferrochelatase which uses internalized iron to form heme, is found in dimethylsulfoxide-inducible murine erythroleukemia (MEL) cells. During MEL cell differentiation which parallels erythroid differentiation in vivo, TfR mRNA increases resulting from transcriptional activation of the gene and increased mRNA stability while ferrochelatase mRNA level increases with a 2.7 kb mRNA being induced preferentially. Such preferential induction is effected by utilization of an upstream polyadenylation signal. TfR-deficient Chinese hamster ovary cells were used to study nonerythroid iron metabolism. Our results show these cells need iron for growth and DNA synthesis and acquire that from transferrin and FeSO$ sb4$ in the medium by a TfR-independent mechanism.</description><creator>Chan, Roxanne Yuen Yee</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Transferrin receptor and ferrochelatase mRNA expression in erythroid and non-erythroid cells : implication for intracellular iron metabolism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t18z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df16w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032461d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a theoretical approach to Ostwald ripening of droplets in arbitrary dimensions. A mean-field theory is constructed to incorporate screening effects among the competing droplets. The mean-field equations are solved to all orders in the volume fraction to provide analytic expressions for the coarsening rate, the droplet distribution function, and the time-dependent droplet number. These results are in agreement with experiments in three-dimension and with very large scale and extensive numerical studies in both two and three dimensions undertaken in this thesis. The numerical study also provides the time evolution of the structure factors, wherein lengths scale with the average droplet radius. Finally, the mean-field theory is extended to exciton systems and surfactant systems.</description><creator>Yao, Jian Hua</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Theory of Ostwald ripening</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x303c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032461d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cs05r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis studies non-vanishing of L-functions attached to automorphic representations on GL(2) at real points in the critical strip. By comparing mean and mean square estimates for cyclotomic twists $L(f, chi,w)$, ${1 over 2} le w1/2$, and that at least $c sb1 q/ log q$ twists do not vanish at 1/2. We also prove that at least $c sb2 y sp{{2 over 3}- epsilon}$ quadratic twists $L(f, chi sb{d},1/2)$ do not vanish by comparing mean and fourth power mean estimates for such twists, where $d le y$ and $ chi sb{d}$ denotes the Kronecker symbol.</description><creator>Stefanicki, Tomasz</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Non-vanishing of L-functions attached to automorphic representations of GL(2)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pp56w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs05r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924d31c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research has resulted in the design and development of an experimental facility to study the combined convective infrared (I.R.) drying process of a capillary porous material (glass beads) in high temperature flow conditions. The necessity to decrease the heat transfer coefficient for the effect of high mass transfer flux (when convection is combined with I.R. heating) has been demonstrated. Further, the analogy between the transfer of heat and mass expressed in terms of average heat and mass transfer coefficient ratios has been verified to apply when the surface is not contaminated. Experiments have also showed that there is a link between the evaporation temperature and crust formation at the evaporating surface. Moreover, an increase in the heat transfer coefficient was observed when the surface reaches the boiling point and is higher than that of the flowing air. Lastly, it was observed that the critical moisture content is independent of the convective drying parameters, sample thickness and the overall incident heat flux. A drying front model is also presented and tested with the experimental results in convection drying and for the combined process. The drying time, the bottom temperature evolution, the surface temperature evolution up to the critical point and the overall shape of the drying rate curve were well reproduced by the model. Simulations have also showed that the effect of the diffusion mass flux on the heat and mass transfer coefficients leads to a decrease of the evaporation rate by a maximum of 8% for both the purely convective and combined processes.</description><creator>Parrouffe, Jean-Michel</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Combined convective and infrared drying of a capillary porous body</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b270n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d31c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gv23m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the techniques and results of our x-ray structural studies of strained Ga$ sb{1-x}$In$ sb{x}$As epilayers grown on GaAs (001) by metallorganic chemical vapor deposition. By combining conventional x-ray techniques with newly developed glancing incidence and reflectivity measurements, we study both the out-of-plane and the in-plane structure. We also obtain direct information on the mechanisms of the structural relaxation which occurs in these systems. The techniques we have used are based on using a conventional x-ray source and could be widely used to characterize and study growth processes and sample quality. Using the conventional characterization of the positions, widths, and intensities of Bragg peaks lattice parameters, domain sizes and strains have been evaluated. Studying the shape of the Bragg peak shows that the simple theoretical models based on the existence of a critical thickness due to dislocation can not be used to explain the structural relaxation observed. Our results based on thin (500 $ pm$ 12A, $x=0.19 pm 0.003$) and thick (40000 $ pm$ 1000A, $x=0.16 pm 0.01$) epilayers require a complicated microstructure in a transition region between the substrate and the surface of the epilayers.</description><creator>Shi, Yushan</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>X-ray structural studies of heteroepitaxy of gallium-indium arsenide on gallium arsenide</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m02t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv23m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz8061493</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the drama of Yusuf Idris (1927-1991), a well-known Egyptian playwright who has made very important contributions to the search for Arab roots, Arab identity, and a new face for Egyptian (Arab) drama. The analysis of Idris's eight plays (written over a quarter of a century) in the light of Egyptian (Arab) post-1952 social, political, and cultural realities has enabled us to clarify the playwright's ideas and understand why his literary works have occasioned so much discussion and so many polemics. This study shows that Idris's plays mirror and document the post-Revolutionary Egyptian (Arab) era. They also appeal to the reader's conscience, calling for change and reform. Furthermore, Idris's plays reflect the artistic search for an original Egyptian (Arab) dramatic form, a search the playwright himself provoked. Finally, Idris's plays reveal the author's faith in the true human qualities of the Egyptian (Arab) man and his tremendous potential, which is yet to be awakened and explored.</description><creator>Rudnicka-Kassem, Dorota</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Idrīs, Yūsuf -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Egyptian drama and social change : a study of thematic and artistic development in Yūsuf Idrīs's plays</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801ph964.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz8061493</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032462p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new high-precision atomic mass measurement technique based on a tandem Penning trap system is described. Data from the mass measurements of rubidium and strontium are analyzed to reveal what information desirable for nuclear physics can be extracted and to indicate the limitations in the presently employed set up at the ISOLDE facility at CERN. The possibility of substantially improving the Penning trap collection efficiency through the use of a Paul (radio-frequency quadrupole) ion trap as a collection device for preparing the radionuclides before the measurement system is then presented. Results from engineering tests on the performance of the Paul trap at the ISOLDE facility are discussed. The work concludes with suggestions for the design of feasible system to capture 100% of weak ISOLDE beams. This new system is to be incorporated into the Penning trap set up at the newly constructed ISOLDE-BOOSTER facility.</description><creator>Rouleau, Gary</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Physics, Nuclear.</subject><title>A tandem Paul-Penning trap mass measurement system for radionuclides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m826x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032462p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k881c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines ideological discourse in contemporary Egypt. It investigates a number of discourses in terms of the meanings they generate and the role or function they play in the maintenance or transformation of relations of power in society. The analysis is guided by a semiotic view of ideology, that is, ideology understood as a system of representation which operates through language and other signifying practices. Central to our understanding of the effects of discourse on power relations is the conception of representation as an autonomous level of 'reality' in relation to other levels. The implication of such a conception is that meanings produced in discourse are not to be validated or adequated against the 'real', but are to be analyzed in terms of their interrelations with socio-economic and political structures, and in terms of their appropriation by social forces in positions of struggle. In this sense, it is relevant to look at the rules which govern the formation of the systems of representation; rules which are specific to the discursive formations. Within the framework of this study, the key mechanisms operative in discourse and ideology are validation and interpellation. Throughout the project, attention is paid to the role these mechanisms play in the production of subjects and the construction of subject positions. That is, particular emphasis is put on how ideological interpellations construct or constitute positions of resistance, struggle, domination, acquiesence which are validated or rejected by the receiver. This returns to the process of appropriation of meanings and the functionalization of discourse. The analysis proceeds through an examination of the narrative and discursive structures of the various discourses under study. It is also concerned with the narrative programs which underlie the discourses as an act or intervention, focusing on the positions of speakers and receivers, the modalization of subject positions and their inscription in relations of power. In treating the Egyptian case, discourses from two socio-political conjunctures are analyzed: one a juncture of populist rupture marked by the consolidation of the revolutionary program, the other a juncture of socio-economic disintegration. The study examines how the conjunctures manifest themselves in discourse. In this way, an attempt is made to see how the particular conjunctures are marked in the functionalization of certain terms and the imposition of certain ideologemes. The work seeks to demonstrate how this is linked to the appropriation of discourse by social forces. With regard to the first juncture, the discursive and narrative structures which underlie the nationalist discourse are identified. Within the later conjuncture, these structures are revealed in relation to the Islamist discourse, while an analysis of the secular discourse is also carried out. The general objective is to situate the process of the construction of meanings in relation to the socio-economic and political conditions which exist in the particular junctures of discourse production.</description><creator>Ismail, Salwa 1960-</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Egypt -- Politics and government -- 1981-</subject><subject>Egypt -- Politics and government -- 1952-1970</subject><subject>Egypt -- Politics and government -- 1970-1981.</subject><title>Discourse and ideology in contemporary Egypt</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j276h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k881c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117q56s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The involvement of protein phosphorylation and gene regulation in signal transduction pathways are examined. In particular the role of the novel STY kinase in signal transduction networks is suggested, followed by a study of the liver-specific and inducible expression of the carbamyl phosphate synthetase I (CPSI) gene. In a screen of an embryonal carcinoma (EC) cell cDNA expression library with an antibody to phosphotyrosine, the STY kinase was identified. STY is represented by a single 1.8 kb transcript in undifferentiated P19 cells. During differentiation of these cells, mRNAs of 3.2 and 5.6 are induced and persist to adulthood. Sequence analysis of the STY kinase revealed a catalytic domain homologous to kinases with serine/threonine phosphorylating specificity especially those involved in cell-cycle control, such as the FUS3 gene. Biochemical analysis of recombinant STY synthesized in bacteria or in vitro indicated a serine-, threonine-, and tyrosine-phosphorylating capability, suggesting that it belongs to a previously unappreciated family of kinases. The promoter region of the liver specific, glucocorticoid and cAMP inducible gene, CPSI was analyzed for transcriptional activity. Sequences extending from the in vivo start site of CPSI gene to $-$1200 bp, were shown to support in vitro transcription with liver nuclear extracts. A region proximal to transcription initiation, from $-$104 to $-$124 was shown to specifically interact with the abundant liver nuclear factor C/EBP. Double stranded oligonucleotides corresponding this cis element abolishes in vitro transcription reactions in a competitive manner. The C/EBP and related factors, LAP and LIP, interaction with CPSI promoter elements has implications in the developmental, liver-specific, as well as the inducible aspects of CPSI gene expression.</description><creator>Howell, Brian</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Signal transducing molecules</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924d32n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117q56s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02870x56c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Emerging VLSI/ULSI technologies have created new opportunities in designing computer architectures capable of hiding the latencies and synchronization overheads associated with von Neumann-style multiprocessing. Pure Dataflow architectures have been suggested as solutions, but they do not adequately address the issues of local memory latencies and fine-grain synchronization costs. In this thesis, we propose a novel hybrid dataflow/von Neumann architecture, called the Super-Actor Machine, to address the problems facing von Neumann and pure dataflow machines. This architecture uses a novel high-speed memory organization known as a register-cache to tolerate local memory latencies and decrease local memory bandwidth requirements. The register-cache is unique in that it appears as a register file to the execution unit, while from the perspective of main memory, its contents are tagged as in conventional caches. Fine-grain synchronization costs are alleviated by the hybrid execution model and a loosely-coupled scheduling mechanism. A major goal of this dissertation is to characterize the performance of the Super-Actor Machine and compare it with other architectures for a class of programs typical of scientific computations. The thesis includes a review on the precursor called the McGill Dataflow Architecture, description of a Super-Actor Execution Model, a design for a Super-Actor Machine, description of the register-cache mechanism, compilation techniques for the Super-Actor Machine and results from a detailed simulator. Results show that the Super-Actor Machine can tolerate local memory latencies and fine-grain synchronization overheads--the execution unit can sustain 99% throughput--if a program has adequate exposed parallelism.</description><creator>Hum, Herbert Hing-Jing</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Computer architecture</subject><title>The super-actor machine : a hybrid dataflowvon Neumann architecture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r942j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870x56c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jq394</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation critiques, develops and applies a form of spatial semiotics, specifically topological semiotics, as a means of interpreting and analyzing the design, operation, use and ideological issues of West Edmonton 'Mega'-Mall (WEM) in the context of postmodern culture. Doing so promotes an understanding of the theoretical and analytical utility and limitations semiotics and postmodernism may hold for landscape studies, while furthering our knowledge about the design and social life of multi-purpose, indoor environments. Drawing from several key geographical concepts (landscape, place, placelessness), semiotic notions (icon, language, myth, sign, signification), postmodern issues (heterotopia, the crisis of interpretation, the linguistic turn), and empirical data (on-site observations, off-site questionnaires, secondary academic, government and corporate studies), the concepts of placial icon, simulated landscape and elsewhereness are developed to critique a "way of seeing" and explain what was viewed at the mega-mall. WEM's postmodern, heterotopic milieu of myths and elsewhereness is argued to collapse due to the mall's dual role as tourist centre/civic centre, making WEM an unoriginal, placeless, homotopic nowhere. Despite their theoretically overburdened and methodologically underdeveloped status, semiotics and postmodernism are shown to be useful catalysts for posing questions and initiating criticisms relevant to contemporary social theory, landscape studies and substantive social issues.</description><creator>Hopkins, Jeffrey</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Shopping malls -- Alberta -- Edmonton</subject><title>Landscape of myths and elsewhereness : West Edmonton Mall</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g903f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq394</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343t768</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cis-diaqua cobalt complex ((L)Co(III)(OH$ sb2) sb2 rbrack sp{3+}$ promoted hydrolyses of phosphate esters, nitriles and carboxy amides are examined (L represents 1,4,7,10-tetraazacyclododecane (cyclen) and its N-methylated derivatives). ((Cyclen)Co(OH$ sb2) sb2 rbrack sp{3+}$ is more active than any other catalysts reported to date for hydrolyzing dimethyl phosphate, acetonitrile and formyl morpholine.  ((Cyclen)Co(OH$ sb2) sb2 rbrack sp{3+}$ efficiently hydrolyzes dimethyl phosphate under mild conditions (k = 3.7 $ times$ 10$ sp{-5}$ M$ sp{-1}$ sec$ sp{-1}$ at pD 6.3, 60$ sp circ$C). This represents the first hydrolysis of dimethyl phosphate (P-O bond cleavage) at neutral pH. Mechanism for the cobalt complex promoted hydrolysis of dimethyl phosphate and its implication on the role of metal ions in ribozymes is discussed.  ((Cyclen)Co(OH$ sb2) sb2 rbrack sp{3+}$ catalyzes the hydration of nitriles to amides. Acetonitrile coordinated to the cobalt complex is hydrated 10$ sp9$ times more rapidly than the uncoordinated acetonitrile at pH 7 and 40$ sp circ$C. Catalytic turnover for the hydration reaction is demonstrated for the first time with the Co(III) complex. Chelated benzamide, a key intermediate in the catalytic hydration of benzonitrile, is isolated and its crystal structure determined. Detailed kinetics and mechanistic analyses of the cobalt complex catalyzed hydration of acetonitrile including the equilibrium constant for complexation of acetonitrile to the cobalt complex (K = 0.6 M$ sp{-1})$ are reported. Synthetic utility of the catalyst including acrylamide production is discussed.  ((Cyclen)Co(OH$ sb2) sb2 rbrack sp{3+}$ efficiently hydrolyzes formyl morpholine under mild conditions (k = 7.97 $ times$ 10$ sp{-5}$ M$ sp{-1}$ sec$ sp{-1}$ at pD 6, 60$ sp circ$C). The equilibrium constant for complexation of formyl morpholine to the cobalt complex is 0.4 M$ sp{-1}.$ The equilibrium constant for complexation of amides to metal complexes had not been previously measured. The efficiency and mechanism of the cobalt complex for hydrolyzing amides are compared to those of carboxypeptidase A.</description><creator>Kim, Jung-Hee.</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, General.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Developing artificial proteases and nucleases : catalytic hydrolysis of unactivated amides, nitriles and phosphates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gp97m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343t768</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pp575</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We present an effective method for solving different types of noisy pattern matching problems in Euclidean space. The matching is performed in either a least-squares or a mixed-norm sense under the constraint that a transformation matrix $ Theta$ is restricted to belong to the orthogonal group. Matching problems of this type can be recast as function optimization problems which can be solved by representing the orthogonal group to which $ Theta$ belongs as a Lie group and then investigating the gradient vector field associated with the function to be optimized. The projection of the gradient field onto the tangent space of the Lie group at $ Theta$, i.e., the Lie algebra, results in a descent/ascent equation for the function. The descent/ascent equation so obtained is used in a classical steepest-descent/ascent algorithm and a singular value decomposition-based recursive method in order to determine the maximum or minimum point of the function under consideration. Since $ Theta$ belongs to the orthogonal group which includes the group of permutations as a subgroup, the proposed procedure works not only for patterns consisting of ordered feature points, but also for the combinatorial problem involving patterns having unordered feature points. Generalizations of the matching problem are also formulated and include the matching of patterns from Euclidean spaces of different dimensions and the matching of patterns having unequal numbers of feature points from the same Euclidean space. Simulations are performed which demonstrate the effectiveness and the efficiency of the proposed approach in solving some practical matching problems which arise in computer vision and pattern analysis.</description><creator>Lie Chin Cheong, Patrick</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Geometrically constrained matching schemes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tw76v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp575</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qb514</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Polystyrene (PS), functionalized with various ionic groups, was blended with polyamides (PA) in order to investigate the effect of ion-dipole interactions on the miscibility of PS/PA blends. Sulfonic acid groups interact strongly with amides, but catalyze the hydrolysis of the amide bonds of the PA. The neutralization of the sulfonic acid groups eliminates this reaction in the blends, and when the counterion is lithium, strong miscibility enhancement is seen between the lithium sulfonated polystyrene (LiSPS) and polyamides-6 (PA-6), $-$66, $-$610 and $-$11. This miscibility enhancement increases with the lithium sulfonate content of the LiSPS and the amide content of the PA, and is also dependent on the blend composition. An equilibrium thermodynamic approach is used to describe the miscibility behavior of the LiSPS blends with PA-6. When the ionic group is sodium sulfonate, lithium carboxylate or sodium carboxylate, the miscibility enhancement is negligible. As a possibly better alternative to the PS ionomers as a blend component with PAs, novel sulfonated poly(styrene-ethylene-butylene)random ionomers were synthesised and characterized.</description><creator>Molnár, Attila</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Miscibility enhancement of aliphatic polyamides with other polymers through ion-dipole interactions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x304n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qb514</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qn62d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In and around the princely courts of Europe, Renaissance humanists drew upon the teachings of classical antiquity, often reinterpreting them to suit their own intellectual and ethical needs. One such need concerned balancing notions of achievement predicated upon gaining others' favor, with ideals of constancy and integrity. Evidence of this dilemma can be found in the works of Niccolo Machiavelli, Desiderius Erasmus, Thomas More, and Michel de Montaigne. In each of these cases, the attachment to differing conceptions of accomplishment and human dignity resulted in contradictions in their writings, and in their lives.</description><creator>Diamond, Jeff Barja</creator><contributor>Taylor, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Tully, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Machiavellianism (Psychology)</subject><subject>Political ethics</subject><subject>Acting -- Political aspects</subject><title>Theatricality and power : politics and "play-acting" in the European Renaissance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t078c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn62d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n956d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An equal-order co-located Control Volume Finite Element Method (CVFEM) for the prediction of multidimensional, incompressible, viscous fluid flow problems has been formulated. CVFEMs provide the geometric flexibility traditionally associated with finite element methods. In addition, their control volume based formulation facilitates physically meaningful interpretation of the resulting discretization equations. In the proposed CVFEM, the calculation domain is divided into three-node triangular and four-node tetrahedral finite elements in two- and three-dimensions, respectively. Each element is further subdivided in such a way that upon assembly of all elements, complete control volumes are formed about each node in the calculation domain. Interpolation functions for the dependent variables are prescribed in a manner that is consistent with the physical process they are intended to approximate. In this context, three different interpolation schemes of the convective flux across control volume surfaces are investigated, one of which guarantees positive contributions to the coefficients in the algebraic discretization equations. Appropriate conservation laws are imposed on the control volumes associated with the nodes. The resulting sets of integral conservation equations are then approximated by algebraic discretization equations, using the previously-mentioned interpolation functions. These nonlinear, coupled, algebraic equations are solved by a sequential solution procedure which incorporates Picard iterations. The proposed method has been implemented into computer programs, and used to solve several test problems. These include convection-diffusion problems, and laminar and turbulent flow problems, in both two- and three-dimensions. The results demonstrate the ability of the proposed CVFEM to accurately solve the mathematical model used in this thesis. Lastly, the CVFEM was used to predict flows similar to those found in film cooled gas turbine aerofoils. A complementary experimental program was designed and set up to investigate such flows. The numerical predictions were compared to the experimental observations of mean velocities, normal turbulent stresses and one component of the turbulent shear stress. These comparisons indicated that the high Reynolds number $k- epsilon$ turbulence model used in this thesis is unable to capture certain features of the flow. It appears as if a low-Reynolds number turbulence model, with appropriate modifications to account for streamline curvature and non-isotropy of the turbulence in the vicinity of the walls, would be better suited to the prediction of such flows. This new model can be easily incorporated into the CVFEM proposed in this thesis.</description><creator>Saabas, Helmut John</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>A control volume finite element method for three-dimensional, incompressible, vicsous fluid flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687k00n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n956d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v710w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A newly developed creep method is described for following the kinetics of manganese sulfide precipitation in four electrical steels. The technique was also applied to a Ti steel, in which the precipitation kinetics were previously determined using a stress relaxation method. The resulting creep rate is sensitive to the occurrence of precipitation; thus the slope of the true strain-log(time) curve decreases immediately after the initiation and increases on the completion of precipitation. The precipitation-time-temperature diagrams determined in this way are of classical C shape on all of the tested materials. Because higher dislocation densities and internal stress levels are maintained, the present technique is more effective for monitoring the precipitation events occurring in the ferritic phases and at high temperatures than the previously developed stress relaxation method. The nucleation sites for precipitation during creep testing were investigated with the aid of electron microscopy. It was concluded that the progress of MnS precipitation can be divided into three stages: nucleation, growth and coarsening. There exists a strong tendency for the nuclei to be formed on dislocations at lower temperatures. However, nucleation at grain boundaries is preferred as the temperature is increased. The classical diffusion-controlled growth theory is not satisfactory for strain-induced MrS precipitation. Thus, a modification was made in such a dynamic case by taking the effects of deformation vacancies into account. The kinetics during the coarsening stage are controlled by both bulk and grain boundary diffusion. The microstructural examinations revealed that both grain deformation and grain boundary sliding take place in the electrical steels at hot working temperatures. Quantitative evaluations showed that the latter process contributes about one-sixth to one-tenth the total strain under the current experimental conditions. The strong retardation of grain deformation after the occurrence of precipitation is explained in terms of the interfacial pinning of mobile dislocations by these incoherent particles. It is also demonstrated that the finely-dispersed precipitates slow down the boundary sliding rate. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Sun, Wei Ping</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Measurement and analysis of MnS precipitation in electrical steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d1483.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v710w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jc946</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Uniform polycrysalline p-type CuInSe$ sb2$ films, thicknesses ranging from 1 to 4 $ mu$m, were deposited by a stable electrodeposition process developed in our laboratory. A (112) preferred orientation was found for the films. Vacuum annealing experiment results showed an improvement in the crystalline quality of the films after the annealing. The metal ratio of the films was not altered significantly by the annealing process. Al/CuInSe$ sb2$ Schottky junctions fabricated on p-type CuInSe$ sb2$ films showed that the current transport mechanism in the intermediate voltage region was governed by a recombination component. A dispersion effect of the capacitance-voltage curves with frequency, observed on the Schottky junctions suggested the presence of either enhanced interface states or deep levels in the depletion region. Solar cells of CdS/CuInSe$ sb2$ were fabricated by vacuum evaporating low resistivity n-type CdS layers on the electrodeposited p-type CuInSe$ sb2$ films. The highest AM1 active area conversion efficiency, for the 0.9 cm$ sp2$ cells, was 5.2% after an air heat treatment at 200$ sp circ$C. The efficiency value was increased to 5.6% in small area devices fabricated using a similar procedure. The air heat treatment was found to reduce the apparent carrier concentration in the CuInSe$ sb2$ films. Current-voltage (I-V) characteristics of the cells showed a definite relationship between the short circuit current and the indium to copper ratio in the CuInSe$ sb2$ films. Temperature dependent I-V curves revealed a dominant recombination current component for the heterojunction cells. The value of barrier height for a cell was estimated to be 0.64 eV. It was found that the differential capacitance values depended on measurement frequencies, resulting in frequency-dependent voltage intercepts. The C$ sp{-2}$-V curves were also observed to shift to more negative voltages under illumination. Interface states were believed to be responsible for all these effec</description><creator>Qiu, C. X. (Xing Xing)</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Investigation of electrodeposited CuInSe2 films for photovoltaic cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418p84b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jc946</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x064r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The use of ion-selective field-effect transistors (ISFETs) as potentiometric microsensors was investigated. In the first stage, an instrument was designed and built to operate an array of ISFETs. A microcomputer was used for instrument control and acquisition of data. The second phase of research focussed on the development of a pH sensitive radiotelemetric device that could eventually be used for the noninvasive monitoring of gastric pH. The first attempt used an ISFET as a variable resistor in a simple telemetry circuit. The drift in the pH dependent signal from this device was significant. The use of a differential sensor was studied as a possible way to minimize the effect of signal drift. This system measured the differential output of a pH ISFET and a pH insensitive ISFET. The pH insensitivity was due to an alkanethiol monolayer at the ISFET$ vert$solution interface. It was shown that ISFETs are well suited for use as sensors in telemetry devices. The union of these previously independent research areas has been achieved.</description><creator>McCarthy, Jeffrey J.</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Potentiometric microsensors and telemetry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v9518.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x064r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bj804</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The socio-economic conditions which affect development in general, and group ranching in particular, among the Maasai of Narok District, Kenya are analyzed. Systems of relationships between Maasai social units are examined to demonstrate how different individuals and groups within Maasai society, each with a diversity of vested interests, react to the opportunities and disadvantages offered them by imposed development programs and altered ecological conditions. A single group ranch, Rotian OlMakongo, is the focus of intensive study. Maasai on this ranch, which is located in a semi-high potential wheat-growing area of Narok District, have largely been resistant to planned change. The reaction of group ranch members to development are analyzed showing how lineage and clan affiliation, age set relations, stock friendships and other systems of relations affect individual and group decision-making. On the one hand the analysis demonstrates how the structure of the group ranch itself is not conducive to the consensual decision-making which ranch planning officials anticipated would occur regarding such important issues as stock limitation. On the other hand traditional Maasai social units are seen at different times both to promote and inhibit new organizational forms to deal with a changing set of economic, ecological and political conditions. A general trend toward impoverishment, disenfranchisement and supplementary economic pursuits is outlined. However, traditional pastoralism is not seen as being totally subsumed by a more dominant, essentially capitalistic mode of production. Rather, traditional pastoralism is seen to define the transformation of internal forms through a structure which incorporates the modern sector. The tension between the traditional and modern sectors is not their disassociation, but rather, their integration into the dynamic process of change within the structure.</description><creator>Doherty, Deborah A.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Masai (African people) -- Social conditions</subject><subject>Women, Masai -- Social conditions</subject><subject>Masai (African people) -- Economic conditions</subject><subject>Kenya -- Economic conditions</subject><subject>Kenya -- Social conditions</subject><title>Maasai pastoral potential : a study of ranching and Narok District, Kenya.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n0234.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bj804</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97ks04q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Most elderly persons with dementia are cared for at home, usually by a spouse or adult child. The objective of the present study was to determine whether there is an excess of psychological and physical health problems among family caregivers of elderly persons with dementia. Data were obtained by interview from close family members of dementia patients, and from a comparison group made up of close family members of patients undergoing cataract surgery. Caregivers had significantly higher levels of depression and physical symptoms than noncaregivers. The association between caregiving and the outcome variables was stronger among subjects who were married to the patient than among those who were the patient's child. Furthermore, greater behavioral disturbance in the patient was associated with higher levels of morbidity in the caregiver. The results suggest that caregivers might benefit from careful monitoring of their health status, and from greater access to specialized support services.</description><creator>Baumgarten, Mona</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Sociology, Individual and Family Studies.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>The psychological and physical health of family members caring for an elderly person with dementia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf40w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks04q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gv255</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:35:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, a comparative linguistic investigation of morphological deficits in two English-speaking and two Greek-speaking agrammatic aphasic patients is presented. Adopting the Strong Lexicalist Hypothesis, the study focuses on the subjects' ability to repeat, comprehend and produce nominal and verbal inflections. The hypotheses investigated concern the effects of language-specific features in agrammatic performance and the role of morphological principles in the two languages. Finally the implications of the data for linguistic theory are investigated. The data show that language-specific features are crucial in determining aphasic performance. Principles of well-formedness of lexical items appear to remain unaffected. Morphological deficits are found to manifest themselves at different levels: the lexical and the postlexical. A Storage Hypothesis which reflects the word structure of complex lexical items in the brain is proposed. Finally, it is proposed that only through a Strong Lexicalist framework can one achieve uniform interpretations of morphological deficits in aphasia.</description><creator>Kehayia, Evanthia.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Morphology</subject><subject>Aphasia</subject><subject>Agrammatism</subject><title>Morphological deficits in agrammatic aphasia : a comparative linguistic study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq54g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv255</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):32900</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>