<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:18:12Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):7150" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569699k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La façon dont les modificateurs de la chromatine régulent les divers processus biologiques et pathologiques est une question émergente. La protéine BRPF1 est un régulateur épigénétique unique avec deux doigts de zinc de PHD, un bromodomaine et un domaine de PWWP. De plus, elle peut former des complexes multiples avec les histones acétyltransférases MOZ, MORF et HBO1. Afin d'identifier les fonctions biologiques de la protéine BRPF1 in vivo, l'expression spatio-temporelle de la Brpf1 a d'abord été cartographiée en utilisant une souche de souris exprimant un gène rapporteur LacZ. L'analyse a révélé une expression dynamique dans les tissus extra-embryonnaires, embryonnaires et fœtaux. Après la naissance, une expression élevée est observée dans le cerveau et les testicules. L'atlas d'expression devrait servir de un guide précieux pour déterminer si les fonctions de Brpf1 sont dépendantes ou indépendantes de Moz, Morf et Hbo1 in vivo.       En concordance avec son expression dynamique, l'inactivation globale du gène murin Brpf1 a causé une létalité embryonnaire à E9.5 et des malformations sur le remodelage vasculaire et de la fermeture du tube neural. De plus, la perte de Brpf1 inhibée prolifération cellulaire et déréglementé l'expression de plusieurs gènes. Étonnamment, une régulation positive de la transcription de la p16 et d'un nouveau gène homologue à SCP3 a été détectée. Ces résultats indiqué que Brpf1 joue un rôle important dans le système vasculaire et le développement du tube neural et régule des programmes cellulaires et transcriptionnels.      Conformément à l'expression spécifique dans le cerveau, MOZ et MORF ont été mutés dans des troubles du développement avec une déficience intellectuelle. Afin d'étudier un rôle potentiel de Brpf1 dans le développement du cerveau, des souris avec délétion spécifique de Brpf1 dans le cerveau antérieur ont été générées. Cette délétion a causé  une létalité postnatale avec anomalies du néocortex, une agénésie du corps calleux et une hypoplasie du gyrus denté. Mécaniquement, la perte de Brpf1 déréglementé cellules et progéniteurs souches neurales à travers défauts sur la neurogénèse, la migration neuronale et la progression du cycle cellulaire. Au niveau moléculaire, l'analyse de micropuces révélé une diminution de la transcription de plusieurs gènes, y compris des facteurs importants pour le développement de l'hippocampe et du néocortex. Étonnamment, l'expression de différents gènes Hox et de facteurs de transcription nécessaires pour les programmes de développement d'autres a été augmentée ou induite de manière ectopique. Ces résultats ont identifié un rôle critique pour Brpf1 dans la régulation du développement du cerveau antérieur et un double rôle pour Brpf1 sur l'expression génique in vivo.        Enfin, compte tenu de l'importance de MOZ pour l'hématopoïèse et les maladies hématologiques, fonctions potentielles de Brpf1 durant l'hématopoïèse ont été caractérisés. Lorsque Brpf1 est spécifiquement supprimé dans le système hématopoïétique, les nouveaux nés meurent à trois semaines dû à une défaillance aiguë de la moelle osseuse. Ce défaut a été causé par une diminution du pool de HSC et une perte de leur fonctionnalité dès E12.5. De plus, les données d'ARN-Seq révélées une diminution de l'expression de plusieurs gènes stemness comme Slamf1, Mecom, HoxA9, Hlf, Gfi1, Egr et Gata3. Ces résultats indiquent un rôle essentiel de Brpf1 dans l'hématopoïèse définitif et illuminés de nouvelles avenues pour élucider les réseaux épigénétiques régissant l'ontogénèse des HSC.       Collectivement, nous avons identifié diverses fonctions du régulateur épigénétique Brpf1 durant l'embryogénèse, le développement du cerveau antérieur et l'hématopoïèse.</description><description>How chromatin modifiers regulate various biological and pathological processes is an emerging issue. Bromodomain- and PHD finger-containing protein 1 (BRPF1) is a unique epigenetic regulator with two PHD fingers, one bromodomain and a PWWP domain. In addition, it can form multiple complexes with histone acetyltransferases MOZ, MORF, and HBO1. To investigate what biological functions mammalian BRPF1 has in vivo, spatiotemporal expression of Brpf1 was firstly mapped using a mouse strain containing a LacZ reporter. The analysis revealed dynamic expression in extra-embryonic, embryonic and fetal tissues. After birth, high expression was present in the brain and testis. The expression atlas should serve as a valuable guide for analyzing whether Brpf1 functions dependently or independently of Moz, Morf and Hbo1 in vivo. In support of the dynamic prenatal expression, global inactivation of the mouse Brpf1 gene caused embryonic lethality at E9.5 and defects on vascular remodeling and neural tube closure. Importantly, Brpf1 loss inhibited cell proliferation and deregulated gene expression. Unexpectedly, transcriptional upregulation of p16 and a novel protein homologous to SCP3 was detected. These results indicated that Brpf1 plays a pivotal role in vasculature and neural tube development, and regulates related transcriptional and cellular programs. Consistent with the specific expression in the brain, both MOZ and MORF were mutated in developmental disorders with an intellectual disability. To investigate a potential role of Brpf1 in brain development, mice with forebrain-specific deletion of Brpf1 were generated. The deletion caused postnatal lethality with neocortical abnormalities, callosal agenesis and dentate gyrus hypoplasia. Mechanistically, Brpf1 loss deregulated neural stem cells and progenitors through defects on neurogenesis, neuronal migration and cell cycle progression. Molecularly, microarray analysis revealed decreased transcription of multiple genes, including transcription factors important for hippocampal and neocortical development. Unexpectedly, expression of multiple Hox genes and various transcription factors necessary for other developmental programs was increased or ectopically present. These results identified a critical role of Brpf1 in regulating forebrain development and a dual role of Brpf1 on gene expression in vivo. Considering the importance of MOZ in hematopoiesis and hematological malignancies, potential functions of Brpf1 in hematopoiesis were characterized. The Brpf1 gene was specifically deleted in the hematopoietic system and the mutant pups died by the third week due to acute bone marrow failure. This defect was caused by decreased HSC pool and loss of HSC functionality starting as early as E12.5. Importantly, RNA-Seq data revealed decreased expression of multiple stemness genes such as Slamf1, Mecom, Hoxa9, Hlf, Gfi1, Egr and Gata3. These results indicated an essential role of Brpf1 in definitive hematopoiesis and illuminated new avenues to elucidate epigenetic networks governing HSC ontogeny. Collectively, I have identified diverse functions of mouse Brpf1, a multivalent chromatin reader, in embryogenesis, brain development and hematopoiesis. </description><creator>You, Linya</creator><contributor>Xiang-Jiao Yang (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Multivalent functions of a chromatin regulator in embryonic development and stem cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227ms55t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569699k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vf079</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans cette these, le theme commun est la theorie des concours. Simplement, un concours est une situation dans laquelle un certain nombre de concurrents competitionnent entre eux afin de devenir l'unique vainqueur et ainsi être recompense d'un prix. Par exemple, si une personne voulait se departir d'un bien quelconque mais sans avoir une preference particuliere pour la personne a qui l'offrir, alors celui-ci pourrait organiser un concours dans lequel le gagnant se verrait offrir le bien. Dans ce concours, la probabilite de gagner depend de l'effort fourni lors du concours. Comme exemples concrets, nous pouvonspenser aux competitions sportives, aux situations de litige, aux concours derecherche et autres. Dans cette these, je propose trois modeles differents. Dans le premier chapitre, j'examine les concours dans lesquelles les concurrents mettent en commun leurs efforts a l'interieur du groupe auquel ils appartiennent, dans le but de gagner un bien public local, consommable uniquement par les membres du groupe vainqueur. Les concurrents sont informes de facon privee de la valeur qu'ils ont pour ce bien. J'y mets egalement en relief l'incitation qu'ont les concurrents a resquiller dependamment de la taille du groupe auquel ils appartiennent et de la taille des autres groupes. Je presente aussi dans cet essai des resultats concernant la difference entre les probabilites qu'ont degagner les grands groupes et les petits groupes. J'y conclus notamment que les grands groupes n'ont pas necessairement l'avantage sur les plus petits. Dans le second chapitre, j'introduis un concepteur de concours tirant unbenefice de l'effort total des concurrents. J'y developpe un mecanisme permettant au concepteur de selectionner un sous-ensemble de concurrents, de facon a maximiser ses profits, en depit du fait qu'il soit ignorant de l'utilite qu'ont les concurrents a participer au concours. Je demontre l'existence d'un mecanisme satisfaisant les concepts de compatibilite des incitations et de rationalite individuelle. Je resouds le probleme du concepteur en utilisant un jeu en trois etapes. A l'etape 0, le concepteur choisit un mecanisme. A l'etape 1, les candidats au concours prennent part au mecanisme et un certain nombre d'entre eux sont selectionnes pour participer en tant que concurrents a l'etape 2, dans laquelle se deroule un concours avec information parfaite. Il s'avere alors dans ce modele que le concours final a tendance a inclure plus de concurrents lorsque les candidats valorisent le prix a gagner de facon relativement homogene. De plus, dependemment du cout marginalqu'engendre la participation d'un concurrent a l'etape 2, certains candidatsvalorisant faiblement le prix a gagner, risquent de ne jamais etre choisis pour participer au concours. Dans le dernier chapitre, je developpe un modele de concours simple pour etudier le probleme de l'elaboration d'une ligue sportive professionnelle. Je modelise une ligue sportive professionnelle en tant que duopole. Ce faisant, je suggere une facon de modeliser l'attribution competitive de talent dans les equipes et ce en utilisant un jeu sequentiel dans lequel les equipes doivent miser a la facon d'une enchere le cout unitaire du talent. Ensuite, l'equipe ayant offert le cout le plus eleve se voit octroyer le droit de choisir en premier la quantite de talent a acquerir au cout offert tandis que l'autre equipe doit choisir en deuxieme la quantitite residuelle voulue, payable au meme cout unitaire. Dans l'equilibre de ce jeu, il est possible que ce soit l'equipe a faible revenue qui se voit octroyer le droit de choisir en premier. De plus,l'equipe a revenu eleve acquiert plus de talent a l'equilibre et je demontre qu'une politique de partage du revenu induit l'equipe a revenu eleve a acquerir relativement plus de talent, ayant alors comme consequence d'avantager encore plus l'equipe a revenu eleve.</description><description>In the first chapter, I analyze a model of rent-seeking contest where groups compete non-cooperatively for a group-specific public good. Individuals have private information about how much they value the public good and face a free-riding problem in choosing effort levels. The probability that a group wins depends on the aggregate effort of its members relative to the aggregate effort of all contestants. For tractability, I restrict effort choices to be binary. I show that, in equilibrium, all contestants can exert positive effort ex post, despite the presence of free-riding incentives. This is in contrast to earlier results for contests with perfect information whereby only one contestant in a group exerts effort. I use simulation to show that when moving a player from a group to a group of equal or greater size, average expected effort in equilibrium decreases. Moreover, Olson's paradox, which asserts that groups of large size are less effective at winning a contest than small groups, may or may not hold. Olson's paradox can hold even though the good is purely public within the winning group. Members of the larger group expect other members to draw large valuations, which explains acute free-riding. In the second chapter, I take the perspective of a contest designer who derives profits from aggregate effort exerted by the contestants. I develop a revelation mechanism that enables the contest designer to select a subset of contestants from a pool of candidates in a way that maximizes her profits, even though she is uninformed about the candidates' valuations for the contest prize. I prove the existence of an incentive compatible and individually rational mechanism. I solve the designer's problem by using a 3-stage game where at Stage 0, the designer designs a mechanism, at Stage 1 the contestants participate in the mechanism then contestants are selected and at Stage 2, information is revealed and the selected contestants participate to a contest. I find that contests tend to be larger when candidates to the contest have valuations close to each other. Also, depending on the marginal cost that a contestant imposes on the designer, some candidates with low valuation for the contested good may never be selected to the contest. In the last chapter, I extend a simple model of contest to study the question of league formation in sports economics. I model a professional sports league as a duopoly. I suggest a way to model a competitive allocation of talent into teams, by introducing a sequential game in which teams must first auction the cost of talent, and then, whichever team has made the highest bid, gets to choose first the quantity of talent to hire at the implemented market cost, and then the other team chooses a quantity from the residual pool of talent. I find that in equilibrium, leadership can be taken by the low-revenue team. Also, I find that the high-revenue team acquires more talent in equilibrium and that a revenue-sharing policy will induce the high-revenue team to acquire relatively more talent than the low-revenue team, thus producing a more uneven contest.</description><creator>Mercier, Jean-François</creator><contributor>Licun Xue (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Economics</subject><title>Three essays in contest theory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zr260.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vf079</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kj95t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis includes four studies pertaining to the efficacy and mechanisms of a personality-targeted intervention program for youth alcohol misuse and psychopathology. Study 1 examines the efficacy of the Preventure personality-targeted intervention program on internalising and externalising symptoms in high-risk youth when delivered by educational professionals. Results demonstrate that intervention participants report global reductions in depressive, anxiety and conduct symptoms relative to their control group counterparts, as well as reduced odds of severe depressive symptoms and conduct problems over two years. There is also some evidence for personality-specific intervention effects in youth most at risk for anxiety and conduct disorders. Study 2 explores the relationship between personality, attentional biases and mental disorders in a community adolescent sample. This study provides a preliminary examination of whether attentional biases may be a suitable target for preventive interventions to supplement the Preventure program. Results suggest that attentional biases to emotional faces are not concurrently or prospectively associated with symptoms of mental disorders. Instead, results provide further validation for a personality-targeted approach, as personality traits are associated with concurrent and prospective risk for mental disorders whilst accounting for baseline mental health symptoms. Studies 3 and 4 focus on understanding the mechanisms and process of the Preventure program across two randomised controlled trials. Study 3 explores mediators of two-year intervention effects on alcohol misuse and mental health symptoms. Results suggest that two-year intervention effects on binge drinking and alcohol-related problems are partially mediated by early changes in drinking behaviours. Global improvements in mood during the six months post-intervention were found to partially mediate two-year intervention effects on both internalising and externalising symptoms. The results suggest that early reductions in the growth in alcohol consumption or mental health symptoms may represent proximal markers of longer term intervention efficacy. Lastly, study 4 uses a mixed methods design to elucidate candidate process variables accounting for early indicators of treatment efficacy. The study combines both investigator-driven hypotheses and youth-generated feedback in order to elucidate key intervention features associated with positive behavioural changes. Findings suggest that youth experiences during group personality-targeted intervention sessions can influence the development of their subsequent alcohol-related behaviours (and, in some cases, in mental health symptoms) over twelve months. This study suggests that youth feedback can be used as an early indicator of treatment fidelity and efficacy. Together, these studies contribute to the literature in support of a personality-targeted approach to prevention and demonstrate the utility of process research in informing and refining the intervention approach. </description><description>La présente thèse inclut quatre études traitant de l'efficacité et des mécanismes d'action de Preventure, un programme ciblé à la personnalité, pour prévenir les psychopathologies et la consommation d'alcool problématique chez les jeunes. L'étude 1 examine l'efficacité de Preventure sur les symptômes internalisés et externalisés de jeunes à haut risque lorsque l'intervention est offerte par des professionnels de l'éducation. Les résultats démontrent une réduction des symptômes de dépression, d'anxiété et des troubles de conduite chez les adolescents ayant participé à l'intervention en comparaison au groupe contrôle, ainsi qu'une reduction du taux de symptômes sévères de dépression et de troubles de conduite sur plus de deux ans. Des preuves de l'effet de l'intervention spécifique à la personnalité chez les jeunes les plus à risque pour l'anxiété et les troubles de comportement ont également été trouvés. L'étude 2 explore la relation entre la personnalité, les biais attentionnels et les troubles mentaux sur un échantillon d'adolescents. Cette étude rapporte des résultats préliminaires sur l'implication des biais attentionels comme outil préventif additionnel au programme Preventure. Les résultats suggèrent que les biais attentionnels face aux émotions faciales ne sont pas associés aux symptômes de santé mentale de façon concomitante ou prospective. Plutôt, les résultats apportent de plus amples validations pour une approche centrée sur la personnalité, étant donné que certains traits de personnalité sont eux-mêmes associés aux symptômes de santé mentale de façon concomitante et prospective, tout en tenant compte de ces mêmes symptômes au début de l'étude. Les études 3 et 4 se concentrent sur la compréhension des mécanismes d'action et processus du programme Preventure à travers deux essais randomisés contrôlés. L'étude 3 explore les médiateurs des effets de l'intervention sur la consommation d'alcool et les symptômes de santé mentale sur deux ans. Les résultats suggèrent que l'impact de l'intervention après deux ans sur le calage d'alcool et les problèmes associés à la consommation sont partiellement induits par des changements précoces de consommation d'alcool. Une amélioration globale de l'humeur six mois après l'intervention a été trouvée comme induisant partiellement un effet sur des symptômes internalisés et externalisés jusqu'à deux ans après l'intervention. Les résultats dans les premiers six mois suggèrent qu'une réduction du taux de croissance de la consommation ou des symptômes de troubles mentaux pourraient représenter des déterminants précoces des effets à long terme de l'intervention. Enfin, l'étude 4 utilise un modèle multi-méthodes pour explorer quelles seraient les processus qui expliqueraient l'efficacité d'un traitement sur douze mois. Cette étude combine les hypothèses des chercheurs ainsi que les comptes rendus des jeunes dans le but d'identifier des caractéristiques associées à un changement de comportement positif. Les résultats de l'étude indiquent que l'expérience des jeunes lors des sessions d'intervention ciblant la personnalité peut influencer le développement de leur comportement futur lié à la consommation d'alcool (et, dans certains cas, les symptômes de santé mentale) sur douze mois. Cette étude suggère que les commentaires des adolescents peuvent être utilisés comme indicateur précoce de la fidélité et l'efficacité du traitement. Ensemble, ces recherches contribuent à la littérature soutenant l'approche ciblée à la personnalité en prévention et démontrent l'utilité des recherches sur les processus lorsqu'il s'agit d'informer et d'améliorer les approches d'intervention. </description><creator>O'Leary-Barrett, Maeve</creator><contributor>Robert O Pihl (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Patricia Conrod (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>The efficacy and mechanisms of personality-targeted interventions for alcohol misuse and mental disorders in adolescents</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tb97h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj95t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v553t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is considerable debate in the phonetic sciences concerning the nature of the information that is critical for speech perception, and the nature of the processing mechanisms that map the relevant signal properties onto phonetic categories.  In the domain of vowel perception, research has shown that the mapping between the speech signal and phonetic structure is non-uniform, in that perceivers (both adult and infant) are universally biased toward the extremes of articulatory/acoustic space (peripheral in F1/F2 space; Polka &amp; Bohn, 2003, 2011).  Much of the evidence for this bias comes from studies showing that perceivers consistently discriminate vowels in an asymmetric manner.  More precisely, perceivers perform better at detecting a change from a relatively less (e.g., /e/) to a relatively more peripheral vowel (e.g., /i/), compared to the same change presented in the reverse direction.  Although the existence of this perceptual phenomenon (i.e., the natural referent vowel [NRV] bias) is well established, the mechanisms and processes that underlie it are poorly understood.  One account of the NRV bias, which derives from the Dispersion–Focalization Theory (Schwartz, Abry, Boë, Ménard, &amp; Vallée, 2005), is that extreme vocalic articulations give rise to speech signals that exhibit increased spectral salience due to formant frequency convergence, or "focalization."  This dissertation presents a series of experiments aimed at assessing whether adult perceivers are indeed sensitive to differences in formant proximity while discriminating vowel stimuli that fall within a given category, and, if so, whether that sensitivity is attributable to general properties of auditory processing, or to phonetic processes that extract articulatory information available across sensory modalities.  In Experiment 1, English- and French-speaking perceivers showed directional asymmetries consistent with the focalization account as they attempted to discriminate synthetic /u/ variants that systematically differed in their peripherality and hence degree of formant proximity (between F1 and F2).  In Experiment 2, similar directional effects were found when English perceivers attempted to discriminate natural /u/ productions that differed in their peripherality when only acoustic-phonetic or only visual-phonetic information was present.  Experiment 3 investigated whether and how the integration of acoustic and visual speech cues influences the effects documented in Experiment 2.  When acoustic and visual cues were phonetically-congruent, an NRV bias was observed.  In contrast, when acoustic and visual cues were phonetically-incongruent, this bias was disrupted, confirming that both sensory channels shape this bias in bimodal auditory-visual vowel perception.  Collectively, these findings advance our understanding of the sensory and cognitive processes that are fundamental to the mapping between the speech signal and vowel categories.  In particular, they suggest that perceivers are universally biased to attend to extreme vocalic gestures specified optically, in terms of articulatory kinematic patterns, as well as acoustically, in terms of formant convergence patterns.  A complete understanding of this bias is not only important to speech perception theories, but provides a critical basis for the study of phonetic development as well as the perceptual factors that may constrain vowel inventories across languages.  </description><description>Un débat considérable dans le domaine des sciences phonétiques entoure la nature de l'information pertinente à la perception de la parole et la nature des mécanismes de processus transformant les propriétés des signaux en catégories phonétiques. Dans le domaine de la perception des voyelles, les recherches démontrent que la relation entre le signal de parole et la structure phonétique est déformée, en ce sens que les auditeurs (les adultes comme les nourrissons) sont universellement biaisés à porter attention aux voyelles dotées de propriétés articulatoires / acoustiques extrêmes (en périphérie de l'espace F1/F2; Polka &amp; Bohn, 2003, 2011). Une preuve importante de ce biais provient d'études qui démontrent que les auditeurs discriminent les voyelles de manière asymétrique. Plus précisément, les auditeurs réussissent mieux à détecter un changement d'une voyelle relativement moins périphérique (par exemple, /e/) à une voyelle relativement plus périphérique (par exemple, /i/), comparativement à la même variation dans le sens inverse. Bien que l'existence de ce phénomène perceptif (c.-à-d. le biais de la voyelle référent naturel [VNR]) soit bien établie, les mécanismes et les processus qui le régissent sont mal compris. Une explication du VNR, qui découle de la théorie de la dispersion-focalisation (Schwartz et al., 1997, 2005), est que les articulations vocaliques extrêmes - comme /i/, /a/ et /u/ - donnent naissance à des signaux de parole particulièrement saillant spectralement en raison de la fréquence de convergence des formants, ou «focalisation». Cette thèse présente une série d'études visant à évaluer si les auditeurs sont sensibles aux différences de proximité des formants tout en discriminant le stimulus vocalique qui relève de la même catégorie phonétique, et dans ce cas, si cette sensibilité est attribuable aux propriétés générales de traitement auditif, ou à des processus phonétiques qui opèrent en termes de propriétés articulatoires. Dans l'étude 1, les auditeurs anglophones et francophones ont démontré des asymétries directionnelles en accord avec les prédictions de la focalisation lorsqu'ils tentaient de discriminer des variantes synthétiques de /u/ qui étaient systématiquement différentes dans leur périphérie et, par conséquent, dans le degré de proximité des formants (entre F1 et F2). Dans l'étude 2, des effets directionnels similaires ont été observés lorsque les auditeurs ont tenté de discriminer les réalisations naturelles de /u/ qui diffèrent dans leur périphérie seulement lors que l'information acoustique ou visuelle de parole était présente. L'étude 3 a étudié comment l'intégration des indices acoustiques vocaux et visuels influencent les effets documentés dans l'étude 2. Lorsque des signaux acoustiques et visuels étaient phonétiquement conformes, un biais de VNR a été observé. En revanche, lorsque les repères visuels et acoustiques étaient phonétiquement incongrus, ce biais était perturbé, ce qui confirme que les deux voies sensorielles créent ce biais dans la perception audiovisuelle. De façon globale, ces résultats améliorent notre compréhension des processus sensoriels et cognitifs qui sont essentiels au lien entre les propriétés des signaux et les catégories phonétiques. En particulier, ils suggèrent que les auditeurs sont prédisposés à détecter des signes vocaliques extrêmes visuellement spécifiés, en termes de modèles articulatoires cinématiques, ainsi qu'acoustiques, en termes de convergence de formants. Une compréhension complète de ce biais est non seulement importante pour les théories de la perception de la parole, mais elle fournit également une base crucial pour l'étude du développement phonétique ainsi que pour les éléments perceptuels qui pourraient restreindre les inventaires de voyelles à travers les langues.</description><creator>Masapollo, Matthew</creator><contributor>Polka, Linda (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Communications Sciences &amp; Disorders</subject><title>On the nature of the natural referent vowel bias</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225d73h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v553t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676z449</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce travail se concentre sur la conception et l'optimization d'une sonde d'interférence à base d'anémométrie thermique utilisée pour simultanément mesurer les champs de concentration et de vitesse dans des écoulements turbulents. Bien qu'un petit nombre d'investigations précédentes aient réussi á effectuer ces mesures avec succès, peu de travail a été fait pour examiner et expliquer les composants nécessaires d'une telle sonde spécialisée, qui nécessite qu'un capteur d'anémométrie thermique soit opéré en aval, et à quelques micromètres, d'un deuxième. Les effets des rapports de surchauffe, la séparation entre les fils, les diamètres des fils, et les matériaux des fils, sont étudiés dans le cadre de cette investigation. Des expériences, effectuées dans la région non-flottable d'un jet turbulent, révèlent que des mesures de concentration et de vitesse bien réussies exigent une sonde d'interférence contenant (i) deux fils de diamètres différents et (ii) une petite distance de séparation, d'environ 10 µm, entre les fils. De plus, le fil en amont devrait être opéré à un rapport de surchauffe élevé et le fil en aval devrait être opéré à un rapport de surchauffe assez faible. En comparant les six sondes d'interférence de conceptions variées construite dans cette thèse, une sonde d'interférence optimale, consistant d'un fil de tungstène de 5 µm, en amont d'un fil de platine-rhodium de 2.5 µm, a été identifiée. La précision de cette sonde a été validée contre des écoulements de conditions connues, des études précédentes, et les mesures d'une sonde à fil-chaud, dont la précision a déjà été établie.</description><description>The present work focuses on the design and optimization of a thermal-anemometry-based interference probe used to simultaneously measure concentration and velocity fields in turbulent flows.  Although a small number of previous investigations have successfully performed such measurements, little work has been done to investigate or explain the necessary components in creating such a specialized probe, which necessitates that one hot-wire-anemometry sensor be operated downstream of, and micrometers from, a second one. The effects of different overheat ratios, wire separation distances, wire diameters, and wire materials, are studied as part of this investigation. Experiments performed in the non-buoyant region of a helium-air jet revealed that successful concentration and velocity measurements required an interference probe containing (i) two wires of differing diameters and (ii) a small separation distance, of about 10 µm, between the wires. Furthermore, the upstream wire should be operated at a high overheat ratio and the downstream wire should operated at a low overheat ratio. From six interference probes of varying designs constructed within this thesis, an optimal interference probe, consisting of a 5 µm tungsten wire, 10 µm upstream of a 2.5 μm platinum-rhodium wire, was identified. The accuracy and precision of this probe was validated against flows of known conditions, previous studies, and measurements from a single-normal hot-wire probe, for which the accuracy and precision have been well established.</description><creator>Hewes, Alais</creator><contributor>Laurent B Mydlarski (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Development of an interference probe for the simultaneous measurement of turbulent concentration and velocity fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pg602.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676z449</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f462802s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The peroxisome proliferator activated receptor gamma coactivator 1 alpha (PGC-1α) co-activates various genes essential to oxidative metabolism, mitochondrial biogenesis and function, reactive oxygen species detoxification and angiogenesis. PGC-1α is expressed in various metabolically active tissues, and its expression is reduced in diabetic patients. This transcriptional co-activator has several isoforms with overlapping functions; a more recently described truncated isoform, PGC-1α4, plays a distinct but complementary role to canonical PGC-1α1, and its role and characteristics in different tissues are yet to be explored. The Gly482Ser polymorphism of PGC-1α is associated with an increased risk of developing diabetes, as well as reduced fitness and increased adiposity, and it is associated with reduced PGC-1α mRNA expression in beta cells. Prior studies are discordant, having restricted their investigation of this polymorphism to its impact on co-activator function on one or two promoters. We hypothesized that since PGC-1α drives its own expression, this polymorphism reduces the stability of the PGC-1α stability. In our studies, we used human PGC-1α constructs with a Glycine or a Serine at amino acid 482. Lower levels of the Serine variant translated protein were detected by Western blot compared with the Glycine variant, despite equal mRNA transcript levels. Both translated products were restored to equal levels by MG132, and cycloheximide chase demonstrated that the 482Ser PGC-1α protein has a shorter half-life than 482Gly PGC-1α. We also observed through qPCR on a range of typical endogenous PGC-1α targets that this polymorphism differentially regulates some but not all gene targets. We also investigated the novel isoform PGC-1α4, which our lab previously found inhibited the cleaving of caspase-3, and exhibited anti-apoptotic properties. Our immunofluorescence data indicated that PGC-1α4 was localized in the cytoplasm and that it shifted to the nucleus in response to TNFα treatment. Using cell fractionation, we noted that not only does the nuclear content of PGC-1α4 increase on treatment with TNFα, but the cytoplasmic content does as well.   Altogether, our results indicate a novel site of regulation on the canonical PGC-1α protein that is associated with human disease, and elucidate a distinct response to TNFα treatment by one of its isoforms, adding nuance to our understanding of this isoform's anti-apoptotic properties, and how its activity is regulated. </description><description>La protéine Peroxisome Proliferator –activated receptor 1 gamma Co-activator 1 alpha (PGC-1α) contrôle l'expression d'une variété de gènes essentiels au métabolisme oxydatif, à la fonction et la biogénèse mitochondriale, à la détoxification des espèces réactives de l'oxygène et à l'angiogénèse. PGC-1α est exprimé dans différents tissues métaboliquement actifs et son expression est diminuée chez les patients diabétiques. Ce co-activateur transcriptionnel a plusieurs isoformes possédant des fonctions qui se chevauchent. Un nouvel isoforme tronqué, PGC-1α4, a été récemment décrit comme ayant un rôle distinct mais complémentaire à l'isoforme canonique PGC-1α1 mais sa fonction dans différents tissues n'a jamais été investiguée. Le polymorphisme Gly482Ser de PGC-1α est associé avec une augmentation du risque d'être diagnostiqué diabétique, une diminution de la capacité aérobique et ainsi qu'une adiposité plus importante. Enfin ce polymorphisme est associé avec une expression  génique réduite de PGC-1α dans les cellules béta du pancréas. Jusqu'à présent, la littérature est réduite sur l'effet de ce polymorphisme sur la fonction de co-activatrice de PGC-1α. Puisque PGC-1α augmente sa propre expression, nous avons  fait l'hypothèse que ce polymorphisme diminue la stabilité de la protéine PGC-1α. Dans nos études, nous avons utilisés des plasmides exprimant l'acide aminé Glycine ou Serine en position 482. Des niveaux d'expressions protéiques diminués du variant Serine, comparé au variant glycine, ont été observés par immunoblot malgré des niveaux d'expression génique équivalents. Les deux variants sont observés au même niveau d'expression protéique après traitement par le MG132 ou cycloheximide, démontrant que la demi-vie du variant Ser482 PGC-1α est plus courte que celle du variant Gly482. Nous avons aussi mesuré par PCR semi quantitative que ce polymorphisme régule différemment des gènes cibles canoniques de PGC-1α. Nous avons investigué le rôle de PGC-1α4, que notre laboratoire a démontré comme ayant des propriétés anti-apoptotiques en inhibant le clivage de Caspase-3. Nos données d'immunofluorescence ont démontrées le contraire, indiquant que PGC-1α4 est importée du cytoplasme vers le noyau après traitement. Par fractionnement cellulaire, nous montrons que le contenu nucléaire et cytoplasmique en PGC-1α4 augmente après traitement par TNFα.Nos résultats indiquent un nouveau site de régulation de la protéine PGC-1α, associé à différentes maladies, et montrent une réponse distincte au TNFα par un des ses isoformes, éclairant notre compréhension de la régulation de ses propriétés anti-apoptotiques.</description><creator>Khan, Naveen</creator><contributor>Jennifer Estall (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Exploring the regulation of PGC-1α-investigating the Gly482Ser polymorphism of PGC-1α and the PGC-1α4 isoform</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g535r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462802s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838329x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Unlike healthy individuals, patients with Cystic Fibrosis (CF) experience extended periods of infection and worsened symptoms when infected with Human Rhinovirus (HRV), the leading agent of the common cold. A negative association has been made between HRV and the antiviral cytokine, interferon (IFN)-beta, bringing forth the question of whether stimulation of antiviral defences leading to an augmentation in IFN-beta can help clear HRV from the airways. The intrinsically elevated levels of airway inflammation as well chronic infection with opportunistic pathogens such as Pseudomonas (P.) aeruginosa creates a need to assess the effect of augmentation of IFN-beta by antiviral defence stimulation on other aspects of innate immunity. In this study, we sought to determine the effect of polyinosinic-polycytidylic acid (poly (I:C)), aviral dsRNA mimic, liposome-complexed poly (I:C) and exogenous IFN-beta on cell viability, inflammation and phagocytosis of P. aeruginosa in monocyte-derived macrophages (MDM). Macrophages are important airway innate immune cells that can take part in the inflammatory response, antibacterial response, and potentially, antiviral response. Due to their prominent role in innate immunity, these cells act as important modulators of the immune response. We observed that poly (I:C), liposome-complexed poly (I:C) and IFN-beta were minimally toxic tocells and while both poly (I:C) and liposome-complexed poly (I:C) were capable of augmenting IFN-beta, poly (I:C) had an associated increase in interleukin (IL)-8 and IL-1beta pro-inflammatory cytokine production. In comparison, exogenous IFN-beta did not mediate as robust an antiviral or inflammatory response. In addition, augmentation of IFN-beta by liposome-complexed poly (I:C) was found to occur through both cytoplasmic receptors: retinoic acid-inducible gene-1 (RIG-I) and melanoma differentiation-associated protein 5 (MDA-5). Lastly, liposome-complexed poly (I:C) was found to increase the phagocytic ability of MDM in response to infection with P. aeruginosa. These results support the use of liposome-complexed poly (I:C) as a potential therapy for CF patients due to its ability to stimulate antiviral defences as well as phagocyticability of a common bacterial pathogen in CF without promoting cellular toxicity or inflammation.</description><description>Contrairement à ce qui est observé chez les personnes saines, les patients atteint de la fibrose kystique (FK) connaissent des périodes d'infection prolongées ainsi que des symptômes aggravés quand elles sont infectées avec le rhinovirus humain (HRV), l'agent causatif du rhume. Une association négative a été établi entre le nombre de copies virales et le cytokine antiviral, interféron (IFN)-beta, ce qui nous mène à questionner si l'augmentation de IFN-beta mènerait à un dégagement du virus des voies aériennes. Le niveau d'inflammation élevé intrinsèque aux voies aériennes en ceux atteint de la FK, ainsi que l'infection chronique par les pathogènes opportunistes comme Pseudomonas (P.) aeruginosa créent un besoin d'évaluer les effets de l'augmentation de IFN-beta par stimulation des défenses antivirales sur d'autres aspects d'immunité innée. Dans cette étude, nous avons recherché l'effet de polyinosinic-polycytidylic acid (poly(I:C)), un ARN double brin synthétique, «liposome-complexed poly (I:C)» et IFN-! exogène sur la viabilité des cellules, l'inflammation et la phagocytose de P. aeruginosa dans les macrophages dérivés de monocytes (MDM). Les macrophages sont des cellules aériennes importantes dans l'immunité innée qui font parties de la réponse inflammatoire, la réponse antibactérienne, et potentiellement, la réponse antivirale. En raison de leur rôle important dans l'immunité innée, ces cellules agissent en tant que modulateur de la réponse immunitaire innée. Nous avons observé que poly (I :C), «liposome-complexed poly (I:C)» et IFN-beta exogène n'étaient pas toxique au cellules. De plus, «liposome-complexed poly (I:C)» était capable d'augmenter IFN-beta tandis que poly (I :C) a été capable d'augmenter IFN-beta et des cytokines inflammatoires :interleukine (IL)-8 et IL-1beta. En comparaison, l'IFN-! exogène n'a pas produit une réponse antivirale et inflammatoire aussi robuste. D'autant plus, l'augmentation de IFN-beta par «liposome-complexed poly (I:C)» s'est produit par les récepteurs cytoplasmiques : «retinoic acid-inducible gene I» (RIG-I) et «melanoma differentiation-associated protein 5» (MDA-5). En dernier lieu, «liposome-complexed poly (I:C)» a augmenté la capacité phagocytaire des MDM en réponse à l'infection avec P. aeruginosa. Ces résultats supportent l'utilisation de «liposome-complexed poly (I:C)» comme un agent thérapeutique potentiel pour les patients atteints de la FK en raison de sa capacité de stimuler la défense antivirale, ainsi que la capacité phagocytaire élevé d'une bactérie commune en FK sans être toxique ou promouvoir la réponse inflammatoire.</description><creator>Cammisano, Maria</creator><contributor>Larry Lands (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>The effect of stimulation of antiviral defences on innate immunity in macrophages</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117r624.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838329x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dz005</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'émergence récente d'une classe spéciale de petits véhicules aériens sans pilote (UAV) à voilure fixe appelés drones agiles ou drones très maniables a conduit à un regain d'intérêt pour la modélisation et la compréhension des dynamiques de ces véhicules.  Les drones agiles sont caractérisés par leur faible poids et leurs faibles moments d'inertie, leurs surfaces à faible rapport hauteur/largeur,  une grande déviation des surfaces de contrôle, un propulseur puissant produisant un rapport élevé force/poids et un sillage aérodynamique puissant.  Grâce à cette configuration unique, les drones agiles atteignent une maniabilité comparable à celles de voilures tournantes et de voilures de battement, ce qui les rend adaptés pour un large éventail de tâches impliquant une voltige à la fois classique et extrême. Alors que les pilotes de RC ont longtemps démontré le potentiel des drones agiles, imiter ses capacités avec l'autonomie reste encore un grand défi, surtout dû au fait que le comportement de ces drones n'est pas bien compris. Ce travail fait un premier pas vers la compréhension et la simulation du comportement des drones agiles pour leur enveloppe de vol complet.  Un modèle dynamique non linéaire à six degrés de liberté est ici présenté. Le modèle est validé pour une plateforme de test YAK54 ARF 3D électrique Aerobat avec une envergure de 0.82 m. Les paramètres inertiels et géométriques sont déterminés en utilisant les mesures du véhicule et un modèle CAO détaillé. Le modèle de drone agile utilise une approche de répartition des composantes intégrant l'aérodynamique. Les ± 180 degrés de l'angle d'attaque complet et la gamme de glissade sur l'aile sont capturés tout en prenant compte d'un faible rapport hauteur/largeur, ainsi que des grands effets de déviations des surfaces de contrôle à la fois pré-arrêt et post-arrêt.  L'effet de l'aérodynamique quasi soutenu et non-soutenu est également étudié.   L'interférence aérodynamique entre différentes composantes telles que l'aile, la queue, etc. est aussi simplement introduite. La plupart des manœuvres de voltige des drones agiles sont possibles grâce à leurs puissants propulseurs, puisqu'il supporte le poids de l'avion, tandis que son sillage aérodynamique fournit de l'air aux surfaces aérodynamiques et de contrôle pour aider à maintenir une capacité de s'élever et la capacité de contrôle. Ainsi, un traitement mathématique détaillé de la dynamique des propulseurs et les effets de l'hélice de sillage aérodynamique ont également exploré dans les travaux présentés.  Un modèle de dynamique de propulseur est développé en tenant compte de ses composantes, spécifiquement la batterie, ESC, moteur DC sans balais et l'hélice. Les effets gyroscopiques résultant de grands tangages et lacet du propulseur sont également pris en compte. Pour le sillage aérodynamique, les effets des axiaux et les tourbillonnements sont considérés. Un nouveau modèle est présenté pour prédire la vitesse axiale présente en aval de l'hélice.Le dernier aspect de ce travail est la validation du modèle de drone agile (mis en œuvre dans Simulink). Une multitude d'expériences comprenant des bancs d'essai statiques et des tunnels aérodynamiques sont effectuées. Une validation approfondie est accomplie en rapport aux données expérimentales pour les composantes individuelles ainsi que le modèle global de drone agile. En général, les résultats simulés sont en accord avec les données expérimentales. Une validation qualitative finale se fait aussi par la configuration du modèle afin de fonctionner en temps réel avec le pilote en boucle et une rétroaction visuelle fournie par X-Plane.  Un pilote professionnel de RC qui a de l'expérience de vol avec la plateforme réelle a testé  la simulation en effectuant diverses manœuvres de RC. Ses commentaires généraux étaient que la simulation agit comme l'avion réel.</description><description>Recent emergence of a special class of small fixed-wing UAVs called agile UAVs or highly maneuverable UAVs, has led to a renewed interest in modeling and understanding full-envelope fixed-wing aircraft dynamics. Agile UAVs are characterized by low weight and inertia, low aspect ratio surfaces with big control surfaces and large deflections, and a powerful thruster producing high thrust-to-weight ratio and a strong slipstream. Owing to this unique configuration, agile UAVs attain maneuverability that parallels that of rotary-wing and flapping-wing UAVs, therefore making them suitable for a wide range of tasks involving both conventional and extreme aerobatic flight. While RC pilots have long demonstrated the potential of agile UAVs, mimicking these capabilities autonomously remains at large a challenge, mainly because the behavior of these UAVs is not well understood. This work takes a first step towards understanding and simulating the behavior of agile UAVs for their full flight envelope. To this end, a six degree-of-freedom nonlinear dynamics model is presented. The model is validated for a YAK54 ARF Electric 3D Aerobat test platform having a wing span of 0.82 m. The inertial and geometric parameters are determined from measurements and a detailed CAD model. The agile UAV model incorporates aerodynamics based on a component breakdown approach. The full ± 180 deg. angle of attack and sideslip range is captured while also taking into account low aspect ratio as well as large control surface deflection effects both pre-stall and post-stall. The effect of quasi-steady and unsteady aerodynamics is also investigated. Aerodynamic interference between different components such as the wing, tail etc. is introduced in a simple fashion. Most of the aerobatic maneuvers of agile UAVs are possible due to its powerful thruster because it supports the aircraft weight, while its slipstream provides air over the aerodynamic and control surfaces to help maintain lift and control. In lieu of this, a detailed mathematical treatment for the thruster dynamics and the propeller slipstream effects have also been undertaken in the current work. A thruster dynamics model is developed by considering its components namely the battery, ESC, brushless DC motor, and propeller. Gyroscopic effects arising from large pitching and yawing of the thruster are also taken into account. For the slipstream, the effects of both axial and swirl components are considered. A novel model is presented to predict the axial velocity up to far downstream of the propeller.The last aspect of this work is the validation of the agile UAV model (implemented in Simulink). A multitude of experiments comprising of static bench tests and wind-tunnel tests are performed. A thorough validation is carried out against experimental data for the individual components as well as the overall agile UAV model. In general, the simulated results are in good agreement with experimental data. A final qualitative validation is also done by configuring the model to run in real-time with the pilot-in-loop and visual feedback provided through X-Plane. A professional RC pilot who has experience flying the real aircraft, tested the simulation by flying various RC maneuvers. His overall comments were that the simulation behaves much like the real aircraft.</description><creator>Khan, Waqas</creator><contributor>Meyer Nahon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Dynamics modeling of agile fixed-wing unmanned aerial vehicles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w7317.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dz005</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tx79w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The elimination of child labour in all its forms is an identified political priority for the international community. This has endured historically and has moved up the agenda since the 1990s, including through its inclusion most recently in the UN Sustainable Development Goals. However, international legal and policy approaches to date have only provided a limited challenge to some of the enduring structural processes that underpin the problem. These include the growing and highly dispersed informal economy, poverty and structural inequality for children and their families, the role and burden of gendered care and social reproduction work, and deprivations in the right to education. This thesis problematizes the limitations of the conceptual framing of childhood economic exploitation under international labour law and international human rights law. Analyzing what it terms the 'prohibition and penalty' approach that has dominated the labour law model of intervention, this thesis argues that this approach fails to effectively challenge a number of these structural processes, in particular the prevalence of child labour in the informal economy. Raising further critical questions in relation to the distinct international human rights law model, this thesis argues that while promising a more holistic approach to children's rights, the human rights law framework relegates the relevance and implications of social reproduction and care to the private sphere of the family, and provides limited protection for crucial socio-economic rights for families. The second part of the thesis examines the ways in which we can address two critical structural dimensions of the problem – the informal economy and social protection mechanisms for families. Emerging policy developments in these fields are reviewed, including the potential of the ILO's recent Decent Work for All Agenda as a response to the informal economy, and the scope and application of social protection mechanisms in this field. Noting some positive trends, this thesis argues that these developments retain some of the limitations identified in the labour law and human rights law models. In particular, they fail to fully grapple with the relevance and implications of social reproduction and care labour as an enduring and less visible element that underpins childhood economic exploitation. Moreover, there remains a disjuncture between progressive policy developments and international legal standards. Drawing on feminist relational theory throughout the analysis, this thesis argues for an approach to childhood economic exploitation that would embed the child within the range of personal and institutional relationships that determine her socio-economic rights over time, and that would centralize rather than marginalise the significance of care and interdependence, in ways that capture the distinct 'situatedness' of children as legal subjects. By engaging in this analysis, this thesis attempts to contribute towards emerging legal and policy approaches in this specific field, and to an enhanced understanding of the distinctive position of the child as a subject of law and development, that is alive to the core significance of varied personal and institutional relationships for the advancement of children's human rights.  </description><description>L'élimination du travail des enfants sous toutes ses formes est une priorité politique identifiée pour la communauté internationale. Il s'agit d'une réalité historique, qui a progressé dans l'agenda politique depuis les années 1990, en partie grâce à son incorporation récente aux Objectifs de développement durable des Nations Unies. Cependant, les approches légales et politiques internationales n'ont à ce jour posé qu'un défi limité à plusieurs des processus structuraux sous-jacents qui font durer le problème. On pense à l'économie souterraine, très dispersée et en pleine expansion, à la pauvreté et à l'inégalité structurelle concernant les enfants et leur famille, au rôle et au fardeau des soins sexospécifiques et du travail de reproduction sociale, et au dénuement en matière de droit à l'éducation. Cette thèse pose le problème des limitations du cadre conceptuel de l'exploitation économique de l'enfance selon le droit international du travail et le droit international en matière humanitaire. Avec l'analyse de ce que l'on appellera l'approche « interdiction et punition », qui a dominé le modèle d'intervention du droit du travail, on en discutera l'échec, car cette approche ne confronte pas efficacement plusieurs de ces processus structuraux, en particulier la prédominance du travail des enfants dans l'économie souterraine. On soulèvera d'autres questions critiques concernant le modèle particulier du droit international en matière humanitaire, posant l'idée que, tout en promettant une approche plus globale des droits de l'enfant, le cadre du droit international en matière humanitaire renvoie l'importance et les implications de la reproduction sociale et des soins à la sphère privée de la famille, et offre une protection limitée des droits socio-économiques cruciaux pour les familles. La deuxième partie de cette thèse s'intéresse aux différentes façons dont nous pouvons résoudre deux dimensions structurelles critiques du problème : l'économie souterraine et les mécanismes de protection sociale pour les familles. On analysera de récents développements politiques dans ces domaines, dont le potentiel de l'Agenda Un travail décent pour tous de l'OIT, en réponse à l'économie souterraine, et l'échelle et l'application des mécanismes de protection sociale qui s'y rattachent. Soulignant quelques tendances positives, on expliquera que ces développements conservent certaines des limitations identifiées dans les modèles du droit du travail et du droit en matière humanitaire. En particulier, ils ne parviennent pas à cerner entièrement l'importance et les implications de la reproduction sociale et du travail de soins en tant qu'élément persistant et moins visible qui sous-tend l'exploitation économique de l'enfance. De plus, la contradiction demeure entre les développements politiques progressifs et les standards légaux internationaux. En se basant sur la théorie relationnelle féministe tout au long de cette analyse, on appellera à une approche de l'exploitation économique de l'enfance qui intègre l'enfant au sein des relations personnelles et institutionnelles qui déterminent ses droits socio-économiques au fil du temps, et qui centralise plutôt que marginalise l'importance des soins et de l'interdépendance, d'une façon qui prend en compte le contexte (« situatedness ») des enfants en tant que sujets légaux. En s'engageant dans cette analyse, on tentera d'apporter sa contribution aux approches légales et politiques qui émergent dans ce domaine spécifique, et d'aider à une meilleure compréhension de la position spécifique de l'enfant en tant que sujet de droit et de développement, vivant jusqu'au cœur l'importance des différentes relations personnelles et institutionnelles pour l'avancement des droits de l'homme pour les enfants.  </description><creator>Hennessy, Róisín</creator><contributor>Colleen Sheppard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Law</subject><title>Economic exploitation and child labour: Towards a structural approach to international labour law and human rights</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg36h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tx79w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tf827</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le glioblastome multiforme (GBM) est la forme la plus fréquente et la plus agressive des tumeurs cérébrales primaires chez les adultes. Le pronostic reste particulièrement mauvais, malgré un traitement qui nécessite la chirurgie, la radiothérapie (RT) et la chimiothérapie en utilisant l'agent alkylant témozolomide (TMZ). O6-méthylguanine-ADN méthyltransférase (MGMT) est une protéine de réparation de l'ADN bien connue pour son rôle dans la résistance aux agents alkylants. Cependant, tous les patients nouvellement diagnostiqués avec GBM reçoivent actuellement le même traitement standard utilisant le TMZ sans tenir compte de leur statut de MGMT. La réponse aux nouvelles thérapies ciblées reste un défi pour le traitement du GBM principalement en raison de l'hétérogénéité des tumeurs, leur aspect très invasif et une angiogenèse anormale. Sunitinib malate (SU11248), une petite molécule qui cible plusieurs récepteurs tyrosine kinase (RTK) en inhibant les RTKs impliqués dans l'angiogenèse a montré seulement un bénéfice thérapeutique limité chez les patients atteints de glioblastome avec une maladie récurrente.Notre groupe a montré le rôle de l'expression de MGMT comme un régulateur négatif de l'angiogenèse et l'invasion dans des lignées cellulaires GBM isogéniques pour l'expression de MGMT avec validation dans les échantillons de patients. En outre, les résultats précliniques ont montré un différentiel anti-proliférative et anti-invasive du sunitinib suggérant que les patients atteints de tumeurs MGMT positives pourraient bénéficier de la thérapie à base de sunitinib. Des études récentes dans deux différents types de cancer ont suggéré le rôle du sunitinib dans la modulation de l'expression du niveau des gènes transcrits dans les cellules tumorales. Jusqu'à présent, la multimodalité de sunitinib n'est pas encore claire dans le GBM. Nous avons émis l'hypothese que (i) l'expression de MGMT dans les cellules tumorales du GBM peut affecter la réponse au sunitinib et (ii) le mécanisme d'action du sunitinib dans le GBM n'est peut être pas limité à l'inhibition de ses cibles connues (RTK). Dans cette étude, nous avons évalué l'efficacité du traitement de sunitinib, sa toxicité et tolérabilité dans un essai clinique de phase II qui teste le sunitinib concomitant avec le traitement RT et TMZ pour les patients sélectionnés avec des tumeurs qui ont un promoteur de gène MGMT non méthylé. Ces patients ne répondent pas à TMZ et peuvent potentiellement bénéficier de la combinaison de sunitinib avec leur traitement standard (certificat d'éthique McG1132). Nous avons également utilisé une stratégie de multiplexage dans des échantillons de plasma de manière prospective pour évaluer les niveaux d'expression d'une large gamme de cytokines et de protéines impliquées dans l'angiogenèse et l'invasion. L'identification d'une signature protéique associée à des niveaux MGMT dans le sang pour la réponse au sunitinib est actuellement en cours dans cette étude longitudinale. Utilisant des lignées cellulaires de glioblastome isogéniques pour MGMT, on a également utilisé l'expression d'un profile de gènes pour identifier des gènes qui peuvent être modulées en réponse au sunitinib. L'analyse du profile de gènes a révélé que le traitement au sunitinib d'une lignée cellulaire GBM MGMT-positive a diminué de manière significative l'expression de stanniocalcine-1 (STC1), une hormone de glycoprotéine associée à une mauvaise survie globale chez les patients avec glioblastome. Nos résultats vont conduire à l'identification de nouveaux biomarqueurs pour sélectionner les patients et prédire la réponse au traitement utilisant le sunitinib. Dans la pratique clinique, l'utilisation de cette signature peut conduire à des stratégies plus efficaces et personnalisés de traitement pour les patients atteints de GBM avec des tumeurs qui ne répondent pas au traitement standard.</description><description>Glioblastoma multiforme (GBM) is the most frequent and most aggressive form of primary brain tumors in adults. The prognosis remains dismal despite treatment that involves surgery, radiation therapy (RT) and chemotherapy using the alkylating agent Temozolomide (TMZ). O6-methylguanine-DNA methyltransferase (MGMT) is a DNA repair protein well known for resistance to alkylating agents. However, all patients newly diagnosed with GBM are currently offered the same standard treatment with TMZ regimen regardless of their MGMT status. Response to new-targeted therapies remains a challenge in GBM mainly due to tumor heterogeneity, a highly invasive pattern and abnormal angiogenesis. Sunitinib malate (SU11248), an oral small molecule multi-targeting receptor tyrosine kinase (RTK) inhibitor affecting RTKs involved in angiogenesis showed only limited therapeutic benefit in GBM patients with recurrent disease. Our group showed the role of MGMT expression as a negative regulator of angiogenesis and invasion in GBM cell lines isogenic for expression of MGMT with validation in patient's samples. Additionally, preclinical findings showed a differential anti-proliferative and anti-invasive effect of sunitinib suggesting that patients with MGMT-positive tumors may derive benefit from sunitinib-based therapy. Recent studies in two different cancer types suggested the role of sunitinib in modulating the expression level of genes transcripts in tumor cells. Thus far, the multimodality of sunitinib is still unclear in GBM. We hypothesize that (i) MGMT expression in GBM tumor cells may affect response to sunitinib and (ii) the mechanism of action of sunitinib in GBM may not be limited to inhibition of its known targets (RTKs). In this study, we evaluated the efficacy of sunitinib treatment, its safety and tolerability in a single arm, phase II clinical trial of concurrent sunitinib with RT and TMZ for selected patients with an unmethylated MGMT gene promoter. These patients do not respond to TMZ and may potentially benefit from the combination of sunitinib with their standard treatment (Ethical Approval McG1132). We also used a multiplexing strategy in plasma samples to prospectively assess expression levels of a large array of cytokines and proteins involved in angiogenesis and invasion. The identification of a blood-based protein signature associated with MGMT levels for response to sunitinib is currently underway in this longitudinal study. Using GBM cell lines isogenic for MGMT, we also used gene expression profiling to identify genes that may be modulated in response to sunitinib. Gene expression profiling (GEP) analysis revealed that treatment of a GBM MGMT- positive cell line with sunitinib significantly decreased the expression of stanniocalcin-1 (STC1), a glycoprotein hormone associated with poor overall survival in patients with GBM. Our findings will lead to the identification of novel biomarkers to select patients and predict response to suntinib-based therapy. In clinical practice, the use of this signature may lead to more efficient and personalized strategies of treatment for GBM patients with tumors unresponsive to standard therapy.</description><creator>Azam, Maryyam</creator><contributor>Siham Sabri (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Identification of a biomarker protein signature for response to Sunitinib in Glioblastoma</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f866h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tf827</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rr54n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Atomic force microscopy (AFM) was developed in the mid 1980's to measure the topography of a sample with atomic resolution. Since the first reported atomic resolution images, AFM has constantly been developed further to gain more insights into structure and property at the nanometer scale. Its great advantage is the capability to spatially resolve the tip-sample interaction at a sub-nanometer scale.  Extensive research and development was conducted over the past two decades to not only measure the structure of a sample but also to extract information about the local properties. Kelvin Probe Force Microscopy is an example of such a technique, enabling the measurement of the local contact potential between the AFM tip and the sample. In this thesis, AFM is used to spatially resolve the surface potential generated upon illumination of a sample with light.A new technique to accurately measure the change of the contact potential difference under pulsed illumination was developed and implemented. This new measurement technique was needed since we reached the limit of currently available methods. These did not allow the measurement of the surface photovoltage as a function of illumination wavelength or time. This new method allows a much more accurate determination of surface potential differences.  Resolving the surface photovoltage on a nanometer length scale with AFM can be of great interest in particular if one can additionally  gain information about the temporal response of the sample. To address this, we developed a method to study the decay of the surface photovoltage by non-contact AFM, which is only limited by the underlying physics process. The approach used to achieve fast time resolution measurements is discussed in a general context. We demonstrate that the well known fundamental sensitivity limits of force detection also govern the achievable time resolution.  The time resolved methods developed in this thesis can be adapted to measure time resolved ion diffusion, thermal response and electronic pulse propagation. As a proof for the novel measurement method, the ultra-fast decay time of the photocarriers in low temperature grown GaAs of about 1 ps was measured by AFM. These experiments were implemented by combining a traditional optical pump-probe modulated excitation with localized readout by AFM, The spatial resolution is therefore given by the AFM setup and not the optical excitation.</description><description>La microscopie à force atomique (MFA) a été développée dans le milieu des années 80 pour mesurer la topographie d'un échantillon avec une résolution atomique. Depuis les premières images de résolution atomiques obtenues, la MFA a constamment été amélioré pour raffiner notre compréhension des phénomènes à l'échelle du nanomètre. Son grand avantage est la capacité de résoudre le potentiel pointe-échantillon à cette échelle auparavant inaccessible. Davantage de recherche et de développement ont été réalisés au cours des deux dernières décennies pour mesurer non seulement la structure de l'échantillon, mais en plus d'extraire des informations sur les propriétés locales. Kelvin Probe Force Microscopy est un tel exemple, permettant la mesure du potentiel de contact local entre la pointe du MFA et l'échantillon. Dans cette thèse, le MFA est utilisé pour résoudre spatialement le potentiel de surface générée lors de l'illumination d'un échantillon avec de la lumière. Une nouvelle technique pour mesurer avec précision le changement du contact différence de potentiel sous un éclairage pulsé a été développée et testée. Cette nouvelle technique de mesure est nécessaire pour repousser la limite des méthodes actuellement disponibles qui ne permettent pas de mesurer la phototension de surface en fonction de la longueur d'onde ou du temps d'illumination. La résolution de la phototension de surface sur une échelle nanométrique avec le MFA peut être d'un grand intérêt, en particulier si l'on peut en outre obtenir de l'information sur la réponse temporelle de l'échantillon. Nous avons développé une méthode pour étudier la diminution de la phototension de surface par MFA, limitée seulement par le processus physique sous-jacent. L'approche utilisée pour cette mesure de résolution temporelle est discutée dans un contexte général. Nous démontrons que les limites de sensibilité fondamentales de détection de force déjà établies régissent également la résolution temporelle réalisable par notre technique. Cela permet aux méthodes de résolution temporelle développées dans cette thèse d'être adaptées pour mesurer la diffusion d'ions dans le temps, la réponse thermique ainsi que la propagation d'impulsions électroniques par MFA. Comme preuve que la méthode de mesure proposée est viable, le temps de décroissance de photoporteurs dans un matériau de GaAs préparé à basse température, d'environ 1 ps, a été mesuré par MFA. Ces expériences ont réalisées en combinant une excitation optique traditionnelle de type pompe-sonde avec lecture localisée par le MFA. La résolution spatiale est donc déterminée par le MFA et non l'excitation optique.</description><creator>Schumacher, Zeno</creator><contributor>Peter H Grutter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>Time-domain Kelvin probe force microscopy for local ultra-fast decay time measurements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kn42w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rr54n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53k072v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is widely recognized that disregarding the uncertainty rooted in data-dependent model selection procedures invalidates various uncertainty measurements which were used to be justified by classical statistical theories. Categorized according to different types of post-selection estimation targets, there has been a great amount of new insights proposed to provide valid post-selection inference for both population- and projection-based regression coefficients. In this thesis, we first motivate the study of post-selection inference through two simulated examples. Upon acknowledging the necessity for valid inference after model selection, we then perform a thorough literature review of major landmarks in tracking the post-selection sampling distribution of regression parameter estimates and  coverage properties of naive confidence intervals/regions. This is followed by a selective overview of existing prominent post-selection statistical inferential paradigms for both population- and projection-based targets. Particularly, emphasis is placed on the construction of valid post-selection confidence intervals. Focusing on methods designed for the projection-based regression coefficients, we carry out simulation studies to compare the performance of various post-selection confidence intervals constructed by these methods. Under the presumed framework of linear regression model with i.i.d. Gaussian errors, this simulated comparison contributes quantitatively to the understanding of merits and limitations of various post-selection confidence intervals for projection-based regression coefficients in terms of average conditional coverage probability, average length of confidence intervals and symmetry of coverage hits and misses. </description><description>Il est généralement admis que de négliger l'incertitude liée aux procédures de sélectionde modèle qui dépendent des données invalide plusieurs mesures d'incertitude qui sonthabituellement justiées par la théorie statistique classique. Catégorisés en fonction desdiérents objectifs d'estimation après la sélection, beaucoup de nouveaux indices ont étéproposés an de mettre au point une inférence post-sélection valide pour les coecientsde régression basés sur la population ou la projection. Dans cette thèse, nous motivonsd'abord l'étude de l'inférence post-sélection à l'aide de deux exemples de simulation. Reconnaissantla nécessité d'une inférence valide après la sélection de modèle, nous faisonsensuite une revue complète de la littérature sur les principaux critères pour obtenir la distributiond'échantillonnage des estimateurs des paramètres de régression, et les propriétésde couverture des intervalles (ou régions) de conance naïfs. Cela est suivi d'une synthèsesélective des importants paradigmes d'inférence statistique post-sélection disponibles pourles objectifs basés sur la population et la projection. Nous plaçons plus particulièrementl'emphase sur la construction d'intervalles de conance post-sélection valides. En mettantl'accent sur les méthodes conçues pour les coecients de régression basés sur lesprojections, nous eectuons des études de simulation pour comparer la performance desdiérents intervalles de conance post-sélection construits avec ces méthodes. Dans lecadre de la régression linéaire avec erreurs gaussiennes i.i.d., cette comparaison simuléecontribue de façon quantitative à la compréhension des mérites et des limites de plusieursintervalles de conance post-sélection pour des coecients de régression basé sur la projectionen termes de la moyenne de la probabilité conditionnelle de couverture, de lalongueur moyenne de l'intervalle de conance et de la symétrie des succès et échecs decouverture.</description><creator>Zhang, Dongliang</creator><contributor>Khalili Mahmoudabadi, Abbas (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Asgharian-Dastenaei, Masoud (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mathematics and Statistics</subject><title>A comparative study of some existing post-model-selection inferential methods in linear regression models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p999s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k072v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mf54t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pendant des décennies, les cellules germinales mâles, en constante production, ont été considérées comme insensibles aux effets de l'âge. Depuis, l'avancement de l'âge paternel été associé à des complications aux cours de la grossesse et à des maladies génétiques chez la descendance. Dans le testicule, une activité métabolique accrue entraîne des niveaux élevés d'espèces oxygénées réactives (EOR) pouvant engendrer de sévères dommages cellulaires ; ces EOR sont naturellement régulées par un réseau complexe d'antioxydants testiculaires. Cependant, le vieillissement engendre une élévation des niveaux d'EOR associée à une détérioration des défenses antioxydantes compromettant la qualité des cellules germinales en développement. Si plusieurs études ont démontré la sensibilité des spermatozoïdes au stress oxydant, il existe peu d'informations relatives à la vulnérabilité et la réponse des cellules germinales en développement à ce même stress. En outre, les mécanismes par lesquels le vieillissement peut altérer la qualité des cellules germinales restent irrésolus. Nos études se concentrent sur les antioxydants clés que sont la catalase (CAT) et la superoxyde dismutase 1 (SOD1). Cette thèse examine les effets du vieillissement sur : (i) les réponses spécifiques de cellules germinales mâles soumises à un stress oxydant et/ou à une supplémentation en agents antioxydants ; (ii) les conséquences de la surexpression de la catalase (MCAT) dans les cellules germinales mâles ; (iii) les conséquences d'une déficience en CAT et SOD1 dans les cellules germinales mâles.  Nos résultats indiquent que le vieillissement chez le rat mâle provoque un déclin prématuré de la viabilité des cellules germinales, une augmentation des dommages à l'ADN dans les spermatocytes, et une plus grande vulnérabilité au pro-oxydant SIN-1 contrecarrées par l'exposition à l'agent antioxydant EUK-134. A ces effets s'ajoutent la défaillance de l'équilibre redox dans les cellules germinales précoces, les spermatides rondes d'animaux âgés étant incapables de produire une réponse au stress oxydant. Nous avons par ailleurs observé que les souris MCAT âgées produisent des spermatozoïdes au même rythme que les souris jeunes et le même nombre de petits à un âge donné, et présentent moins de dommages à l'ADN spermatique. Enfin, si la déficience en SOD1 produit une défaillance de l'équilibre redox dans les cellules germinales âgées et des dommages à l'ADN spermatique indépendamment de l'âge, l'absence de CAT engendre une compensation par PRDX1 allégeant le stress oxydant et réduisant les dommages à l'ADN spermatique. Considérés dans leur ensemble, ces résultats permettent une meilleure compréhension du phénomène de vieillissement des cellules germinales mâles, et mettent en évidence l'intérêt des traitements antioxydants chez les hommes subfertiles et âgés souhaitant fonder une famille dont les spermatozoïdes présentent des dommages oxydatifs.  </description><description>For decades, it was considered that male germ cells, that are continuously produced, were impervious to the effects of aging. Today, it has become clear that advanced paternal age is associated with complications in pregnancy and genetic diseases in offspring. High metabolic activity in the testes results in elevated levels of reactive oxygen species (ROS) that can severely damage cells. Thus, a complex network of antioxidants function to regulate ROS within the testes. However, aging leads to elevated ROS and the deterioration of antioxidant defenses, which may compromise the quality of developing germ cells. Previous studies have shown that spermatozoa are highly susceptibility to oxidative damage, but less is known about the susceptibility of developing germ cells and their responses to oxidative stress. Furthermore, the effect of ROS and aging on the quality of germ cells remains unclear. Our studies focused on the key antioxidants, catalase (CAT) and superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1). This thesis examined the effects of aging: 1) on germ cell specific responses to oxidative insult and antioxidant supplementation; 2) the consequences of overexpressing catalase (MCAT) in male germ cells; 3) and the consequences of CAT or SOD1 depletion in male germ cells.  We found that germ cells from aged rats displayed a premature decline in viability, elevated ROS, increased spermatocyte DNA damage, increased susceptibility to pro-oxidant SIN-1, and were protected by antioxidant EUK-134. Aging resulted in redox dysfunction in early germ cells, with the round spermatids from aged animals being unable to mount a response to manage oxidative stress. We observed that aged MCAT mice generate sperm at the same rate as young mice, have no decrease in the age-dependent number of pups per litter, and that MCAT sperm had reduced oxidative stress associated damage. Finally, the loss of SOD1 with aging is shown to result in germ cell redox dysfunction, and DNA damage in spermatozoa regardless of age, while loss of CAT in germ cells results in compensation by PRDX1, alleviating oxidative stress and reducing the level of DNA damage in spermatozoa. Taken together, the findings of this thesis contribute to the basic understanding of aging in male germ cells, and highlight the potential role of antioxidant supplementation for sub-fertile men and aspiring aged fathers that have oxidative damage in their sperm.</description><creator>Selvaratnam, Johanna</creator><contributor>Bernard Robaire (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics</subject><title>Aging male germ cells: responses to oxidative stress &amp; the effects of altered antioxidant status</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859j278.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mf54t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397b921</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette dissertation est composée de trois études examinant trois différents aspects des systèmes de santé: l'assurance santé, la prise de décision des pharmaciens et patients ainsi que la prise de décision des médecins et patients. Le premier chapitre discute de comment la New Cooperative Medical Scheme (NCMS), l'assurance médicale des Chinois vivant dans la Chine rurale, varie entre comtés et à travers le temps. Je collecte des données détaillées à propos de l'assurance des Chinois ruraux et je contribue à la littérature portant sur l'évaluation de la NCMS en démontrant l'hétérogénéité de l'assurance. Le deuxième chapitre étudie comment la régularisation sur le comportement des pharmaciens affecte la demande du consommateur pour les médicaments de prescription génériques. Ce chapitre ajoute à la connaissance sur la façon de contrôler la croissance des dépenses pour les médicaments de prescription aux États-Unis. Le dernier chapitre analyse comment le comportement des médecins et des patients pourrait changer si l'information à propos de la qualité des médecins devenait plus précise. Ce chapitre fait la lumière sur si oui ou non, le programme de cartes concernant les qualités du médecin augmente le bien-être.</description><description>This dissertation is composed of three studies that examine three different aspects of the health care system: health insurance, pharmacist and patient decision making, and physician and patient decision making. The first chapter discusses how the designs of New Cooperative Medical Scheme (NCMS), the health insurance for rural residents in China, vary cross counties and over time. I collect first-hand data about the details of the insurance for rural Chinese and contribute to the literature of evaluating the NCMS by providing evidence of the heterogeneity of the insurance. The second chapter studies how the regulations on pharmacist's behavior affect consumer demand for generic prescription drugs. It contributes to our understanding of how to control the expenditure growth on prescription drugs in the United States. The last chapter analyzes how physician and patient's behavior change when information about physician quality becomes more precise. It contributes to our understanding of whether report card programs on physician qualities are necessarily welfare improving. </description><creator>Song, Yan</creator><contributor>Fabian Lange (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Economics</subject><title>Three essays in health economics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687k892.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397b921</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w502z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il semble exister, dans la manière d'interpréter la liberté spatiale, une opinion dominante qui accorde peu d'importance à la notion d'un bien commun qui rend cette liberté possible. La complexité de la chose vient du fait que la notion de bien commun est elle-même ambiguë en soi. Cependant, cet avis dominant voit le problème du partage du bien commun dans le contexte des tensions évidentes entre les grandes puissances spatiales, les états émergents, et l'idée que la liberté prend un sens particulier dépendamment du niveau de développement. L'idée générale ne tient pas compte du fait que les solutions aux soucis de gouvernance spatiale, qu'ils soient anciens ou récents ont été beaucoup moins garantes des intérêts des  petites nations, rendant la gestion des bénéfices accumulés totalement dépendante du libre arbitre de ces états capable d'effectuer de manière indépendante toute une panoplie d'activités spatiales. Par conséquent, à cause de cet état de fait, le débat autour du bien commun est soulevé de manière à rechercher un bénéfice personnel pour chaque nation au lieu de s'axer autour des résultats que peuvent avoir une utilisation collective de l'Espace. Ces derniers temps, la problématique a reçu peu d'attention. C'est parce que l'on croit qu'elle est partiellement résolue à travers des cadres normatifs tels que l'Article 1 du Traité de l'Espace et de la Déclaration des Avantages de l'Espace. Alors qu'une tentative de soulever à nouveau des problématiques associées à des contentieux historiques, censés être résolus, peut sembler illusoire ou futile, telle analyse peut être utile, selon le degré d'importance que le lecteur accorde à l'essence de la nature humaine. À cette fin, les écrits des théoriciens juridiques, politiques et sociales, ainsi que les méthodologies des écoles juridiques critiques peuvent s'avérer judicieux pour une conceptualisation plus profonde du débat historique, la compréhension actuelle des libertés spatiales, en plus de déterrer des perspectives futures afin d'aider à adresser la problématique actuelle et pressante reliée à l'espace : la pérennité des activités spatiales. À travers les lentilles de la nouvelle école de pensées que l'on appelle « Cosmopolitan Approaches to International Law » (CAIL), cette thèse propose des domaines à investiguer afin de trouver des solutions à certaines des tensions courantes perçues dans la gouvernance spatiale globale. </description><description>There appears to be a dominant position in interpreting the freedom of Outer Space which has not given much real significance to the idea of common benefit as that which enables this freedom.  The reason that this causes difficulty is that there is an ambiguity to the concept of common benefit. This dominant position, however, sees the issue of benefit-sharing in the context of the perceived tension between established space faring nations and emerging and aspirant States and the idea that freedom could take on a different meaning depending on where one is on the scale of development. It fails to recognize that solutions to contemporary and historical space governance challenges have been much less oriented towards the interests of less developed States or new entrants, making the accrual and sharing of benefits dependent on the free will of those States able to carry out a variety of space activities independently. As a result of this, the debate around common benefit is exploited to seek individual benefit derived for a State as opposed to what our effort to use space collectively can generate. In recent times, the issue has not received much attention. This is because it is believed to be partly resolved through normative frameworks such as Article 1 of the Outer Space Treaty and the Space Benefits Declaration. While an attempt to re-address historical contentious issues, asserted to be resolved, may appear illusory or futile; such analysis can be useful depending on the account that the reader believes should be given to the normative character of human nature. To this end, the writings of legal, political and social theorists and methodologies from Critical Legal Schools may prove insightful for a deeper contextualization of the historical debate, the current understanding of the freedoms of Outer Space as well as unearth future perspectives to aid in addressing the current pressing space related issue of our time: Sustainability of Space Activities. Through the lens of Cosmopolitan Approaches to International Law (CAIL), this thesis proposes to investigate some of the perceived tensions prevalent in global space governance. </description><creator>Aganaba, Timiebi</creator><contributor>Richard Janda (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Air and Space Law</subject><title>Cosmopolitan approaches to international law: finding the right lens to view the freedom of outer space</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr1720761.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w502z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v821m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The transitions between lactation and dry periods constitute a very critical phase in the reproduction cycle of dairy cows. After cessation of milking, the mammary gland is highly susceptible to new intra-mammary infections because of udder engorgement and milk leakage as well as a weakened immune system. In the absence of teat stimulation and udder emptying, the mammary gland regresses during a remodeling process known as involution. This physiological event involves a decrease in milk component synthesis and secretion by mammary epithelial cells, renewing of a portion of the mammary epithelium, activation of different proteases and an increase in the permeability of tight junctions linking epithelial cells together. However, exact elements triggering involution are not fully elucidated yet. Once mammary gland involution is completed, the udder is more resistant against bacterial infections. In addition, occurrence of involution is facilitated by the decrease in basal prolactin concentrations and in prolactin released during milking towards the end of lactation. Consequently, a strategy to improve cow's udder health would be to hasten the involution process by either increasing tight junction permeability or by decreasing the prolactinemic signal before drying-off. Another strategy to improve udder health around drying-off would be to increase lactation persistency by maintaining the prolactinemic signal over the course of lactation. In our first study, mammary gland involution was accelerated through the intra-mammary infusion of casein hydrolysates. These products of the natural degradation of caseins by plasmin during milk accumulation in the udder constitute a good candidate for triggering involution. In the second experiment, we shortened photoperiods or treated cows with melatonin aiming to reduce both prolactin concentrations and milk production before drying-off and to hasten involution. Only short day photoperiods slightly reduced milk production and tended to decrease milking-induced prolactin release but neither treatment affected the speed of the involution process. In the third experiment, the hypothesis that glucocorticoids participate in the regulation of the milking-induced prolactin release was tested in cows in mid-lactation. Glucocorticoid administration led to a depression in milk yield that was associated with a decrease in basal prolactin concentrations in both serum and milk and with a reduction in the milking-induced prolactin release. In summary, prolactin secretion could be maintained by glucocorticoid inhibitors during lactation and intra-mammary infusions of casein hydrolysates could be used to accelerate involution.</description><description>Les transitions entre periodes de lactation et de tarissement constituent des phases critiques dans le cycle reproducteur de la vache laitière. Après l'arrêt de la traite, la glande mammaire est fortement susceptible de contracter de nouvelles infections intra-mammaires en raison d'un engorgement du pis causant des fuites de lait et d'un affaiblissement du système immunitaire. En absence de stimulation du trayon et de vidange du lait, la glande mammaire régresse au cours d'un processus de renouvellement appelé involution. Ce processus physiologique engendre une diminution de la synthèse et de la sécretion des constituants du lait par les cellules épithéliales mammaires, un renouvellement d'une portion de l'épithélium mammaire, l'activation de différentes protéases et l'augmentation de la perméabilité des jonctions serrées liant les cellules épithéliales entre elles. Cependant, les éléments précis décléncheurs de l'involution ne sont pas encore complètement déterminés. Une fois l'involution terminée, la glande mammaire devient plus résistante face aux infections bactériennes. D'autre part, le déroulement de l'involution est facilité par la baisse des concentrations basales de prolactine et de la quantité de prolactine sécrétée lors de la traite à l'approche de la fin de la lactation. Par conséquent, une bonne stratégie pour améliorer la santé des vaches serait d'accélérer le processus d'involution soit en administrant des traitements susceptibles d'augmenter la perméabilité des jonctions serrées, soit en réduisant le signal prolactinémique avant tarissement. Une autre stratégie pour éviter les problèmes infectieux lors du tarissement serait d'accroître la persistence de la lactation en maintenant le signal prolactinémique au cours de la lactation. Dans notre première étude, l'involution de la glande mammaire a été accélérée grâce à des infusions intra-mammaires d'hydrolysats de caséine. Ces produits de la dégradation naturelle des caséines par la plasmine lors de l'accumulation du lait dans le pis constituent de bons candidats comme éléments déclencheurs de l'involution. Dans la seconde experience, nous avons réduit la photopériode ou traité les vaches avec de la mélatonine afin de diminuer à la fois les concentrations de prolactine et la production de lait avant le tarissement dans le but d'accélérer l'involution. Seule l'exposition à une photopériode de jours courts a légèrement réduit la production de lait et a eu une tendance à décroître la libération de prolactine induite par la traite, mais aucun traitement n'a affecté la vitesse de l'involution. Lors de la troisième expérience, l'hypothèse que les glucocorticoides participent à réguler la libération de prolactine induite par la traite a été testée chez des vaches en milieu de lactation. L'administration de glucocorticoides a engendré une baisse de la production laitière, celle-ci ayant été associée à une diminution des concentrations basales de prolactine dans le sérum et le lait ainsi qu'à une réduction de la sécretion de prolactine lors de la traite. En conclusion, la secretion de prolactine pourrait être maintenue par des inhibiteurs des glucocorticoides lors de la lactation et des infusions intra-mammaires d'hydrolysats de caséine pourraient être utilisées pour accélérer l'involution.</description><creator>Ponchon, Benjamin</creator><contributor>Xin Zhao (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Animal Science</subject><title>Evaluation of various strategies to accelerate mammary gland involution at drying-off and study of the prolactin secretion regulation by glucocorticoids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913s484.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v821m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05ff56g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le sucre issu de la sève de l'Arenga pinnata est consommé par la population Indonésienne depuis des décennies.  À Tomohon en Indonésie, le sucre est produit par méthode traditionnelle suivant les connaissances locales utilisant peu de moyens. Cette étude s'est intéressée à développer des connaissances sur les paramètres du procédé transformant la sève d'Arenga pinnata en sucre, et ce afin d'améliorer les pratiques existantes et améliorer la qualité du sucre ainsi produit, et effectuer la caractérisation du sucre pour aider les producteurs à forger une place de choix pour leur sucre sur les marchés. La première étude  s'est concentrée sur les changements de propriétés de la sève d'Arenga pinnata, suivant sa récolte, en particulier les changements de pH, de sucre inverti et de couleur.  Avec une augmentation du temps, le pH de la sève diminuait et le sucre inverti augmentait.  Les mesures de couleurs basées sur CIELAB (espace couleur L*a*b*) ont indiqué que le changement de pH de la sève s'est enligné avec des changements des valeurs L* et b*.  La transformation de la sève en sucre, par évaporation de l'eau,  a été le sujet de la seconde étude.  Des transformations des caractéristiques physico-chimiques lors du procédé thermique ont été observées avec l'évolution de la température, du pH et des solides solubles totaux (TSS).  Le pH a augmenté au début du procédé thermique pour atteindre son maximum au point d'ébullition, pour ensuite diminuer jusqu'à la fin du procédé.  La température finale de la sève concentrée était d'environ 127°C correspondant à des TSS de plus de 93% (%w/w) et des valeurs de pH proches du pH initial de la sève fraîche. La couleur a changé de façon significative durant le procédé de transformation pour la production de sucre, de la sève, à sa transformation en un sirop épais, jusqu'à la production d'un sucre solide ou le procédé de brassage menant à la formation de sucre granulé.   Les paramètres CIELAB (espace couleur L*a*b*) et les différents qualificatifs couleurs qui en découlent, nommément la différence de couleur (ΔE*), l'angle hue (h), la chromacité (C*) et le ratio a*/b* ont été déterminés.  En fonction du temps, la sève chauffée est devenue plus foncée (diminution de L*), plus rouge (augmentation de a*), et plus jaune (augmentation de b*).  Pendant le brassage du sirop, le sucre est devenu plus pâle (augmentation de L*), plus rouge (augmentation de a*), et plus jaune (augmentation de b*).  La couleur du sucre solide était significativement différente de la couleur du sucre granulé (ΔE*), alors que les deux sucres peuvent être qualifiés être de couleur rouge-orange  à jaune-orange (h) avec plus de jaune (selon le ratio a*/b*) et d'apparence colorée (C*). La dernière étude a examiné les caractéristiques physico-chimiques du sucre granulé d'Arenga pinnata. Le sucre possède des caractéristiques uniques avec un pH moyen de 6.285, un contenu en TSS de 93.4%, de 2.98% en sucre inverti, de couleur jaune (de par son h et son ratio a*/b*) et une propriété nutritionelle de par son contenu élevé en composés phénoliques totaux (2432 μg/g GAE), et un potentiel antioxydant de 0.6 mg/ml (IC50) déterminé par son activité phagocyte de radicaux libres.  L'analyse FTIR (spectrométrie infrarouge par transformée de Fourier) du sucre d'Arenga pinnata a confirmé que le sucrose était le sucre principalement présent, alors que la tendance des granules à s'agglomérer a été déterminée par imagerie par microscopie à balayage électronique.Cette étude contribuera à améliorer les pratiques existantes et utilisées par les populations locales en comprenant mieux les paramètres de qualité qui régissent la transformation de la sève fraîche en sucre.  Les résultats de cette étude serviront à paver l'avenir de la recherche sur la production de sucre issu de la sève d'Arenga pinnata tout en aidant les producteurs à développer de meilleures ouvertures sur les marchés pour leur sucre.</description><description>Arenga pinnata sugar has been consumed by the local people of Indonesia for decades. In Tomohon, Indonesia, the sugar has been processed following the indigenous knowledge which consists of minimal process parameters. This study has focused on developing knowledge on the process parameters involved in producing Arenga pinnata sugar from the sap, which is needed to improve existing process techniques to enhance the quality of produced sugar, and on the characterization of the sugar which will help the farmers to gain a better market positioning for their sugar. The first study investigated the changes in Arenga pinnata sap, as a raw material, following the harvesting identified by pH, invert sugar and colour changes. As the time increased, the pH of the sap decreased and the invert sugar increased. Colour measurements following CIELAB (L*a*b* colour space) indicated that the change in pH of the sap is more associated with L* and b* values. Processing the sap into sugar, by the removal of water through boiling, was carried out in the second study. Physical and chemical transformations involved during the heating process of Arenga pinnata sap into sugar were observed by their changes in temperature, pH and Total Soluble Solids (TSS). The pH increased in the beginning of the heating process until it reached a peak at the boiling point, followed by a continuous decrease to the end of the heating process. The final temperature of the concentrated sap was about 127oC corresponding to a TSS of more than 93 (% w/w) and pH values close to the initial pH of the fresh sap. The colour changed significantly during the process steps involved in sugar processing, i.e., from the heating of the sap until it became a thick syrup, to the production of solid sugar, and the stirring process of the thickened syrup to form granulated sugar. CIELAB (L*a*b* colour space), and several colour determinations, namely total colour difference (ΔE*), hue angle (h), chroma (C*) and a*/b* ratio were determined in the study. As a function of time, the sap became darker (L*decreased), more red (a* increased), and more yellow (b* increased) during the heating process. During the stirring process the sugar became lighter (L* increased), more red (a* increased), and more yellow (b* increased). The colour of the solid sugar was significantly different than the colour of the granulated sugar (by ΔE*), nonetheless both sugars can be categorized as having red-orange to yellow-orange colour (by h) with more yellow (by a*/b* ratio) and colourful appearance (by C*).The final study examined the physico-chemical attributes of granulated Arenga pinnata sugar. The sugar showed unique characteristics with an average pH of 6.285, 93.4% total sugar content, 2.98% invert sugar, yellow in colour, and nutritional properties with a high total phenolic compounds content (2432 µg/g of GAE), and antioxidant potential identified by free radical scavenging activity (IC50) of 0.6 mg/ml. The Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR) spectra of the sugar confirmed that sucrose was the main sugar in Arenga pinnata sugar, and the tendency of the granules to clump together was identified using scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images. This study contributes to improving the existing practices applied by indigenous people through better understanding of the important quality parameters involved during processing of the fresh sap into sugar. The findings from this work not only will serve as a base for future studies on Arenga pinnata sugar production, but also help the farmers to develop a better market for their sugar.</description><creator>Victor, Inneke</creator><contributor>Valerie Orsat (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>Processing of «Arenga pinnata» (palm) sugar</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g273s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05ff56g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77ss54f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>By taking it out of its biological role, DNA has served as a robust, reliable and programmable nanofabrication building block for the assembly of a variety of two- and three-dimensional discrete nanometer-sized structures with arbitrary shapes and designs. These molecularly addressable materials could serve as platforms for the site-specific hybridization with nanometer precision. Besides structural complexity, DNA objects evolved to comprise an intrinsic dynamic character allowing them to respond to surrounding stimuli in a predictable manner. Many researchers have previously constructed nanostructures using methods that rely on the spontaneous assembly of DNA in solution, in which case the more complex the assembly design is, the more error-prone the product becomes. This constitutes a major problem for the application of DNA-based structures in dynamic devices such as machines, motors, robots, and computers, where even small errors in assembly can drastically affect performance. Therefore, quantitative tools for analysing structures and dynamics of complex DNA nanostructures are critical. Single molecule fluorescence techniques have been transformative to the field of nanoscience and have played a leading role in providing a mature understanding and an informative feedback on the building blocks and final products of self-assembly. This thesis demonstrates how different single molecule fluorescence methodologies can be utilized to study and advance the structure, dynamics and integrity of DNA-assemblies, specifically those shaped as nanotubes. Conceptually, this research can be divided into four main parts: (i) synthesis optimization, (ii) structural characterization, (iii) monitoring dynamic structures, and (iv) studying structural dynamics. First, a solid-phase synthesis strategy and its visualization through single-molecule spectroscopy was devised to assemble DNA nanotubes in a stepwise fashion, with a full control over their size and sequence pattern. This method paves the way for the production of custom-made DNA nanotubes with fewer structural flaws than the spontaneous-assembly method. Second, single molecule photobleaching and two-color colocalization approaches were uniquely combined to provide a systematic way of assessing the polydispersity, stoichiometry and degree of defectiveness of different DNA nanotubes structures. These approaches will be of significant importance for many research groups synthesizing large supramolecular structures or studying naturally occurring ones, such as protein clusters, amyloids, etc. Third, in situ single molecule immobilization-based fluorescence microscopy was employed to introduce structural changes into DNA nanotubes by dynamically adjusting one or several of the edge lengths between the building blocks using a combination of strand displacement and loops. This is interesting for sensing applications, especially when the analyte produces large scale, detectable structural changes, and also for creating molecular muscles, capable of extension and contraction under external control. Lastly, dynamics and robustness of DNA nanotubes, reconfigured in response to site-specific deletion of DNA strands, were investigated using two color single molecule microscopy. This strategy enables to develop a better understanding of the collective structural changes within DNA structures in response to modifications in their repeat unit. Together, the different methods developed in this thesis underline the importance of single molecule techniques as powerful tools which can advance the field of DNA nanotechnology by enabling the production of well-defined high-quality objects that can meet the designer's compositional and dynamic specifications.</description><description>Au-delà de son rôle biologique, l'ADN a servi comme un matériau de nanofabrication robuste, fiable, et programmable pour l'assemblage d'une variété de structures nanométriques, adoptant des formes arbitraires en deux et en trois dimensions. Ces nanostructures adressables au niveau moléculaire, pourraient servir comme des plates-formes d'hybridation site-spécifique, précise à l'échelle nanométrique. De nombreux chercheurs ont déjà construit des nanostructures en utilisant des méthodes qui reposent sur l'assemblage spontané des brins d'ADN en solution, durant lequel des erreurs pourraient se produire surtout dans des modèles de plus en plus complexes. Ceci constitue un problème majeur pour l'application des structures à base d'ADN dans des dispositifs dynamiques tels que des machines, des moteurs, des robots et des ordinateurs, où même des erreurs minimes d'assemblage peuvent considérablement affecter la performance du dispositif. Par conséquent, le développement d'outils quantitatifs dans le but d'analyser les structures et la dynamique des objets d'ADN complexes est essentiel. La technique de microscopie de fluorescence de molécules uniques a joué un rôle principal dans la transformation du domaine de la nanoscience en fournissant une compréhension mature etinformative des différents matériaux de nanofabrication et des produits finaux de l'autoassemblage.Cette thèse démontre la façon dont différentes méthodologies simplifiées de fluorescence de molécules uniques peuvent être utilisées pour étudier et développer la structure, la dynamique et l'intégrité des assemblages d'ADN, en particulier ceux en forme de nanotubes. Conceptuellement, cette recherche peut être divisée en quatre parties principales: (i) l'optimisation de la synthèse, (ii) la caractérisation structurale, (iii) la surveillance des structures dynamiques et (iv) la dynamique structurelle. En premier lieu, une stratégie de synthèse enphase solide et sa visualisation par microscopie de molécules uniques a été conçue pour assembler des nanotubes d'ADN de manière progressive, avec un contrôle total sur leur taille et leur séquence modèle. Cette méthode va permettre la production de nanotubes d'ADN faits sur mesure ayant l'avantage de présenter des défauts structurels minimes comparativement à ceux résultants de la méthode d'assemblage spontané en solution. En deuxième lieu, une technique de microscopie de fluorescence qui utilise le photoblanchiment de molécules uniques, a été combiné avec une méthode de colocalisation de deux couleurs, fournissant une façon systématique pour évaluer la polydispersité et la stoechiométrie de différents nanotubes d'ADN. En troisième lieu, un protocole in situ utilisant la microscopie de fluorescence à base d'immobilisation de molécules uniques a été utilisé pour introduire des changements structurels dans les nanotubes d'ADN. Dans ce but, une combinaison de déplacement de brin d'ADN et de boucles d'ADN a été adoptée afin d'ajuster de façon dynamique une ou plusieurs des longueurs d'arêtes entre les différents blocs. Cette approche est intéressante pour les applications de détection, en particulier lorsque les analytes génèrent des changements structurels détectables et à large échelle. Enfin, la dynamique et la fidélité de la structure des nanotubes d'ADN, reconfigurés suite à la délétion site-spécifique de brins d'ADN, ont été étudiées à l'aide de la microscopie de fluorescence de molécules uniques à deux couleurs. Cette stratégie permet d'acquérir une meilleure compréhension des changements structurels collectifs au sein des nanostructures d'ADN en réponse à des modifications dans leur unité de répétition. Collectivement, les différents procédés développés dans cette thèse soulignent l'importancedes techniques de microscopie de fluorescence de molécules uniques comme outils puissantsqui pourraient être exploités afin de progresser le domaine de la nanotechnologie de l'ADN.  </description><creator>Hariri, Amani</creator><contributor>Gonzalo Cosa (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Hanadi Sleiman (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Advancing DNA nanotechnology using single molecule fluorescence methodologies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tb992.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77ss54f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g2742</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Accumulated plaque in the carotid artery can be either stable or unstable. In the latter case, pieces from the plaque may break off and travel to the brain, potentially blocking blood flow and causing a stroke. The assessment of plaque stability is usually done visually based on its ultrasound image. Recently, Computer Aided Diagnostics (CAD) tools have been proposed to support clinical decisions that use machine learning techniques to analyze carotid plaque ultrasound images, and classify plaques as stable or unstable. Previous work has used supervised or unsupervised learning methods for this task, with the Support Vector Machine (SVM) being one of the most widely used supervised classifiers. However, only limited labelled data is available for training since the "gold standard" for plaque characterization as stable or unstable is to perform biopsy after endarterectomy. On the other hand, unlabelled data are readily available. A further complication arises from the fact that there is an imbalance in class labels (in our case stable or unstable), with data labelled as unstable dominating the training data set. The objective of this thesis is to investigate whether the use of unlabelled data in a semi-supervised algorithm can lead to better classification accuracy than that from a purely supervised classifier. To that end, we propose to use the 2ν-SVM classifier (a version of the SVM which efficiently handles cases with imbalance in the class labels) in the Branch-and-Bound (BB) implementation of a semi-supervised SVM. We investigate the performance of the proposed method on both synthetic data, specifically the popular 2-Moon data set, and on carotid plaque ultrasound images, where amongst the set of labelled plaque images there is at least twice as much unstable plaques than stable plaques. For the 2-Moon data with class imbalance in the labelled data set, the use of 2ν-SVM with a semi-supervised algorithm yielded an improved classification result over the same semi-supervised algorithm in combination with the generic SVM, and also over pure supervised SVM classifiers. In the case of carotid plaque images, for which the training data was composed of 18 labelled (6 stable, 12 unstable) and 18 unlabelled images - the results were inconclusive. A highest classification accuracy of 70.11% was achieved with both a supervised 2ν-SVM, and the BB (semi-supervised) algorithm that used the 2ν-SVM as a classifying component. The plain SVM, either when used as a purely supervised classifier, or as part of the BB algorithm, yielded lower classification accuracy, proving that the 2ν-SVM better handles cases when the labelled training data contains imbalanced numbers of class labels.</description><description>La plaque accumulée dans l'artère carotide peut être stable ou instable.  Dans ce dernier cas, des fragments de plaque peuvent se déloger et s'emboliser au cerveau, potentiellement bloquant des vaisseaux sanguins et causant un accident vasculaire cérébral. L'évaluation de la stabilité de la plaque est habituellement effectuée de façon visuelle à partir d'images échographiques.  Récemment, des outils diagnostiques assistés par ordinateur (DA), utilisant des techniques d'apprentissage automatique qui analysent les images échographiques de la plaque carotide et la classifie comme stable on instable, ont été proposés afin de guider la conduite clinique.  Les travaux antérieurs dans ce domaine sont basés sur des méthodes d'apprentissage supervisés ou non-supervisés, notamment la méthode par Machine à Vecteur de Support (MVS), qui est une méthode de classification supervisée des plus répandue. Malheureusement, dans le cas de la plaque dans l'artère carotide, seulement un ensemble limité de données est disponible pour l'apprentissage car la norme pour la classification de la plaque est d'effectuer une biopsie suite à un endartériectomie.  Par contre, des données non-classifiées sont disponible en grand nombre.  Une autre difficulté provient du fait que l'ensemble des données d'apprentissage comporte un déséquilibre dans le nombre d'éléments de chaque étiquette (dans ce cas stable ou instable), avec un nombre plus grand d'éléments étiquetés comme instable.L'objectif de ce mémoire est de déterminer si l'utilisation de données non-étiquetés dans un algorithme de classification semi-dirigé peut conduire à une classification plus exacte qu'un algorithme de classification dirigée pure.  À cette fin, nous proposons l'utilisation d'un algorithme de classification 2ν-MVS (une variante de la méthode par MVS qui prend en charge un déséquilibre dans le nombre d'éléments de chaque étiquette) dans l'implantation des graphiques binaires de la MVS semi-dirigé.  Nous étudions le rendement de la méthode proposée sur deux ensembles de données synthétiques; l'ensemble commun « 2-Moon » et un ensemble d'images échographiques de plaque de l'artère carotide.  Ces deux ensembles sont caractérisés par un déséquilibre de deux fois plus de plaque instable que de plaque stable. Les résultats démontrent que pour l'ensemble 2-Moon avec déséquilibre, l'utilisation de l'algorithme de classification 2ν-MVS semi-dirigé résulte en une amélioration de l'exactitude de la classification lorsque comparé avec le même algorithme de classification semi-dirigé combiné avec l'algorithme de classification générique MVS et l'algorithme de classification dirigé MVS pure.  Dans le cas des images de plaque carotide, dont les données contiennent 18 images d'apprentissage étiquetées (dont 6 stables et 12 instables) et 18 images non-étiquetées, les résultats ont été non-concluant.  Une exactitude de classification de 70.11% a été obtenue avec l'algorithme dirigé 2v-MVS, et avec l'algorithme utilisant des graphiques binaires (semi-dirigé) et 2v-MVS comme composante de classification.  L'algorithme MVS, utilisé soit comme méthode de classification pure ou comme composante de l'algorithme de graphes binaires, résulte en une exactitude de classification moindre; ce qui démontre que l'algorithme 2v-MVS prend mieux en charge les cas où l'ensemble des données d'apprentissage comporte un déséquilibre dans le nombre d'éléments de chaque étiquette.</description><creator>Watfa, Mahmoud</creator><contributor>Ioannis Psaromiligkos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>2v-SVM-based semi-supervised learning with application to carotid plaque characterization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm870.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g2742</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h2171</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While pain management is typically assessed as a decrease in pain intensity, this does not necessarily relate to perceptions of pain relief. Relief is an inherently pleasurable and rewarding experience, and is the pleasurable, affective opponent to pain; indeed pain and pleasure are thought to lie on an affective spectrum that may be mediated by the opioid system. Activation of the opioid system, for example by morphine, enhances responses to pleasurable stimuli and decreases pain responses. Similarly, endogenous, or naturally occurring, opioid peptides are released following pain and pleasure. However, it is unknown to what extent opioids mediate the interaction of pain and pleasure or even determine how an individual perceives these processes separately. Therefore, the purpose of this thesis was to investigate the role of endogenous opioids in mediating individual perceptions of pain, pleasure, and the interaction between these processes. In the first experiment, described in Chapters 2 and 3, obese individuals were used as a model of a dysfunctional opioid system to investigate whether an over-active opioid system affected pain and pleasure responses. Obese patients have higher circulating levels of endogenous opioid peptides, which has been associated with decreased pain perception in this group. In Chapter 2, it was demonstrated that obese participants do have decreased pain perception, but this was limited to areas with excess adipose tissue, suggesting that higher circulating levels of endogenous opioids likely do not contribute to this phenomenon. Indeed in Chapter 3, we show that basal levels of endogenous opioids did not relate to pain or pleasure responses in either obese or non-obese participants. However, blockade of endogenous opioids with the antagonist, naltrexone, increased pain and decreased pleasure, but again these responses did not differ between obese and non-obese groups. This indicates that opioids do contribute to pain and pleasure, but this effect is not changed by altered activity of the opioid system in obesity. Finally, naltrexone-induced changes in pain and pleasure were correlated, suggesting that pain and pleasure do form an opioid-mediated affective spectrum. While basal endogenous opioids did not correlate with brief pain responses in obese and non-obese participants, Chapter 4 demonstrates that basal opioids do determine pain sensitivity during ongoing painful stimulation. Interestingly, higher basal opioids correlated with increased ongoing pain sensitivity. Basal opioid levels may be an indicator of endogenous opioid tone; therefore, individuals with lower basal opioids are able to mount a response during pain to decrease perception, but individuals with higher basal opioids are not able to mount the same response and thus show higher pain perception. Finally, the influence of opioids on pain-pleasure interactions was demonstrated by decreased subjective perceptions of relief following opioid blockade. Using an experimental model of pain relief in which pain perception was constant between placebo and naltrexone sessions, blocking opioids with naltrexone decreased subjective ratings of relief and relief pleasure. This finding has important implications for chronic pain patients who show altered reward processing. Because relief is rewarding, these deficits may extend to pain relief and could result in decreased analgesic efficacy in chronic pain patients.</description><description>L'efficacité de la gestion de la douleur est habituellement mesurée par une diminution de l'intensité douloureuse, mais celle-ci ne correspond pas toujours au ressenti du soulagement de la douleur. Le soulagement est une sensation plaisante, à l'opposé affectif de la douleur. La douleur et le plaisir sont deux extrêmes d'un même continuum affectif, médié par le système opioïdergique. Les opioïdes endogènes sont libérés lors d'une expérience douloureuse ou plaisante. Cependant, l'étendue de l'influence des opioïdes sur l'interaction entre la douleur et le plaisir n'est pas connue, ni même si ces deux processus sont perçus comme distincts ou non. L'objectif de cette thèse est d'étudier le rôle joué par les opioïdes endogènes dans la relation entre la perception de la douleur et du plaisir, ainsi que dans l'interaction entre ces deux processus. Nous avons étudié si un système opioïdergique hyperactif affecte les réponses douloureuses ou plaisantes avec comme modèle d'un système opioïdergique dysfonctionnel des individus obèses. Les patients obèses ont un niveau de peptides opioïdes endogènes circulant plus élevé, associé à une diminution de la perception de la douleur. Nous avons démontré que les participants obèses ont une perception de la douleur diminuée, se limitant aux régions qui ont un excès de tissu adipeux. Ceci suggère qu'un niveau d'opioïdes endogènes plus élevé ne contribue pas à la diminution de perception de la douleur. Nous avons démontré que le niveau basal d'opioïdes endogènes n'est pas corrélé avec la réponse à la douleur ou au plaisir, que les participants soient obèses ou non. Pourtant, le blocage des récepteurs opioïdes avec l'antagoniste Naltrexone entraîne une augmentation de la perception douloureuse et une diminution de la sensation de plaisir, de façon similaire chez les participants obèses ou non-obèses. Ceci indique que les opioïdes contribuent à la douleur et au plaisir, sans que cette fonction soit affectée chez les participants obèses dont le système opioïde est altéré. Enfin, les changements de perception douloureuse et de plaisir induits par la Naltrexone sont corrélés, ce qui suggère que la douleur et le plaisir font partie d'un même continuum affectif, médié par les opioïdes. Alors que nous avons montré que le niveau basal d'opioïdes ne corrèle pas avec les réponses douloureuses brèves chez les participants obèses et non-obèses, je décrit que le niveau basal d'opioïdes détermine la sensibilité à la douleur lors de stimulations douloureuse prolongées. Il est intéressant de noter qu'un niveau basal d'opioïdes élevé corrèle avec la sensibilité à des stimulations douloureuse prolongées. Le niveau basal d'opioïde semble être un indicateur du tonus d'opioïde endogène: les individus qui ont un niveau basal faible seraient capables d'augmenter leur niveau d'opioïdes en réponse à la douleur, permettant une diminution de la perception douloureuse, mais les individus qui ont un niveau basal élevé ne seraient pas capables d'avoir la même réponse du système opioïde et éprouvent donc une perception de la douleur plus élevée. Pour conclure, nous avons démontré l'influence des opioïdes sur l'interaction douleur-plaisir par une diminution de la perception subjective de soulagement lors du blocage du système opioïde. En utilisant un modèle expérimental de soulagement de la douleur pour lequel la perception de la douleur était similaire dans la session placébo et Naltrexone, nous avons démontré que le blocage du système opioïde avec la Naltrexone diminue la sensation subjective de soulagement et l'aspect plaisant du soulagement. Ces résultats sont importants pour les patients qui souffrent de douleur chronique car ils ont un système de récompense altéré. Le soulagement de la douleur provoquant des sensations plaisantes similaires à une récompense, ce déficit pourrait être impliqué dans la diminution de l'efficacité de l'analgésie chez les patients qui souffrent de douleur chronique. </description><creator>Price, Rebecca</creator><contributor>Petra Schweinhardt (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>The role of endogenous opioids in pain, pleasure, and pain-pleasure interactions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xv51t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h2171</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jp174</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les tourbières ne recouvrent que 3% de la surface de la planète. Toutefois, elles stockent jusqu'à 30% du carbone (C) contenu dans le sol globalement. Cela suggère que le stockage de C et l'importance écologique des tourbières sont proportionnellement beaucoup plus élevés que leur étendue pourrait suggérer. Les microorganismes supportent la décomposition de la matière organique et, donc, C et la mobilisation des éléments nutritifs. Toutefois les contrôles de l'activité microbienne restent mal connus. L'objectif général de cette thèse est d'élucider le rôle microbien dans la décomposition de la matière organique dans les tourbières tempérées. J'ai exploré les contrôles microbien-écologiques et ceux du substrat, avec un accent particulier sur l'activité enzymatique extracellulaire, sous la variabilité naturelle du climat et l'augmentation de la déposition de nutriments.Le carbone organique dissous (COD) sert de nombreuses fonctions écologiques et chimiques, y compris celle de substrat microbien. Grâce à des expériences de laboratoire, la concentration, la biodégradabilité et les propriétés intrinsèques du COD lessivé de la tourbe, des matériaux frais, et la litière ont été caractérisés pour neuf espèces de végétation de tourbières ombrotrophes. La concentration initiale de COD et la fraction de COD biodégradable différaient significativement entre les espèces et étaient significativement plus élevées dans les matériaux frais que dans la litière ou la tourbe. Les espèces et le degré de décomposition de la matière organique d'origine sont des contrôles importants de la qualité du substrat microbien.Les travaux de laboratoires et de terrain ont déterminé que la température et le pH sont les contrôles environnementaux communs des mécanismes enzymatiques pour quatre types de tourbières biogeochimiquement différentes. Cependant, certains facteurs spécifiques au site tels que la disponibilité des nutriments conduisent à des écarts par rapport à ces modèles. Dans l'ensemble, l'activité enzymatique diminue de façon significative avec la profondeur et démontre une variation significative au cours de la saison de croissance. Le minimum d'activité est au printemps et le maximum en été et en automne ce qui souligne la vulnérabilité du sol des tourbières stock de C organique au réchauffement climatique anthropique.L'analyse en laboratoire des échantillons provenant d'une expérience de fertilisation à l'azote (N), au phosphore (P) et au potassium (K) à long terme (9-14 ans) a révélée des changements significatifs par rapport aux contrôles dans la tourbe, la stœchiométrie des matières dissoutes nutritives et l'activité extracellulaire enzymatique. Les résultats suggèrent des réponses simultanées et de lutte contre la fertilisation des éléments nutritifs à long terme soulignant des interactions complexes entre la végétation de surface, les microbes et la disponibilité des nutriments. En particulier, la N-inhibition de l'activité phénol-oxydase peut partiellement compenser l'effet d'amélioration de la qualité du substrat microbien sur C et la mobilisation des éléments nutritifs.La recherche dans cette thèse contribue une nouvelle compréhension des contrôles sur la décomposition microbienne de la matière organique et, finalement, la production de gaz à effet de serre et l'exportation de COD dans les tourbières du nord. Ce travail montre également que les relations microbien-écologiques sont complexes et que les facteurs propres au site posent des problèmes pour leur intégration dans les modèles écologiques.</description><description>Peatlands only cover ~3% of the globe's terrestrial and fresh water surface and yet they store up to 30% of the global soil carbon (C). As such, the C storage and ecological importance of peatlands are proportionally much greater than their area might suggest. Microorganisms drive organic matter decomposition, and thus C and nutrient mobilization, though the controls on microbial activity remain poorly understood. The overall objective of this thesis was to elucidate the microbial role in organic matter decomposition in temperate peatlands. I explored substrate and microbial-ecological controls, with particular emphasis on extracellular enzyme activity, under both natural climate variability and increased nutrient deposition.Dissolved organic carbon (DOC) serves numerous ecological and chemical functions including acting as a microbial substrate. Through laboratory experiments, the concentration, biodegradability, and intrinsic properties of DOC leached from peat, fresh material, and litter from nine species of ombrotrophic bog vegetation were characterized. Initial DOC concentration and the fraction of biodegradable DOC differed significantly among species and were significantly higher in fresh material than either litter or peat extracts. Vegetation species and degree of decomposition of the parent organic matter are significant controls on microbial substrate quality.Through laboratory and field measurements, temperature and pH were determined to be the common environmental controls on the enzyme-latch mechanism across four biogeochemically different peatland types though site-specific factors such as nutrient availability led to deviations from these patterns. Overall, enzyme activity decreased significantly with depth and showed significant variation over the course of the growing season with a minimum in the spring and a maximum in the summer and fall highlighting the vulnerability of the peatland soil organic C stock to anthropogenic climate warming.Laboratory analysis of samples from a long-term fertilization experiment found significant changes in peat and dissolved matter nutrient stoichiometry and extracellular enzyme activity relative to control following 9 – 14 years of nitrogen (N), phosphorus (P), and potassium (K) fertilization. Results suggest concurrent and counteracting responses to long-term nutrient fertilization with complex interactions among surface vegetation, microbes, and nutrient availability. In particular, the N-inhibition of phenol oxidase activity may partially counteract the effect of enhanced microbial substrate quality on C and nutrient mobilization.Research in this thesis contributes new understanding of the controls on microbial decomposition of organic matter, and ultimately greenhouse gas production and DOC export, in northern peatlands. This work, however, also shows that microbial-ecological relationships are complex and site-specific factors pose problems for incorporating them in ecological models.</description><creator>Pinsonneault, Andrew</creator><contributor>Nigel Thomas Roulet (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Timothy R Moore (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Geography</subject><title>Substrate and enzymatic controls on temperate peatland carbon cycling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hz19n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jp174</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w0325724</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les facteurs de transcription « cap'n'collar » (CNC) à motif basique et à glissière à leucines jouent un rôle crucial dans l'expression des gènes chez les mammifères, la réponse au stress et le cancer. Le membre de la famille CNC découvert le plus récemment, NFE2L3 (Nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 3), aussi appelé NRF3, est impliqué dans la carcinogenèse, la réponse au stress oxydatif, l'inflammation et le développement cellulaire. Cependant, les aspects structurels de cette protéine et les mécanismes de régulation de celle-ci sont encore mal compris. Cette thèse met en évidence le mécanisme d'import nucléaire de NFE2L3 et donne des indices sur la régulation de cette protéine au sein de la cellule. Elle révèle également deux nouveaux régulateurs de ce facteur de transcription.NFE2L3 est une protéine complexe avec une répartition très stricte entre trois compartiments cellulaires. NFE2L3 existe sous trois différentes formes (A, B et C). La transformation de la forme nucléaire «C » et son mécanisme d'import nucléaire sont des éléments clés dans la régulation et l'activité transcriptionnelle de NFE2L3. Nous montrons que la forme « C » de NFE2L3 est une version clivée de la protéine au niveau N-terminal. Nous démontrons que NFE2L3 contient un signal monopartite de localisation cellulaire (NLS : « nuclear localisation signal »), qui régule l'importation de ce facteur de transcription dans le noyau. Le signal d'export nucléaire riche en leucine (NES : « nuclear export signal ») identifié au niveau N-terminal de la protéine ne joue aucun rôle dans la régulation de NFE2L3 car il est clivé pendant la transformation de la forme nucléaire « C ». Des analyses d'immunofluorescence et d'immunoblot ont révélé que la forme sauvage de NFE2L3 est localisée à la fois dans le noyau et le cytoplasme tandis que la forme mutée n'ayant plus de NLS fonctionnel est incapable de s'accumuler dans le noyau. Nous montrons que l'importine-beta 1 lie la séquence NLS de NFE2L3 et médie son import nucléaire. L'importine n'a jamais été capable de lier le mutant de NFE2L3 sans NLS fonctionnel. Ce mutant affiche également une diminution de l'activité du promoteur du gène de l'hème oxygénase 1 (HMOX1) en aval. Ces résultats démontrent l'importance de la séquence NLS dans l'import nucléaire et la capacité de transactivation de NFE2L3. Le taux de renouvellement de NFE2L3 est très rapide comparé à celui d'autres protéines cellulaires. NFE2L3 est stabilisé avec des inhibiteurs du protéasome tels que MG-132, la beta-lactacystine et l'epoxomycine. Pour la première fois, nous démontrons la poly-ubiquitination de NFE2L3 à la fois par les chaines d'ubiquitine K48 et K63. Il est intéressant de noter que l'E3 ligase FBW7 régule également la dégradation de NFE2L3 via l'ubiquitination. FBW7 se lie physiquement à NFE2L3 et favorise la poly-ubiquitination. Nous avons identifié un phénomène intéressant, où la dimérisation de FBW7 était absolument nécessaire à l'ubiquitination de NFE2L3 et donc à sa dégradation. Nous prévoyons l'existence de nombreux motifs sur NFE2L3 permettant l'attachement de FBW7 via sa dimérisation. L'expression de FBW7 réduit de manière significative la répression de NQO1 dépendante de NFE2L3, une enzyme de détoxification jouant un rôle vital dans la chimio-protection et le cancer.Nous avons aussi montré que l'expression de NFE2L3 est négativement régulée par la glycogène synthase kinase 3 (GSK3) d'une manière dépendante de FBW7. Nous montrons que GSK3 est capable d'interagir avec NFE2L3 et le phosphoryler. Nous  avons montré que la forme NFE2L3 ubiquitinée est stabilisée lorsque l'expression de GSK3 et de FBW7 est diminuée en même temps. Finalement, la dégradation de NFE2L3 par FBW7 est restituée en diminuant le taux de GSK3, confirmant que GSK3 est requis pour la régulation de NFE2L3 médiée par FBW7.</description><description>Cap 'n' Collar (CNC) basic leucine zipper transcription factors play crucial roles in mammalian gene expression, stress and cancer. The most recently discovered CNC family member, NFE2L3 (Nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 3), also referred to as NRF3, has emergent roles in carcinogenesis, oxidative stress response, inflammation and cell differentiation. This thesis unveils the nuclear import mechanism of NFE2L3 and its processing within the cell. The report also reveals two novel regulators of this transcription factor. NFE2L3 is a complex protein with a highly stringent distribution between three cellular compartments. NFE2L3 exists in three different forms (A in the ER, B in the cytosol and C in the nucleus). We show that the nuclear 'C' form of NFE2L3 is an N-terminally cleaved version of the protein. We demonstrate that NFE2L3 contains a C-terminal monopartite nuclear localization signal (NLS), which facilitates NFE2L3 import into the nucleus. We also show that importin beta-1 binds to the NLS of NFE2L3 and mediates its nuclear import. The NFE2L3 mutant also displayed diminished promoter activity of ARE-driven Heme oxygenase 1 (HMOX1) gene. These results signify the importance of the NLS in NFE2L3 nuclear import and transactivation capacity. NFE2L3 has a very rapid turnover when compared to other cellular proteins. NFE2L3 is also stabilized upon treatment with proteasome inhibitors, MG-132, beta-lactacystin and epoxomycin. For the first time, we demonstrate polyubiquitination of NFE2L3. FBW7 E3 ligase regulates NFE2L3 via ubiquitination-mediated degradation. FBW7 physically binds to NFE2L3 and promotes poly-ubiquitination. We also identified an interesting phenomenon, where FBW7 dimerization was required for NFE2L3 ubiquitination and subsequent degradation. We predict that there are multiple motifs on NFE2L3 that FBW7 binds to via dimerization. FBW7 expression significantly reduced NFE2L3-dependent repression of NQO1, a well-known detoxification that plays a vital role in chemoprotection and cancer. We report that NFE2L3 expression is negatively regulated by glycogen synthase kinase 3 (GSK3) in an Fbw7-dependent manner. We show that GSK3 interacts with and phosphorylates NFE2L3. Degradation of NFE2L3 through FBW7 depend on GSK-3 mediated phosphorylation of NFE2L3. NFE2L3 is stringently regulated in the cell by complex intracellular compartmentalization and post-translational modifications like glycosylation and ubiquitination. It is a transcription factor that has not yet been studied in detail; however, its roles in various aspects of human diseases are about to be unveiled in the near future. Here we report our findings that shed light on the structure and function of this rather intriguing protein. </description><creator>Kannan, Meenakshi</creator><contributor>Volker Manfred Blank (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Intracellular trafficking and regulation of the NFE2L3 transcription factor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827f256.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w0325724</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60d025t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse concerne l'intersection de la théorie de réseau alimentaire et de recherche en espèces envahissantes. L'omnivorie, définie à plusieurs niveaux trophiques, se trouve dans une multitude de réseaux alimentaires terrestre, marin et d'eau douce, en raison de la capacité de l'omnivore de réduire le maximum et le minimum des tailles de population du consommateur qu'il consomme et les ressources dont il et le consommateur se nourrissent. Tandis que les recherches empiriques et théoriques ont déterminé que l'omnivorie dans les réseaux alimentaires indigènes sont stabilisantes, si cette stabilité est conférée par l'introduction d'un omnivore reste inconnue. Dans cette thèse, j'utilise une combinaison de méthodes, incluant des méta-analyses, des expériences et de la théorie, pour illustrer l'impacte d'omnivores introduits et leurs effets sur la stabilité, (i.e. la persistance du réseau alimentaire), est une fonction de la force de l'interaction. Les méta-analyses, qui ont combiné plusieurs études d'invertébrés aquatiques introduits, ont révélé que quand on compare l'impact des omnivores introduits avec les prédateurs sur la communauté récipiendaire, l'impact est plus grand quand les omnivores sont introduits. De plus, l'impact sur le consommateur dans la communauté récipiendaire est relié à la force de l'interaction de l'espèce envahissante. L'espèce avec les plus fortes réponses fonctionnelles avait des plus grands impacts sur les consommateurs dans les communautés récipiendaires. Dans le laboratoire, j'ai reproduit un réseau alimentaire avec une introduction d'un omnivore pour quantifier le taux de croissance du consommateur sous différents modules de réseau alimentaire incluant l'omnivorie. En utilisant des ratios de ARN:ADN, j'ai déterminé qu'au cour d'un expérience de 24 heurs, le taux de croissance et sa variance étaient les plus élevés dans le réseau alimentaire omnivore. Les analyses des différences de taux de croissance et sa variation à travers les modules de réseau alimentaire ont démontré que les différences individuelles dans le taux de croissance du consommateur peuvent contribuer à la stabilité des réseaux alimentaires avec l'omnivore en réduisant les forces de l'interaction entre le prédateur et les consommateurs. Finalement, j'ai utilisé une méthodologie de modélisation pour analyser comment la force d'interaction dans la communauté récipiendaire interagit avec la force de l'omnivorie pour déterminer les conséquences de l'introduction de l'omnivore. Le modèle a révélé que l'introduction d'un omnivore peut augmenter la persistance d'un réseau alimentaire quand les fortes interactions de consommateur-ressource pourraient autrement le pousser à l'extinction. En général ma thèse révèle que les conséquences de l'introduction d'omnivores dépendent sur les forces d'interactions – non seulement les nouvelles interactions formées entre l'omnivore et la communauté récipiendaire mais aussi les forces d'interaction existantes dans cette communauté. </description><description>This thesis concerns the intersection of food web theory and invasive species research. Omnivory defined as feeding at multiple trophic levels occurs in a plethora of terrestrial, marine and freshwater food webs, owing to the capacity of the omnivore to reduce the maximum and minimum population sizes of the consumer that it feeds on and the resource that both it and the consumer feed on. While both empirical and theoretical pursuits have determined that omnivory in native food webs is stabilizing, whether this stability is conferred by introduced omnivores remains unknown. In this thesis I use a combination of meta-analyses, experiments and theoretical approaches to illustrate that the impact of introduced omnivores and their effect on stability (i.e. persistence of the food web) is a function of interaction strength. The meta-analyses, which coalesced several introduced aquatic invertebrates studies, revealed that when comparing the impact between introduced omnivores and predators on recipient consumers, the impact is greater when omnivores are introduced. Further, the impact on the consumer in the recipient community is related to the interaction strength of the introduced species. Species with stronger functional responses had greater impacts on consumers in recipient communities. In the laboratory, I reproduced a food web subject to the introduction of an omnivore to quantify the growth rate of the consumer under different food web modules including omnivory. By using RNA:DNA ratios I determined that over the course of a 24-hour experiment growth rate and variation in growth rate was highest in the omnivory food web. Analyses of differences in growth rates and its variation across food web modules revealed that individual differences in consumer growth rates might be contributing to stability in food webs with omnivory by decreasing interaction strengths between predator and consumers. Finally, I used a modeling approach to analyze how interaction strength within the recipient community interacts with the strength of omnivory to determine the consequences of the introduction of the omnivore. The model revealed that the introduction of an omnivore could increase the persistence of a food web when strong consumer-resource interactions would otherwise drive it to extinction. Overall my thesis reveals the consequences of the introduction of omnivores depend on interaction strengths – not only the novel interactions formed between the omnivore and the recipient community but also the existing interaction strengths within that community.</description><creator>Granados, Monica</creator><contributor>Gregor Fussmann (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Biology</subject><title>Interaction strength and the consequences of non-native omnivory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204175k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d025t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956j55p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le trouble de dépression majeur (TDM) touche entre 6,4 et 10,1 % de la population. Malgré sa prévalence et son lourd bilan, notre compréhension de sa pathophysiologie demeure insuffisante. Plusieurs molécules ont été mises en avant comme biomarqueurs potentiels, sans toutefois permettre l'identification d'un seul biomarqueur validé. Les antidépresseurs (AD) représentent le traitement le plus commun pour le TDM, mais environ un tiers des patients ne répondra pas de façon adéquate après plusieurs tentatives de traitement. De ce fait, il existe un grand besoin non seulement d'identifier des biomarqueurs du TDM, mais aussi d'identifier des marqueurs de prédiction ou de suivi de la réponse au traitement. Les gènes individuels et les réseaux biologiques sont régulés par l'activité de microARNs (miARNs) qui peuvent moduler l'expression des gènes subtilement ou peuvent être des déterminants d'activation ou d'inactivation des gènes. Les miARNs présentent une possibilité prometteuse comme biomarqueurs de maladies et de réponse aux traitements. Plusieurs sources de données soutiennent cette idée en indiquant que les miARNs pourraient être impliqués dans la pathogénèse des désordres neuropsychiatriques. Cette thèse de doctorat se concentre sur des études menées sur des échantillons de cerveaux humains post-mortem, de sang issu d'essais cliniques de patients en dépression ou de modèles animaux de dépression, sur des essais cellulaires et des analyses informatiques qui soutiennent le potentiel important des miARNs comme biomarqueurs pour le TDM et la réponse au traitement par AD. Nos résultats présentent d'importantes avancées dans le développement d'outils de diagnostic précoces, de stratégies préventives et de traitements pharmacologiques efficaces pour les troubles de l'humeur.</description><description>Major depressive disorder (MDD) affects between 6.4 and 10.1% of the population and despite its prevalence and considerable burden, our understanding of its pathophysiology remains rudimentary. Several molecules reported to be dysregulated in MDD have been suggested as potential biomarkers, however, a validated biomarker has yet to be identified. Antidepressants (ADs) are the most common treatment for MDD, yet roughly one third of patients experience an inadequate response to treatment after several attempts. Thus, there is a great need for not only identifying biomarkers of MDD but also those that can predict and/or monitor response to treatment. Individual genes and biological networks are regulated through the activity of microRNAs (miRNAs), which act as fine-tuners and on-off switches of gene expression. As such, miRNAs offer great hope as biomarkers of disease and response to treatment. This is supported by several lines of evidence suggesting that miRNAs could be involved in the pathogenesis of neuropsychiatric disorders. This doctoral thesis focuses on experiments performed in postmortem human brains, blood samples from clinical trials of depressed patients, animal models of depression, cellular assays, and computational analyses that support the role of miRNAs as promising biomarkers of MDD and AD response. Our results provide important steps in the development of early diagnostic tools, preventive strategies, and effective pharmacological treatment for mood disorders.</description><creator>Lopez Buitrago, Juan Pablo</creator><contributor>Gustavo Turecki (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Human Genetics</subject><title>The role of microRNA in major depression and antidepressant treatment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72pb00b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956j55p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634632j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:44:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La croissance et la survie des bactéries sont directement liées à leurs capacités à se nourrir et à se défendre. Cela implique une interaction efficace entre l'organisme et l'environnement. Leur enveloppe complexe est la clé de cette interaction intime qui a permis aux bactéries de s'adapter avec succès à une variété de niches écologiques. L'objectif de ma thèse était d'étudier les mécanismes de transport des protéines membranaires par microscopie électronique et particules isolées (SP-EM). Pour cela, j'ai choisi d'étudier un transporteur ATP-dépendant (MalFGK2), un prototype AB-toxines (Anthrax) et un transporteur impliqué dans la  multi-résistance médicamenteuse (TriABC). 1) Le transporteur du maltose MalFGK2, un prototype de transporteur (ABC) ATP-dépendantMalFGK2 est un importateur de maltose d'E. Coli. Au cours du transport, le domaine membranaire de MalFG s'ouvre soit vers l'intérieur de la cellule soit vers son extérieur en réponse la fixation de l'ATP et à son hydrolyse. Le transport nécessite une protéine périplasmique MalE. Dans la littérature, les rôles distincts du nucléotide, MalE et du maltose dans le cycle de la catalyse n'étaient pas clairs. Nos résultats en SP-EM présentent les premières structures de MalFGK2 lié à divers nucléotides en l'absence de MalE ainsi que la première structure de MalFGK2-MalE en l'absence de nucléotides et de maltose. Nous avons démontré que l'ATP et MalE jouent un rôle essentiel, distinct et complémentaire, pour alimenter le cycle du transport du maltose. Il indique également que le maltose influence sur la conformation du transporteur. 2) Les toxines de l'anthrax, le meilleur prototype caractérisé de la famille des AB-toxines (ou toxines binaires)  Les toxines AB de Bacillus anthracis sont composées de l'antigène protecteur (PA) et deux protéines: le facteur de l'œdème (EF) et le facteur létal (LF). PA s'organise en un heptamère ou octamère qui se transforme en un pore permettant à EF et LF d'entrer dans la cellule. Nos résultats nous permettent de proposer un modèle selon lequel l'arrangement moléculaire des 3 LFs et leurs interactions les uns avec les autres, ainsi que le décalage de symétrie entre les 3 molécules de LF et le complexe PA heptamérique, définit l'ordre de translocation et jouent un rôle important pour maintenir l'efficacité de la translocation indépendamment de la concentration de LF. 3) La pompe à efflux du triclosan TriABC, un modèle de transporteur causant une multi-résistance médicamenteuseTriABC est un complexe exprimé par Pseudomonas aeruginosa lui permettant  d'expulser le triclosan et le SDS. Il comprend une pompe (TriC) et deux protéines de fusion de la membrane : TriA et TriB. Notre analyse d'images nous a permis de distinguer TriA, TriB et TriC dans le complexe assemblé. Cela était inconnu jusqu'à lors. De plus, nos résultats préliminaires par microscopie électronique à froid (cryo-EM)  nous permettent de distinguer les différents domaines de TriC incluant la poche d'entrée du SDS/triclosan. Approfondir l'analyse d'image devrait permettre de comprendre comment TriA/TriB stimule le transporter au niveau moléculaire.Dans l'ensemble, l'étude de ces trois systèmes contribue à la compréhension du fonctionnement bactérien du transport membranaire. Cette compréhension structurelle permet le développement de nouvelles stratégies pour les applications médicales. En effet, les toxines AB sont capables de la translocation de grosses molécules (90 kDa dans le cas de la maladie du charbon) en utilisant la voie de l'endocytose. La reprogrammation de ces toxines peut être utilisée pour l'introduction de grosses molécules dans la cellule dans le cadre de thérapies médicamenteuses. Les transporteurs ABC sont conservés depuis le règne bactérien jusqu'aux eucaryotes. De nombreux homologues sont impliqués dans les maladies humaines telles que le diabète. Enfin, les pompes à efflux sont les principales cibles des antibiotiques.</description><description>Bacteria growth and survival is directly linked to its ability to nourish itself and defend itself. It implies a reliable interplay between the organism and the environment. Their complex envelope is the key of this intimate interaction that allowed bacteria to successfully adapt to a variety of ecological niches. Crossing-over cell membranes implicate transporters, channels, receptors or toxins for infection. The objective of my thesis was to study transport mechanisms of membrane proteins using single particle electron microscopy (SP-EM). During my PhD project, I studied an ATP-Binding Cassette transporter (MalFGK2), an AB-toxin (anthrax toxins) and a Multidrug Resistance transporter (TriABC). 1) The maltose transporter MalFGK2, a prototype of ATP-Binding Cassette transporter (ABC) MalFGK2 is an E. Coli maltose importer. For transport, the MalFG membrane domain alternates between inward and outward facing conformations in response to ATP binding and hydrolysis. The transport requires the periplasmic protein MalE. In the literature, the distinct role of the nucleotide, MalE and the maltose in the catalysis cycle was not clear. Using single particle electron microscopy, we analyzed the conformations taken by MalFGK2 in 10 different biochemical conditions. Our results present the first structures of MalFGK2 bound to various nucleotides in the absence of MalE as well as the first structure of MalFGK2-MalE in the absence of nucleotides and maltose. We demonstrated that ATP and MalE play essential, distinct and complementary roles in powering the maltose transport cycle and that the maltose substrate influences the conformation of the transporter. 2) Anthrax toxins, the best characterized prototype of the family of AB-toxins (or binary toxins) The AB toxins from B. Anthracis are composed of the Protective Antigen (PA) and two proteins Edema Factor (EF) and the Lethal Factor (LF). PA organizes itself in a heptamer or octamer complex that converts into a pore allowing EF and LF to enter the cell. Our studies focused on the assembly of PAs and LFs and the initiation of translocation. We calculated the 3DEM map of the fully loaded (PA)7(LF)3 "prepore" complex by cryo-Electron Microscopy (cryo-EM). We propose that the molecular arrangement of LFs with PAs and the LF-LF interactions specify the order of translocation and play an important role to maintain translocation efficient independently of the concentration of LF. 3) The triclosan effux pump TriABC, a model of Multidrug Resistance transporter (MDR)TriABC is a complex expressed by Pseudomonas aeruginosa expel triclosan and SDS out of the cell. It comprises a pump (TriC) located in the inner membrane and two membrane fusion proteins (TriA and TriB) located in the periplasmic space. However, how exactly TriA and TriB assemble with TriC remained unknown. We analyzed the TriC and TriABC complexes by negative staining. We showed that TriC alone is very flexible with an open and closed pore. The addition of TriAB stabilizes the complex in an open pore conformation. Our preliminary cryo-EM map of TriABC allows distinguishing the different domains of TriC including the SDS/triclosan entry pocket as well as TriA/TriB. Further image analysis should make possible to understand how TriA/TriB stimulates the transporter at the molecular level. Overall, the study of these three systems contributes in the understanding of bacterial membrane transport functioning. This structural comprehension allows developing of new strategies for medical applications. Indeed, AB toxins are able to translocate big molecules (90 kDa in the case of anthrax) by using the endocytosis pathway. Reprogramming of these toxins can be used for entry of big molecules into cell for drug therapy. ABC transporters are conserved from the bacterial reign to the eukaryote cells. Many homologues are implicated in human diseases like diabetes. Efflux pumps are major targets for antibiotics.</description><creator>Fabre, Lucien</creator><contributor>Isabelle Rouiller (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Anatomy and Cell Biology</subject><title>Study of bacterial transport membrane proteins by single particle electron microscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xm34j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634632j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):7175</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>