<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:56:11Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):1375" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s690f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phase morphology of injection moulded blends of polypropylene (PP) and ethylene vinyl alcohol copolymer (EVOH) changes dramatically throughout the sample and especially across the sample thickness. In particular, the development of a laminar structure was evaluated by image analysis of scanning electron micrographs. The results indicate that a laminar morphology is most likely to develop in the shear zone, as maxima in particle size and aspect ratio are observed in directions parallel and transverse to flow in this region of the sample. This laminar structure is more pronounced at high concentrations of the EVOH minor phase, and at low maleation levels of the matrix resin, as well as for low mould thickness. The influence of processing conditions such as injection speed, mould and melt temperatures appears to be small. Intensive preblending of the components in a twin screw extruder hinders the development of the laminar structure. Toluene permeability measurements show that the presence of a laminar phase morphology in injection moulded samples contributes to substantial improvements of barrier characteristics of the materials. However, impact tests indicate that there is need to optimize the conditions employed in producing the laminar morphology without deterioration of mechanical properties.</description><creator>Walling, Nadja</creator><contributor>Kamal, M. R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Plastics Technology.</subject><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Phase morphology and properties of injection moulded polypropylene-ethylene vinyl alcohol copolymer blends</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qr62s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s690f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634578z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Optics is receiving increasing attention as an attractive technology to implement high performance backplanes. The growth in the fields of digital telecommunications and parallel computing is demanding backplanes with ever-increasing interconnection densities and data transfer rates (2, 5). As a possible solution to the limitations of electrical backplanes (9), research into free-space photonic backplanes is underway at McGill University (1). The field of research into photonic backplane architectures is new and relatively small amounts of literature are available on the subject. Hence, the research effort at McGill represents one of the first architectural level studies in the field of free-space photonic backplanes. As part of the research program underway at McGill, a photonic backplane architecture has been proposed (27) and is currently under construction (1). Due to the novelty of the backplane architecture there was a need for a preliminary investigation into its feasibility and capabilities. A large analytic performance model which could analyze the numerous architectural variations of the backplane has been developed (25). In this thesis a software tool, based on the analytic model in (25), has been developed for broad design space explorations of the backplane architecture. The modelling approach is general and can be extended to the analysis of arbitrary networks and backplane architectures. However, this thesis will focus on the design space exploration of internally nonblocking ATM switches on various backplane architectures. Throughout the thesis, the synchrononous smart pixel array design from June 1994 will be assumed.</description><creator>Verghese, Manoj</creator><contributor>Szymanski, Ted (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A software based design space exploration of a free-space photonic backplane</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj68d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634578z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k06989583</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The generation of spectrally pure analog sinewave with predictable characteristics is an important issue of mixed-signal testing. Digital frequency synthesizers exhibit many good features but current implementations are area expensive. This dissertation will study a novel digital frequency synthesizer approach based on digital resonators and delta-sigma modulation. Except for a 1-bit digital-to-analog converter, the analog signal generator implementation is entirely digital allowing precise control over the amplitude and frequency of oscillation. It may therefore be tested using digital methods, making this signal generator attractive for analog built-in self-test (BIST) implementations. Furthermore, this signal generation method is area efficient as it does not require a ROM or a multiplier. However the presence of a delta-sigma modulator in a feedback loop make these circuits non-linear. The limitations of the linear model will therefore be addressed. We envision that this signal generator can be used in communication or for analog testing. One such application, wireless communication system BIST will be presented.</description><creator>Veillette, Benoît R.</creator><contributor>Roberts, Gordon W. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A study of delta-sigma oscillator circuits</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289m044.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k06989583</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892c98z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The continuous heating to fracture test (CHF) developed at McGill was used to study the effect of decarburization on the incipient melting temperature. In the CHF test, a sample was deformed at a constant true strain rate, while its temperature is increased at a constant rate. This test allows the incipient melting temperature to be determined using a single test, instead of the several required by isothermal tensile testing. An isothermal decarburization step, to create a decarburized layer at the surface of the sample, was added prior to the CHF test. Analysis of the true stress vs temperature curves obtained by CHF testing allows the incipient melting temperature to be determined. Optical metallography was used to determine the effect of decarburization time on the observed depth of decarburization. The heat transfer characteristics of induction heating were studied, since this heating technique is known to create a significant temperature gradient at the surface of the piece being heated. Since the decarburized layer is in the high temperature zone, and also has a higher melting point due to its lower carbon content, it plays an important role in the melting process. A phenomenological model was derived to describe the melting process. It allows for both the temperature gradient due to induction heating and the melting point gradient due to decarburization. The hypothesis is advanced that melting takes place at the position, within the sample, where the temperature profile crosses the incipient melting temperature gradient. From this study, it appears that decarburization acts so as to limit the risk of hot shortness on a workpiece being forged at high temperatures. This is because decarburization raises the IMT, and in this way widens the temperature window of optimum workability.</description><creator>Trudel, Alain</creator><contributor>Jonas, John J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Effects of decarburization on the incipient melting temperature of AISI 4140 steel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd90k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c98z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472z46h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Jameson cell is a relatively new flotation device that has been successfully used in several applications, ranging from mineral recovery to de-oiling dairy effluents. The cell comprises a plunging jet bubble column (downcomer) which discharges in a separation tank. The effect of operating variables on Jameson cell performance, e.g., gas holdup in the downcomer and interaction between the downcomer and separation tank, was investigated in this thesis. Gas holdup in the downcomer of the Jameson cell was determined using conductivity measurements with ring-shaped electrodes installed in the interior wall of the downcomer. The Maxwell model was used to calculate the gas holdup from the conductivity measurements. In both two-phase and three-phase tests, the conductivity signal was also shown to be able to detect process disturbances (e.g., changes in flow regime). Interaction between the downcomer and the separation tank was studied by altering the level in the separation tank. When gas flowrate was not controlled, the level affected the gas flowrate, pressure, pool level/free jet length, mixing zone length, and gas holdup in the downcomer. A pressure technique was used to determine the mixing zone length. The effect of the superficial gas velocity on the froth/pulp interface position in the separation tank was also studied. Although no relationship could be drawn between gas flowrate and separation tank level, froth flooding or loss of froth interface was observed at a superficial gas rate (with respect to the separation tank) $ ge$1.2 cm/s.</description><creator>Summers, Allen James</creator><contributor>Finch, J. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>A study of the operating variables of the Jameson cell</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pj421.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z46h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3013447</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A numerical study is carried out to predict 3-D fluid flow and heat transfer of confined turbulent single and twin slot jets in the presence of a crossflow. The low Reynolds number k-$ sigma$ turbulence (Launder and Sharma (17)) model was used to calculate the Reynolds stress and the turbulent heat flux. In the present work the following cases were studied: (1) Case I considers an impingement surface heated by a single turbulent slot jet. (2) Case II considers an impingement surface cooled by twin turbulent slot jets. In the latter case the buoyancy effect has been taken into consideration through Boussinesq approximation. In each case, the velocity vector field for the entire calculation domain and the heat transfer rate on the impingement surface are presented. The parameters studied include: the jet Reynolds number, confinement-to-impingement surface spacing, and crossflow-to-jet velocity ratio. In case II, an additional parameter representing the jet-to-jet spacing was also investigated. In both cases, the impingement surfaces was assumed to be at a constant temperature. The flow field results were found to be in qualitative agreement with most of the past related experimental work. In case I, the average Nusselt numbers were compared with those obtained from Martin's (3) correlation. A good agreement was found in the range of validity of this correlation (low crossflow).</description><creator>Ragel, Kamal R.</creator><contributor>Hasan, M. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>A numerical study of 3D turbulent flow and heat transfer of confined slot jets in a crossflow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m539.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3013447</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956h970</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Changes in the secondary structure and aggregation of concanavalin A (Con A) were investigated by differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) and Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy. The secondary structure of Con A has been shown to be affected by factors such as temperature, pH, ionic strength, pressure and the presence of sugars. DSC studies indicated that the thermal stability of Con A is enhanced in the presence of salts, sugars and by pH. Detailed examination of the conformation-sensitive amide I band in the FTIR spectrum of Con A revealed that concentration, sugars, metal ions and pressure (range from 0-14.4 kbar) had no effect on the structural conformation of Con A at room temperature. Variable-temperature FTIR studies of the thermal stability of Con A as a function of pH showed that maximum thermal stability is achieved under alkaline conditions (pH 8-10). It was also found that sugars enhanced the thermal stability of Con A to varying degrees and that the stabilizing effect of the sugar was not dependent on the sugar binding specificity of the lectin.</description><creator>Zhao, Yue</creator><contributor>Ismail, A. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Plant lectins -- Analysis.</subject><title>Variable-temperature Fourier transform infrared investigation of the secondary structure of Concanavalin A</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd579.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h970</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tx206</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Instruction scheduling and register allocation play very important roles in compilation techniques for high-performance computers. In this thesis we study different analyses and transformations that may affect the performance of instruction scheduling and register allocation. An important technique for increasing code parallelism is alias analysis. Alias analysis can reduce the number of dependences in a Data Dependence Graph (DDG) by disambiguating address references. Our study shows that points-to analysis, the alias analysis method implemented in the McCAT compiler, can substantially increase parallelism in benchmarks with indirect memory references. In this thesis we also discuss the phase ordering problem of instruction scheduling and register allocation. An integrated approach--IPS (Integrated Prepass Scheduling) is implemented in the McCAT compiler. Experimental results show that IPS is an effective way to coordinate instruction scheduling and register allocation. Postpass scheduling and BDSF (Branch Delay Slots Filling) has been also implemented. Experiments were performed to measure the effectiveness of each scheduling method and combinations of the scheduling methods. These experiments show that IPS + postpass + BDSF is the best approach for the benchmarks studied.</description><creator>Zhang, Yingwei</creator><contributor>Hendren, Laurie (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Instruction scheduling and register allocation for the MCCAT</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827d72c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tx206</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d208b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ornithine decarboxylase (ODC) is the rate determining enzyme in the biosynthesis of polyamines which are essential for cell growth. In chickens, significantly higher bioactivity is reported in broiler than in egg layer strains of chickens (Bulfield et al., 1988). To characterize the genetic differences in growth rates and ODC levels in chickens, an ODC cDNA and genomic gene were cloned and sequenced. Sequencing of ODC cDNA revealed that this clone (pODZ3: 2,052 bp) was not a full length of ODC cDNA and contained 2 putative introns. The open reading frame (introns deleted) coded for a protein of 404 amino acids which had about 85% amino acid identity with human ODC. Sequencing of genomic ODC clone (pODG2-8: 5098 bp) represented the 3$ prime$ end of ODC gene from downstream of intron 7. Northern blotting of chicken RNA probed with the insert of pODZ3 revealed 2 hybridizable messages of 1.6 and 2.1 kb, respectively. In addition, analysis of MspI restriction fragment length polymorphism (RFLP) using the 3$ prime$ end of ODC gene as a probe suggested that two MspI RFLPs present in the lean line of broiler chickens was related to selection of high lean body mass.</description><creator>Zhang, Ling, 1962-</creator><contributor>Zadworny, David (advisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Cloning.</subject><subject>Chickens -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Molecular cloning.</subject><subject>Chickens -- Genetic engineering.</subject><title>Molecular cloning and characterization of the chicken ornithine decarboxylase gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397b319.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d208b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fd91v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alzheimer's dementia (AD) is a degenerative neurological disorder involving predominantly the central cholinergic neurons but also other neurotransmitter systems. Over the last decade, several investigators have reported the presence of AD-related peripheral manifestations many of which involving cholinergic and adrenergic markers in non-neuronal tissues such as platelets, fibroblasts, lymphocytes and others. However, since these are unrelated to structures innervated by the peripheral nervous system, it is difficult to comment on their possible pathological as well as functional implications in the process of the disease. The aim of the present study was to evaluate possible AD-related dysfunctions in peripheral tissues known to be innervated by anatomical structures located outside the CNS. Cholinergic as well as adrenergic receptors density and affinity were evaluated in pial vessels obtained post-mortem from 8 confirmed cases of AD and 8 elderly non-demented controls. In addition, direct and axonal reflex sweating responses elicited by local iontophoretic application of acetylcholine were evaluated in 30 probable AD patients, 30 elderly and 30 young controls. There was a significant (p $&lt;$ 0.05) 43% reduction in total muscarinic binding sites in AD pial vessels as compared to control vessels. When the binding assays were performed in the presence of 75 nM pirenzepine (in order to block muscarinic binding sites with high affinity to pirenzepine), there was still a significant (p $&lt;$ 0.05) 40% diminution in the labelled sites compared to control vessels. The population of $ alpha$1-adenergic binding sites was also significantly reduced (35%: p $&lt;$ 0.05) in AD vessels. In all cases, affinity of the cerebrovascular receptors was comparable in AD and control vessels. On the other hand, ChAT activity (used as an index of cerebrovascular cholinergic innervation) determined in human pial vessels showed a non-significant 25% reduction in AD compared to control pial membranes. Similarly, $ beta$-adrenergic binding site density was unaltered in AD vessels. Functional evaluation of the sweating response in AD patients and related controls showed that the nicotinic receptor mediated axonal reflex sweating response was significantly reduced in AD patients as compared to young controls and elderly controls (44% and 40% respectively, p $&lt;$ 0.05). In contrast, the slight diminution observed in direct sweat response (mediated by muscarinic receptors) between AD patients, elderly and young controls was not statistically significant. In view of the reported distribution of muscarinic and adrenergic receptors in the pial vessel wall, the reduction in total and subtype specific muscarinic binding sites as well as the drop in $ alpha$1-adrenoceptors may argue in favour of a degenerative process at the level of the blood vessel wall itself. Such conclusions would agree with the relatively preserved cholinergic innervation suggesting spared cerebrovascular innervation. In contrast, the significant reduction in axonal reflex sweat response observed in AD, is strongly suggestive of a peripheral degenerative process involving post-ganglionic sympathetic neurons to sweat glands. The detected changes are suggestive of a further decrement of autonomic control in AD different from what have been observed in normal aging. These changes may contribute to the deterioration of the brain perfusion and autonomic functions regulation in AD.</description><creator>Zamar, Nadim Y.</creator><contributor>Hamel, Edith (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Kravitz, Elliot (advisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Sudomotor activity and cerebrovascular cholinergic and adrenergic binding sites in aging and Alzheimer's dementia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r309c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fd91v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h689</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rats are nocturnal animals, their ingestive behaviours show circadian rhythms and the suprachiasmatic nuclei (SCN) of the hypothalamus are the primary pacemaker of these rhythms. Serotonin (5-HT) is one of the most abundant neurotransmitter in the SCN and it is involved in the regulation of ingestive behaviour. In this study, we compared food and water intakes of male adult Wistar rats infused during 7 days with serotonin (2.5 nmol/24h) or artificial cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) in the SCN in a three-way selection of macronutrients. Within 5-HT infusion, nocturnal and diurnal water intakes, and the nocturnal caloric intake from the protein diet were significantly lower than those of the CSF infused group. Decrease in water consumption was most significant in the early and middle dark phases. Besides, increased diurnal energy intake and decreased nocturnal energy intake were observed during 5-HT and CSF infusion. In conclusion, this first chronic and continuous infusion work on 5-HT in the SCN specifically disrupted the circadian rhythmicities in water and protein consumptions.</description><creator>Wong, Chi Yan.</creator><contributor>Thibault, Louise (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Serotonin -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Ingestion -- Regulation.</subject><subject>Rats -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Circadian rhythms.</subject><title>Circadian rhythms of the specific appetites in rats centrally infused with serotonin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw64f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h689</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v983j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Five allelic, maternal-effect mutations which affect developmental and behavioral timing in Caenorhabditis elegans have been identified. They result in a mean lengthening of embryonic and post-embryonic development, the cell cycle period, and life span, as well as the periods of the defecation, swimming, and pumping cycles. These mutants also display a number of additional phenotypes related to timing. For example, the variability in the length of embryonic development is several times larger in the mutants than in the wild-type, resulting in the occasional production of mutant embryos developing more rapidly than the most rapidly-developing wild-type embryos. In addition, the duration of embryonic development and the length of the defecation cycle of the mutants, but not of the wild-type, depends on the temperature at which their parents were raised. Finally, individual variations in the severity of distinct mutant phenotypes are correlated in a counter-intuitive way. For example, the animals with the shortest embryonic development have the longest defecation cycle and those with the longest embryonic development have the shortest defecation cycle. Most of the features affected by these mutations are believed to be controlled by biological clocks, and we therefore call the gene defined by these mutations clk-1, for "abnormal function of biological clocks".</description><creator>Wong, Anne</creator><contributor>Hekimi, Siegfried (advisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biological rhythms</subject><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Genetics</subject><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Longevity.</subject><title>Mutations in the clk-1 gene of Caenorhabditis elegans affect developmental and behavioural timing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw59j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v983j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mk98w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Wilms' tumor suppressor gene, WT1, encodes a zinc finger protein thought to be involved in transcriptional regulation. It has been shown in a yeast two-hybrid system that wt1 can form homodimers. In this study, random mutations that abrogate this interaction in yeast were generated and characterized as a preliminary means of defining the amino acid residues required for wt1 homodimerization. Five types of mutations were identified: mutations that alter the 5$ prime$ Untranslated Region (UTR), and silent, frameshift, nonsense and missense mutations. Further examination of the position and effect of the frameshift, nonsense and missense mutations suggested the amino terminus, specifically exons 1 and 2, as the region of the protein required for homodimerization. It is hoped that a better understanding of the wt1-wt1 interaction may shed light on the role of this protein in normal kidney development and tumorigenesis.</description><creator>Winnett, Elaine</creator><contributor>Pelletier, J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Structure-function analysis of the WT1 tumor supressor gene product</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw57r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk98w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z306s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The response of soil arylsulfatase enzymes to natural and artificial substrates was evaluated. An immobilized arylsulfatase reactor was used to hydrolyse ester sulfate compounds in two soils with different morphological properties and management schemes. Hydrolysable ester sulfates cleaved by the immobilized arylsulfatase reactor constituted 35 to 55% of the HI-reducible S in these soils. Naturally occurring low molecular weight (LMW) ester sulfate compounds were found to accumulate in soil and persist during storage. These compounds were examined as the naturally occurring substrate for soil arylsulfatase enzymes. Arylsulfatase activity was evaluated using artificial (p-nitrophenol sulfate) and natural (LMW ester sulfates) substrates. The response of arylsulfatase activity in soil and humic-arylsulfatase complexes to p-nitrophenol sulfate did not reflect the ability of these complexes to hydrolyse natural soil substrates. A preliminary experiment was conducted to examine arylsulfatase activity and soil sulfur in relation to sulfur in plant tissue and grain from wheat. Tissue sulfur was more strongly associated with soil sulfur than wheat grain.</description><creator>Whalen, Joann</creator><contributor>Mehuys, G. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Warman, P. R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Soil enzymology.</subject><subject>Arylsulfatases.</subject><title>Evaluation of soil Arylsulfatase enzymes using natural and artificial substrates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj343.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z306s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc58q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the relationship between nutrient additions and algae and invertebrate productivity in a nutrient-poor wetland of the Interlake Region of Manitoba, Canada. Alfalfa hay was added to experimental enclosures in May 1992. Alfalfa additions were made in unprocessed and ground forms and consisted of three treatments: ground low, whole low, and whole high. Dissolved oxygen, surface water nutrients, algae standing crop, and invertebrate production were monitored at open marsh sites and in treatment and control enclosures during 1992 and 1993. Stable $ sp{13}$C, $ sp{15}$N and $ sp{34}$S isotope ratios were determined for the alfalfa additions, and for surface water, algae, macrophytes, sediments and invertebrates. In general, the effects of nutrient additions were confined to 1992. Treatment enclosure dissolved oxygen levels decreased immediately following fertilization, recovering in the low treatments by early June. Low oxygen conditions persisted in whole high enclosures throughout most of 1992. Dissolved and suspended nutrient concentrations, and phytoplankton chlorophyll a increased but, with the exception of dissolved N, were soon lost from the water column. Treatment enclosure epiphytic algae increased while epipelon did not respond to fertilization. The primary effect of fertilization on invertebrate production was an increase in treatment enclosure chironomid larvae during 1992. As with productivity measures, stable isotope ratio values suggested a temporary presence of alfalfa nutrients in the enclosed food webs. Only the isotope ratios of metaphytic algae and snails collected during August 1992 indicated an incorporation of alfalfa nutrients.</description><creator>Weeber, Russell C.</creator><contributor>Murkin, H. R. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Titman, R. D. (advisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Wetland ecology -- Manitoba -- Interlake Region.</subject><subject>Biogeochemical cycles -- Manitoba -- Interlake Region.</subject><subject>Freshwater ecology -- Manitoba -- Interlake Region.</subject><subject>Food chains (Ecology) -- Manitoba -- Interlake Region.</subject><title>Nutrient addition and the use of stable isotope techniques in wetlands of the Interlake Region of Manitoba, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw609.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc58q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p9250</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Short/branched chain acyl-CoA dehydrogenase (SBCAD), a member of the acyl-CoA dehydrogenase (ACD) family of enzymes, catalyzes the oxidation of branched chain fatty acids and the branched chain amino acids isoleucine and valine. This research project focuses on expression studies of the SBCAD gene. Northern blot analysis detected two SBCAD mRNA species of 2.7 and 6.5 kb in various human tissues and cell types. A single 4.1 and 2.0 kb SBCAD message was detected in rat and pig tissues, respectively, revealing a species difference in SBCAD mRNA size. Studies of human and rat SBCAD tissue-specificity and relative abundance, at both the RNA and protein levels, identified liver and kidney as the tissues with the highest levels of SBCAD expression, establishing a unique tissue-specific expression pattern that is not seen among the other members of the ACD family. Furthermore, a fetal and adult difference in SBCAD expression was observed in human kidney, suggesting that the SBCAD gene may be developmentally regulated in some tissues. Finally, an attempt was made to isolate and characterize the SBCAD promoter region in order to provide valuable data for future SBCAD promoter studies.</description><creator>Vicanek, Caroline Michaela</creator><contributor>Rozen, Rima (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Branched chain amino acids -- Metabolism -- Disorders</subject><subject>Dehydrogenases</subject><subject>Gene expression</subject><title>Expression studies on the shortbranched chain acyl-CoA dehydrogenase (SBCAD) gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dc02f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p9250</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988n14z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Caco-2 cells were incubated with 2.5 ug/ml Brefeldin A for up to 2 hours prior to fixation. The 2 hour incubation was sometimes followed by 1 or 2 hours of chase. In the Golgi apparatus of untreated cells, CMPase enzyme activity was localized to the TGN, TPPase activity to trans saccules and NADPase activity to middle saccules. In cells treated for 5 minutes, tubulovesicular clusters (tvc's), normally seen at the cis face of Golgi stacks in control cells, expanded greatly in size. By 15 minutes, the Golgi apparatus disappeared and was replaced by numerous tubular structures some of which, TPPase and NADPase-positive, appeared to derive from the tubules of the intersaccular areas of the stacks, while others, CMPase-positive, may be derived from TGN elements. The tubules and the tvc's persisted for up to 2 hours and did not connect with the rER. Apart from occasional light reaction for TPPase activity, rER cisternae were never labeled. After a one hour chase interval, the Golgi complexes began to reform and were often associated with tvc's on their cis face. By 2 hours, the Golgi complexes were often completely reformed and exhibited normal localization of phosphatase activities.</description><creator>Vasilescu, Daniela Eliza</creator><contributor>Bennett, Gary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Effects of brefeldin A treatment on the structure of the Golgi apparatus and the localization of marker enzyme activities in Caco-2 cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945s97z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988n14z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn107108g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Niche segregation among 4 species of sculpins (Myoxocephalus quadricornis, M. scorpius, M. scorpioides and Gymnocanthus tricuspis) inhabiting the east coast of James bay was studied along estuarine and depth gradients at different times of year between 1987 and 1990. A high degree of habitat overlap and absence of feeding segregation among sculpins was observed. M. quadricornis and M. scorpius dominated catch in the estuary and in the coastal zone, respectively. M. scorpioides and G. tricuspis were less abundant and generally avoided the estuary. G. tricuspis was the only cottid which seemed to migrate. Significant differences in the diets were observed at different sites, seasons and years, but not along depth gradients (2 a 20 m). The distribution and abundance of sculpins appeared to be regulated by physical (salinity and temperature) and biological (competition) factors.</description><creator>Vanier, Benoît</creator><contributor>Whoriskey, Frederick (advisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Sculpins -- Habitat -- Nunavut -- James Bay</subject><title>Répartition des ressources spatiale et alimentaire chez quatre espèces de cottidés (Myoxocephalus quadricornis, M. scorpius, M. scorpioides et Gymnocanthus tricuspis) cohabitant la côte orientale de la baie de James, Canada</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214r214.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107108g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860898f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lettuce mosaic virus (LMV) is an economically important pathogen with worldwide distribution. LMV infection in L. sativa can cause significant yield losses. Resistance to LMV in L. sativa is conferred by the recessive gene mo. We attempted to position the mo gene on the L. sativa map. The ultimate goal is a better understanding of plant-virus interactions. To do so, Random Amplified Polymorphic DNA (RAPD) markers were screened in the near isogenic lines (NILs) Vanguard and Vanguard 75. These NILs differ in the presence of the mo gene in Vanguard 75. Polymorphic markers were screened for linkage to mo in two F$ sb2$ populations segregating for resistance to LMV. The F$ sb2$ populations used were derived from 2 crosses, the first one between the L. sativa cultivars Dwarf 2 (resistant to LMV via the presence of mo) and Saffier and the second one between two breeding lines 87-25M-1 (momo) and 87-1090M-1 (MoMo). In order to develop a highly stringent antibody detection system to phenotype plants infected with LMV, a plasmid construct was developed which overproduces LMV coat protein. This construct will be used in the future to produce enough recombinant LMV coat protein for antibody production. To further characterize mo, a selection of cultivars resistant and susceptible to LMV according to the literature were subjected to various temperature changes to determine the environmental influences on virus movement.</description><creator>Ubalijoro, Eliane</creator><contributor>Fortin, M. G. (advisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Lettuce mosaic disease.</subject><subject>Lettuce -- Disease and pest resistance -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Characterization of resistance to lettuce mosaic virus in Lactuca sativa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j90z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860898f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cw15c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ultradian rhythm of growth hormone (GH) secretion from the anterior pituitary gland is ultimately controlled by the complex interaction of two hypothalamic hormones, a stimulatory GH-releasing factor (GRF), and an inhibitory hormone, somatostatin (SRIF). In the present study, we used the long-acting SRIF analog, octreotide, as a probe in both the normal and mutant dwarf rat to (1) further clarify the temporal nature of the SRIF/GRF interplay in GH regulation in vivo, and (2) define possible mechanisms of action of SRIF in generating the ultradian rhythm of GH secretion characteristic of the normal male rat. Administration of octreotide to free-moving, chronically cannulated adult male rats resulted in an almost complete obliteration of spontaneous GH pulses for 3 hours, with gradual recovery observed 3-6 hours after injection. Rats pretreated with octreotide i.v. and subsequently challenged with GRF exhibited reduced GH responsiveness to exogenous GRF at 1 hour post treatment. In contrast, preexposure to octreotide for 3 hours resulted in a 2-3 fold enhancement in GH responsiveness to GRF compared to controls pretreated with normal saline to normal saline-pretreated controls. In contrast, we report that preexposure to octreotide (n = 6) in a strain of dwarf rats, which shows a selective reduction in pituitary GH synthesis and storage, failed to significantly enhance GRF-induced GH release. Our findings suggest that SRIF pretreatment promotes the accumulation of pituitary GH stores in a readily releasable pool so that subsequent GRF challenges can exert an accentuated effect on pituitary somatotrophs. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Turner, Joel P.</creator><contributor>Tannenbaum, G. S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>In vivo evidence that preexposure to somatostatin enhances growth hormone responsiveness to growth hormone-releasing factor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v984t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cw15c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55md921</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cerebral vasospasm is a common cause of ischemia and death in patients suffering from cerebral hemorrhage, most notably subarachnoid hemorrhage (SAH), and it usually occurs 4-14 days after the initial episode of bleeding. Many mediators of cerebral vasospasm (CVS) have been proposed, but at this time the pathogenesis of CVS is poorly understood, and oxyhemoglobin is thought to be the principal pathogenic agent. This project was designed to examine the effects of oxyhemoglobin on the vascular tone of the middle and basilar cerebral arteries in vitro and to evaluate the validity of using bovine vessels as an animal model of the human cerebral vasculature in which to study cerebral vasospasm. Human vessels were studied in parallel with the bovine arteries to test the validity of the animal model. To further evaluate the model, some experiments were also carried out on canine vessels, because the dog has frequently been used for cerebrovascular studies in the past. The cow is a better model of the human cerebral vasculature than the dog. Arteries respond to a variety of vasoactive stimuli, in a manner closely resembling human vessels, and can be induced into a prolonged vasospastic state by exposure to oxyhemoglobin. Vasospasm in all three species was independent of endothelial status, functional innervation, or morphological evidence of atherosclerosis. Vasospasm could not be prevented by diltiazem, nicardipine or ascorbic acid, but was partially reversed in some samples by verapamil. Bovine vessels would appear to be exceptionally useful for studies designed to test pharmacological agents for the prevention or therapy of post-hemorrhagic vasospasm and also to determine the pathophysiological mechanisms involved.</description><creator>Tretiak, Tania</creator><contributor>Zorychta, E. (advisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>A bovine in vitro model of human cerebral vasospasm</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tx21g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55md921</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df61q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A field lysimeter experiment was conducted during 1993 and 1994 using 4 water table depths (WTD) (0.3, 0.6, 0.8, and 1.0 m), 13 treatment levels of calcium (0, 1500, and 2500 kg/ha) and potassium (0, 160, and 400 kg/ha), to determine their effects on tomato quality and yield. Plant parameters measured included: yield (fruit/plant), fruit height, maximum and minimum equatorial width, degree of catfacing (scale of 1 to 5), and sunscald (scale of 0 to 2). Water table treatment was usually highly significant for the parameters measured at harvest. Largest height, equatorial width and yield of tomato fruit occur with 0.6 to 0.8 m WTD. Fertilizer treatments were rarely significant by WTD, but if they were, they tended to be in the 0.3 or 1.0 m WTD. Maintaining a WTD of 0.6 to 0.8 m and fertilizing with 160 kg/ha of K can improve quality and total yield of tomatoes.</description><creator>Trenholm, Leif</creator><contributor>Madramootoo, C. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Tomatoes -- Yields.</subject><subject>Tomatoes -- Quality.</subject><subject>Tomatoes -- Fertilizers.</subject><subject>Water table.</subject><subject>Tomatoes -- Water requirements.</subject><title>Effects of water table depths and fertilizer treatments on yield and quality of tomatoes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n077f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df61q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tb53f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The prognosis of breast cancer is characterized by a high degree of variability, which is partially accounted for, by a set of clinical, pathological and biological parameters. The aim of my study was to test whether met, a proto-oncogene encoding a protein related to normal histological differentiation, undergoes structural changes in breast cancer. I have extracted tumor DNA from 83 breast cancer patients and performed Southern blot hybridization with the MetH probe. This study demonstrates that somatic alterations of met occur in 22% of informative women with breast cancer. No correlation was found between loss of heterozygosity (LOH) for met and conventional horizontal prognosis factors or status for c-erbB-2 proto-oncosene expression. Estrogen receptor (ER) showed correlation with progesterone receptor (PR), and S phase correlated with ploidy and size of the tumor. It remains to be confirmed whether overall survival (OS) and disease free survival (DFS) correlate with genetic alteration of met.</description><creator>Tougas, Liette</creator><contributor>Jothy, Serge (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Prognastic markers in breast cancer : is there a role for the met proto-oncogene?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w1811.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb53f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97ks513</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Energy availability and environmental issues are of growing concern; nations are striving to use energy more efficiently while at the same time decreasing the negative impacts on the environment. The objectives of this study are to: (1) establish a supply price for ethanol derived from switchgrass, (2) establish an accounting budget for carbon dioxide during feedstock production and processing into ethanol, and (3) determine the cost/tonne of CO$ sb2$ using this strategy. Total cost of production of the feedstock for cycles of 5, 10, 15, and 20 years are $357.06/ha ( $32.73/ODT), $337.81/ha ( $30.96/ODT), $331.52/ha ( $30.39/ODT), and $328.47/ha ( $30.11/ODT) respectively. Thus, the approximate cost of producing one litre of ethanol from switchgrass is $0.47/litre. Overall, the switchgrass-ethanol system is a net carbon sink for all four cycles, and each hectare of swithgrass sequesters between 1.9 and 6.8 tonne of CO$ sb2$ per year. However, this process is not indefinite, and will stop once the soil organic matter reaches an equilibrium. The current price for gas is $0.24/litre (excluding taxes and profit margins). According to the price differential existing between ethanol and gasoline and the CO$ sb2$ emissions difference between both systems, the cost of sequestering CO$ sb2$ ranges between $83/tonne and $129/tonne, with the adoption of this specific strategy. At the macro level, Quebec and Canada's total carbon dioxide emissions reached 70 million tonnes and 461 million tonnes respectively, in 1991. Thus, displacing fossil-based energy sources (gasoline) with a renewable energy source (ethanol from switchgrass) to reduce those emissions by 20 % by the year 2010, incurs a cost ranging between $1.16 billion and $1.8 billion for Quebec, and between $7.7 billion and $11.9 billion for Canada. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Tayara, Ahmad</creator><contributor>Henning, John (advisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biomass energy.</subject><subject>Panicum virgatum</subject><subject>Carbon cycle (Biogeochemistry)</subject><subject>Energy crops.</subject><subject>Alcohol as fuel.</subject><title>Evaluation of switchgrass as an energy feedstock : economic feasibility, and carbon dioxide accounting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602298x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks513</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cj69p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:07:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A knowledge of the allometry of algal growth and respiration can be applied to biomass-size distribution models which are in turn used in the prediction of fish yield and ecosystem studies. However, the scaling exponents reported in the literature are variable. This variation may be attributed to differences in the expression of cell size and phylogeny, but could also reflect small sample size which underlie most published regressions. This thesis establishes the allometry of algal growth and respiration based on a larger sample taken from the literature, and evaluates the effects of differences in gross taxonomy and in the expression of cell size on these relations. Allometric relations based on cell carbon appear more consistent with relations from other taxa than those based on cell volume, reflecting the size dependence of algal elemental composition which does not occur in most other taxa. The allometric relation of algal respiration (R in pl O$ rm sb2 cdot cell sp{-1} cdot hr sp{-1})$ was found to be R = 0.030C$ sp{0.93}$ where C is cell carbon content in pg C$ rm cdot cell sp{-1}$. Among the 6 divisions studied (Chlorophyta, Chrysophyta, Cyanophyta, Euglenophyta, Pyrrophyta, Rhodophyta), chlorophytes, euglenophytes and rhodophytes exhibited different respiration-size relation but separate relations were not developed for each of those groups due to patterns in residuals or small sample sizes. The specific rate of algal growth ($ mu$ in divisions$ cdot$day$ sp{-1}$) also depends on size and it is found to be $ mu$ = 3.45C$ sp{-0.21}.$ All taxa studied here (Chlorophyta, Chrysophyta, Pyrrophyta) have similar scaling exponents for growth but Pyrrophyta have significantly lower growth rates than other algae of similar size.</description><creator>Tang, Evonne P. Y. (Evonne Pui Yue)</creator><contributor>Peters, Robert H. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Algae -- Growth</subject><subject>Plants -- Respiration</subject><subject>Plant allometry</subject><title>The allometry of algal growth and respiration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9355093.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj69p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):1400</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>