<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:01:15Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):27975" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827c93x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The methodologic issues involved in evaluating trends in mortality by Census Division (CD) are explored. The three trend measures investigated included Poisson regression, ordinary least squares (OLS), and a measure based on Raveh's measure of monotone association for time series. Assumptions required for the parametric methods of Poisson regression and OLS were not satisfied. The non-parametric method based on the ranking of the measure of monotone association did not require such assumptions. Significant spatial correlation in the measure of monotone association was observed for all-cause mortality. Using deaths among persons 35-69 years for 3 causes, comparisons were carried out by cross-tabulations, Pearson rank correlation coefficients, and an investigation of discrepancies. Minor discrepancies resulted from differences in trends of age-specific death rates and from CDs with small populations. Rather than distinguishing further between the three trend measures, guidelines should be developed for minimum populations at risk required for mapping as well as methods for combining regions.</description><creator>Semenciw, Robert</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><subject>Sociology, Demography.</subject><title>Evaluation of trend measures of census division mortality, Canada 1974-1986</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zc26t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827c93x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p157f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The amount of Municipal Solid Waste (MSW) produced in Canada was 12.6 million tonnes in 1980. Cadmium, which is one heavy metal characteristically present in leachate from MSW, is an extremely toxic metal to all living organisms. Clay liners are used to contain contaminants such as heavy metals (aluminum, mercury, manganese, lead, and zinc) present in leachate from landfill sites containing MSW. Consequently, an investigation into the mechanisms of cadmium adsorption from leachate onto clay was pursued. Characteristically, such leachates contain trace quantities of heavy metals and abundant quantities of chloride ions. For this study, leachate samples were collected from the Meloche landfill site in Kirkland, Quebec. This leachate is characteristic of other leachates, and in one monitoring well it contained cadmium (Cd) at 0.069 mg/L (ppm) and chloride ions (Cl$ sp-$) at 677 mg/L (ppm). Under these conditions, the formation of complex ions between cadmium and chloride has the potential to interfere with the adsorption of cadmium by clay minerals.</description><creator>Sheremata, Tamara W.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Effect of chloride ions on the adsorption of cadmium from leachate onto kaolinite</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j925n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p157f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r9674875</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Meeting the needs of the Learning Disabled has become one of the most researched and documented areas in special education. Individualized programs which incorporate components to promote motivation, skill building, skill generalization and strategy use, and social competence have been called for in the literature (Deshler, Schumaker, Lenz, &amp; Ellis, 1984), however, there have been remarkably few evaluations of such programs (Horn, O'Donnell, &amp; Vitulano, 1983). This study evaluated a multidimensional intervention program using the objectives-oriented method. The Kaufman Test of Educational Achievement and three nonstandardized measures were used to evaluate the four program objectives. Analysis of the individuals' gains indicated that objective achievement was idiosyncratic. Group gain analysis indicated significant gains only in English class marks, F(7,1) = 7.40, p =.3. The results are discussed and implications for future research are outlined.</description><creator>Schnaiberg, Romy S. (Romy Sue)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Learning disabled teenagers</subject><subject>Individualized instruction</subject><title>An evaluation of a multidimensional intervention for learning disabled adolescents /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171z298.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r9674875</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032422q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis studies low-rate wideband analysis-by-synthesis speech coders. The wideband speech signals have a bandwidth of up to 8 kHz and are sampled at 16 kHz, while the target operating bit rate is 16 kbits/sec. Applications for such a coder range from high-quality voice-mail services to teleconferencing. In order to achieve a low operating rate, the coding places more emphasis on the lower frequencies (0 to 4 kHz), while the higher frequencies (4 to 8 kHz) are coded less precisely but with little perceived degradation. The study consists of three stages. First, aspects of wideband spectral envelope modeling using Line Spectral Frequencies (LSF's) are studied. Then, the underlying coder structure is derived from a basic Residual Excited Linear Predictive coder (RELP). This structure is enhanced by the addition of a pitch prediction stage, and by the development of full-band and split-band pitch parameter optimization procedures. These procedures are then applied to an Code Excited Linear Prediction (CELP) model. Finally, the performance of full-band and split-band CELP structures are compared.</description><creator>Roy, Guylain</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Low-rate analysis-by-synthesis wideband speech coding</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g6309.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032422q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dn593</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nicolas Poussin's landscapes, The Four Seasons, 1660-1664, have been the subject of extensive analysis because of their enigmatic character and the modulation in Poussin's style in his last years. The meaning of these representations has, however, remained cryptic and, to some extent, neglected. This thesis attempts to make a contribution toward unravelling the mystery of The Four Seasons. These profound works reflect Poussin's religious persuasion, knowledge of which is essential to an understanding of them. Poussin's religious convictions, however, are difficult to discern with any precision; for, although he died a Catholic, he was closely associated with the progressive thinking that influenced religious belief in the Baroque age, much of which was rejected by the Church of Rome. Nevertheless, Poussin was undoubtedly a devout Christian, inspired particularly by the early Christian Fathers and Stoics. It is in nature, above all, though, that he perceived God's presence and message which he strove to capture in his "altarpiece" to the seasons.</description><creator>Challons, Siu</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Poussin, Nicolas, 1594?-1665. Four seasons</subject><title>Nicolas Poussin's The Four Seasons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v233.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dn593</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s134w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When a geometric algorithm is designed without considering the effect of the round-off errors inherent in finite precision arithmetic operations, the results from a computer implementation of the algorithm are often found to be quite different than expected. This thesis describes some of the issues involved in the design of geometric primitive operations that are reliable and accurate when implemented. In particular, algorithms are presented for the problems of point coincidence, determination of the orientation of the angle formed by three ordered points, line segment intersection and point inclusion in a triangle. The algorithms return a YES or NO answer only if it can be determined, through error analysis techniques, that the answer is definitely correct; otherwise a descriptive error message is returned. The techniques of partitioning a problem into rectangular sub-problems, and defining bounding rectangles around regions of interest are used to reduce the amount of numerical computation.</description><creator>Sander, Luise</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>The design of robust primitives for geometric algorithms : with applications to line segment intersection and planar convex hull algorithms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w597x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s134w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708x84n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The increases in complexity of industrial process simulations necessitate faster methods and more accurate models for analysis. In many cases automation of industrial plants using real-time control cannot be solved using present computer methodologies. This thesis introduces a parallel methodology that outlines the steps to design and implement a distributed continuous simulation. Implementing the system in parallel reduces the simulation time to comply with predetermined time constraints. The methodology determines the structure of the simulator, organization of the distributed tasks and management of the variable memory allocation. A dynamic model for transient, incompressible pipe flow is used to test the parallel methodology. The generalized flow equations are developed for two applications: a tank-pipe and pipe network model. The models are translated into computer algorithms using parallel techniques developed in the simulation methodology. The individual subroutines of the simulation are directly implemented on a parallel processing and a multi-tasking computer. The flow algorithms are tested on both computers to demonstrate the benefits obtained by using the parallel methodology on a multi-processor computer. Model sizes are varied to provide a performance scale comparing multi-processor results with that of a single processor.</description><creator>Cohen, Steven G.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>The development of a distributed methodlogy for process simulation with applications in pipe flow /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731513c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708x84n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967490g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this thesis was to investigate the contributions of both the vestibular and foot/ankle somatosensory inputs to the mechanisms controlling lower limb muscular activity of normal human subjects. The standing subject was modelled as a single-link inverted pendulum, producing whole head-body tilts about an axis colinear with the ankle joints. A paradigm was developed whereby the vestibular and the ankle proprioceptive afferent systems were systematically and selectively controlled or eliminated. There was a greater tendency for reflex response to be activated in the three lower limb muscles when the forward tilts had an acceleration larger than 1.4 g. This was found when the whole head-body tilts were delivered with minimal changes in ankle angle or a significant change in ankle angle from the neutral position towards dorsiflexion. Frequency of occurrence was greater for the more proximal muscle when there was minimal ankle dorsiflexion, and for one of the distal muscles when there was ankle dorsiflexion. The proximal hip extensor muscle tended to have the shortest latency during whole head-body tilts alone, while the most distal muscles had the shortest latency when the tilts occurred concomitantly with ankle rotation.</description><creator>Lo Monaco, Emmanuel</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety.</subject><title>A study of forward head-body tilts in human balance control /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687j704.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967490g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nj279</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This documentary study sought to determine the relevance of the James Bay Cree's cultural values and practices to their policy-making process as school committee members. The Cree's formal school system, for which they have full responsibility, is based on the values and practices of non-native society. Using the historical method, both primary and secondary sources were searched for relevant information concerning Cree culture and its distinguishing characteristics. Evidence of a distinct egalitarian society, practicing consensus, reciprocity and communal land use was found. Sources also indicated the continuing existence and adaptability of Cree values and practices despite prolonged interaction with non-native society. This thesis proposes that these cultural values and practices predispose the Cree to be effective school committee members. The study provides data for a possible future ethnographic study of Cree school committee participation. Further research could also focus on the policy-making process required of Cree school board members.</description><creator>Douglas, Anne</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Indians of North America -- James Bay Region</subject><subject>Cree Indians</subject><subject>School management and organization -- Decision making</subject><subject>Cree Indians -- Education</subject><title>The significance of James Bay Cree cultural values and practices in school committee policy-making : a documentary study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cf48m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj279</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920fx96d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies on normal and regenerated rat aortic endothelium at 1, 2, 3 and 4 weeks following segmental balloon denudation injury were carried out to evaluate: (1) the permeability to intravenously injected Evans blue (EB) and horseradish peroxidase (HRP) using en face aortic preparations and (2) the volume density of stress fibers by morphometry using thin section electron microscopy. The results of these studies indicated that: (1) the permeability of the regenerated endothelium to both EB and HRP was identical to normal endothelium at all time points studied and (2) stress fiber volume density significantly increased in regenerated endothelium at 1 week as compared to control, however, returned to and remained at normal value at and after 2 weeks following segmental balloon injury. These results are consistent with the view that structural and functional changes in regenerated vascular endothelium, if present, are transient in nature and the integrity of endothelial monolayer is eventually reestablished during the repair process that follows a single injury.</description><creator>Cokay, Mehmet Sami</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Permeability to Evans blue and horseradish peroxidase and morphometry on stress fibers in normal and regenerated rat aortic endothelium following segmental balloon injury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569561f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fx96d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j96022023</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>$ beta$-Galactosidase (E.C. 3.2.1.23) or lactase was produced by the growth of a selected Bacillus subtilis strain (KL88) which was adapted to grow at 10$ sp circ$C. The growth and enzyme production were maximal at 2% (w/v) lactose supplemented with 0.2% (w/v) yeast extract. A Fast Protein Liquid Chromatography system (FPLC) was used for $ beta$-galactosidase purification. The enzyme was purified to 44-fold over the crude extract with a recovery of $ sim$54%. Native-PAGE and SDS-PAGE using "PhastSystem" showed the presence of two isoenzymes having molecular weights of 88 and 170 kD. The purified enzyme showed high activity at low temperatures (10$ sp circ$C) and recorded an optimum pH of 7.0. The K$ sb{ rm m}$ values were found to be 2.21 mM and 28.08 mM for o-nitrophenyl-$ beta$-D-galactopyranoside (ONPG) and lactose, respectively. $ beta$-Galactosidase from psychrotrophic Bacillus subtilis was specific to the $ beta$-D-glycosidic linkage normally present in lactose. To investigate the possibility of producing proteinase-free $ beta$-galactosidase from this psychrotrophic microorganism, FPLC was used for the rapid separation of $ beta$-galactosidase.</description><creator>Abdelrahim, Khalid Ali</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Dairy processing.</subject><subject>Bacillus subtilis.</subject><subject>Beta-galactosidase -- Analysis.</subject><title>Production and characterization of b-galactosidase from psychrotrophic Bacillus subtilis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gt86p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j96022023</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149q943</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation investigates a "universal" question--what the exact nature of the relationship between music and theology is--by examining two particulars: (1) the music and thought of the French Roman Catholic composer Olivier Messiaen, and (2) the theology of music of Protestant theologian/musicologist Oskar Sohngen. It should be emphasized, however, that the main focus of the paper is upon the "particulars," since the primary objective of this study is to demonstrate the remarkable similarity of thought which exists between the theory of Sohngen and the musical practice of Messiaen. After an exposition of Sohngen's three categories of relationship between music and theology (music as science, as worship, and as creatura) there is an extensive examination of Messiaen's compositional techniques which reveals the latter's implicit use of these same three categories. In the final chapter of this work, after a discussion of several problems which are inherent in each of the particular approaches to music and theology, there is a return to the universal question, in response to which a precise, working definition is finally established.</description><creator>Epstein, Heidi</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Söhngen, Oskar, 1900- -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Messiaen, Olivier, 1908- -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Music -- Religious aspects -- Christianity.</subject><subject>Church music</subject><title>The nature of the relationship between music and theology according to Oskar Söhngen and Oliver Messiaen /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f008.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149q943</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cv198</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work of this thesis centres around two related themes, the first being the characterization of the through-thickness inhomogeneity found in rolled sheet at various stages in its production. The second is involved with attempting to understand how and to what extent the existing inhomogeneity affects the correlations with the anisotropies of some physical or mechanical properties. For this, the inhomogeneity of six steels were measured. Three were specimens removed from the sheet during the early processing of conventional grain-oriented ferrosilicon steel, one sample taken after the first cold rolling stage, another taken after the intermediate anneal, while the last was taken after the following stage, i.e. after the second cold rolling. To contrast the extensive inhomogeneity expected in the ferrosilicon steels, the remaining three steels consisted of two continuous-annealed, interstitial-free, extra-low-carbon steels and one aluminum-killed, batch-annealed, low-carbon steel, all three of which are commercial final product, deep drawing steels.</description><creator>Blandford, Peter</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Through-thickness inhomogeneity of steel-sheet texture and its affect on material properties</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666569w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv198</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816n71v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of our study was to examine if there is an ERG component (a-wave, b-wave, or OPs) that could be used as an estimate of the intraretinal time of visual processing. To investigate that matter, we proceeded to simultaneous recordings of the ERG and of single cell unit activity at the geniculate level in paralyzed and anesthetized rabbits. Our results show that 86.4% of the geniculate cells (n = 162) responded to the flash before the peak of the b-wave. One of the oscillatory potentials, the OP2, was preceding the geniculate activity in 77.8% of the cases. Furthermore, the shifts in latency of the geniculate cells induced by varying the intensity of the flash were better correlated to the peak time of OP2 than to the peak time of the b-wave. The mean correlation coefficient between the peak time of OP2 and the latency of the LGN unit response is 0.91 $ pm$ 0.13, against 0.70 $ pm$ 0.29 for the b-wave, and 0.63 $ pm$ 0.27 for the a-wave. Our results suggest that OP2 better reflects the primary visual processes at the retinal level and provides a better estimate of the intraretinal time taken for visual processing.</description><creator>Benoit, Julie</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Temporal relationship between ERG components and lateral geniculate unit activity in the rabbit</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62f958f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816n71v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pp087</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to receive full compensation for damage caused during air transportation, plaintiffs try to get around the liability limitations of the Warsaw regime, inter alia, by alleging willful misconduct on the part of the carrier or its agents and servants under Article 25 of the Warsaw and Hague Conventions. On their part, carriers have an interest in limiting their potential liability under the said regime, and in avoiding any possibility of breaking the stipulated monetary limitation. Consequently, the said provisions are litigated frequently without, however, bringing uniform results in different jurisdictions of the world. This thesis makes a study of the application and interpretation of the willful misconduct exception (Article 25) of the original Warsaw Convention as well as its subsequent amendments. The study reviews the treatment accorded to the relevant provisions in different common and civil law jurisdictions. Further, the problem is examined from the point of view of Muhammadan Islamic jurisprudence. This paper also traces the legislative history of the relevant provisions of the original treaty and its subsequent amendments. The final chapter of the thesis assesses the possibility of a "new" consolidated regime for international air carriage and concludes that at present Montreal Protocols Nos. 3 and 4 may be allowed to work.</description><creator>Khan, Asmatullah</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Transportation.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Air carrier's unlimited liability under the Warsaw system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ch87d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp087</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634493v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Free-Trade Agreement between Canada and the United States (FTA) acts clearly as a pioneer in international trade in services by integrating binding obligations that will governe trade in services. It occurs at a crucial point as the establishment of a multilateral framework of principles and rules for trade in services is attracting the attention of the international community. The present document examines the eventual contribution of the FTA in developing pertinent principles and rules for international trade in services while considering some of the main principles and rules agreed upon during the mid-term ministerial review of the Uruguay Round: transparency, most-favored nation principle, national treatment and market access. Therefore it generally reminds us of the application of these principles and rules in the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade while taking into account the difficulties arising from it for trade in services. Then it analyses the dispositions of the FTA in their relevancy. Finally, it examines the opportunity of inserting such principles in an eventual multilateral agreement on trade in services.</description><creator>Jolivet, Christian</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>Contribution de l'accord de libre-échange au développement de régles et principes pour le commerce international des services</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jm643.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634493v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161741p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lipoxygenase was extracted from Canola seeds (Brassica napus cv, Westar) and partially purified by precipitated with ammonium sulfate at 20-50% of saturation. The optimum pH for the enzyme activity was 7.5 and its K$ sb{ rm m}$ value was 2.0 $ times$ 10$ sp{-4}$ M. The activity of the enzyme extract was considerably greater on linoleic acid than on its ester or on linolenic acid. The effect of cyanide on the enzyme activity was also investigated. Further purification of the enzyme extract was performed by successive chromatography on ion-exchange and gel filtration, using FPLC system. Four lipoxygenase isozymes (I, IIA, IIB and III) were separated. The homogeneity of each isozyme was demonstrated by the presence of a single protein band on SDS-PAGE gel electophoresis. The molecular weights of isozymes I, IIA, IIB and III were, respectively, 72,000, 106,000, 78,000 and 62,000. The optimum pH for lipoxygenase activity was 6.5 for isozyme I and 6.0 for isozymes IIA, IIB and III.</description><creator>Khalyfa, Abdelnaby</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Lipoxygenases.</subject><subject>Canola.</subject><title>Isolation, purification and characterization of lipoxygenase isozymes from canola (Brassica napus cv, Westar) seed</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bq54q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161741p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qj886</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Discharge coefficients are an important parameter in the prediction of the air displacement performance of ventilation outlets and in the design of ventilation ducts. Discharge coefficients of a wooden ventilation duct 8.54 metres in length and of a constant 0.17 m$ sp2$ cross sectional area were measured. Four different outlet shapes and 3 aperture ratios of each shape were tested. A split plot experimental design was used to evaluate the effect of outlet shape, outlet size, and distance from the fan on discharge coefficient. The relationship between duct performance characteristics and discharge coefficient was examined. A mathematical equation to predict the discharge coefficient was developed and tested. Discharge coefficient values measured ranged from 0.19 to 1.25 depending on the aperture ratio and distance from the fan. Outlet shape had no significant effect. The apparent effects of aperture ratio and size are due to the effects of head ratio. The equation predicting the discharge coefficient had a maximum error of 5 percent for the aperture ratios of 0.5 and 1.0, and 15 percent at an aperture ratio of 1.5.</description><creator>Kinsman, Roger Gordon</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Air ducts -- Design and construction.</subject><subject>Air flow -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Outlet discharge coefficients of ventilation ducts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn9997900.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qj886</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451j740</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Partant du constat de l'importance du sujet pour le peintre futuriste a une epoque ou les avant-gardes europeennes tendent a l'abstraction, la presente etude demontre que la ville fut un theme capital dans l'elaboration de l'esthetique futuriste. En effet, les peintres italiens ne cherchaient pas tant a depeindre l'apparence, l'aspect visible de la ville qu'a apprehender de facon conceptuelle les idees-forces qui en emanaient. A travers l'entite "ville", ils revelerent les concepts inherents au monde moderne et en etablirent les equivalents plastiques. Ainsi, c'est a travers le sujet de la ville que s'expriment les idees-forces les plus originales du mouvement, telles que la modernolatrie, le dynamisme universel, la vitesse, le devenir, la transformation, l'unanimisme et le simultaneisme, illustres dans trois chapitres intitules 'La ville montante', 'La ville electrisee' et 'La ville simultanee'. Geux-ci demontrent comment certains motifs recurents du cadre urbain comme les echafaudages des chantiers de construction, les lampadaires, les foules ou les bolides sont transcendes par ces idees-forces. La representation de la ville par les futuristes ne releve pas simplement de la description mais d'un programme d'abord politique puis esthetique: l'avant-garde italienne a cree une nouvelle conception du beau, a revele la beaute de la ville moderne et des valeurs qui lui sont inherentes.</description><creator>Hollevoet, Christel</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Art, Italian -- 20th century</subject><subject>Futurism (Art) -- Italy</subject><subject>Cities and towns in art</subject><title>Contribution à l'étude de la représentation picturale de la ville dans le futurisme italien</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x5169.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451j740</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440t61w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this research is to provide an account of literary expertise by examining literary experts and students in English Literature as they describe a fictional narrative. The experimental text is a complex narrative conveyed by means of character dialogue. To investigate expert performance this study developed a model of text description that identified semantic units in the description protocols as a set of possible "discursive patterns." A discursive pattern identifies the text unit being described along with the point of reference of the description, that is, from the point of view of the reader, the author, or simply the text. The results indicate that students' descriptions closely paraphrased the text, repeating either the narrative events or the characters' speech, while experts' descriptions reflected higher-level references to narrative structure or the function of the dialogue which were derived either from the text or from prior knowledge. Experts relied on specific information in the text as a support for more inferential statements. In addition, experts commented more extensively on the language of the text. Experts also included references to the author, the reader and the relationship between the two. It seems that experts view the text as the result of deliberate linguistic and conceptual choices made by an author and awareness of these choices appears to guide their descriptions.</description><creator>Graves, Barbara</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Criticism -- Methodology</subject><subject>Critics</subject><title>On literary expertise : the description of a fictional narrative by experts and novices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gh49r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440t61w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193b20f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In early nineteenth century Lower Canada, a direct relationship existed between the colony's laws of employment and the nature of its economy. As the artisanal and manufacturing centre of British North America, Montreal, in the first third of the century, had a pre-industrial economy. Its legal treatment of the master/servant relationship was established and directed by masters, and drew heavily upon the spirit of the pre-industrial traditions of English common law, emphasizing the criminal liability of servants failing to respect contractual obligations. Montreal's domestic servants, who were drawn from the poor and popular classes, and included mostly women and minors, were often at the greatest disadvantage in this legal system, because of their gender and economic backgrounds. Not only did their masters and mistresses have economic and social advantages, but they also controlled the legal system.</description><creator>Hogg, Grace Laing</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Master and servant -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History -- 19th century</subject><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Economic conditions -- 19th century</subject><subject>Employees -- Law and legislation -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><title>The legal rights of masters, mistresses and domestic servants in Montreal, 1816-1829 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848r746.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193b20f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687j71d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of three different vocal timbres on uncertain singers' ability to match and discriminate pitches. Fifty-six children between six and eight year old were randomly assigned to one of four groups. In the Own Voices group, subjects were training in pitch matching using subjects' own voices. They trained in pitch discrimination using a model child voice as stimuli. In the Model Child group, subjects were training in pitch matching and pitch discrimination using a model child voice of the same sex and age as that of the subject. Subjects in the Female Adult group were training in pitch matching and pitch discrimination using a female adult voice as stimuli. Subjects in the control group had no training. It was found that timbre affected uncertain singers' ability to match and discriminate pitches. Pitch matching to one's own voice was more accurate than pitch matching to a child's voice. The discrimination of high and low pitches was more accurate when a model child's voice was used than when an adult voice was used.</description><creator>Gratton, Martine</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Musical pitch</subject><subject>Musical ability -- Testing</subject><title>The effect of three vocal models on uncertain singers' ability to match and discriminate pitches /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021g45d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687j71d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns0647074</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>O'Neill, Gary.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Biology, General.</subject><title>Studies on the immunosuppressive effect of human alpha-fetoprotein on cell-mediated immune reactions in vitro</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q130.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns0647074</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666570n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Casey Common, Julia.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Biology, General.</subject><title>Variability of tillering behaviour in six-rowed spring barley (Hordeum vulgare L. emend Lam.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kh60h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666570n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pn89d778g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:02:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Droniuk, Randal</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Biology, General.</subject><title>Sodium-stimulated transport of metabolites in two marine bacteria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm247.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d778g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):28000</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>