<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:29:23Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):35025" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dx12r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was designed to address the need for learning opportunities that enable adolescents to become producers and critics of statistics. The producer/critic model (Palinscar &amp; Brown, 1984) was adapted to the context of statistical investigation where questions are formulated and data are subsequently collected, analyzed, and represented to address this question (Graham, 1987). In the producer phase learners design, conduct, and present a group investigation to peers. In the critic phase, groups evaluate investigations produced by unknown peers which are presented in a computer-based learning environment, Critiquing Statistics (CS). The critic phase served as the intervention and was expected to yield three positive outcomes: (1) sophisticated statistical reasoning; (2) a strong understanding of statistical investigation; and (3) a close alignment of evaluations between learners and experts due to successful internalization of criteria. However, the effects of the intervention were also expected to be mediated by the types of questions investigated and the nature of group collaborations. These outcomes were assessed by comparing groups that participated in the critic phase (intervention) with those that did not (control). Investigations produced and evaluated from the first to the second producer phase provided the basis for this comparison. Six groups of three students participated in the study. The descriptive analyses yielded mixed results. As expected, the types of questions investigated and the nature of group collaborations interacted with reasoning and understanding. These two factors accounted for the quantity and quality of reasoning that were higher initially in the control than in the intervention. How groups defined the task based on their questions explained the larger amount of understanding initially found in the intervention compared to the control. However, the intervention's effect was to enhance the quality of understanding on more aspects</description><creator>Lavigne, Nancy C.</creator><contributor>Lajoie, Susanne P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Statistics -- Study and teaching (Secondary)</subject><title>Project-based investigations for producing and critiquing statistics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sh95k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx12r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sv46m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>These studies were undertaken to further characterize HIV-1 reverse transcriptase (RT), a pluripotent enzyme capable of RNA-dependent DNA polymerization (RDDP), DNA-dependent DNA polymerization (DDDP), and RNaseH activity. RT is absolutely required for the replication of the virus, because it converts the viral RNA genome into double-stranded pre-integrative DNA. As such, RT is the target of many anti-HIV drug antagonists, such as the nucleoside analogue inhibitors, of which 3TC is an example. RT is an extremely error-prone polymerase; the rapid development of drug resistance mutations in association with 3TC treatment is due to the selection of mutations in the RT gene of HIV-infected individuals. We found that a methionine to valine mutation at amino acid 184 (M184V) of RT was associated with higher RDDP fidelity than wild-type RT; this may reduce the development of further drug resistance mutations and may slow immune escape in treated individuals. To further characterize RT, we studied the role of the HIVA nucleocapsid protein (NC7), a viral chaperone that participates in genomic RNA binding, tRNAlys3 incorporation, and nucleic acid annealing. NC7 plays a role in the processivity of RT and also promotes the first template switch of reverse transcription. We developed an endogenous assay of de novo reverse transcription in lysed virions, and showed that mutations in the NC7 gene reduce reverse transcription over and above decreased genomic RNA incorporation. Mutations which reduced endogenous reverse transcription were associated with decreased infectivity and growth in these viruses. Finally, we used a cell-free assay with mutant NC7 proteins to show that the zinc finger domains are dispensable for full-length strand transfer during reverse transcription. However, NC7 mutant proteins that could not catalyze full-length reverse transcription were still able to promote the annealing of (-)ssDNA and acceptor RNA. This suggests that different biological activities of NC7 are attributable to different domains of the protein.</description><creator>Hsu, Mayla, 1969-</creator><contributor>Wainberg, Mark A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>The fidelity of M184V-containing reverse transcriptase and the role of the nucleocapsid in reverse transcription of HIV-1 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n00w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sv46m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zq21d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Disposal of acid generating sulphidic tailings is a major environmental problem facing the Canadian as well as the international mining and mineral industries. If the deposited tailings are not treated the sulphide minerals oxidise and create an acidic environment. The leachate from such a site is rich in soluble heavy metals and has the potential to contaminate the groundwater as well as the local surface watercourses. This thesis explores an alternative treatment method via ettringite formation, which stabilises and solidifies these highly reactive tailings. Ettringite has the capacity of uptaking other metals into its structure by isomorphous substitution. Ettringite has also a negative surface charge, which makes it a good adsorbent for positively charged cations. Furthermore, the high pH solution required for ettringite formation will cause the precipitation of heavy metals from the solution. Therefore, ettringite in a lime-remediated sulphate rich acid mine drainage system could serve as a physical and chemical stabilization agent, which could also reduce the remediation costs over other commercially available stabilization technology. In order to assess the feasibility of forming ettringite in sulphide rich tailings, a thermodynamic model was used to investigate the optimal geochemical parameters. The model predicts that ettringite is stable over a wide range of compositions and pH. Results presented in this thesis show that the sulphate content of the tailings samples could limit the precipitation of ettringite, and monosulphate could be the end-precipitate. Long-term leachability and durability analysis showed that ettringite can be formed as a stable mineral in lime, fly ash, and aluminum rich sulphidic tailings samples. Ettringite formation reduced the leachability of the heavy metals and improved the geotechnical characteristics of the treated samples. Freeze and thaw analyses showed that formation of ettringite produce a low permeability and high strength tailings sample capable of withstanding harsh environmental fluctuations.</description><creator>Hossein, Mohsen.</creator><contributor>Hassani, Ferri P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Role of ettringite formation in the stabilizationsolidification of sulphide-bearing mine waste</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139371j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq21d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz202</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study combines both descriptive, qualitative analyses of caregiver-child interaction and fine-grained, quantitative analyses of the communicative intentions expressed in conversations between caregivers and their children in two cultural settings. Participants in the study were 10 James Bay Cree families from the northern Quebec communities of Eastmain and Wemindji and 10 Mainstream families from the greater Montreal area. Data were derived from several sources including two-hour videotaped samples of naturalistic caregiver-child interaction, interviews of the caregivers, and informal observation notes. The data from all sources were compared and contrasted to produce qualitative descriptions of the normative structure of caregiving, caregiving activities, and communicative interaction in the two cultural settings. Transcripts of the videotaped data were coded for communicative intention using the Inventory of Communicative Acts - Abridged (Ninio et al., 1994) and were analyzed quantitatively to permit direct cross-cultural comparison of the communicative interaction in the Cree and Mainstream cultures. Three continua of variation between the two cultures in the style of communicative interaction emerged from the qualitative analyses: reactive vs. interactive, comprehension vs. elicitation, and directive vs. child-centred. Comparisons of the communicative intentions expressed in caregiver-child interactions revealed both similarities and differences between the two cultures. The patterns of communicative interaction and the distribution of communicative intentions reflected differences in the structure of caregiving and the stated beliefs and values of the caregivers in the two cultural groups. The implications of the findings for the social interaction theory of language acquisition are discussed.</description><creator>Hough-Eyamie, Wendy P.</creator><contributor>Crago, Martha (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Psychology, Developmental.</subject><subject>Speech Communication.</subject><title>The development of intentional communication : a cross-cultural study of the role of input</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq21n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz202</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fn45b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mid-seventeenth-century England saw numerous religious sects come into existence, one of which was the Calvinistic Baptist group. During the upheaveal of the revolutionary years this group was often accused of heresy by their orthodox/reformed contemporaries. At that time Hanserd Knollys, one of their London pastors, was personally charged with holding heterodox beliefs, in particular, Antinomianism, Anabaptism and Fifth Monarchism. In addition, Knollys has been accused of hyper-Calvinism. This version of Calvinism was held by some eighteenth-century English Calvinistic Baptists. Some Baptist historians have suspected Knollys of holding this teaching in the seventeenth-century, or at least they have felt it necessary to defend him against it. All of these charges are serious, and consequently bring into question Knollys' orthodoxy. This thesis will systematically examine each charge made against Knollys in its context, and comprehensively from Knollys' writings seek to determine if they were valid. Furthermore, this thesis will elucidate Knollys theology, particularly his soteriology, ecclesiology and eschatology.</description><creator>Howson, Barry.</creator><contributor>Klempa, William (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Baptists -- England -- History -- 17th century.</subject><subject>England -- Church history -- 17th century.</subject><subject>Dissenters, Religious -- England -- History -- 17th century.</subject><subject>Baptists -- England -- Doctrines -- History -- 17th century.</subject><subject>Knollys, Hanserd, 1599?-1691.</subject><title>The question of orthodoxy in the theology of Hanserd Knollys (c. 1599-1691) : a seventeenth-century English Calvinistic Baptist</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418p89q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn45b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182m91c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Effluents are neutralized with lime forming a voluminous waste sludge which may slowly redissolve in groundwater. This sludge may also be a significant secondary metal source. The present research aims to develop a concept for metals removal and recovery using stabilized colloidal suspensions of activated silica sol, which acts as a neutralizing agent and an adsorption medium. Silica sol was prepared by firstly acidifying a sodium silicate solution to initiate polymerization, which would ultimately yield a gel. Polymerization was then arrested before gelation by water dilution giving a stabilized, negatively charged sol. Adsorption and precipitation were distinguished by comparing the coloured products from adding silica sol, lime or sodium hydroxide to cobaltous sulphate solution. Studies of dissolved copper/silica sol interactions showed copper adsorption/desorption to be a reversible pH-controlled process, which was monitored 'in-situ' using a cupric specific ion electrode. Dissolved copper values determined by the electrode were identical to those measured by atomic absorption spectrometry (AAS) for solutions at below pH 7. At above pH 7, the electrode showed zero dissolved cupric, but AAS reported some dissolved copper, attributed to desorbed colloidal cupric hydroxide. A copper/sol underflow sharply divided from a clear overflow were the adsorption products. Addition of concentrated sulphuric acid to centrifuged underflow produced a concentrated copper solution and regenerated sol. The separation of two metals (cupric and ferric) using pH control was also demonstrated. Adsorption/desorption cycles were used to remove iron from synthetic effluents producing concentrated iron products. Three consecutive cycles were required to produce 30 g/L dissolved iron, suitable for sewage treatment, from 0.5 g/L iron effluent. Final pH control with lime precipitated desorbed colloidal hydroxides. Good settling characteristics following adsorption/precipitation from synthetic and actual mine effluents were observed. Problems included gypsum build-up, while excess silica addition gave dispersion, high silica losses and no phase separation. Nickel was selectively recovered over iron and magnesium from a tailings pond sludge by acid leaching then solution treatment with activated silica/lime. One adsorption/desorption cycle produced up to a 17 g/L Ni product from 2 g/L Ni leach solution.</description><creator>El-Ammouri, Elias G.</creator><contributor>Distin, P. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Heavy metals removal from effluents by adsorption on activated silica sols by Elias El-Ammouri.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pf614.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182m91c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t7975</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Malaria remains an important public health problem in developing countries. Because of difficulties in control programmes, naturally acquired immunity (NAI) for many is the only factor that limits the number and severity of malaria episodes. To improve scientific knowledge about the determinants of NAI, this study describes the relationship between previous exposure-dependent factors and malaria occurrence in a Brazilian migrant population. Using an open-cohort design, all individuals living in two hypo-endemic rural communities of Peixoto de Azevedo (MT - Brazil) between September 1996 and April 1997 were enrolled. An interview, spleen measurement, blood samples for anti-RESA ELISA-based indices and malaria thick smears were undertaken at baseline. Incident malaria infections were identified through follow-up visits (4-months interval) and lab monitoring. Associations between previous exposure-dependent factors and time to malaria onset or malaria episode frequency were assessed using Cox's proportional hazards or linear regression models. The study population consisted of 521 individuals, mostly males (60.5%), mean age 26.3 (+/-18.0) years, born in hypo or non-endemic malaria areas (63.1%) and living in endemic areas for 11 years, on average. The majority had non-palpable spleens (65.4%) and had experienced malaria during their lifetime (93.0%) and during the last two years (76.1%). A total of 107 (20.5%) individuals were lost to follow-up. The malaria incidence rate was low [101 cases: 4.49 per 100 person-months], and vivax malaria was four times more frequent than falciparum malaria. The anti-RESA index was positively associated (p ≤ 0.003) with indicators of previous-exposure to malaria: age, malaria episodes during lifetime and months lived in mining environments. Higher malaria incidence rates were associated with lower anti-RESA indices [hazard ratio (HR) = 0.979, p = 0.004] and increased malaria episodes during the last two years (HR = 1.049; p &lt; 0</description><creator>Duarte, Elisabeth Carmen.</creator><contributor>Gyorkos, Theresa W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><title>Previous exposure-dependent factors related to protection against malaria in a Braziliam Amazon migrant population : an open cohort study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s1617950.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t7975</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000001847</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present thesis covers two aspects of statistical analysis applied to the genetics of human diseases. First, the significance of LOD-score results for the confirmation of linkage is addressed, with special emphasis on small pedigrees. A new analytical approach is presented for the linkage analysis of heterogenetic traits, using hereditary spastic paraplegia as a model, a disease well suited for the analyses. The critical significance values for confirmation of linkage are evaluated using Bayesian statistics, and empirical P-values for LOD score results are calculated using computer simulation methods. The presented analytical approach resulted in conclusive linkage analyses on small to medium-size families, under the restrictions of genetic heterogeneity. The second part addresses linkage-disequilibrium based fine mapping in the French Canadian population. The performance of five linkage-disequilibrium based fine-mapping methods is evaluated using French Canadian chromosomes with one of three diseases found in this population: oculopharyngeal muscular dystrophy (OPMD), hidrotic ectodermal dysplasia (HED), and sensorimotor polyneuropathy with or without agenesis of the corpus callosum (ACCPN). The gene for OPMD was recently mapped and cloned, allowing us to evaluate the performance of the methods with the OPMD results, and to make predictions about the ACCPN and HED putative gene positions. In addition, a new approach to linkage-disequilibrium based fine mapping is presented using FrenchCanadian ascending genealogies. The method involves two steps. First, the likely founding couple of a mutation-bearing chromosome is identified using a computerised randomisation statistic. Then, using a delete-d jackknife resampling scheme, the distribution of gene mapping estimates is calculated from the count of ancestral recombinants and ancestral meioses joining the identified founding couple to the disease gene carriers. Gene mapping estimates are calculated from each marker individually, and confidence intervals of the estimates are derived from the jackknife distributions. The method, when applied to French Canadian families with OPMD, successfully confirmed the localisation of PABP2 responsible for OPMD and performed better than other linkage disequilibrium-based mapping models.</description><creator>Dubé, Marie-Pierre.</creator><contributor>Rouleau, Guy A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Genetic epidemiology -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Human population genetics -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Genetic epidemiology.</subject><subject>Human population genetics.</subject><title>New approaches in human genetic analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jz90d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000001847</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r04q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The propagation of non-ideal detonations arising from friction, heat transfer and reactions steps involving a competition between exothermic and endothermic reactions (pathological detonations) has been studied theoretically by including source terms in the 1-D conservation equations of momentum and energy. To predict the steady-state non-ideal detonation velocity, the detailed structure of the detonation has been considered. The Generalized C-J Criterion has been used to seek a singularity-free solution from the whole spectrum of possible solutions to the differential equations for the structure. For pathological detonations, the steady-state analysis predicts a detonation velocity in excess of the ideal C-J value in the H2 --Cl2 mixture, in agreement with experimental observations. Unsteady pathological detonation calculations with a simplified two-rate law model have also been carried out. The resulting asymptotically stable detonations are found to be in agreement with the steady-state predictions. For non-ideal detonations due to friction, the Generalized C-J criterion is found to break down for very low detonation velocities. An alternative criterion based on matching the detonation wave with the back boundary condition is used instead. A continuous spectrum of steady-state solutions has been found for detonation velocities ranging from the ideal C-J value down to that of a sonic wave. For activation energies above some critical value, multiple steady-state solutions have been found for a given friction factor, and various detonation regimes have been defined. An unsteady analysis of the transient development of non-ideal detonations due to friction has been carried out to determine whether the solutions from the steady-state analysis can be approached asymptotically. Friction and heat transfer are found to increase the instability of the detonation wave. Oscillatory and even chaotic detonations were observed for values of the activation energies corresponding to stable detonations in absence of source terms (ideal detonation). Moreover, the transient analysis has revealed that in the case of multiple steady-state solutions, only that with the highest detonation velocity could be approached asymptotically. The transient results of detonation with friction and heat transfer have been found to be in qualitative agreement with the experimental gaseous detonations propagating in porous media and in obstacle fields.</description><creator>Dionne, Jean-Philippe.</creator><contributor>Lee, John H. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Theoretical study of the propagation of non-ideal detonations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p201s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r04q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d5951</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The scope of the indium-mediated allylations in aqueous media has been successfully expanded and an improved understanding of the synthetic utility of the reaction has been developed. The range of useful functionalities that can be efficiently produced by the methodology has been increased and the concise construction of naturally occurring and/or biologically significant substrates has been undertaken. We have demonstrated how N-acylimidazoles could be allylated under controlled temperature conditions, in aqueous media furnishing predominantly 4-alkyl-1,6-heptadien-4-ols. The intermediate alpha-alkyl-beta,gamma-unsaturated ketones were present in significant amounts only when the bulk of the acyl or alpha substituents were such that it interfered with a subsequent allylation. An investigation into the efficient production of the homo allylic ketone, independent of bulk was also performed. Success in this light was effected with the introduction of infrequently used, N-acylpyrazoles in a unique Wienreb-amide type role. These substrates also proved useful for the generation of beta-keto esters in a direct manner via a indium-mediated Reformatsky-type reaction in THF. A successful extension of the methodology into the realms of intramolecular carbocylizations proved to be high yielding and exclusive in terms of gamma-regio and cis-diastereoselectivity. The high utility of the reaction was shown with the synthesis of oxygen heterocyles fused with alpha-methylene-gamma-butyrolactones, substrates, which were revealed to be cytotoxic against several cancer cell lines. An easy incorporation of chiral auxiliaries to the cyclization reactions was also introduced, and a path to possibly produce these important compounds in an enantioselective manner, revealed. Indium-mediated allylations in aqueous media also proved useful as a tool for the general construction of paraconic acids, which are naturally occurring, densely functionalized and biologically active 5-membered lactones. A facile route free of labor-intensive tasks was designed and utilized in the production of naturally occurring methylenolactocin and protolichesterinic acid. A further extension to include the synthesis of a related bis -fused lactone, canadensolide, encountered serious problems. Here it was discovered that the reaction of an enolizable allylic indium species with water occurred more quickly than the intended reaction of this species with an aldehyde in an intramolecular cyclization. This, coupled with other results observed throughout our research, revealed that though very useful, the indium-mediated allylation is negatively affected by the presence of gamma-carboxylate groups. While the C-In bond appears to have a low propensity to react with the aqueous media and react quantitatively with appropriate electrophiles, the presence of a gamma-carboxylate group offers the possibility of enol formation leading to the generation of an O-In species that is rapidly protonated. We were therefore able to successfully use the methodology in this circumstance, only for the production of a deoxy analog while canadensolide remained illusive.</description><creator>Bryan, Vernal Jermaine.</creator><contributor>Chan, Tak-Hang (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Indium-mediated allylations in aqueous media : an expansion of the scope and a demonstration of the synthetic utility of the reaction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rn019.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d5951</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322g03g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis studies the problem of language learnability in relation to two different but related sets of structures in Spanish, both involving multifunctional clitic pronouns. The first of these is the reflexive clitic se which is used in impersonal and inchoative constructions. The second is the dative clitic le which appears in certain clitic doubling constructions. In both cases the structures exhibit subtle properties which cannot be readily inferred from the input. In the first place, this study provides a syntactic analysis of the structures related to each of these clitics. Regarding the first of these, the reflexive se, it is suggested that it can be generated in at least two functional positions: as the head of AgrO in impersonal constructions, and as the head of Inner Aspect in the case of inchoatives. In the impersonal construction the theme argument NP moves to check case and ϕ features with se in AgrO, thus triggering agreement on the verb. In the case of the inchoative, the NP moves into the specifier of AgrS. Thus, the NP in the impersonal construction is an object with some subject-like properties, which derive from agreement with the verb. The NP in the inchoative construction is a subject. Regarding the dative clitic le, it is generated as the head of Inner Aspect. The NP which is stranded after a preposition incorporates into the verb must move to Inner Aspect to check case and ϕ features with le. As a result, the NP is interpreted as affected. The process of incorporation in Spanish is subject to several constraints which fall out naturally from this account. In the second place, the problem of learnability is investigated empirically in relation to second language acquisition (SLA) with two empirical studies which look at the grammar of speakers who appear to have reached an end state in their second language. The tasks used in these studies were designed to test the speakers' knowledge of the properties related to the two multifunctional clitics. The subjects included two groups of near-native Spanish speakers, that is, speakers who can pass or almost pass for native speakers, but who learned Spanish as a second language after puberty. One group was made up of English speakers, the other of French speakers. The reason for choosing near-natives is that data from learners who appear to have reached a very high level of proficiency are crucial in determining whether adult learners can in fact acquire a grammar which is indistinguishable from a native speaker grammar. It has been suggested [Bley-Vroman, 1990] that L2 learning is fundamentally different from L1 acquisition and that, as a result, the final state L2 grammar differs in important ways from native speaker grammars. This thesis argues against this position. Results show that L2 learners are able to acquire subtle properties not evident in the input. This suggests that L2 acquisition is constrained by Universal Grammar in the same way as L1 acquisition is.</description><creator>Bruhn de Garavito, Joyce L. S.</creator><contributor>Travis, Lisa (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>White, Lydia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Spanish language -- Reflexives.</subject><subject>Second language acquisition -- Evaluation.</subject><subject>Spanish language -- Clitics.</subject><title>The syntax of Spanish multifunctional clitics and near-native competence /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km383.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g03g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579t960</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A general procedure for the solid-phase synthesis of branched oligonucleotide analogs, including some with similar base sequence to the yeast ( Saccharomyces cerevisiae) rp51 mRNA, is described using the automated solid-phase phosphite triester approach. Using readily available phosphoramidite reagents, branch-points were introduced by sequential removal of the phosphate (beta-cyanoethyl or methyl) and silyl protecting groups without detaching the nascent oligonucleotide from the solid-support. This then allowed the extension from the branch-point in the conventional 3',5 ', or the unconventional 5',3' directions, thus affording complete control over the base composition and direction of strand around the branch point. The protocol was modified for the synthesis of msDNA, a DNA/RNA branched chimera. Using a combination of silyl and Fpmp groups for the protection of 2'-hydroxyl functions, a linear oligonucleotide was assembled. Branching was then introduced using the methodology developed for branched DNA. Utilization of capillary electrophoresis (CE) in the analysis of branched nucleic acids was also touched upon. CE proved to be a very powerful technique in the separation and identification of a mixture of four branched oligonucleotides. This technique, CE, was also seen to be an attractive alternative for following the debranching reaction, thus eliminating the need for radioactively labeled substrates. The unique structural properties of branched nucleic acids were exploited in investigation of the association properties of bNAs. By synthesizing branch molecules, capable of forming T:A/T triplexes in the parallel (Hoogsteen) or the antiparallel (reverse Hoogsteen) T:A/T motifs allowed, for the first time, a direct comparison of their relative stabilities. Most of the 0.25 kcal mol-1/TAT base triplet difference in stabilities was seen to come from differences in enthalpy, with the parallel (Hoogsteen) base triplet being more stable. Studies to explore structural effects in the use of a branched adenosine as replacement for nucleotide loops in duplex DNA are also described. Branched oligonucleotides of the type rA[2',5'dC ndA10-5']3',5dC ndT10-3' and rA[2',5' dCn3',3' dA10-5']3', 5dCndT10-3' are shown to form hairpin duplexes with thermal stabilities comparable to or better than that of one with a natural deoxynucleotide loop. Molecular modeling was used to study the conformation of branched hairpin loops. In certain cases branched hairpins adopted conformations similar to the ones seen in naturally occurring super stable RNA hairpins. The branched nucleic acids (bNAs) also proved to be invaluable tools for studying in vitro splicing and the substrate specificity of the yeast debranching enzyme.</description><creator>Braich, Ravinderjit Singh.</creator><contributor>Damna, Masad J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Branched nucleic acids novel probes for studying pre mRNA processing and triple helical DNA</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d5969.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579t960</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zz239</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Under normal conditions the sinoatrial node serves as the pacemaker of the heart. However, under disease states other pacemaker sites can emerge which compete with the sinoatrial node or with each other. This thesis describes theoretical and experimental studies of pacemaker initiation and interaction. The first aspect of this thesis deals with an arrhythmia called modulated parasystole, which is generated by the interaction between the sinus pacemaker and an ectopic pacemaking focus. A mathematical model was developed to study the dynamics of modulated parasystole using discontinuous circle maps. The mathematical model displayed banded chaos, characterized by zero rotation interval width in the presence of a positive Lyapunov exponent. Banded chaos in the parasystole map produces rhythms characteristic of those found clinically. The second aspect of the thesis deals with spontaneous pacemaker activity and interaction using optical mapping techniques and mathematical models. A macroscopic imaging system was designed and constructed that records fluorescent signals from thin preparations over large areas (1 cm2 ) for long time periods (&gt;30 minutes). Rotating waves (rotors) of cellular activity were observed by mapping calcium in nonconfluent cultures of embryonic chick heart cells. Unlike previous observations of rotors or spiral waves in other systems, the rotors did not persist but exhibited a repetitive pattern of spontaneous onset and offset leading to a bursting rhythm. Similar dynamics were observed in simple excitable media models that incorporated spontaneous initiation of activity and a decrease of excitability as a consequence of rapid activity (fatigue). These results provide a mechanism for bursting dynamics in normal and pathological processes. Activation maps were also obtained from the rabbit atrioventricular (AV) node, a small region of the heart with specialized pacemaking and conducting properties. This work determined sites of delay and spontane</description><creator>Bub, Gil.</creator><contributor>Shrier, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Glass, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Optical mapping of pacemaker interactions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm58t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz239</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr34m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation demonstrates that irrationality in representative modernist novels is a significant and valuable feature of subjectivity. Building on contemporary theories of the novel, the thesis develops two closely related issues: the novel as an aesthetic vehicle of subjectivity and the novel as a reflection of its socio-historical moment. In major novels by William Faulkner, Hermann Broch, and Virginia Woolf a surrender to irrationality is paradoxically portrayed as a positive act which can contribute to a more complete fulfilment of the self. Furthermore, twentieth century notions of the self are often expanded, complicated, or revised at least in part through the genre of the novel which is used to represent them. In three main chapters, the thesis draws an original link between studies of the novel as genre on the one hand, and explorations of the meaning of irrationality in early twentieth century fiction on the other. The first on Faulkner includes a section outlining my research into the theoretical domain of subjectivity, irrationality, modernism, and the novel which serves as a background for Faulkner, but remains pertinent also to the chapters on Broch and Woolf which follow. With reference to recent social theorists, philosophers of the novel, medical researchers, and literary critics, the dissertation establishes that Faulkner Broch, and Woolf construct works which advance the notion that irrationality can be conducive to the development of an autonomous, private self which is actively engaged in the outside world. Moreover, in each of the novels at the centre of this study, irrational characters personify an aspect of the novel which is essential to the structural development of the genre. Key works by Faulkner, Broch, and Woolf insist that irrationality is at the core of a dynamic and modernist representation of identity. In novels by Faulkner, irrationality contributes to a flexible sense of time and to the elaboration of a valuable intersubjective communication. In Broch's trilogy, an irrational approach to reality encourages the development of a temporal, ethical, and subjective freedom. For Woolf, the validation of irrational impulses restrains a compulsive and debilitating drive towards introspection and facilitates social interaction.</description><creator>Sautter, Sabine.</creator><contributor>Wihl, Gary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Broch, Hermann, 1886-1951 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Faulkner, William, 1897-1962 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Irrationality and the development of subjectivity in major novels by William Faulkner, Hermann Broch, and Virginia Woolf</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bz98d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr34m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956h571</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aggregate morphologies as a function of apparent pH (PH*) have been studied for PS-b-P4VP diblocks in DMF/H2O. The pH* changes are induced by addition of HCl or NaOH (100 nM to 20 mM). As the pH* increases, the morphology changes from large compound micelles to a mixture of spheres, rods, and vesicles, to spheres, to rods, back to spheres when no acid or base is added, then to rods again, back to spheres again, and finally to a mixture of spheres, rods, lamellae, and vesicles. The interplay of the charge introduction into the corona chains, shielding, and steric-solvation interaction is responsible for the complex behavior. The effect of NaCl on the neutral copolymer and the effect of pH* on a quaternized copolymer are also explored. Thermodynamics of micellization of PS-b-PAA copolymers in DMF/water have been investigated as a function of four variables, i.e. the water content, PS block length, PAA block length, and NaCl concentration. Based on a closed association model, thermodynamic functions (DeltaG, DeltaH, and DeltaS) are estimated. Morphological phase diagrams, as well as kinetics and mechanisms of the rod to vesicle transition for PS-b-PAA diblocks in dioxane/water have been studied. In the study of morphological phase diagrams, the regions of stability are identified for spheres, spheres and rods, rods only, rods and vesicles or rods and bilayers, vesicles or bilayers alone, and for some copolymers, more complex mixtures. Evidence is presented that spheres, rods, and vesicles represent true equilibrium structures. The influence of the water content and polymer concentration on aggregate morphologies and the effect of fractionation on the phase diagram are discussed. The block length dependence of the phase diagram is also explored. It is found that copolymers with long core-forming blocks favor the formation of vesicles, and that for copolymers with short core-forming blocks, vesicles are favored at high water contents and other bilayers at relatively low water contents. In the kinetic and mechanistic study, two consecutive first order relaxation processes are found. In the first, the rod is flattened and then converts to a lamella, while in the second, the lamella closes to form a vesicle. Two relaxation times are explored in terms of the initial water content, size of the jump in the water content, and polymer concentration.</description><creator>Shen, Hongwei, 1966-</creator><contributor>Eisenberg, Adi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Thermodynamic and kinetic aspects of morphological transitions of diblock copolymer self-assemblies in solution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t798f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h571</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bj872</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of age on the structure and functions of the epididymis were studied using the Brown Norway rat model. Striking quantitative and qualitative changes during aging in the histology of the epididymis were observed. Characteristic features of aging, such as increases in basement membrane thickness and massive accumulation of lipofuscin, were found. In addition, epididymis-specific signs of aging such as polymorphism of lysosomes, presence of giant vacuoles and spermiophagy, and a major increase in the number of halo cells were also found. The precise nature of halo cells was demonstrated by using specific antibodies. In epididymides from young adult animals, halo cells are composed of three types of immune cells: helper T cells, cytotoxic T cells and monocytes. The three immune cell types present increased with age in the epididymal epithelium in a segment specific manner. In contrast their numbers did not increase significantly in the interstitial tissue. Furthermore, the concentration of cytotoxic T cells and monocytes-macrophages was enhanced in the epididymal epithelium of aged rats whose epididymal lumen contained few spermatozoa. The recruitment of immune cells might be triggered by the accumulation of damaged epithelial cells, or by sperm antigens leaking through the blood epididymis barrier. Thus, the epididymal microenvironment that is essential for the maturation of spermatozoa could be altered in old age. The effect of advancing paternal age on pregnancy and progeny outcomes was assessed by mating Brown Norway male rats of increasing age with young Sprague-Dawley females. The effects of advancing paternal age on the offspring included an increase in preimplantation loss, a decrease in the average fetal weight on day 20 of gestation, and an increase in early neonatal death. These results indicated that the quality of spermatozoa decreases as males age.</description><creator>Serre, Valérie.</creator><contributor>Robaire, Bernard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Effects of age on the structure of the epididymis and on the fertility and progeny outcome in the brown Norway rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139372t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bj872</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tr00j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The metallic adhesion and tunneling properties of an atomically defined junction were measured and analyzed. The junction consisted of a tip opposing a flat surface in the scanning probe microscopy (SPM) configuration. Measurements were performed in ultrahigh vacuum (UHV) at 150 K. Sub-nN force resolution was achieved on a stiff cantilever beam employing an in-situ differential interferometer. Tips were prepared from W and Ir wire and imaged with atomic resolution in-situ using field ion microscopy (FIM). Ultrasharp tips with an apex radius of 20--30 A were fabricated from single crystal W(111) wire and engineered with FIM to terminate in only three atoms. Calculations indicate that for those tips metallic adhesion forces dominate over van der Waals and capacitive electrostatic forces. The sample was a thin (111) oriented Au film. Metallic adhesion forces and the tunneling current were measured simultaneously for the W-Au system as a function of tip sample separation. In contrast to theoretical simulations the system featured exceptional mechanical stability with adhesive forces of up to 5 nN. In particular no indications of a sudden jump-to-contact, which is commonly believed to be an inherent property of metallic contacts, were found. Furthermore, the range over which the metallic adhesion forces act is four times larger than expected. Experiments with sharp but not atomically defined W tips corroborate those results. The observed long interaction range is discussed in the framework of various models. Some of the consequences of this new property for force microscopy applications are pointed out.</description><creator>Schirmeisen, André.</creator><contributor>Grutter, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Metallic adhesion and tunneling at the atomic scale</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm69k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tr00j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p23g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fast purinergic neurotransmission has recently been shown to be mediated through ionotropic P2X receptors activated by extracellular adenosine 5'-triphosphate (ATP). P2X protein mapping within central nervous system (CNS), P2X channel subunit composition pertaining to relevant native receptor phenotypes, and species-specific differences between mammalian P2X orthologs remain to be investigated. The first manuscript (Le et al., 1998a) reported the regional, cellular, and subcellular localization of P2X4 gene product within adult rat brain and spinal cord structures. P2X4 receptors were shown to be widely expressed on the postsynaptic side throughout the CNS. The second manuscript (Le et al., 1998b) documented a novel P2X receptor phenotype resulting from the heteropolymerization between major central P2X4 and P2X6 subunits. P2X 4+6 heteromultimeric channel phenotypes were characterized by distinct time-dependent protein expression levels and novel pharmacological profiles compared to P2X4 homo-oligomers. The third manuscript (Le et al., 1999) was undertaken based upon similar reasoning as well as experimental strategies as the P2X 4+6 study (Le et al., 1998b). The existence of heteromultimeric P2X1+5 receptors were screened with functional as well as biochemical assays demonstrating that this oligomeric complex gave rise to hybrid properties between homopolymeric P2X1 and P2X 5 subunits. Reciprocal co-purifications between interacting P2X 1 and P2X5 subunits were also demonstrated in this study. The fourth manuscript (Le et al., 1997) reported the molecular cloning of the human ortholog (hP2X5R) of rP2X 5 subunit, which is being the most rare transcript among all reported rat P2X cDNAs to date. hP2X5R subunit was found to be a 422 amino acid-long protein and having 62% homology to rP2X5 receptors. In an effort to contribute to a better assessment of the physiological roles of fast purinergic synaptic signaling (Le et al., 1998a) mediated likely by native receptors generated by heteromultimerization (Le et al., 1998b; Le et al., 1999) while keeping in mind that species-dependent differences between mammalian P2X orthologs (Le et al., 1997) should be taken into account whenever rodent systems would be used for drug screening studies. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Lê, Khanh-Tuoc.</creator><contributor>Seguela, Philippe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Functional and biochemical characterization of central ATP-gated P2x channels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df264.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p23g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Montreal Neurological Institute</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97ks157</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The presence of a sex difference in mutual eye-to-eye contact in dyadic interaction is well documented from late infancy through adulthood with females making more mutual eye contact than males. Only one study (Hittelman &amp; Dickes, 1979) found evidence for this behavior pattern in newborns, but no research has been done to follow-up these findings. Systematic examination of the development of sex differences in mutual gaze behavior can aid in unraveling the differential effects of biological and social influences on the development of gendered social behavior. This project was a longitudinal, within participants replication and extension of Hittelman and Dickes study: Seventy neonates (32 female, 38 male) age 13--112 hours postpartum and their parents participated in the Time 1 data collection, and 23 (9 female, 14 male) infants and their parents were seen a second time at 13--18 weeks postpartum (Time 2). Mutual gaze between the infant and two interacters (1 female, 1 male) was measured, and parents completed the Parental Sex-Typing of Newborns (Paston) Rating Scale to measure their sex-typed perceptions of newborns and young infants. Results indicated: (a) No empirical evidence for sex differences at Time 1; (b) Strong evidence for sex differences in mutual gaze behavior at Time 2 indicating development of this sex-typed pattern in early infancy; (c) The emergence of sex differences in mutual gaze behavior from Time 1 to Time 2 is entirely accounted for by a radical change in female infants' gaze behavior; and (d) Empirical evidence linking mothers' sex-typed beliefs about their infants and infants' sex-typed gaze behavior. Results are discussed within the theoretical contexts of the social learning and biological perspectives. This study demonstrates that infants' sex-typed behavior and mothers' gender-typed perceptions begin early in life. It is concluded that sex differences in mutual gaze behavior are a complex interplay of biological or social forces acting in concert. Subsequent research in this area should focus on the specific forces involved in bringing sex differences in mutual gaze behavior to fruition.</description><creator>Leeb, Rebecca T.</creator><contributor>Rejskind, F. Gillian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Eye contact.</subject><subject>Sex differences (Psychology) in children.</subject><title>Here's looking at you, kid! : sex differences, sex-typing, and mutual gaze behavior in young infants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g910v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks157</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j67315629</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of the pedunculopontine tegmental nucleus (PPTg) in motivation and cognitive functions is controversial. In order to clarify the involvement of this nucleus in learning, rats with N-methyl-D-Aspartate (NMDA) lesions to the PPTg were tested on the acquisition of a delayed non-matching to position task (DNMP) performed in a T-maze. Unlike sham-lesioned rats, animals with PPTg lesions did not learn the task. Analysis of the behavior displayed by the lesions animals, however, suggested that these rats suffered from elevated emotionality or arousal, rather than from learning deficits. This hypothesis was confirmed by demonstrating that the anxiolytic compound diazepam (1 mg/kg) normalized the performance of the PPTg-lesioned rats on the DNMP task and reduced the indices of anxiety displayed by animals with PPTg lesions when tested on the elevated plus maze. These results suggested the possibility that the motivational impairments reported to be induced by PPTg lesions, could also be an artifact of lesion-induced elevation of anxiety or arousal. Thus, in order to verify this hypothesis, it was tested whether diazepam would modify the expression of conditioned place preference (CPP) to morphine and amphetamine in animals with NMDA-induced lesions to the PPTg. Diazepam reversed the effects of the lesion on a morphine CPP but not on an amphetamine CPP. A series of experiments, aimed at characterizing the effects of diazepam on morphine and amphetamine reinforcement in normal rats, showed that diazepam, either systemic or injected in the nucleus accumbens, blocks the reinforcing effects of amphetamine but has no effect on the reinforcing effects of morphine. These results suggest that impairments in CPP learning caused by PPTg lesions do not result from motivational deficits, but are caused by elevated emotionality or abnormal arousal.</description><creator>Leri, Francesco.</creator><contributor>Franklin, Keith (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Cerebral peduncle.</subject><subject>Rats -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Mesencephalic tegmentum.</subject><subject>Maze tests.</subject><title>Analysis of behavioral deficits induced by pedunculopontine tegmental lesions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t371r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67315629</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920fz411</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we performed a detailed study of the thermal conductivity in a wide range of quasicrystals. Three systems were studied: AlPdMn, AlCuFe and AlPdRe, and the samples were in both single and polycrystalline form. A further variable was added by introducing a controlled level of defects. At low temperatures (below 20K), the thermal conductivity is defect limited, being controlled by boundary scattering, two level systems, stacking faults and dislocations. At high temperatures (above 20K), we find the thermal conductivity is limited by intrinsic properties of the quasicrystalline structure and phonon-phonon scattering. From fitting the thermal conductivity to a detailed model we are able to predict the maximum thermal conductivity of a perfect quasicrystal.</description><creator>Legault, Stéphane.</creator><contributor>Strom-Olsen, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Heat transport in quasicrystals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t8008.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz411</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752j48z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Gilles Deleuze makes a paradox of ethics. Throughout his oeuvre, he establishes polarities (affirmation versus negation, difference versus identity, rhizome versus arborescence, etc.), and demonstrates rhetorically a preference for one pole over the other. This would seem to constitute, if not an obligation or imperative, at least an urgency, a suggestion that those who find his discussion compelling should favor that one pole and act in such a way as to promote it or move toward it. However, for a variety of reasons, it proves difficult or even impossible to put this 'ethics' into practice. This thesis examines the reasons for this impossibility through close readings of four of Deleuze's texts, Nietzsche and Philosophy, Difference and Repetition, Anti-Oedipus, and A Thousand Plateaus. In each text, I highlight the polarities, showing where Deleuze's expressed preference lies. Then I demonstrate the obstacles to an implementation of this preference. Moving from text to text, I trace how Deleuze's attempts to deal with the question of ethics change over his career, becoming more sophisticated and opening up new problems and possibilities. Although the nature of the paradox of ethics varies from case to case, I discover at least two difficulties in general. The first concerns the move from the abstract to the concrete: Deleuze often expresses a polarity in abstract or metaphysical terms, which collapses when extended into the concrete. Metaphysically, affirmation is sharply distinguished from negation; where affirmation creates difference, negation levels difference to produce homogeneity. Practically, however, it is impossible to locate this distinction in the world; no person, place, thing, or event can be said to be either affirmative or negative. This relates closely to the second general difficulty, the insertion of the subject. Even if it were possible to make a practical distinction between two poles of value, it is impossible to locate the subject in relation to those poles. That is, even if the world can be said to behave affirmatively or negatively, the subject is only accidentally related to this behavior, and so ethics becomes a purely ontological matter, bearing no relation to the will or intention of a subject.</description><creator>Evens, Aden.</creator><contributor>Lamarre, Tom (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Deleuze, Gilles, 1925-1995 -- Ethics.</subject><title>Practically impossible : Deleuze and ethics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21th157.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j48z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fd48k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Why was it so difficult for European Union countries to establish the European Central Bank? In the 1992 Maastricht Treaty, EU governments committed themselves to an independent, stability-oriented ECB, and to ensuring low inflation rates and low budget deficits. Between 1992 and 1998, they fought over the terms of membership and whether European economic policy should promote growth more than stability. Political parties transmit voter preferences over growth and stability into national policy on the basic priorities of monetary union, while the arrangement of economic institutions reinforces or frustrates the ambitions of a governing coalition. This not only leads to governments with clear priorities that conflict at the European level. Governing coalitions frustrated by economic institutions that thwart their economic policies can promote monetary union in order to force changes domestically. Therefore, conflict arose among stability-oriented governments over whether low budget deficits and inflation were to be achieved before EMU was launched. This reflected the conflict between France and Germany. The dissertation examines the links between the politics of economic policy in France, Germany and Spain, and their policies toward Economic and Monetary Union.</description><creator>Donnelly, Shawn.</creator><contributor>Brawley, Mark R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>European Central Bank.</subject><subject>Monetary policy -- France.</subject><subject>Monetary unions -- European Union countries.</subject><subject>Monetary policy -- Germany.</subject><subject>Monetary policy -- Spain.</subject><title>Explaining commitments to the European Central Bank : the interaction of voter opinion and institutional arrangements in France, Germany and Spain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246t70c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fd48k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87ps10m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cost of testing state-of-the-art integrated circuits keeps increasing as the dimensions shrink and more functionality is incorporated into a single chip. Innovative methods are well established to test digital circuits, but analog circuits still rely on expensive equipment and ad-hoc techniques for their testing. This thesis investigates periodic sigma-delta bitstreams for analog signal generation as a way to enhance analog and mixed-signal circuit testability. By using only a few bits of information, it is possible to generate high quality signals with very low hardware. It will be explained how to create these bitstreams with theoretical and empirical data provided to help in choosing the different parameters. Many types of signals which can be generated using this approach will be studied, along with their circuit implementation. Four silicon implementations, each with different goals targeted towards built-in self-test of analog and mixed-signal circuits, will be analyzed and the results of experimental work will be presented. The technique has also been extended to multi-bit generation, as a way to increases the performance of existing arbitrary waveform generators. Novel calibration techniques are proposed to increase the quality even in the presence of non-linear DACs.</description><creator>Dufort, Benoit.</creator><contributor>Roberts, Gordon W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Analog signal generation using periodic sigma-delta modulated streams</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fz429.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87ps10m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085n02f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the relationship between the community and school in Arctic Bay in north Baffin Island. The objective is two-fold: first, to provide insights into the interaction between Inuit community members and school, and second, to describe and analyze the internal changes that school effects among community members. The central concern underlying the thesis is the ongoing process of Inuit cultural change. This thesis expands the framework for studies in educational anthropology in two ways. First, the thesis examines the interaction between the community and the school from the perspective of the community, rather than from that of the school. Second, it applies anthropological understandings of social structure, social control and social personhood as analytical categories in examining the two cultural contexts. The thesis illustrates the fundamental contradictions in worldview between Inuit and the institution of schooling. Observations of contemporary life illustrate that Inuit have been able to maintain the organizing principles of their kinship system in the transition from pre-settlement life to the community. Observations of socialization in school illustrate that the social norms and interrelational processes young Inuit learn in school contradict some of the organizing principles of Inuit kinship. Moreover, the responsibilities that Inuit adults are required to undertake as parents of school children impinge on their kinship obligations. The thesis concludes that although Inuit have maintained authentic, albeit modified, cultural practice in the community, the socialization of school, a culturally foreign institution, increasingly impinges on their normative values and social relations.</description><creator>Douglas, Anne S.</creator><contributor>Gillell, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Wenzel, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Inuit -- Education -- Sociological aspects.</subject><subject>Inuit -- Education -- Nunavut -- Arctic Bay.</subject><title>"There's life and then there's school" : school and community as contradictory contexts for Inuit selfknowledge</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0968807.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085n02f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):35050</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>