<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:00:31Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15075" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139556v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following offers a new perspective to explain the disintegration of the Peloponnesian League and the Boeotian Federation in the early half of the fourth century B.C. Members of both these alliances had legal and conventional expectations regarding what they had to give and what they could receive from their associations. Tensions and conflicts arose within an alliance once an individual polis did not fulfill its duties and obligations. There were two factors that persuaded a member not to meet their expected responsibilities: one was the role of a polis ' factions and the other was the intervention in the association's affairs by a third party. It was primarily the failure of an alliance's members to meet each others expectations that inevitably led to the dissolution of these interstate organizations.</description><creator>Galatas, Connie.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Boeotian League.</subject><subject>Greece -- History -- To 146 B.C.</subject><subject>Peloponnesian League.</subject><title>Allies for all times? : a study on the disintegration of Greek interstate alliances in the classical period</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b9502.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139556v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s837b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is a taboo surrounding death in our North American culture. We're not sure how to talk about it, or how to connect through it. The HBO series Six Feet Under breaks this taboo with its honest, humorous and moving look at death and dying. There are important lessons to be drawn from this series. Teachers could revolutionize their classrooms as this show has revolutionized television: by dealing with issues that most tend to avoid. Parker Palmer and Mary Rose O'Reilley's views on education provide a foundation for this thesis. First, teachers need to recognize the fragility of their students as well as their own. Second, they need to appreciate that loss comes in many forms, and that mourning is often necessary. Third, teaching needs to create a space for both students and teachers to express themselves. Fourth, this space also needs to exist in order for both teachers and students to truly listen to one another. Fifth, teachers need to change their own perception of death and dying if they expect students to do the same. Last, teachers need to promote the idea of connection with the world outside the classroom. This thesis's intention is to bring awareness and acceptance around death and dying to individuals, particularly teachers, by exploring Six Feet Under through the characters' journeys, and extracting its many valuable lessons.</description><creator>Sweer, Jennifer.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Loss (Psychology) in children.</subject><subject>Children and death.</subject><subject>Bereavement in children.</subject><title>Six feet under : lessons for life and for the classroom</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z7091215.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s837b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816q99z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Marie-Claire Blais's trilogy Soifs, the history of the 20th Century is registered in an inter-cultural and inter-discursive realm both as a history which is "infernal" (chaotic, violent, fragmented) and as one which is civilizing. The objective of this study is to observe and comment on this double inscription, to evaluate how it takes charge of and modulates signs and representations already in circulation in social discourse. The author seeks to discern the inter-discursive work of manipulation and translation of social discourse from a point of view which is at once formal, narrative, linguistic and ideological, to ultimately identify the ideological work of Blais's novels on a fundamental stake within current society: the historical past.</description><creator>Théberge-Cockerton, Sonia Sara, 1981-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>History in literature.</subject><subject>Blais, Marie-Claire, 1939- -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Le XXe siècle en héritage : l'inscription de l'histoire dans la trilogie Soifs de Marie-Claire Blais</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x2734.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816q99z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fg34n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a multimodal sonification system that combines video with sound synthesis generated from motion capture data. Such a system allows for a fast and efficient exploration of musicians' ancillary gestural data, for which sonification complements conventional videos by stressing certain details which could escape one's attention if not displayed using an appropriate representation. The main objective of this project is to provide a research tool designed for people that are not necessarily familiar with signal processing or computer sciences. This tool is capable of easily generating meaningful sonifications thanks to dedicated mapping strategies. On the one hand, the dimensionality reduction of data obtained from motion capture systems such as the Vicon is fundamental as it may exceed 350 signals describing gestures. For that reason, a Principal Component Analysis is used to objectively reduce the number of signals to a subset that conveys the most significant gesture information in terms of signal variance. On the other hand, movement data presents high variability depending on the subjects: additional control parameters for sound synthesis are offered to restrain the sonification to the significant gestures, easily perceivable visually in terms of speed and path distance. Then, signal conditioning techniques are proposed to adapt the control signals to sound synthesis parameter requirements or to allow for emphasizing certain gesture characteristics that one finds important. All those data treatments are performed in realtime within one unique environment, minimizing data manipulation and facilitating efficient sonification designs. Realtime process also allows for an instantaneous system reset to parameter changes and process selection so that the user can easily and interactively manipulate data, design and adjust sonifications strategies.</description><creator>Savard, Alexandre.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Human-computer interaction.</subject><subject>Gesture in music.</subject><title>When gestures are perceived through sounds : a framework for sonification of musicians' ancillary gestures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kx34q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fg34n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z1620</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent work in anthropology has translated systemic disjuncture to individual subjectivity, under the premise that "disordered" political economies cause "disordered" identities. However this work underplays the role of affect in "gathering" subjectivity amidst external transformation. The following thesis proposes a concept of "mood" as a set of conjoined, low-level affects that provides continuity in contexts of neoliberalism and change. It investigates women's "moods" in an urbanizing region of Uttarakhand, India. Drawing from ethnographic interviews in a village, and a migrant community, mood is shown to involve components of capitalist anxiety that articulate with attitudes of docility and duty. Experiences typically described as "postmodern" including "incompleteness", "estrangement" and "alienation", are common to, and produce "classical" gendered affects in both rural and urban settings. Although anxiety can be destabilizing, it joins paradoxically with these affects to lubricate women's sense of "belonging" in a place.</description><creator>Sehdev, Megha</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Hindu women -- India -- Uttaranchal.</subject><subject>Women -- India -- Uttaranchal -- Attitudes.</subject><subject>Mood (Psychology)</subject><subject>Women -- India -- Uttaranchal -- Economic conditions.</subject><title>Moody migrants : the relationship between anxiety, disillusionment, and gendered affect in semi-urban Uttarakhand, India</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644w18c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z1620</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80j0077</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Among the various studies written on the voluminous artistic production relating to the clownish figure in the XIXth century, more specifically on its melancholic form in the second half of the century, very few have carried interest to the novel. The objective of this master's thesis is to study the clown as a novel character, through Gavroche (Victor Hugo, Les Miserables ), Kenwell and Cox (Jules Claretie, Le Train 17) and the brothers Zemganno (Edmond de Goncourt, Les Freres Zemganno ). We will focus on the way those hyperbolic figures spread out their marginality, their laughter and their illusions within the novel, thus providing information on this one. Our analysis of the clown's passage through the novel, which always deploys in three phases (the marginal entrance, the ascension and the fall), demonstrates the incompatibility between the realistic material from the XIXth century and this nevertheless infinitely novelistic being.</description><creator>Gagnon, Evelyne.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Hugo, Victor, 1802-1885. Misérables.</subject><subject>Goncourt, Edmond de, 1822-1896. Frères Zemganno.</subject><subject>Clowns in literature.</subject><subject>Claretie, Jules, 1840-1913. Train 17.</subject><title>Portrait du clown en personnage de roman : A partir de Gavroche (Les misérables), Kenwell et Cox (Le train 17) et les frères Zemganno (Les frères Zemganno)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w581m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80j0077</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795c345</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As we mature, we always change what we think about life, and as we absorb change and evolve within our particular experience, we undergo a personal process of receiving and creating values. Hermans (2001) argues that values define a person and that an analysis of these values is the best way to understand someone and the society of which that person is a part. This thesis is a narrative inquiry into the evolution of values experienced by a laid-off worker in the changing social context of contemporary China. The main body of the thesis consists of three parts: (1) my brother Quan's childhood, (2) my brother's youth in Mao's time, and (3) my brother's experience of becoming a laid-off worker in Deng's time when my brother was in his middle age. I use the life history of my brother to exemplify the lives of those in China who are caught between opposing political directions to provide some insight into China's evolution in the late 20th and early 21st century.</description><creator>Wang, Qian, 1972-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>China -- Social conditions -- 2000-</subject><subject>Unemployed -- China.</subject><subject>China -- Social conditions -- 20th century.</subject><title>A narrative inquiry into the evolution of values experienced by a laid-off worker in China : a view of contemporary China through the eyes of one family</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m294w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795c345</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913t36j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Phaedra and Hippolytus myth is a frequently dramatized narrative of uncontrollable desire. This thesis examines two versions, Euripides' Hippolytus, first presented in 428 B.C. as part of the Athenian festival of Dionysus, and Sarah Kane's 1996 play, Phaedra's Love, first presented as part of the Gate Theatre of London's "new playwrights, ancient sources" series. In each play, Phaedra's desire is constructed according to sociohistorical conditions which are temporary in their cultural significance. Once the moment of creation has passed, so have the conditions in which each version of desire is originally understood. However, these constructions of Phaedra's desire also bear a simultaneously transhistorical quality as they complicate human notions of agency. In the West, therefore, Phaedra's desire is represented as a tragically constructed emotion. This thesis posits desire as transhistorically relevant in its ability to question modes of human subjectivity.</description><creator>Chartrand, Amy.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Desire in literature.</subject><subject>Euripides. Hippolytus.</subject><subject>Kane, Sarah, 1971-1999. Phaedra's love.</subject><title>&amp;quot;What will you do?&amp;quot; : Phaedra's tragic desire and social order in the West</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429d91s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913t36j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj1395574</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Were it necessary to choose two words that could capture the philosophy of Jean-Jacques Rousseau, these two words would have to be truth and nature for, in his works, this philosopher does more than assert that he, and he alone, possesses truth in its entirety. He equally maintains that his sole desire lies in sharing this truth with human kind, that we might rediscover our true nature, one that we have long ago forgotten. In fact, these very words adorn his tomb in the Pantheon where he was finally brought to rest: "Ici repose l'homme de la nature et de la verite." However, upon closer examination of two of his major works, Emile or on Education and The Social Contract, both published in 1762, a surprising contradiction is brought to light. In these treatises, he makes the child and the people believe that they are free when he is merely using rhetoric to manipulate them. For example, in Emile he gives the following advice to tutors: "Take the opposite course with your pupil; let him always think he is master while you are really master. There is no subjection so complete as that which preserves the forms of freedom; it is thus that the will itself is taken captive." While in The Social Contract he recommends using divine intervention to assure that the people "obey freely, and bear with docility the yoke of public happiness." Is Rousseau simply a gifted sophist who, by hiding the rhetoric he uses, can present himself as a man of truth in order to better form the child and the people to do his bidding? Or, is there a justification for his duplicity? Could it be possible that in some instances duplicity must be used if truth is ever to be attained by all human beings? By examining the rhetoric Rousseau uses in Emile and The Social Contract, this thesis attempts to shed some light on this somewhat troubling contradiction.</description><creator>Corbett, Nicole Stephanie-Anne, 1983-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Deception in literature.</subject><subject>Rousseau, Jean-Jacques, 1712-1778 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Truth in literature.</subject><title>Vérité et duplicité dans l'œuvre de Jean-Jacques Rousseau</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p383g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1395574</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kf16v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The designs of two functional magnetic resonance imaging-compatible electronic interfaces for use in neuropsychological studies involving musical tasks are presented. The devices, a two-button response box in the form of a computer mouse and a piano keyboard, were designed for rhythmic tapping and piano performance tasks, respectively. In order to correlate changes in neural activation acquired through magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) with task performance, the electronic collection of behavioural data, such as the timing of button or key presses was required. These behavioural measures were captured electronically and communicated to a host computer for synchronization with feedback, stimuli, and the MRI scanner itself. As well, data was logged for offline analysis. Due to the intense and volatile electromagnetic fields, most commercially-available electronic interfaces do not function properly and can even pose a serious safety hazard within the MRI scanner environment. Therefore these custom-designed interfaces were free of ferromagnetic parts and all electronic components were relegated to the control room outside of the scanner environment. Acquisition of button and key presses was accomplished using fibre optic sensors, which are immune to electromagnetic interference. The devices performed successfully within the scanner, and MRI scans showed no image artifacts caused by the prototypes. Sensing of key and button transition velocity was sufficient after extensive calibration. Next generation prototypes are planned and will implement more robust and tighter tolerance manufacturing, improved sensing techniques, the acquisition of isometric forces, and an auto-calibration scheme.</description><creator>Hollinger, Avrum.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Music and technology.</subject><subject>Human-computer interaction.</subject><subject>Magnetic resonance imaging.</subject><title>Design of fMRI-compatible electronic musical interfaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q974j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kf16v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z1638</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electrical parameter profiles of human breast images can be used to simulate and analyze the anticipated effects on tissue from its interaction with electromagnetic fields involved in the cancer treatment exposure. In part, the success of this approach depends on the accuracy and precision in identifying the different tissue types. In this work, we propose two methods of segmenting human breast images with malignant tumors. The first method of algorithmic partitioning of the image involves manual color-edge contouring of the tissues using a cursor and subsequent identification of the tissue types. For the second method, MRI T1 values and thresholds are used to perform segmentation and we investigate the potential of incorporating edge detection. The first method is effective, while the second lacks precision, but eliminates the need of manual contouring. The images are imported as BMP files into SEMCAD, an electromagnetic simulation tool based on finite-difference time-domain method, which recognizes the grouped tissues and creates a model of the image. The model allows the user to easily assign electrical parameter values to the grouped tissues, according to the measured values reported in the literature.</description><creator>Al-Roubaie, Zahra.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Breast -- Radiography.</subject><subject>Breast -- Diseases -- Diagnosis.</subject><subject>Diagnostic imaging -- Digital techniques.</subject><subject>Breast -- Imaging.</subject><title>Human breast images : segmentation, analysis and conversion to electrical parameter profiles for Semcad-X electromagnetic simulator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dq65n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z1638</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nj25b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For the last few decades, youth behavioral problems have been constantly increasing. As an outcome of the complex interactions of multiple factors, these problems seriously challenge families, the educational system and society. The author presents a multiple case study, with three levels of analysis. Through a qualitative method, subjective data are collected through semi-structured interviews. An individual vertical analysis and a collective horizontal analysis give access to the subjective perspectives of participants (the parent, child and teacher) and the sociocultural context. The results show pattern of life marked by ruptures and conflicts, the need for relation, recognition and guidance. Furthermore, there is a marked absence of communication between the implicated people and spiritual beliefs surrounding this problematic are considered. Intervention avenues are suggested.</description><creator>St-Arnaud, Paula, 1973-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Adolescent Psychology -- Quebec.</subject><subject>Socioeconomic Factors -- Quebec.</subject><subject>Child Psychology -- Quebec.</subject><subject>Child Behavior Disorders -- psychology -- Quebec.</subject><title>Facteurs socioculturels québécois relatifs aux troubles du comportement chez les élèves francophones d'origine Québécoise du secteur public primaire de l'est de Montréal</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s378c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj25b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000003492</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The past decade has seen an increased interest in multiwavelength optical sources. Various methods and technologies exist for developing multiwavelength lasers with varying features and characteristics. A particular category that has gained much interest, are multiwavelength fiber lasers that combine nonlinear gain from stimulated Brillouin scattering with linear gain from erbium doped fibers. This thesis demonstrates experimentally a Brillouin semiconductor multiwavelength fiber laser that utilizes semiconductor optical amplifiers as the linear gain medium. This novel technique allows for multiwavelength Brillouin fiber lasers to operate in any wavelength band for which SOAs are available. We begin by demonstrating a ring cavity configuration with a single wavelength output in the C/L bands. This configuration is enhanced for multiwavelength generation by the addition of a feedback path. The setup is then implemented in the O-band to demonste that the Brillouin fiber laser can be made to operate at any wavelength. Finally, several linear cavity configurations are explored and shown to improve the performance of the multiwavelength output in the O- and C/L- bands.</description><creator>Hayder, Alaa.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Brillouin scattering.</subject><subject>Fiber optics.</subject><subject>Semiconductor lasers.</subject><title>Multiwavelength Brillouin semiconductor fiber lasers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010t54r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000003492</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x733c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Plasticizers are ubiquitous environmental contaminants. Biodegradation of some of these chemicals, such as di(2-ethylhexyl) phthalate (DEHP or DOP), has been shown to lead to the accumulation of toxic metabolic breakdown products. As a result there is a desire to produce new, fully biodegradable, "green" plasticizers. With this goal in mind, a series of tests were developed to be used to measure the plasticizing efficiency of potential green plasticizers. The base resin selected for the study was poly(vinyl chloride) (PVC). The glass transition temperature (Tg) of the plasticized polymer was measured by temperature-modulated differential scanning calorimetry (TMDSC). Tensile tests were carried out on samples of the material from which the tensile strength and the strain at break of the material were measured. The aforementionned properties were measured for PVC plasticized with the commercial plasticizers DEHP, diethylene glycol dibenzoate (DEGDB) and dipropylene glycol dibenzoate (DPGDB) at several plasticizer concentrations. 1,5 pentanediol dibenzoate (PDDB) was synthesized and evaluated as a plasticizer by comparing results for this compound with those for the commercial plasticizers using the developed tests. The depression in Tg and tensile properties were comparable at a fixed composition for blends with PDDB relative to blends with DEHP, DEGDB, and DPGDB. PDDB was subjected to biodegradation unsing co-metabolism by the common soil bacterium Rhodococcus rhodocrous (ATCC 13808). After 16 days of growth, nearly all the PDDB was degraded and only small amounts of transient, unidentified, metabolites were observed in the growth medium during the experiment.</description><creator>Firlotte, Nicolas.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Plasticizers -- Biodegradation.</subject><subject>Benzoates.</subject><subject>Green products.</subject><subject>Plasticizers -- Testing.</subject><title>Mechanical testing and biodegradation of an alternative dibenzoate plasticizer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kb911.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x733c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322j18h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Master's dissertation explored whether a rapid orienting of attention toward or away from social stress information during a restful state, relates to the magnitude of glucocorticoids (GC) released in response to a stressor, the Trier Social Stress Test (TSST). It also assessed whether childhood rearing in a low socioeconomic status (SES) context mediates this relationship. Subjects rested for 45 minutes during which time they completed a modified version of Posner's attention paradigm, comprising social stress words. Immediately following, participants were exposed to the stressor. Results indicated that a rapid attentional engagement toward social stress words associated with pronounced GC responses to the TSST. Fast engagers displayed lower self-esteem and did not differ in terms of their past SES. These findings demonstrate that attentional biases for social stress information at rest combine with diminished self-esteem to predict the magnitude of GC released during psychological stress irrespective of early SES conditions.</description><creator>Pilgrim, Kamala.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Attention -- physiology.</subject><subject>Socioeconomic Factors.</subject><subject>Stress -- physiopathology.</subject><subject>Hydrocortisone -- secretion.</subject><title>Mechanisms underlying cortisol reactivity to stress in low and high socioeconomic status individuals : role of naturally-occurring attentional biases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fc73z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322j18h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f470t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mine production schedule defines the sequence of extraction of selected mine units over the life of the mine, and consequentially establishes the ore supply and total material movement. This sequence should be optimized so as to maximize the overall discounted value of the project. Conventional schedule approaches are unable to incorporate grade uncertainty into the scheduling problem formulation and may lead to serious deviations from forecasted production targets. Stochastic mine production schedulers are considered to obtain more robust mine production schedule solutions. The application of stochastic approaches to the mine production schedule problem is recent and additional testing is required to better understand these tools and to define the value of a stochastic solution as compared to the conventional result. Two stochastic schedulers are tested in a low-grade variability copper deposit, optimization parameters are discussed and their results compared with a conventional schedule. The first method uses a stochastic combinatorial optimization approach based on simulated annealing to address the mine production schedule problem. The method aims for maximization of the net present value (NPV) of the project and minimization of deviations from the production targets. These objectives are attained by incorporating grade uncertainty into the mine production schedule problem formulation. The second method formulates the problem as a stochastic integer programming problem, in which the objective is the maximization of the projects' NPV and the minimization of production targets deviations. The model can also manage how the risk of deviating from the targets is distributed between production periods. Both stochastic approaches were tested in a low-grade variability copper deposit. In both case studies, the value of a stochastic solution is demonstrated to be higher than the conventional one. This fact demonstrated the misleading results that a conventional schedule may produce and shows the importance of not ignoring the presence of uncertainty when defining the mine production schedule for a project.</description><creator>Nascimento Leite, Andre.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Strip mining -- Planning.</subject><subject>Mathematical optimization.</subject><subject>Stochastic processes.</subject><title>Stochastic optimization approaches to open pit mine planning : applications for and the value of stochastic approaches</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042x58c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f470t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rp72g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neck pain is an increasing problem in industrialized societies. Research is necessary to find ways to objectively measure neck dysfunction. The purpose of this Master's project was to examine the test-retest properties of a dynamometric system for neck force measurements and to obtain reference measures on isometric cervical strength in a healthy population. Twenty-eight healthy subjects participated in this study; 16 males and 12 females. Cervical strength was measured using the MCU(TM) Multi-Cervical Unit (BTE Technologies(c)) in six directions: flexion, extension, protraction, retraction and right and left lateral flexion. The test-retest reliability was good to excellent (≥ 0.85) for all directions. Males were on average 58% stronger than females, with the greatest difference in t1exion. The standard error of measurement and minimal detectable change values were found to be much smaller than the average strength measures. Studies are needed to address the implementation of the MCU in clinical settings.</description><creator>Reichert, Alison.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Cervical vertebrae.</subject><subject>Neck.</subject><title>Test-retest properties of objective maximal neck force measures in a population of healthy adults</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451n102.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rp72g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655k97v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the most difficult and serious challenges facing the mental health professional is the prevention of suicide. Efficient prevention, however, depends on early detection of patients at risk for suicidal behaviour, which in turn depends on a better understanding of the predisposing factors. Over the last years, based on a large volume of data, it has become increasingly clear that subjects who commit suicide present high levels of impulsive and impulsive-aggressive behaviours. In the first approach, we investigate whether levels of the impulsive aggressive diathesis were more important in suicide occurring at different life stages. In the second, we investigate whether levels of the diathesis predicted when during the course of major depressive disorder suicide occurs. Family studies have consistently indicated that suicidal behaviour tends to cluster in families. However, relatives also present increased risk for psychiatric morbidity, and therefore, the critical question is whether or not the liability to suicidal behavior is given by the same predisposition to the coexistent psychiatric disorders. Therefore, in the third study, we examined the independence of familial liability using a three group design. The relatives of deceased suicide probands who died in the context of a major depressive episode are compared to the relatives of living depressed subjects without a history of suicide and to the relatives of healthy controls screened for the absence of major depression and suicide.</description><creator>McGirr, Alexander.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Impulse Control Disorders -- psychology.</subject><subject>Suicide.</subject><subject>Aggression -- psychology.</subject><subject>Depressive Disorder, Major -- psychology.</subject><title>The role of impulsive and impulsive aggressive behaviours in the risk for suicide and the familial transmission of suicidal behaviours /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72pb876.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655k97v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c605g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite their environmental benefits, wind farms, have attracted controversy with regard to their impacts on birds. These impacts include collision risks, direct and indirect habitat loss and barrier effects. The main objectives of this study were to determine whether the Baie-des-Sables wind farm, located on the south shore of the St-Lawrence River, is having an impact upon the spring migration of raptors. Emphasis was placed on comparing the differences between both behaviour and abundance of migrating raptors between the wind farm and a contr9l area. Three aspects of behaviour were recorded; altitude, change in direction and flight type. No significant differences were found between the wind, farm area and the control area with respect to migratory behaviour and abundance of any species. Low-lying topography and the fact most migratory raptors flew above blade height likely explain why no differences were found between the wind farm and control area.</description><creator>Ross Boulianne, Michael, 1982-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Birds of prey -- Migration -- Québec (Province) -- Baie-des-Sables.</subject><subject>Wind power plants -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Baie-des-Sables.</subject><title>Assessing the effects of the Baie-des-Sables (Quebec) wind farm on the spring migratory behaviour and abundance of raptors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn91m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c605g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z9033476</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In response to Tibetan social pressures in the 11th century, Atisa initiated a renewal of Buddhist monasticism that resulted in all Buddhist praxis outside of meditation being strictly framed by attitudes and behaviors informed by love and compassion. Atisa's teachings are exemplified in pithy sayings that point to the heart of bodhisattva practice, and this mind training practice developed into a tradition in the period immediately following his passing. The success of the method, and of the emulation of Atisa as exemplar of a perfect bodhisattva, led to the adoption of mind training throughout Tibetan Buddhism. "Tibetan Mind Training: Tradition and Genre" explains the relation between a native Tibetan literary genre and monastic Buddhist practice found in the 14th century compilation Mind Training: The Great Collection (theg pa chen po blo sbyong rgya tsa). The introduction provides context and presents methodology. Chapter one argues that 'blo sbyong' should be translated as 'mind training.' Chapter two has two broad arguments: a rebuttal of a conception of mind training as an essentially psychological preparation for other practices; and an explanation of its praxis as the interaction of mind and real objects. Chapter three explains the relation of mind training praxis and tradition, with reference to Atisa's reforms. Chapter four explains some characteristics of the literary genre of mind training.</description><creator>Troughton, Thomas, 1964-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Tibetan literature.</subject><subject>Buddhism -- China -- Tibet.</subject><subject>Buddhist monasteries -- China -- Tibet.</subject><title>Tibetan mind training : tradition and genre</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397c774.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9033476</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hd278</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1968, a study demonstrated that consolidated memories can be affected again if they are reactivated. Given the importance of the stress hormones glucocorticoids (GCs) on memory consolidation, the goal of the current study was to assess whether GCs had the capacity to affect a reactivated long-term memory and whether neutral and emotional memories were affected differently. At the first session, participants encoded a movie containing neutral and emotional scenes. Two days later, they recalled the story. Half of them were then exposed to a psychosocial stressor. Memory performance was assessed again right after the stressor and five days later. The stressed group recalled less neutral material five days after the stressor compared to controls. Immediately after the stressor, the stressed group recalled more emotional material than controls. Moreover, this enhanced memory trace was maintained across time. This highlights the importance of minimizing exposure to stressful contexts when reactivating emotional memories.</description><creator>Marin, Marie-France.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Emotions -- physiology.</subject><subject>Stress, Psychological -- physiology.</subject><subject>Memory -- physiology.</subject><subject>Hydrocortisone -- secretion.</subject><title>Immediate and delayed effects of stress on a reactivitated declarative long-term memory trace</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k1633.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hd278</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vc074</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the major unresolved questions in cancer biology is why the majority of tumour cells express mutant p53 proteins. p53 is considered the prototype tumour suppressor protein, whose inactivation is the most frequent single genetic event in human cancer (Bourdon et al., 2005). Genetically-engineered p53-null knockout mice acquire multiple tumours very early on in life and human Li-Fraumeni families who carry germline mutations in p53 are highly cancer-prone (reviewed in Vousden and Lane, 2007). p53 mutant proteins have been found to acquire novel functions that promote cancer cell proliferation and survival, yet exactly why mutant p53s acquire oncogenic activity is still poorly understood. Mutant p53 has also been found to complex with wildtype p53, thus acting in a dominant negative way. However, this inhibition is incomplete since many cancers with mutant p53 alleles also have a loss of the second wild-type p53 allele and thus only express the mutant p53 (Baker et al., 1989). An N-terminal truncated p53 isoform, p47, arising from alternative splicing of the p53 gene (Ghosh et al., 2004) or by alternative initiation sites for translation (Yin et al. , 2002), has been described. Alternative splicing was found to be universal in all human multi-exon genes (Wang et al., 2008) and therefore determining the role of the p47 isoform with respect to the p53 gene is essential. Evidence in this study suggests that mutant p53 (p53RI75H) has a similar structure and function as p47, including the ability to complex with and impair both p53 and p73. Therefore, in addition to expressing a tumour suppressor protein, the p53 gene can also express an onco-protein (p47). This study therefore argues that tumours select for mutant p53 because it has gained the ability to function like p47, a wild-type p53 isoform.</description><creator>Marini, Wanda.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Tumor Suppressor Protein p53 -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Alternative Splicing.</subject><subject>Nuclear Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Tumor Suppressor Protein p53 -- genetics.</subject><subject>Intracellular Signaling Peptides and Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><title>Comparing mutant p53 and a wild-type p53 isoform, p47 : rationale for the selection of mutant p53 in tumours</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qd23c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vc074</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816r00h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This project explores the power dynamics within the Iranian political system, asking what accounts for the rise and fall of a president's power relative to the other dominant formal and informal institutions in Iran. Comparing perspectives that focus on charisma, ideology and political bargaining, I argue that the relative power of the president is contingent on a variety of institutional and behavioural factors which define his ability to bargain within an institutional structure of overlapping spheres of control. Within this study, I challenge the traditional emphasis on process as a point of departure for analyses, and stress the need for a change in orientation to effect or output. Finally, I argue that the extensive factionalism within Iranian politics defines the political system and is integral to the cost-benefit calculations of various actors within the institutional matrix of the state.</description><creator>Jacobsen, Donavan.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Presidents -- Iran.</subject><subject>Iran -- Politics and government -- 1997-</subject><subject>Iran -- Politics and government -- 1979-1997.</subject><title>The rise and fall of presidential power in Iran /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80j008h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816r00h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hw178</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis offers a revaluation of the role played by Akramiya and Islam in the events of 13 May 2005 in Andijan. Using Scott's concept of the hidden transcript coupled with a Marxist analysis of the Uzbek state, this thesis suggests that the insistence on public conformity demanded by the state's secular nationalist project, in the context of a political economy of exploitation, creates dissonance with regards to the meaning of Islam among popular classes. Akramiya proposed a vision of Islam in tune with notions of moral economy. The protest constituted the public affirmation of an emerging intersection between class-based and religious identities. The temerity of the protestors when faced with increasing levels of violence was a reaction to the psychological effects of domination and the emotions associated with participation in an open act of defiance within the context of oppressive authoritarian rule.</description><creator>Herk, Christian.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Andizhon (Andizhon viloi︠a︡ti, Uzbekistan)</subject><subject>Insurgency -- Uzbekistan -- Andizhon (Andizhon viloi︠a︡ti).</subject><title>Unpacking Andijan : a critical synthesis of reports dealing with the events of 13 May 2005</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612s062.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hw178</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nz166</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:32:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The intracellular human pathogen Salmonella enterica serovar Typhi (S. typhi) causes the systemic disease known as typhoid fever. This disease afflicts approximately 17,000,000 people every year, of which over 600,000 cases are fatal. Sequencing of the S. typhi genome has allowed a better understanding of the pathogenesis caused by this bacterium. In silico research on the genome sequence identified three open reading frames, termed prpZ gene cluster, present in the Ty2 and multi-drug resistant CT18 strains of S. typhi but absent in all other sequenced serovars of S. enterica. Further analysis of this gene cluster revealed that the three genes are transcribed as an operon that encodes two eukaryotic-like Ser/Thr kinases (PrkX and PrkY) and a protein phosphatase 2C (PP2C) (PrpZ). A previous study has shown that the recombinant His-PrpZ protein has all the hallmarks of a PP2C. Typically, PP2Cs hydrolyze phosphoserine and phosphothreonine residues. In addition, His-PrpZ was found to hydrolyze phosphotyrosine residues, making it a dual specificity phosphatase. A subsequent investigation implicates the prpZ gene cluster in S. typhi virulence as the survival of a prpZ operon deletion mutant is compromised after 48 hours of macrophage infection when compared to wild type bacteria. It is clear from these results that the prpZ operon plays a role in the pathogenesis of S. typhi. To determine the role of these three genes in virulence, an in vitro characterization of PrkY was carried out as well as an examination of the possible physiological roles of PrpZ. We have demonstrated that PrkY is an active protein kinase capable of phosphorylating artificial substrates in the presence of Mg2+ and/or Mn2+. Optimal phosphorylation of substrates is achieved in the presence of 5mM Mg2+ at pH 8.0. In addition, we have identified a putative interaction between PrkY and PrpZ, leading to an inhibition of the kinase activity of PrkY. While exploring the possible physiological functions of PrpZ, we have found that this protein is secreted by Ty2 S. typhi in both LB and in the low pH, low phosphate and low Mg 2+ LPM medium. These findings suggest that PrkY and PrpZ may have antagonistic effects in a S. typhi specific virulence pathway involved in the modulation of host cell signaling by secreted bacterial virulence factors.</description><creator>Gros, Pierre-Paul.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Protein-Serine-Threonine Kinases -- genetics.</subject><subject>Virulence Factors -- genetics.</subject><subject>Salmonella typhi -- genetics.</subject><title>The characterization of PrpZ and PrkY, two eukaryotic-type proteins of Salmonella enterica serovar Typhi /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mj944.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nz166</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15100</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>