<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:07:30Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):4500" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s2564</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le gaufrage d'un film est un précède mécanique dans lequel un film plat est transformé en un produit gaufre. Durant le précède, des champs thermiques et de tension sont appliques sur le polymère, causant des changements dans la microstructure et les dimensions physiques de la matière. L'analyse technogéniques du précède requiert l'étude de différents aspects ayant rapport à la caractérisation de la microstructure avant et après le gaufrage. Une variété de techniques a été utilisée pour caractériser les propriétés et la microstructure de films gaufres par rapport a: la cristallinité, l'orientation, les propriétés mécaniques et les dimensions des films gaufres. Des modèles mathématiques ont aussi été développes afin de prédire la température, la tension et la déformation du film de plastique pendant le gaufrage. […]</description><description>Film embossing is a mechanical process in which a flat film is transformed into an embossed product. During the process, thermal and stress fields are applied to the polymer, causing changes in the microstructure and physical dimensions of the material. The engineering analysis of the process requires the study of various aspects relating to the characterization of the microstructure before and after embossing. A variety of experimental techniques were employed to characterize the properties and microstructure of embossed films in relation to: crystallinity, orientation, mechanical properties and dimensions of the embossed films. Mathematical models were also developed to predict the temperature, stress and deformation in the plastic films during embossing. […]</description><creator>Haber, Andrew</creator><contributor>Kamal, M. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1990</date><subject>Thermoplastic film</subject><title>An engineering analysis of the thermoplastic film embossing process</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cd218.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s2564</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr90z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experimental results are presented for electrode erosion on copper cathodes in magnetically rotated arcs in a steam plasma medium. Arc currents of lOO A, gas pressures of 1.1 atm. and a transverse magnetic field of 0.11 Tesla were generally used. The arc voltage and arc velocity were measured and the erosion rates determined by weight loss after chemical cleaning. The test results with steam showed an increase in arc velocity and arc voltage and a decrease in the cathode erosion rate as the concentration of steam in argon increased. For pure steam, the arc velocity was 56 m/s vs. 2 m/s for Ar, the erosion rate was evaluated at 2.3 pg/C vs. 14.8 pg/C for Ar and the measured arc voltage was 193 V vs. 44 V for Ar. […]</description><description>Les résultats expérimentaux de l'érosion des cathodes en cuivre, par un arc souflé par un champ magnétique, dans une plasma de vapeur d'eau, sont présentés. Un courant d'arc de 100 A, une pression de 1.1 atm. et un champs magnétique de 0.11 Tesla ont généralement été utilisés. La tension et la vitesse de l'arc ont été mesurées et le taux d'érosion calculé d'après la perte de masse après nettoyage chimique. Les essais avec des concentrations croissantes de vapeur d'eau dans l'argon ont résulté en une hausse de la tension et de la vitesse de l'arc et en une baisse du taux d'érosion de la cathode. Avec de la vapeur d'eau pure, la vitesse de l'arc était de 56 m/s vs. 2 m/s avec l'argon, le taux d'érosion a été évalué à 2.3 ug/C vs. 14.8 pg/C avec l'argon et la tension de l'arc était de 193 V vs. 44 V avec l'argon. […]</description><creator>Habelrih, Maysaa</creator><contributor>Munz, R. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1990</date><subject>Steam plasma</subject><title>Electrode erosion in steam plasma</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp75x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr90z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s257d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Kant's rejection of rationalism starts in 1755 with the analysis of Leibniz's two metaphysical principles. Kant's preoccupation in this first essay is the source of necessity. He shows the logical nature of Leibniz first principle and the weaknesses of the second. He finally demonstrates the falsity of the corollaries. This final step directs Kant to a recognition of the over intellectual nature of Leibniz' s method. In 1763, Kant writes Versuch, den Begriff der negativen Grossen in die Weltweisheit einzuffihren and it is there that he finds the source of the necessity that he was seeking. By distinguishing between logical opposition and real opposition, Kant is directed to the notion of causality. He concludes that the causal connection of the principle of sufficient reason is real and necessary and not logical. This conclusion leads Kant directly to the problem of the first critique, the possibility of the synthetic judgments apriori.</description><description>Le rejet du rationalisme par Kant débute en 1755, avec une analyse des deux principes métaphysiques de Leibniz. Dans ce premier essai, la source de la nécessité est la préoccupation de Kant. 11 fait ressortir l'aspect logique du premier, les faiblesses du second et, finalement, il démontre la fausseté des corollaires. Avec la fausseté des corollaires Kant reconnait l'intellectualisme de la méthode de Leibniz. En 1763, il écrit l'essai pour introduire en philosophie le concept de grandeur négative, on il trouve la source de la nécessite qu'il recherchait. En distinguant l'opposition logique de l'opposition réelle, Kant s'adresse A la notion de causalité. Il conclut que la liaison causale inhérente au principe de raison suffisante est une liaison causale réelle et non une liaison causale logique. Cette conclusion mène Kant directement au problème de la première critique, soit la possibilité des jugements synthétiques a priori.</description><creator>Beaupré-Dubois, Louisette.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Leibniz, Gottfried Wilhelm, Freiherr von, 1646-1716.</subject><subject>Kant, Immanuel, 1724-1804 -- Views on rationalism.</subject><subject>Rationalism.</subject><title>Kant et le rejet du rationalisme</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z75z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s257d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vd85g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The inability to measure where an annihilation photon interacts within a detector crystal limits PET resolution uniformity by blurring the outer regions of the image. This problem is solved by dividing a scintillation crystal along its length into two regions, by a black absorbing band, that are equally likely to absorb a PET photon. Light collected from the front and back of the crystal allow the region of photon interaction and photon energy to be determined, using dual parameter acquisition. The design was tested by sweeping a radiation beam across a bismuth germanate crystal detector. The percentage of incorrectly positioned events was no more than 10% and the energy signal amplitude varied by less than 6%. </description><description>L'uniformité de la résolution spatiale de la TEP est limité par l'incapacité de déterminer ou un photon d'annihilation est absorbé dans un détecteur a scintillation, ce qui brouille la réqion exterieure de l'imaqe. ce problème est résolu en divisant un cristal en deux reqions, avec une bande noire, qui ont une probabilité éqale d'arreter un photon. La lumière collectée a l'avant et a l'arriere du cristal permet de déterminer la réqion d'interaction du photon et 1 16nerqie du photon avec un système d'acquisition a deux paramètres.Le détecteur a été évalué en balayant un faisceau des rayons qammas sur un cristal de qermanate de bismuth. Le pourcentaqe des événements mals positionés n'était plus que 10% et l'amplitude du siqnal d'énerqie a varié moins que 6%. </description><creator>Bartzakos, Peter</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Photons</subject><title>Measuring the depth of interaction of pet annihilation photons in scintillation crystals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f5931.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd85g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z7090163</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il existe de nombreuses conceptualisations rivales de la maladie, notamment des définitions éminemment normatives et des démarches qui seraient dénuées de valeur ou des démarches structurelles/fonctionnelles. Le manque de clarté du concept de maladie a donné lieu à un élargissement de cette notion, surtout au royaume de la psychiatrie. Des notions plus globales de la maladie ont multiplié les astreintes qui s'exercent sur les systèmes et les professionnels de la sante, également le prétexte de l'excuse médicale dans les tribunaux et au travail et ont influe sur la façon dont la société réagit aux problèmes de responsabilité. Nous proposons de définir la maladie comme une avarie de l'intentionnalité corporelle, le concept d'intentionnalité corporelle constituant une norme par rapport a laquelle il est possible de juger si la maladie est présente ou non. Le concept d'intentionnalité corporelle provient partiellement de la théorie de !'action. Cette nouvelle définition nous sert alors à évaluer la classification psychiatrique des dérèglements mentaux, la DSM 111, tandis que nous nous interrogeons sur ses répercussions générales sur divers secteurs de responsabilité. </description><description>There are numerous competing conceptualizations of disease, including highly normative definitions and purportedly value-free or structure/ function approaches. The lack of clarity of the concept of disease has led to broadening of the notion of disease, especially in the realm of psychiatry. More inclusive concepts of disease have increased demand on health-care systems and professionals, have increased use of the medical excuse in the courtroom and in the workplace, and have affected the ways in which society responds to issues of responsibility. It is proposed that disease can be defined as the breakdown of bodily intentionality, where the concept of bodily intentionality provides norms against which to_ judge whether disease is present. The concept of bodily intentionality is derived in part from action theory. This new definition is then used to evaluate the prevailing psychiatric classification of mental disorders, DSM 111, and general implications for various areas of responsibility are investigated.</description><creator>Giesbrecht, Harvey</creator><contributor>Norton, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Medicine -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Responsibility.</subject><subject>Mental illness -- Philosophy.</subject><title>Disease and responsibility</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246v29v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z7090163</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21th81t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Au cours d'un essai preliminaire, pour le developpement d'un systeme bon marche, de saisie des donnees geophys1ques, 32 Ko de memoires vives furent ajoutees a un ordinateur VIC-20 de Commodore, pour enregistrer les donnees. Le systeme actuel comprends deux unites independantes: 1) une interface de conversion analogique-numerique, ayant une resolution de 8 bits, et possedant 16 canaux d'entree. 2) une interface de telemetrie, utilisant la modulation de frequence pour la transmission des donnees, sur un canal. Les essais de laboratoire et sur les lieux ont confirme l'utilite du convertisseur analogique-numerique, dans un grand nombre d'applications telles que la numerisation des formes d'ondes et le controle des evenements.  D'excellentes transmissions I , I I et receptlons de donnees furent realisees par cable, sur une distance de 100 metres. La transmission par radio a tres faible-portee (&lt;45m' etres) utilisant la Bande Publique, fut en general, une reussite, et ou l'interference est faible, la receptlon correcte des donnees peut etre augmentee audela de 120 metres. Le developpement se poursuit.</description><description>In a preliminary development of an inexpensive system of geophysical data acquisition, 32K of Random Access Memory was added to a Commodore VIC-20 computer to store the sampled data. The present system comprises two independent units: 1) an eight-bit , 16-channel analog-to-digital converter interface. 2) a telemetry interface that uses frequency modulation over one channel. Laboratory and field tests confirmed the usefulness of the analog-to-digital converter in a large number of applications such as waveform digitization and event monitoring. Excellent transmission and reception of data was accomplished via cable links, over a distance of about 100 meters. Very short-range (&lt;45 meters) radio telemetry over the Citizen's Band frequency was successful in general and where interference is low, error-free data reception can be extended to more than 120 meters. The development is continuing.</description><creator>Momayezzadeh, Mohammed</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Geophysics -- Measurement -- Data processing.</subject><subject>Geophysics -- Data processing.</subject><title>An inexpensive system of geophysical data acquisition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m4233.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21th81t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644t93h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Postmodernism lives. It thrives, it beckons, and it torments. But it most definitely exists. Few critics can deny it, and that is perhaps the only point where most of them can agree. As Douwe Fokkema puts it, “Much to the embarrassment of the literary historian, the term postmodernism has become a household word even before there was time to establish its meaning." (vii). While some critics claim that it exists as an extension of modernism and others submit that it is an entirely new direction, very little consensus can be reached over the question of how exactly one gains membership to the club. One thing the debate serves to show is that postmodernism is far from a unified movement. […] </description><creator>Young, Lee Scott.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Postmodernism</subject><title>Games for adults : a play in two acts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w663.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t93h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bw845</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The central theme of this thesis is one of ascertaining the contemporary international legal norms which govern the nationalization of property of aliens in underdeveloped countries. The thesis defines the conceptual scope and content of the 'regime' of nationalization; draws a clear conceptual distinction between nationalization and other types of property "takings"; and argues, by employing a historicist approach, that those ·norms which traditional international law evolved in connection with "takings" of the "expropriation- type” do not apply over nationalization incidents that take place in underdeveloped countries in the contemporary period. The author of thesis, then, suggests that the appropriate rules should be sought, instead, in the "norm-generating" works of the U.N., and argues that international controversies which arise from contemporary nationalization incidents should be resolved pursuant to the new juridical norms that emanate from the authoritative body of international consensus which evolved within the U.N. machinery. </description><description>Le thème central de cette thèse est celui de vérifier les normes légales internationales contemporaires qui régissent la nationalisation de la propriété des étrangers dans les pays sous-développés. La thèse définit l'étendue et le contenu conceptuels, du régime de la ·nationalisation; établit une nette distinction conceptuelle entre le nationalisation et d’autres genres d'appropriations; et argumente, en employant une approche historiciste que ces normes que le droit international traditionnel a dégagées par rapport aux prises en main du "genre expropriation", ne s'appliquent pas aux incidents de nationalisation qui ont cours dans les pays sous-développés depuis la période contemporaine. Par conséquent, l'auteur de cette thèse suggère que les règlements appropries devraient être pulses, plutôt, dans les travaux « générateurs de normes » des N.U., et poutient que les controversis internationales qui surgissent à cause d'incidents dus à la nationalisation contemporaire devraient être résolues, con conformémens aux nouvelles normes juridiques émanant d'un confus de concencus international faisant autorité, qui se dégagèrent au sein de l'apparatus des N. U . </description><creator>Sharew, Getachew</creator><contributor>Cohen, Maxwell (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1983</date><subject>Nationalization</subject><subject>The United Nations</subject><subject>Legal norms</subject><title>Contemporary Trends in the Evolution of the International Legal Norms Governing Nationalization of Property of Aliens in Underdeveloped Countries with Special Emphasis on the Juridical Implications of the Works of the United Nations : Volume 5</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924f04p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw845</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75rb11r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The central theme of this thesis is one of ascertaining the contemporary international legal norms which govern the nationalization of property of aliens in underdeveloped countries. The thesis defines the conceptual scope and content of the 'regime' of nationalization; draws a clear conceptual distinction between nationalization and other types of property "takings"; and argues, by employing a historicist approach, that those ·norms which traditional international law evolved in connection with "takings" of the "expropriation- type” do not apply over nationalization incidents that take place in underdeveloped countries in the contemporary period. The author of thesis, then, suggests that the appropriate rules should be sought, instead, in the "norm-generating" works of the U.N., and argues that international controversies which arise from contemporary nationalization incidents should be resolved pursuant to the new juridical norms that emanate from the authoritative body of international consensus which evolved within the U.N. machinery. </description><description>Le thème central de cette thèse est celui de vérifier les normes légales internationales contemporaires qui régissent la nationalisation de la propriété des étrangers dans les pays sous-développés. La thèse définit l'étendue et le contenu conceptuels, du régime de la ·nationalisation; établit une nette distinction conceptuelle entre le nationalisation et d’autres genres d'appropriations; et argumente, en employant une approche historiciste que ces normes que le droit international traditionnel a dégagées par rapport aux prises en main du "genre expropriation", ne s'appliquent pas aux incidents de nationalisation qui ont cours dans les pays sous-développés depuis la période contemporaine. Par conséquent, l'auteur de cette thèse suggère que les règlements appropries devraient être pulses, plutôt, dans les travaux « générateurs de normes » des N.U., et poutient que les controversis internationales qui surgissent à cause d'incidents dus à la nationalisation contemporaire devraient être résolues, con conformémens aux nouvelles normes juridiques émanant d'un confus de concencus international faisant autorité, qui se dégagèrent au sein de l'apparatus des N. U . </description><creator>Sharew, Getachew</creator><contributor>Cohen, Maxwell (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1983</date><subject>Nationalization</subject><subject>The United Nations</subject><subject>Legal norms</subject><title>Contemporary Trends in the Evolution of the International Legal Norms Governing Nationalization of Property of Aliens in Underdeveloped Countries with Special Emphasis on the Juridical Implications of the Works of the United Nations : Volume 4</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55zb08z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rb11r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj706</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The central theme of this thesis is one of ascertaining the contemporary international legal norms which govern the nationalization of property of aliens in underdeveloped countries. The thesis defines the conceptual scope and content of the 'regime' of nationalization; draws a clear conceptual distinction between nationalization and other types of property "takings"; and argues, by employing a historicist approach, that those ·norms which traditional international law evolved in connection with "takings" of the "expropriation- type” do not apply over nationalization incidents that take place in underdeveloped countries in the contemporary period. The author of thesis, then, suggests that the appropriate rules should be sought, instead, in the "norm-generating" works of the U.N., and argues that international controversies which arise from contemporary nationalization incidents should be resolved pursuant to the new juridical norms that emanate from the authoritative body of international consensus which evolved within the U.N. machinery. </description><description>Le thème central de cette thèse est celui de vérifier les normes légales internationales contemporaires qui régissent la nationalisation de la propriété des étrangers dans les pays sous-développés. La thèse définit l'étendue et le contenu conceptuels, du régime de la ·nationalisation; établit une nette distinction conceptuelle entre le nationalisation et d’autres genres d'appropriations; et argumente, en employant une approche historiciste que ces normes que le droit international traditionnel a dégagées par rapport aux prises en main du "genre expropriation", ne s'appliquent pas aux incidents de nationalisation qui ont cours dans les pays sous-développés depuis la période contemporaine. Par conséquent, l'auteur de cette thèse suggère que les règlements appropries devraient être pulses, plutôt, dans les travaux « générateurs de normes » des N.U., et poutient que les controversis internationales qui surgissent à cause d'incidents dus à la nationalisation contemporaire devraient être résolues, con conformémens aux nouvelles normes juridiques émanant d'un confus de concencus international faisant autorité, qui se dégagèrent au sein de l'apparatus des N. U . </description><creator>Sharew, Getachew</creator><contributor>Cohen, Maxwell (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1983</date><subject>Nationalization</subject><subject>The United Nations</subject><subject>Legal norms</subject><title>Contemporary Trends in the Evolution of the International Legal Norms Governing Nationalization of Property of Aliens in Underdeveloped Countries with Special Emphasis on the Juridical Implications of the Works of the United Nations : Volume 3</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268758z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj706</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p0969617</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The central theme of this thesis is one of ascertaining the contemporary international legal norms which govern the nationalization of property of aliens in underdeveloped countries. The thesis defines the conceptual scope and content of the 'regime' of nationalization; draws a clear conceptual distinction between nationalization and other types of property "takings"; and argues, by employing a historicist approach, that those ·norms which traditional international law evolved in connection with "takings" of the "expropriation- type” do not apply over nationalization incidents that take place in underdeveloped countries in the contemporary period. The author of thesis, then, suggests that the appropriate rules should be sought, instead, in the "norm-generating" works of the U.N., and argues that international controversies which arise from contemporary nationalization incidents should be resolved pursuant to the new juridical norms that emanate from the authoritative body of international consensus which evolved within the U.N. machinery. </description><description>Le thème central de cette thèse est celui de vérifier les normes légales internationales contemporaires qui régissent la nationalisation de la propriété des étrangers dans les pays sous-développés. La thèse définit l'étendue et le contenu conceptuels, du régime de la ·nationalisation; établit une nette distinction conceptuelle entre le nationalisation et d’autres genres d'appropriations; et argumente, en employant une approche historiciste que ces normes que le droit international traditionnel a dégagées par rapport aux prises en main du "genre expropriation", ne s'appliquent pas aux incidents de nationalisation qui ont cours dans les pays sous-développés depuis la période contemporaine. Par conséquent, l'auteur de cette thèse suggère que les règlements appropries devraient être pulses, plutôt, dans les travaux « générateurs de normes » des N.U., et poutient que les controversis internationales qui surgissent à cause d'incidents dus à la nationalisation contemporaire devraient être résolues, con conformémens aux nouvelles normes juridiques émanant d'un confus de concencus international faisant autorité, qui se dégagèrent au sein de l'apparatus des N. U . </description><creator>Sharew, Getachew</creator><contributor>Cohen, Maxwell (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1983</date><subject>Nationalization</subject><subject>The United Nations</subject><subject>Legal norms</subject><title>Contemporary Trends in the Evolution of the International Legal Norms Governing Nationalization of Property of Aliens in Underdeveloped Countries with Special Emphasis on the Juridical Implications of the Works of the United Nations : Volume 2</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483m53j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p0969617</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j3334717</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The central theme of this thesis is one of ascertaining the contemporary international legal norms which govern the nationalization of property of aliens in underdeveloped countries. The thesis defines the conceptual scope and content of the 'regime' of nationalization; draws a clear conceptual distinction between nationalization and other types of property "takings"; and argues, by employing a historicist approach, that those ·norms which traditional international law evolved in connection with "takings" of the "expropriation- type” do not apply over nationalization incidents that take place in underdeveloped countries in the contemporary period. The author of thesis, then, suggests that the appropriate rules should be sought, instead, in the "norm-generating" works of the U.N., and argues that international controversies which arise from contemporary nationalization incidents should be resolved pursuant to the new juridical norms that emanate from the authoritative body of international consensus which evolved within the U.N. machinery. </description><description>Le thème central de cette thèse est celui de vérifier les normes légales internationales contemporaires qui régissent la nationalisation de la propriété des étrangers dans les pays sous-développés. La thèse définit l'étendue et le contenu conceptuels, du régime de la ·nationalisation; établit une nette distinction conceptuelle entre le nationalisation et d’autres genres d'appropriations; et argumente, en employant une approche historiciste que ces normes que le droit international traditionnel a dégagées par rapport aux prises en main du "genre expropriation", ne s'appliquent pas aux incidents de nationalisation qui ont cours dans les pays sous-développés depuis la période contemporaine. Par conséquent, l'auteur de cette thèse suggère que les règlements appropries devraient être pulses, plutôt, dans les travaux « générateurs de normes » des N.U., et poutient que les controversis internationales qui surgissent à cause d'incidents dus à la nationalisation contemporaire devraient être résolues, con conformémens aux nouvelles normes juridiques émanant d'un confus de concencus international faisant autorité, qui se dégagèrent au sein de l'apparatus des N. U . </description><creator>Sharew, Getachew</creator><contributor>Cohen, Maxwell (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1983</date><subject>Nationalization</subject><subject>The United Nations</subject><subject>Legal norms</subject><title>Contemporary Trends in the Evolution of the International Legal Norms Governing Nationalization of Property of Aliens in Underdeveloped Countries with Special Emphasis on the Juridical Implications of the Works of the United Nations : Volume 1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xb92w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3334717</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rk46g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Based on library search, personal observation, and structured interviews, the efficiency, effectiveness and administration of 16 youth polytechnics, in five Districts of the Eastern Province of Kenya were studied. The study found that most polytechnics lack adequate equipment and tools, have underdeveloped curricula, and few courses frequented by women. Competition for work contracts and lack of initial capital diminishes chances for self-employment. These institutions suffer from high dropout rates, a lack of employment opportunities in the rural areas, and a lack of awareness in some communities of their importance. Instructors are not recognized as civil servants and are paid low salaries. Based on these findings, it was evident that the effectiveness and efficient functioning of youth polytechnics is dependent on the provision of adequate tools and well-trained instructors in addition to developing a positive attitude on the part of the trainees. Introduction of trades which are liked by female trainees is vital. Most of the instructors were not sure who their employer was; that is, the Ministry of Culture and Social Services or the local Management Committee. The study found that admitting students from distant areas affected the development of the local rural areas where the institutions are located. Finally, local Management Committees were often unaware of the economic importance of the youth polytechnics to the local area.  </description><description>Des recherches en bibliothèques, des observations personnelles et des entrevues structurées ont été utilisées comme base pour étudier le rendement, l'efficacité et l'administration de 16 écoles polytechniques pour jeunes dans cinq régions de la province orientale du Kenya. L'étude démontre que la plupart des écoles polytechniques manquent d'équipement et d'outils, ont des plans d'étude sous-développés et peu de cours attrayants pour les personnes de sexe féminin. La concurrence pour les contrats de travail et la manque de capital de premier établissement réduisent les occasions de travail indépendant. Ces institutions subissent un haut taux d'abandon et démontrent un manque de débouchés pour des emplois dans les milieux ruraux ainsi qu'un manque de conscience de l'importance de ces institutions de la part de certaines communautés. Les instructeurs ne sont pas reconnus comme fonctionnaires et ne reçoivent que des salaires très bas. Selon ces résultats, il est devenu évident que le rendement et l'efficacité du fonctionnement des écoles polytechniques pour jeunes dépendent de l'apport d'outils appropries et d'instructeurs qualifies ainsi qu'une attitude positive des apprentis. L'introduction de métiers qui seront attirants pour les apprentis de sexe féminin est vitale. La plupart des instructeurs ne savaient pas qui étaient leurs employeurs; c'est-A-dire, le Ministère de la Culture et des Services Sociaux ou le Comité Local de Gestion. L'étude a démontré que l'admission d'élevés de régions éloignées affectait le développement des régions rurales près desquelles les institutions sont situées. Finalement, les comités locaux ignoraient souvent 1 'importance économique des écoles polytechniques pour jeunes leur région. </description><creator>Ndua, E. M.</creator><contributor>Anderson, Gary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1988</date><subject>Education, Rural -- Kenya -- Research.</subject><subject>Technical education -- Kenya -- Planning.</subject><subject>Area vocational-technical centers -- Kenya.</subject><title>Technical Study in Kenya: A Study of Youth Polytechnics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569670m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rk46g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pq385</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le stress psychologique peut être un facteur de risque pour le développement de l'hypertension essentielle. Toutefois, le rapport entre les réactions cardiovasculaires transitoires et les hausses soutenues de tension arterielle n'est pas clair. L'étude des modèles de réactions hémodynamiques de personnes exposées a un stress soutenu pourrait aider à expliquer ce rapport. Les recherches effectués auprès de personnes ayant des antécédents familiaux d'hypertension peuvent s'avérer particulièrement importantes, vu le risque accru de cette maladie chez ces individus. Une série d'études a été entreprise dans laquelle des sujets à tension normale, ayant des parents a tension normale et à haute tension, ont été exposés à un stress d'une heure exigeant une réaction d'adaptation active. Les résultats des recherches ont révélé, entre autres, que: 1) les enfants des hypertensifs et autres personnes à réactions cardiaques aigues ont présente une résistance vasculaire à la hausse au niveau de l'avant-bras au fur et à mesure que la session de stress progressait, 2) ce modèle de résistance reflétait une activité alpha-adrénergique, et 3) la réactivité cardiovasculaire accentuée des enfants des hypertensifs semble, en général, être reliée a l'activité des récepteurs adrénergiques périphériques. Ces résultats pourraient avoir des conséquences sur de nombreuses théories du développement de l'hypertension.</description><description>Psychological stress may be a risk factor for the development of essential hypertension. However, the relationship between transient cardiovascular responses to stress and sustained elevations of blood pressure is unclear. Studying the hemodynamic response patterns of individuals exposed to extended stress may help to explain this relationship. Research on individuals with a family history of hypertension may be particularly important because of their elevated risk for the disorder. In a series of studies, normotensive subjects with hypertensive and normotensive parents were exposed to a one·hour active coping stressor. Among the findings were (1) offspring of hypertensives and other cardiac hyperreactors exhibited increasing forearm vascular resistance as the stress session progressed, (2) this pattern of resistance reflected alpha·adrenergic activity, and (3) exaggerated cardiovascular reactivity in offspring of hypertensives, in general, appeared to be linked to activity at peripheral adrenergic receptors. These results may have implications for a number of theories of hypertension development. </description><creator>Miller, Sydney B.</creator><contributor>Ditto, Blaine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Hypertension -- Psychosomatic aspects.</subject><subject>Stress (Psychology)</subject><title>Hemodynamic Patterns of Response to Psychological Stress and Risk of Hypertension</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289m329.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pq385</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jg99z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objectif de cette thèse est de développer et de vérifier un modèle pour les boucles d'accrocha.ge de phase, utilisable dans les études de stabilité transitoire des réseaux de transport. Cet objectif a été atteint au moyen des phases suivantes: La boucle de phase a été simulée au moyen du logiciel de simulation PSPICE. Trois types de boucles de phase ont été réalisés: avec contrôleur PI (proportionnel intégrale), PI avec filtre, et PI avec filtre synchronne (Fourier). La dynamique des boucles de phase a été évalué au moyen de leur réponse à des perturbations en échelon de la phase ou de l'amplitude, tandis que la performance harmonique a été étudié en ajoutant du deuxième harmonique au signal d'entrée. Pour valider les modèles détaillés, les boucles de phase ont aussi été réalisés avec des composants électroniques et soumis aux même perturbations. Des résultats très semblables ont été obtenus au moyen de ces deux méthodes. […]</description><description>The objective of this thesis was to develop and validate a phase-locked loop (PLL) model suitable for transient stability studies of power systems. Such a model is to be implemented in transient stability programs. This objective has been achieved through the following phases: The phase-locked loop was modelled in details by means of the PSPICE simulation software. Three types of PLL were simulated: PLL with PI controller, PLL with PI controller including a filter and PLL with PI controller including the synchronous (Fourier) filter. The PLL dynamics was evaluated by means of step responses to phase and amplitude perturbations, while the PLL harmonic performance was evaluated using the second harmonic component added to the input signal. In order to validate the PLL detailed models, the PLL circuits were realized in electronic components. The test were performed and step responses to the phase and amplitude perturbations were recorded as well as to steady-state second harmonic excitation. The very close agreement between laboratory recordings with the simulation results, was achieved.  […]</description><creator>Martin, Louis V.</creator><contributor>Gavrilovic, M. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Phase-locked loop (PLL)</subject><title>Phase-Locked Loop Simulation in Transient Stabilities Studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w6974.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jg99z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x151w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une nouvelle méthode de spectroscopie d'ionisation résonnante (SIR) a été mise au point à l'aide d'un laser continu. Elle est basée sur l'excitation résonnante de la première étape d'un schéma d'excitation en trois étapes de deux longueurs d'ondes. La faisabilité de cette méthode, et les variations de la puissance du signal ainsi que de la résolution spectrale ont été étudiées en fonction de la puissance des lasers. A titre de démonstration, le déplacement isotopique (DI) et la structure hyperfine (SHF) de la transition a 64 nm de l'état fondamental 4f106s2 5I8 vers l'état excite 4f10(5I8) 6s6p3(p02), d'un echantillon de dysprosium naturel, furent mesurées avec succès. Un bon accord entre des valeurs prcooemment publiées et ces résultats expérimentaux (DI des isotopes 162Dy, 163Dy et 164Dy; SHF de 163Dy) a été obtenu.</description><description>A new high resolution resonant ionization spectroscopic (RIS) technique has been developed using a CW laser for the first resonant transition of a three-step- two-colour RIS scheme. The feasibility of the method, and the variation of signal strength and the spectral resolution as a function of laser powers have been investigated. As a demonstration, measurements were successfully performed of the isotope shifts (IS) and the hyperfine structure (HFS) of the 564 nm line, a 4f106s2 5I8 ground state to a 4f10(5I8) 6s6p3(p02) excited state, of a naturally abundant sample of the rare earth element dysprosium. The experimental results of the IS between the isotopes 162Dy, 163Dy and 164Dy, and the HFS for 163Dy were found to be in good agreement with those of previous studies. </description><creator>Liu, Chen</creator><contributor>Crawford, John E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1988</date><subject>Resonant ionization spectroscopic (RIS)</subject><title>A Multi-Step Resonant Ionization Spectroscopy Technique Using CW Laser Excitation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m646h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x151w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dv578</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le but de ce mémoire de maitrise est essentiellement de présenter, dans une perspective juridique et économique, les diverses manifestations de l'intervention gouvernementale dans les exportations de technologie aérospatiale, et de vérifier si cette intervention est bénéfique pour l'industrie aérospatiale canadienne. Dans le premier chapitre, les divers mécanismes d'aide fédéraux et québecois à la promotion des exportations sont décrits. Par ailleurs, l'impact d'accords commerciaux multilatéraux ou bilatéraux sur la liberté des gouvernements de subventionner à leur guise les exportations est examiné. Dans le deuxième chapitre, le second volet de l'intervention gouvernementale, celui du contrôle des exportations, est étudié. L'auteur examine le mécanisme canadien de contrôle des exportations en analysant les lois et règlements applicables et en expliquant la politique du gouvernement fédéral à ce sujet. Puis, mention est faite des efforts effectues à l'échelle internationale dans le cadre du COCOM qui regroupe généralement les pays de l'OTAN. Finalement, la question délicate de l'application en sol canadien de la législation américaine sur le contrôle des exportations est étudiée. Dans le dernier chapitre, l'auteur tente de vérifier si un équilibre existe, pour l'industrie aérospatiale canadienne, entre ces deux priorités des gouvernements: promotion et contrôle des exportations. </description><description>The purpose of this thesis is to describe, in legal and economic terms, the various manifestations of government intervention in exports of aerospace technology, and to find out if this intervention is beneficial to the Canadian aerospace industry. The first component of government intervention concerns export promotion and in the first chapter, the various federal and provincial facilities are examined as well as the impact of bilateral or multilateral commercial treaties. In the second chapter, the second component of government intervention, dealing with export controls, is described. The applicable Canadian laws and regulations are examined, and the federal government's policy on the subject is explained. Then, international efforts involving most NATO countries in an organization known as COCOM are examined. Finally, the sensitive question of the extraterritorial application of American export control legislation on Canadian soil is considered. In the last chapter, the author attempts to determine whether an equilibrium exists, for the Canadian aerospace industry, between these two priorities: export promotion and export control.</description><creator>Lessard, Stéphane</creator><contributor>Jakhu, Ram S. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Matte, Nicholas M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Foreign trade promotion -- Canada.</subject><subject>Export controls -- Canada.</subject><subject>Conflict of laws -- Foreign trade regulation.</subject><title>Canadian Government Intervention ion Exports of Aerospace Technology: Legal and Economic</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h981.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dv578</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913s263</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Puisqu'on croit que les poissons volants fraient sur des surfaces flottantes, la composition et l'abondance saisonnière des objets flottants ont été mesuré par des filet de neuston à des stations situes a 3, 6, et 9 mille nautiques au large de la Barbade. En tout, 431 echantillons, utilisant un filet de neuston, ont été ramassés entre octobre, 1987 et septembre, 1988. Les objets flottants était soit d'origine terrestre ou côtière. Seulement 38% des échantillons contenait des objets flottants et seulement 1% des échantillons contenait des objets flottants avec des œufs de poissons volants. L'abondance des objets flottants était le plus élevé entre les mois de mars et septembre, quand l'eau atteignant la Barbade est principalement d'origine Sud-Americaine. Cette periode ne correspond pas avec la saison de fraie de l'espèce de poisson volant exploite commercialement, Hirundichthys affinis près de la Barbade (décembre - mai). [...]</description><description>Since flyingfish are believed to spawn on floating substrates, the composition and seasonal abundance of flotsam was surveyed by neuston tows at stations 3 nmi, 6 nmi and 9 nmi offshore of Barbados. A total of 431 tows were conducted between October, 1987 and September, 1988. The flotsam was of coastal marine and terrestrial origin. Only 38% of tows contained flotsam, and only 1% of tows produced flotsam with flyingfish eggs. Flotsam was most abundant between March and September, when water reaching Barbados originates primarily from the South American mainland. This period does not correspond with the spawning season of the commercially exploited flyingfish, Hirundichthys affinis, near Barbados (December-May). […] </description><creator>Lao, Mario Rommel T.</creator><contributor>Hunte, Wayne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Flyingfishes -- Spawning.</subject><subject>Fishes -- Spawning -- Barbados.</subject><subject>Exocoetidae -- Spawning.</subject><title>Distribution and Abundance of Flotsam, Larval Fish and Juvenile Fish off Barbados with Particular Reference to the Exocoetidae</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw038.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913s263</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Oceanography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rz86b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the present thesis numerical calculations of flow properties are carried out on the cylindrical Couette flow of a Lennard-Jones gas by using the generalized hydrodynamic equations. Thermoviscous coupling and normal stress effects are taken into account. These generalized hydrodynamic equations are based on the modified moment method for the solution of the Boltzmann equation. Calculations are first conducted in the absence of normal stresses with the view of investigating the dissipative terms in the constitutive equations. The range of Knudsen numbers covers the normal, transition and free molecular regimes. There is good agreement with experiment and results based on the Monte Carlo simulation method. Agreement with experiment is improved when normal stress effects are included. In this case, a phase-transition-like behaviour emerges in the flow properties and a slip in the gas velocity appears at the inner cylinder, as the Knudsen number exceeds a critical value. This behaviour results in the singularity in the entropy production which is reminiscent of a second-order phase transition in thermodynamic systems. For a fluid subject to a high shear rate, the flow is shown to approach the Eulerian behaviour in the limit of infinite Reynolds number. At the critical Reynolds number one observes the onset of a phase-transition-like behaviour with a decrease in slope in the drag coefficient vs. Reynolds number curve. Linear stability analysis shows the existence of two critical Reynolds numbers and three marginal stability curves in the case of axisymmetric stationary oscillations.</description><description>La présente thèse traite numériquement le calcul des propriétés de courant cylindrique de Couette d’un gaz de Lennard-Jones en utilisant les équations hydrodynamiques généralisées. Le couplage thermovisqueux et les effets de contraintes normales sont tenus en compte. Ces équations hydrodynamiques généralisées sont basées sur la méthode de moments modifiée pour la résolution de l’équation de Boltzmann. En premier lieu, les calculs sont performés en l’absence de contraintes normales en vue d’examiner les termes de nature dissipative dans les relations de comportement. Les trois régimes de densité normale, de transition et moléculaire libre sont couverts dans les calculs. Il en résulte un bon accord avec les résultats expérimentaux et ceux bases sur la méthode de simulation de Monte Carlo. L'accord avec les résultats expérimentaux est amélioré quand les effets de contraintes normales sont inclus. Dans ce cas, un comportement similaire a une transition de phase dans les propriétés du courant et un glissement dans la vitesse du gaz au cylindre intérieur apparaissent, une fois que le nombre de Knudsen excède une valeur critique. Ce comportement résulte en la singularité dans la production d'entropie qui rappelle une transition de phase de second degré dans les systèmes thermodynamiques. Pour un fluide sujet à un haut gradient de vitesse, le courant s’approche du comportement Eulérien dans la limite infinie du nombre de Reynolds. A la valeur critique du nombre de Reynolds on observe l'émergence de la transition de phase avec une diminution de la tangente a la courbe du coefficient de trainée en fonction du nombre de Reynolds. L’analyse de stabilité linéaire révèle l’existence de deux nombres de Reynolds critiques et trois courbes de stabilité marginale dans le cas d’oscillations axisymétriques stationnaires. </description><creator>Khayat, Roger E.</creator><contributor>Eu, B. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Reynolds number</subject><title>Generalized Hydrodynamics for Cylindrical Couette Flow of a Lennard-Jones Fluid</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g671.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz86b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602335v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Significant evolution of the global airline business has forced both carriers and regulators to adapt. While traditional roles for the regulator, including air safety and infrastructural regulation, (airports, etc.) remain, the removal of economic regulation has produced an enhanced reliance on antitrust law among others to govern orderly development of the industry. This paper examines the resulting evolution in the role of the regulator in both the old world and the new. </description><description>La transformation profonde qu'a connue l’ensemble de l'industrie du transport aérien a obligé les transporteurs et les organismes de réglementation à s'adapter. Les fonctions traditionelles de réglementation rattachées notamment à la sécurité aérienne et aux règlements en matière d'infrastructure (aeroports, etc.) n’ont pas changé, mats la suppression des règles économiques a engendré entre autres une plus grande dépendance envers la loi « antitrust » afin d'assurer l’évolution ordonnée de l'industrie la présente thèse étudie les modifications qu'est appelé à subir le rôle de l'organisme de réglementation dans l'ancien et le nouveau monde. </description><creator>Gialloreto, Louis</creator><contributor>Bradley, Martin A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Deregulation.</subject><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation.</subject><title>The Evolving World of Air Transport Regulation in the Old World and the New: A Review of Future Roles for the Air Transport Regulator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795b047.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602335v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386m81g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette Thèse traite des vibrations latérales de faisceaux de cylindres (en caoutchouc) flexibles, soumis à l'écoulement longitudinal d'un fluide (eau) incompressible, à l'intérieur d'un conduit circulaire rigide. Les cylindres, dont certains étaient munis de jauges d'élongation implantées, étaient fixes aux deux extrémités (amont et aval), a un assemblage rigide d'ailettes profilées. La théorie est un modèle d'oscillations aléatoires, avec les déflections des cylindres basées sur une sommation des modes propres d'une poutre, la réponse étant fonction des effets de l'écoulement moyen le long des cylindres, ainsi que des fluctuations de pression dans la couche limite de l'écoulement turbulent. Divers faisceaux, ayant différents nombres de cylindres ainsi qu'un nombre de combinaisons de cylindres flexibles et rigides, furent analyses, aussi bien expérimentalement que théoriquement. Il est démontré ici que la théorie est en accord qualitatif excellent avec les essais expérimentaux, en terme de densités spectrales de puissance, et des cohérences et phases entre cylindres; néanmoins, les niveaux prédits des amplitudes sont d'un ordre de grandeur plus élevés que ceux qui ont été mesures. </description><description>This Thesis examines the experimental and theoretical lateral vibration characteristics of flexible (rubber) cylinder clusters, subjected to axial incompressible (water) flow, within a rigid circular containment channel. The cylinders, some of which were instrumented with embedded strain gages, were clamped at both their upstream and downstream ends, to streamlined rigid fin assemblies. The theory is a random vibration model, with cylinder deflections based on natural beam mode summation, and response dependent on both the effects of the mean flow along the cylinders, and of turbulent boundary layer pressure fluctuations. Various bundles with different numbers of cylinders, as well as with combinations of flexible and rigid cylinders, were investigated, both experimentally and theoretically. It is shown that the theory is in excellent qualitative agreement with experiments, in terms of power spectral densities, and coherences and phases between cylinders; nevertheless, predicted amplitude levels are one order of magnitude higher than those measured. </description><creator>Gagnon, Jean O.</creator><contributor>Paidoussis, M. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Axial Flow</subject><title>Fluid Coupling and Response Characteristics of Cylinder Clusters in Axial Flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw84w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m81g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jt627</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Extrusion blow molding is utilized in the production of plastic hollow containers. The predominant stage in the process sequence is the formation of the preform, known as the parison. Parison extrusions through an annular die are subject to varying degrees of swell and sag along the length. Different parts also require varying amounts of polymer depending on part design. This demands variations in the wall thickness along the length of the parison. Control o£ the thickness profile is necessary to minimize resin usage while maintaining the required product characteristics. Presently, parison thickness distribution is controlled by open loop parison programmers. These programmers require cumbersome trial and error procedures to ascertain the necessary die gap set point profile. Unexpected disturbances entering the system are not compensated for. […]</description><description>Le moulage par soufflage est un procédé utilise pour l’élaboration de containers en plastique creux.L’étape prédominante du cycle de fabrication est l’extrusion d’une tube, appelée "paraison"· L’extrusion de cette paraison au travers d’une filière annulaire fait apparaître des variations de gonflement et d’étirement le long de l’extrudât. De même, suivant leurs formes, certaines parties de pièces moulées exigent une quantité de polymère plus ou moins importante. Cela impose des variations d'épaisseur sur toute la longueur de la tube. Le contrôle de l’épaisseur du profil est nécessaire si l’on veut minimiser les dépenses en résine tout en respectant les caractéristiques du produit conçu. Actuellement, les épaisseurs de paraison sont contrôlées par des programmes en boucle ouverte qu.t nécessitent des essais encombrants et des procédures de tatonnement permettant de s’assurer le profil exacte d'ouverture de filière exigé, les perturbations extérieures qui entrent. Dans le système n’étant pas compensées. […]</description><creator>DiRaddo, Robert</creator><contributor>Kamal, M. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Patterson, W. I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Extrusion Blow Molding</subject><title>On-Line Measurement and Control of Parison Dimensions in Extrusion Blow Molding</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t446m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt627</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rw80j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was aimed at establishing the link between a newly discovered humoral peptide, atrial natriuretic factor (ANF), and the peripheral nervous system. ANF has been shown to inhibit the function of the sympathomedullary system when infused in vivo for a prolonged time. ANF - like peptides have been isolated and characterized from the autonomic ganglia of the rat and some parts of the central nervous system; the clear presence of the ANF prohormone has been documented, indicating a neuronal origin for the extracted peptide. ANF occurrence in sympathetic ganglia is dependent on the anatomical continuity of preganglionic cholinergic nerves. […]</description><description>Cette étude a pour but d'établir une relation entre un peptide humoral récemment découvert, le facteur natriurétique de l'oreillette (ANF), et le système nerveux périphérique. Lorsqu'infusé in vivo pendant une période prolongée, l'ANF inhibe le fonctionnement du système sympathomédullaire. Des peptides similaires à l 'ANF ont été isoles et caractérisés à partir de ganglions autonomes et de certaines parties du système nerveux central de rats; la présence évidente de prohormones d'ANF a été rapportée, indiquant une origine neuronale du peptide qui en était extrait. Le fait de retrouver de l'ANF dans les ganglions sympathiques est dépendant de la continuité anatomique des nerfs cholinergiques préganglionaires. […]</description><creator>Debinski, Waldemar</creator><contributor>Kuchel, Otto (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Buu, Nguyen T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1988</date><subject>Atrial natriuretic factor (ANF)</subject><title>Relationship between Atrial Natriuetic Factor and the Autonomic Nervous System</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mf22j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw80j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nd546</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of calcium-activated phospholipid-dependent protein kinase [protein kinase C] in the regulation of renal phosphate [Pi] reabsorption and vitamin D metabolism was studied in Hyp mice and Pi-deprived mice, which exhibit alterations in these renal functions. Protein kinase C activity was elevated in renal cytosolic fraction from Hyp mice, whereas brush border membrane [BBM] and mitochondrialprotein kinase C was comparable in normals and mutants. Pi deprivation elicited a decrease in BBM protein kinase C in normal mice, and an increase in mitochondrial protein kinase C in both genotypes. Similar substrates were demonstrated in subcellular fractions from both genotypes, with an additional cytosolic substrate in Hyp mice.</description><description>Nous avons étudié le rôle de la protéine kinase phospholipide-dépendante et activée par le calcium [protéine kinase C] dans la régulation du transport rénal du phosphate [Pi] et du métabolisme de la vitamine D chez la souris Hyp et la souris privée de Pi, deux modèles chez qui ces fonctions rénales sont modifiées par rapport à la normale. L'activité de la protéine kinase C était élevées dans le cytosol rénal de la souris Hyp, alors que l'activité dans les fractions membranaire (bordure en brosse [BBM]) et mitochondriale était comparable chez les souris normales et mutantes. La privation du Pi a diminué l'activité de la protéine kinase C dans la fraction BBM des souris normales, et a augmenté l'activité dans la fraction mitochondriale des souris normales et mutantes. Les substrats endogènes dans les fractions subcellulaires en provenance des deux types de souris étaient semblables, a l'exception d'un substrat cytosolique additionnel chez la souris Hyp</description><creator>Boneh, Avihu</creator><contributor>Tenenhouse, Susie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1988</date><subject>Protein kinase</subject><title>Calcium-Activated Phospholipid-Dependent Protein Kinase [Protein Kinase C] in Mouse Kidney: Effect of Diet and Mutation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xh214.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nd546</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qp513</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nous avons entrepris des études microscopie photonique et électronique radioautographiques en dans le but de révéler les sites de liaison in vivo du facteur natriurétique auriculaire (FNA) chez le rat. Nous avons pu démontrer la présence de ces sites de liaison dans le cerveau, les reins, les yeux ainsi que l'intestin grêle. Dans le cerveau, les sites de liaison sont situés au niveau des organes circumventriculaires, des vaisseaux sanguin et du plexus choroide. Dans le cortex rénal, ils se retrouvent principalement localises sur les cellules épithéliales viscérales. En outre, nous avons pu démontrer que le FNA inhibe la contraction des glomérules isoles en réponse a l'angiotensine II. Dans la médullaire rénale; les sites de liaison du FNA sont localises sur les vasa recta descendants et les tubules collecteurs. Dans l'œil, ils se trouvent à la base des cellules "pigmentées" du procès ciliaire. Les sites de liaison de l'intestin grêle se partagent entre les fibroblastes de la lamina propria et la base des entérocytes. Cette carte détaillée des sites de liaison du FNA devrait s'avérer d'une grande utilité pour la compréhension du rôle physiologique du FNA circulant et de ses implications physiopathologiques. </description><description>Studies were undertaken to localize in vivo binding sites for atrial natriuretic factor (ANF) in rats by light and electron microscope radioautography. ANF binding sites were identified in the brain, kidney, eye and small intestine. In the brain, they were present in the circumventricular organs, blood vessels and choroid plexus. In the renal cortex, they were mainly localized in epithelial visceral cells. In addition, ANF inhibited the decrease in the size of isolated glomeruli induced by Angiotensin II. ANF binding sites in the renal medulla corresponded mainly to the descending vasa recta, and to papillary collecting tubules in the renal papilla. In the eye, ANF binding sites were present at the base of "pigmented" cells of the ciliary processes. In the small intestine, they were localized in fibroblast like cells of the lamina propria, at the base of mature enterocytes and to a lesser extent in the capillaries. Such detailed map of ANF binding sites may be very helpful in our understanding of the mechanisms and implications of circulating ANF in physiological and pathophysiological states where this hormone seems to play a major role in the homeostasis of body fluid volume and blood pressure. </description><creator>Bianchi Filho, Cesario</creator><contributor>Cantin, Marc (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1988</date><subject>Binding sites</subject><title>Localization and Distribution of Binging Sites for Atrial Natriuretic Factor in the Rat: A Light and Electron Microscope Radioautographic Study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m647s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qp513</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):4525</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>