<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:44:49Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40400" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483m090</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The early Canadian long poem has often been faulted for its lack of aesthetic integrity, being seen in many cases as little more than poorly "versified rhetoric," but it has never been submitted to a thorough rhetorical analysis. An investigation of the rhetorical devices at work in the early Canadian long poem, however, reveals them to be highly strategic operations of both the imperial-colonial project in British North America and the emerging national consciousness of the new nation of Canada. These operations may be understood more clearly through the close examination of periodic "ruptures" in the texts--inconsistencies, contradictions, anomalies, and deflections--which underscore the frequently conflictual nature of the "unsaid" (the real historical, economic and social conditions) and the surface level of the narrative (the aesthetic and generic constraints). Such an analysis reveals the extent to which the problems of allegiance, anxiety and identity were inextricably involved in the colonial and national projects, an involvement which the poetry, despite its intentions, could neither mask nor resolve.</description><creator>Mazoff, C. D. (Chaim David), 1949-</creator><contributor>Trehearne, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Canadian poetry -- 19th century -- History and criticism</subject><subject>Canadian poetry -- 18th century -- History and criticism</subject><title>Allegiance anxiety identity : the rhetoric of legitimation in the early Canadian long poem, from Carey to Crawford</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tb41n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483m090</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb26c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation studies parts of six medieval Jewish Torah commentaries in order to examine how they related to what we call Pentateuchal poetry. It examines their general approaches to Bible interpretation and their treatments of all Pentateuchal poems. It focusses on qualities we associate with poetry--parallelism, structure, metaphor, and syntax--and explores the extent to which they treated poems differently from prose. The effort begins by defining Pentateuchal poetry and discussing a range of its presentations by various ancient writers. Subsequent chapters examine its treatment by Rabbi Saadia Gaon of Baghdad (882-942), Abraham Ibn Ezra of Spain (1089-1164), Samuel Ben Meir (1080-1160) and Joseph Bekhor Shor (12th century) of Northern France, David Kimhi of Provence (1160-1235), and Obadiah Sforno of Italy (1470-1550). While all of these commentators wrote on the poetic passages, none differentiated systematically between Pentateuchal prose and poetry or treated them in substantially different ways. Samuel Ben Meir, Ibn Ezra, Bekhor Shor, and Kimhi did discuss some poetic features of these texts. The other two men were far less inclined to do so, but occasionally recognized some differences between prose and poetry and some phenomena unique to the latter.</description><creator>Meir, Amira</creator><contributor>Levy, B. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Hebrew poetry, Biblical -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Medieval Jewish interpretation of pentateuchal poetry</title><language>heb</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10ws281.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb26c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816p445</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In independently derived drug resistant sublines of the mouse lymphoid tumor P388, multidrug resistance (MDR) is associated with the exclusive overexpression of the mdr3 gene, which occurs either from a single copy gene (P388/VGR-10) or after gene amplification (P388/ADM-2). The mechanism underlying mdr3 overexpression in these cells was investigated. Nucleotide sequence analysis revealed the presence of several putative cis-regulatory elements in the genomic region overlapping the transcription start site of mdr3. However, the 5$ sp prime$ end of mdr3 mRNAs was shown to be altered in the MDR derivatives of P388, indicating that the normal start site is not used in these cells. In the two cell lines, these alterations are associated with a genomic rearrangement in the 5$ sp prime$ region of the gene caused by the insertion of retroviral sequences. In P388/ADM-2, the integration of an intracistemal A particle within an L1Md repetitive element immediately upstream of mdr3 results in the activation of the gene. In P388/VCR-10 cells, transcriptional activation of mdr3 is caused by the integration of an intact mouse mammary tumor virus (MMTV) within intron I in the opposite transcriptional (antisense) orientation compared to that of the gene. This integration results in the production of MMTV/mdr3 fusion transcripts from a cryptic promoter in the 5$ sp prime$ long terminal repeat (LTR) of the provirus. In transient transfection experiments, it was shown that the antisense 5$ sp prime$ LTR alone only weakly activates the reporter gene luciferase. However, addition of mdr3-derived sequences from intron I downstream of the 5$ sp prime$ LTR strongly activates the expression of luciferase, suggesting the presence of an activator/enhancer element in this region. These results and subsequent identification of independent genomic rearrangements in the 5$ sp prime$ region of mdr3 in additional MDR P388 derivatives analyzed in this study suggest a mechanism of gene activation i</description><creator>Lepage, Pierre, 1962-</creator><contributor>Gros, Philippe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Activation of the mouse mdr3 gene in multidrug resistant derivatives of the lymphoid tumor P388</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j7416.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p445</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kv773</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The human T cell leukemia virus type I (HTLV-I) is the etiological agent of adult T cell leukemia. The oncogenic potential of HTLV-I resides in the viral Tax protein which behaves as a strong transcriptional activator of viral gene expression. Tax is also capable of trans-activating numerous growth regulatory genes by an indirect mechanism. One of the targets of Tax protein is the NF-$ kappa$B/I$ kappa$B family of transcriptional regulators. The objective of this thesis was to characterize the molecular mechanisms by which Tax interacts with the NF-$ kappa$B/I$ kappa$B proteins to initiate aberrant gene expression. HTLV-I infected and Tax expressing T cell models were initially used to demonstrate a constitutive level of NF-$ kappa$B DNA binding activity and increased NF-$ kappa$B-dependent transcriptional activity. NFKB2 and c-Rel subunits were overexpressed in these cells and constituted the majority of the NF-$ kappa$B/Rel heterodimers binding to DNA. A reduction in NF-$ kappa$B p65 nuclear expression and DNA binding activity was also observed. Importantly, a novel complex composed of NFKB2 p100 and Tax was detected in HTLV-I infected cells, thus demonstrating physical interaction between viral and cellular proteins. These in vivo observations were confirmed in Tax-NF-$ kappa$B co-transfection studies which demonstrated a Tax-dependent correlation between expression of NFKB2 p100 and processing to p52, induction of c-Rel, and trans-activation of NF-$ kappa$B-mediated gene expression. A co-transfection-immunofluorescence assay provided additional support for direct Tax-NF-$ kappa$B physical interactions by demonstrating the ability of p100, p105 and p52 to modify the intracellular localization of Tax. The possibility that constitutive NF-$ kappa$B activity resulted from a Tax-mediated effect on $ rm I kappa B alpha$ function was also examined. Constitutive phosphorylation and increased turnover of I$ kappa$Ba were observed in HTLV-I infected and Tax expressing</description><creator>Lacoste, Judith</creator><contributor>Hiscott, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>HTLV-I tax interactions with the NF-kBIkB regulators of transcription</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c78g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kv773</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hb747</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The variational analysis methods are applied to retrieve the steady state wind field from single-Doppler radar data. The wind field is retrieved by fitting, in the least-squares sense, constraining model equations to observations measured during a short assimilation period (2 or 3 time sequences). The weak and strong constraint formalisms are reviewed and examined using the one-dimensional linear advection equation as a constraint. It is shown that the retrieval is not unique, but the problem can be controlled by a smoothness constraint. Variational two-dimensional and three-dimensional wind retrieval algorithms are developed and tested using actual dual-Doppler radar data. The conservation of reflectivity and the radial momentum equation are used as weak constraints in both algorithms. The anelastic form of the continuity equation is also included as a strong constraint in the three-dimensional algorithm. The two-dimensional algorithm is tested and compared to echo tracking methods using Doppler radar observations in the clear-air planetary boundary layer. The resolution at which the methods can effectively retrieve the horizontal wind field is examined in detail. The variational algorithm can properly retrieve wind structures greater than 10 km wavelength. The three-dimensional algorithm is tested using observations of a precipitating microburst. It is demonstrated that the three-dimensional wind field can be retrieved, but the method fails near the ground level. In addition, the retrieval is sensitive to the radar position relative to the observational domain due to systematic model errors. The computational efficiency of the three-dimensional wind retrieval algorithm allows its semi-operational implementation at the J. S. Marshall Radar Observatory of McGill University.</description><creator>Laroche, Stéphane</creator><contributor>Zawadzki, Isztar (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Variational analysis methods for retrieval of wind field from single-doppler radar data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm90q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb747</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mp25q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Homeosis, the expression of features characteristic of one structure in the position of a different structure, and its role in floral development and evolution is explored in several different species of angiosperms. The expression of perianth features in stamen positions, and of inflorescence features within the flower is demonstrated in a comparative study of single- and double-flowering begonias. Floral development in three native plant species is then described, and compared to published accounts of development and phylogeny in related species to show: the expression of petal features in stamen positions in Sanguinaria canadensis; the replacement of petals with stamens and vice versa within and among plants of Actaea rubra; and the replacement of stamens with tepals in Calla palustris. These three species are all examples of naturally occurring homeosis, suggesting an important role for homeosis as an evolutionary process.</description><creator>Lehmann, Naida L.</creator><contributor>Sattler, Rolf (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Begonias -- Morphogenesis</subject><subject>Flowers -- Morphogenesis</subject><title>Homeosis in floral development emphasizing the perianth and androecium</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mh425.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp25q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nk089</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A numerical modelling approach is chosen to study equilibrium and time-dependent aspects of the ocean's thermohaline circulation. In the first part, the roles of basin geometry and surface buoyancy forcing in determining the asymmetry of the present-day thermohaline circulation are considered. An idealized flat-bottomed two-basin model of the Atlantic and Pacific is found to favour equilibria with sinking in the southern hemisphere only (Southern Sinking) or also in the North Atlantic (Conveyor), even under a freshwater flux forcing field with more precipitation over the North Atlantic than over the North Pacific. Another new result is the range of Conveyor equilibria found under mixed boundary conditions. Rare cases with North Pacific sinking are characterized by a very fresh halocline in the Southern Ocean and a reversed pole-to-pole surface density contrast. A more quantitative investigation leads to an approximately linear relationship between the Atlantic overturning and the meridional gradient of zonally-averaged depth-integrated steric height from the northern boundary of the ocean to the southern tip of Africa; on the other hand, the local linear relationships postulated in most two-dimensional plane models of the overturning circulation could not be validated. In the second part, the climatology of a global ocean model is presented, and the importance in the model of the warm water route of the Conveyor through the Indian Ocean relative to the cold water route through Drake Passage is noted. The implied ocean heat and freshwater transports from the Canadian Climate Centre second generation atmospheric general circulation model are then presented, and are shown to be incompatible with the present-day thermohaline circulation. Finally, in the third part, a simple new parameterization of the sea surface temperature-evaporation feedback is developed as an extension of the traditional mixed boundary conditions. The positive sign of the feedback for the thermohaline circulation is demonstrated, and three examples featuring decadal, century and millennial timescale variability in one-hemisphere idealized basins are discussed. No fundamental alterations of the mechanisms under mixed boundary conditions are found, although the timescale is altered or the variability interrupted sooner in some cases.</description><creator>Hughes, Tertia M. C.</creator><contributor>Weaver, Andrew J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>Uniqueness and variability of the ocean's thermohaline circulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d191c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nk089</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x3308</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The hippocampus is necessary for normal memory in rodents, birds, monkeys, and people. Damage to the hippocampus can result in the inability to learn new facts, defined by the relationship among stimuli. In rodents, spatial learning involves learning about the relationships among stimuli, and exemplifies the kind of learning the requires the hippocampus. Therefore, understanding the neural mechanisms underlying spatial learning may elucidate basic memory processes. Many hippocampal neurons fire when behaving rats, cats, or monkeys are in circumscribed regions (place fields) of an environment. The neurons, called place cells, fire in relation to distal stimuli, but can persist in signaling location when the stimuli are removed or lights are turned off (memory fields). In this thesis, computational models of spatial information processing simulated many of the defining properties of hippocampal place cells, including memory fields. Furthermore, the models suggested a neurally plausible mechanism of goal directed spatial navigation which involved the encoding of distances in the connections between place cells. To navigate using memory fields, the models required an excitatory, distributed, and plastic association system among place cells. Such properties are well characterized in area CA3 of the hippocampus. In this thesis, a new electrophysiological study provides evidence that a second system in the dentate gyrus has similar properties. Thus, two circuits in the hippocampus meet the requirements of the models. Some predictions of the models were then tested in a single-unit recording experiment in behaving rats. Place fields were more likely to occur in information rich areas of the environment, and removal of single cues altered place fields in a way consistent with the distance encoding mechanism suggested by the models. It was concluded that a distance encoding theory of rat spatial navigation has much descriptive and predictive utility, but most of its predic</description><creator>Hetherington, Phil A. (Phillip Alan)</creator><contributor>Shapiro, Matthew L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Hippocampus (Brain) -- Computer simulation.</subject><subject>Rats -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Neural networks (Neurobiology)</subject><subject>Space perception -- Physiological aspects -- Computer simulation.</subject><subject>Perceptual-motor processes -- Computer simulation.</subject><title>Hippocampal function and spatial information processing : computational and neural analyses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pv55t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x3308</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827d55q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pyrithiamine-induced thiamine deficiency (PTD) in the rat results in a metabolic disorder associated with selective cerebral vulnerability. The basis of the histological lesions that develop in areas that include the thalamus, medial geniculate, and inferior colliculus is undetermined but an underlying glutamate-mediated form of excitotoxicity may be responsible. This work examines the possibility that PTD leads to changes in extracellular glutamate concentration, membrane polarization status, and gene expression consistent with a decreased ability to maintain homeostatic integrity. At the acute symptomatic stage, extracellular glutamate by concentration as determined microdialysis was found to be elevated in the thalamus but within normal limits in the non-vulnerable parietal cortex. This result suggests an involvement of glutamate in the pathogenesis of thiamine deficiency lesions. An in vivo examination of L-type voltage-sensitive calcium channel activity using quantitative autoradiography and ($ sp3$H) -nimodipine at the same stage of PTD revealed that increased activity was present in and localized to the thalamus, but was absent in areas resistant to histological damage. The finding indicates a likelihood of regional depolarization. Finally, induction of the proto-oncogene c-fos was detected in the thalamus and inferior colliculus with quantitative in situ hybridization analysis at the acute symptomatic stage, thereby confirming the association of PTD with depolarization-related events occurring in advance of the appearance of frank infarction. Together, these results suggest that vulnerability in the thalamus may be determined by an inability to maintain spatial buffering of extracellular glutamate under energy-compromised conditions. Such an environment may be sufficient to set into motion event cascades in these cells that lead to the demise of the structure as a whole.</description><creator>Hazell, Alan Stewart</creator><date>1995</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The pathophysiology of pyrithiamine-induced thiamine deficiency encephalopathy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq110.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827d55q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df49f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The five exteroceptive senses are used extensively as metaphors for describing the divine-human relationship in the Old Testament. The thesis seeks to explore the significance of sensory language for understanding the TENAK's perspectives on the relationship between God and mortals. A phenomenology of the senses is sketched in the first chapter drawing upon the works of Merleau-Ponty, Straus, Leder, Howes and Classen. This leads the author to delineate the "rubrics" (salient features) of the Senses. The rubrics are applied to individual texts which use sensory language to see whether they serve as a useful tool for exegesis. Tables are presented which contain lexical data on sensory language used to describe God's knowledge of humans (chapter two) and humanity's knowledge of God (chapter three). Differences in the sensory language describing the two directions of knowledge are noted and commented upon. The thesis thus looks at the sensory language in the TENAK at both a micro-level (individual texts) and a macro-level (over-all patterns of sensory language). It is argued that the rubrics serve as a positive tool of exegesis and that the patterns detected are of significance in understanding certain basic perspectives of the TENAK'S view of the relationship between the deity and mortals.</description><creator>Humphrey, Francis</creator><contributor>Runnalls, Donna R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Metaphor in the Bible</subject><title>Sensory language and the divine-human relationship in the TENAK [i.e. Tanakh]</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956h83n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df49f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w6710</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of a parasite-produced or -induced soluble immunosuppressor in experimental kala azar was examined. It was found that in vivo infections with Leishmania donovani in the hamster (Mesocricetus auratus) produce a soluble immunosuppressor, which appears in the serum of the host and which reduces the proliferation of responding populations of murine splenocytes in a one-way mixed leukocyte reaction (MLR). The production in vitro infections of murine splenic macrophages from C57BL/6J ($Lsh sp{ rm s}$), C57L/J ($Lsh sp{ rm R}$) and BALB/c strains, the suppressive activity was not contained in either parasite-conditioned culture medium or in parasite extracts or from macrophages which have internalized killed parasites or inert particles and it is not blocked by the action of 2-mercaptoethanol or indomethacin in the culture medium. The suppressor was found to be able to selectively inhibit or reduce the proliferation of splenocytes of both the C57BL/6J and C57LN strains in a one way MLR, with the level of suppression being significantly greater upon splenocytes of the susceptible $Lsh sp{ rm s}$ strain. The suppression was dependent upon the genotype of the macrophages present in the responding population. The suppressor was also able to significantly inhibit the processing of human serum albumin by macrophages, to reduce the number of Ia ligands on the surfaces of macrophages and the production by these cells of IL-1 upon silica stimulation. Significant reduction was also seen in the production of IL2 and in the expression of its receptor by PHA-stimulated T cells exposed to the suppressor. Partial purification and identification of the suppressor demonstrated that the suppressive activity was present in fractions between 30 and 50 kDa in size; the suppressor was also heat labile and freeze-thaw sensitive. The suppressive molecule(s) may therefore play a significant role in the establishment and pathology of L. donovani infections.</description><creator>Fielding, Mark</creator><contributor>Tanner, C. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Leishmania.</subject><subject>Immunosuppression.</subject><subject>Macrophages</subject><subject>Leishmaniasis -- Immunological aspects.</subject><title>Studies on a soluble immunosuppressive factor produced by Leishmania donovani infected macrophages</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w936r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w6710</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b528z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A computational and experimental study was made of the steady developing laminar convective heat transfer to viscous non-Newtonian fluids described by the power law model flowing in straight channels of circular and several non-circular cross-sections. In the numerical study the governing conservation equations in three dimensions subject to suitable boundary conditions were solved after appropriate discretization, using the Galerkin finite element method. Fourteen different cross-sectional geometries were studied numerically. Effects of temperature-dependent apparent viscosity, viscous dissipation as well as Prandtl number were included in the model. The thermal boundary conditions tested were: uniform wall temperature and uniform wall heat flux on the entire duct surface. Predicted velocity fields, pressure drop, and heat transfer distributions were compared with available data and simulation results as appropriate. Results are presented on the comparative thermal performance of various cross-sectional ducts. In the experimental study the critical Reynolds numbers were measured for distilled water flowing through a semi-circular and an equilateral triangular duct. Local Nusselt number distributions are presented for ducts with the horizontal bottom plane sides subjected to uniform heat flux while the rest of the channel is well insulated. The measured pressure drop and Nusselt number distribution for Carbopol solutions compared very well with the numerical predictions.</description><creator>Etemad, Seyed Gholamreza</creator><contributor>Mujamdar, A. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Laminar heat transfer to viscous non-Newtonian fluids in non-circular ducts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053j02x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b528z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j3334297</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Si ra-maghazi, which tells of the life of the Prophet and the early Islamic community, is not a historical genre. A literary mode which has its origins in an oral transmission, it is essentially hagiographic in spirit. The literature carries some unique characteristics. Constituted of numerous individual traditions juxtaposed one next to the other, it is--other than for those key events that have become mythologized--essentially dependent on the compiler and his purpose for its layout. This dissertation explores the genre through a comparative case study of Muhammad and the Jews as narrated in the Kitab si rat rasul Allah of lbn Ishaq and the Kitab al-maghazi of al-Waqidi. Appreciating the interpretation of the individual compiler concerned, it compares, in terms of method, structure, sources, chronology, and style, their different approaches to the subject of the early establishment of Islam. The differences reinforce the argument for appreciating si ra-maghazi as literary rather than a historical genre. More importantly, they bring into focus the tendentious nature of si ra-maghazi to understand why neither one of these texts may be used to substantiate the information in the other.</description><creator>Faizer, Rizwi Shuhadha, 1946-</creator><contributor>Little, D. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Ibn Isḥāq, Muḥammad, d. ca. 768. Sīrat Rasūl Allāh.</subject><subject>Wāqidī, Muḥammad ibn ʻUmar, 747 or 8-823. Maghāzī</subject><title>Ibn Isḥâq and al-Wâqidî revisited : a case study of Muḥammad and the Jews in biographical literature</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z77f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3334297</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967566m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The necessity of modelling multibody systems with flexible links in high-speed operations and space structures has become apparent. In this thesis, a general formulation for the simulation of multibody systems with multiple kinematic loops and flexible links of arbitrary shapes is developed. Parallel manipulators, space structures, multi-armed manipulators, and cooperating serial manipulators are examples of these systems. Finite element method is used for discretization of the flexible links, while the Lagrange formulation is used to derive the equations of motion of the uncoupled links. The kinematic constraints equations are generated next by using the natural orthogonal complement (NOC) of the twist-constraint matrix. Here, the formulation of the problem is obtained both in joint and in Cartesian spaces. Using the NOC, the constraint forces are eliminated from the equations of motion to obtain the governing equations of the system in minimum coordinates. Moreover, the formulation incorporates geometric nonlinearities in the elastic displacements, which can be very crucial in large rigid-body motions. A simulation environment is developed to perform the procedures underlying the above formulations for different types of robotic manipulators with kinematic loops and flexible links. To highlight the link flexibility effect, the governing equations of motion are used in the simulation of the aforementioned systems to compare the results obtained with the rigid and the flexible-link models.</description><creator>Fattah, Abbas</creator><contributor>Angeles, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Dynamics of robotic manipulators with flexible links and kinematic loops</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wh95b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967566m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n062t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A mutational analysis of genes which confer resistance to the yeast K1 killer toxin has identified a number of components involved in the synthesis of a $ beta(1 to 6)$-linked glucan polymer found in the Saccharomyces cerevisiae extracellular matrix. The KRE9 gene is predicted to encode a 30 kDa serine/threonine rich cell wall protein, which is modified by O-glycosylation before being secreted at the cell surface where it likely functions in $ beta(1 to 6)$-glucan assembly. Null mutations in KRE9 lead to killer resistance, slow vegetative growth, and reduced cell wall $ beta(1 to 6)$-glucan levels which are 10 to 20% of wild type. A study of the KRE11 gene has revealed that its product, Kre11p, is a 63 kDa cytoplasmic protein which appears to be involved in the regulation of glucan assembly. Through genetic interactions and epistasis assignments with these and other KRE genes, the basis of a biosynthetic pathway for the synthesis of this extracellular matrix polymer has emerged. A search for genes involved in the regulation of cell surface assembly has led to the identification of SKN7. Sequence analysis of Skn7p revealed a region of homology to the DNA-binding domains found on heat-shock transcription factors, and a distinct region of similarity to a large family of bacterial "two-component" signal-transduction proteins. Two-component systems have historically been confined to prokaryotic organisms, and the identification of SKN7 has raised the possibility that two-component signaling pathways involving phospho-histidine and phospho-aspartate transfer reactions may exist in higher eukaryotes. Skn7p appears to function in yeast as a nuclear localized two-component response regulator, whose transcriptional B activity is regulated through aspartic acid phosphorylation. The Skn7p signal transduction pathway may act in concert with the yeast PKC1-mediated MAP-kinase cascade, to regulate cellular growth events at the cell surface.</description><creator>Brown, Jeffrey L., 1968-</creator><contributor>Bussey, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Genetics</subject><title>Identification and functional characterization of the Saccharomyces cerevisiae KRE9, KRE11, and SKN7 genes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jg79g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n062t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tn91m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The way in which texture development is affected by hot rolling, intercritical rolling, and warm rolling was studied in a plain carbon, a niobium microalloyed and an interstitial free steel. Three processing parameters were varied: the austenitizing temperature (1250$ sp circ$C or 1150$ sp circ$C), amount of reduction (90% or 75%) and finish rolling temperature (1020$ sp circ$C, 870$ sp circ$C, 770$ sp circ$C, 730$ sp circ$C and 630$ sp circ$C for the first two materials, and 1020$ sp circ$C, 920$ sp circ$C, 870$ sp circ$C, 820$ sp circ$C, 720$ sp circ$C and 620$ sp circ$C for the IF steel). It was found that lower reheating temperatures and larger deformations lead to more intense textures. The effect of finish rolling temperature was different for each steel. In the plain carbon, only warm rolling produced a strong texture. In the interstitial free steel, the strongest textures were again produced by rolling in the ferrite range. In the niobium microalloyed steel, the retardation of austenite recrystallization intensifies the fcc deformation texture components; thus, a fairly strong texture is inherited by the ferrite, which is in turn enhanced by further deformation. The experimental textures were compared with the transformation textures predicted by using the Kurdjumov-Sachs relationship. It was found that when most of the reduction was applied in the austenite recrystallization range, the cube texture appeared to form, which transformed preferentially into the rotated cube $ { 001 } langle110 rangle$. When the austenite remained in the pancaked state, the expected transformation products of the fcc rolling texture, i.e. the copper $ { 112 } langle111 rangle$, brass $ { 110 } langle112 rangle$, S $ { 123 } langle634 rangle$ and Goss $ { 110 } langle001 rangle,$ again appeared, with clear preferences for particular variants. The calculations indicate that the final ferrite texture formed from either recrystallized or deformed austenite is significantly modifi</description><creator>Butrón Guillén, Martha Patricia</creator><contributor>Jones, Johm J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Transformation textures in hot rolled steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107098f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tn91m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj2364019</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Data required for the surveillance of the population of small areas and the implementation and evaluation of health preventive programmes are usually obtained from surveys conducted within each relevant small area. The substantial cost of local surveys has encouraged the search for other methods of obtaining the required information. One alternative consists of using small area estimators. Despite extensive applications of these procedures in diverse fields, guidelines concerning their use for the prediction of health variables are still lacking. In an effort to explore the applicability of small area estimators to the prediction of health parameters of Quebec's health areas, we conducted two empirical evaluations of these methods. Using data from Canadian surveys, estimates of health variables were produced for several Quebec's areas according to different techniques of small area estimation. The estimates were compared to a "standard" for each area and health variable, on the basis of average mean square error percents and Spearman correlations. Synthetic, regression-sample, and empirical Bayes estimators were evaluated. We observed that the more variable a health characteristic was among areas, the more difficult it was to predict accurately. While no small area estimator performed uniformly well for all the variables considered, the linear regression-sample estimators were generally at advantage according to the different criteria of evaluation. In the studied context, no gain was obtained by using more sophisticated procedures like the empirical Bayes estimators.</description><creator>Cardin, Sylvie.</creator><contributor>Boivin, Jean-Francois (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Health Care Management.</subject><title>Empirical evaluation of small area estimators in community health</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gq22r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj2364019</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720f85k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Paper in a calender nip is subjected to a pressure pulse which reduces its thickness and roughness, thus improving the product quality. Strain recovery after the nip is time-dependent, and some permanent strain remains. The material behaviour is viscoelastic; recovery depends on the pulse magnitude and duration, and does not occur immediately on exiting the nip. An improved description of the viscoelastic response to a calender pulse would allow design of adaptive control systems using feedforward techniques. Measurements of paper thickness in the nip, immediately after the nip and 24 hours after calendering were made with newsprint sheets running through an experimental calender operating at industrial conditions. The calculated strains were first related to the operating conditions using empirical curve-fitting methods, then using linear viscoelastic models. Empirical results describe the data well, and can be used to design improved control systems. Linear viscoelastic modeling was less successful since the material behaviour is not linear. Photomicrographs of sheet cross-sections were taken, and the observed non-linearities were discussed qualitatively in terms of paper and fibre properties.</description><creator>Browne, Thomas, 1955-</creator><contributor>Crotogino, R. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Douglas, W. J. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><subject>Agriculture, Wood Technology.</subject><title>Viscoelastic properties of paper in a calender nip</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s205n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720f85k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cs42w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of an Optimal Power Flow (OPF) algorithm is to find the steady-state operation point of a generation-transmission system which minimizes a pre-specified cost function and meets a set of operational and/or security constraints. OPF algorithms are among the tools present in many Energy Management Systems and their usefulness is increasingly being recognized by power utilities. This thesis presents an algorithm which uses the parameters existing in the OPF problem to find its solution. These parameters can be in the objective function or the equality or inequality constraints. This algorithm is applied to a parameterized OPF model built according to the following criteria: (i) when all parameters present in the model are relaxed from their given levels, a solution can be trivially found for this parameterized problem and (ii) when all parameters are returned to their original values, the parameterized model is equal to the original OPF. As the initially relaxed parameters are returned to their original values, they define a sequence of OPF problems which converge to the original one. The algorithm is designed to track the optimal solutions of these intermediate problems until the optimum of the original OPF. This tracking is made in a systematic manner. By using a binary search or a linear prediction method, the algorithm finds the maximum increment of the parameters which allow only one inequality to be fixed at its limit or to be released. The parameters are then adjusted to their new values, defining a new OPF problem with known optimal active feasible set. As a consequence, the optimal solution of this new problem can be easily found by solving the first order optimality conditions by Newton's method. In this way, the optimum is tracked from one active feasible set to the next until the parameters reach their original values. The parameterization permits the solution of the OPF problem for a fixed and variable load using the same mechanism described in the previous paragraph. As a result of this systematic tracking, the method is robust and able to provide a very good insight about the behaviour of the OPF solutions. In addition, the main difficulties encountered in solving the OPF problem are easily visualized and, in particular, the approach permits the differentiation of the potential causes for the failure of the tracking process, including the identification of unsolvable cases. The sensitivities of the optimal solution as a function of the parameters are also by-products of the method; including the Bus Incremental Costs and the System Incremental Cost as functions of the loads. The approach is also flexible enough to permit the simulation of line contingencies and of Flexible AC Transmission Systems (FACTS devices). The algorithm developed was tested in numerous networks with different objective functions and initializations and the results demonstrated the potential of this technique.</description><creator>De Almeida, Katia Campos</creator><contributor>Galiana, F. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Energy.</subject><title>A general parametric optimal power flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh572.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs42w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cv96c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis discusses the first language acquisition of three morphosyntactic mechanisms of transitivity alternation in arctic Quebec Inuktitut. Data derive from naturalistic longitudinal spontaneous speech samples collected over a nine-month period from four Inuit children aged 2;0 through 2;10 at outset. Both basic and advanced forms of passive structures are shown to be used productively by Inuktitut-speaking children at an early age relative to English-speaking children, but consistent in age with speakers of non-Indo-European languages reported on in the literature; potential explanations of this difference include frequency of caregiver input and details of language structure. Morphological causatives appear slightly later in the acquisition sequence, and their first instances reflect use of unanalyzed routines. Lexical causatives are present from the earliest ages studied. Evidence of a period of overgeneralization of lexical causatives in one subject at the same time as the morphological causative shows signs of being productively acquired suggests that the seeming overgeneralization may reflect nothing more than as yet unstable use of the morphological causative. Noun incorporation structures are shown to be used productively by Inuktitut-speaking children at an early age relative to Mohawk-speaking children; potential explanations of this difference include details of language structure and relative language use in the environments of the learners. Findings are considered in light of current debates in the literature concerning continuity versus maturation of grammatical structure, and concerning the functional categories available to the child at early stages of acquisition. Data presented argue against maturation, and suggest that all functional categories can be accessed by the Inuktitut-speaking child early in the acquisition process.</description><creator>Allen, Shanley E. M. (Shanley Elizabeth Marilou)</creator><contributor>White, Lydia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Inuktitut dialect -- Québec (Province) -- Acquisition.</subject><subject>Inuktitut dialect -- Québec (Province) -- Passive voice.</subject><subject>Inuktitut dialect -- Québec (Province) -- Causative.</subject><subject>Inuktitut dialect -- Québec (Province) -- Transitivity.</subject><title>Acquisition of some mechanisms of transitivity alternation in Arctic Quebec Inuktitut</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236402k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv96c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m5982</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A model of the sequence of decisions required for mine development and production has been formulated and is operated as a computer-based game. The Mine Manager is an operations research game in which the user assumes the role of mine management in the exploitation of a mineral deposit. Potential applications of the game lie in experimentation, policy formulation and education in mine economics. The Mine Manager is described using the terminology of games. The selection of parameters and of the level of detail in the model reflects a compromise between realism and simplicity. At the development stage, the selection of project specifications concerns the mining method and capacity installation. Decisions on cut-off grade and/or cut-off value, capacity utilization, the sequence of mining, stockpiling and expansion are made during the mine life. Decision making takes place within a framework provided by an abstraction of the operating environment of a mine, and must comply with a set of rules. These rules ensure that only feasible decisions are made. Within this constraint, the model offers a high degree of flexibility in setting the values of the decision variables. The Mine Manager combines elements of geology, mining, management and gaming. Conditional simulation is used to generate grades of copper, zinc and gold in a massive sulphide deposit. Mining operations in both underground and open-pit mines are modelled, and hypothetical capital and operating cost functions are developed for the mine and mill. A pricing model generates new price series for each run of the game. The Mine Manager is operated interactively on a microcomputer through the use of modular software. The user interface and a sample run of the game are described, and the information displays created by the game are presented.</description><creator>Allison, Jacqueline</creator><contributor>Dimitrakopoulos, Roussos (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Bilodeau, Michel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>A computer-based mine development and production management game</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z033b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m5982</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xb51n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Semantic trees have served as a theoretical tool for confirming the unsatisfiability of clauses in first-order predicate logic, but it has seemed impractical to use them in practice. In this thesis we experimentally investigated the practicality of generating semantic trees for proofs of unsatisfiability. We considered two ways of generating semantic trees. First, we looked at semantic trees generated using the canonical enumeration of atoms from the Herbrand base of the given clauses. Then, we considered semantic trees generated by selectively choosing the atoms from the Herbrand base using an improved semantic tree generator, AISTG. A comparison was made between the two approaches using the theorems from the "Stickel Test Set". In underlying the practicality of using semantic tree generators as mechanical theorem provers, another comparison was made between the AISTG and a resolution-refutation theorem prover "The Great Theorem Prover".</description><creator>Almulla, Mohammed Ali</creator><contributor>Newborn, Monty (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Analysis of the use of semantic trees in automated theorem proving</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v0486.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb51n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xk48p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new fast response conductivity meter was developed and tested. The "five time constant" of the meter is 0.08 s which meets the requirement for measurements under the dynamic conditions relevant to this work. In a laboratory column, a bubble interface was created by introducing a step change of gas flow, and the rising velocity of this interface, $u sb{in},$ was measured using a conductivity method with the new conductivity meter. A measurement of the three-dimensional bubble swarm velocity in the column was obtained by interpolation from the $u sb{in}$ measured as a function of $J sb{g2} vert J sb{g} sb1 ,$ where $J sb{g} sb1$ and $J sb{g} sb2$ are the superficial gas velocities before and after a step change of gas flowrate, respectively. This velocity was referred to as the hindered velocity, $u sb{h}.$ The buoyancy velocity, $u sb0 ,$ was readily determined by switching off the gas, i.e. $u sb0 = u sb{in}$ at $J sb{g} sb2 = 0.$ The average gas velocity, $u sb{g},$ was corrected to the local average gas velocity, $u sb{g,loc},$ to obtain the average gas velocity under the local pressure conditions at a given vertical position in the column. The experimental results showed that $u sb{h}$ was significantly less than $u sb{g,loc}$ (and $u sb{g}).$ This is because the $u sb{h}$ is the three-dimensional bubble swarm velocity and $u sb{g,loc}$ is the one-dimensional bubble swarm velocity. Unlike $u sb{g,loc},$ the $u sb{h}$ was constant along the column, which was supported by theoretical momentum analysis. The $u sb{h}$ is proposed as the key characteristic swarm velocity of the system. For the air-water only system in the two-dimensional domain, using parabolic models for gas holdup and liquid circulation velocity profiles over the cross section of the column, the $u sb{h}$ could be fitted to the experimental data. For the air-water-frother system, the $u sb{h}$ could not be fitted to the experimental data which is attributed to the air bubbles adopting a circulatory flow pattern. In the air-water only system under batch operation, Nicklin's derivation (1962), i.e. $u sb{g} = u sb0 + J sb{g},$ was supported only under restrictive conditions, namely $u sb{g}$ and $J sb{g}$ must be measured at atmospheric pressure. Considering the local values, the experiments showed that $u sb{g,loc}$ was not equal to $u sb0 + J sb{g,loc}.$ In the presence of frothers under batch or countercurrent operation, the experiments showed that Nicklin's derivation was not applicable even if atmospheric values of $u sb{g}$ and $J sb{g}$ were used.</description><creator>Shen, Gang, 1953-</creator><contributor>Finch, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Bubble swarm velocities in a flotation column</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f24c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk48p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591b31s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research examines factors that either promote or hinder workplace writing among Chemical Engineering students during their study in two Technical Report writing courses. It examines the extent to which a workplace writing environment, which instructors believe they create, is actually enacted in the classroom, and also explores the differences in intended and actual learning outcomes between instructors and students. A number of qualitative research methods were used to gather data for sixteen student case studies. These methods include taped and transcribed interviews with students and the two course instructors, an analysis of all student reports and course documentation, classroom observations, taped student-professor conferences, and taped responses from both instructors as they evaluated each student report. Research findings suggest that students learned the required technical report format since everyone passed the course. Findings further suggest, however, that explicit efforts to enact a professional chemical engineering writing environment within this university context were generally unsuccessful. Writing tasks did not reflect an authentic workplace writing situation where writers believed their composing purpose was to communicate with others within their community of Chemical Engineering. Even though attempts were made by instructors to create such an environment, the writing task actually became a school-based exercise where students learned to provide the right textual format in order to meet with both teacher expectations and writing success. The study concludes that educators must be aware of their real teaching and learning agendas and that these objectives must be conveyed adequately to students. Findings also reinforce the difficulty of enacting authentic workplace writing contexts within academic environments, and ways to achieve this goal are discussed. This research also contributes to evolving theoretical discussions about writing and the teaching of writing.</description><creator>Sloat, Elizabeth A.</creator><contributor>Dillon, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Technical writing</subject><subject>Engineering students</subject><title>Case studies of technical report writing development among student engineers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719p20b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b31s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w169r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The kinetics and mechanism of hydrolysis of both activated and unactivated phosphate diesters in the presence of aqueous solutions of Ce(III) salts are studied in detail. In the presence of 20 mM Ce$ rm (ClO sb4) sb3 (pH 8, 37 sp circ C)$ a DNA dinucleotide (dApdA) is converted to the nucleoside (dA) and inorganic phosphate with a half-life of approximately 100 minutes. This reaction is oxygen dependent and a mechanism involving the activation of oxygen by Ce(III) to give a Ce(IV) coordinated peroxide dianion as the active species is proposed. The addition of 20 mM hydrogen peroxide to 2mM La(III) (pH 7.0, 25$ sp circ$C) results in a 34,000 fold increase in the rate of BNPP hydrolysis over that observed in the presence of 2mM La(III) alone and an overall 5 x l0$ sp8$ fold rate increase over the uncatalyzed rate. Incorporation of $ sp{18}$O from hydrogen peroxide into the inorganic phosphate product and evidence from the reaction kinetics and potentiometric titrations indicate that the mechanism involves nucleophilic attack of a La(III) coordinated peroxide dianion upon the substrate. La(III) hydroxide clusters formed from the combination of La(III) (20 mM) and NaOM (40 mM) rapidly converts an RNA dinucleotide (ApA) to the monophosphates (2$ sp prime$-AMP and 3$ sp prime$-AMP) (t$ sb{1/2}$ = 8 sec at pH 8.7, 20$ sp circ$C). The presence of molecular oxygen does not improve the efficiency of Ce(III) in cleaving ApA; however, it does assist in the cleavage of the monophosphates which are not cleaved by Ce(III) in the absence of O$ sb2$ or La(III).</description><creator>Takasaki, Bryan K.</creator><contributor>Chin, Jik (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Lanthanide ions in the development of artificial nucleases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g272.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w169r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40425</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>