<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:41:18Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39575" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v7272</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dynamic characteristics of engineered-to-order (ETO) environments are in conflict with the basic assumptions of Manufacturing Resource Planning (MRP) systems, which makes MRP based manufacturing planning systems fail to meet the needs of ETO companies. ETO environments are complex and require sophisticated planning techniques. In fact, the shortcomings of planning and scheduling systems are exacerbating the ability of ETO companies to reduce manufacturing cycle times. This thesis presents an overview of ETO environments and related manufacturing planning and scheduling systems. The reasons for the failure of present MRP systems to address ETO environments are discussed along with an analysis of the planning systems of real companies. A new framework for manufacturing planning and scheduling in ETO environments is proposed. It addresses the importance of coordinating planning and scheduling among engineering, material procurement and the shop floor. It incorporates finite capacity scheduling into MRP systems to overcome load fluctuations. It also has scheduling mechanisms to address the dynamic nature of ETO environments.</description><creator>Jin, Guang, 1955-</creator><contributor>Thomson, Vince (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Industrial.</subject><title>A new framework for manufacturing planning and scheduling in engineered-to-order environments /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010r95k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v7272</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hk99d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A method is presented to solve supervisory control problems of discrete event systems and produce divergence-free controllers, which guarantee to avoid unbounded internal communications. The method is described in terms of process spaces, a formalism to model concurrent systems, and applied to safety models. Semantics mappings are described, which relate process spaces to I/O automata and other labeled transition systems. Divergence-free solutions are obtained based on a strong notion of divergence freedom. Our method, which produces the solution for a supervisory control problem, can also detect the absence of such solution and helps to obtain synthesizable specifications for the solutions as well. Finally, a case study is considered where the supervisory control formulation is used to derive the specification of a divergence-free protocol converter to interface two mismatched communication protocols.</description><creator>Hallal, Hesham H.</creator><contributor>Negulescu, Radu (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Divergence-free supervisory control and applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225c828.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hk99d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838230g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the most influential authors of the past decade who has tried to assess a theoretical model of defense of 'cultural rights' from a liberal prospective is Will Kymlicka. Kymlicka appears even to believe that his model of multiculturalism represents the only systematic account of minority rights that is yet available within liberal theory. He assumes that other liberal thinkers---e.g. Raz, Taylor, Habermas---'have sketched some concepts or principles which they think should govern liberal approaches to ethnocultural demands' but their views constitute, at the end of the day, 'more outlines than systematic theories' (Kymlicka 1997: 86, n. 1). This essay stems from my critical reading of Kymlicka's theory. It is not my intention here to provide an alternative model of dealing with 'cultural differences'. My aims are much more modest. First, I want to provide a critical assessment of Kymlicka's theory by pointing out some of its conceptual ambiguities. Second, I want to discuss the case of Switzerland by defending the thesis that it does not constitute a multinational state. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Stojanovic, Nenad.</creator><contributor>Patten, Alan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Kymlicka, Will.</subject><subject>Switzerland -- Social policy.</subject><subject>Multiculturalism -- Switzerland.</subject><subject>Switzerland -- Politics and government.</subject><title>The idea of a Swiss nation : a critique of Will Kymlicka's account of multination states</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73px81k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838230g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p28v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ethnicity and political action have always been interesting connections. With diaspora groups, this connection is intensified due to their strong desire for a homeland. Some members of the Kurdish community in Canada do not leave their political aspirations back home. As refugees, they use their newfound freedom to promote their political causes. Along with their political aspirations, also come political divisions. For Kurdish immigrants (mostly refugees), the importance of the homeland, their desire for 'nation-status' and recognition of their ethnic identity are paramount concerns. These desires take on different shapes and forms for different members of the community. This study shows that their degree of activism and their success are primarily a result of their attitudes toward Kurdistan, their family situation, their past experiences and their ability to put regional differences behind them. The Kurdish community is not homogeneous and these rifts in the community may keep it from flourishing.</description><creator>Sciortino, Josephine Esther.</creator><contributor>Weinfeld, Morton (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Kurdistan.</subject><subject>Kurds -- Canada.</subject><title>The genesis of an ethnic community : the case of the Kurds in Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p651k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p28v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920fz48z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examined structural constraints on early child code mixing. Constraints are widely attested in adult bilinguals (Myers-Scotton, 1993; Poplack, 1980). It has been argued that these constraints preserve the structural properties of both languages. It is uncertain whether constraints on early child code mixing are the same as constraints on adult code mixing. The present analysis was based on Poplack's two structural constraints: the free morpheme and the equivalence constraints. Ten French-English bilingual subjects were observed at 4 time periods, between approximately 2;00 and 3;06 years of age. The children's utterances containing elements from both languages were analysed for violations of Poplack's constraints. The violation rate was extremely low, less than 2% of the total mixed utterances. These results corroborate Lanza (1997), Vihman (1998), Allen et al. (2000), and Paradis et al. (2000), who likewise found that structural constraints on code mixing are operational from early in acquisition.</description><creator>Sauvé, Deanne.</creator><contributor>Genesee, Fred (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Bilingualism in children.</subject><subject>Code switching (Linguistics)</subject><subject>Language acquisition.</subject><title>Grammatical constraints on child bilingual code mixing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h02t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz48z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kv659</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this research paper is to analyse the literary works and the writers of Italian origin who have actively contributed to the creation of Italian-Canadian immigration literature, and above all, that referent to the Montreal milieu. For this and other reasons, it distinguishes itself from other Italian-Canadian productions and precisely due to this reality, the objective of this research is to: (1) examine its role, its characteristics, the difficulties its writers experience, its literary artistic value and the recognition it receives in our literary environment; (2) compare the creative approach adopted by some writers to the perfect example, Primo Levi; (3) expose its contents and reoccurring themes; (4) examine the question of the literary language of expression of these works; (5) demonstrate the social usefulness of this literary production.</description><creator>Tedeschi, Antonio.</creator><contributor>Gilardino, S. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Canadian literature -- Italian-Canadian authors -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Italian Canadians -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Immigrants in literature.</subject><title>La letteratura dell'emigrazione italo-canadese di Montréal /</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182n01d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kv659</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cc73t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis looks into the role of identity in ethnic conflict from social-psychological and cognitive perspectives. The literature of Social Psychology suggests that one strategy of social groups under pressure or threat is to revert to their collective identity and manipulate it in ways that yield a distinct positive value for group members. Focusing on the main proponent of this view, Social Identity Theory, and transposing its premises onto an ethnic level, an Ethnic Identity Theory is proposed that explains ethnic identity's utility for the positive self-esteem of members of an ethnic group during a time of crisis. As far as the cognitive aspect is concerned, the focus moves on to the individual level of analysis. It explores the issue of how information may be represented in the human brain, and proposes that it is due to particular 'exclusive' cognitive strategies of knowledge categorization, storing and re-processing that ethnic conflict is enhanced. Borrowing from Artificial Intelligence literature on Schemata and Frame theory, ethnic identity is treated as a frame with multiple slots for various traits that comprise an ethnic identity. Such modeling helps illustrate how properties related to the architecture of these mental structures result in the constructed ethnic identities becoming more rigid---their individual traits acquiring singular importance and, once challenged, affecting the whole identity. This study concludes by pointing that, if intransigence and inflexibility concerning ethnic identity traits begins on a cognitive micro-level, then, little progress towards peace should be expected in on-going ethnic conflicts, unless cognitively unbiased third parties are involved in peace-making, and unless their involvement includes action on a cognitive-learning level to change convictions about warring groups members' perception of their own as well as others' ethnic identities.</description><creator>Kotsovilis, Spyridon Demetrius.</creator><contributor>Meadwell, Hudson (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Macedonia (Republic) -- Relations -- Greece.</subject><subject>Greece -- Relations -- Macedonia (Republic)</subject><subject>Ethnicity.</subject><subject>Culture conflict.</subject><subject>Ethnic relations.</subject><title>Identity and ethnic conflict : their social-psychological and cognitive dimensions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h634z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc73t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p887s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present thesis examines Shafi'i's theory of naskh and its influence on the 'ulum al-Qur'an. The thesis looks at two types of sources: internal and external. Internally, the discussion focuses on the origins of naskh, the background and construction of Shafi'i's theory of naskh, tracing the ingredients of Shafi'i's thought in general and of his theory of naskh in particular. Having established Shafi'i's theory of naskh, the thesis goes on to examine it externally by considering Shafi'i's influence on six authors of naskh books (Naḣḣas's al-Nasikh wa al-Mansukh, Makki's al-Idḍaḥ, Ibn al-Jawzi's Nawasikh al-Qur'an, Shu'lah's Ṣafwat al-Rasikh, Ibn al-'Ata'iqi's al-Nasikh wa al-Mansukh) and his impact on the exegesis of eight Qur'anic verses -Q. 2: 106, Q. 22: 52, Q. 45: 29, Q. 7: 154, Q. 16: 101, Q. 13: 39, Q. 4: 160, and Q. 3: 7, discussed by six authors of tafsir (Ṭabari's Jami' al-Bayan, Jaṣṣaṣ's Aḥkam al-Qur'an, Zamakhshari's al-Kashshaf , Ibn al-Jawzi's Zad al-Masir, Qurṭubi's al-Jami' li Aḥkam al-Qur'an, and Suyuṭi's al-Durr al-Manthur). This thesis argues that despite its marginality in Shafi'i own time and throughout the ninth century in general, his theory of naskh played a significant role in the process of elaborating and systematizing the conceptual discourse on naskh in Qur'anic studies. Support for this assertion is found in the direct quotation of Shafi'i's view by the authors discussed herein, as well as by inference through a comparative analysis of their opinion. Nevertheless, this influence was not carried over into the domain of exegesis.</description><creator>Kusmana.</creator><contributor>Hallag, Wael B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Shāfiʻī, Muḥammad ibn Idrīs, 767 or 8-820.</subject><title>Shāfiis theory of naskh and its influence on the Ulm̄ư al-Qurān</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bg886.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p887s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz309</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is about the body and about how medical discourses conceptualise the body in health and in illness. However, any inquisitiveness about the body is determined by historical, social and political environment that nurtures the discursive formations of knowledge. I focus particularly on the conceptualisation of the body in the two distinct medical traditions of Western and Chinese medicine. I examine Michel Foucault's analysis on the medical gaze and on the external technologies of power deployed on the body of the individual and on the social body. The knowledge generated from the medical gaze is articulated through a normalising and prescriptive discourse. The gaze of Chinese medicine that looks at the workings of the cosmos to define the truth about the body generates similar authoritative knowledge that targets the individual and the social body. However, this effect of power, although it never disappears entirely, undergoes significant transformations when it enters the arena of human activities and the potential for improvisation in the behaviour of the human actor. There is always a gap between the text and the practice.</description><creator>Lemire, Diane M.</creator><contributor>Yates, Robin D. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Medicine, Chinese.</subject><subject>Medicine -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Discourse analysis.</subject><subject>Body, Human.</subject><title>The body in Western and Chinese medicine : discourses and practices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gf77t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz309</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zq336</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the relationship between Handel's borrowing practice and his creation of a new genre---the English Biblical oratorio. It focuses on the types of borrowing, the genres Handel borrowed from, and the use of self-borrowing vs. borrowing from other composers. A comprehensive list of borrowings discovered in Handel's Biblical oratorios (Appendix A) allows the patterns in Handel's borrowing practice and the evolution of the genre to be revealed and discussed. Chapter One provides a review of the literature on Handel's borrowing in general and the historical roots of Handel's Biblical oratorios. Chapter Two looks at the scholarly treatment of Handel's borrowing, and goes on to discuss specific musical examples of three borrowing types: Type I (reuse), Type II (rework), and Type III (new work). The final chapter identifies borrowing patterns that emerge in Handel's early, middle, and late Biblical oratorios. The borrowing type shifts from Type I to Type III, whereas the genres borrowed from change from sacred choral works to secular operas. Self-borrowings dominate in his early oratorios, drastically decrease in the middle period, and increase again in the late period.</description><creator>Lai, Wendy W., 1975-</creator><contributor>Cumming, Julie E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Oratorios.</subject><subject>Oratorio.</subject><title>Handel's borrowing practice in his biblical oratorios</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cz31k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq336</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j731z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Shifting cultivation is considered to be a key cause of deforestation in the tropics as agriculturalists transform the rain forest into cropland and later allow for its regeneration through fallowing. Forest fallows strongly influence the ecological and economic potential of shifting cultivation, yet, secondary forest management among shifting cultivators remains poorly understood. This study focuses on secondary forest management among peasant households in a land-abundant ejido, near the Calakmul Biosphere Reserve of Mexico. Data were gathered through in-depth household interviews and field visits with 44 households, accounting for more than 450 fields. Striking differences were found in fallowing practices in Nuevo Becal. The holding of secondary forest is related to access to male labour, wealth in land-assets, household age, and the holding of pasture. Fallow length at the plot level is associated with household age, land holding size and the manner in which land is acquired. Fallow periods tend to be longer for cycles begun from primary forest and appear to have become longer over time. This study demonstrates the importance of the microdynamics that influence differential land use decisions among households under apparently similar environmental and macroeconomic conditions.</description><creator>Abizaid, Christian.</creator><contributor>Coomes, Oliver T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Ejidos -- Mexico -- Nuevo Becal.</subject><subject>Fallowing -- Mexico -- Nuevo Becal.</subject><subject>Shifting cultivation -- Mexico -- Nuevo Becal.</subject><subject>Rain forests -- Mexico -- Nuevo Becal.</subject><title>Shifting cultivation and fallowing practices in a "land-abundant" ejido : an intra-community study of Nuevo Becal, Campeche, Mexico</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq693.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j731z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j96022618</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts to gauge the strengths and limitations of the Java programming language in terms of its use in the production of multimedia compositions: in particular, the ways in which Java supports the creation of interactive, non-deterministic musical works. An original solution to the problem of multimedia design is presented: a hierarchically defined, basic, yet flexible scripting language that is interpreted using Java. This scripting language allows the user to incorporate his/her own media into a coherent and interactive form using a small set of simple keywords and basic operators. It also allows new functionality to be added by advanced users with a basic knowledge of Java. By investigating how such a scripting language may be implemented, the extent to which Java may be applied towards multimedia applications in general is revealed.</description><creator>Beaulac, Jacqueline.</creator><contributor>Pennycook, Bruce (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Java (Computer program language)</subject><subject>Interactive multimedia.</subject><subject>Composition (Music) -- Computer programs.</subject><title>Interactive multimedia composition on the World Wide Web : a solution for musicians using Java</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fz497.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j96022618</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w415t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the image of the prostitute in four films: Klute (1971) Pretty Baby (1978) McCabe and Mrs. Miller (1972) and American Gigolo (1980). It includes a review of the image of the prostitute in art and literature in the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. These earlier images are compared and contrasted with the images presented in the four films and used to analyze how women are represented through the role of the prostitute in Klute, Pretty Baby and McCabe and Mrs. Miller. American Gigolo presents male prostitution in a manner conventional to prostitution, but unconventional in terms of representing men. American Gigolo provides a contrast for the three other films in terms of both gender and the image of the prostitute.</description><creator>Artt, Sarah.</creator><contributor>Straw, Will (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Prostitutes in motion pictures.</subject><title>Under the red light : images of prostitution in Klute, Pretty baby. McCabe and Mrs. Miller, and American gigolo</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h359h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w415t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr43k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This essay focuses on the moral aspect of Alexander Solzhenitsyn's political thought. It constitutes an extensive review and analysis of his work in the field of literature as well as social and political criticism. The first part deals with Solzhenitsyn's critique of Marxism, which remained for many years the main target of his attacks. The second part looks at Solzhenitsyn's historical analysis of the Soviet Communist experience. Subsequently, the essay examines the critique of the West expressed by the Russian writer during his exile in Europe and America. The last part deals with Solzhenitsyn's perception of post-Communism Russia and some of his major propositions for the future.</description><creator>Bernier, Jean, 1976-</creator><contributor>Boss, Valentine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Solzhenit︠s︡yn, Aleksandr Isaevich, 1918-2008 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>La vision politico-morale d'Alexandre Soljénitsyne /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sj09q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr43k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892c644</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Purpose. There are reports indicating that diuretics may increase the risk of gastrointestinal bleeding. The study was conducted to verify this hypothesis and to assess whether the risk varies with the different types of diuretics. Methods. Using the Saskatchewan health database, a nested case-control design was used, conducted within a population-based cohort of 47,865 new users of antihypertensive medications in Saskatchewan, from 1980 to 1983, and followed up to mid 1987. 753 subjects hospitalized for gastrointestinal bleeding were identified during this period, each of whom was matched with 10 randomly selected controls from a risk set formed at the index date, namely when a case was identified. Results. The rate of hospitalization for gastrointestinal bleeding in this cohort was 2.83 cases per 1,000 subjects per year. The adjusted rate ratio of gastrointestinal bleeding for current use of any diuretic within the 30-day time window prior to the index date was 1.54 (95% confidence interval, CI 1.27 to 1.86) compared with no current use of antihypertensive medications. Among the different classes, potassium-sparing diuretic are associated with the highest adjusted rate ratios (2.64; 95% CI, 1.35 to 5.16), and current use of combination of thiazide diuretics and potassium sparing with the lowest (1.39; 95% CI, 1.11 to 1.73) in the 30-day time window. The adjusted rate ratio of hospitalization for gastrointestinal bleeding for current use of a daily dose of thiazide diuretics less than 50mg was 1.34; 95% CI, 0.37 to 4.90, and for a daily dose equal to 50 to 60 mg the rate ratio was 1.81; 95% CI, 0.93 to 3.54, while for a daily dose greater than 60mg the rate ratio was 2.99; 95% CI, 1.14 to 7.84 within the 30-day time window. Results were similar when a 60-day exposure time window was used. Higher doses of furosemide (loop diuretic) were positively associated with hospitalization for gastrointestinal bleeding. Conclusion. Diuretic use appears to increase the risk of gastrointestinal bleeding.</description><creator>Blay, Daniel.</creator><contributor>Suissa, Samy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>The risk of gastrointestinal bleeding associated with diuretics among hypertensive persons /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n0455.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c644</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df38x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study sought to maximize prenatal and postnatal interventions in order to accelerate lung growth and improve lung function in two animal models. Prenatal interventions consisted of fetal tracheal occlusion (TO), antenatal glucocorticoids and exogenous surfactant at birth (SURF) in an ovine model of congenital diaphragmatic hernia (CDH). CDH, CDH+TO, CDH+SURF, CDH+TO+SURF and unoperated twin control lambs were compared. Prenatal growth of both lungs was accelerated after fetal TO. Prophylactic surfactant did not improve gas exchange or ventilation but did increase lung compliance over 8 hours. The incidence of tension pneumothoraces was slightly decreased after exogenous surfactant. Fetal TO yields the best results in terms of overall postnatal lung function, likely acting via surfactant independent mechanisms. Postnatal intervention involved perfluorocarbon (PFC) liquid distention of the right upper lobe in healthy newborn piglets. Postnatal lung growth, as measured indirectly by rates of DNA synthesis, was not accelerated after PFC distention.</description><creator>Butter, Andreana.</creator><contributor>Glageole, Helene (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Laberge, Jean-Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Lung growth and lung function after a) fetal lamb tracheal occlusion and exogenous surfactant at birth in congenital diaphragmatic hernia and b) selective perfluorocarbon distention in healthy newborn piglets</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps214.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df38x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj2363900</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pyridoxal isonicotinoyl hydrazone (PIH) has been described as an orally effective Fe chelator. It is both membrane permeable and plasma soluble, and has a high affinity for Fe, making it an ideal model on which to base future chelators. Ten novel ligands have been synthesized based on these attributes. Characterization experiments were performed to determine the ligands' selectivity and binding affinity for iron, their lipophilicity as both free and Fe-ligand complexes, and their stoichiometric relationship with iron. Efficacy of the chelators has been determined through their ability to effectively mobilize non-heme 59Fe from pre-labeled cells. Intracellular levels of chelator bound 59Fe were also determined. Concentration-dependence and time-dependence mobilization experiments were performed to determine the minimal concentrations of ligands required to elicit maximal 59Fe release. Toxicity experiments with various ligand concentrations were performed in order to determine the concentration which inhibits at least half of cellular growth as compared with control. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Mouralian, Cindy.</creator><contributor>Ponka, Premysl (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Evaluation of novel iron chelators for therapeutic use in secondary iron overload disorders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg31r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj2363900</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763878q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In a normal inflammatory response, the polymorphonuclear neutrophil (PMN) is recruited to a site of injury or infection through a sequence of events that include margination, rolling, adhesion, diapedesis and chemotaxis. These processes become dysregulated in SIRS, sepsis and MODS. Septic patients demonstrate decreased PMN exudation to peripheral sites and an absence of a C5a chemotactic gradient across the intravascular and extravascular environments. Using both in vitro and in vivo PMN transmigration assays, we evaluated the role of an intact C5a gradient on human PMN recruitment to peripheral inflammatory sites in sepsis. We demonstrated in vitro that a C5a gradient could induce both beta2-integrin dependent and independent transendothelial migration of septic PMN. In vivo, the exogenous re-establishment of the C5a gradient increased septic PMN exudation to normal baseline levels. These observations implicate an intact C5a gradient as an essential component to optimal PMN recruitment in sepsis.</description><creator>Campisi, Giuseppina.</creator><contributor>Christou, Nicolas V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Role of the C5a chemotactic gradient in reduced polymorphonuclear neutrophil (PMN) exudation in sepsis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d603h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763878q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451k42x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis discusses the role of Environmental Impact Assessments in the implementation of the concept of sustainable development within the realm of North-South tensions regarding responsibilities for environmental conservation. Environmental Impact Assessments provide opportunities for realizing sustainable development not only because they operationalize the integration principle of sustainable development by facilitating the equilibrium between development and environmental conservation objectives, essential for ecological sustainability, but also because, in allowing for public participation in the assessment process, they promote the realization of the civil right of participation in public affairs, an essential component of good governance required for sustainable development to thrive. However, the thesis scrutinizes the reality in developing countries of adopting Environmental Impact Assessments. They are not yet accorded a lot of value because it is foreign technology imported from the North, which must be adopted often as a conditionality to that much needed development assistance, which often does not take into account cultural realities in developing countries and which inadvertently plays a role in the growth of Third World debt, corruption and erosion of sovereignty in the Third World. It argues, therefore that the utility of Environmental Impact Assessment in the realization of global sustainable development is limited by the existence of these realities unless modifications are made in the implementation of Environmental Impact Assessments in developing countries.</description><creator>Akol, Doris.</creator><contributor>Provost, Rene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Sustainable development.</subject><subject>Environmental impact analysis.</subject><title>Assessing the utility of environmental impact assessments as a strategy for global sustainable development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333415w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k42x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s1932</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The business corporation is an important engine for the creation of wealth and it plays a vital role in promoting economic development and social progress in both domestic and international economies. Hence companies must operate within a governance framework that keeps them focused on their objectives and accountable for their actions. There is the need to establish adequate and credible governance arrangements. The degree of observance to the basic principles of good corporate governance is an important factor for investment decisions. Traditional corporate doctrine has taken the separation of ownership from control as the core problem of corporate governance. On this view, the principal function of corporate law is to devise strategies and mechanisms to ensure that corporate decision-making is based only on shareholders' interests. However, corporate managers are subject to influence from many other sources. Thus, the study of corporate governance must take account of all factors that affect managerial decision-making. In this thesis, I examine the influence that debt financing brings to bear on corporate governance and examine whether debt-holders should be beneficiaries of corporate fiduciary duties. I conclude that any such duty should be narrowly cast.</description><creator>Aboagye, Enoch Larbi.</creator><contributor>Janda, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Corporate governance.</subject><subject>Debt financing (Corporations)</subject><title>Debt financing : an emerging influence on corporate governance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg158.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s1932</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wm06s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While the use of microbial model systems in experimental evolution has made great contributions to our understanding of evolutionary processes, technological limitations and the problems of transparency they cause continue to inhibit their use in understanding even the most basic evolutionary phenomena. Conventional mathematical models are too constraining in that the range of genotypes and fitnesses must be designated at the outset, and so such models cannot be used to describe truly open-ended systems. In this thesis, I use Artificial Life technology to investigate patterns and mechanisms of evolution over short and long periods of time in a simulated chemostat-type system. The system may be rendered completely transparent, and is "open" in that genotypes with unique sequences and fitness arise unpredictably through mutation and selection. The results demonstrate that Artificial Life technology is an open-ended, yet tractable system that may be used satisfactorily to investigate problems that he beyond the reach of current theory and biotechnology. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Yedid, Gabriel.</creator><contributor>Bell, Graham A. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Artificial life.</subject><subject>Evolution -- Computer simulation.</subject><subject>Population genetics -- Computer simulation.</subject><subject>Quantitative genetics.</subject><title>Changing a bit at a time : patterns and mechanisms of microevolution and macroevolution in an electronic microcosm</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924d51v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wm06s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g4526</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes a system that retrieves exchange-traded option quotes on stocks, which are specified by the user, from the website www.moneynet.com. The data obtained from the Web is analyzed to determine the "breakeven" stock prices. A breakeven stock price is the expiration-date stock price for call or put options, in order for the call or put holders as a group to break even. This information is very useful as it helps us to understand the stock markets and the opinions of stock traders. It is useful for expectation analysis as well. The system is written in Excel 2000 and the data obtained from the Web is displayed on Excel spreadsheets and is transformed into a format that can be analyzed by the program. The program consists of approximately 900 lines of VBA code and uses many advanced Excel built-in functions.</description><creator>Zhang, Lingyan, 1970-</creator><contributor>Newborn, Monty (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Economics, Finance.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Automated data acquisition and analysis of stock options</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397996x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g4526</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r486</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thirty-eight oligotrophic lakes located around the Reservoir Gouin in central Quebec (48°N, 75°W) were sampled over three years to test the hypothesis that forest clearcutting and fires should be reflected in both higher nutrient export rates and ultimately in greater areal hypolimnetic oxygen deficit rates (AHOD). Significant differences in estimated total phosphorus export rates across treatments were found. However, no effect of clearcutting or forest fire on hypolimnetic oxygen consumption rates could be demonstrated as the result of a much greater and confounding variation in the effect of lake morphometry and the absence of information on the role of catchment-derived organic matter on the AHOD. Consequently, only lake morphometry (hypolimnetic volume to hypolimnetic surface area ratio) served as a predictor of the AHOD. Covariation of mean hypolimnetic water temperature with morphometric variables underlines the influence of lake morphometry on heat dynamics and hypolimnetic respiration rates in these lakes. This research made considerable use of specialized data manipulation techniques involving a relational database management system, owing to the size of the dataset used (114 lake-years of data). The specific approach used in this thesis is presented in an appendix.</description><creator>St. Onge, Peter Douglas.</creator><contributor>Kalff, Jacob (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Forest fires -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Clearcutting -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Water -- Dissolved oxygen -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>The effect of clearcut logging and forest fires on hypolimnetic oxygen depletion rates in remote Canadian Shield lakes /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w018.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r486</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784n50h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sensitivity studies of the ice sheet model and forcing in the McGill Paleoclimate Model (MPM) are presented. The MPM is a five component (atmosphere, ocean, sea ice, land surface, ice sheet) sectorially averaged Earth system Model of Intermediate Complexity (EMIC). The ice flow rate factor is found to have a large effect on both the ice volume and the extent of the southern margin. Values corresponding to equivalent temperatures of -7°C and -4°C are most appropriate for the initiation of glaciation (formation of Laurentide and Fennoscandian ice sheets) during the last glacial period. The formulation for the lateral ice discharge is improved to allow for a more realistic description of the east-west length scale of the ice sheets. Significant increases in both the ice volume and growth rate are obtained. To improve the ice sheet-atmosphere coupling in the MPM, a high resolution nested land surface component is introduced. By calculating the land surface processes on the higher resolution of the ice sheet component, a more accurate representation of the dependence of the surface air temperature on the surface elevation of the ice sheet can be included. This removes grid related artifacts from the equilibrium ice sheets determined by the model. It is shown that this high resolution nested component does not significantly affect the growth rate of the ice sheets during the initiation phase of glaciation.</description><creator>Smith, Gregory C.</creator><contributor>Mysak, Lawrence A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Physical Geography.</subject><subject>Geophysics.</subject><title>McGill paleoclimate model ice sheet sensitiivity to ice flow rate and discharge parameters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z7169.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784n50h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cg16j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR) is an important enzyme in the metabolism of folate and methionine. MTHFR catalyzes the conversion of 5,10 methylenetetrahydrofolate (5,10-methyleneTHF) to 5-methyltetrahydrofolate (5-methylTHF). 5-MethylTHF is a co-substrate for homocysteine remethylation to methionine catalyzed by the vitamin B12-dependent enzyme methionine synthase. A common MTHFR variant, 677C → T substitution resulting in the conversion of an alanine to a valine residue, has been shown to be a thermolabile form of MTHFR and to have reduced activity (Frosst et al., 1995). Since many diverse cancer cells have been documented to be methionine-dependent in culture, the effects of MTHFR downregulation on cell survival of transformed cells was examined. In addition, the influence of the MTHFR 677C → T polymorphism on the sensitivity of transformed lines to antifolate drug treatment was studied. To test the effect of decreased MTHFR expression on cell viability, we transfected antisense oligonucleotides (ASOs) complementary to the MTHFR mRNA into the colon carcinoma cell line SW620. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Sekhon, Jaspreet.</creator><contributor>Rozen, Rima (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Antisense inhibition of methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase as a cancer treatment and a pharmacogenetic study to examine the effects of a common polymorphism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3334165.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg16j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39600</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>