<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:44:33Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40350" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913r71q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examined the relationship of amateur golfers' perceptions of their perceived physical self-efficacy to their performances on the golf course. Ninety-one amateur golfers completed two questionnaires and a participant profile. The perception of their physical ability in general was measured by the Physical Self-Efficacy Scale, and the Perceived Golf Ability Questionnaire was developed to assess their perceptions of golfing self-efficacy. Respondents were asked to play 15 consecutive golf games and record their scores on an especially designed detailed scorecard. The participants' data were divided into five levels of performance based on their handicap indexes. It was hypothesized that players having greater skills (low handicap indexes) would have higher general perceived physical self-efficacy, than those having lesser skills (high handicap indexes). It was also hypothesized that the more golf-specific self-efficacy measure would be a better predictor of performance on the golf course. ANOVA and hierarchical regression analyses were employed to determine the predictive values of the two measures of perceived physical self-efficacy of actual golf performance. The general physical self-efficacy measure did not predict performance whereas the more golf-specific measure was a significant predictor of performance on the golf course. The ability of specific items of the golf self-efficacy measure to predict performance of various shots in golf was also examined.</description><creator>Gagnon, Marie-Josée</creator><contributor>Neil, Graham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Golf</subject><subject>Self-efficacy</subject><subject>Athletic ability</subject><subject>Sports -- Psychological aspects</subject><title>Physical self-efficacy and amateurs' performance on the golf course</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j529.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r71q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zs60z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis argues that non-argumentational strategies of persuasion in the major-length speeches of Jesus in the Gospel of Mark account for a considerable part of the author's intended persuasive effect. Gospel criticism has typically read these speeches as deposits of possible authentic words of Jesus, as evidence of Christology or as links in the plot of Mark's narrative while rhetorical criticism of the Gospels has focused upon Jesus' shorter utterances as argumentation within episodes. However, the speeches are not consistently logical or argumentational and they stand out in the larger narrative as extended stretches of Jesus' voice. Treating the four longest units of Jesus' speech as rhetorical units in their own right (Mk 4:11--32; 9:39--50; 12:1--11; 13:5--37), the thesis attempts to show how these texts might have worked to persuade Mark's audience towards change in action or attitude. Although neither argumentation at the rational-conceptual level nor the context of the narrative are denied, attention is focused on the rhetorical force of the speeches themselves and the features designed to affect the audience at the level of feeling or emotion. Persuasive goals are discernable in the speeches not only in what Jesus argues but also in the way he talks.</description><creator>Fast, Lesley D.</creator><contributor>Henderson, Ian H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Rhetoric in the Bible.</subject><subject>Jesus Christ -- Words</subject><title>Rhetorical dimensions of speech representation : a study of the speeches of Jesus in the gospel of Mark</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df46m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zs60z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57ns896</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines and analyzes the controversy around white rapper Eminem to inspect the way in which black and white theories of belonging function within an American context. The assumption behind the racial dichotomy that defines whites and blacks in oppositional positive and negative terms presumes that identity is structured along race stereotypes. This belief is evident in the differing responses to Eminem's affiliation with hip-hop culture and through the extent in which he employs hip-hop cultural forms, styles, and traits into his rap image. Although a popular mainstream artist, Eminem (and his "thug" Slim Shady alter ego) maintains his credibility within hip-hop circles by using elements of parody, play, and persona to depict his satirical views of American life. Finally, the systematic attacks against Eminem that label him as deviant are rarely levelled against other black rappers, exposing the different societal expectations that exist for whites and blacks.</description><creator>Fernandes, Denise</creator><contributor>Straw, William (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Music and race</subject><subject>Hip-hop</subject><title>The new "role model" for the hip-hop generation : dissecting the hype to locate Eminem, Slim Shady, and Marshall Mathers through race relations, black cool, media coverage, and the search for hip-hop credibility</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qd93s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57ns896</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p011w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to examine the effects of HBO2 therapy on exercise-induced muscle damage. Subjects (n = 16 university student volunteers) were randomly divided into an experimental group that received HBO2 therapy and a control group that did not receive any treatments. HBO2 treatments consisted of 5 sessions of breathing 95% oxygen at 2.5 atm abs for 100 min. Temporary muscle soreness was created using a single-leg eccentric exercise task involving the quadriceps femoris. Over the next 14 days, measurements were obtained on muscle soreness, leg circumference, quadriceps peak torque, quadriceps average power, fatigue and plasma creative kinase. After eccentric exercise, plasma CK levels and perceived muscle soreness were elevated but were not different between HBO2 and control groups. HBO2 therapy did not alter leg circumference, quadriceps peak torque, average power or fatigue compared to the control group. The data indicated that five HBO2 treatments did not speed recovery following eccentric exercise that induced temporary muscle damage.</description><creator>Germain, Geneviève</creator><contributor>Montgomery, David L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Sports injuries -- Treatment</subject><subject>Hyperbaric oxygenation</subject><title>Effect of hyperbaric oxygen therapy on exercise-induced muscle injury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b309n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p011w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zq425</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cystic Fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator (CFTR) Cl - channels are rapidly and efficiently deactivated by a type 2C serine/threonine phosphatase (PP2C). The efficiency of this regulation suggests that PP2C and CFTR are associated within a regulatory complex. Previous work has shown that PP2C and CFTR can be co-immunoprecipitated and reversibly coupled by exposing cell lysates to the hydrophilic cross-linker dithiobis [sulfosuccinimidyl proprionate]. While it is clear that PP2C can associate with CFTR, the nature of the interaction between them has not been defined. The goal of this study was to identify specific region(s) within CFTR that mediate this interaction. The interaction between CFTR and PP2C was strong enough to be reproduced in the absence of cross-linking agents, supporting its physiological relevance. We then translated CFTR in vitro and incubated it with cell lysates containing endogenous PP2C, however interaction between the proteins was not observed under these conditions. Since the association seemed to require some factor present in cells, a distal fragment of CFTR was expressed in vivo and used for pull down assays. PP2C was co-purified under these conditions, suggesting an interaction between PP2C and the C-Tail of CFTR. To further narrow down the region of interaction, three residues within the C-Tail (Y1424, LL1430/1431) that had been shown previously to interact with the AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK, a known PP2C substrate and possible targeting protein) were mutated to alanines. When this mutant was used in a pull-down assay, no association with PP2C was observed, consistent with a role for AMPK-binding residues and AMPK in the association of PP2C with CFTR.</description><creator>Tryansky, Jonathan N.</creator><contributor>Hanrahan, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Characterization of the interaction between the cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator and protein phosphatase type-2C</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343t96r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq425</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139394v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thermal kinetics of enzymatic time-temperature integrators (TTIs) were experimentally evaluated under both conventional and microwave heating systems in the pasteurization temperature range (50 to 90°C). Recent developments of process evaluation methodologies have Shown that standardized enzymatic time-temperature integrators (TTIs) could be successfully used for fast and correct quantification of thermal processes. Promising results have been reported for the alpha-amylase based TTI from Bacillus subtilis (BAA), which was chosen in this study as the TTI to compare the effectiveness of continuous-flow heating systems with microwave and conventional heating modes. Thermal inactivation kinetics of alpha-amylase was studied by measuring the residual activity of heat treated samples in isothermal conditions in a temperature range of 50 to 95°C and pH range, 5.0 to 6.9. Based on a first order rate of inactivation kinetics, kinetic parameters, decimal reduction time, D, and temperature sensitivity indicator, z, were calculated. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Tong, Zhen, 1970-</creator><date>2002</date><subject>Amylases.</subject><subject>Food -- Effect of heat on.</subject><subject>Microwave heating.</subject><title>Evaluation of conventional and microwave heating systems for food processing based on TTI kinetics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq08p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139394v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jt10g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Healthy human newborns fed glucose solution prior to testing exhibit higher levels of blood glucose and are able to remember a spoken word for a longer time than infants who receive water. To determine whether a natural feeding affects newborn auditory memory and whether it is related to blood glucose, memory for spoken words was examined for two groups of newborns---one tested before and the other after---routine breast or formula feedings (pre- vs postprandial), using a partially infant-controlled habituation recovery paradigm. Prior to analyses, the postprandial group was split at the median for blood glucose to define two groups: high and low glucose. The results indicate that infants' memory for words is better after a feed than before a feed. However, better memory following a natural feeding is not related to blood glucose, implying that the ingestion of food may modulate memory by more than one mechanism.</description><creator>Valiante, A. Grace (Antonella Grace)</creator><contributor>Young, Simon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Psychology, Cognitive.</subject><title>Natural feeding enhances human neonatal memory for spoken words</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df485.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt10g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rk07s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Prostate Specific Antigen (PSA) is a biochemical marker used to monitor prostate cancer following treatment. We have analyzed serial PSA data for a cohort of men who underwent radical surgery for prostate cancer in the early 1990s. We first describe the development of a statistical model that reflects the characteristics of these data. It accommodates, via a mixture model with constrained parameters, two sub-populations of men who are and are not cured, along with the biologic pattern in the latter. We then describe how we fit this model using Gibbs Sampling. We describe how the output can be converted into parameters of interest to patients and their physicians.</description><creator>Turner, Elizabeth, 1978-</creator><contributor>Dendukuri, Nandini (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Analysis of prostate specific antigen "trajectories" : statistical challenges</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d1882.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rk07s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881n910</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Knowing the detrimental effects that chronic hypersecretion of cortisol can have on hippocampal-dependent memory and the anatomical integrity of the hippocampus in normal elderly humans and animals, the goal of this project was to describe correlates of cortisol hypersecretion in normal elderly humans. Subjective complaints of memory and depressive symptomatology were chosen as possible correlates because they have previously been linked to cortisol hypersecretion. Normal elderly volunteers were recruited based on their subjective complaints of memory and/or depression and grouped as a LOW, MODERATE or HIGH cortisol secretor, based on salivary cortisol levels measured over the course of one year. Subjects were administered neuropsychological tests and psychosocial and environmental questionnaires that have been known to differ with different stress profiles. Results revealed that subjective complaints of memory and depressive symptomatology were not significantly related to hypersecretion of cortisol. Diurnal and seasonal cortisol secretory patterns did, however, differentiate HIGH secretors from MODERATE and LOW secretors such that there was a loss of diurnal and seasonal rhythmicity in the HIGH secretor group. Additionally, psychosocial questionnaires focusing on locus of control revealed that LOW secretors externalized control mechanisms more than MODERATE secretors. The possibility of lack of cortisol rhythmicity as a correlate of chronic hypersecretion of cortisol in young-elderly individuals as well as changes in locus of control mechanisms during aging are discussed.</description><creator>Pim, Heather D.</creator><contributor>Lupien, Sonia J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Chertkow, Howard M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Correlates of hypersecretion of cortisol in the normal elderly population : investigating subjective complaints of memory and depressive symptomatology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96022775.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881n910</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xg782</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several species of raptors are found in prairie landscapes managed and enhanced for waterfowl. Red-tailed Hawks (Buteo jamaicensis ) and Great Horned Owls (Bubo virginianus) may benefit from such management in a manner that is counter to its goals and objectives; that is, waterfowl may comprise a significant proportion of their diet, resulting in a decline in waterfowl numbers. The overall aims of this three-year study were to determine whether the feeding habits of the two raptor species are selective and to determine if waterfowl is a preferred prey group. The diet was determined through pellet analysis, prey remains and direct nest observations during the nestling growth period. Availability of most prey species was assessed through small mammal trapping and by conducting waterfowl censuses. It was determined that both raptors select for duck species. The average waterfowl biomass consumed per nestling represented 21.5% of the total biomass consumed for Great Horned Owls and 23.5% for Red-tailed Hawks. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Pauzé, Marc D.</creator><contributor>Titman, R. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Bird, D. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Ducks -- Predators of -- Saskatchewan.</subject><subject>Great horned owl -- Food -- Saskatchewan.</subject><subject>Red-tailed hawk -- Food -- Saskatchewan.</subject><title>Predation by great horned owls and red-tailed hawks in a prairie landscape enhanced for waterfowl</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rq59t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xg782</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j984t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>These studies examined the effects of leptin administration on the regulation of hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis and energy balance in neonatal rat pups. We found a significant inverse relationship between leptin and corticosterone secretion in naive pups from PND6--20. We demonstrated that chronic elevation of leptin during the first 10 days of life increased the efficiency of glucocorticoid feedback on the HPA axis following stress exposure, by increasing GR expression in the PVN and the DG. Acute leptin injection did not reduce food intake on PND5, 8 and 10, although it increased the mRNA levels of SOCS-3 and POMC, while it modulated NPY in both directions, depending on the level in the ARC. Chronic leptin treatment increased the mRNA expression of POMC, while it decreased that of Ob-R and GR. Furthermore, an acute injection of leptin on PND10 increased the mRNA expression of SOCS-3 and CRFR-2 and decreased that of NPY in pups chronically treated with leptin.</description><creator>Proulx, Karine</creator><contributor>Walker, Claire-Dominique (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Regulation of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis and appetite-related neuropeptides by leptin during the early postnatal period in rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848s44p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j984t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c2464</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this thesis was to assess the acceptance of an online-questionnaire in a survey of young adults in southern Germany. The online-questionnaire was implemented in a study of respiratory diseases. Each of 280 subjects, aged 18 to 20 years, was assigned randomly to one of two groups who responded using (1) a paper-based questionnaire and (2) an otherwise identical questionnaire that was to be completed on the Internet. This group also received a copy of the printed questionnaire. Only eight subjects made use of the online-questionnaire, and the remainder of the respondents used the paper-based instrument. The major reason given for not using the online-questionnaire was that subjects considered it too time-consuming (39.7%). Additionally, 27.0% of the subjects did not have access to the Internet at home. In conclusion, the acceptance of an Internet-based questionnaire by adolescents with an Internet coverage of about 60% may still be low.</description><creator>Radon, Katja</creator><contributor>Goldberg, Mark (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Evaluation of an internet-based online-questionnaire administered to young adults</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs827.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c2464</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qd942</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present project investigated the effect of epidural blockade with local anesthetic on the catabolic stress response during and immediately after abdominal surgery in fasting patients and during infusion of glucose at 2 mg·kg-1·min-1. The kinetics of glucose and protein metabolism were assessed by the stable isotope tracers [6,6-2H2]glucose and L-[1-13C]-leucine. Epidural blockade was associated with a lower plasma glucose concentration and glucose production when compared to control subjects in the fasted state. Whole body protein breakdown, amino acid oxidation and protein synthesis were suppressed during surgery, and epidural blockade had no modifying effect on perioperative protein metabolism. The suppression of endogenous glucose production by exogenous glucose was more pronounced in the presence of epidural blockade. Perioperative protein metabolism, however, was not influenced by epidural blockade during glucose infusion. Although epidural blockade suppressed glucose metabolism both in the fasted state and during glucose administration, it failed to exert a modifying effect on perioperative protein metabolism.</description><creator>Lattermann, Ralph</creator><contributor>Wykes, Linda (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Glucose -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Proteins -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Peridural anesthesia.</subject><subject>Surgery -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><title>Epidural blockade and the catabolic response to surgery : an integrated analysis of perioperative protein and glucose metabolism using stable isotope kinetics in the fasted and fed state</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z729c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qd942</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x099v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Metal contamination can disrupt the trophic links in food webs by altering the taxonomic composition and size structure of benthic invertebrate communities. Benthic invertebrate samples and perch (Perca flavescens) were collected from six lakes along a gradient of metal pollution in Rouyn-Noranda, Canada. The benthic communities of the contaminated lakes were less diverse and had smaller individuals (0.09 mg d.w. and 0.16 mg d.w. vs. 0.22 mg d.w. in the reference lake). The stomach contents of perch from contaminated lakes were less diverse, showed a greater reliance on chironomids or zooplankton, and cannibalism than perch from less polluted lakes. The mean size of prey in perch from contaminated lakes was smaller than in reference lakes (3.7 mg d.w. and 7.39 mg d.w. vs. 47.7 mg d.w. and 67.1 mg d.w. in reference lakes). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Kövecses, Jennifer</creator><contributor>Rasmussen, J. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Yellow perch -- Effect of water pollution on -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi-Témiscamingue.</subject><subject>Yellow perch -- Effect of heavy metals on -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi-Témiscamingue.</subject><subject>Environmental toxicology -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi-Témiscamingue.</subject><subject>Food chains (Ecology) -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi-Témiscamingue.</subject><title>Impacts of heavy metals on lake food webs : changes to the littoral benthic invertebrate communities and the consequences for yellow perch (Perca flavescens)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt692.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x099v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qb98mh39v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neonatal excitotoxic lesions of rat ventral hippocampus (nVH) have been demonstrated to induce post-pubertal behavior and neurochemical alterations analogous to those observed in schizophrenia (Sams-Dodd et al., 1997; Flores et al., 1996A; Lipska et al., 1995; and Lipska et al., 1993). To better characterize the mechanism of nVH lesions, we have examined the effects of transient glutamatergic blockade on the major output structures of VH, namely nucleus accumbens, cingulate prefrontal cortex, infralimbic prefrontal cortex and ventral tegmental area. A single bilateral injection of NMDA antagonist D-2-amino-5-phosphonopentonoic acid (AP-5) was administrated stereotaxically into male neonatal Sprague-Dawley rat at postnatal day 7. Animals were subsequently tested for alteration in prepulse inhibition, locomotor activity, social interaction and anxiety pre- and postpubertally. Histological study was also made to determine the nature of neurodevelopmental damage. The results suggest a development window of glutamatergic activity critical for mediating long-term adult behaviors.</description><creator>Lafleur, Isabelle</creator><contributor>Srivastava, Lalit (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Changes in adult behavior following a single neonatal injection of NMDA antagonist AP-5 in different rat brain regions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z971h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mh39v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm371</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To understand the molecular basis of developmental control of cell division during C. elegans organogenesis, two different approaches were taken. First, a screen was performed to identify mutants with altered numbers of intestinal nuclei using a reporter transgene specific to the intestinal nuclei. The intestine displays three different cell division patterns; mitosis, karyokinesis and endoreplication, therefore, in this screen we could potentially isolate mutants in genes affecting any of these different cell cycles. An F2 semi-clonal screen was performed and mutants with fewer or supernumerary numbers of intestinal nuclei were isolated. One mutant, rr31, with twice the wild type complement of intestinal nuclei was mapped and the defect was subsequently shown to be due to a gain-of-function mutation in the cell cycle phosphatase cdc-25.1. Further characterization of the cdc-25.1(gf) mutant, showed that the extra intestinal cells arise from an additional division of the intestinal cell precursors during embryogenesis, and that this phenotype is unique to the intestinal lineage. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Kostić, Ivana</creator><contributor>Roy, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Development.</subject><title>Regulation of embryonic and postembryonic cell divisions in Caenorhabditis elegans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p225c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm371</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544br360</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Regional economic disparities are a widely noted characteristic of the Canadian economy. This thesis examines regional disparities in terms of wages and labour productivity in the manufacturing sector. Regional disparities are analysed along three dimensions: provinces, rural/urban areas and industrial structure. Various competing theories are discussed and compared to the findings. Shift-share based decomposition analyses the magnitude and pattern of disparity and controls for industrial structure. Weighted regression is used to combine provincial and rural/urban effects. The findings support theories that emphasize provinces as units of analysis. The rural/urban results gave qualified support to urban theory. Accounting for industrial structure impacted both the rural/urban and provincial results. The regression analysis found the rural/urban dimension was significant; however, industrial structure and provincial effects were more significant. These results suggest industrial location and provincial economic policies can influence regional economic disparities in Canada.</description><creator>Campbell, Robert Wilfred</creator><contributor>Brown, Mark (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Wage differentials -- Canada.</subject><subject>Manufacturing industries -- Labor productivity -- Canada.</subject><subject>Regional economic disparities -- Canada.</subject><title>Wages and labour productivity in Canada : across the provinces and over the ruralurban divide</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741t65k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544br360</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806179t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Characterizing dissolved organic matter (DOM) composition remains a major unresolved problem in aquatic ecology. "Tryptophan-like" dissolved organic matter fluorescence (FDOM) was found to be a much better predictor of heterotrophic bacterial metabolism in 28 Quebec lakes than dissolved organic carbon (DOC), describing 52, 44, 51 and 55% of the variability in bacterial production (BP), bacterioplankton respiration (BR), total bacterial carbon consumption (TBCC), and total plankton community respiration (CR), respectively. In addition, the study provides indirect support for the view that FDOM represents a product of bacterial activity, rather than a bioavailable substrate. This is the first field study to show that fluorescence spectroscopy can be used to characterize an aspect of DOM composition that is related to bacterial metabolism, and provides results that encourage further exploration of the potential uses of DOM fluorescence spectroscopy as a predictive tool.</description><creator>Cammack, W. K. Levi.</creator><contributor>Klaff, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Fluorescence spectroscopy</subject><subject>Microbial metabolism</subject><subject>Lake ecology -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Bacteria, Heterotrophic -- Metabolism</subject><title>Dissolved organic matter fluorescence : relationships with heterotrophic metabolism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db87j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806179t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v488q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Santillan-Mackey model of the tryptophan operon was developed to characterize the anthranilate synthase activity in cultures of Escherichia coli. Similarly, the GABA reaction scheme was formulated to characterize the response of the GABAA receptor at a synapse, and the Hodgkin-Huxley model was developed to characterize the action potential of a squid giant axon. While the Hodgkin-Huxley model has been studied in great detail from a mathematical vantage, much less is known about the preceding two models in this regard. This work examines the stiffness of all three models; a novel perspective for both the Santillan-Mackey model and the GABA reaction. The characterization of the stiffness in these problems gives theoretical biologists insight into the dynamics of the reactions. It also enables them to select more computationally efficient methods for numerical simulations. The discovery of invariant manifolds in the Santillan-Mackey model and the GABA reaction in this work present experimentalists with concrete assays, against which the models can be tested.</description><creator>Caberlin, Martin D.</creator><contributor>Nigam, Nilima (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Stiff ordinary and delay differential equations in biological systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dv01d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v488q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t108w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The prion protein (PrP) is known for its implication in a number of neurological disorders. Interestingly, overexpression of Bcl-2 in these PrP-/- cells protects against serum deprivation, suggesting that PrP may function like Bcl-2 to prevent cells from undergoing apoptosis. Based on this idea, this thesis demonstrates that PrP is a potent protective agent against Bax-mediated death of cultured human primary neurons. This neuroprotective function appears to require the presence of the octapeptide repeat region of PrP. Surprisingly, while the majority of PrP resides on the cell surface as a glycophosphatidyl inositol (GPI)-anchored protein, the GPI anchor is not required for the neuroprotective function of PrP. In contrast, PrP needs trafficking past the cis-Golgi to be effective against Bax since its neuroprotective function is sensitive to brefeldin A and monensin treatments. On the other hand, we have established a yeast-based assay to analyse the function of PrP against Bax. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Bounhar, Younes</creator><contributor>LeBlanc, Andrea C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The prion protein protects against Bax-mediated cell death /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pp99p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t108w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87ps39k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Laboratory soil columns, 0.3 m diameter $ times$ 0.7 m long, and two computer simulation models, LEACHM-N and NTRM, were used to investigate nitrate-nitrogen ($ rm NO sb{3 sp{-}}$-N) leaching in a sandy loam soil. The following treatments were studied: no-till (NT), reduced tillage (RT), and conventional tillage (CT) practices, with residue (R) and without residue (NR). Nitrogen fertilizer was applied at a rate of 180 kg/ha in granular form (experiment I), and in solution form a year later (experiment II). In both experiments, water was applied 5 times over 3 to 4 weeks duration, with each application lasting for 30 minutes. Each column received an average of 24 mm water in experiment I and 32 mm in experiment II. Soil moisture contents were measured and water for $ rm NO sb{3 sp{-}}$-N concentration determination sampled at 0.1, 0.2, 0.4, and 0.6 m depths, following each water application. In each experiment I, higher nitrate-nitrogen concentrations ($ lbrack rm NO sb{3 sp{-}}$-N)), occurred at the 0.1 and 0.2 m soil layers in RT and CT treatments initially, but less leached to lower layers, while more $ rm NO sb{3 sp{-}}$-N leached to lower depths (below 0.4 m) in the NT treatment. In experiment II, more $ rm NO sb{3 sp{-}}$-N leached below 0.4 m in RT and CT than in NT treatments. Conventional tillage exhibited the lowest drainage rates. Tillage and residue effects were significant only at early stages (4 hours or before) at some depths of experiment I ($P&lt;0.05$). Maximum $ lbrack rm NO sb{3 sp{-}}$-N) occurred at 0.4 m depth in all treatments. LEACHM-N estimated more $ rm NO sb{3 sp{-}}$-N leaching below 0.4 m in RT and CT treatments than in NT treatment. The model performed poorly only immediately after fertilizer application, showing up to 50% deviation from observed data. Although LEACHM-N overpredicted $ lbrack rm NO sb{3 sp{-}}$-N) in the 0.2 m soil layers in all treatments, estimations remained within standard deviations of observed data. NTRM performed well below 0.4 m depths, but often underpredicted $ rm NO sb{3 sp{-}}$-N leaching at shallower depths. From both the laboratory experiments and mathematical simulations it was concluded that when fertilizer is applied in granular form, no till practice is undesirable because deeper $ rm NO sb{3 sp{-}}$-N leaching (below 0.4 m) occurs. Reduced tillage may be the preferred choice in such a situation. When fertilizer is applied in solution, reduced and conventional tillage practices are undesirable because deeper $ rm NO sb{3 sp{-}}$-N leaching occurred. No till practice may be a better choice in such a case.</description><creator>Serem, Vincent Kipyego Arap</creator><contributor>Madramootoo, C. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Corn -- Residues.</subject><subject>Tillage.</subject><subject>Soils -- Leaching.</subject><subject>Soils -- Nitrate content.</subject><subject>Soil percolation.</subject><title>Effects of tillage and corn residues on nitrate-nitrogen and water movement through soil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n984k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87ps39k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666646s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is concerned with an experimental and modeling study of a novel drum dryer for black liquor utilizing multiple impinging jets of superheated steam. Drying of black liquor to solids contents in excess of 92% is a pre-requisite for some of the new black liquor recovery cycles being examined. An experimental drum dryer was designed and built to evaluate the performance characteristics and effects of various operating parameters thereon. Appropriate ranges of parameters such as steam jet temperature and velocity were examined experimentally to quantify the optimal operating conditions for the formation of black liquor film on the drum surface as well as the drying kinetics. To permit scale up of the laboratory scale data to industrial size a two-region mathematical model was developed to simulate the impinging jet flow and the drying of the black liquor film. Both polar and three dimensional cylindrical coordinate systems were employed for solving the governing transport equations. A modified low Reynolds number version of the $k sim varepsilon$ turbulence model was selected after a careful evaluation of the predictions of various $k sim varepsilon$ models for impingement flow and heat transfer. The computed heat transfer distribution on the film surface was applied as the boundary condition for the quasi unsteady one-dimensional diffusion model for the liquor film. Agreement between experimental data and results of the model was found to be satisfactory.</description><creator>Shiravi, Amir Hossein</creator><contributor>Mujumdar, A. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Kubes, G. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Drum drying of black liquor slurry using superheated steam impinging jets</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rq61v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666646s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10ws24x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Photothermal deflection or 'mirage effect' spectroscopy was applied to the quantitative profiling of the optical absorbers in thin polymer films with depth dependent absorption coefficients. In addition, the mirage effect system instrumentation was designed and constructed. Improvements to the precision and accuracy of the instrumentation were implemented, which allowed for quantitative measurements of optical depth dependent layers to be profiled in samples consisting of thin polymer multilayered films. A theoretical model based on one-dimensional heat conduction was developed and used to analyze the experimental results. Further improvements were made to the model by applying diffraction theory to recover heat flux profiles. This added precision for the analysis was required for use in the inverse problem theory. The results from using this theoretical model were interpreted. The mirage effect technique was applied to the dynamic diffusion of solutions containing ionic species through a perfluorosulphonated ionomer membrane. The recovery of the heat flux profiles (solved using inverse problem theory) enabled the recovery of optical absorption profiles, and therefore, concentration profiles. A diffusion model (also developed in this work), enabled the diffusion coefficients of these species to be determined from the concentration profiles. By these means, the diffusion processes of species into the membrane were examined.</description><creator>Schweitzer, Melodie A. (Melodie Ann)</creator><contributor>Power, J. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Optical depth profiling of thin polymer films and diffusion in membranes by photothermal deflection or "mirage effect" spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/000002037.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws24x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860882j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Program analysis is a process of estimating properties of a program statically. Program analyses have many applications, including compiler optimizations, software maintenance and testing, and program verification. In this dissertation we present a new framework for efficient program analysis. At the heart of our approach is a new program representation called the DJ Graph. Using DJ graphs we present several new algorithms for solving problems encountered in program analysis. The problems that we have solved range from a simple loop identification problem to sophisticated exhaustive and incremental data flow analysis, including the construction of Sparse Evaluation Graphs. The algorithms presented here are simple, more general, and/or more efficient than existing methods for solving similar problems. To study the effectiveness of our algorithms on real programs we implemented many of them, and experimented on a number of FORTRAN procedures taken from standard benchmark suites. Our results indicate that the algorithms presented here perform well in practice.</description><creator>Sreedhar, Vugranam C.</creator><contributor>Gao, Guang R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Efficient program analysis using DJ graphs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw43x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860882j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hx35t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Elevated glucoconicoid levels have becn shown to inhibit synaptogenesis, enhance susceptibility to excitotoxic insults and impede normal central nervous system (CNS) development. Though virtually every cell in the hippocampus expresses relatively high levels of both MR and GR, the various cell fields differ considerably in their sensitivity to glucoconicoids. This thesis examined the cellular expression of MR and GR using in situ hybridization in animal and human models known to encompass changes in hippocampal neuron plasticity and/or survival. Entorhinal cortex lesioning (ECL), a well characterized model of reactive synaptogenesis in the rat, was found to cause a transient yet robust decrease in GR mRNA levels in the dentate gyrus 24 hours following lesioning while CAl levels increased significantly as compared to sham-treated controls. In contrast, MR mRNA expression was unaltered in all cell fields. This study suggested that the transient decline in GR mRNA observed during a period of active synaptogenesis might dampen the inhibitory effects of glucocorticoids on this process. Since stimulation of the entorhinal cortex is known to result in intrahippocampal release of glutamate, we tested the hypothesis that increased glutamate release might underlie these changes in GR. For this purpose, animals injected with kainic acid (KA) were examined at several intervals following injection. KA injection, which results in both direct stimulation of glutamate receptors as well as massive release of glutamate, was also found to selectively decrease GR mRNA levels in the dentate gyrus but not in CAl over the first 12-24 hour post-injection. At longer time intervals, GR mRNA levels eventually decreased in the CAl as compared to sham-injected controls, as expected from the cell loss occurring in this region. Interestingly, MR mRNA levels displayed a uniform decrease in all hippocampal cell fields. These findings suggested that glutamate was likely to be the signal regulating GR expression in the hippocampus. Moreover, the selective reduction in GR expression in the dentate gyrus may decrease susceptibility of these cells to glucoconicoid endangerment. We also investigated the role of corticosteroid receptors as mediators of neuronal plasticity during normal hippocampal development in the rat, a period characterized by high glutamate levels. Overall GR mRNA expression was low during the first 2 weeks of development coinciding with a period of process outgrowth and synapse formation. GR mRNA levels were even lower in actively dividing dentate granule neurons during this same period. Highest levels of GR rnRNA expression, occurring at different times for both CA cell fields and dentate granule cells, coincided precisely with their previously described periods of final stage maturation. Since increased hippocampal glutamate release is a common feature in these models, our findings suggest that cell-specific dynamic changes in corticosteroid receptor expression in response to glutamate may underlie the differential effects of glucoconicoids on synaptic reorganization and neuronal survival in the dentale gyrus. It has been well established that in aged animais, decreased hippocampal corticosteroid receptors are associated with glucocorticoid hypersecretion, hippocampal neuropathology and cognitive impairments. Surprisingly, we found no change in individual cellular expression MR and GR mRNA in aged, cognitively-impaired and cognitively-unimpaired rats as compared to young adults. Similarly, no difference in the expression of either conicosteroid receptor was observed in Alzheimer's patients and age-matched control subjects. Since elevated glucocorticoids are hallmarks of both these models, we have postulated that relatively elevated levels of corticosteroid receptors within hippocampal neurons in these models may enhance their susceptibility to glucocorticoids' deleterious effects on plasticity and neuronal survival.</description><description>Cette these examine l'expression cellulaire des minerclocorticoides (MR) and des glucocorticoides (GR) par hybridation in situ dans plusieurs modeles, animal et humain, demontrant des changements importants de plasticite neuronale et/ou de survie neuronale dans l'hippocampe. La lesion du cortex entorhinal chez le rat, un modele bien connu de synaptogenese reactive, produit une baisse importante et transitoire des niveaux d'ARN messager (ARNm) des GR dans le gyrus dente pendant les premieres 24 heures apres lesion, alors que dans le champ CA1 de l'hippocampe, ces niveaux sont significativement eleves pas rapport aux animaux controles. A l'oppose, l'expression des ARNm des MR demeure inchangee dans toutes les regions del'hippocampe. Cette etude demontre que la baisse transitoire d'ARNm des GR observee dans une periode de synaptogenese accrue, pourrait temperer les effets inhibiteurs des glucocorticoides dans ce processus. Puisqu'il est bien etabli que la stimulation du cortex entorhinal cause une liberation importante de glutamate dans l'hippocampe, nous avons postule que cette augmentation pouvait causer les variations d'expression observees ci-dessus. Nous avons examine des animaux injectes a l'acide kainique (AK) a differentes intervalles apres le traitement. Au dela, les niveaux d'ARNm des GR diminuent dans le CA1 par rapport aux controles, compte tenue de la perte cellulaire dans cette region. De facon interessante, des diminutions des niveaux d'ARNm des MR ont ete observe dans toutes les regions de l'hippocampe. Puisque nos etudes demontrent que des changements dynamiques de l'expression des ARNm des corticosteroides peuvent influencer la capacite du neurone a former de nouvelles synapses ou a survivre, nous avons examine le role des recepteurs corticosteroides en tant que mediateurs de la plasticite neuronal pendant le developpement de l'hippocampe chez le rat. Les niveaux d'ARNm pour les GR sont encore plus faibles dans les neurones du gyrus dente que subissent une division cellulaire rapide pendant cette periode. Les niveaux les plus eleves de l'expression des ARNm des GR dans les neurones du gyrus dente et ceux du CA1 sont atteints a des jours differents, qui coincident aussi a leur maturation finale. Sachant que les niveaux de glutamate sont eleves dans tous ces modeles, nos resultats suggerent qu'en reponse au glutamate, des changements dynamiques d'expression des recepteurs aux corticosteroides specifique a un type cellulaire peuvent expliquer les differents effets des glucocorticoides sur la reorganisation synaptique et la survie des neurones dans le gyrus dente. Il est bien etabli que chez le animaux ages, une baisse des recepteurs aux corticosteroides dans l'hippocampe est associee a l'hypersecretion des glucocorticoides, a certaines neuropathologies de l'hippocampe et aux deficits cognitifs, De facon inattendue, nous n'avons observe aucun changement dans l'expression cellulaire des MR ou des GR chez les animaux ages atteints ou non de deficits cognitifs par rapport a de jeunes adultes. De plus, aucun changement des niveaux d'expression des recepteurs aux corticosteroides n'a ete observe dans le tissus de patients atteints de la maladie d'Alzheimer par rapport aux sujets controles. Puisque le taux eleves en glucocorticoide est caracteristique de ces deux modeles, des niveaux relativement eleves en recepteurs aux corticosteroides des neurones pourraient augmenter leur susceptibilite aux effets nefastes des glucocorticoides sur la plasticite et la survie neuronale. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>O'Donnell, Dajan J. (Dajan James)</creator><contributor>Meaney, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Regulation of cellular corticosteroid receptor expression in the rat hippocampus as a potential mediator of neuron differentiation andor survival</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h373b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hx35t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40375</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>