<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:45:44Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40600" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881m18s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electric arcs operating in the thermo-field mode are used in many industrial processes. They are used in electricity transport and distribution, in metal production industry, and in plasma processing applications like in plasma spraying and as the plasma source in physical vapour deposition (PVD) processes. The electric arc-based systems have the common problem of material degradation at the attachment point of the electric arc on the electrode, mainly the cathode surface. The cathode erosion is particularly severe in higher power devices such as plasma torches and circuit breakers. The cathode erodes while producing the ions needed for the electric discharge to occur. Cathode erosion is one big limitation to the use of electric arcs in industry. Carbon nanotubes (CNTs) are 1-D structures with a diameter in the nanoscale range giving them very good field emission properties. These properties make them possible candidates to form metal-CNT composites that can be used as electrodes. The CNTs presence at the electrode surface may help in providing an enhanced electron emission and reduced erosion. The long term objective of this project is to form a new class of electrode materials, namely copper-CNT nanocomposites. One major problem of using these CNTs in composites is their agglomeration and inability to disperse easily. In this project, a pulsed arc discharge system is used to study the capability to ablate, disperse, transport, and deposit the CNTs onto a substrate. The project involves studying the ability to form a nanocomposite made of copper and CNTs from a target and deposition of the copper-CNT mixture on a substrate.</description><creator>El Mallah, Nadine Hassan.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Dispersion of the carbon nonotubes in a vacuum arc system and synthesis of copper-carbon nanotubes composites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nadine Hassan El Mallah, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c074w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m18s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v8181</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hydrogen can be the key solution of all our energy needs in the future and to face climate change while reducing greenhouse gases. Syngas, H 2 and CO, is industrially produced by steam reforming of methane. A potential alternative is the catalytic partial oxidation of methane. The process is fast, exothermic and auto-thermal. A dual sequential bed catalyst is used, which makes use of a combustion catalyst followed by a reforming catalyst in order to carry out catalytic partial oxidation in two steps. Numerical simulations using finite elements methods coupled with global kinetics are performed to have a better understanding of the transient process and the solid and gas temperature profiles in a catalyst. The results include temporal and spatial reactant conversion, product selectivity, and temperature profiles in the catalyst. Where possible simulation results are compared to experimental data. The model shows high yields of hydrogen from methane and air which fits the experimental results in most of the cases. It also fits qualitatively the transient results. The influence of the kinetics was investigated and it is the principle limitation of the model which leads to a poor quantitative description.</description><creator>Flynn, Julie.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Simulation of millisecond catalytic partial oxidation of methane in a monolithic reactor for the production of hydrogen using finite element methods</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Julie Flynn, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fk76x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v8181</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d004t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the changing environment of the middle and lower Yellow River basin from the Zhou to the reign of Han Emperor Wu (ca. 1045-87 B.C.), a period characterised by an increase of government control over the land along with an intensification and expansion of agriculture. The second chapter employs palaeoecological sources to look at the early environment of the region, arguing that the eastern plains were mixed forest-steppe, and that the regions to the west were mostly steppe. The third chapter uses archaeological sources to explore the rise of civilisation, the fauna of the region in the Shang period and the spread of iron tools. The fourth chapter is divided into two sections, the first of which looks at what can be learned from the texts of the period concerning agriculture, land clearance, deforestation, hunting, fishing and economic geography. The second half concerns the intensification of state power in regulating and transforming natural environments through legal measures and water control projects, as well as the development of a market economy.</description><creator>Lander, Brian.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Yellow River (China) -- History.</subject><subject>Plant ecology -- China -- Yellow River Region -- History.</subject><subject>Yellow River Region (China) -- Environmental conditions -- History.</subject><title>Writing the environmental history of the Yellow River region from the Zhou to the Han : sources and methodological problems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Brian Lander, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290961q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d004t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x4252</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this thesis is to address the dating, attribution, patronage, formal motifs, structural solutions, stylistic associations and historical context of the Chapel of the Assumption of the Virgin in the Slovakian town of Spissky Stvrtok. In the course of the text, it is revealed that the structure is a contained and coherent system of architectural forms that represents an international transmission of ideas, a continuous development of the architectural vocabulary of the Gothic, and the relevance of "the periphery" to a comprehensive understanding and appreciation of the Late Middle Ages. To that end, the chapel is shown to stand as material evidence of a developed Late Gothic sensibility in the northern margins of the Kingdom of Hungary in the second half of the 15th century, of the wealth and power of the lords in that region, and of the far-reaching influence of the Viennese lodge of masons.</description><creator>Janko, Joan Paula.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Architecture, Gothic -- Slovakia -- Spišský Štvrtok.</subject><subject>Kaplnka Nanebovzatia Panny Marie (Spišský Štvrtok, Slovakia)</subject><title>The Chapel of the Assumption of the Virgin in Spišský Štvrtok : Late Gothic architecture on the periphery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Joan Paula Janko, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17ct13d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x4252</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000000221</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous studies of how working memory (WM) capacity affects lexical ambiguity resolution have been inconclusive about the choice between inhibition and activation comprehension strategies. In contrast, an adaptive inhibition hypothesis suggests that this choice depends on the availability of WM resources. We used a cross-modal semantic priming paradigm. Participants listened to sentences biasing the subordinate meanings of homonyms, presented at a fast or slow speech rate. We measured lexical decision response latencies to target words that were related to either the subordinate or dominant meaning of homonyms. A WM test was used to evaluate participants' WM capacity. At a fast rate, both high and low WM participants activated dominant (or irrelevant) meanings of the subordinate-biased homonyms. At a regular rate, participants with low WM capacity activated dominant meanings; however, participant with high WM inhibited them. Thus, people with high WM activate and inhibit alternative meanings more flexibly than people with low WM.</description><creator>Kadulina, Yara.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Short-term memory.</subject><subject>Speech.</subject><title>The effects of working memory and speech rate on lexical ambiguity resolution /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Yara Kadulina, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nh39w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000000221</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cq74r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For several critics, Milan Kundera's novels illustrate the disenchantment of the world and the demystification of all myths. In this thesis, we accept this point of view while insisting on the persistence of sacred elements in the works of Kundera. We formulate the hypothesis of the "inoculation" of a sacred part (i.e. myths, scenes and figures of the Holy Bible, etc.) in the prose of the novel---"le caractere concret, quotidien, corporel de la vie", as Kundera wrote---in order to anchor this often unstable matter and alleviate the brevity of the character's life. Our analysis of three novels (The Book of Laughter and Forgetting, The Farewell Party and The Joke) reveals an oscillation between the sacred and the prose within the works of Milan Kundera. This movement is illustrated, in the text, by the motif of the baroque angel.</description><creator>Livernois, Jonathan.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Kundera, Milan -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Holy, The, in literature.</subject><title>La présence du sacré dans l'oeuvre de Milan Kundera /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jonathan Livernois, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w7530.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cq74r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zn67m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Surface observations, lake evaporation data and upper-air soundings were collected in a special data-collection effort during the months of August and September of 2004 and 2005 on an island in the middle of Great Bear Lake, Northwest Territories. For this period of the year, the late summer, when increasing variability in surface pressure starts occurring, the effect of different synoptic-scale regimes on the lake-atmosphere interface is investigated to understand the regional specificities, with comparisons to nearby stations and a high spatial and temporal resolution reanalysis model (North American Regional Reanalysis). The planetary boundary layer over the lake systematically shows typical surface and mixed layer structures but with varying depths depending on the mean lower tropospheric temperature. Inversions in the surface layer, linked with warm regimes, support deep mixed layers. Within the surface layer, during warm regimes, a superadiabatic lapse rate can support (or not) a higher-stability sublayer on top of it, in which case the mixed layer happens to be much deeper. The first mechanism for lake evaporation includes the occasional passage of synoptic-scale storm systems with both warm and cold frontal features creating strong, short-lived latent heat interactions between the lake and the atmosphere, but relatively low total amounts of evaporation. The main mechanism for extensive evaporation is a cold anticyclone allowing for significant daytime insolation. A lake-breeze circulation can then develop and provide strong-enough mesoscale winds for diurnal upward latent heat exchanges, with wind channelling into Keith Arm of the lake for strong lake-breeze onshore winds.</description><creator>Milewski, Thomas.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Atmospheric Sciences.</subject><subject>Physics, Astronomy and Astrophysics.</subject><title>Analysis of planetary boundary layer : wind and thermodynamic structures over Great Bear Lake during varying synoptic-scale regimes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Thomas Milewski, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731412w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zn67m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w0323331</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Narratives play a significant role in many computer games, and this is especially true in genres such as role-playing and adventure games. Even so, many games have narratives which possess a certain number of flaws that can deteriorate the playing experience. This less than satisfying gameplay experience can obviously affect the commercial success of a given game. Our research originates from the need to identify these narrative flaws. In response to this need, we present a, framework for computer game narratives analysis. Our work focuses on Interactive Fiction games, which are textual, command-line and turn-based games. We first describe a, high level computer narrative language, the Programmable Narrative Flow Graph (PNFG), that provides a high level, user-friendly interface to a low level formalism, the Narrative Flow Graph, (NFG) [38]. The PNFG language is delivered with a set of enhancements and low level optimizations that reduce the size of the generated NFG output. As part of our work on the analysis of narrative structures, we developed a proof of concept heuristic solver that attempts to automatically find solutions to games from a lightweight, high level representation. We also define narrative game metrics and present a, metrics framework that simplifies the measurement and development of such metrics. These metrics contribute to broadening our general knowledge about game narratives.</description><creator>Martineau, Félix.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>PNFG : a framework for computer game narrative analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Félix Martineau, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096727h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w0323331</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gs92m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The importance of the B7/CD28/CTLA-4 pathway in regulating peripheral T cell activation is well documented, but conflicting evidence regarding its participation in thymocyte negative selection still remains. To analyze the role of B7-dependent interactions in the selection of developing thymocytes, we studied T cell development in mice that constitutively express the costimulatory ligand B7.2 on thymocytes. We show that B7.2 expressed on thymocytes interacts with CD28 in vivo but does not appear to alter T cell development in mice capable of generating a polyclonal T cell repertoire. However, analyses of five lines of TCR/B7.2 double transgenic mice (H-Y, OT-I, 2C, OT-II and DO11) indicate that CD28/B7.2-mediated interactions in the thymus influence T cell selection according to the TCR affinity for self-peptide/MBC ligands. This is the first in vivo demonstration that CD28 costimulation participates in the deletion of thymocytes that express TCR of low affinity.</description><creator>Martel, Dominic.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Contribution of the B7CD28CTLA-4 pathway to the selection of thymocytes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Dominic Martel, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25x888w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gs92m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117p185</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Clinical depression has been unilaterally construed as a biochemical imbalance in serotonerigic systems. The over-simplification of disease reflects economic, political, and social forces that pathologize normal behaviors to manufacture illness. This paper considers evolutionary and dynamic systems biology to advance the idea that subclinical depression is an illness within culture that manifests biologically, as opposed to being organically created and sustained. The classic medical model underestimates psychosocial elements of depression. Patient narratives show the limitations of the medical model and suggest a need for a new depression paradigm, which is the biopsychosocial model. This paper is critical of both the biological etiology of depression and the social and cultural elements that create and sustain depressive episodes.</description><creator>Merkel-Keller, Jessica V.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>Expectations and illness : depression as a culture-bound syndrome in North America</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jessica V. Merkel-Keller, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n135t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117p185</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k755j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Polybrominated diphenyl ethers (PBDEs) are a class of brominated flame retardants that are recognized as global environmental contaminants and a potential health risk. They have been shown to elicit neurodevelopmental toxicity through disruption of the cholinergic neurotransmitter system in rodent models, but the effects of environmentally relevant exposures in wildlife species are unknown. The objective of this study was to assess the effects of the commercial pentabrominated diphenyl ether mixture DE-71 on cholinergic parameters in captive mink (Mustela vison) following dietary exposure of adult females and in utero, lactational and dietary exposure of their offspring. Adult females were fed diets containing 0, 0.1, 0.5 or 2.5 μg/g DE-71 from four weeks prior to breeding through weaning of their kits at six weeks of age. A portion of the weaned kits were maintained on their respective diets through 27 weeks of age. Cholinergic neurochemical biomarkers, including muscarinic acetylcholine receptor (mAChR) and nicotinic acetylcholine receptor (mAChR) binding, cholinesterase (ChE) activity and acetylcholine (ACh) concentration, were assayed in the cerebral cortex, and ChE activity measured in the plasma. Results indicated no significant effects of DE-71 on cholinergic parameters in the cerebral cortex, but a 3-fold increase in ChE activity in the plasma of adult females in the 2.5 μg/g DE-71 group. There were also no direct effects of DE-71 on mAChR or mAChR binding or ChE activity in the enzyme and receptor fractions from the whole brain of untreated mink following in vitro exposure to 0-23.6 nM DE-71. This study demonstrated that environmentally relevant exposures to DE-71 did not affect key parameters of the cholinergic neurotransmitter system in the brain of captive mink.</description><creator>Bull, Kimberly.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Pentabromodiphenyl ether -- Toxicology.</subject><subject>Cholinergic mechanisms.</subject><subject>American mink -- Effect of chemicals on.</subject><title>Effects of a commercial pentabrominated diphenyl ether mixture on cholinergic parameters in captive mink</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kimberly Bull, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w37637025.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k755j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j596c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>More intensive production of hogs and cattle in Quebec during the past decade has benefited local economies, but led to over-fertilization of agricultural soils and eutrophication of waterways. Provincial ministries responded to this issue by developing regulations to control manure applications. The objective of this thesis was to determine the environmental risk associated with applying farm manure in the late fall. Spreading manure in fall after harvesting corn was a common practice for many agricultural producers in Quebec, but this period is now viewed as very risky, having more negative environmental consequences than other manure application periods. This two-year study used common diagnostic tools to compare the fertilization efficiency of solid dairy farm manure (DFM) spread in early fall, late fall and spring on a heavy clay soil used for corn production. In the first year, when DFM was the only nutrient source, there was no difference in corn yield that could be attributed to the manure application period. In the second year, each DFM plot was split and six levels of inorganic fertilizer (from 55 to 240 kg N ha-1) were applied ("Strip Split Plot") after planting. Corn tissue analysis (chlorophyll content, leaf N content at silking, cornstalk NO3 concentration) indicated that more residual N was supplied from late fall manure application than other manure application periods. Monitoring of soil NO3-N concentrations indicated that most of the NO3-N migration through the soil profile occurred after the early fall manure application. Late fall manure application appears to be the most efficient at supplying N for corn production, without deleterious environmental impacts, when DFM is applied to a heavy clay soil.</description><creator>Cantin, Jean.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Dairy cattle -- Manure -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region.</subject><subject>Fertilizers -- Application -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region.</subject><title>The environmental risks linked to different manure application periods /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jean Cantin, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cw43z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j596c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wv994</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The regenerating (Reg) genes have been associated with tissue repair and have been directly implicated in pancreatic beta-cell regeneration. Peptide administration of INGAP, a hamster Reg3, can reverse hyperglycaemia in rodents and stimulate new beta-cell growth in human epithelial cultures. New Reg genes in rats and hamsters were identified using homology reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) with degenerate Reg3 primers and selected products were further sequenced using rapid amplification of cDNA ends (RACE). This method resulted in no novel rat Regs, although a putative rat INGAP with 65% identity to the mouse INGAP protein was discovered by a BLAST homology search of the rat genome. The putative rat INGAP protein was shorter than both mouse and hamster INGAP and a mRNA transcript could not be amplified by PCR. It is thus concluded that this rat homologue of INGAP is a pseudogene. Homology RT-PCR did, however, result in the discovery of a new hamster Reg3 gene of 765 nucleotides (nt) that encodes a 174 amino acid (aa) protein. This protein sequence was identified as a novel hamster Reg3gamma with 78% and 75% identity to the rat Reg3gamma and mouse Reg3gamma protein, respectively. The hamster Reg1 gene coding region was fully sequenced from a reported partial sequence using RACE to yield a 756 nt transcript that encodes a deduced 173 aa protein. This protein was identified as hamster Reg2, rather than Reg1 as was initially reported, with an 81% identity to mouse Reg2. Mice and hamsters are the only species known to carry either of the functional INGAP or Reg2 genes. It remains to be determined whether these genes bestow mice and hamsters with special regenerative abilities in the pancreas.</description><creator>Castellarin, Mauro.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>The identification and sequence analysis of new regenerating (Reg) gene members in rats and hamsters /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Mauro Castellarin, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx265.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wv994</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935320p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Common Substring in Random Strings (CSRS) problem is defined as follows: what is the probability that a set of r random strings of length n generated by a random process P contain a common substring of length k? In this thesis, we investigate the CSRS problem and introduce two new methods for computing approximate solutions to the CSRS problem in the cases where the random strings are generated by a Bernoulli or Markov process. We also present generalizations to the methods to compute the probability of finding a common substring among only q of the r random strings, and to allow mismatches in the substring occurrences. We show through simulation experiments that the two new methods introduced in this thesis provide a substantial improvement in accuracy over previous methods when there are r &gt; 2 random strings in the problem instance.</description><creator>Blais, Éric.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Computing probabilities for common substrings in random strings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Éric Blais, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rk602.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935320p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mp93m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A combination of DGPS/GIS mapping, invertebrate surveys and environmental monitoring over one year (July 2004--July 2005) were used to examine the recovery of permanent tidal pools on a salt marsh in the lower Bay of Fundy which underwent an unmanaged restoration after breach of the dyke over 50 years ago. The results are compared to those of a nearby relatively undisturbed reference marsh. Pools were found to represent a substantial portion of the marsh habitat, comprising 13% of the total marsh area in the recovering marsh and 4.8% in the natural marsh. Observations indicate ice may be an important mechanism of pool formation and growth in these marshes. Water temperature in the pools ranged from freezing (-2°C) to a maximum of 36°C with ice covering pools for up to one month in the winter. Salinity of the pools ranged from near freshwater (4) to hypersaline (41). Environmental variability was mainly driven by climatic conditions with increased tidal flooding of pools at low elevations tending to make the conditions more stable. A total of 42 macroinvertebrate taxa were identified in pools of the two marshes, with species richness (S) of individual pools ranging from 13 to 23. An estimated 50 years since dyke failure, the invertebrate fauna of pools in the recovering marsh is indistinguishable from that of the reference marsh. No significant differences in macroinvertebrate communities were detected between sampling dates, pool size or pool depth. Non metric multidimentional scaling and hierarchical cluster analysis supported separating the pool invertebrate communities of this study into those occurring in regularly flooded pools, and those occurring in irregularly flooded pools. Average production of pool macroinvertebrates ranged from 1.79 to 4.03 g dry wt m-2, depending on the amount of vegetative cover in the pools. The pools are characterized by low equitability in species abundance and biomass. The numerically dominant organisms of the pools were mites (Acarina), the gastropod Hydrobia tottentei, Tubificidae oligochaetes, and Chironomus sp. larvae as well as copepods and ostracods.</description><creator>Noel, Paula.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Tide pools -- Fundy, Bay of, Region.</subject><subject>Tide pool ecology -- Fundy, Bay of, Region.</subject><subject>Salt marshes -- Fundy, Bay of.</subject><title>Resilience of pool habitat in a Bay of Fundy salt marsh : a comparative study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Paula Noel, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sq41z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mp93m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s0392</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is an emerging demand for natural and engineered CO2 sinks to combat the effects of global warming. Carbon capture and storage (CCS) processes are expected to play a predominant role within a broad portfolio of technical innovations to mitigate greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. A range of CCS methods will be required to provide GHG control technologies for the broad scope of industrial sectors. Within this class of technologies carbon dioxide accelerated concrete curing has the global potential to permanently and safely sequester up to 550 Mt CO2/yr while producing non-reinforced concrete products with improved physical properties and in less time than traditionally cured products. Previous research has exhibited shallow CO 2 penetration depth and modest CO2 uptake in grout and concrete samples despite using severe process conditions such as high pressures, temperatures and long experimental durations. Chemical and microstructural changes during carbonation were investigated to clarify the previously unexplained limitations in CO2 uptake and provide solutions to enhance CO2 storage. Loss of exposed particle surface area was identified as the most significant factor limiting complete carbonation of cement grout samples. The findings were applied to design a bench scale, flow-through carbonation curing reactor that sequestered CO2 at an average of 8.3 wt % of the cured cement with complete depth of penetration. The sequestration results were achieved with ambient temperature (20°C), 40% relative humidity, atmospheric pressure (1 atm), as-captured flue gas CO2 partial pressure (0.20) and low flow (1 Lpm) in less than 60 minutes.</description><creator>Niven, Robert A. J.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Physiochemical investigation of CO₂ accelerated concrete curing as a greenhouse gas mitigation technology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Robert A. J. Niven, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n361k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s0392</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77sq40p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Children's speech sound errors may reflect deficits in acoustic-phonetic, articulatory-phonetic, or phonological knowledge of those sounds. The purpose of the current study was to explore the factors believed to contribute to accurate articulation of /s/ in children with typically developing speech. Forty-eight children in their pre-kindergarten or kindergarten year participated. Acousticphonetic knowledge was assessed using a computer game targeting identification of correct and incorrect productions of /s/. Articulatory-phonetic skill was evaluated using maximum repetition tasks and by assessing stimulability for /s/. Phonological knowledge was assessed by examining the acoustic cues used by children to distinguish their productions of /s/ and /theta/. Acoustic-phonetic knowledge and phonological knowledge were each found to explain a small but significant amount of the variance in articulation accuracy. Three different perspectives regarding the relative importance of perceptual and articulatory skills in the development of phonological knowledge are discussed. Clinical implications of the results are considered.</description><creator>Ohberg, Alyssa.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology.</subject><title>Articulatory, perceptual, and phonological determinants of accurate production of s</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Alyssa Ohberg, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k08d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sq40p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mj22b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Coronary artery disease (CAD) is a major health concern for both developed and developing countries. With a heritability estimated at around 50%, there is a strong rationale to better define the genetic contribution of CAD. In order to do so, my thesis project consists in the genetic analysis of over 1400 individuals from the Saguenay Lac St-Jean region using 1536 single nucleotide polymorphisms in 103 candidate genes for CAD. Using this data, suggestive linkage for HDL cholesterol was found on chromosome 1 and several significant associations were observed with lipoprotein-related traits as well as adiponectin plasma concentration, including two novel associations.</description><creator>Paré, Guillaume.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Bioinformatics.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Genetic analysis of 100 loci for coronary artery disease and associated phenotypes in a founder population</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Guillaume Paré, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b1517.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mj22b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343s56k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The High Risk Assessment Review Team (HART) in Belleville, Ontario is a community coordinated initiative that reviews domestic violence cases before the criminal court. Record analysis was conducted on 60 case files that had gone through criminal court in that jurisdiction. The purpose was to determine if a sample of cases reviewed by HART (n=30) would yield a higher rate of conviction and increased contact with community agencies when compared to a sample of cases (n=30) prior to this team being implemented. A logistical regression yielded no statistically significant results but did demonstrate a higher rate and likelihood of conviction in the HART sample as well as a greater involvement and likelihood of involvement with community agencies.</description><creator>Prime, Beth-Ann.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Family violence -- Ontario -- Belleville.</subject><subject>Community organization -- Ontario -- Belleville.</subject><subject>Social case work -- Ontario -- Belleville.</subject><subject>Social action -- Ontario -- Belleville.</subject><title>Community coordinated initiatives and domestic violence : a study of the high risk assessment review team in Bellville [sic], Ontario</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Beth-Ann Prime, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bh51g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s56k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wq547</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study used combined methods of observations, interviews and document analysis to understand issues related to aging in Indonesia. The study describes relevant policy and practices for older persons in Indonesia, and discusses major social issues of poverty, the need for social security, and ambivalent views of older people in Indonesian society. While the Social Department Affair (Depsos) has pioneered in providing initiatives for older persons, the benefits of these supports are often limited (e.g., formal sector, urban areas). Complexities of the emphasis on family caregiving, constrained government budgets, and social stigma (e.g., "the last priority") mean that older people do not necessarily receive appropriate support from government and society. The role of religion, culture and gender in shaping aging issues are specifically discussed. It would seem that improving the lives of older people in Indonesia requires a social work approach drawing on outside examples while maintaining local tradition.</description><creator>Napsiyah, Siti.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Aging -- Social aspects -- Indonesia.</subject><subject>Aging -- Indonesia.</subject><title>Understanding aging issues in Indonesia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Siti Napsiyah, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83kz57z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wq547</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010q323</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to examine to perceptions of early adolescent girls with regards to friendships, peer relations and stress. Ten early adolescent girls (aged 12-13 years) were interviewed using a semi-structured qualitative format. Findings report that subjects felt a sense of belonging in friendships, as well as experiencing exclusion from friends. In summary, the participants reported that they do experience stress and that it is friends, boys and parents that act as the main stressors in their life. A number of strengths were reported, including friendship as protective factor, empathy and optimism. The Positive Youth Development Framework is identified and implications for future research and social work practice are discussed.</description><creator>Graziani, Sylvie.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Friendship in adolescence.</subject><subject>Stress in adolescence.</subject><subject>Girls -- Psychology.</subject><title>Early adolescent experiences of friendships, peer relations and stress : drawings on girl's impressions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Sylvie Graziani, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000024k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010q323</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924c030</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thus thesis focuses on the roles of social work (on the part of governments and NGOs) in dealing with Indonesia's Ambon conflict (1999 to date). The research seeks to map the roots of the conflict and the interventions made by both level of government and NGOs and to examine the strengths and weaknesses of their social work efforts in conflict resolution. Based on an analysis of these efforts of these institutions, this thesis offers some suggestions as to an enhanced role for social work in dealing with future reconciliation in Ambon especially and in Indonesia generally.</description><creator>Lessy, Zulkipli.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Social service -- Indonesia -- Ambon.</subject><subject>Ethnic conflict -- Indonesia -- Ambon.</subject><subject>Ambon (Indonesia)</subject><subject>Reconciliation.</subject><title>The Ambon conflict and social work interventions : a critical study of reconciliation efforts between Muslim and Christian communities initiated by governmental and non-governmental organizations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Zulkipli Lessy, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t8841.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c030</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613mx848</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The adoption of a new constitution, the changes in legislation, and the well-known shift in policies and State practices introduced by the Chavez administration, are some of the factors that persuaded me to examine not only the legal protection but the actual exercise of internationally recognized core labour standards in Venezuela, notably freedom of association and the right to collective bargaining, the elimination of forced labour, the abolition of child labour and the elimination of discrimination at work. Given the structure and nature of the ILO, its mechanisms of enforcement are limited. Despite the successful ILO objective of promoting compliance with workers' rights, certain Member States like the Government of Venezuela, continue to violate labour rights. This situation requires the search for alternatives. The idea that inspired this paper was an attempt to look for alternatives in regionalism. The hypothesis is that a sub-regional approach through the Andean Community, comprising Andean countries, offers a more effective means to protect labour rights in Venezuela than an international approach through the ILO. However, the solution points more to a joint international-regional approach to better ensure workers' rights in Venezuela and the Andean region.</description><creator>Gómez-Lugo, Fanny.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Human rights -- Venezuela.</subject><subject>Labor laws and legislation -- Andes Region.</subject><subject>Labor laws and legislation -- Venezuela.</subject><subject>Human rights -- Andes Region.</subject><title>The protection of fundamental rights at work : a study of Venezuela and the Andean Community</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Fanny Gómez-Lugo, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537156v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613mx848</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956g095</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As the advantages of space based systems to support global communications, data transfer, navigation and military activities have been identified and exploited through the decades, the economic and security well being of many nations has become increasingly dependent upon space. In a world of evolving threats, dependence has highlighted the vulnerability of space assets. This thesis considers the current legal framework governing outer space and whether or not the framework supports space weaponization and the use of force in space. Chapter One provides an overview of the journey into space and how the military has taken advantage of space. In Chapter Two, the international legal regime governing outer space is analyzed, and the principle of "peaceful purposes" examined. Chapter Three considers the legal authority to resort to the use of force under international law, how that law applies in the outer space environment and briefly addresses arms control restrictions in outer space. Chapter Four focuses on the future, considering the question of whether or not space weaponization and the use of force in space are inevitable developments in the evolution of uses of space or, if there are viable alternatives that will address valid security concerns while preserving space as a weapons free environment.</description><creator>Gleeson, Patrick K.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Space warfare.</subject><subject>Space law.</subject><title>Legal aspects of the use of force in space</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Patrick K. Gleeson, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816m868.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956g095</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405s962n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis in the first part analyses the major international conventions with respect to liability exposure of airlines and aircraft operators performing international flights. Emphasis will be laid on the transportation of passengers, baggage and cargo and on the legal framework in place to award compensation for damages caused to persons and property on the surface of the earth. The study continues with an evaluation of natural hazards inherent to air transport and explains the typical standard aviation insurance policies and the scope of cover for the hull of the aircraft, for passengers and for third parties on the ground. Furthermore, an overview will be given of the 'extended exclusion clauses for Weapons of Mass Destruction (WMD)' commonly inserted in war risk insurance policies as a result of terrorist attacks. Finally, this study will focus on the new insurance requirements implemented by the EU Regulation 785/2004 and its implication for air carriers.</description><creator>Halter, Marc Rémy.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Liability for aircraft accidents.</subject><subject>Aviation insurance.</subject><title>Aviation insurance in international air transport</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Marc Rémy Halter, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n137c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405s962n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40625</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>