<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:45:16Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40500" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732d922h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, I investigate the potential of E-Government in enhancing ethnic economies. I focus on the Chinese ethnic economy because it is a crucial component of the Canadian economy. I conducted a survey among 50 Chinese businesses in Montreal, interviewed officers in the local government and a Chinese business association to explore their opinions of E-Government for Chinese ethnic economic development. Based on the results, I developed a suite of web-based information, Geographic Information Systems and E-Commerce tools that were integrated into an E-Government application. Lastly, the prototype was compared with other E-Government sites to determine its unique features. I found that E-Government was a possible tool for advancing economic development in the Montreal Chinese community by providing categorized information, translated and customized government services and geographic information for their business decisions. It is hoped that this application can be used to promote economic development in other communities and ethnic economies.</description><creator>Han, Yang, 1981-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Chinese -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject>Internet in public administration -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Using E-government to strengthen Montreal's Chinese ethnic economy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Yang Han, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn009z038.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732d922h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wg288</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an analysis of the chiastic structure in the tenth episode of James Joyce's Ulysses, Wandering Rocks, and how it relates to the chiastic elements in the novel as a whole. My reading of Wandering Rocks and Ulysses is designed to explain the contradiction between the episode's appearance of structural stability and the novel's consistent denial of unifying structures. Chiastic structure will be shown to reflect a formal process of simultaneous growth and decay that develops in the novel, and the reading of Wandering Rocks will establish how the pattern traces points of convergence between the novel's aesthetics and the organic processes that occur in the referential level of the text. While I argue that Wandering Rocks announces an inevitable loss of structural stability, the examination of its structure reveals formal principles that remain consistent throughout Ulysses .</description><creator>Howie, Jordan.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Joyce, James, 1882-1941. Ulysses.</subject><subject>Chiasmus.</subject><title>A cemetery of symmetry : chiastic structure in Wandering Rocks and Ulysses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jordan Howie, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h469n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wg288</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kq715</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Translation is the conversion of one language into another: from the language of nucleotides to the language of amino acids; from our genetic code to functional proteins. This process is fundamental to cellular activities such as growth, differentiation, proliferation and even cell death. Translation is the final step in the flow of the genetic information. Therefore, regulation at this level allows for an immediate and rapid response to changes in physiological conditions. Translation is a complex multi-stage process, which is highly regulated, especially at the level of initiation. It requires several players: initiator transfer RNA (tRNA), 40S and 60S ribosomal subunits, as well as several eukaryotic initiation factors (eIFs), culminating in the positioning of the 80S ribosome at the initiation codon of a messenger RNA (mRNA). Recognition of the cap structure of the mRNA by eIF4F (composed of the cap binding protein eIF4E, the RNA helicase eIF4A and the scaffolding protein eIF4G), is a key step in this process and also the rate-limiting step of translation initiation. The human eIF4E-Homologous protein (h4EHP) was originally cloned in our laboratory in 1998. This cytoplasmic protein bares 30% identity and 60% similarity to the human eIF4E and is also a cap-binding protein. However, the function of 4EHP in translation has remained elusive: it does not interact with any known initiation factor and has no effect on overall translation rate. Recently, isoforms of human 4EHP in D. melanogaster and C. elegans were found to play a role in repression or activation of specific mRNAs. In order to assess the role of human 4EHP as a translational modulator, novel interacting partners were investigated using various methods. h4EHP was shown to specifically interact with eIF4E-transporter (4ET), elongation factor 2 (eEF2), eIF4A and certain ribosomal proteins (L4, L13, L27a). In addition, specific assays were performed to examine the post-translational modifications of h4EHP, such as phosphorylation. Lastly, the possible roles of h4EHP in metastasis and in microRNA-mediated repression, were investigated.</description><creator>Madjar, Kfir.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Investigation of the function of human eIF4E-Homologous protein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kfir Madjar, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn9996955.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kq715</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25x8895</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two experiments were conducted to evaluate the effects of arginine, vitamin E, and their combination on cardiopulmonary performance and nitric oxide synthase (NOS) activity in broilers undergoing cold-induced ascites (pulmonary hypertension) after an acute challenge with epinephrine. One day-old male broilers ( n = 25/treatment) were supplemented with arginine (0.3% water supplementation), vitamin E (400 IU/L or kg, water or feed supplementation; experiment 1 and 2 respectively) or both compounds, above NRC (1994) recommendations. From day 28 to 42, a catheterization was performed (n = 8/treatment) to evaluate pulmonary and mean arterial pressures, and heart rate. After recording baseline values, two injections of epinephrine (1 or 0.5 mg/kg body weight, experiment 1 and 2, respectively) were administered in a 20 min interval. The NOS activity was estimated through the conversion of 14C-arginine to 14C-citrulline in isolated pulmonary arteries ( n = 8/treatment). Overall, the time taken for pulmonary arterial pressure to return to values no different from initial baseline levels was longer for the birds consuming high levels of vitamin E (alone or in combination with arginine) compared to birds supplemented only with arginine. Although NOS activity was highly variable, birds fed with high arginine levels tended to have the lowest NOS activity. These results showed that vitamin E supplementation at the levels used in these experiments has detrimental effects on cardiopulmonary performance, and does not improve NOS activity in isolated pulmonary arteries.</description><creator>Lorenzoni, Alberto Gino.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Broilers (Chickens) -- Cardiovascular system.</subject><subject>Broilers (Chickens) -- Diseases -- Chemotherapy.</subject><subject>Vitamin E in animal nutrition.</subject><subject>Arginine.</subject><subject>Ascites -- Chemotherapy.</subject><title>Effects of alpha-tocopherol and L-arginine on cardiopulmonary function in broilers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Alberto Gino Lorenzoni, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n1363.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25x8895</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644r887</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we present a theory to calculate the time-dependent current flowing through an arbitrary noninteracting nanoscale phase-coherent device connected to arbitrary noninteracting external leads, in response to sharp step- and square-shaped voltage pulses. Our analysis is based on the Keldysh nonequilibrium Green's functions formalism, and provides an exact analytical solution to the transport equations in the far from equilibrium, nonlinear response regime. The essential feature of our solution is that it does not rely on the commonly used wideband approximation where the coupling between device scattering region and leads is taken to be independent of energy, and as such provides a way to perform transient transport calculations from first principles on realistic systems, taking into account the detailed electronic structure of the device scattering region and the leads. As an illustration of the general theory, we perform a toy model calculation for a quantum dot with Lorentzian linewidth and show how interesting finite-bandwidth effects arise in the time-dependent current dynamics. Finally, we describe possible generalizations of our theory to the cases of superconducting leads (an example of broken symmetry) and one-dimensional leads in the Luttinger liquid regime (an example of an interacting system).</description><creator>Maciejko, Joseph.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Time-dependent quantum transport in mesoscopic structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Joseph Maciejko, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nb527.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644r887</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977v137</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aim. To investigate the cross cultural validity of a French language version of a questionnaire that measures Oral Health related Quality of Life in young children. Method. Data were collected from community-based and hospital dental clinic-based samples of parent-child dyads. Cross cultural validity was assessed through: (i) internal consistency; (ii) test-retest reliability; (iii) convergent validity; (iv) discriminative validity; (v) cross cultural comparison and (vi) responsiveness to change. Results. Indicators of internal consistency and test-retest reliability were very good. Indicators for convergent validity were good. The instrument could discriminate between the population and clinic based samples. The cross cultural comparison suggested differences between English and French speaking groups. The responsiveness evaluation was non-conclusive. Conclusions. These results suggest this French language questionnaire has good reliability and validity, although responsiveness remains to be demonstrated.</description><creator>Li, Shanshan, 1979-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry.</subject><title>Validation of a French language questionnaire to measure oral health related quality of life in young children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Shanshan Li, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g0502.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977v137</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jb75s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two species of desert truffles, Tirmania and Terfezia were collected from the Northern desert region in Saudi Arabia for antimicrobial and antioxidant activity testing. Both species were extracted with four types of extraction solutions, methanol, ethanol, ethyl acetate and water to test for antimicrobial activity and with three extraction solutions, methanol, ethanol and water for antioxidant activity. Using disc diffusion method, the extracts were subjected to twenty three different microorganisms to observe the antimicrobial activity by measuring clear zones. Methanol extract from Tirmania was the most effective, followed by those extracted with ethanol, water and ethyl acetate respectively. In Terfezia, ethanol extract was better than methanol extract in effectiveness. Ethyl acetate extracts were the least effective. The results indicate that truffles possess antimicrobial activity with broad spectrum effects against Gram positive, Gram negative, aerobic and anaerobic bacteria as well as Saccharomyces, while no effect was recorded with fungi. The results on antioxidant activity showed that truffles have very strong antioxidant property with 99.9% with ethanol extracts of Tirmania species and 95.5% with ethanol extract of Terfezia species using beta-carotene bleaching method and antioxidant property with 96.1% with ethanol extracts of Tirmania species and 95.3% with methanol extract of Terfezia species using DPPH free radical method.</description><creator>Ali, Saleh A.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Truffles.</subject><subject>Anti-infective agents.</subject><subject>Antioxidants.</subject><title>Antimicrobial and antioxidant activity of two desert truffles, Tirmania and Terfezia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Saleh A. Ali, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vb57w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jb75s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977v14h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Semiconductor nanocrystals exhibit strongly size-dependent absorption spectra and consequently are of great interest for use in nanoscale devices. As the excited states of these crystals are short-lived, spectroscopic investigation of the nature and size dependence of their energy levels requires femtosecond laser pulses. We have synthesized cadmium selenide nanocrystals and constructed a femtosecond instrument around a commercial laser system from Coherent to study them. The instrument is capable of measuring the autocorrelation and crosscorrelation of laser pulses and can measure the transient absorption dynamics of nanocrystals via pump-probe spectroscopy. A novel means of simultaneously measuring the dynamics associated with two different excitation wavelengths has also been employed. I have written a LabVIEW program for data acquisition from this instrument, capable of reducing measurement noise through averaging and rejection of bad measurements. We have successfully used this software in probing specific transitions in cadmium selenide nanocrystals.</description><creator>Anderson, Kevin E. H.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Semiconductor nanocrystals : synthesis, characterization, and instrumentation for femtosecond spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Kevin E. H. Anderson, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q4210.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977v14h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cb071</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"No (person) is an island" (Donne J, 1975, p. 87). The importance of social support in the lives of human beings is evident and for immigrant adolescents the role of social networks is important to facilitate their adjustment within the majority culture and to navigate their identity within spaces of belonging. This study aims to describe how Filipino immigrant adolescents in Cote-des-Neiges, a district in Montreal, organize social support and how this relates to their mental health. This research is a mixed design with a sequential strategy. Firstly, data about social support from an epidemiological survey of Filipino youth are analyzed. Secondly, ethnographic research elaborates the findings from the quantitative part. The results suggest that social networks play a dual role of both support and conflict for the adolescents and that there is a complex interplay between migratory trajectory and the strategies for organizing social support and negotiating spaces of belonging.</description><creator>Ang Chiu Li, Winny.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Sociology, Ethnic and Racial Studies.</subject><subject>Psychology, Social.</subject><title>Negotiating spaces of belonging : social support in Filipino immigrant youth</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Winny Ang Chiu Li, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rh284.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cb071</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xf530</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A number of reports examining the role of CEACAM1 (Carcinoembryonic Antigen-related Cell Adhesion Molecule 1) in T lymphocytes have defined for it both stimulatory or inhibitory co-receptor functions. Using our unique Ceacaml1-/- mouse model, we previously observed that CEACAM1 is not involved in the development nor in the migration of T cells, but that it exerts a co-inhibitory effect on their activation and proliferation. Here, we report that its loss does not affect the ratios of naive and memory helper or cytotoxic T cells. Moreover, cytotoxic T cells from OT-1:Ceacam1-/- mice, resulting from breeding OT-1 TCR transgenic mice with Ceacam1-/- mice, are hyperproliferative and secrete more interleukin-2 and interferon-7 than their OT-1 counterparts. Finally, studies involving CD2-CCl-L transgenic mice whose T cells overexpress CEACAM1 did not consistently yield the hypoproliferative behaviour expected. Together, these findings suggest that CEACAM1 is an inhibitory co-receptor in T cells.</description><creator>Atallah, Renée.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>CEACAM1, an inhibitory co-receptor in T lymphocytes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Renée Atallah, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mj212.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xf530</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tp60k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Military jet over-flight activities pose a potential threat to staging waterfowl and pilots. The migration period is important for nutrient acquisition and courtship as these waterfowl enter the breeding season. Using a focal animal (continuous) technique for five-minute intervals, diurnal Time/Activity (TA) budgets for Canada Geese (Branta canadensis canadensis) (n=751), American Black Duck (Anas rubripes) (n=474) and Common Goldeneye (Bucephala clangula) (n=1274) were compiled during 216 hours of behavioural observation. The study was conducted from 26 April to 27 May, 2002 at the outlet of Lac Fourmont, Labrador (52° 03' 30"N, 60° 31' 01" W), in an ashkui or area of open water in an otherwise frozen landscape, which is known historically as a place to hunt waterfowl. These staging grounds are within the 130 000 km2 Low-level Training Area (LLTA) of the Quebec-Labrador Peninsula. Generalized Linear Modeling (GLM) of ranked variables was used to analyze behaviour by: observer, sex, pair status, time of day, date, and each weather parameter. Male Common Goldeneye spent more time in courtship behaviours (2.7%) than females (1.1%) and they spent most of the daylight hours feeding (males 53.3% and females 54.5%), with little time resting (4.8% and 5.2%, respectively). In contrast, Black Ducks and Canada Geese spent relatively little time feeding (12.4% and 5% respectively) and most of their time sleeping (35% and 38% respectively) and locomotion (37.8% and 11% respectively). Ashkui are important to Common Goldeneyes for foraging, and to Canada Geese and Black Ducks for resting prior to the breeding season. Ninety-one low-level jet over-flights occurred and sound levels (n=336 h) at the study site were measured. Effects of low-level jet over-flights were analyzed using GLM of ranked variables in order to analyze a number of variables simultaneously. All behavioural observations that occurred in the quarter hour periods up to 165 minutes after an over-flight were analyzed. Alert and courtship behaviours of Canada Geese increased after over-flights. Other behaviours were negatively affected to a lesser degree. Locomotor activities by Black Ducks increased significantly immediately following over-flights with a stronger movement response with increased noise. Increases in agonistic and comfort behaviours of Common Goldeneye were detected following over-flights with few other significant affects on their behaviour.</description><creator>Newbury, Tina L.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Low altitude aeronautics -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Labrador.</subject><subject>Goldeneye -- Effect of noise on -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Labrador.</subject><subject>Black duck -- Effect of noise on -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Labrador.</subject><subject>Canada goose -- Effect of noise on -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Labrador.</subject><title>Effect of low-level flying military aircraft on the behaviour of spring staging waterfowl at Lac Fourmont ashkui, Labrador, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Tina L. Newbury, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tm220.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tp60k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f4625734</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this study was to investigate whether or not the treatment of nuclear donor cells with inhibitors of protein synthesis and cyclin-dependent kinases (CDKs) affect the development of swine embryos produced by somatic cell nuclear transfer. Host oocytes were derived from pre-pubertal females and matured in vitro for 42-46 h under standard conditions. Nuclear donor cells were fetal fibroblasts maintained in culture for 2 to 6 passages. Oocytes were reconstructed with cells treated for 22-24 hours with cycloheximide (CHX; 10mug/ml), roscovitine (ROS; 25 muM), the combination of CHX + ROS (CR), or untreated cells. Two hours after reconstruction, the oocytes were activated using ionomycin (15muM/5 min) and strontium chloride (10mM/4h), maintained for 6 h in the presence of cytochalasin B (7.5mug/ml) and CHX (10mug/ml), and then cultured in porcine zygote medium (PZM3) for 6 days. The cleavage rate, 63.7% (n=318), 55.2% (n=99), 56.7% (n=107) and 60.6% (n=347), at 48 h post-fusion were not significantly different between embryos derived from ROS, CHX, CR and control cells, respectively. Developmental rate to blastocyst stage was higher for embryos reconstructed with ROS (12.2%) and untreated cells (12.1%) when compared to CHX (5.7%) and CR (4.9%). Blastocysts produced with ROS treated cells had similar number of nuclei compared to embryos reconstructed with untreated donor cells (30.9+/-10.4 vs. 32.2+/-8.0). Phosphorylated H2A.X (gammaH2A.X) was highly expressed in donor cells treated with CR compared to non treated cells, but it was similarly expressed in most of 1-cell stage embryos reconstructed with control or treated cells. Flow cytometry analysis showed that the majority of the fibroblasts were at G 0/G1 phase of the cell cycle at the time of nuclear transfer. It was concluded that the treatment of nuclear donor cells with inhibitors of protein synthesis and CDKs did not improve the in vitro development of somatic cell nuclear transfer embryos in pigs.</description><creator>Lalonde, Annie.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Cell nuclei -- Transplantation.</subject><subject>Swine -- Cloning.</subject><subject>Swine -- Embryos.</subject><title>Development of porcine embryos produced by nuclear transfer from somatic cells treated with protein synthesis and cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Annie Lalonde, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cw447.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f4625734</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p741z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis evaluates how developmental conditions influence settlement, survival, and yearling primiparity in juvenile red squirrels. This was accomplished by comparing the fates of offspring from food supplemented versus non-supplemented mothers, and by using logistic regression to evaluate the effects of body mass, resource availability, and reproductive parameters on juvenile success. Maternal nutrition, previous and present year's cone production, and body mass contributed significantly to settlement and survival during all juvenile life history stages (emergence, settlement, and overwinter survival). Heavier than average juveniles were also more likely to reproduce as yearlings. Nevertheless, natal body mass was not a predictor of recruitment, indicating persistent influence of early developmental conditions on life history fates above and beyond mass effects. A greater impact of resource availability than body size on fitness among red squirrels may reflect this species' reliance on hoarded food rather than body fat for energy reserves.</description><creator>Kerr, Tricia D.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Tamiasciurus hudsonicus -- Food -- Yukon.</subject><subject>Tamiasciurus hudsonicus -- Yukon -- Reproduction.</subject><title>Direct and indirect energetic influences on juvenile red squirrel survival, recruitment, and reproduction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Tricia D. Kerr, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dv81r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p741z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722h914k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The colour of guppies (Poecilia reticulata) evolves as a compromise between sexual selection (favouring conspicuousness) and natural selection (favouring crypsis). However, guppies live in a variety of habitats and with a variety of predators and consequently in a variety of selective environments. I investigated how habitat and predator's visual systems affect the evolution of colour. I used regressions to assess the importance of habitat features on the evolution of colour for 29 guppy populations. I then quantified the colour of guppies living in the presence and absence of two predators. The prawn predator is insensitive to orange light while the fish predator is insensitive to ultraviolet light. Habitat explained some variation in colour, but not in a consistent manner. Guppies living with the prawn were more orange and guppies living with the fish had more ultraviolet reflectance, providing evidence for the use of these aspects of colour as private signals.</description><creator>Millar, Nathan Peter.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Guppies -- Adaptation -- Trinidad and Tobago.</subject><subject>Guppies -- Color -- Trinidad and Tobago.</subject><subject>Natural selection -- Trinidad and Tobago.</subject><title>The influence of habitat and the visual systems of predators on the evolution of male colour in guppies, Poecilia reticulata /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Nathan Peter Millar, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mc34x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722h914k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719m683</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Most recent Canadian studies on the mental health and behavioural problems of Canadian immigrant children have focused on the impact of various socioeconomic and demographic factors. To better understand the emotional and behavioural problems of immigrant children, it is important to look beyond the children's family demographics and to assess the broader social context. The current study explored the effects of immigrant children's social relationships within families and peer groups, as well as the effects of their demographic backgrounds, on the children's behavioural problems. This paper is based on the data for 182 Chinese immigrant children aged 11 to 13 years old collected from the New Canadian Children and Youth Study (NCCYS) 1st Wave in Montreal. Measures of the social relationships and behavioural problems include the following three tools: children's perceptions of their emotional and behavioural problems scales (five subscales); children's perception of parental relationships (parental nurturance, parental rejection, and relationships with parents); peer relationships (social competence, involvement with peers in trouble, and participating in bullying). The regression results indicated that immigrant children's relationships with both parents and peers were the most significant predictor of specific behaviour problems. Demographic factors, especially family structure, gender, and ethnicity, were also found to influence behavioural problems of Chinese immigrant children. In order to improve the integration and adaptation process for immigrant children and their families with adjustment difficulties in their social relationships and behavioural problems, relevant intervention and prevention programs (including early identification of children at risk, developing pro-social skills, improving parent-child interaction skills) need to be developed in school settings in collaboration with the community, by government, and by ethno-specific community groups.</description><creator>Choi, Ye Ri, 1973-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Children of immigrants -- Canada.</subject><subject>Problem children -- Canada.</subject><subject>Chinese-Canadian families.</subject><title>Chinese immigrant children : predictors of emotional and behavioural problems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Ye Ri Choi, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623c96f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719m683</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mm526</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Problem. Oppressive cultural and social representations are inscribed on the body and intersect with women's subjective identity. Objective. The present study explores the use of the body as a vehicle for resistance against such inscriptions. Method. The practice of martial arts is investigated as one of the means of empowerment for women. Quantitative methods were used to compare the levels of empowerment in a group of women who practice martial arts versus a comparison group of women who do not practice martial arts. Results. Quantitative analysis revealed that while no differences were found in overall empowerment scores between the two groups, differences were found on the subscales of empowerment. Women who practice martial arts demonstrated lower levels of Righteous Anger on the empowerment scale than women who do not practice martial arts. Closely reaching statistical significance, women who practice martial arts demonstrated higher levels of Control on the empowerment scale.</description><creator>Azoulay, Liat.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Self-defense for women -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Human body.</subject><subject>Feminist theory.</subject><title>The body as a vehicle for empowerment : women and martial arts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Liat Azoulay, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dg03s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mm526</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj1392257</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This qualitative, quasi-phenomenological study presents strategies and methods hospital-based mental health social workers utilize to promote social justice and advocate for their clients. Three frontline mental health social workers and one mental health department head were interviewed. The findings of this research demonstrated that the participating social workers utilized a variety of creative and flexible approaches to promote social justice and successfully advocate for their clients. These approaches included: the use of appropriate language, using the system against itself, developing written standards and regulations for their tasks, and forming a network of allies.</description><creator>Enros, Brynn Marie.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Patient advocacy.</subject><subject>Social workers.</subject><title>Mental health social workers : strategies for social justice advocacy in a hospital setting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Brynn Marie Enros, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074v35j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1392257</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505084x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work of balancing the role of child welfare worker and mother is often a challenging one, particularly during times of high stress. In this study six women with young children employed in children welfare settings were interviewed about their experience of burnout. The interviews explored their understanding and personal experience of combining both motherhood with their employment as child welfare workers. The centrality of supportive supervision in modifying the experience of burnout is addressed. The unpredictability, responsibility and risk women face in front line child welfare produces extreme stress, which often becomes extremely difficult to manage, in particular when coupled with the task of raising young children.</description><creator>Ensby, Jill.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Burn out (Psychology)</subject><subject>Child welfare workers.</subject><title>The experience of burnout : mothers as child welfare workers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jill Ensby, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v5716.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505084x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wc91z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The practice of international trade is specific and evolves rapidly in accordance with its needs. Today arbitration constitutes the usual way to settle disputes of international commerce. However, certain rules of arbitration do not seem to be adapted with this practice. The written form of the arbitration agreement as required by, inter alia, the New York Convention and the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration is one of them. First this thesis presents the rules of these two instruments. Then international trade's practice is examined, and especially the incorporation of arbitration clauses by reference and the use of electronic means to conclude such clauses. There is a noteworthy discrepancy between the rules and reality of trade. Having exposed the various difficulties, this thesis examines national laws and case law in order to determine whether they offer satisfactory solutions. Different interesting answers have been brought in Civil Law as well as Common Law countries. Yet they remain local and do not allow for harmonization worldwide. They even often vary one from another and are sometimes contradictory. A more satisfactory solution could be found on the international level, and more specifically by the UNCITRAL. Indeed the Commission entrusted the Working Group II the mission of proposing a solution. A proposal of compromise has been drafted, namely, a revised article of the Model Law and an interpretative instrument of the New York Convention. This soft proposal is interesting but will perhaps not be able to settle all the problems related to the issue of the arbitration clause's form.</description><creator>Decoux, Amandine.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Arbitration and award, International.</subject><subject>Arbitration and award.</subject><title>The arbitration agreement and the reality of international trade : how much form do we need?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Amandine Decoux, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c768p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wc91z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b152h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The principle 'best interests of the child' has been expanded by the legal community in recent years to apply to any matter involving children in family law proceedings. The weight ascribed to this principle, however, has been diluted. In custody, access and child protection cases, evidence of which custodial arrangements are in a child's interests are often presented by adult parties in prolonged and costly proceedings. The judge makes an order which is intended to meet the child's "best interests", in the child's absence. This paper first examines the historical and theoretical justifications for children's rights in Canadian and international law and the "best interests" principle. Second, the concept of "legal representation for children" is explored, with specific reference to inconsistencies in the jurisprudence concerning the role of independent representation for children. This paper argues that to truly reflect a custodial or access arrangement made in the child's "best interests", it is imperative that the child's voice be heard by the court through independent legal counsel assigned to represent that child's individual needs and concerns.</description><creator>Fleishman, Jodi Rebecca.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Legal assistance to children.</subject><subject>Children's rights.</subject><subject>Custody of children -- Moral and ethical apects.</subject><title>Mandatory legal representation for children in custody, access and child protection proceedings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jodi Rebecca Fleishman, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sj904.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b152h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jk612</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the influence of contemporary approaches to biodiversity conservation on conceptions of state sovereignty over natural resources. Traditional approaches to state sovereignty have emphasized the right of states to exploit natural resources. Contemporary approaches to biodiversity conservation, however, have given rise to a more flexible and dynamic understanding of state sovereignty over natural resources: one encompassing sovereign rights of exploitation along with corresponding conservation responsibilities. Founded upon this premise, the thesis focuses on the emergence of a 'balanced' approach to state sovereignty over natural resources and examines its effects on the role of states in managing natural resources. While addressing it as the basis of the emergence of the recognition of a duty of environmental protection, inter alia, in the form of biodiversity conservation and sustainable use of biological resources, the author suggests that the balanced approach to state sovereignty has been instrumental in redefining the role of states, and the role of the sovereignty principle itself in achieving the goal of biodiversity conservation.</description><creator>Echeverria, Hugo.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biodiversity conservation -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Sovereignty.</subject><subject>Government ownership -- Law and legislation.</subject><title>Biodiversity conservation and state sovereignty</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Hugo Echeverria, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x426b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jk612</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859f937</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis reviews the legal, political and technical aspects of aeronautical information, with a particular focus on the situation of aeronautical information in Europe. It portrays the evolution of aeronautical information and its current nature. It looks at the responsibility for the publication of aeronautical information and the evolution of that notion due to recent trends towards corporatisation to the detriment of full State ownership. It also examines the question of liability for the publication of aeronautical information, including the various legal regimes under which victims of defective aeronautical information can claim compensation, as well as the legal mechanisms underlying and implementing such compensation regimes. The final chapter is concerned with electronic aeronautical information and the specific legal challenges this technological revolution has brought about.</description><creator>De Grandmont, Philippe.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Aids to air navigation -- Electronic publishing.</subject><subject>Aids to air navigation -- Electronic publishing -- Europe.</subject><title>Soon to be paperless, but nevertheless not lawless : legal challenges surrounding the publication of aeronautical information</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Philippe De Grandmont, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m440f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859f937</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386j42c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cavity ring-down spectroscopy (CRDS) is a novel, accurate, sensitive and non-intrusive laser-based technique using multiple-paths molecular absorption to measure weak absolute concentrations of atoms or molecules (ppm range or better). In CRDS, a laser pulse is coupled into an optical cavity equipped of highly reflective mirrors mounted at both ends and containing the absorbing medium. The laser pulse experiences numerous round trips inside the cavity thus considerably increasing the absorption path. The decay of the laser pulse intensity leaking out of one of the cavity mirrors is monitored in real-time and the concentration of the species is obtained by fitting a Beer-Lambert's decay to the measured signal. The resulting signal is an exponentially decaying function with a 1/e cavity ring-down (tau), proportional to the absolute concentration of the absorbing species. The main objective of this Master's project was to develop a CRDS system to be used for the study of plasma-surface interactions. The CRDS cavity measures 92 cm in length and has a spatial resolution of 1 mm2, and is flexible enough in its design to accommodate a low-pressure glow discharge or a miniature atmospheric pressure plasma torch at the centre of the cavity. In this study, the low-pressure glow discharge plasma is used to produce CH radicals from a 95% Ar - 5% C2H2 gas mixture. Preliminary optical emission spectroscopy- (OES) measurements near 431 rim indicated the presence of CH radicals in the plasma. For the CRDS experiments, the electronic transition A2Delta ← X2pi of the CH radical was probed using a tunable dye laser (10Hz, 5 ns pulse, 0.8 cm -1 linewidth) tuned to 431.131 nm, and at a pulse energy of approximately 30-40 muJ. The CRDS system was able to measure CH radical concentrations ranging from 1.78x1012cm-3 to 2.18 x10 12 cm-3.</description><creator>Ouimet-Storrs, Alexandre.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Development of a cavity ring-down spectroscopy setup and validation with carbon-hydrogen radical measurements in an argon and acetylene direct currentb low-pressure glow discharge plasma</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Alexandre Ouimet-Storrs, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s276c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386j42c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440s769</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Multi-wavelength laser sources have attracted much interest in the last decade as new photonic technologies have enabled the realization of such sources with much improved characteristics. Tunable continuous-wave multi-wavelength fiber lasers may now offer, for example, the ability to tune the wavelength spacing between the lasing lines and, also at times, the possibility to control the individual output peak powers. The more flexible and low-cost solutions benefiting from higher optical spectrum bandwidths also attract the most interest for future applications. These lasers find clients in so many fields such as optical test and measurement, optical communications, sensing, and processing like microwave photonic filtering. The search for such a flexible, stable and affordable laser source has fueled the investigation presented in this thesis. We first analyze the different approaches taken in the past for the implementation of tunable continuous-wave multi-wavelength lasers and follow with the development of a novel, relatively low-cost, tunable multi-wavelength semiconductor fiber laser (SFL). All the design steps are clearly explained and characterized. The final SFL is then used for the demonstration of two applications: chromatic dispersion measurements in long fiber spools, and the new design of a photonic microwave filter.</description><creator>Pagé, Véronique.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physics, Optics.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Design and applications of a tunable multi-wavelength SFL</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Véronique Pagé, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v8199.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440s769</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff365549t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:03:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The application of a 2D hydraulic-habitat model, River2D, to simulate flows and fish habitat areas in a reach of the Nicolet River (Quebec, Canada) containing two sets of double-wing rock current deflectors to enhance fish habitat was examined. Depth-averaged velocity in the reach was determined using one or two measurement points in the vertical under the assumption that the profile was logarithmic; however, the presence of boulders and obstructions disturbed the profile, making it difficult to characterize using only two measurement points. The sensitivity of the simulation results to roughness characterization, topographic scale, mesh refinement, and boundary conditions was evaluated. The simulated and observed depths had correlation coefficients of 0.93 to 0.97, while the velocity correlation coefficients were 0.56 to 0.67. Qualitatively, the model accurately predicted the flow patterns, e.g. the recirculation zones downstream of the deflectors. Habitat suitability curves for brown trout, taken from literature, were used in the habitat model. Simulated discharges from 0.74 m3/s to 1.94 m3/s were critical minimum flows for suitable spawning brown trout habitat. The model was adequate for qualitatively simulating flow and habitat in this reach, however, the complex flow conditions may be better represented by a 3D model.</description><creator>Ng, Karen Pei-Tak.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Hydrology.</subject><title>Two-dimensional hydraulic-habitat modeling of a rehabilitated river</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Karen Pei-Tak Ng, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311p63g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365549t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40525</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>