<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:35:07Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38075" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d407g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Functioning, the most important outcome of stroke interventions, is complex to characterize. Stroke survivors measure functioning compared to what they did in their prestroke lives; hence equating functioning with recovery. To optimize the recovery of functioning, research suggests that rehabilitation interventions should start early post-stroke. To quantify changes in function owing to different interventions, the average value on an index comprised of multiple items related to function is compared or the proportions of people categorized into different functional levels are compared. Currently, there is no agreed upon method of quantifying improvements in functioning and using multiple indices is problematic. This thesis examined combining a method of quantifying behaviours, Rasch analysis that produces measures with interval properties from ordinal observations, with the component of the International Classification of Functioning (ICF), to conceptualize, define, and quantify functioning in a single measure. The ensuing prototype measure was limited in scope. Therefore, using data from a longitudinal prognostic study involving people with acute stroke assessed at three days and followed up at three months, a Functioning measure at three months, the F3m, was developed. The F3m is a valid and reliable measure that amalgamates tests where performance is observed and self-report questionnaires where people rate their difficulties in performing physical activities. The F3m covers all ICF components and can be used to quantify recovery at three months. Interventions to improve early functioning post-stroke must impact favourably on the factors that affect early recovery. The most influential factor related to recovery, to date, has been early functioning. As a measure of such early functioning did not exist, a measure of functioning at three days, the FM, was constructed in a manner similar to the F3m. Univariate and multivariate analyses were then used to identify strong early factors collected 24-72 hours post-stroke, and link the factors to function at 3 months. A seven-variable predictive model of functioning was derived. The most important influential predictor of functioning in the model, the comprehensive FM measure, can now be used to evaluate and develop early interventions to enhance functioning, and to act as a covariate explaining the recovery of functioning.</description><creator>Finch, L. (Lois), 1947-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Measuring and predicting early functioning post-stroke</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© L. Finch, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236650n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d407g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vn11j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The initiation of adaptive immune responses requires the interactions of T cells with antigen presenting cells (APC) in the context of an immunological synapse (IS). Naive T cell responses are dependent on the engagement of CD28 and CTLA-4 by CD86 and CD80, respectively amplifying and dampening the antigen specific signal. CD80 and CD86 cosignaling molecules display three major domains: a membrane distal IgV-like domain, a membrane proximal IgC-like domain and an intracellular domain. Crystallographic data has shown that only the IgV domain of CD80 and CD86 physically interacts with CTLA-4. However, extensive mutational analyses have also implicated the IgC domain in receptor binding and in the overall function of these molecules. The role of CD80 and CD86 within the IS and their exact molecular structure remains to be elucidated. The work presented in this thesis employs wild type, mutant, deleted and chimeric forms of CD80 and CD86 to characterize the role of their domains in molecular structure, receptor binding and overall cosignaling function in an antigen specific cellular interaction system. CD80 and CD86 are shown to be associated to the AFC cytoskeleton. A highly conserved K4 motif within CD86 is shown to be a cytoskeletal association motif. Moreover, CD86 is shown to physically interact with ERM proteins. Only cytoskeleton-linked CD86 localizes at the IS and induce IL-2 production. CD80 and CD86 molecular organization is clearly established using cytometry-based fluorescence resonance energy transfer (FCET) and biochemical approaches. CD80 exists as a mixed monomeric and dimeric population and CD86 as a monomer in live cells. The crucial role of CD80 and CD86 IgC domain in multimerization is revealed. Importantly, the molecular structure of these molecules correlates with their binding properties and cosignaling function. A functional picture of CD80 and CD86 domains emerges where the IgV is responsible for receptor binding, the IgC domain impacts dimerization, and the intracellular domain functionally links these proteins to the cytoskeleton. The findings presented in this thesis certainly contribute to the general understanding of cosignaling protein interactions and functions and may facilitate the design of structure-based immunotherapeutics.</description><creator>Girard, Tanya.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Role of CD80 and CD86 cosignaling proteins functional domains in molecular structure and adaptive immune responses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Tanya Girard, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f4629569.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vn11j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b534d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Translational control is crucial to balancing the cell's protein output and genetic expression. The substrate of the translational machinery---messenger RNA (mRNA)---is itself subject to regulation. The lifetime of an mRNA is limited and therefore mRNA decay is a critical step in the regulation of gene expression. Translation and mRNA decay are intimately related processes as they both handle the cell economy. mRNAs are generally in a balancing act between the translational and the repression/decay machinery, which ultimately decides the fate of an mRNA and its protein expression rate. In fact, translation affects the rate of mRNA decay. For instance, aberrant messages which contain a premature-termination codon (PTC) require ribosome scanning in order to read the message, discover the mistake, and essentially prompt its destruction. Here, a relationship between the nuclear translation-like factor---eIF4AIII, the nuclear import factor of cIF4E---4E-T, and mRNA decay was discovered. eIF4AIII is a nuclear protein that interacts physically or functionally with translation initiation factors eIF4G and eIF4B, respectively, and shares strikingly high identity with the initiation factors eIF4AI/II. This work demonstrates that eIF4AIII but not eIF4AI is required for nonsense-mediated decay (NMD). NMD is a surveillance mechanism in eukaryotes which degrades the mRNA when a PTC is present. NMD is a splicing and translation-dependent event in mammalians. We show eIF4AIII is deposited at the exon-exon junction during splicing, is a shuttling protein, and is necessary for NMD. At steady state, 4E-T is predominantly cytoplasmic and is concentrated in bodies that conspicuously resemble the recently described Processing bodies (P-bodies), which are sites of mRNA decay. We demonstrate that 4E-T colocalizes with mRNA decapping factors in bona fide P-bodies and that its binding partner, eIF4E, is tethered to P-bodies in a 4E-T dependent manner. Moreover, 4E-T controls mRNA half life. We demonstrate that 4E-T interaction with eIF4E represses translation, which is thought to be a prerequisite for targeting of mRNAs to P-bodies. Hence, analysis of prospective translation factors has led to elucidation of mRNA decay pathways.</description><creator>Ferraiuolo, Maria A.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>The role of eIF4AIII and 4E-T in mRNA decay /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Maria A. Ferraiuolo, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qw96v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b534d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236651x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hybrid poplars are fast-growing trees, well-suited for the production of bioenergy and wood products. They are often planted on marginal agricultural lands where soil fertility is low. The application of nitrogen (N) fertilizers is expected to replenish soil N reserves and support hybrid poplar productivity throughout the short-rotation growth period. The objective of this thesis was to assess the effect of two organic N fertilizers, papermill biosolids and pig slurry, on tree growth, nutrient uptake and soil fertility in a Populus trichocarpa x Populus deltoides hybrid poplar plantation. I also evaluated how these organic amendments influenced N transformation rates and denitrification losses. Hybrid poplar growth was greater when trees were fertilized with mixed biosolids: pig slurry fertilizer treatments compared to biosolids or pig slurry alone. Assessment of foliar nutrition with the critical value approach (CVA) and compositional nutrient diagnosis (CND) methods revealed that foliar N and P concentrations were limiting to tree growth. Vector analysis (VA) reflected growth responses in fertilized trees, relative to an unfertilized control, but may not be useful as a diagnostic tool due to the indeterminate growth habit of hybrid poplars. Nevertheless, surface application of papermill biosolids and pig slurry had the potential to improve soil fertility by increasing soil pH and extractable nutrients in the hybrid poplar plantations. Nutrient use efficiency (NUE) was greater in plots receiving the mixed biosolids:pig slurry treatment than biosolids or pig slurry alone. Laboratory incubations and 15N isotope pool technique revealed that pig slurry was a source of readily-mineralizable N one month after fertilizer application, and stimulated the gross nitrification rate and immobilization, while papermill biosolids contributed to a larger mineral N pools at the end of the season. Our results suggest that denitrification will be greater in biosolids-treated soils, which have a higher extractable Ca concentration and soil pH, as well as more NO3-N and available C for denitrifiers. Further investigation under field conditions would help us to evaluate the N transformations and losses mediated by microbial activities following organic fertilizer application in a hybrid poplar plantation.</description><creator>Lteif, Arlette.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Poplar -- Fertilizers -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Poplar -- Breeding -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Nitrogen fertilizers -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Organic fertilizers -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Poplar -- Québec (Province) -- Growth.</subject><title>Biomass production and nitrogen transformations in a hybrid poplar plantation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Arlette Lteif, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tk70q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236651x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644w857</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Treatment delivery verification is an essential step of radiotherapy. The purpose of this thesis is to develop new methods to improve the verification of photon and electron beam radiotherapy treatments. This is achieved through developing and testing (1) a way to acquire portal images during electron beam treatments, (2) a method to reconstruct the dose delivered to patients during photon beam treatments and (3) a technique to improve image quality in kilovoltage (kV) cone beam computed tomography (CBCT) by correcting for scattered radiation. The portal images were acquired using the Varian CL21EX linac and the Varian aS500 electronic portal imaging device (EPID). The EGSnrc code was used to model fully the CL21EX, the aS500 and the kV CBCT system. We demonstrate that portal images of electron beam treatments with adequate contrast and resolution can be produced using the bremsstrahlung photons portion of the electron beam. Monte Carlo (MC) calculations were used to characterize the bremsstrahlung photons and to obtain predicted images of various phantoms. The technique was applied on a head and neck patient. An algorithm to reconstruct the dose given to patients during photon beam radiotherapy was developed and validated. The algorithm uses portal images and MC simulations. The primary fluence at the detector is back-projected through the patient. CT geometry to obtain a reconstructed phase space file. The reconstructed phase space file is used to calculate the reconstructed dose to the patient using MC simulations. The reconstruction method was validated in homogeneous and heterogeneous phantoms for conventional and IMRT fields. The scattered radiation present in kV CBCT images was evaluated using MC simulations. Simulated predictions of the scatter distribution were subtracted from CBCT projection images prior to the reconstruction to improve the reconstructed image quality. Reducing the scattered radiation was found to improve contrast and reduce shading artifacts. MC simulations, in combination with experimental techniques, have been shown to be valuable tools in the development of treatment verification methods. The three novel methods presented in this thesis contribute to the improvement of radiotherapy treatment verification. They can potentially improve treatment outcome by ensuring a better target coverage.</description><creator>Jarry, Geneviève.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Photon beams -- Therapeutic use -- Reporting.</subject><subject>Radiotherapy -- Positioning.</subject><subject>Electron beams -- Therapeutic use -- Reporting.</subject><subject>Radiation dosimetry.</subject><title>Study of novel techniques for verification imaging and patient dose reconstruction in external beam radiation therapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Geneviève Jarry, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021k337.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644w857</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hw87z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Arctic Oscillation (AO) and the North Atlantic Oscillation (NAO) are the most pronounced modes of extratropical atmospheric wintertime variability in the Northern Hemisphere. This thesis investigates different aspects of the AO and NAO on the in traseasonal and seasonal time scales. First, the question of how the differences between the AO and NAO are influenced by the choice of the definitions of the NAO and to what extent the AO and NAO differ from each other is investigated using the daily NCEP/NCAR reanalysis data spanning 51 boreal winters. One AO index and four different NAO indices are used in this study. It is found that the AO and NAO are quite similar to each other when both are defined using pattern-based indices, while some notable differences are observed between them when the NAO is defined using a station/gridpoint-based index. Then the predictability of the AO and NAO is examined using a simple general circulation model (SGCM). Numerical experiments are performed to determine the sensitivity of the setup processes of the AO and NAO to the details of the initial conditions. The predictive skills for the AO and NAO are compared to each other. Finally, the potential role of tropical Pacific forcing in driving the seasonal variability of the AO is explored using both observations and the SGCM. The results indicate that a negative thermal forcing over the western tropical Pacific and a positive forcing north of the equatorial mid-Pacific play important roles in producing an AO-like atmospheric response.</description><creator>Jia, XiaoJing, 1977-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Atmospheric circulation -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>North Atlantic oscillation.</subject><title>The mechanisms and the predictability of the Arctic oscillation and the North Atlantic oscillation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© XiaoJing Jia, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bk159.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hw87z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zs54c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The inclusive production of the neutral strange particles, Λ, Λ and K0S , has been studied with the ZEUS detector at HERA. The measurement provides a way to understand the fragmentation process in ep collisions and to check the universality of this process. The strangeness cross sections have been measured and compared with Monte Carlo (MC) predictions. Over the kinematic regions of interest, no Λ to Λ asymmetry was observed. The relative yield of Λ and K0S was determined and the result was compared with MC calculations and results from other experiments. A good agreement was found except for the enhancement in the photoproduction process. Clear rapidity correlation was observed for particle pairs where either quark flavor or baryon number compensation occurs. The K0SK0S Bose-Einstein correlation measurement gives a result consistent with those from LEP measurements. The Λ polarizations were measured to be consistent with zero for HERA I data.</description><creator>Liu, Chuanlei, 1976-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Strange particles.</subject><subject>Nuclear counters.</subject><title>Neutral strangeness production with the ZEUS detector at HERA</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Chuanlei Liu, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dk94v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zs54c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h383t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Laccase (E.C 1.10.3.2) catalyzes the oxidation of aromatic substrates with the simultaneous reduction of molecular oxygen to water. It has significant potential for use in many applications due to its high reaction rates, broad substrate-specificity, and use of oxygen as an inexpensive co-factor. The objective of this research was to investigate the ability of laccase from Trametes versicolor to catalyze oxidation reactions under a variety of reaction conditions and to model the kinetics of these transformations. Phenol was selected as a model substrate. Laccase was very stable when incubated at temperatures less than 30°C and pHs between 6 and 7. The optimum pH for phenol transformation was 6, but when present in sufficient quantities, laccase was able to significantly transform phenol at pHs from 4 to 7 and temperatures from 10 to 60°C. Laccase stability was negatively impacted by the presence of four common redox mediators. Of these, 2,2'-azino-bis(3-ethylbenzothiazoline-6-sulfonate) (ABTS) and 2,2',6,6'-tetramethylpiperidine-N-oxyl (TEMPO) significantly enhanced phenol transformation but large quantities were required, which may limit the feasibility of the use of these mediators in many applications. A series of kinetic models was developed in order to achieve a better understanding of the mechanisms and kinetics of laccase-catalyzed reactions and to eventually assist in the choice and design of suitable reactor systems. These models were designed to predict the transient oxygen and phenol concentrations during laccasecatalyzed reactions at pH 6 and 25°C. Over the course of developing and validating these models, it was observed that: (1) the rate-limiting step in the catalytic reactions is the reaction between the oxidized form of laccase and phenol; (2) the stoichiometric ratio, which is defined as the molar ratio of phenol transformed to oxygen consumed in the catalytic reaction, was found to increase with phenol concentration in the reaction mixture from a theoretical lower limit of 1 and to approach a theoretical upper limit of 4; and (3) laccase inactivation occurs over the course of the reaction and was found to be dependent on the rate of substrate transformation. Ultimately, these findings were incorporated into a comprehensive kinetic model to predict transient species concentrations in an open-system environment where the degree of substrate transformation was not limited by oxygen availability. The model accounts for enzyme kinetics, oxygen mass-transfer, variable reaction stoichiometry, and inactivation related to reaction products. Excellent agreement was observed between measured and modeled phenol and oxygen concentrations for a wide range of initial phenol concentrations and enzyme activities. Simplified models were also developed by incorporating an assumption, referred to as the pseudo-steady-state assumption, that at any instant during the reaction, the enzyme achieves an approximate steady-state distribution of its various forms around the catalytic cycle. The pseudo-steady-state assumption had the advantage of reducing the complexity of model equations without sacrificing their predictive abilities and allowing enzyme quantities to be expressed in activity units instead of molar concentrations.</description><creator>Soegiaman, Selvia Kurniawati.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Laccase.</subject><subject>Phenol.</subject><subject>Catalysis.</subject><subject>Oxidation.</subject><title>Kinetics of the laccase-catalyzed oxidation of aqueous phenol</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Selvia Kurniawati Soegiaman, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qw974.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h383t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430893b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The general objectives of this thesis project were to describe and to understand the dynamics creating occurrence patterns of saproxylic wood-feeding Coleoptera in snags (i.e., standing dead trees) of black spruce and aspen along the decay gradient. The first part of this thesis focuses on pre-landing host-selection behaviours in coniferophagous species, i.e. the use of host-produced volatiles to locate potential hosts. Results presented suggest that most saproxylic wood-feeding beetles studied herein use volatiles to orient towards potential habitat patches but that olfactive information does not allow the identification of suitable hosts at close range prior to landing. The second part of the thesis focuses on the occurrence patterns themselves and on underlying mechanisms. Sampling was conducted using snag dissection, a novel method allowing a better characterization of larval stage wood-feeding assemblages. Opposite patterns were observed between the two host species studied, as abundance and species richness were highest in early stages of decay in spruce, and in middle to late stages of decay in aspen. In aspen, numerous nutritional and physical parameters of dead wood correlated significantly with wood-borer occurrence. However, most of these parameters were strongly auto-correlated, and the explanatory model most highly ranked by model selection consisted of only a snag age term. Also, a simple neutral model based on temporal autocorrelation in occurrence probability produced patterns similar to those observed through sampling. In the last original paper presented, results suggest that wood-boring larvae select for specific types of substrate in highly variable aspen snags. This selection on the part of the larvae likely decreases the impact of the oviposition site on subsequent larval performance, and could explain the lack of strong selection seen on the part of the mother. My results suggest very different host-selection dynamics in black spruce and aspen, as assemblages of the former were dominated by early-decay species with volatiles-driven colonization dynamics, while middle- to late-decay species dominated the later, seemingly through mostly neutral colonization mechanisms. Some of my findings suggest that patterns observed in black spruce and aspen could be extrapolated to a coniferous/deciduous host dichotomy in colonization dynamics of woodfeeding species, based on divergent secondary chemistry and wood structure.</description><creator>Saint-Germain, Michel, 1973-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Black spruce -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi-Témiscamingue.</subject><subject>Wood borers -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi-Témiscamingue.</subject><subject>Beetles -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi-Témiscamingue.</subject><subject>Populus tremuloides -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi-Témiscamingue.</subject><title>Host-selection behaviour and host-use patterns of saproxylic beetles in snags of aspen (Populus tremuloides Michaux) and black spruce (Picea mariana (Miller)) in the province of Québec, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Michel Saint-Germain, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204325s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430893b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mh237</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Variability between individuals in pain and analgesia phenotypes is often observed in both clinical and experimental settings. The source of this variability has long been attributed to the interplay of environmental and genetic factors, but we have only recently begun identifying these determinants. Experiments comparing isogenic strains of mice have suggested that different pain tests may share a genetic basis; likewise, analgesic magnitude induced by disparate drug classes may be influenced by a common set of genes. We have presently used a quantitative trait locus mapping strategy to search for genes responsible for variability in analgesic response to five analgesic drugs (the opioids morphine and U50,488, and the non-opioid drugs clonidine, epibatidine, and WIN55,212-2). We first used a B6129PF2 intercross population to map sensitivity to clonidine, morphine, and WIN55,212-2 to a 30 cM region on distal Chromosome 1. In silico and congenic strain mapping techniques allowed us to refine this linkage, as well as generalize it to four of the five drugs and seven mouse strains. Kcnj9 (GIRK3) was identified as a likely candidate gene underlying response to multiple analgesic modalities. We showed that this gene is differentially expressed between C57BL/6 and 129P3 strains in the periaqueductal gray. We also determined that Kcnj9 null mutant mice exhibit attenuated analgesic responses. We previously mapped nociceptive response to the formalin test to two loci on Chr. 9 and 10 using an AB6F2 cross. Using in silico mapping, we identified several haplotypes near the Atp1b3 gene on Chr. 9 (a subunit of the sodium-potassium pump) that correlated highly with early phase formalin response. We then showed that pharmacological antagonism of the sodium-potassium channel eliminates the strain difference observed between A and C57BL/6 mice, supporting a role for this gene in determining response to formalin. Positional cloning of the Chr. 10 locus, employing recombinant and congenic strains, allowed us to refine the location of the locus to a &lt;3 cM interval. A small number of genes in this region were identified as differentially expressed by microarray analysis, providing a short list of candidate genes for follow-up investigation.</description><creator>Smith, Shad Benjamin.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Phenotype.</subject><subject>Analgesia.</subject><subject>Nociceptors.</subject><title>Positional cloning of genes contributing to variability in nociceptive and analgesic phenotypes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Shad Benjamin Smith, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p233b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mh237</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zz318</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Designing systems with the ability to make optimal decisions under uncertainty is one of the goals of artificial intelligence. However, in many applications the design of optimal planners is complicated due to imprecise inputs and uncertain outputs resulting from stochastic dynamics. Partially Observable Markov Decision Processes (POMDPs) provide a rich mathematical framework to model these kinds of problems. However, the high computational demand of solution methods for POMDPs is a drawback for applying them in practice. In this thesis, we present a two-fold approach for improving the tractability of POMDP planning. First, we focus on designing good heuristics for POMDP approximation algorithms. We aim to scale up the efficiency of a class of POMDP approximations called point-based planning methods by designing a good planning space. We study the effect of three properties of reachable belief state points that may influence the performance of point-based approximation methods. Second, we investigate approaches to designing good controllers using an alternative representation of systems with partial observability called Predictive State Representation (PSR). This part of the thesis advocates the usefulness and practicality of PSRs in planning under uncertainty. We also attempt to move some useful characteristics of the PSR model, which has a predictive view of the world, to the POMDP model, which has a probabilistic view of the hidden states of the world. We propose a planning algorithm motivated by the connections between the two models.</description><creator>Tabaeh Izadi, Masoumeh.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Markov processes.</subject><subject>Planning -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>On knowledge representation and decision making under uncertainty</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Masoumeh Tabaeh Izadi, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806428z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zz318</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80j079g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rapid progress has been made toward understanding the significance of CDK inhibitor proteins (CKIs) in the regulation of cell cycle progression. The overall goal of this study has been targeted to further expand our knowledge of CKI function through the investigation of a previously uncharacterized CKI named cki-2 during development in C. elegans. The characterization of cki-2 using a reverse genetic approach called co-suppression has revealed a novel mechanism that cki-2 and its related cell cycle regulators are required for the appropriate elimination of centrioles during oogenesis. Loss of cki-2 in the germ line caused perdurance of centrioles into the one-cell embryo, resulting in supernumerary centrosomes and aberrant cell divisions in the first cell cycle. This was significantly suppressed by reduction of cyclin E and a Cdk2 homologue, indicating that these cell cycle regulators are involved in this critical developmental process. In order to further understand the function of cki-2, a yeast two-hybrid screen was conducted which allowed us to identify three CKI-2 interacting proteins: orthologues of PCNA (PCN-1), SUMO (SMO-1), and a RING finger protein called RNF-1. CKI-2 has functionally separable domains in its amino (Cyclin/Cdk binding)- and carboxy (PCNA binding)-terminus and they exert distinct roles in cell cycle progression. It was observed that CKI-2 is covalently modified by SUMO on its N-terminus and this causes CKI-2 to relocalize to thr nucleolus, which is associated with its rapid degradation. Since many RING finger proteins act as components of the multi-subunit E3 ubquitin ligases, we speculated that RNF-1 might be involved in the CKI-2 degradation. This possibility was tested by co-expression of RNF-1 with CKI-2, revealing that co-expression of RNF-1 suppresses the embryonic lethality caused by the CKI-2 overexpression and moreover, this is correlated with an increased rate of CKI-2 degradation. In addition, western blot analyses performed on different genetic backgrounds suggested that the CKI-2 degradation occurs in an ubiquitin-dependent manner through the proteasome-mediated proteolysis pathway. Furthermore, a yeast-based assay developed to test a possible role of SUMO in modulating the CKI-2/RNF-1 interaction demonstrated that SUMO may antagonize the interaction between CKI-2 and RNF-l, these highlighting an intriguing model that appropriate levels of CKI-2 are regulated through ubiquitin-dependent proteolysis mediated by RNF-l, and which maybe modulated by SUMO.</description><creator>Kim, Dae Young, 1968-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Development.</subject><title>Role of cki-2 during development in C. elegans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Dae Young Kim, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m827q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80j079g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52jc98k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main focus of this thesis is on investigating the minimum size of the Representative Volume Element (RVE) and finite-size scaling of properties of random linear and nonlinear elastic composites. The RVE is a material volume which accurately describes the overall behavior of a heterogeneous solid, and is the core assumption of continuum mechanics theory. If the composite microstructure admits the assumption of spatial homogeneity and ergodicity, the RVE can be attained within a specific accuracy on a finite length-scale. Determining this scale is the key objective of this thesis. In order to theoretically analyze the scale-dependence of the apparent response of random microstructures, essential and natural boundary conditions which satisfy Hill's averaging theorem in finite deformation elasticity are first considered. It is shown that the application of the partitioning method and variational principles in nonlinear elasticity and thermoelasticity, under the two above-mentioned boundary conditions, leads to the hierarchy of mesoscale bounds on the effective strain- and free-energy functions, respectively. These theoretical derivations lay the ground for the quantitative estimation of the scale-dependence of nonlinear composite responses and their RVE size. The hierarchies were computed for planar matrix-inclusion composites with the microstructure modeled by a homogeneous Poisson point field. Various nonlinear composites with Ogden-type strain-energy function are considered. The obtained results are compared with those where both matrix and inclusions are described by a neo-Hookean strain-energy function as well as with the results obtained from the linear elasticity theory. The trends toward the RVE are also computed for nonlinear elastic composites subjected to non-isothermal loading. The accuracy of the RVE size estimation is calculated in terms of the discrepancy between responses under essential and natural boundary conditions. Overall, the results show that the trends toward the RVE as well as its minimum size are functions of the deformation, deformation mode, temperature, and the mismatch between material properties of the phases. The last part of the thesis presents an investigation of the size effect on thermoelastic damping of a micro-/nanobeam resonator. It does not follow the framework described above. The main concern here is the size and the vibration frequency, at which the classical Fourier law of heat conduction is no longer valid, and the finite speed of heat propagation has to be taken into account.</description><creator>Khisaeva, Zemfira F.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>Scale effects in finite elasticity and thermoelasticity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Zemfira F. Khisaeva, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nj98v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jc98k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63t097t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Asthma is a common inflammatory airway disease affecting over 2.5-3 million Canadians. This disease involves a Th2-driven immune response. Th2-type cytokines, (interleukin (IL)-4, IL-5, and IL-13) are upregulated in human asthmatics and in animals models of allergic airway inflammation. A recently characterized cytokine, IL-17E (IL-25), expressed in vitro by Th2 lymphocytes, macrophages and mast cells, generates a Th2 phenotype in mice. Overexpression of IL-17E promotes asthma-like features in animal models, namely, elevated levels of IL-4, IL-5 and IL-13, increased airway hyperreactivity, eosinophilia, increased IgE, airway epithelial cell hypertrophy/hyperplasia, and airway mucus hypersecretion. IL-17E binds the interleukin-17B receptor (IL-17BR), which is expressed in a variety of tissues and is upregulated under inflammatory conditions. We have investigated the expression of this receptor on structural cells of the airways in addition to assessing the effect of IL-17E on these cells. We hypothesized that airway smooth muscle cells (ASMC), lung epithelial cells and lung fibroblasts express IL-17BR and that proinflammatory cytokines could modulate its expression. The three cell types constitutively express IL-17BR mRNA and protein, and its expression was consistently upregulated by the proinflammatory cytokine TNFalpha. We also observed that the Th1 type cytokine IFNgamma decreased IL-17BR expression in ASMC, we observed a similar decrease by TGFbeta in fibroblasts. IL-17E appears to have profibrotic properties, as it upregulates the expression of pro-collagen alpha1 mRNA in ASMC, this could suggest that it could increase basement membrane thickening in vivo, a characteristic feature of airway remodelling. Pro-inflammatory and pro-eosinophilic cytokines such as RANTES, eotaxin, IL-8 and GM-CSF are increased in lung fibroblasts treated with IL-17E. In A549 lung epithelial cells, IL-17E also acts synergistically with TNFalpha to induce GROalpha mRNA and this effect can be inhibited by recombinant IL-17BR. In addition, IL-17E promoted the proliferation of bronchial epithelial cells isolated from biopsies taken from control and mild asthmatic donors. Collectively, our results show that the IL-17E receptor is consistutively present in structural cells of the airways and increases in the presence of TNFalpha. Our results also suggests a potential pro-remodelling and pro-inflammatory role for IL-17E on these cells.</description><creator>Lajoie, Stéphane.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Expression of a functional receptor for IL-IL-I7E on structural cells of the airways</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Stéphane Lajoie, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732df166.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63t097t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sj012</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pathogenesis of the enteric protozoan parasite Entamoeba histolytica remains poorly understood. Moreover, the host responses during the early periods of interaction in the gut remain to be clarified. In this study I investigated the cell specific responses to the parasite and the importance of cross talk between epithelial-immune cells that could potentially influence the outcome of infection, with a central focus on Nuclear factor (NF)-kappaB. NF-kappaB is a ubiquitous transcription factor that plays a critical role in mucosal inflammation and its regulation by E. histolytica has not been studied so far. Gal-lectin is a well characterized parasite virulence factor and vaccine candidate. I first characterized the interactions between Gal-lectin and macrophages and found that several proinflammatory genes are upregulated as early as 2h. The Gal-lectin activated NF-kappaB and up-regulated Toll like receptor-2 expression in an NF-kappaB- and p38 Mitogen Activated Protein (MAP) kinase-dependent manner. As intestinal epithelial cells (IEC) form the first line of active host defense against mucosal pathogens, I determined the interaction between ameba soluble proteins and naive IEC. I observed that the parasite could elicit a chemokine response via activation of PI3 kinase and phosphorylation of p65 subunit to induce monocyte chemoattractant protein-1. The consequent recruitment of immune cells could be responsible for colonic inflammation. Finally, I made the novel observation that in macrophage-primed IEC, ameba proteins elicited a cytoprotective stress response. Using a combination of siRNA and over expression studies, I demonstrated that amebic proteins increased the expression and phosphorylation of Heat shock protein (Hsp) 27 thereby enhancing its association with and subsequent inhibition of Inhibitory kappaB kinase (IKK). The resulting inhibition of NF-kappaB could be a potential mechanism that explains the absence of inflammation in the majority of infected individuals. Taken together, the findings of this study open up a new facet in the pathogenesis of amebiasis and unravel a novel paradigm to study host-parasite interactions in the gut.</description><creator>Kammanadiminti, Srinivas Jagannadha.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Entamoeba histolytica.</subject><subject>Intestinal mucosa.</subject><subject>Amebiasis -- Pathogenesis.</subject><title>Early interactions between Entamoeba histolytica and mucosal cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Srinivas Jagannadha Kammanadiminti, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b762p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sj012</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892g27m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years, gull control has become closely tied to seabird restoration in the Gulf of Maine. Herring (Larus argentatus ) and Great Black-backed (L. marinus) gulls are the principal targets of control, yet anecdotal reports suggest that gull predation remains an important source of egg and chick mortality at many managed seabird colonies. The main objective of this study was to examine the impact of gull predation on the reproductive success of several waterbird species nesting at restoration sites in Maine. Particular emphasis was placed on understanding gull foraging behavior, identifying foraging constraints, and applying this knowledge to management of gulls and small seabirds. Productivity of Common (Sterna hirundo), Arctic ( S. paradisaea), and Roseate (S. dougallii) terns was monitored and daily predation watches were conducted at Eastern Egg Rock, Maine from 2003-2005. In 2004 and 2005 only, attempts were made to shoot gulls preying on terns. Shooting failed to eliminate predation, and tern predation risk was influenced by nest location, but not year. Common and Arctic terns experienced heavy predation in all years, but Roseate Tern nests were seldom depredated, presumably because Roseates selected nest-sites with more cover. Great Black-backed Gull predation was influenced by visibility, tidal state, and year, while Herring Gull predation depended only on the stage of the tern breeding cycle. There was little evidence that gulls preyed selectively on unfit chicks. The limitations of shooting are discussed and non-lethal alternatives suggested. Common Eider (Somateria mollissima dresseri) nest (hatching) success, habitat use, and duckling survival were studied at Stratton Island, Maine in 2004-2005. Eiders nested in a variety of habitats offering vegetative cover and enjoyed high nest success. Duckling survival was negligible however, because of opportunistic, group attacks by Great Black-backed Gulls. Glossy Ibis (Plegadis falcinellus) also appeared to suffer heavy gull predation, with adults occasionally attacked in flight. In 2006, gull displacement walks, gull nest/egg destruction, and occasional shooting were used on a trial basis and may enhance future eider production.</description><creator>Donehower, Christina E.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Eider -- Predators of -- Control -- Maine, Gulf of.</subject><subject>Herring gull -- Control -- Maine, Gulf of.</subject><subject>Great black-backed gull -- Control -- Maine, Gulf of.</subject><subject>Terns -- Effect of predation on -- Maine, Gulf of.</subject><subject>Terns -- Predators of -- Control -- Maine, Gulf of.</subject><subject>Eider -- Effect of predation on -- Maine, Gulf of.</subject><title>An adaptive approach to managing gull predation at seabird restoration sites in Maine /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Christina E. Donehower, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059cc55f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892g27m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qd932</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a wide spectrum of novel extensions and enhancements to critical components of modern electromagnetic analysis and design systems. These advancements are achieved through the use of computational intelligence, which comprises neural networks, evolutionary algorithms, and fuzzy systems. These tools have been proven in myriad industrial applications ranging from computer network optimization to heavy machinery control. The analysis module of an electromagnetic analysis and design system typically comprises mesh generation and mesh improvement stages. A novel method for discovering optimal orderings of mesh improvement operators is proposed and leads to a suite of novel mesh improvement techniques. The new techniques outperform existing methods in both mesh quality improvement and computational cost. The remaining contributions pertain to the design module. Specifically, a novel space mapping method is proposed, which allows for the optimization of response surface models. The method is able to combine the accuracy of fine models with the speed of coarse models. Optimal results are achieved for a fraction of the cost of the standard optimization approach. Models built from computational data often do not take into consideration the intrinsic characteristics of the data. A novel model building approach is proposed, which customizes the model to the underlying responses and accelerates searching within the model. The novel approach is able to significantly reduce model error and accelerate optimization. Automatic design schemes for 2D structures typically preconceive the final design or create an intractable search space. A novel non-preconceived approach is presented, which relies on a new genome structure and genetic operators. The new approach is capable of a threefold performance improvement and improved manufacturability. Automatic design of 3D wire structures is often based on "in-series" architectures, which limit performance. A novel technique for automatic creative design of 3D wire antennas is proposed. The antenna structures are grown from a starting wire and invalid designs are avoided. The high quality antennas that emerge from this bio-inspired approach could not have been obtained by a human designer and are able to outperform standard designs.</description><creator>Dorica, Mark.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Computational intelligence.</subject><subject>Antennas (Electronics) -- Design and construction -- Data processing.</subject><subject>Numerical grid generation (Numerical analysis)</subject><title>Novel electromagnetic design system enhancements using computational intelligence strategies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Mark Dorica, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687n42k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qd932</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547w647</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mobile ad hoc networks (MANETs) are generating much interest both in academia and the telecommunication industries. The principal attractions of MANETs are related to the ease with which they can be deployed due to their infrastructure-less and decentralized nature. For example, unlike other wireless networks, MANETs do not require centralized infrastructures such as base stations, and they are arguably more robust due to their avoidance of single point of failures. Interestingly, the attributes that make MANETs attractive as a network paradigm are the same phenomena that compound the challenge of designing adequate security schemes for these innovative networks. One of the challenging security problems is the issue of certificate revocation in MANETs where there are no on-line access to trusted authorities. In wired network environments, when certificates are to be revoked, certificate authorities (CAs) add the information regarding the certificates in question to certificate revocation lists (CRLs) and post the CRLs on accessible repositories or distribute them to relevant entities. In purely ad hoc networks, there are typically no access to centralized repositories or trusted authorities; therefore the conventional method of certificate revocation is not applicable. Another challenging MANET security problem is the issue of secure routing in the presence of selfish or adversarial entities which selectively drop packets they agreed to forward; and in so doing these selfish or adversarial entities can disrupt the network traffic and cause various communication problems. In this thesis, we present two security protocols we developed for addressing the above-mentioned MANET security needs. The first protocol is a decentralized certificate revocation scheme which allows the nodes within a MANET to have full control over the process of certificate revocation. The scheme is fully contained and it does not rely on any input from centralized or external entities such as trusted CAs. The second protocol is a secure MANET routing scheme we named Robust Source Routing (RSR). In addition to providing data origin authentication services and integrity checks, RSR is able to mitigate against intelligent, colluding malicious agents which selectively drop or modify packets they are required to forward.</description><creator>Davis, Carlton R.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Mobile communication systems -- Security measures.</subject><subject>Ad hoc networks (Computer networks) -- Security measures.</subject><title>Security protocols for mobile ad hoc networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Carlton R. Davis, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m355d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547w647</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583z024n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Amazon region is one of the richest areas on the planet in terms of its biodiversity and natural resources. The large scale harvesting of trees in this region is a relatively new activity, and it is uncertain whether the exploitation of timber species will result in depletion of forest genetic resources. To examine this, I have assessed levels of inbreeding, gene flow, and genetic diversity in populations of Amazonian forest trees undergoing logging. Because of their high variability within populations, microsatellite genetic markers were chosen for the study, and it was verified through an initial sampling experiment that this class of markers is sufficiently stable within somatic tissue of large and long-lived trees such that population studies could be undertaken with them. By sampling adult trees and seed progenies at several microsatellite loci, high levels of gene flow and low levels of inbreeding were found within populations of Sextonia rubra and Carapa guianensis, two important insect-pollinated Amazonian forest tree species. Comparing seed progeny collected before versus after selective logging of a population of Carapa guianensis, no measurable evidence was found that that the population genetic dynamics is impacted by logging. In particular, levels of inbreeding, gene flow, and population substructure were the same before and after logging. Comparing different populations distributed over the Amazon basin, a phylogeographical structure in the chloroplast DNA of Carapa guianensis that corresponds to major tributaries of the Amazon river was discovered, suggesting that seed dispersal through rivers may contribute to genetic connectivity among populations. Overall, the results of this thesis suggest that the large effective population sizes, the high levels of gene flow, and the low levels of inbreeding in exploited Amazonian tree populations may allow them to counteract potential negative genetic impacts of selective logging, at least at the levels of harvesting carried out during this study, and for the Carapa guianensis population investigated.</description><creator>Cloutier, Dominic.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Crabwood -- Amazon River Region -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Forest genetic resources conservation -- Amazon River Region.</subject><title>Conservation genetics of exploited Amazonian forest tree species and the impact of selective logging on inbreeding and gene dispersal in a population of Carapa guianensis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Dominic Cloutier, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741w935.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583z024n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593v0590</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The exploitation of the superprism phenomenon for optical demultiplexing using a slab photonic crystal on the silicon on insulator platform is the main subject of this thesis. The S-vector and k-vector superprisms are considered. Design equations for the S-vector superprism demultiplexer which fully take into account the nonlinear spectral dependence of beam propagation and dispersion are introduced. This allows wide-band coarse wavelength division multiplexing (CWDM) demultiplexers to be designed. Selecting minimum prism area as a metric, the best photonic crystal lattice, design parameters and prism geometry is sought. A full 3-D modeling approach using the plane wave expansion method is employed to ensure the practicality of the design. We show that the slab 1-D photonic crystal can provide the smallest superprism. Based on our result, an area of 1367 mum2 is sufficient to resolve 4 standard CWDM channels (20nm channel spacing). We extend this approach by proposing a stratified photonic crystal which has 5 times less area for an 8 channel CWDM design. We then propose the first fully integrated k-vector superprism layout. Design rules and equations are presented and we use these to obtain the design parameters that result in a minimum prism area. We show that an optimized 1-D photonic crystal k-vector superprism with the area of less than 0.1 mm2 is sufficient to resolve 32 standard dense wavelength division multiplexing (DWDM) channels (100GHz channel spacing). The resulting chip size is approximately 4.5 times less than an equivalent etched grating demultiplexer. We also demonstrate that fast lenses can be made using slab 1-D photonic crystal with an periodicity. We introduce an analytical approximation technique for slab 1-D photonic crystals based on the weighted index method. The variational nature of the method leads to acceptable results for moderate refractive index contrast materials. The method can also be extended to 2-D cases and to nonlinear systems. The plane wave expansion (PWE) method and field matching have been combined to obtain a new method which is capable of obtaining all types of modes including the leaky modes of slab 1-D photonic crystals. The method requires fewer plane waves than the conventional PWE method but provides a better approximation. We compare our results with an accurate finite element method as a benchmark. A report of our first attempt for the fabrication, post-possessing and optical characterization of the proposed k-vector superprism demultiplexer is also presented. We recommend the development of a cladding, and more accurate fabrication procedures for future investigations.</description><creator>Bakhtazad, Aref.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physics, Optics.</subject><title>Slab photonic crystal demultiplexers : analysis and design</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Aref Bakhtazad, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sm41w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593v0590</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fd450</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nous considérons, dans cette dissertation, les plans d'expérience bayésiens optimauxpour les problèmes de point de rupture avec changement d'espérance. Un cas de pointde rupture avec changement d'espérance à une seule trajectoire se présente lorsqu'uneséquence de données est prélevée le long d'un axe temporelle (ou son équivalent) etque leur espérance change de valeur. Ce changement, s'il survient, se produit à unendroit sur l'axe inconnu de l'expérimentateur. Cet endroit est appelé "point derupture". Le fait que la position du point de rupture soit inconnue rend les tests etl'inférence difficiles dans les situations de point de rupture à une seule trajectoire.</description><description>We consider optimal design for changepoint problems with particular attention paid to situations where the only possible change is in the mean. Optimal design for changepoint problems has only been addressed in an unpublished doctoral thesis, and in only one journal article, which was in a frequentist setting. The simplest situation we consider is that of a stochastic process that may undergo a, change at an unknown instant in some interval. The experimenter can take n measurements and is faced with one or more of the following optimal design problems: Where should these n observations be taken in order to best test for a change somewhere in the interval? Where should the observations be taken in order to best test for a change in a specified subinterval? Assuming that a change will take place, where should the observations be taken so that that one may best estimate the before-change mean as well as the after-change mean? We take a Bayesian approach, with a risk based on squared error loss, as a design criterion function for estimation, and a risk based on generalized 0-1 loss, for testing. We also use the Spezzaferri design criterion function for model discrimination, as an alternative criterion function for testing. By insisting that all observations are at least a minimum distance apart in order to ensure rough independence, we find the optimal design for all three problems. We ascertain the optimal designs by writing the design criterion functions as functions of the design measure, rather than of the designs themselves. We then use the geometric form of the design measure space and the concavity of the criterion function to find the optimal design measure. There is a straightforward correspondence between the set of design measures and the set of designs. Our approach is similar in spirit, although rather different in detail, from that introduced by Kiefer. In addition, we consider design for estimation of the changepoint itself, and optimal designs for the multipath changepoint problem. We demonstrate why the former problem most likely has a prior-dependent solution while the latter problems, in their most general settings, are complicated by the lack of concavity of the design criterion function.</description><creator>Atherton, Juli.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Optimal designs (Statistics)</subject><subject>Bayesian statistical decision theory.</subject><title>Bayesian optimal design for changepoint problems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Juli Atherton, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765375323.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fd450</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064990s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A model study for the synthesis of the fungal metabolites phomoidride A and B is presented. Building on previous studies from our group, the carbocyclic core of these molecules was constructed using a [6+4] cycloaddition between tropone 41 and the silyl enol ether of 2-cyclopenten-1-one. Efforts to install the C-17 phomoidride sidechain on substrates derived from this carbocycle met with limited success. This led us to revise our strategy by employing the novel 5-substituted cyclopentadiene 118. In contrast to the known instability of 5 substituted cyclopentadienes towards [1,5] hydrogen shifts, the 2-silyloxy moiety of 118 imparted remarkable thermal stability on the diene. A practical method was developed for the multigram-scale synthesis of cyclopentenone 132, a useful synthon and precursor to 118. Diene 118 underwent smooth [6+4] cycloaddition with tropone 41 at 23°C to give 133 in 51-54% yield.* Attempts to install the C-17 stereocenter of the phomoidrides through hydroboration of alkene 120 were thwarted by low yields. Remarkably, significant amounts of Markovnikoff products (9-23%) were isolated after the hydroboration of 120 and related alkenes with BH3·DMS. We undertook a series of DFT studies (B3LYP16-31G*) to understand the origins of reduced anti-Markovnikoff selectivity. These studies suggested that the bridging ketones and remote diene both contributed to this phenomenon. These studies led us to synthesize carbocycle 158. In line with predictions, hydroboration of saturated diketone 158 was completely selective for the anti-Markovnikoff product.* The C-17 sidechain of the phomoidrides was successfully extended through a conjugate addition reaction. Compound 189, which contains the correct stereochemistry of the C-9 and C-17 sidechains, represents our furthest progress to date on the molecules.* *Please refer to dissertation for diagrams.</description><creator>Ashenhurst, James Alexander.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Synthetic studies on the phomoidrides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© James Alexander Ashenhurst, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3659295.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064990s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jj72z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sulfuric acid hydrolysis of native cellulose fibers produces stable suspensions of cellulose nanocrystals. Within a specific concentration range, the suspensions spontaneously form an anisotropic chiral nematic liquid crystal phase. This thesis examines the phase separation behaviour of these suspensions, alone and in the presence of added macromolecules. Initially, the effect of hydrolysis conditions on the nanocrystal and phase separation properties for hydrolyzed softwood pulp were investigated and compared to suspensions prepared from hardwood pulp. The macromolecules studied, blue dextrans of varying molecular weights and dye ligand densities, were synthesized and characterized with a number of techniques. The polyelectrolytic nature of these macromolecules was found to strongly influence their physico-chemical properties. Added blue dextran causes separation of an isotropic phase from highly concentrated, completely anisotropic suspensions. The observed phase separation was found to be associated with the charged dye molecules attached to the dextran. The partitioning behaviour of blue dextrans in biphasic aqueous suspensions of native cellulose nanocrystals was also studied with regard to the effect of total concentration of blue dextran, degree of dye substitution and dextran molecular weight on the blue dextran partition coefficient. Electrostatic and entropic contributions to the partition coefficient of blue dextran were discussed. Triphase isotropic-isotropic-nematic (I1--I 2--N) equilibria are observed in suspensions containing both neutral dextrans and polyelectrolytic blue dextrans of varying molecular weight. Based on these results, phase diagrams for cellulose nanocrystal suspensions with different combinations of dextran and blue dextran are presented.</description><creator>Beck, Stephanie Christine.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Cellulose.</subject><subject>Suspensions (Chemistry)</subject><subject>Nanocrystals.</subject><subject>Nanofluids.</subject><subject>Dextran.</subject><title>Phase separation phenomena in cellulose nanocrystal suspensions containing dextran-dye derivatives</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Stephanie Christine Beck, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hh50c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jj72z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wh719</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation seeks to expand our understanding of variation in foreign policy. Although we have a series of large, extant literatures dealing with the sources of foreign policy, there has been less attention paid over the last decade to understanding why states change their behavior. At the same time, the thesis argues that foreign policy change is best understood as a result of the role of individual decision-makers and the role that emotion plays in their foreign policy calculations. Foreign policy depends on the decisions made by individual leaders. The type of individual thus determines the specific policy. Here individuals are categorized as ideological or adaptable. Ideological individuals are more rigid in their belief structures, are more likely to select policies that fit with their extant understandings of the world and the position of their state in it, and more likely to rely on the emotional or affective appeal an object or issue holds for them. Adaptable leaders are more flexible, not tied to specific ideologies or reliant on emotion to guide their thinking, and thus more likely to choose or learn ideas that best respond to changing environmental conditions. At the same time, how a state's decision-making institutions are structured tells us how likely it is that an individual's own predilections matter. In polities where decision-making is centralized (e.g., in the office of the prime minister), individuals have greater leeway to put their ideas (whether based on their ideological outlooks or shifting environmental circumstances) into practice, while in de-centralized polities other actors constrain the leader from autonomous decision-making. In such cases, it is likely that an individual's ideas will conform to those of the constraining actors. Finally, the role of ideas is taken into consideration, as the dominant national ideas about foreign policy regarding a specific issue-area help us better understand the context in which individuals make (or change) foreign policy. This model is tested against alternate explanations---systemic imperatives, Constructivism, public opinion, poliheuristic theory, and prospect theory---in two case studies: the Israeli decision to pursue and sign the 1993 Oslo Accords, and the 2002 decision by the Islamist government in Turkey to actively lobby for membership in the European Union. Both foreign policies represent significant variation, and both provide important theoretical and empirical puzzles for scholars.</description><creator>Sasley, Brent E.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Israel -- Foreign relations.</subject><subject>Turkey -- Foreign relations.</subject><subject>International relations.</subject><title>Individuals and the significance of affect : foreign policy variation in the Middle East</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Brent E. Sasley, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322j89g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wh719</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483p415</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'identification des facteurs predictifs de la reunification familiale des adolescents places represente un prealable a une pratique plus efficace. Cette etude exploratoire consiste en une analyse des dossiers de 102 adolescents places dans une ressource de readaptation du CJM-IU. L'echantillon est compose de deux groupes: un groupe d'adolescents reunifies (n=51) et un groupe d'adolescents non reunifies (n=51). Elle poursuit trois objectifs: definir le portrait des adolescents; explorer et identifier les facteurs associes a la reunification familiale; elaborer un modele de facteurs qui predit la reunification familiale d'un adolescent. En concordance avec la litterature et le cadre ecosystemique de l'etude, cinq categories de facteurs sont analysees: les facteurs lies a l'adolescent, aux parents, a la famille et a l'environnement, a l'intervention et a l'histoire et aux conditions de placement. Les resultats demontrent que c'est davantage au plan des facteurs lies a l'intervention, a l'histoire et aux conditions de placement que des differences entre les adolescents reunifies et les adolescents non reunifies s'observent. Les analyses de regression logistique ont conduit a l'elaboration de deux modeles de prediction de la reunification familiale. Le premier modele revele une combinaison de cinq facteurs: la duree du placement, la possibilite de sortie dans le milieu familial, le nombre d'episodes de placement, l'origine ethnoculturelle et la presence d'un suivi concurrent ou consecutif en LPJ et LJC. Ce modele comporte une limite puisqu'il considere seulement les facteurs sans donnee manquante. Le second modele, elabore a partir de tous les facteurs, revele une configuration de trois facteurs: l'implication parentale, l'origine ethnoculturelle et l'ambivalence de la mere. Au plan de la recherche, ces resultats demontrent la necessite de poursuivre les travaux, en conduisant des etudes longitudinales, employant l'analyse de survie; en interrogeant directement les acteurs impliques; et en explorant la relation d'association entre l'origine ethnoculturelle et la reunification familiale. Au plan de l'intervention, ces resultats soutiennent la necessite de systematiser la pratique de la reunification familiale; consolider le reseau familial du jeune; developper des programmes de reunification familiale; revoir les modalites d'organisation des ressources d'hebergement; et diversifier l'offre de services.</description><creator>Simard, Marie-Claude.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Family social work.</subject><subject>Social work with children.</subject><subject>Foster home care.</subject><title>La réunification familiale des adolescents placés en ressource de réadaptation : étude des facteurs prédictifs</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Marie-Claude Simard, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nd137.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483p415</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38100</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>