<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:51:48Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257g921</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an attempt to analyze Sayyid Qutb's approach to Qur'an exegesis in his Fi Zilal al-Qur'an. It compares the earlier with the later revised editions of the exegesis as it studies change in his thought and Weltanschauung. Qutb believed that the sacred text was a book of guidance and inspiration with immediate relevance to contemporary issues and challenges, giving direction to practical affairs as though it had been revealed specifically for today's problems. It is suggested that social, political, economic, and psychological factors contributed to his interpretation and revision. The thesis explores the degree of the revision made as well as its significance, with special reference to the case of zakat (alms) and riba (usury)-related verses in particular. Although the fundamental stance is basically consistent, i.e. that Islam is a distinct, divinely-ordained system for all aspects of life, it shows that Qutb tended to draw sharp distinctions between those who strove for the establishment of God's law in the world, and those who opposed them. Thus, in his exegetical endeavour, he became inevitably influenced by his socio-political background, and his exegesis was different from other contemporary ones, because it expressed the views of an activist advocate of social, political and religious reform, even though his thought was at times vague and idealistic.</description><creator>Syahnan, Mhd.</creator><contributor>Boullata, Issa J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Quṭb, Sayyid, 1903-1966. Fī ẓilāl al-Qurʾān.</subject><title>A study of Sayyid Quṭb's Qurʾān exegesis in earlier and later editions of his Fī ẓilāl al-Qurʾān with specific reference to selected themes /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t553.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257g921</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10ws31b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The last works of Jane Austen and Barbara Pym, written while each was knowingly dying, both continue and transform a discourse of illness and cure traceable through their canon. Illness figures both literally and metaphorically in their narratives; in Austen as failures in wholeness and in Pym as failures in love. After undergoing the metaphorically medical treatments of purging and vivifying in Austen and inoculating in Pym, their female protagonists achieve conditions of health and wholeness by closure of the narrative. In the dying works, individual metaphorical illnesses become a general societal condition of fragmentation, and cure becomes more elusive. The shared use of a village undergoing profound change reflects each writer's own bodily transformation as certain death approaches, and the restoration of health to the village-as-body becomes one of achieving balance or homeostasis. This is effected in the narrative by the hinted-at curative powers of nature in Sanditon and of restored faith in A Few Green Leaves. On a theoretical level, both texts reflect their narratives of dis-ease and cure. Pym's last text remained unpublished before her death and therefore "ill" because not functioning, but second opinions and faith in her reputation confirmed its public health. Austen's Sanditon as a fragment embodies its own discourse of dis-ease, or failure of wholeness, and requires a curative act on the part of the reader to restore it to some sense of ideal wholeness or health.</description><creator>Staunton, S. Jane.</creator><contributor>Conway, C. Abbott (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Diseases in literature.</subject><subject>Pym, Barbara. Few green leaves.</subject><subject>Austen, Jane, 1775-1817. Sanditon.</subject><title>"Dying, in other words" : discourses of dis-ease and cure in the last works of Jane Austen and Barbara Pym</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032492d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws31b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p665x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the cholera epidemic in Montreal during the summer of 1832, focusing on the Montreal Board of Health, the public health regulations, medical involvement on the Board, and the voluntary movement. Using newspapers, judicial documents, and correspondence, it seeks to re-examine the epidemic to further the understanding of the modernization of the Canadian state in the area of public health. Many of the histories concerning the modernization of the Lower Canadian state have focussed on the 1837 rebellions as a breaking point between the 'old' state and the 'modern' state. If modernization can be equated with the process of increased state influence on society, then the 1832 epidemic provided an opportunity for the government to become more involved in the social regulation of individual lives. And the process was not solely influenced by the 'state,' as citizen committees played a role during the epidemic. Nor must Lower Canada be seen in a vacuum, as the shifts that occurred in Montreal during the epidemic coincided with those taking place in London, Paris and New York. An analysis of the state during the epidemic suggests its growing significance in individual lives, particularly those of the poor. The appearance of cholera hospitals, the use and enforcement of public health regulations by a board of health, and the social assistance to the immigrants, orphans, and widows illustrate this modernizing state.</description><creator>Sendzik, Walter.</creator><contributor>Young, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Epidemics -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Cholera -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Public health -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><title>The 1832 Montreal cholera epidemic : a study in state formation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb296.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p665x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tb42x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>According to Locke and Latham (1990), goal-setting is a powerful motivationa! tool which captivates the individual's attention and sense of effort in pooling all available resources to accomplish a task with accrued determination. Goal-setting has been used successfully in sports and physical activities (Kyllo &amp; Landers, 1995). Positive results have also been realized with low achievers in academic tasks (Bandura &amp; Schunk, 1981). The purpose of this investigation was to test the effects of goal-setting on basketball free throwing with normally achieving (NA) boys and girls, and with children having learning disabilities (LD), ages 9-13 years. This study also tested the relationship between Perceived Physical Self-Competence (Harter, 1978b) and performance. Results indicated that the children with LD in the goal-setting group outperformed the control group. However, goal-setting failed to differentiate the performances of NA children. No correlation was established between Perceived Physical Self-competence and the performance of these children. Methodological key points are discussed and suggestions are given for future research with goal-setting and children. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Savoie, Nicole A.</creator><contributor>Reid, Greg (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Physical education for children with disabilities.</subject><subject>Learning disabled children.</subject><title>Goal setting in the acquisition of a motor skill with children who have learning disabilities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm24q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb42x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c2528</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a comparative study of the educational reforms initiated by the Aligarh and Muhammadiyah movements in India and Indonesia respectively. It covers three main points: Ahmad Khan's and Ahmad Dahlan's educational philosophy; the educational system of the Muhammadan Anglo-Oriental College (MAOC) and Muhammadiyah schools; and the impact of the educational reforms of the two movements to Muslim education in general in the two countries. As will be explained in this thesis, Ahmad Khan and Ahmad Dahlan were deeply concerned with economic and social problems faced by the Muslims due to colonial policies. Both scholars came to the conviction that education was one of the most important ways to solve those problems. The two scholars, therefore, each contrived to design a new system of education for Muslims, which would produce graduates capable of meeting the new demands of the changing socio-political context while retaining their faith. Their ideas were eventually realized in the establishment of the MAOC and the Muhammadiyah schools, respectively. Even though these two institutions were unable to satisfy all Muslim aspirations, they succeeded in making Muslims in India and Indonesia aware of the need for pragmatic education, which was to contribute to the empowerment of Muslims in the colonial era.</description><creator>Ruswan, 1968-</creator><contributor>Alvi, Sajida S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Islamic education -- Indonesia -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Muhammadiyah (Organization)</subject><subject>Aligarh movement.</subject><subject>Islamic education -- India -- History -- 19th century.</subject><title>Colonial experience and muslim educational reforms : a comparison of the Aligarh and the Muhammadiyah movements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161816j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c2528</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bk10n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fictional characters who mistake reality for fiction can be considered as parodies, beings invented by the author to denounce the illusions of which they are victims. But this viewpoint is not valid if the novels in which those "mistaken readers" exist suggest, to the contrary, that reality is problematic; it is therefore impossible to judge the characters without "afterthoughts", since these characters, in a way, are pointing to the fact that the reality they live in is "unreal". Such is the case with Madame Bovary and Don Quijote. These two novels, as a result of different "techniques", essentially tell their readers to be suspicious about what is "true" and what is "false". These are novels without a strong authorial voice, novels that speak more about how characters conceive reality than about reality itself, which remains in both cases a complete mystery. This viewpoint can be extended into a definition of the novel, in terms of what it says (or doesn't say) about the world. And in fact, a novel doesn't say anything about the world, at least not directly. It could be described as "a machine" made from what the characters say. Obviously, such a machine cannot be taken too seriously, since nobody (that is to say no real person) is actually saying what is being said in its pages. But at the same time, by refusing to show the fictional world in itself, (by always showing it through the eyes of fictional characters), the novelist reminds his reader that the real world itself is inescapably ambiguous.</description><creator>Roy, Yannick.</creator><contributor>Ricard, Francois (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Reality in literature.</subject><subject>Cervantes Saavedra, Miguel de, 1547-1616. Don Quixote.</subject><subject>Flaubert, Gustave, 1821-1880. Madame Bovary.</subject><title>Les mauvais lecteurs dans le roman /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dx38w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bk10n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386m35c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of the present study was to assess whether girls with LD were at a greater risk for self-reported depressive symptomatology compared to both boys with LD and girls without LD. Differences in the pattern of responses of girls with LD and boys with LD on the Children's Depression Inventory (CDI) were also evaluated. In order to identify a learning disability, the short-form of the Weschler Intelligence Scale for Children and the Wide Range Achievement Test were administered to 204 subjects. Results revealed that girls with LD demonstrated an increased risk for depressive symptomatology as compared to girls without LD. Boys, on the other hand, regardless of a learning disability, manifested a comparable rate of depressive symptomatology. It appears that having a learning disability increases girls' propensity towards depression. Finally, differences in the pattern of responses were found for girls and boys with and without LD.</description><creator>Ross, Shana.</creator><contributor>Heath, N. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Sex differences (Psychology) in children.</subject><subject>Depression in children.</subject><subject>Learning disabled children.</subject><title>Gender differences in the prevalence and expression of depression in children with and without learning disabilities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r61r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m35c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322g32x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent criticism has cast the suburban playhouses of Early Modern London as marginalised institutions, in at least a topographic if not a symbolic sense. This thesis will contend that marginality is a relative term, and that for the inhabitants of the suburb, of Clerkenwell, the salient social function of the Red Bull theatre was not to serve the City as a site for licence, but to provide a neighbourhood space in which bonds of community could be formed. Arguing that theatres were built in particular locations not just to escape City prohibitions, but to draw on proximate audiences, I provide a brief history of Clerkenwell and place the Red Bull in its local context. By figuring the Red Bull, both in terms of its standard repertoire and its audience, as a prototypical "community theatre," I develop a sociology of dramatic production which understands this Early Modern theatre as a crucial nexus of local solidarity.</description><creator>Richards, Keith Owen.</creator><contributor>Bristol, Michael D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Clerkenwell (London, England) -- History.</subject><subject>Red Bull Theatre (London, England)</subject><subject>Theater -- England -- London -- History.</subject><title>The Red Bull as community theatre in Clerkenwell /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c947b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g32x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73px95x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Definitions and concepts of learning in the workplace have evolved considerably in the last two decades in response to significant changes impacting most workplace environments throughout the industrialized world. Comprehensive definitions of learning at work go beyond an emphasis on improving performance to consider the workplace as a social environment which can be structured to enhance or thwart adult learning and development. A wider and more socially relevant range of approaches to workplace learning are emerging. By focusing on learning as a process rather than a product, this study attempts to gain a deeper understanding of the daily informal learning experiences among a group of clerical and secretarial workers. Through interviews and a qualitative research approach it examines the meanings these women attribute to their workplace learning experiences. It explores some of the ways in which women's unique learning capabilities interface with a particular environment.</description><creator>Rapaport, Irene.</creator><contributor>Jackson, Nancy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Adult education of women.</subject><subject>Adult learning.</subject><title>Women's informal learning experiences at work : perspectives of support staff in an educational institution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569633g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73px95x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zd11d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The case study examines the process of change undergone by the McGill Institute for Learning in Retirement (McGill ILR), a volunteered organization. ILRs have emerged across North America in the past 15 years and their success is attributed to the congenial participatory learning environment and the fact that members volunteer to administer the program activities in collaboration with a host university. Four years after it was founded, leaders sensed the need to evaluate McGill ILR's strengths and weaknesses. Under the aegis of McGill Centre for Continuing Education, a Planning Committee designed and implemented an organizational self-assessment to provide recommendations for change and ensure sustainability. The study revealed: (a) that this community of older adults taught themselves how to respond to change effectively and (b) that the overarching characteristics of an ILR, together with a spirit of dialogue, provided an organizational structure which helped volunteers absorb change.</description><creator>Rafman, Carolynn.</creator><contributor>Lusthaus, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Organizational change -- Case studies.</subject><subject>McGill University. McGill Institute for Learning in Retirement.</subject><title>McGill Institute for Learning in Retirement : a case study of change in a volunteer-led organization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r34f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd11d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676x68p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Towards the end of the fifteenth century in Italy an upwardly mobile, morally questionable, and highly erudite woman appeared on the social and literary circuit: the courtesan. Technically a prostitute, she rose above her often dubious beginnings to bask in the prestige accorded to society's elite. Although revered by some, her blatant transgression of traditional gender roles and class hierarchies offended many others. The writings of her detractors attempted to lower the courtesan's status to that of a common prostitute, by ridiculing her intellectual achievements and by depicting her as unclean and diseased. This thesis, which focuses on sixteenth-century Venice, will examine six works criticizing courtesans, and demonstrate what each work reveals about the dynamics of power in sixteenth-century gender and power relations, as they manifested themselves in the sexual arena.</description><creator>Pesuit, Margaret.</creator><contributor>Kroha, Lucienne, Paula Clarke (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Courtesans -- Italy -- Venice -- History -- 16th century.</subject><subject>Courtesans in literature.</subject><title>Representations of the courtesan in sixteenth-century Venice : sex, class, and power</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j67315921.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676x68p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qn992</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Elizabeth Jane Gardner (1837-1922) was an American artist who lived in Paris from 1864-1922. She was the most frequently represented woman artist of any nationality at the Paris Salon in the late nineteenth century, and the only American woman to have ever won a medal (1887). In 1896, she married William Bouguereau, the major academic painter of the time. Yet in spite of these distinctions, Elizabeth Gardner has received surprisingly little scholarly attention. This thesis is a biographical and analytical study of the expatriate artist, based on her unpublished letters in the Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C. Though the focus is primarily on her years as a practicing artist in Paris (1864 to 1896), attention is also given to her early and late years, and to the collaborative nature of her relationship with Bouguereau. A chronology of the artist, as well as inventories of her paintings and letters are also included.</description><creator>Pearo, Charles.</creator><contributor>Kiefer, Carol Solomon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Gardner, Elizabeth Jane, 1837-1922.</subject><title>Elizabeth Jane Gardner : her life, her work, her letters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr52j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn992</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gf936</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In a world where nationalist movements are on the rise with the potential to contest state legitimacy, the study of nationalism both as a political phenomenon and as an academic topic becomes more salient. This study attempts to explain the causes of nationalism, as well as the conditions that contribute to its militarization. It advances working definitions of the concepts of ethnic groups, nations and nationalism, and identifies the differences between ethnic and national politics. The emergence of nationalism is analyzed through a model. which aims to present a causal relationship between nation, nationalism and militarized crisis. The derived propositions and hypotheses are tested on the Nagorno-Karabagh case, an irredentist conflict in Transcaucasia that has developed into a militarized crisis and has escalated to war.</description><creator>Papazian, Lalig.</creator><contributor>Brecher, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Armenia (Republic) -- Relations -- Azerbaijan.</subject><subject>Nagorno-Karabakh Conflict, 1988-1994.</subject><subject>Azerbaijan -- Relations -- Armenia (Republic)</subject><subject>Nationalism.</subject><title>Nationalism and militarized crisis : the case of Nagorno-Karabagh</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967571g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gf936</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913r79x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Research conducted with Montreal schizophrenics who frequent alternative groups for the mentally ill was aimed at exploring their strategies of identity reconstitution. Applying Paul Ricoeur's concept of the "narrative identity" and its emphasis on the recollection, interpretation, and narrations of events, the content of schizophrenics' life narratives was analyzed to establish the manner in which identity and experience were fashioned, and what role social and cultural elements played in this process of transformation. The results of this research indicate that schizophrenics who try to position themselves anew frequently tend to reject biomedical meanings and definitions as a privileged frame of reference. Instead of the biomedical paradigm and its usually negative connotations, explanations of supernatural and autobiographical origins are preferred. Drawing on our culture's diverse references in some kind of unique-amalgamation of meaning frames, highly individualized and distinctive identities are constructed. These identities, although unusual or 'abnormal' when looked at from the point of view of mainstream society, often constitute significant steps in the personal growth and well being of people who suffer from schizophrenia.</description><creator>Mittmannsgruber, Ingrid.</creator><contributor>Corin, Ellen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Identity (Psychology)</subject><subject>Schizophrenics.</subject><title>From other to self : the narrative articulation of identity by recovering schizophrenics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333432j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r79x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924d67r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a comparative study between Michelangelo Buonarroti's ceiling frescoes in the Sistine Chapel and John Milton's Paradise Lost. The parallels discussed arise out of the Renaissance humanism shared by both of these artists and expressed their works of art. Beginning with Michelangelo, I will establish the relation of Renaissance humanism to the Sistine Chapel ceiling decoration and define Michelangelo's specific conception of the theories associated with this movement. Subsequently, the same critical approach will be applied to Milton's Paradise Lost, which will be revealed to be notably humanistic despite its positioning at the end of the Renaissance in a Protestant country. After exploring the individual works of Michelangelo and Milton separately, I will then consider the views shared by these two in their treatments of the myth of the Fall of humanity: both artists believe in the ultimate dignity and freedom of humankind, and portray both Adam and Eve as free and autonomous individuals; the Sistine ceiling frescoes and Paradise Lost likewise emphasize the regenerative rather than the damning aspect of the Fall of humanity, expressing the humanistic insistence on the value of human experience; finally, the humanistic notion that art, both literary and visual, instructs its audience while entertaining it, provides the governing artistic theory behind the works of both Michelangelo and Milton. Although the commonalities between Michelangelo's Sistine ceiling and Milton's Paradise Lost are extensive, I will not attempt to claim that Milton was specifically influenced by Michelangelo's frescoes. However, my study will reveal the potential for interart analogies to provide greater insight into the individual works of art and literature being analysed.</description><creator>McConomy, Erin Elizabeth.</creator><contributor>Borris, Kenneth (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Humanism in art.</subject><subject>Michelangelo Buonarroti, 1475-1564 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Cappella Sistina (Vatican Palace, Vatican City)</subject><subject>Humanism in literature.</subject><subject>Milton, John, 1608-1674. Paradise lost.</subject><title>Renaissance humanism in Michelangelo's Sistine Chapel and Milton's Paradise Lost</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f7936.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d67r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55md79g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although many historians consider Joseph II's campaign of 1788 against the Ottoman Turks a failure, no one has yet provided a thorough account of it. This study attempts to put something into the void. Based mostly on original sources found in the Kriegsarchiv (War Archives) in Vienna, it examines the campaign from the perspective of Joseph II. The first chapter tries to explain how Joseph became involved in a conflict with the Porte. The second chapter covers the period of February-July 1788, when Joseph postponed his offensive on Belgrade until the fall and waited in Zemun on the defensive. The third chapter begins with the Ottoman advance into the Banat of Timisoara in early August 1788 and ends with the Habsburg army's retreat to winter quarters in November. Despite failing to take Belgrade, the Habsburg army captured strategically important positions for the campaign of 1789. The difficulties encountered cannot be blamed solely on Joseph's poor generalship. Other factors, such as insufficient Russian assistance, a difficult climate and terrain and a surprisingly strong Ottoman effort, must also be considered.</description><creator>Mayer, Matthew Z.</creator><contributor>Longworth, P. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Austria -- History -- Joseph II, 1780-1790.</subject><subject>Austro-Turkish War, 1788-1790 -- Campaigns</subject><subject>Joseph II, Holy Roman Emperor, 1741-1790.</subject><title>Joseph II and the campaign of 1788 against the Ottoman Turks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wh99f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55md79g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fk048</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this thesis is to analyze the topoi found in various writings on the Indian subcontinent, which depict Muslim mystics, the Sufis, as responsible for the conversion, forced or peaceful, of non-Muslim Indians to Islam. Our analysis of various historiographical traditions produced in the Subcontinent between the eleventh and the twentieth centuries, will show that this image of Sufis qua missionaries is more the result of socio-political considerations (legitimization of imperial order; posthumous images of Sufis in the eyes of different folk audiences, etc.) than the reflection of historical reality. This thesis also examines the processes, most of them indirect, in which Sufis were involved and which on the long run led to the acculturation and to the Islamization of certain non-Muslim groups, thus opening the way for the birth and then consolidation of a Muslim identity.</description><creator>Massoud, Sami, 1962-</creator><contributor>Alvi, Sajida (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Muslim converts -- India.</subject><subject>Sufis -- India.</subject><subject>Sufism -- India.</subject><title>Sufis, Sufi ṯuruq̲ and the question of conversion to Islam in India : an assessment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053j08k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fk048</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708z80r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Following the creation of Ikatan Cendekiawan Muslim Indonesia ICMI, Indonesian Muslim Intellectual Association) on December 6, 1990, an event which had shaken the Indonesian political scene, discussion of the relation and affinity between Islam and the state once again came to the fore. The controversy surrounding ICMI's establishment revolved around two basic questions, namely, whether it was a political maneuver by the New Order government, or a true manifestation of the Muslim community's aspirations. The resulting situation prompted a large number of responses from people of various backgrounds. Support, opposition and neutrality towards ICMI arose during its five year existence (1990-1995). These responses took cognizance of the hidden motives behind the New Order's political support of the organization, as well as the government's new appreciation and accommodation of Islam and Muslim demands. The present thesis will thus note, evaluate and analyze these responses in light of the specific context surrounding ICMI's establishment, as well as the numerous analyses extended by various political observers. The thesis will also seek to explain why ICMI became a phenomenon welcomed by most Indonesian Muslims.</description><creator>Mardatillah, Fuadi.</creator><contributor>Federspiel, Howard M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Islam and state -- Indonesia.</subject><subject>ICMI (Organization)</subject><subject>Intellectuals -- Indonesia -- Societies, etc.</subject><title>Intellectual responses to the establishment of Ikatan Cendekiawan Muslim Indonesia (ICMI), 1990-1995</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc44c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z80r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hm16v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, the author investigates the link between the process of economic and political integration within the European Union and the phenomenon of nationalist assertion. By examining the cases of Flanders and Scotland, it is argued that increased nationalism is a normal and predictable outcome of the process of integration in general, and of the EU more specifically. By analysing four factors--economic incorporation, system-wide policies, systems of transfer payments, and political isolation--the author finds two trends within the nationalist movements. The first is that the nationalist groups seek to acquire several of the powers currently held by the states of which they are currently part, Belgium and the United Kingdom respectively. The second is that these sub-state groups see themselves as part of a new order in which states are losing their significance. Neither of the theories associated with these observations on their own, however, satisfactorily explains the link between integration and increased nationalist assertion in the nationalist movements studied. The conclusion is that the nationalist groups accept the concept of an authority above the level of the state, nation, or region, but emphasise the necessity of a large degree of regional autonomy and a real voice for these regions in the decision-making process of this authority. Since the European Union is and always has been an exclusive club of member states, nationalist groups consider, within the framework of current institutional arrangements, that full statehood may be the only way to achieve their goals.</description><creator>Maertens, Marco.</creator><contributor>Brawley, Mark R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>European Union -- Scotland.</subject><subject>European Union -- Flanders.</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Flanders.</subject><subject>Europe -- Economic integration.</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Scotland.</subject><subject>European Union.</subject><title>European integration and sub-state nationalism : Flanders, Scotland, and the EU</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838250z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hm16v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz53m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While much has been written on the relationship between Islamic law and customary law in Muslim countries, for the most part, the literature reflects the conflict approach. To date, this methodological framework persists as most Western Islamicists continue to view the encounter between the two legal systems as conflict ridden. This thesis is an attempt to re-evaluate this entrenched paradigm. By utilising the principles of Islamic legal methodology (usul al-fiqh) in conjunction with legal and socio-political approaches, this study seeks to shed new analytical light on the encounter of Islamic law with adat law (customary law) in Indonesia. The two legal systems, it is argued, have a shared existence long pre-dating the intervention of the colonial powers in Indonesian legal affairs, which speaks of accommodation and coexistence. In what is both a syncretic and a purist society, Indonesians have successfully harmonized the two legal traditions such that compromise and derivative solutions, based upon elements from both legal systems, have often been attained. In post-colonial Indonesia, the dialogue between the two sets of laws persists today as the tradition of avoiding conflict in legal resolution continues uninterrupted by the flux in legal policy from colonial to national rule. Family law in particular illustrates the endurance of such a phenomenon in the current period. Three cases--conditional repudiation, common property in marriage and obligatory bequest--are discussed as models of the two substantive legal systems working jointly to construct a new legal entity. The conciliatory exchange between Islamic and customary law in Indonesia refutes therefore the paradigm by which the two legal systems are posited as irreconcilable.</description><creator>Lukito, Ratno.</creator><contributor>Hallaq, Wael B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Adat law -- Indonesia.</subject><subject>Islamic law -- Indonesia.</subject><title>Islamic law and Adat encounter : the experience of Indonesia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn43j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz53m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97ks41v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1972, Italo Calvino published Le citta invisibili, a text which marked a radical departure from "traditional" narrative methods. This study is an analysis of the literary techniques used in the text. It posits Calvino's critical and theoretical evolution as the source of the specific stylistic choices that determine the originality of the work.</description><creator>Ludovico, Roberto.</creator><contributor>Kroha, Lucienne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Calvino, Italo -- Literary style.</subject><subject>Calvino, Italo. Città invisibili.</subject><title>Le città invisibili di Italo Calvino : le "ragioni" dello scrittore</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bk11x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks41v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d6141</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates the theory and practice of song criticism from a primarily literary perspective. It maintains that much contemporary song criticism deals inadequately with the complex relationships between verbal, vocal and musical texts that comprise the three basic elements of the modern song. To justify this claim, and to grasp how the current situation might have arisen, the thesis delves into the history of song and traces its developments. It concludes that modern and classical song differ in ways that the "serious vs. popular" debate do not address: autonomy of authorship, frame of reference, and proper context for interpretation. To remedy this situation, the thesis anatomizes modern song and outlines a "top-down" approach to song criticism with lyrics as the primary frame of reference, supplemented by emotive cues found in the music and vocal performance. Concurrently, the anatomy is put into practice, using examples from the unofficial canon of modern song.</description><creator>Linekin, Kim.</creator><contributor>Gibian, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Popular music -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Music and literature.</subject><title>The modern popular song as a literary art form /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft38d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d6141</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193b92p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an examination of the double motif used by Charles Dickens in A Tale of Two Cities, Great Expectations, and Our Mutual Friend. There is a subtle shift that takes place in these last completed works, from a double motif which is used to prescribe individual behaviour along the lines of domestic or Christian ideology, to one which examines the social and psychological consequences of the individual's submission to such ideological imperatives. In fine, Dickens begins to distance himself from the stock, physical double he had inherited, turning instead to a double that finds its causes and ramifications firmly located in both the social and psychological spheres. This increasing complexity of the double motif is indicative of Dickens' gradually more sophisticated, less stereotypical view of the relationship between the individual and society than that suggested by his famous caricatures or his previous works.</description><creator>Lawrie-Munro, Brian.</creator><contributor>O'Toole, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Doubles in literature.</subject><subject>Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>The double in Dickens' final completed novels /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tr26p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193b92p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b8026</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Constance de Salm (1767-1845) is an unknown French woman author who nevertheless enjoyed much success in her time. The French Revolution of 1789 and the disappointments that it brought in regards to woman's rights incited her to also use her writings to forward women's cause. In this work, we will first introduce this "illustrious unknown writer" through a biography relating the important periods of her life while also drawing a parallel with the literature she wrote during her career. We will then go over those "feminist" writings in order to focus on the major themes.</description><creator>Lauzon, Martine.</creator><contributor>Duquette, Jean-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Salm, Constance de, 1767-1845 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Une moraliste féministe : Constance de Salm</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935494p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b8026</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dx395</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:00:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Can the political eloquence of Louis-Joseph Papineau, one of the great Canadian orators of the nineteenth century, be revived? There are still no significant studies on the logic of argumentation or on the image of a certain representation of the political crisis set by the orations of the Honorable Speaker of the House of Assembly of Lower-Canada. The following thesis focuses on Louis-Joseph Papineau's political discourses of 1830-1837. By the analysis of the representations and the reasonings, of the argumentation, of the rhetorical functions fulfilled by the discourses and also by the analysis of the social vectors at work in these, this document establishes landmarks and proposes a topographical outlook of Papineau's political rhetoric. It seek;s to show the topic organisation and functioning of this rhetoric, in a nineteenth century setting of oratorical and political culture.</description><creator>Larin, Claude.</creator><contributor>Angenot, Marc (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Lamonde, Yvan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Papineau, Louis Joseph, 1786-1871 -- Oratory.</subject><subject>Political oratory -- Québec (Province) -- History -- 19th century.</subject><title>Rhétorique des discours politiques de Louis-Joseph Papineau, 1830- 1837</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c948m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx395</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):50</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>