<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:50:24Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12475" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xm87k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les corrélations entre le comportement du cortex visuel et les habiletés visuelles permettent de comprendre le lien fonctionnel entre l'activité des neurones et le comportement d'un sujet lors du visionnement d'un écran. Ces corrélations sont déduites à travers des courbes ROC représentant les covariances entre les comportements et les neurones (la probabilité de choix et de détection) et ce, en utilisant des filtres avec une fonction de transfert Sinc. Ces filtres capturent efficacement les covariances entre les activités neurologiques et les comportements durant des stimuli constants. Toutefois, il n'est pas optimal d'utiliser ces filtres pour capturer ces corrélations lors de situations réelles et variantes en fonction du temps. Dans cette thèse, nous présentons une technique de filtrage équivalent combinée avec une validation croisée pour améliorer l'estimation de la courbe ROC représentant les covariances entre les comportements et les neurones lors de conditions de stimulus dynamiques. Suite à l'utilisation d'un modèle de déchargement sous forme d'une distribution Poisson, nous démontrons que cette approche maximise l'aire sous la courbe ROC et converge vers la vraie covariance entre les comportements et les neurones. Nous démontrons également que le filtre équivalent combiné à une validation croisée permet de représenter la dynamique des covariances des comportements et des neurones de la région visuelle MT durant la détection de brefs stimuli. Les corrélations temporelles entre les réponses du cortex visuel ont un effet considérable sur la détermination des connections fonctionnelles entre les neurones. Pour être en mesure d'étudier les interactions des corrélations du fonctionnement des neurones, nous avons calculé les valeurs des fonctions de transfert linéaires entre les régions corticales V1 et V2 en utilisant des données collectées à l'aide d'électrodes extracellulaires multiples enregistrées. Le but derrière cette analyse est de comprendre l'effet de l'influx nerveux de V1 sur les neurones V2 en usant de systèmes d'identification linéaires. Une fonction de transfert linéaire (ou fonction « kernel ») est une métrique utile à comprendre la connexion entre deux régions du cortex puisqu'elle quantifie l'intégration temporelle des neurones V1 dans V2. Nous avons employé un modèle de régression à variables multiples pour estimer la combinaison entre les « kernels » V1-V2. Face à l'insertion simultanée d'une multitude de variables V1 dans notre modèle, cette analyse à variables multiple s'est avérée être adéquate; permettant de minimiser le biais dans les « kernels » causés par les activités corrélées entre les neurones V1.Nous avons estimé 25,470 « kernels » à l'état de repos (lorsqu'aucune image n'apparait sur l'écran) et à l'état de stimulus. La qualité a été évaluée dépendamment de la valeur du ratio du signal-bruit de la variance estimée du « kernel » sur la variance du « kernel » brouillé. Les « kernels » considérés de bonne qualité (ayant un ratio signal-bruit supérieur à 1) ont été extraits des données de l'état de repos (4,665) et celles des conditions de stimuli (2,542). Il s'est avéré que ces deux types de données suivent une forme exponentielle avec des constantes de temps égales à 18 et 27 ms respectivement. Donc la convolution des V1 avec le « kernel »  est équivalente à V2. V2 à son tour tend à intégrer les variables V1 dans la fonction exponentielle décroissante dont la moyenne combinée est de 21 ms. Nous pouvons noter que la forme du « kernel » est indépendante de la manifestation du stimulus visuel. Bien que les dynamiques du circuit du cortex peuvent contribuer au « kernel » quantifié, les propriétés intégratives des neurones s'avèrent être des éléments importants de la fonction de transfert linéaire de V1-V2.</description><description>Observed correlations between responses in visual cortex and perceptual performance help draw a functional link between neural activity and visually guided behavior. These correlations are commonly derived with ROC-based neural-behavioral covariances (referred to as choice or detect probability) using boxcar analysis windows. Although boxcar windows capture the covariation between neural activity and behavior during steady-state stimulus presentations, they are not optimized to capture these correlations during realistic time-varying visual inputs. In this thesis, we implemented a matched-filter technique, combined with cross-validation, to improve the estimation of ROC-based neural-behavioral covariance under dynamic stimulus conditions. We show that this approach maximizes the area under the ROC curve and converges to the true neural-behavioral covariance using a Poisson spiking model. We also demonstrate that the matched filter, combined with cross-validation, reveals the dynamics of the neural-behavioral covariations of individual MT neurons during the detection of a brief motion stimulus.Temporal correlations among responses in the visual cortex, on the other hand, have a substantial effect on determining the functional connectivity between neurons. In order to study the interactions of correlations in neural processing, we measured the linear transfer function between cortical areas V1 and V2 using data collected with multi-electrode extracellular recordings. Our aim was to study the effect that a single V1 action potential has on V2 neurons using linear systems identification. A linear transfer function (referred to as a kernel) is a useful metric for understanding functional connectivity between two cortical areas because it quantifies the temporal integration by V2 of V1 inputs. We used a multiple-input single-output regression model to estimate the pairwise V1-V2 kernels. Because of the large number of simultaneous V1 inputs used in our model, this multivariate analysis has the advantage of minimizing the bias in the kernels due to correlated activity between V1 neurons.We estimated 25,470 kernels from the blank and stimulus periods. Kernel quality was evaluated based on a signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) of the estimated kernel variance to the shuffled kernel variance. Putative good kernels (high SNR &gt; 1) were extracted from the blank (4,665) and stimulus (2,542) conditions, and both were found to be exponential in shape with 18 and 27 ms time constants, respectively. Thus, V2 neurons tended to integrate V1 inputs over an exponentially decaying window, with a combined average time constant of 21 ms, that was independent of the occurrence of a visual stimulus. Although the dynamics of cortical circuitry likely contribute to our measured kernels, the integrative properties of single neurons appear to be a dominant component of the V1-V2 linear transfer function.</description><creator>Farah, Kamal</creator><contributor>Mark Coates (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>ROC- and LTF- based estimates of neural- behavioral and neural-neural correlations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f931m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xm87k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kn91t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La thèse de doctorat aborde le thème de la participation sociale des aînés vieillissant avec des incapacités physiques. Trois objectifs étaient visés par la recherche : premièrement, comprendre comment des personnes vieillissant avec des incapacités voient leur participation à la société; deuxièmement, explorer leurs pratiques de participation sociale; troisièmement, comparer ces conceptions et pratiques à la vision de la participation telle que promue dans les politiques sociales adoptées par le Gouvernement du Québec dans le domaine du vieillissement. Le concept central de la recherche est la participation sociale, telle qu'interprétée par les participants de la recherche et par les politiques sociales étudiées. Une double méthodologie de recherche a été développée. D'une part, une étude de cas a permis d'étudier comment des aînés ayant des incapacités physiques perçoivent et vivent leur participation à la société. D'autre part, une analyse critique de contenu a conduit à mieux comprendre comment des politiques québécoises sur le vieillissement utilisent la notion de participation sociale. La mise en relation des résultats de ces deux volets de recherche, respectivement ancrés dans les expériences du groupe d'aînés concernés et les discours d'un agenda politique contemporain, a mené à combler un espace vacant dans la littérature scientifique, à questionner les stéréotypes associés au lien entre participation sociale et incapacités, ainsi qu'à nourrir des réflexions et des approches d'intervention en service social plus sensibles à la diversité des vieillissements.</description><description>This doctoral thesis explores the theme of social participation among seniors aging with disabilities. The research had three objectives: first, understanding how people aging with disabilities see their participation in society; second, exploring their practices of social participation, and; third, comparing the notions and experiences of seniors aging with disabilities with the vision of participation that is adopted by the government of Quebec in the field of aging. A dual research methodology was developed. A case study of a group of seniors engaged in a photonovel project about aging with disabilities allowed the study of how they perceived and lived their participation in society. And a critical content analysis permitted a better understanding of how the concept of social participation is used in Quebec aging policy. The relationship between the results of these two sets of data, one anchored in the experience of a group of seniors, and the other in the discourse of a contemporary political agenda, addresses a gap in the scientific literature by problematizing the stereotypical understanding of the connection between social participation and disability. The conclusions of the thesis nourish reflections and suggest new intervention approaches in social work that are more sensitive to the diversity of aging experiences.</description><creator>Raymond, Émilie</creator><contributor>Jill Hanley (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Amanda Marie Grenier (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Social Sciences - Social Work</subject><title>Les discours et les pratiques de participation sociale d'aînés handicapés : exploration critique d'un carrefour peu fréquenté</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gw97m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kn91t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kt61j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Conseils de détection directe de la matière noire ont été présentés par les DAMA, CoGeNT, et CRESST collaborations, malgré un certain nombre de résultats nuls qui semblent contredire ces allégations. Bien que la norme matière noire indépendante du spin n'est pas capable de concilier la résultats, la matière noire modèles contenant couplages de isospin-violation ont montré des résultats prometteurs dans résolution des problèmes de détection directe de la matière noire. Diffusion inélastique ou dynamique dépendant de la matière noire a également été démontré que aider à atténuer ces tensions. À la lumière des observations XENON100 2012, analyse actualisée de la contamination de l' événement de surface à CoGeNT, la révision de la résolution de l'énergie utilisée par XENON10, et de nouveaux résultats provenant des détecteurs de silicium CDMS-II, nous étudier la mesure dans laquelle indépendante du spin, dépendant du spin, et des modèles combinés de la matière noire isospin-violation sont capables d'expliquer les données de détection directs actuels. De plus, nous explorons l'effet d'une trempe de sodium dépendant de l'énergie facteur $Q_{\rm Na}$ pour le montage des observations DAMA, et de donner une prévision de isospin-violation de XENON1T. En plus de l'analyse habituelle impliquant des parcelles de l'espace de phase, nous étudions un modèle de halo-indépendant de la matière noire dans l'espace des vitesses minimales requises pour une particule de matière noire se disperser hors d'un noyau donné. Pour la première fois, une telle analyse est effectuée pour les modèles de matière noire qui embrassent les deux couplages élastiques et isospin-violation, ainsi que de la matière noire avec des interactions dépendant du dynamique et spin. En ce qui concerne les modèles considérés ici, nos résultats ne soutiennent pas une question d'interprétation sombre de données de détection directe soit dans la norme ou formalismes halo-indépendant.</description><description>Hints of direct detection of dark matter have been presented by the DAMA, CoGeNT, and CRESST collaborations, despite a number of null results that seem to contradict such claims. Although standard spin-independent dark matter is not capable of reconciling the results, dark matter models containing isospin-violating couplings have shown promise in solving the issues surrounding direct detection of dark matter. Inelastic or momentum-dependent scattering dark matter has also been shown to help alleviate these tensions. In light of the 2012 XENON100 observations, updated analysis of surface event contamination at CoGeNT, revision of the energy resolution employed by XENON10, and new results from the CDMS-II silicon detectors, we study the extent to which spin-independent, spin-dependent, and combined models of isospin-violating dark matter are capable of explaining current direct detection data. Moreover, we explore the effect of an energy-dependent sodium quenching factor $Q_{\rm Na}$ for fitting the DAMA observations, and give an isospin-violating prediction for XENON1T. In addition to the usual analysis involving phase space plots, we investigate a halo-independent model of dark matter in the space of minimum velocities required for a dark matter particle to scatter off a given nucleus. For the first time, such an analysis is performed for models of dark matter which embrace both inelastic and isospin-violating couplings, as well as for dark matter with momentum- and spin dependent interactions. With respect to the models considered herein, our results do not support a dark matter interpretation of direct detection data in either the standard or halo-independent formalisms.</description><creator>Whittamore, Zakary</creator><contributor>James M Cline (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Physics - Elementary Particles and High Energy</subject><title>Isospin-violating dark matter and direct detection experiments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676z99w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kt61j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k8428</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Examinant l'évolution des États providences au cours des quatre dernières décennies, cette thèse explore les facteurs qui ont influencé les niveaux de couverture sociale et la standardisation des prestations en France et en Italie. La thèse met particulièrement l'accent sur l'influence des partis politiques et des syndicats sur l'extension d'accès à l'allocation chômage minimum et aux soins de santé. La force de cette comparaison provient du contraste des politiques tant entre les domaines politiques qu'entre les deux pays. Faisant face à un nombre croissant d'individus n'ayant pas accès à des prestations à cause d'un marché du travail de plus en plus segmenté, le cas italien a été marqué par une réforme remarquable d'universalisation du système de santé, avec toutefois un manque persistant d'assistance sociale universelle; tandis qu'en France, une « résidualisation » des systèmes existants dans les deux domaines a prévalu. Combinant une recherche archivistique avec des entretiens approfondis auprès des élites ainsi qu'en épluchant de nombreuses sources secondaires, cette thèse affirme que la variation des réformes susmentionnées est davantage fonction des arrangements institutionnels que fonction d'idéologie partisane. Bien que les partis de gauche aient été les principaux moteurs des réformes, ils n'ont pas toujours su problématiser les lacunes des couvertures sociales, puisque l'extension de prestations universelles implique normalement des compromis fiscaux ou politiques. Dans ce contexte, certaines particularités caractéristiques des États de l'Europe du Sud (comme la centralité de la famille et le clientélisme) ont conditionné l'importance politique des lacunes dans la couverture sociale, autant pour les partis politiques que pour le public. Ensuite, l'opinion publique a également influé sur la probabilité des réformes pendant que les motivations organisationnelles des partis ont joué sur le genre de réformes recherchées.Pour évaluer si les conclusions de la comparaison qualitative par paires peuvent être généralisées, les résultats ont ensuite été testés sur les pays de l'OCDE utilisant une analyse statistique. Cette analyse a fourni l'occasion d'examiner la définition appropriée des variables dépendantes, ainsi que la modélisation correspondante, dans l'analyse comparative des politiques. La thèse soutient que l'analyse de durée offre une façon particulièrement utile de modéliser les changements politiques. Dans l'ensemble, les résultats de l'analyse statistique concordent avec les conclusions tirées de la comparaison des cas français et italien : les niveaux de couverture sociale et la standardisation des prestations dans les États providences de l'OCDE sont fonctions d'une interaction complexe entre les institutions de protection sociale, les préférences publiques ainsi qu'entre les partis politiques et syndicats.</description><description>Examining the evolution of welfare states over the past four decades, this dissertation explores the factors that have impacted coverage levels and benefit standardisation, with a particular emphasis on the role of left-wing parties and unions in reforming access to healthcare and income support for the unemployed in France and Italy. This comparison derives its force from contrasting policy outcomes across both countries and policy domains. In dealing with the growing swaths of individuals incapable of accessing benefits as the labour market became increasingly segmented, the Italian case was marked by dramatic universalising reform in healthcare but a persistent lack of universally available social assistance, while in France residualising transformations within the pre-existing framework prevailed in both sectors. Using a combination of archival research, in-depth elite interviews, and secondary source research, this thesis argues that the aforementioned variation in welfare state reform is less about partisanship than it is about institutional arrangements. While left-wing parties have been the main drivers of reform, they do not consistently problematise gaps in coverage, since the extension of generous benefits to all typically entails fiscal and/or political trade-offs. Within this context, certain characteristic features of Southern European states (such as the centrality of the family and clientelism) condition the political importance of coverage gaps, both for parties and the public. Public opinion then impacts the likelihood of reform, while the organisational incentives of parties structure the type of reform pursued. In order to assess the generalisability of conclusions drawn from the qualitative paired comparisons, the findings are then tested across OECD countries using statistical analysis. The analysis provides an opportunity to consider the proper definition of the dependent variables, and the corresponding modeling strategy, in comparative policy analysis. The thesis argues that duration analysis offers a particularly useful way of modelling policy change. Overall, results provide support for the conclusions drawn from the comparison of France and Italy: coverage levels and benefit standardisation in OECD welfare states are functions of complex interactions between social welfare institutions, public preferences, and political parties and unions. </description><creator>Kevins, Anthony</creator><contributor>Stuart Soroka (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>Filling the gaps: the extension of income support and healthcare in France, Italy, and beyond</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429d57g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k8428</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33s0781</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bien que la littérature ait apporté des informations importantes pour l'étude des réactions des utilisateurs aux technologies de l'information (TI), des lacunes demeurent. En effet, peu de recherches théorisent spécifiquement à propos l'artefact TI pour comprendre son utilisation. En outre, la littérature est dominée par une hypothèse sous-jacente que l'acceptation des TI est favorable alors que la résistance aux TI est défavorable. De même, cette littérature adopte surtout des conceptualisations simplifiées de l'utilisation des TI et n'a pas mis l'accent sur le processus associé à cette utilisation. Cette thèse tente de combler ces lacunes et met en lumière des thèmes importants liés aux réactions des utilisateurs aux TI.Notre premier essai étudie les perceptions des utilisateurs en ce qui concerne les modifications apportées à une TI après son implantation. Bien que ces modifications puissent influencer l'utilisation des TI et ses impacts, elles n'ont guère été étudiées du point de vue de l'utilisateur. Nous proposons et validons une mesure ancrée dans une théorie de l'artefact TI qui évalue ces modifications dépendant de si l'utilisateur estime qu'elles ajoutent de nouvelles fonctionnalités, améliorent les fonctionnalités existantes, suppriment des parties du système, améliorent la compatibilité avec d'autres technologies et /ou améliorent la vitesse et la fiabilité du système. La mesure proposée contribue à l'étude des réactions des utilisateurs aux TI, en mettant l'accent sur l'artefact TI.Notre deuxième essai propose un cadre pour l'étude de l'acceptation et la résistance aux TI ainsi que sur la panoplie de comportements et d'impacts qui leur sont associés. Il met en avant des nuances voilées par le fait que ces variables sont généralement considérées séparément, en faisant abstraction du contexte organisationnel d'utilisation. Nous proposons que ces variables doivent être étudiées en relation avec les objectifs de l'organisation et des directives organisationnelles qui sont destinées à faciliter ces objectifs. En fonction de ces objectifs, nous montrons que la résistance et les dérives par rapport aux directives organisationnelles peuvent parfois profiter à l'organisation. Pareillement, l'acceptation et le respect de ces directives peuvent aussi, parfois, avoir des conséquences néfastes. Nous soulignons également les scénarios selon lesquels les employés et de l'organisation peuvent remettre en question ces directives afin de permettre des effets plus favorables.Le dernier essai propose un concept appelé "enhanced use", qui se réfère aux usages innovants qu'un utilisateur peut faire avec les fonctionnalités d'une TI. Basés sur des données d'entrevue, nous identifions des patterns distincts du "enhanced use" et les façons dont ces patterns sont influencés par la tâche, l'utilisateur et les variables liées au système. Dans l'ensemble, nous constatons qu'à la base du "enhanced use", des différences existent  souvent liées à l'analysabilité de la tâche et au type de système utilisé. Notre analyse montre également que le degré de réflexion engagé pour le "enhanced use" dépend en grande partie de la complexité de la tâche à accomplir et des connaissances utilisées à cet égard. Finalement, notre analyse suggère que le degré d'interdépendance des tâches et le type de système utilisé sont souvent associés aux différents patterns d'adaptation du "enhanced use".En somme, cette thèse contribue à la recherche sur les réactions des utilisateurs de TI. Elle met l'accent sur des thèmes importants liés à l'utilisation des TI, y compris les perceptions des modifications aux TI, les impacts des différents comportements liés aux TI et le processus caractérisant les utilisations innovantes des TI.</description><description>Although the extant literature has brought important insight to the study of individual users' reactions to information technology (IT), some limitations remain. Indeed, few studies theorize specifically about the IT artifact and incorporate these theories in the study of IT use. Also, the literature is dominated by an underlying assumption that acceptance of IT is favorable while resistance to IT is unfavorable. Another limitation is that this literature largely adopts a lean conceptualization of IT use and lacks a focus on the process of IT use (e.g. the process by which individuals make new uses of IT features). This dissertation tries to address these limitations and sheds light on important themes related to users' reactions to IT.Our first essay studies users' perceptions with regards to the modifications to an IT that occur after its implementation. Although these modifications potentially influence IT use and its impacts, they have hardly been studied from the end user's perspective. We propose and validate an artifact-focused measure of perceptions of IT modifications based on whether or not a user considers that the changes add new functionalities, improve existing functionalities, remove parts of the system, improve compatibility with other technologies and/or improve the system's speed and reliability. Our proposed measure contributes to studying users' reactions to IT, by focusing on the IT artifact; it also paves the way for further research on the very important and increasingly pervasive phenomenon of IT evolution.Our second essay proposes a framework that focuses on acceptance and resistance, and investigates the diverse set of IT- related behaviors and impacts that may be associated with them. It uncovers nuances obscured by the fact that these variables are generally considered separately, and in abstraction of the organizational context of use. With the concept of organizational intent, we show that resistance and employees' deviation from organizational IT use mandates sometimes benefit the organization. At the same time, acceptance and compliance with organizational IT use mandates may, at times, have adverse consequences. We also highlight scenarios under which employees and organizations can challenge these mandates to enable more favorable impacts. The last essay is an in-depth study of the process of using IT features in new ways, which we call 'enhanced use'. Based on interview data, we identify distinct patterns of enhanced use and the ways these patterns are influenced by task, user and system-related variables.  We argue that the locus of innovation for enhanced use often differs according to the analyzability of the task and the type of system used. Also, the extent of substantive use involved in enhanced use depends largely on the complexity of the task at hand and on the IT-related knowledge used. Finally, our analysis suggests that the degree of task interdependencies and the type of system used are often associated with different patterns of adaptation for enacting enhanced use. Overall, we contribute a broad sketch of the interplay between the task-, IT- and knowledge-related variables that shape patterns of features adoption, use and extension after an IT is adopted.In sum, this dissertation enriches the research on users' reactions to IT. It focuses on important themes related to IT use including users' perceptions of IT changes, the impacts of different IT-related behaviors and the process of making new uses of IT features.</description><creator>Bagayogo, Fatou</creator><contributor>Liette Lapointe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Business Administration - Management</subject><title>Three essays on users' reactions to information technology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074z291.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s0781</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Desautels Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sx11x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Guanine quadruplexes are non-canonical secondary structures that can form in guanine-rich DNA and are stabilized by monovalent cations present in physiological conditions. Bioinformatics studies have identified putative G-quadruplex forming sequences throughout the human genome, in the telomeres and promoter regions of oncogenes. Small molecules that promote the folding of these G-rich sequences into a G-quadruplex structure can result in biologically relevant phenomena that have profound effects on cancer cell proliferation, generally through telomerase inhibition and suppression of oncogene expression, thereby accomplishing one of the main goals of chemotherapy: to halt tumor growth.G-quadruplex forming sequences vary in their nucleobase composition, which allows for topologically distinct monomeric structures. These varying topologies present a means of targeting one polymorph rather than all, which permits site-specific therapies for small molecules that can discriminate between the structures. To date, both organic and inorganic compounds with varying degrees of efficacy in their targeting of this DNA structure have been reported. From this wealth of empirical data, it has been shown that small molecules can bind to G-quadruplexes most often through end π-stacking, although interaction with the loops and groove environments can be permitted with extended side-chains from a highly aromatic core. Herein, we present efforts made towards the creation of transition metal-based G-quadruplex binders consisting of phenanthroimidazole ligands coordinated to platinum(II) and iridium(III) centers. These complexes are ideally suited for recognition of G-quadruplex motifs due to their electron-poor heteroaromatic nature and inherent positively-charged metal center for optimal π-stacking with the G-tetrad surface. Through the use of molecular modeling, biophysical (circular dichroism, fluorescence intercalator displacement assays, surface plasmon resonance, continuous variation analysis, fluorescence binding assays), biological (telomerase inhibition assays, cell cytotoxicity assays, mRNA levels analysis, western blotting), and electrochemical (cyclic voltammetry, electrogenerated chemiluminescence) techniques, we study the properties of these complexes and their interaction with biologically relevant G-quadruplexes. </description><description>Les quadruplexes de guanine sont des structures secondaires non-canoniques pouvant être trouvées dans des séquences d'ADN riches en guanine. Ces derniers sont stabilisés par des cations monovalents présents dans les conditions physiologiques. Des études bioinformatiques ont permis d'identifier des séquences au sein du génome humain pouvant former des G-quadruplexes, notamment dans les télomères et les régions promotrices de certains oncogènes. Les petites molécules qui promeuvent l'agencement de ces séquences riches en guanine en G-quadruplexes peuvent donner lieu à des phénomènes bouleversant l'équilibre de prolifération cellulaire de par une inhibition de l'enzyme télomérase et une tendance à réduire l'expression d'oncogènes. Ainsi, il serait possible d'atteindre un des principaux objectifs de la chimiothérapie : stopper la croissance d'une tumeur.Les séquences formant des G-quadruplexes diffèrent en terme de composition nucléotidique ce qui leur permet de s'associer en structures monomériques aux topologies variées. Ces différences topologiques représentent un moyen d'agir sur un polymorphe plutôt qu'un autre, ce qui permet la mise en place de thérapies ciblées grâce à l'utilisation de petites molécules capables de discriminer entre les structures. Jusqu'à maintenant, des composés organiques et inorganiques aux degrés de spécificité divers et variés ont été recensés. A partir de cette abondance de données empiriques,  il a été démontré que, le plus souvent, les petites molécules se lient en surface des G-quadruplexes via des interactions aromatiques-aromatiques («π-stacking »), bien que les interactions directes avec les boucles ou les brins de la structure soient possibles dans le cas de molécules possédant de longues chaînes annexes à un cœur hautement aromatique.Nous présentons ici les travaux réalisés visant à la création de composés comportant un métal de transition se liant aux G-quadruplexes. Ceux-ci consistent en des complexes de platine (II) ou d'iridium (III) coordinés à des molécules de phénantroimidazoles. En raison de leur nature hétéroaromatique pauvre en électrons et de leur centre métallique chargé positivement, ils sont conçus pour interagir de façon optimale avec les G-quartets en surface des G-quadruplexes. Grâce à l'utilisation d'outils variés comme la modélisation moléculaire, des techniques biophysiques  (dichroisme circulaire, tests par déplacement d'agents intercalants fluorescents, résonance plasmon de surface, analyse de variations continues, tests par reconnaissance spécifique d'agents fluorescents), biologiques (tests d'inhibition de télomérase, tests de cytotoxicité cellulaire, quantification d'ARN messagers, immunobuvardage de type western), et électrochimiques (voltampérométrie cyclique, électrochimiluminescence), nous étudions les propriétés de ces complexes et leurs interactions avec des G-quadruplexes biologiquement pertinents.</description><creator>Castor, Katherine</creator><contributor>Hanadi Sleiman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Chemistry - General</subject><title>Transition metal complexes as G-quadruplex DNA binders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395wb776.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sx11x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311s70h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thalamus is a heterogeneous brain region involved in sensory processes, movement and cognition. While there is much literature detailing the anatomy and electrophysiological properties of the midline thalamus, there is little data on the functional aspects of this region.  There has recently been an interest in determining how the nucleus reuniens (NRe) of the midline thalamus is involved in cognitive processes, given its anatomical connections with both prefrontal cortex and hippocampus. While a few studies have focused on the NRe's involvement in memory (given its projections to the hippocampus), none have empirically examined whether the structure contributes to higher order, prefrontal-dependent functions. As such, there are two primary objectives of this dissertation. The first is to examine the anatomical organization of the NRe, and the second, to characterize the involvement of the NRe in higher order cognitive functions.Chapter 1 provides a review of the anatomical and functional literature describing the NRe. Traditional tracing studies have identified the NRe as a source of monosynaptic input to both the prefrontal cortex and hippocampus, but none have conclusively identified the NRe as the sole relay of prefrontal-hippocampal communication. In Chapter 2, we describe the use of a transynaptic tracer (pseudorabies virus, strain Bartha) to map the disynaptic connections from the prefrontal cortex to the hippocampus. We found that the NRe of the midline thalamus is one potential relay between the ventral prefrontal cortex and ventral hippocampus. As both of these regions have been implicated in response control and higher order cognitive behaviours, in Chapters 3 and 4 we tested rats with NRe lesions in behavioural tasks which assessed components of executive function. In Chapter 3, we measured the effects of rat NRe lesions in a test of inhibitory control and attention. Rats with NRe lesions displayed a high motivation to retrieve their food reward, and were able to accurately detect brief visual stimuli. In addition, lesions of the NRe resulted in transient impulsive behaviour while simultaneously decreasing compulsive responding. Given these behavioural changes, we further attempted to characterize the involvement of the NRe in prefrontal-dependent functions in Chapter 4. In a test of attention and working memory, we found that rats with NRe lesions were superior in their ability to attend to visual stimuli, as well as inhibit themselves from responding prior to the onset of the stimuli. However, the NRe-lesioned animals were initially unable to perform the working memory component of the task. This deficit was also seen during the acquisition of a spatial working memory task, but did not persist in subsequent sessions of testing. Rats with NRe lesions were faster and more accurately able to perform a discrimination task, and did not have difficulty with adapting to changes in the contingencies of the task. Unlike the previous experiments, the NRe lesion had no effect on behaviours assessed during a test of decision making.These findings are summarized in Chapter 5, in which the implications of the experimental data are discussed. While we have confirmed that the NRe is indeed a major thalamic link between the prefrontal cortex and hippocampus, we have also identified the subdivisions of the regions to which it connects. Furthermore, our data has extended the available behavioural literature regarding the function of the NRe, and how it is involved in higher order cognitive processes. We conclude that the NRe is clearly involved in a range of complex and prefrontal-dependent behaviours, proposing that this thalamic region is integral to executive function from both an anatomical and functional perspective.</description><description>Le thalamus est une région hétérogène du cerveau impliquée dans les processus sensoriels, cognitifs ainsi que locomoteurs. Alors que la litterature détaillant l'anatomie et les propriétés électophysiologiques des noyaux thalamiques médians abonde, il existe peu de données décrivant son aspect fonctionnel. Considérant les connections anatomiques du noyau réuniens (NRe) du thamalus médian au cortex préfrontal et à l'hippocampe, de plus en plus de recherches se sont penchées sur son rôle dans les processus cognitifs. Alors que quelques études se sont penchées sur le rôle du NRe dans la mémoire (puisqu'il projette à l'hippocampe), aucune n'avait empiriquement examinée si le NRe contribuait aux fonctions cognitives supérieures dépendantes du cortex préfrontal (FCS). Ainsi, cette thèse se penchera sur deux aspects principaux du NRe. D'abord, l'organisation anatomique du NRe sera examinée, puis, son implication dans les FCS sera caractérisée. Le chapitre 1 fournira une révue de la littérature décrivant l'anatomie et les fonctions du NRe. Les études de traçage traditionnelles ont identifié le NRe comme fournissant une entrée monosynaptique à la fois au cortex préfontal et à l'hippocampe. Cependant, aucune étude n'a encore identifié le NRe comme un relais unique de la communication prefonto-hippocampal. Le chapitre 2 décrit l'utilisation d'un traceur transynaptique (l'herpèsvirus Bartha) afin de cartographier les connections disynpatiques partant du cortex préfontal à l'hippocampe. Les résultats présentés dans cette thèse montre que le NRe est un relais potentiel entre le cortex préfontal ventral et l'hippocampe ventral. Comme ces deux régions sont impliquées dans le contrôle de la réponse et les fonctions cognitives supérieures, les chapitre 3 et 4 traiteront des perfomances de rats ayant subis une lésion du NRe à des tâches comportementales évaluant les fonctions exécutives.Le chapitre 3 expose les effets d'une lésion du NRe chez le rat dans un test de contrôle de l'inhibition et d'attention. Les rats avec une lésion du NRe montrent une motivation accentuée pour obtenir la nourriture et démontre leur capacité à détecter précisément des stimuli visuels brefs. De plus, la lésion du NRe provoqua l'apparition de comportement impulsifs transitoires en plus de diminuer les réponses compulsives. Étant donné ces changements comportementaux, le rôle du NRe dans les FCS est caractérisé davantage au chapitre 4.  Dans un test évaluant l'attention et la mémoire de travail, il a été démontré que les rats avec une lésion du NRe montraient une capacité supérieure à suivre les stimuli visuels ainsi qu'à inhiber leurs réponses avant l'apparition de ces stimuli. Cependant, les animaux ayant subi une lésion du NRe étaient initialement incapable de compléter la composante de la tâche impliquant la mémoire de travail.  Ce déficit était aussi présent durant l'apprentissage de la tâche requérant la mémoire spatiale de travail mais a fini par s'estomper au fil des sessions subséquentes. Les rats avec une lésion du NRe étaient plus rapides à compléter une tâche de discrimination avec une plus grande précision et n'ont pas eu de difficulté à s'adapter aux changements de contingences de la tâche. Contrairement aux résultats précédents, la lésion du NRe n'a pas affecté le comportement tel qu'évalué durant une tâche de prise de décision.L'implication des ces résultats expérimentaux est discutée au chapitre 5. Il a été non seulement confirmé que le NRe est effectivement un lien majeur entre le cortex préfontal et l'hippocampe mais ces résultats identifient aussi avec une plus grande précision les régions où ils se connectent. De plus, ces données enrichissent la littérature comportementale sur le rôle du NRe et son implication dans les FCS. En conclusion, le NRe est clairement impliqué dans un éventail de FCS soutenant la thèse que cette région du thamalus est partie prenante des fonctions exécutives non seulement anatomiquement mais aussi fonctionnellement.</description><creator>Prasad, Judy</creator><contributor>Yogita Chudasama (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Psychology - Experimental</subject><title>The nucleus reuniens of the midline thalamus: Anatomical and functional contributions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h767q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311s70h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r1942</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La modulation à porteuses multiples (MCM) est une technique de transmission efficace pour les communications filaires et sans fil à débit de données élevé, où la bande passante est divisée en plusieurs sous-canaux ayant chacun leur propre fréquence porteuse. Il existe de multiples réalisations possibles pour les systèmes MCM, mais le multiplexage orthogonal par répartition en fréquence (OFDM) est la solution la plus répandue dans les applications et standards présentement en vigueur. Toutefois, en raison de l'utilisation de filtres de synthèse et d'analyse rectangulaires, certaines imperfections causées par le canal de transmission, tels que les interférences à bande étroite (NBI) et le décalage de la fréquence porteuse (CFO), peuvent dégrader de manière significative les performances d'OFDM. Par ailleurs, les futurs réseaux de télécommunication nécessiteront des débits de transmission plus élevés, une plus grande efficacité de la bande passante et plus de flexibilité dans la gestion d'utilisateurs multiples non synchronisés. Les techniques de bancs de filtres à porteuses multiples (FBMC) ont récemment attiré l'attention de nombreux chercheurs.Dans ce contexte, nous proposons tout d'abord une nouvelle méthode pour la conception des bancs de filtres sur-échantillonnés à reconstruction parfaite (OPRFB) basés sur la modulation par transformation de Fourier discrète (DFT), pour les applications de transmultiplexage dans les systèmes MCM. La propriété de reconstruction parfaite (PR) est assurée par l'utilisation d'une famille paramétrique de matrices para-unitaires dans la réalisation des filtres polyphasés utilisés pour la transmission et la réception des données. L'optimisation des paramètres de conception pour la méthode choisie a pour but de minimiser l'énergie des filtres de synthèse et d'analyse dans la bande de coupure, ce qui conduit à une amélioration du confinement spectral. Les résultats d'analyse et de simulations montrent que les bancs de filtres OPRFB donnent lieu à un avantage marqué. En particulier, on constate une réduction significative du taux d'erreurs binaires (BER) lors de la transmission de données au moyen de la structure OPRFB proposée.Notre deuxième contribution porte donc sur le développement et l'analyse d'un nouvel estimateur conjoint des paramètres CFO et la réponse impulsionnelle du canal (CIR) basé sur le principe de la vraisemblance maximale (ML) et utilisant une séquence d'entraînement connue, toujours dans un contexte à usager unique. La borne de Cramer Rao (CRB) sur la variance des estimateurs non-biaisés des paramètres CFO et CIR est également dérivée. La performance du nouvel estimateur ML est soumise à l'étude par l'entremise de simulations numériques dans des conditions réalistes, soit en présence de CFO et de canaux à évanouissements en fréquence sélectifs. Les effets de différents motifs de tonalités pilotes sur la performance de l'estimation sont également. Les résultats démontrent l'excellente performance du nouvel estimateur ML conjoint proposé, qui peut déterminer avec une grande précision les paramètres CFO et CIR inconnus dans les différentes configurations expérimentales soumises à l'étude.Notre troisième et dernière contribution traite de l'extension de ce nouvel estimateur ML au cas d'usagers multiple. Plus précisément, nous considérons l'estimation conjointe du CFO et des coefficients CIR basée sur le principe ML dans la liaison montante des systèmes de transmission OPRFB multi-usagers (MU-OPRFB). Suite à son extension au cas multi-usagers, la performance de l'estimateur ML conjoint est examinée à l'aide de simulations numériques pour différents schémas d'allocation des sous-bandes entre les usagers. En outre, différentes distributions de tonalités pilotes dans le temps sont prises en compte et leurs effets sont étudiés sur des canaux radio mobiles variant dans le temps. Le potentiel d'application du nouvel estimateur ML aux systèmes multi-usagers est démontré.</description><description>Multicarrier modulation (MCM) is an efficient transmission technique for high data rate wired and wireless communications, where the channel bandwidth is divided into several subchannels with their own carriers. There are many different possible realizations for MCM systems, but with no doubt, orthogonal frequency division multiplexing (OFDM) has been the most prevalent solution in many current applications and standards. However, due to its use of a rectangular prototype filter, channel impairments such as narrowband interference (NBI) and carrier frequency offset (CFO) can greatly deteriorate the performance of OFDM. Moreover, future telecommunication networks call for higher data rate, increased bandwidth efficiency and flexibility in handling unsynchronized users. Filter bank multicarrier (FBMC) techniques have recently attracted considerable attention within the research community as a venue to fulfill these needs and potentially outperform the established OFDM in application areas such as dynamic spectrum access (DSA) and cognitive radio.In this context, we first propose a novel method for the design of discrete Fourier transform (DFT) modulated oversampled perfect reconstruction filter bank (OPRFB), for transmultiplexing application in MCM systems. The perfect reconstruction (PR) property is enforced by employing a parametric class of paraunitary matrices to form the transmit/receive polyphase filters of the transceiver system. Specifically, the polyphase filters are obtained by cascading special types of paraunitary matrices characterized by a limited set of design parameters. To reduce the number of these parameters, three different factorization methods are employed and compared.  Through the optimization of these design parameters, the stop-band energy of the subband filters can be minimized which leads to improved spectral containment. Numerical results show that the proposed scheme leads to a clear advantage not only in additive white Gaussian noise (AWGN) and frequency selective channels, but also in the presence of channel impairments such as NBI or CFO. In particular, it is found that a significant reduction in the bit error rate (BER) can be achieved by employing the proposed scheme. Secondly, still in the context of single-user systems, we derive a data-aided joint maximum likelihood (ML) estimator of the CFO and the channel impulse response (CIR) for OPRFB transceiver systems operating over frequency selective fading channels. Then, by exploiting the structural and spectral properties of these systems, we are able to considerably reduce the complexity of the proposed estimator through simplifications of the underlying likelihood function. The Cramer Rao bound (CRB) on the variance of unbiased CFO and CIR estimators is also derived. The performance of the proposed ML estimator is investigated by means of numerical simulations under realistic conditions with CFO and frequency selective fading channels. The effects of different pilot schemes on the estimation performance for applications over time-invariant and mobile time-varying channels are also examined. The results show that the proposed joint ML estimator exhibits an excellent performance, where it can accurately estimate the unknown CFO and CIR parameters for the various experimental setups under consideration.Our third and final contribution deals with the extension of these newly proposed estimators to the multi-user case. More specifically, we consider the joint estimation of the CFO and channel equalizer coefficients based on the ML principle in the uplink of multi-user OPRFB (MU-OPRFB) systems. The performance of the proposed joint ML estimator is examined for various subband allocation schemes by means of numerical simulations. Also, different distributions of pilots over time are considered and their effects are investigated over mobile time-varying channels.</description><creator>Rahimi, Siavash</creator><contributor>Benoit Champagne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Oversampled perfect reconstruction filter bank transceivers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881q327.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r1942</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945v20r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fil rouge est un diptyque comprenant Rouge, pour quatuor de saxophones, et Infrarouge pour quintette mixte. Nous situons ce projet esthétique au carrefour des pensées de John Dewey, Richard Shusterman et Gilles Deleuze dans l'optique d'un art conçu comme expérience. Ce cadre philosophique nous aide à mieux comprendre ce que peut être une approche expérientielle de la musique, notamment en termes de « logique de la sensation », ainsi qu'à positionner notre démarche dans le contexte de la musique de concert. Dans un second temps, la sémiotique figurale deleuzienne alimentera significativement notre paradigme compositionnel. À ce titre, Fil rouge repose sur une sémiotique originale où dominent les concepts de figure et de texture performatives, ainsi que certaines stratégies formelles para-discursives (i.e. non narratives). Finalement, la poétique de l'œuvre s'articule autour d'une approche spécifique de la forme diptyque, ainsi que d'un travail sur la couleur-sensation « rouge ».</description><description>The diptych Fil rouge is comprised of Rouge (saxophone quartet) and Infrarouge (mixed quintet). We situate this aesthetic projet at the crossroads of John Dewey's, Richard Shusterman's and Gilles Deleuze's thoughts, with respect to a conception of art as experience. This philosophical framework helps us in defining an experiential approach to music, notably in terms of "logic of sensation", as well as in positionning our own aesthetics in the context of Western art music. Secondly, Deleuze's figural semiotics significantly informs our compositional paradigm. In this regard, Fil rouge is based on a genuine semiotics where the concepts of performative figure and texture play a central role, alongside with formal strategies that we describe as para-discursive (e.g. non-narrative). Finally, the poetics of Fil rouge relies upon a specific take on the diptych form, and on "red" as a color-sensation.</description><creator>LeBlanc, Jimmie</creator><contributor>Denys Bouliane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</subject><title>Fil rouge: les concepts de figure et de texture performatives comme fondements d'une approche expérientielle de la musique</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nh94j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945v20r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827f922</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Self-assembled nanostructures provide an exciting opportunity to generate new materials with molecular resolution, and in a massively parallel fashion. Nanomaterials often display unique properties relative to their bulk analogues, giving them attractive potential in fields like electronics, photonics, structural biology, and therapeutics. DNA, beyond its role in genetics, is also one of the best self-assembling molecules known. It uses specific base-pairing interactions to come together into a well-defined, rigid double helix. We can therefore predict exactly how two different strands of DNA will interact in solution with impressive accuracy. DNA nanotechnology applies this ability to the generation of complex nanostructures using DNA as a building material. One of the key challenges facing DNA nanotechnology is to find a practical balance between structural complexity and ease of synthesis. This thesis develops simplified methods to build and control DNA nanostructures, in an effort to make them more practical and viable for future applications. Conceptually, this research can be divided into three main parts. First, a method to build discrete 3D prisms from a minimal number of components is developed. These structures incorporate new strand connectivity and a balance of symmetric and unique sequence to generate a library of well-defined geometries from a minimal amount of DNA. Second, DNA nanotubes are generated using a long, continuous, enzymatically produced backbone strand, and from a simplified set of component strands. Together, these methods provide templated length, enhanced stability in biological settings, efficient cellular penetration, and the ability to generate long linear patterns of various cargo molecules using a DNA-minimal approach. Third, a method to produce monodisperse DNA strands with user-defined patterns of sequence domains is developed. Using temporal control and in situ ligation, complex patterns can be generated and amplified from a small number of building blocks, and used as template strands in the construction of DNA nanostructures. Together, the concepts developed in this work can be used to make functional DNA nanostructures in a practical manner, with an emphasis on reducing synthetic effort while retaining structural complexity.</description><description>Les structures auto-assemblées offrent une excellente occasion de créer de nouveaux matériaux disposant d'une résolution moléculaire et d'un procédé de fabrication massivement parallèle. Les nanomatériaux présentent souvent des propriétés uniques lorsque comparés à leur analogues de plus grande échelle ce qui leur confère un potentiel attrayant dans des domaines tels que l'électronique, la photonique, la biologie structurale et le développement de produits thérapeutiques. L'ADN, au-delà de son rôle en génétique, est aussi l'une des meilleures molécules auto-assemblantes connues. Les liaisons spécifiques entre les bases de l'ADN permettent la formation d'une double hélice rigide et bien définie. Nous pouvons donc prédire exactement la façon dont deux brins différents d'ADN vont interagir en solution et ce, avec une impressionnante exactitude. La nanotechnologie en ADN se sert cette propriété afin de générer des nanostructures complexes qui utilisent l'ADN en tant que matériau de construction. L'un des principaux défis auxquels la nanotechnologie en ADN doit faire face est de trouver une balance fonctionnelle entre la complexité structurale et la facilité de synthèse. Cette thèse présente des procédés simplifiés pour construire et contrôler des nanostructures en ADN dans le but de les rendre plus pratiques et viables en vue d'applications futures. Conceptuellement, cette recherche peut être divisée en trois parties principales. En premier lieu, une méthode pour construire des prismes tridimensionnels distincts à partir d'un nombre minimal de composantes est élaborée. Ces structures intègrent de nouvelles connectivités entre les brins, de même qu'une balance entre la symétrie et l'unicité des séquences utilisées, afin de créer un ensemble de géométries bien définies à partir d'une quantité minimale d'ADN. En second lieu, des nanotubes d'ADN sont générés en utilisant une longue séquence continue d'ADN produite de façon enzymatique en tant que squelette, ainsi qu'un ensemble simplifié de brins constitutifs. Collectivement, ces procédures assurent l'obtention de nanotubes possédant une longueur contrôlée au moyen de séquences utilisées en tant que gabarits, une stabilité accrue dans des milieux biologiques, une pénétration cellulaire efficace et permettent d'introduire de longs motifs linéaires lors de l'arrangement de molécules cargo, tout en profitant d'une approche minimale en ADN. En troisième lieu, un procédé produisant des séquences d'ADN monodisperses qui comprennent des domaines de séquences avec des motifs définis par l'utilisateur est décrit. En se servant d'un contrôle temporel et d'un protocole de ligation in situ, des motifs complexes peuvent être générés et amplifiés à partir d'un nombre minimal de composantes pour ensuite être utilisés en tant que brins-gabarit dans la construction de nanostructures d'ADN. Collectivement, les concepts développés dans cette thèse peuvent être exploités afin de fabriquer des nanostructures d'ADN fonctionnelles de manière pratique avec une emphase mise sur la réduction de l'effort synthétique et la conservation de la complexité structurale.</description><creator>Hamblin, Graham</creator><contributor>Hanadi Sleiman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Chemistry - General</subject><title>Practical designs for DNA nanostructures: balancing minimal design and structural complexity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322h898.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827f922</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nf36g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation presents arguments in favour of an explicit Logical Form representation of components responsible for direct referentiality and domain restriction in definites, with a focus on Austro-Bavarian German, Standard Swedish, and Standard Canadian English.It provides a semantico-pragmatic analysis of the ban on wh-subextraction out of DPs with the "strong" articles in Austro-Bavarian and demonstratives in English which assumes their direct referentiality. The ungrammaticality of question formation is proposed to result from the pathological uninformativeness of its possible answers. The ban on wh-subextraction thus emerges as a new testing tool for direct referentiality.I further propose an analysis of the cases where strong articles and demonstratives do not behave directly referentially. Assuming structural decomposition of strong articles and demonstratives into a determiner head and a relational head, I propose that directly referential interpretation results from a silent individual pronoun occupying the specifier of the relational head, whereas covarying interpretations arise as a result of either a restrictive relative clause occupying this position, or else a relational noun functioning as the relational component itself. I proceed to extend this approach to account for the distribution of strong and weak definite articles in DPs with restrictive relative clauses. A strong-DP is predicted to be used in all contexts where it is taken for granted that there is more than one individual with the nominal property because of the pragmatic pressure to use an LF with a component which triggers an "anti-uniqueness" presupposition. I show the latter to be a required feature of the semantic model for strong articles and demonstratives on independent grounds.In the second part I analyze the pattern of the free-standing article omission in Swedish. I identify the omission with the use of a covert restrictor-less definite article, which accounts for why it is easily available with context-sensitive modifiers whose semantics has to make reference to a domain restrictor, but is limited to the cases of "global uniqueness" with context-insensitive ones. Thus Swedish, I propose, illustrates the case of a "rudimentary" article which, if the only one available, would make the problem of incomplete descriptions unsurmountable. This conclusion relies on, and thus provides evidence for, the unavailability of either domain restriction at the NP-level or implicit global restriction of the domain of individuals as a means of modelling the behaviour of Swedish definites.</description><description>La thèse avance des arguments en support de la représentation explicite des éléments responsables pour la référence directe et pour les restrictions du domaine dans les expressions définies et se base sur les données de l'austro-bavarois, le suédois et l'anglais canadien.Je propose une analyse sémantique-pragmatique de l'agrammaticalité du mouvement wh des syntagmes nominales avec les articles "fortes" en austro-bavarois et avec les démonstratifs en anglais qui les traite comme directement référentiels. Il est proposé que les réponses possibles à telle question ne portent pas d'information nouvelle, ce qui donne comme le résultat l'agrammaticalité de la question. L'agrammaticalité du mouvement wh devient donc une diagnostique pour la référence directe.Je propose aussi une analyse des cas où les articles fortes et les démonstratifs ne sont pas directement référentiels. En assumant une décomposition structurelle des articles fortes et des démonstratifs en une tête déterminative et une tête relative, je propose que l'interprétation directement référentielle se produit au cas où un pronom personnel silencieux occupe le spécificateur de la tête relative, tandis que l'interprétation qui admets une covariation se produit au cas où soit une proposition relative occupe le spécificateur en question, soit un nom relatif fonctionne comme une tête relative. J'applique cette analyse à la distribution des articles fortes et faibles dans les syntagmes nominales avec des propositions relatives restrictives.La seconde partie développe une analyse de l'omission de l'article défini indépendant dans le suédois. Je traite l'omission comme l'usage d'un article défini silencieux qui ne peut pas restreindre le domaine de la quantification, ce qui explique pourquoi elle est possible avec les modificateurs qui fournissent leur propres restrictions contextuelles, tandis qu'elle est possible seulement dans les cas de l'unicité "globale" avec les modificateurs qui ne fournissent pas des restrictions contextuelles. L'analyse met en évidence l'indisponibilité soit de la restriction du domaine sur le niveau nominal, soit de la restriction implicite globale.</description><creator>Simonenko, Alexandra</creator><contributor>Bernhard Schwarz (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Language - Linguistics</subject><title>Grammatical ingredients of definiteness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pr10p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nf36g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72pb612</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse traite de la dynamique linéaire et non linéaire d'une structure mince et flexible dans un écoulement axial d'eau ou d'air. Ce sujet a des applications importantes, par exemple en ce qui concerne les vibrations des faisceaux d'éléments combustibles dans les réacteurs nucléaires, les échangeurs de chaleur et l'angioplastie. Le manque de connaissances sur le comportement tridimensionnel de la structure mince dans les applications mentionnées ci-haut a motivé la recherche présentée dans cette thèse. Les résultats théoriques donnent les vitesses d'écoulement critiques pour le déclenchement des instabilités fluide-élastiques, ainsi que les amplitudes et fréquences associées à ces instabilités.  Des expériences ont été menées afin de valider et de compléter les résultats théoriques pour des écoulements d'eau. Les résultats obtenus à partir des expériences sont présentés sous la forme de moyennes de déplacements adimensionnels 'root-mean-square', et les fréquences en fonction de la vitesse d'écoulement adimensionnelle. Enfin, la forme tracée par le cylindre oscillant a été cartographiée.Dans les problèmes d'interaction fluide-structure, les forces de fluide, telles que les forces hydrodynamiques non visqueuses, les forces associées au frottement, et les forces hydrostatiques et de pression agissant sur la structure souple jouent un rôle vital sur la dynamique du système. Par conséquent, un calcul précis des coefficients de ces forces est impératif dans les équations de mouvement associés aux forces fluides mentionnées ci-dessus, tels que les coefficients longitudinales et normales visqueux, le coefficient de traînée de base, et le coefficient de force normale dans un fluide stagnant. Ces coefficients de force actuellement calculés ont ensuite été intégrés dans les équations linéaires et non linéaires du mouvement, et les équations ont été résolues pour obtenir la réponse du cylindre dans l'écoulement d'eau. La réponse du système à partir du modèle linéaire d'un écoulement d'air a également été obtenu. L'effet du confinement sur la dynamique linéaire a aussi été étudié.Un modèle de cylindre en porte à faux tridimensionnel non linéaire a également été créé et simulé dans un logiciel de modélisation par éléments finis et de simulation un logiciel commercial, à savoir ADINA, afin de compléter les résultats obtenus à partir de modèles linéaires et non linéaires. Les résultats des simulations de ADINA ont été obtenus pour des écoulements d'eau, ainsi que des écoulements d'air.Les résultats expérimentaux ont validé les résultats des modèles analytique et numérique. Les résultats ainsi obtenus sont appelés à jouer un rôle important dans l'amélioration des techniques et applications industrielles et médicales mentionnées ci-dessus pour assurer un fonctionnement au dessous des conditions d'écoulement critiques.</description><description>This thesis deals with the theoretical study of the linear and nonlinear dynamics of a slender flexible cantilevered cylindrical structure subjected to external axial water and air flows, of interest because of several important practical applications such as nuclear reactor fuel-element bundles, double pipe heat exchangers, and angioplasty. Lack of knowledge to account for the three-dimensional behaviour, important in the above-mentioned practical applications, was the motivation behind the present work. The theoretical results were obtained in the form of the amplitudes and frequencies of the instabilities, as well as the critical flow velocities at which these instabilities occurred. Experiments were conducted to validate and complement the theoretical results for water flow. The results obtained from the experiments were presented in the form of dimensionless mean displacements, their corresponding root mean square values, and frequencies as a function of dimensionless flow velocity. Finally, the path traced by the oscillating cylinder was mapped.   In fluid-structure interaction problems, the fluid forces such as the inviscid hydrodynamic forces, the frictional or viscous forces, and the hydrostatic or pressure forces acting on the flexible structure play a vital role in defining the dynamics of the system. Therefore, a precise calculation of the force coefficients, such as longitudinal and normal viscous coefficients, base drag coefficient, and zero-flow normal force coefficient present in the equations of motion associated to the above mentioned fluid forces, is imperative. These presently calculated force coefficients were then incorporated in the linear and nonlinear equations of motion and solved to obtain the response of the cylinder in water flow. The response of the system from the linear model in air flow was also obtained. The effect of confinement on the linear dynamics was also studied. A nonlinear three-dimensional cantilevered cylinder model was also created and simulated in a commercially available finite element modeling and simulation package, namely ADINA, in order to complement the results obtained from the linear and nonlinear models. The results of the ADINA simulations were obtained in water as well as air flows.Experimental results validated the analytical and numerical model results. The results, thus obtained, are expected to play an important role in improving the above-mentioned engineering and medical applications to ensure operation below critical flow conditions.</description><creator>Jamal, Ahmad</creator><contributor>Michael P Paidoussis (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Luc Mongeau (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Three-dimensional nonlinear dynamics of cantilevered cylinders in axial flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nv163.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72pb612</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kd984</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Songbirds use vocal signals for social communication. Song can be produced in a variety of social contexts, and previous studies have demonstrated that the structure and organization of song significantly changes across social contexts. However, little is known about the neural circuits and neurotransmitters that contribute to the social modulation of song. Here we combine behavioural, immunocytochemical, and pharmacological experiments to reveal the mechanisms underlying context-dependent changes to syllable sequencing and structure in Bengalese finches. Throughout the circuit underlying vocal motor control, we found that expression of the immediate early gene EGR-1 was greater when birds sang alone compared to when they sang in a courtship context. Investigation of EGR-1 expression in catecholamine-producing neurons suggested a role of catecholamines in the social modulation of song. To test this idea, we analyzed the effect of amphetamine on song organization and found that amphetamine reproduced social context effects on syllable structure but did not affect sequencing. These data support the notion that the social modulation of neural activity within the song system underlies context-dependent changes in song, and that catecholamines like dopamine contribute to the social modulation of vocal behaviour.</description><description>Les oiseaux chanteurs utilisent des signaux vocaux pour la communication sociale. Le chant peut être produit dans divers contexts sociaux et des etudes anterieures one démontré que la structure et l'organisation du chant variant considérablement selon les contexts sociaux. Cependant, nous savons peu de choses sur les circuits neuronaux et les neurotransmetteurs qui contribuent à la modulation sociale du chant. Nous combinons ici des experiences comportementales, immunocytochimiques et pharmacologiques afin de découvrir les mécanismes qui sous-tendent les changements contextuels åa la structure et à l'enchaînement des syllabes chez les dominos. Dans l'ensemble du circuit qui sous-tend le contrôle moteur vocal, nous avons découvert que l'expression du gène précoce immédiat EGR-1 était plus importante lorsque les oiseaux chantaient seuls que lorsqu'ils chantaient dans un contexte de pariade. Un examen de l'expression du gène EGR-1 dans les neurones producteurs de catécholamine donne à penser que les catécholamines jouent un rôle dans la modulation sociale du chant. Pour vérifier cette idée, nous avons analysé l'effet de l'amphétamine sur l'organisation du chant et nous avons découvert que l'amphétamine reproduisait les effets du contexte social sur la structure des syllabes, mais qu'elle n'avait aucun effet sur l'enchaînement des syllabes. Ces données appuient la notion selon laquelle la modulation sociale de l'activité neuronale dans le système de chant sous-tend les changements contextuels dans le chant et que les catécholamines, comme la dopamine, contribuent à la modulation sociale du comportement vocal.</description><creator>Matheson, Laura</creator><contributor>Jon Sakata (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Neural circuits underlying the social modulation of vocal communication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hv84x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kd984</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vx27q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'injection souterraine des nanoparticules de fer à zéro valence (NZVI) est une technologie émergente pour l'assainissement in situ des sites contaminés par des polluants toxiques comme les solvants chlorés et les métaux lourds. L'un des principaux défis dans l'application des particules de NZVI à des fins de rémédiation est que les particules de NZVI ne sont pas facilement transportées dans des milieux poreux souterrains. L'objectif général de cette recherche est de relever ce défi en réalisant un certain nombre d'expériences en colonnes et en 2-D sur desbassins à l'échelle pilote ainsi que par l'analyse de la mécanique de dépôt de nanoparticules métalliques en théorie. Bien que de nombreuses études ont porté sur la stabilité et le transport de nanoparticules de fer (NZVI) revêtues de polymère / poly-électrolyte, la comparaison de l'effet du même type de stabilisant en polyélectrolyte ayant des poids moléculaires différents, sur la stabilité et le transport des particules de NZVI enrobées n'ont pas été effectués systématiquement à ce jour. Des poids moléculaires variables des polyélectrolytes homologues peuvent provoquer des variations de viscosité en solution libre et dans l'étendue de la stabilisation colloïdale électrostérique de NZVI en s'attachant sur la surface des nanoparticules. Des études antérieures sur le transport des particules NZVI ont été menées dans les colonnes placées verticalement, qui souvent ne sont pas représentatifs de l'orientation de l'écoulement réel sur le champ, ce qui conduit à une différence de potentiel de performance du transport de particules NZVI entre l'orientation de l'écoulement vertical couramment utilisé et le modèle à flux horizontal. Outre, les effets à l'échelle grandissante (de la colonne à l'échelle de laboratoire, pilote ou des manifestations à l'échelle du champ) sur le transport de NZVI sont rapportés. Dans cette étude, une enquête approfondie sur le transport de NZVI est effectuée dans un réservoir en 2-D à l'échelle pilote afin de faire la lumière sur la performance du transport des particules de NZVI dans des conditions qui sont plus près de la situation réelle. Enfin, pour calculer le coefficient de vitesse de dépôt des nanoparticules de métal en cours de transport, un nombre considérable d'études sur les particules de NZVI ont été effectué en employant des équations de transport à fin de prédire le contact de rendement du capteur unique qui sont mis au point sur la base des calculs numériques pour les particules colloïdales communes moins denses tels que des particules de latex, qui ont des densités plus inferieures que celles des particules de métal. Prenant le mode d'écoulement horizontal et les effets de la densité de nanoparticules métalliques en considération, une nouvelle méthode est développée en trois dimensions (3-D) afin de prédire plus précisément l'efficacité du collecteur unique de particules NZVI .</description><description>Subsurface injection of nano scale zero valent iron (NZVI) particles is an emerging technology for in situ remediation of the sites contaminated by toxic contaminants such as chlorinated organic dense non aqueous phase liquids (DNAPLs) and heavy metals. One of the key challenges in applying NZVI particles for remediation at the field scale is that NZVI particles are not readily transported in subsurface porous media. The overall objective of this research is to address this challenge by conducting a number of column experiments and 2-D pilot scale tank experiments as well as by exploring the deposition mechanics of metal nanoparticles theoretically. Although numerous studies have focused the stability and transport of polymer/polyelectrolyte coated NZVI particles, the comparison of the effect of the same type of polyelectrolyte stabilizer with different molecular weight on the stability and transport of the corresponding coated NZVI particles has not been systematically conducted to date. Varying molecular weights of homologous polyelectrolytes can cause changes in viscosity and rheology in free solution, and alter the extent of colloidal stability when coated on the nanoparticles. Furthermore, most of the studies on NZVI particle transport have been conducted in the vertically placed columns, which are not representative with the actual flow orientation in field, leading to a potential difference of transport performance of NZVI particles between the commonly used vertical flow orientation and the horizontal flow model. In addition, the scale-up effects (from laboratory-scale column to pilot-scale or field-scale demonstrations) on NZVI transport are reported. In this study, a thorough investigation on NZVI transport is conducted in a 2-D pilot-scale tank to shed some light on the transport performance of NZVI particles under conditions that are more close to actual circumstances. Finally, to calculate the deposition rate coefficient of metal nanoparticles during transport, a considerable number of studies on NZVI particles transport employed equations for predicting the single collector contact efficiency that are developed on the basis of the numerical calculations for common colloidal particles such as latex particles, which have smaller densities than those of metal particles. Taking the horizontal flow mode and the density effects for metal nanoparticles into consideration, a new methodology is developed in three dimensions (3-D) to more precisely predict the single collector efficiency of NZVI particles.In the first study, the influence of the molecular weight of the polyelectrolyte grafted on NZVI particle on its stability and transport was investigated. Three carboxymethyl celluloses (CMC) with different molecular weights (90,000 Da, 250,000 Da and 700,000 Da) were used to stabilize NZVI particles. The comparison of the results revealed that the stability and transport of NZVI particles were improved significantly by CMC with high molecular weight, due to its high viscosity property. In the second study, the effects of gravity on NZVI particle during its transport were extensively assessed in vertical and horizontal placed columns under different conditions (mean sand diameters and NZVI concentrations). The results indicated that the gravity forces significantly reduced NZVI particles transport in coarse sand and at high NZVI concentration in horizontally placed columns. To thoroughly study the impact of horizontal orientation flow on the transport of NZVI particles at a larger scale, a series of transport experiments were conducted in a pilot-scale 2-D tank. Furthermore, to address the challenges met in predicting the single collector efficiency in horizontal orientation flow mode, a methodology based on trajectory analysis of particles around a Happel sphere-in-cell model for porous media in 3-D was developed. </description><creator>Li, Jing</creator><contributor>Subhasis Ghoshal (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Multi-scale investigations of carboxymethyl cellulose- coated nanoscale zero valent iron particle transport in porous media</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xp93v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vx27q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920g108k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research study seeks to better understand youth educational and leadership development in the post-earthquake and developmental context of Haiti through the perspective of Haitian youth. Through a qualitative exploration of the perspectives of Haitian youth this study investigates what Haitian youth identify as the barriers to their development in terms of educational advancement and leadership opportunities, and what Haitian youth identify as solutions to these barriers to foster their own future development. The purpose of this study was to empower the participants by giving them opportunities to voice their concerns, and to share what they believe are acting as barriers to their educational advancement and the obtainment of potential leadership opportunities. Additionally, the participants used this study as a platform to voice their ideas so as to how these barriers can be broken down by specific solutions. This research study adopted arts-based methodologies such as storyboard/drawing and Photovoice, and also included the use of focus groups as an inclusive research design. As a result, these processes lead to the creation of relevant themes related to identified barriers, fostering meaningful development, creating awareness, and 'jumpstarting' the possibility for sustainable change for future generations of Haitian youth.</description><description>Ce travail de recherche vise à mieux comprendre le développement éducatif et leadership des jeune Haïtiens après le séisme du 12 janvier 2010. Cette recherche a été fait avec le point de vue d'un groupe de jeunes Haïtiens.  Cette étude examine ce que les jeunes identifies comme obstacles à leur développement éducationnels, et aussi ce qui les empêchent de devenir les leaders de demain. Le but de cette étude était de donner aux participants la possibilité d'exprimer leurs préoccupations, et de partager ce qu'ils croient qui agissent comme des barrières à leur développement éducatif. Les jeunes ont aussi identifier des solutions à ces obstacles afin de favoriser leur développement. Les participants ont utilisé cette étude comme une plate-forme pour exprimer leurs idées. Cette étude de recherche a adopté les méthodologies basées sur les arts tels que storyboard/dessin et Photovoice, et comprenait également l'utilisation de groupes de discussion. En conséquence, ces procédés ont crées des thèmes pertinents liés aux obstacles identifiés, et aussi les inspirer à la possibilité pour un changement durable pour les générations futures de la jeunesse haïtienne.</description><creator>Trudeau, Ryan</creator><contributor>Claudia A Mitchell (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Education - Social Sciences</subject><title>Empowering Haiti's youth with leadership through education and action: investigating their perspectives and lived experiences</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773z90n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920g108k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644v99c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Flatworms of the genus Schistosoma are wide-spread and clinically significant parasites of humans in the tropics and sub-tropics. In evolutionary terms, they are representatives of the earliest metazoans to have evolved separate sexes, and to possess anatomically distinct central and peripheral nervous systems. Schistosome infections are currently controlled by a single drug, praziquantel (PZQ), but the emergence of schistosome strains resistant to PZQ is a growing concern.A deeper understanding of the basic biology of schistosomes is the first step towards target-based drug discovery. Neuronal receptors of schistosomes are attractive targets for drug development because all major physiological activities and behaviors in these parasites are coordinated by their nervous system. Neuronal signaling in schistosomes is mediated by a variety of neurotransmitters and associated receptors, including members of the pentameric ligand-gated ion channel (pLGIC) superfamily. The S. mansoni genome encodes 4 putative non-AChR-like inhibitory pLGIC subunits and 13 putative nAChR-like pLGIC subunits.The work presented in this thesis focuses on L-glutamate (L-glu) neuronal signaling in S. mansoni. L-glu is an important neurotransmitter in essentially all vertebrate and invertebrate phyla, but its functional roles in S. mansoni are poorly understood. Here, we further contribute to knowledge in this field by providing the first molecular evidence for the contribution of an inhibitory, glutamate-gated Cl  channel (GluCl)-mediated component to glutamatergic neurotransmission in S. mansoni.First, we show that the 4 non-AChR-like inhibitory pLGIC subunit candidates encode GluCl subunits (SmGluCl-1-4) that are pharmacologically and evolutionarily distinct from insect, nematode and snail GluCls. Using an electrophysiology approach in Xenopus oocytes, we demonstrate that SmGluCl-1, -2 and -3 subunits exhibited low micromolar affinity for L-glu, are permeable to Cl , but are insensitive to ivermectin and meclonazepam. Phylogenetic analyses suggest that the SmGluCl subunits belong to a previously uncharacterized clade of flatworm GluCls that includes several GluCl candidates from related trematode and cestode species.Then, we provide evidence that the SmGluCl subunits are expressed in all human stages of the parasite. An analysis of SmGluCl stage-specific expression by RT-PCR amplification reveals that transcripts from all 4 SmGluCl subunits are expressed in S. mansoni cercaria, schistosomules, adults and eggs. Confocal immunolocalization reveals that all the SmGluCl subunits are widely expressed in the nervous system of male and female worms, and exhibit partially overlapping expression patterns in the central nervous system and in the peripheral nerve cords and plexuses supplying the body, attachment organs, reproductive tract and tubercles. The lack of apparent co-localization between SmGluCl subunits and phalloidin suggests that they are not expressed in the musculature. Together, these findings offer possible clues regarding the physiological functions they mediate, including interneuronal signaling, indirect regulation of motility, attachment and feeding, oogenesis and sensory signaling.Finally, we present initial data from prospective work aimed at developing a YFP assay for HTS of compound libraries against S. mansoni GluCls heterologously expressed in mammalian cells. We confirm by confocal immunofluorescence that heterologously expressed FLAG-tagged SmGluCl-2 is localized at the membrane surface of HEK-293. Further work is underway to demonstrate the feasibility of this assay for HTS against S. mansoni GluCls as a means of exploring the potential of new compounds as either therapeutic leads or pharmacological probes targeting S. mansoni GluCls to explore their physiological functions.</description><description>Les vers plats (platyhelminthes) du genre Schistosoma sont des parasites de l'homme répandus dans plusieurs régions tropicales et sous-tropicales. Le seul médicament disponible pour traiter la schistosomiase est le praziquantel (PZQ). L'émergence de souches de schistosomes résistantes au PZQ est une préoccupation croissante. Le système nerveux des schistosome exerce un contrôle exclusif sur toutes les activités physiologiques de ces parasites, déterminant leurs particularités comportementales au sein de leur hôte. La signalisation neuronale chez les schistosomes est modulée par une variété de neurotransmetteurs et des récepteurs qui leur sont associés, incluant les membres de la superfamille des récepteurs ionotropes sensible à un ligand de type pentamérique (pLGIC). Le génome de S. mansoni encode 4 sous-unités putatives de pLGIC insensibles à l'acétylcholine (non-AChR) et 13 sous-unités putatives de pLGIC de type nAChR.Le L-glu est un neurotransmetteur important, retrouvé chez presque tous les vertébrés et les invertébrés, mais les fonctions neurologiques qu'il module chez S. mansoni sont mal comprises. Cette thèse fournit la toute première preuve que le L-glu peut générer des potentiels postsynaptiques inhibiteurs médiés par l'activation de pLGICs sensibles au L-glu (GluCl). Les 4 gènes candidats encodant des sous-unités pLGIC de type non-AChR sont des sous-unités GluCl (SmGluCl-1-4). Ces récepteurs SmGluCl diffèrent des récepteurs GluCl retrouvés chez les insectes, les nématodes et les gastropodes. Des expériences d'électrophysiologie montrent que les sous-unités SmGluCl-1, -2 et -3 forment des récepteurs perméables aux ions Cl  et sensibles à des concentrations de L-glu de l'ordre du micromolaire (7-27 µM), mais sont insensibles à l'ivermectine et au meclonazepam. Les analyses phylogénétiques suggèrent que les sous-unités SmGluCl appartiennent à un nouveau groupe de sous-unités GluCl retrouvées exclusivement chez les vers plats parasitaires.Ensuite, nous démontrons par RT-PCR que les ARN messagers encodantque les sous-unités SmGluCl sont produites par tous les stades de développement du parasite interagissant avec l'humain. Des expériences d'immunolocalisation révèlent que ces sous-unités SmGluCl sont abondamment exprimées dans les vers mâles et femelles, au niveau du système nerveux central, ainsi que dans certains des cordons et plexus nerveux du système nerveux périphérique innervant l'enveloppe corporelle, les organes d'attachement, l'appareil reproducteur et les tubercules. Les récepteurs SmGluCl ne sont pas exprimés dans la musculature des schistosomes. En somme, la distribution des sous-unités SmGluCl dans le système nerveux suggère que ces récepteurs pourraient être impliqués dans la signalisation interneuronale et sensorielle et pourrait réguler de manière indirecte la mobilité, l'attachement et l'alimentation et l'ovogenèse.Enfin, nous présentons des données préliminaires obtenues dans le cadre d'un projet visant à développer une méthode analytique permettant le criblage à haut débit (high-throughput screening, HTS) de banques de composés d'intérêt pharmaceutique, afin de tester leur effet sur l'activité des récepteurs GluCl des schistosomes. Cette méthode analytique sera effectuée dans des cellules de mammifères exprimant les récepteurs SmGluCl de manière hétérologue et permettra de mesurer l'activité de ces récepteurs en fonction de la fluorescence émise par la protéine YFP. Nous avons confirmé par immunolocalisation que SmGluCl-2 exprimée de manière hétérologue dans des cellules HEK-293 est localisée au niveau de la surface membranaire. D'autres travaux sont en cours pour démontrer la faisabilité de ce test pour l'identification par HTS de molécules modulant l'activité des récepteurs GluCl de S. mansoni. Les composés identifié pourront être utilisés comme sondes pharmacologiques afin d'approfondir l'étude des fonctions physiologiques modulées par les récepteurs GluCl de S. mansoni.</description><creator>Dufour, Vanessa</creator><contributor>Timothy Geary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Parasitology</subject><title>Molecular characterization of novel glutamate-gated chloride channel subunits from «Schistosoma mansoni»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193d168.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644v99c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s1619456</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this study, I will argue that the difference between profane love and sacred love, as examined in Jāmī's masnavī Yūsuf va Zulaykhā, can be conceptualized through vision and narrative planning. Jami's tale centers on Zulaykhā's love for Yusuf and her subsequent conversion to monotheism. The text makes extensive use of the sense of sight, especially through the trope of jelvah-i maḥbūb, the blinding hierophany of the beloved, to create meaning and to illustrate the transformation of Zulaykhā's profane love into sacred love. This transformation occurs in several stages, each of which conveys philosophical and mystical doctrines from Ibn 'Arabī.</description><description>Lors de cette étude, nous argumenterons que la différence entre l'amour profane et l'amour sacré, tel que présentée par Jāmī dans le masnavī Yūsuf va Zulaykhā, peut s'exprimer par la vision et la répartition du récit. Le récit de Jāmī se concentre autour de l'amour de Zulaykhā pour Yūsuf et sa conséquente conversion au monothéisme. Le texte utilise le sens de la vue , surtout à travers la figure de style jelvah-i maḥbūb, la hiérophanie éblouissante du bien-aimé, afin d'illustrer et de donner un sens à la transformation de l'amour profane de Zulaykhā en amour sacré. Cette transformation a lieu en plusieurs étapes, chacune communiquant des doctrines mystiques et philosophiques d'Ibn 'Arabī.</description><creator>El-Murr, Leila</creator><contributor>Prashant Keshavmurthy (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Literature - Middle Eastern</subject><title>Seeing God: the use of theories of vision in Jāmī's «Yūsuf va Zulaykhā»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xp944.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1619456</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m2670</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines preferential diffusion effects in laminar and turbulent premixed combustion.  Stretched, fuel-lean, laminar flames of methane, propane and hydrogen are studied experimentally in a counter-flow flame configuration to investigate the effect of Lewis number on stretched flames.  Laminar flame results show that a maximum reference flame speed exists for mixtures with Le &gt;= 1 at lower flame-stretch values than the extinction stretch rate.  A continually-increasing reference flame speed is measured for Le &lt;&lt; 1 mixtures until extinction occurs when the flame is constrained by the stagnation point.Turbulent counter-flow flame experiments are then performed for these mixtures, using high-blockage turbulence-generating plates to produce turbulence intensities on the order of u'/sLo = 1 to 10.  Measurements of average and instantaneous velocity within the turbulent flame are performed by time-resolved particle image velocimetry measurements.  Average and instantaneous flame front position is also measured by Rayleigh spectroscopy.Measurements of average turbulent burning velocity demonstrate the ambiguity in definitions of the burning velocity and the difficulty of examining turbulent flame chemistry using averaged measurements.  Instantaneous statistics are shown to be superior tools for studying turbulent combustion.  The probability-density functions (PDF) of the local flamelet burning velocities for Le &gt;= 1 mixtures show that the instantaneous flamelet burning velocities increase with increasing turbulence intensity and flame stretch.  The PDF for the Le ~= 1 mixture has a sharply skewed shape at high turbulence intensity and has a sharp drop-off in probability at a velocity that corresponds with the experimentally-measured maximum reference flame speed from the laminar flame experiments.  In contrast, in the Le &lt;&lt; 1 turbulent flames, the most-probable instantaneous flamelet burning velocities increase with increasing turbulence intensity and can significantly exceed the maximum reference flame speed measured in counter-flow laminar flames at extinction.These results are reinforced by instantaneous flame position measurements.  Flame front location PDFs  show the most probable flame location to be linked to velocity PDFs.  Furthermore,  hydrogen PDFs are recognizably skewed as u'/sLo increases, indicating a tendency for the Le &lt;&lt; 1 mixture to propagate farther into the unburned reactants.  These results support the leading edge theory of premixed turbulent flame propagation for flames in which preferential diffusion effects are expected.In the study of turbulent flames, this work promotes the use of local, instantaneous statistics as a tool for describing experimental results and studying fuel chemistry.</description><description>La thèse porte sur les effets de diffusion préférentiels en combustion prémélangée laminaire et turbulente.  Les flammes étirées laminaires de méthane, de propane et d'hydrogène sont étudiés expérimentalement dans une configuration de flamme à contre-courant pour mesurer l'effet du nombre de Lewis sur la vitesse de flamme étirée.  Résultats de flamme laminaire montrent qu'il existe une vitesse de référence maximale pour les mélanges avec Le &gt;= 1 à des valeurs d'étirement plus faibles que la valeur d'extinction.  Une augmentation de la vitesse de référence est mesurée pour mélanges Le &lt;&lt; 1 jusqu'à l'extinction se produit lorsque la flamme est limitée par le point de stagnation.Expériences de flammes turbulentes à contre-courant sont ensuite effectuées pour ces mélanges, en utilisant des plaques génératrices à haut blocage pour produire des intensités de turbulence de l'ordre de u'/sLo = 1 à 10.  Des mesures moyennes et instantanées de la vitesse de la flamme turbulente sont effectuées par vélocimétire image-particule, résolues en temps.  La position moyenne et instantanée du front de flamme est également mesurée par spectroscopie Rayleigh.Des mesures de la vitesse moyenne de combustion turbulente démontrent l'ambiguïté dans les définitions de la vitesse de combustion et la difficulté de l'examen de la chimie de la flamme turbulente en utilisant des mesures moyennes.  Des statistiques instantanées sont présentés comme outils supérieures pour l'étude de la combustion turbulente.  Les fonctions de densité de probabilité (FDP) des vitesses de flammelette locales pour Le &gt;= 1 montrent que la vitesse instantanée de flammelette augmente avec l'augmentation de u'/sLo.  Le FDP pour le mélange Le  ~= 1 a une forme fortement asymétrique à haute intensité de turbulence et a une forte baisse à une vitesse qui correspond à la vitesse de référence maximale expérimentalement mesurée à partir des expériences laminaires.  Finalement, dans les flammes Le &lt;&lt; 1, les vitesses instantanées les plus probables augmentent avec l'augmentation de u'/sLo et peuvent considérablement dépasser la vitesse de la flamme de référence maximale mesurée pour flammes laminaires.Ces résultats sont renforcés par mesures de position instantanée de la flamme.  Les FDPs de position montrent que la position la plus probable est lié au FDP de vitesse.  En outre, les  FDPs d'hydrogène sont biaisée avec l'augmentation de u'/sLo, indiquant une tendance de Le &lt;&lt; 1 à brûler vers les réactifs, ce qui soutient la théorie du bord d'attaque.Alors que les propriétés moyennes de combustion turbulente perdent d'informations physiques importantes, ce travail favorise l'utilisation de statistiques instantanées comme outil pour décrire les résultats expérimentaux et de décrire la chimie des carburants.</description><creator>Salusbury, Sean</creator><contributor>Jeffrey Bergthorson (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Experiments in laminar and turbulent premixed counter-flow flames at variable Lewis number</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c583n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m2670</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246w23d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La fibrillation auriculaire (FA) est l'arythmie la plus fréquente. Des propriétés cardiaques électriques et structurelles altérées participent à l'initiation et au maintien de la FA. Un remodelage structurel est une composante majeure de l'insuffisance cardiaque congestive (ICC). La FA et l'ICC sont souvent des événements concomitants dans les populations de patients. Les fibroblastes cardiaques ont un rôle clé dans ce remodelage structurel du cœur, ceci via la synthèse et le dépôt excessif de matrice extracellulaire (MEC), conduisant à la fibrose. Une meilleure compréhension du fonctionnement de ces fibroblastes, et la mise au point de stratégies visant leur régulation pourraient permettre un traitement préventif de ce remodelage néfaste. Le but de cette thèse était d'approfondir les connaissances sur les fonctions fibroblastiques, avec en point de mire, l'identification de nouvelles cibles thérapeutiques pour lutter contre le remodelage structural.Dans un modèle expérimental d'ICC, la fibrose auriculaire est plus évidente qu'au niveau ventriculaire. La fibrose atriale est importante en cas d'ICC, mais inexistante dans les oreillettes contrôles; ce qui conduit a l'hypothèse que les fibroblastes seraient intrinsèquement différents dans ces deux conditions. Toutefois, la culture de ces deux types de fibroblastes ne montre aucune différence dans l'expression de gènes de la MEC. Cela pourrait être dû aux conditions de culture qui occulteraient les phénotypes observés in vivo. Cette thèse démontre que les fibroblastes atriaux, selon qu'ils soient issus d'animaux contrôles ou avec ICC, sont en réalité très différents en terme d'expression de gènes, de morphologie, ou de propriétés de leurs canaux ioniques. En effet, ces différences phénotypiques d'importance disparaissent une fois ces fibroblastes mis en culture.Dans le but d'expliquer le mécanisme d'activation des fibroblastes atriaux dans le cas d'ICC, l'étude du micro-ARN 29 (miR29) a été entreprise. MiR29 est impliqué, après infarctus du myocarde (IM), dans la régulation de l'expression de la MEC de la zone péri-infarcie. D'où l'hypothèse que l'expression de miR29 serait diminuée dans les fibroblastes atriaux d'animaux avec ICC, entraînant une augmentation de l'expression de la MEC. MiR29 a une expression diminuée dans les tissus et fibroblastes atriaux d'animaux en ICC, en corrélation avec une augmentation de l'expression de la MEC. Chez les patients atteints de FA, les niveaux plasmatique et tissulaire de miR29 sont également diminués. Une relation directe entre miR29 et l'expression de gènes de la MEC a été démontrée via l'utilisation de lentivirus pour supprimer ou augmenter miR29 dans les fibroblastes atriaux. La restauration des niveaux de miR29 dans des cas d'ICC ou de FA pourrait prévenir le remodelage structurel.Il a récemment été montré que la voie de signalisation Wnt-Frizzled est activée après IM chez le rat, induisant la formation d'une cicatrice. Il y a toutefois peu d'informations concernant l'expression des différents gènes Wnts et Frizzleds dans les fibroblastes cardiaques, en conditions contrôle ou malade. Une des finalités de cette thèse était de mieux caractériser cette voie de signalisation. Les fibroblastes atriaux et ventriculaires expriment la vaste majorité des 10 récepteurs Frizzled, et des 19 ligands Wnts. Fzd2 voit son expression fortement augmentée, aussi bien dans l'oreillette que dans le ventricule, dans les fibroblastes issu d'animaux en ICC, par rapport aux contrôles, lui suggérant un rôle de régulateur du phénotype de ces fibroblastes. Dans les mêmes conditions, Wnt2 et Wnt4 voient leur expression augmentée. Les fibroblastes atriaux traités par Wnt4 présentent une augmentation de l'expression d'un gène de la MEC. Au contraire, l'inhibition de Wnt2 et Wnt4 pourrait ralentir la surexpression de gènes de la MEC par les fibroblastes atriaux d'animaux en ICC.</description><description>Atrial fibrillation (AF) is the most common type of arrhythmia. Altered electrical and structural properties of the heart give rise to the initiation and maintenance of AF. Structural remodeling is an important component of congestive heart failure (CHF). AF and CHF commonly occur together in patient populations. Cardiac fibroblasts are the main drivers of structural remodeling in the heart, through the generation of fibrosis by excess extracellular matrix (ECM) synthesis and deposition. Understanding fibroblast behaviour and designing strategies to regulate it could prevent adverse remodeling in disease states. The purpose of this thesis was to gain insight into fibroblast behaviour with the ultimate goal of identifying new therapeutic targets to combat structural remodeling.In an experimental model of CHF atrial fibrosis is more prominent than ventricular. This observation was partly explained by the fact that atrial fibroblasts are intrinsically different from ventricular; atrial fibroblasts are more responsive to pro-fibrotic stimuli. Atrial fibrosis is prominent in CHF and absent from control atria leading to the hypothesis that CHF and control fibroblasts are intrinsically different. Cultured atrial fibroblasts from control and CHF animals however, do not display differences in ECM gene expression. It was hypothesized that this was due to culturing conditions masking in vivo phenotypes. This thesis showed atrial fibroblasts from control and CHF animals are actually intrinsically different in terms of gene expression, morphology, and ion channel properties. Indeed, these important phenotypic differences are lost when cells are placed into culture.In an attempt to explain mechanistically why CHF atrial fibroblasts are more activated as compared to control, microRNA29 (miR29) was investigated. MiR29 has been implicated in regulating ECM expression in the border zone post-myocardial infarction (MI). The hypothesis was generated that miR29 would be decreased in CHF atrial fibroblasts resulting in increased ECM expression. MiR29 was decreased in atrial fibroblasts and tissue from CHF animals. This correlated with increased ECM expression. In human AF patients miR29 plasma and tissue levels were decreased. A direct relationship between miR29 and ECM gene expression was shown using lentiviral suppression and upregulation of miR29 in atrial fibroblasts. Restoring miR29 levels in conditions such as CHF or AF could prevent structural remodeling.Wnt-frizzled signalling was recently shown to be activated post-MI in rats, contributing to scar formation. Little information is known regarding expression of wnts and frizzleds in cardiac fibroblasts in control or disease conditions. An aim of this thesis was to characterize the wnt pathway. Atrial and ventricular fibroblasts were found to express the majority of the 10 frizzled receptors and 19 wnt ligands. Fzd2 was strongly increased in both atrial and ventricular fibroblasts in CHF as compared to control suggesting it may regulate fibroblast behaviour. Similarly, wnt2 and 4 were upregulated in atrial fibroblasts in CHF animals as compared to control. Wnt4 treated atrial fibroblasts showed increased expression of an ECM gene. Inhibiting wnt2 and 4 signalling could decrease excess ECM gene expression in CHF atrial fibroblasts.</description><creator>Dawson, Kristin</creator><contributor>Stanley Nattel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</subject><title>The regulation of atrial fibroblast behaviour and its role in atrial fibrillation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b429b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246w23d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569755q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte: Plusieurs aspects de la réponse inflammatoire au lipopolysaccharide (LPS) incluant la fièvre, les symptômes de maladie, la suppression de l'interaction sociale, et la suppression de l'apport alimentaire sont plus prononcés et plus prolongés chez les rats rendus obèses par un régime alimentaire (DIO). Le LPS augmente également la thermogenèse dans le tissu adipeux brun, un effet médié en partie par la signalisation de l'interleukin (IL)-1β dans le système nerveux central. But: Le but des expériences présentées dans cette thèse était d'évaluer si le LPS induit une augmentation plus prononcée et plus prolongée de la thermogenèse chez les rats DIO et  d'identifier  des changements au niveau du système nerveux central qui pourraient être responsables de cette augmentation. Méthode: Des  rats mâles Wistar ont été soumis à un régime alimentaire standard de laboratoire (chow) ou au régime chow ainsi qu'au supplément liquide Replenish jusqu'à ce que leur poids ait atteint 500g et 600g respectivement.  Ils ont ensuite reçus une seule injection de saline ou de LPS (100 ug / kg). L'expression de certains marqueurs thermogéniques a été mesurée dans le tissu adipeux brun 6 et 18 jours après l'injection. De plus, l'expression de gènes associés avec la signalisation de la mélanocortine a été mesurée dans l'hypothalamus 24 heures et 6 jours après l'injection. Pour déterminer si ces changements dans l'expression de gènes étaient associés avec une augmentation de la thermogenèse, les températures corporelles et du tissu adipeux brun ont été mesurée dans une seconde cohorte de rats  pendant 6 jours à partir du moment de l'injection. Résultats: L'expression des marqueurs thermogéniques dans le tissu adipeux brun était plus élevée chez les rats DIO 6 jours après LPS. L'augmentation de la température était aussi plus importante et plus prolongée chez ces rats. Cette augmentation a persisté plus longtemps que la fièvre et que l'effet du LPS sur la signalisation hypothalamique. Conclusion: Ces données confirment que l'obésité accentue et prolonge l'effet du l'LPS sur la réponse inflammatoire. </description><description>Background: Several facets of the coordinated response to the bacterial product lipopolysaccharide (LPS) are greater and more prolonged in diet-induced obese (DIO) rats, including fever, presentation of sickness symptoms, suppression of social interaction, and suppression of food intake. LPS also increases brown fat thermogenesis, an effect that is partially mediated by central Interleukin (IL)-1β. Aim: The aim of these experiments was to assess whether DIO rats have a greater and more prolonged increase in brown fat thermogenesis after LPS and, if so, to identify prolonged changes in neural mechanisms that could underlie this. Method: Adult male Wistar rats were given access to either a chow or supplemented diet and injected with saline or LPS (100 ug/kg) at 500g and 600g body weight respectively. Long-term changes in mRNA expression of markers of brown fat thermogenesis 6 and 18 days post LPS injection as well as hypothalamic expression of genes associated with melanocortin signaling 24 hours and 6 days post injection was assessed using qPCR analysis. To determine whether any changes in gene expression were associated with an increase in brown fat thermogenesis, a separate cohort was implanted with temperature-sensitive probes to measure changes in core and brown fat temperature hourly for 6 days post injection. Results: The brown fat thermogenic markers measured were up regulated in DIO-LPS rats compared to Chow-LPS rats on day 6-post injection. Consistent with this, DIO rats had a greater and more prolonged increase in brown fat temperature. This persisted longer than the fever and treatment effects on hypothalamic IL-1β and melanocortin signaling. Conclusion: These data support a wide-ranging and prolonged effect of obesity on the response to acute immunogenic challenge.  </description><creator>Sheppard, Megan</creator><contributor>Giamal Luheshi (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Lipopolysaccharide induces a greater and more prolonged increase in brown fat thermogenesis in diet-induced obese rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kn923.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569755q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w557j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le compostage est une méthode de plus en plus populaire pour la gestion municipale et résidentielle des déchets. Le compostage uniforme est nécessaire pour obtenir un produit homogène de haute qualité et assurer la destruction des agents pathogènes. Il est donc essentiel de maintenir une température uniforme dans tout le compost. Pour mieux y parvenir, un récipient de compost équipé d'un système de redistribution de la chaleur (HRS) a été conçu, construit et vérifié. Ce système est composé d'un échangeur de chaleur, un tube en plastique, et une bobine de cuivre rempli d'eau. La digestion bactérienne des matières organiques cause une augmentation de la température de l'eau à l'intérieur du HRS et provoque un effet de flottabilité qui enchaîne un déplacement d'eau à l'intérieur du tube de cuivre, distribuant la chaleur du centre le plus chaud du compost vers les zones plus froides et ce, sans apport d'énergie externe. La chaleur est également redistribuée par conduction le long du tube de cuivre.  Les résultats obtenus suggèrent que le HRS atteint son objectif, mais des pertes de chaleur ont été découvertes à la sortie d'air de 4 ̎. Un échangeur de chaleur à air (AES) a été ajouté pour réduire la perte de chaleur. Un total de douze expériences ont été effectuées : quatre avec le HRS, quatre avec l'AES et quatre contrôles. Les vaisseaux été équipés de thermocouples placés à 33, 54 et 84 cm du sol. Les vaisseaux équipés du HRS ont démontré des températures plus élevées au cours des 10 premiers jours de l'expérience (p &lt; 0,001).</description><description>Composting is an increasingly popular method of municipal and residential waste management. Uniform composting is necessary to obtain a consistent product and to ensure the destruction of pathogens. It requires that a homogeneous temperature be maintained throughout the compost. To accomplish this, a compost vessel with a heat redistribution system (HRS) was designed, constructed and tested. This system was composed of a heat exchanger, plastic tubing and a copper coil filled with water. The system moved heat from the warmer center of the compost bed to the cooler areas at the outside and bottom of the bed without external inputs of energy. Once composting began, the temperature of the water inside the heat exchanger increased and buoyancy effects caused the water to flow through the copper tubing, distributing the core heat throughout the compost. Heat was also redistributed by conduction along the copper tubing. The HRS can be used in applications requiring assurance of uniform composting conditions and a high-quality product. Previously obtained test data suggested that the HRS system accomplished its goal, but high amounts of heat loss occurred through the four-inch exhaust vent.  An air heat exchanger (AES) was added to reduce heat loss from the top aeration vent. A total of twelve experiments were run: four with the HRS, four with the AES and four controls. The vessels were fitted with thermocouples at 33, 54 and 84 cm from the bottom. The HRS vessels demonstrated higher temperatures during the first 10 days of the experiment (p&lt;0.001).</description><creator>Jamaleddine, Eyad</creator><contributor>Grant Clark (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Agriculture - General</subject><title>Composting bioreactors: heat redistribution and heat recovery system for small compost vessels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zt869.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w557j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612r804</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Primary health care reform has become an area of priority in health policy with a strong importance placed on interdisciplinary teams of health care professionals. Quebec's model, the groupes de médicine de famille (GMFs), were introduced late in 2002 emphasizing team-centered approaches to service delivery and aiming to improve access to primary health care, especially to improve after-hours access and to increase the number of Quebecers with a family doctor.A decade after their implementation, I investigated the impact of GMFs on various measures of access to primary health care and perceived remaining barriers. I emphasize potential access – i.e. measures that capture whether an individual has the ability to access needed health care including having a regular medical doctor.I used data from seven waves of the Canadian Community Health Survey to capture reported access to primary care and barriers to access. GMFs emerged at different rates in different health regions across Quebec allowing the construction of a GMF 'participation' measure using the share of primary care physicians practicing in GMFs in each health region and year. I employed a modified difference-in-difference analysis design that uses multivariate regression analysis to control for time trends in the outcomes, time-invariant differences between regions and individual-level covariates in an attempt to estimate the causal impact of GMF implementation on access to primary health care.I verified that pre-policy differences in terms of population and socioeconomic characteristics between regions with ultimately high vs. low rates of GMF participation are reasonable and remain fixed over time, making comparisons of these regions appropriate. Results suggest that rates of reported access have increased over time in most Quebec health regions. However, these measures of access vary across regions and some always report lower rates of access. Controlling for time trends, fixed differences between regions, and individual characteristics, reported access does not change significantly as GMF participation increases. Improved access to primary health care was one of the principal objectives of Quebec's primary care reform a decade ago. My findings suggest that increased GMF participation has not improved several important measures of access, and that additional policy measures may be necessary to increase potential access to primary health care. </description><description>La réforme des soins de santé de première ligne occupe une place prioritaire parmi les réformes de santé, notamment avec une grande importance accordée à des équipes interdisciplinaires de professionnels de santé. Le modèle choisi par Québec, les groupes de médecine de famille (GMFs), a été mis en place à la fin de 2002. Ce modèle met l'emphase sur  des équipes interprofessionnelles et vise à augmenter le nombre de Québécois avec un médecin de famille, ainsi qu'à offrir une plus grande accessibilité des services de la première ligne, notamment hors les heures normales de travail. Une décennie après leur implantation, j'ai étudié l'impact des GMFs sur diverses mesures d'accès aux soins de santé de première ligne. Je mets l'emphase sur l'accès potentiel – c'est-à-dire les mesures permettant de déterminer si un individu a la possibilité d'accéder aux soins de santé nécessaires, y compris d'avoir un médecin régulier.J'ai utilisé des données de sept cycles de l'Étude sur la santé dans les collectivités canadiennes pour capturer l'accès déclaré aux soins de première ligne et obstacles à cet accès. Il existe une variation régionale dans l'implantation des GMFs à travers les différentes régions sociosanitaires du Québec, ce qui me permet de construire une mesure de participation aux GMFs constituée de la proportion des médecins de première ligne pratiquant en GMF par région sociosanitaire et par année. J'ai employé une analyse qui consiste de modèles de différence-dans-les-différences modifiées qui utilise une analyse de régression multivariée pour contrôler les tendances temporelles, les différences constantes entre les régions, et les covariables au niveau individuel, le but étant d'estimer l'effet causal de la mise en œuvre des GMFs sur l'accès aux soins de santé de première ligne.J'ai vérifié que les différences de caractéristiques populationnelles et socio-économiques dans la période pré-politique entre les régions ayant un taux élevé par rapport à celles ayant un faible taux de participation aux GMFs sont raisonnables et fixes au cours des années de mon étude, rendant ainsi toute comparaison de ces régions appropriées. Les résultats suggèrent que les taux d'accès déclarés ont augmenté au fil du temps dans la plupart des régions sociosanitaires du Québec. Toutefois, ces mesures d'accès varient selon les régions et certains signalent toujours des taux inférieurs d'accès. Contrôlant pour les tendances temporelles, les différences fixes entre les régions, et les caractéristiques individuelles, l'accès déclaré ne change pas de manière significative avec l'augmentation de la participation aux GMFs.Un meilleur accès aux soins de santé de première ligne constituait l'un des principaux objectifs explicites de la réforme des soins de santé de première ligne de 2002. Mes résultats suggèrent que l'augmentation de la participation aux GMFs n'a pas amélioré plusieurs mesures importantes d'accès. En conséquence, des politiques supplémentaires pourraient être nécessaires pour accroître l'accès potentiel aux soins de santé de première ligne.</description><creator>Dunkley-Hickin, Catherine</creator><contributor>Erin Strumpf (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Effects of primary care reform in Quebec on access to primary health care services</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257j08x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612r804</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vp20f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ignition of titanium in bulk form when exposed to a supersonic ﬂow of oxygen is studied. Prior studies have shown that the ignition of various bulk metals was possible and suggested that, despite air at ambient conditions (1 bar, 300 K) being outside the ignition envelope of these metals, they are capable of igniting in pure oxygen at elevated pressure and may continue to burn in air once ignited. The data from prior studies were relatively sparse in their measurement of the oxygen partial pressure and ﬂow (or projectile) velocity required to observe bulk metal combustion. The present study focuses on performing a systematic investigation of the envelope of projectile velocities and oxygen pressures for which exothermic reaction is observed to occur for titanium projectiles. Projectiles, consisting of spheres 3.175 mm (0.125 in) in diameter, were launched at speeds of 0.7 to 1.8 km/s (Mach 2.0 to 5.4) using a single-stage light-gas gun into a test section of oxygen with pressure varying between 1 and 5.5 bar in order to determine the conditions necessary to observe combustion. The projectile is observed using a combination of high-speed photography, photodetectors, and spectrometers to quantify the luminosity emitted. The results are correlated with the melting and boiling points of titanium, the adiabatic ﬂame temperature, and the stagnation conditions of the supersonic ﬂow. A model was also developed and successfully reproduced the main experimental trends as well as corroborated the above claim that combustion was occurring. </description><description>L'allumage de titane en vrac lorsqu'il est exposé à un écoulement supersonique d'oxyène est étudiée. Des études antérieures on montré que l'allumage de divers métaux en vrac étaient possible et a suggéré que, en depit de l'air dans les conditions ambiantes (1 bar, 300 K) étant à l'extérieur de l'enveloppe de l'allumage de ces métaux, ils sont capables d'allumer dans l'oxygène pur à des pressions élevées et peuvent continuer à brûler dans l'air une fois allumés. Les données provenant d'études antérieures étaient relativement rares dans leur mesure de la pression partielle d'oxygène et la vitesse du projectile requise pour observer la combustion du métal en vrac. La présente étude se concentre sur la réalisation d'une étude systématique de l'enveloppe de vitesses des projectiles et des pressions d'oxygène pour lesquels on observe une réaction exothermique se produire pour les projectiles de titane. Les projectiles, composé de sphères 3,175 mm (0.125 po) de diamètre, ont été lancés à des vitesses de 0,7 à 1,8 km/s (Mach 2,0 à 5,4) par un canon à gaz léger à un seul étage dans une section d'essai de l'oxygène avec une pression variant entre 1 et 5,5 bar afin de déterminer les conditions nécessaires pour observer la combustion. Le projectile est observée à l'aide d'une combinaison de la photographie à haute vitesse, des photodétecteurs, et spectromètres pour quantifier la luminosité émise. Les résultats sont en corrélation avec les points de fusion et d'ébullition de titane, la température de flamme adiabatique, et des conditions de stagnation de l'écoulement supersonique. Un modèle a également été élaboré et reproduit avec succès les principales tendances éxperimentales ainsi que corroboré la demande ci-dessus que la combustion se produisait.</description><creator>Devito, Anthony</creator><contributor>Andrew J Higgins (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>The combustion of bulk metals in a high-speed oxidizing flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jf41k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp20f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g3349</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'implosion dynamique de cinq cylindres métalliques à épaisseurs minces ayant des résistances différentes (aluminium 6061-O, aluminium 6061-T6, acier 1018, et de l'acier inoxydable 304) à un rapport constant masse-explosif (M/C) a été étudiée. L'historique de la vitesse de la surface intérieure du cylindre a été enregistré par vélocimétrie photonique Doppler (VPD). Les évolutions des vitesses ont été comparées à un modèle analytique et des simulations d'hydrocode fait en LS-DYNA. Un modèle Gurney pour l'accélération de la paroi à l'aide d'une constante de temps en fonction de la pression détonique a donné un bon accord avec les expériences et les simulations. La décélération causée par les effets de la résistance de matériel a été modélisée analytiquement et comparée à l'évolution de vitesse d'expérience. L'épaississement de la paroi a été observé directement par VPD dans un cas de charge explosif élevée et ensuite vérifiée avec la simulation numérique et un modèle analytique. Finalement, l'effet d'instabilités causées par le flambage des tubes a été observé et les expériences réalisées ont été analyses dans son contexte.</description><description>The dynamic implosion of five thin-walled metal cylinders of different strengths (aluminum 6061-O, aluminum 6061-T6, steel 1018, and stainless steel 304) was studied experimentally at two constant mass-to-explosive (M/C) ratios. The velocity history of the inner surface of the imploding cylinder was recorded via photonic Doppler velocimetry (PDV). The time histories and peak velocities were compared to an analytic model and LS-DYNA hydrocode simulations. A Gurney-based model for the acceleration of the wall using a detonation pressure-based time constant gave good agreement with both the experiments and simulations. The deceleration caused by strength effects was modeled analytically and then compared with the entire velocity history. Wall thickening was directly observed by PDV in a high explosive loading case and then verified with both numerical simulation and an analytic model. Buckling instability theory was reviewed and the experiments were analyzed in its context.</description><creator>Serge, Matthew</creator><contributor>Andrew J Higgins (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Strength effects in explosively-imploded cylinders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55zb99d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g3349</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dw54n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:18:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Shot peening is a cold working mechanical deformation process consisting of bombarding a metallic surface with small spherical media, called shots, at velocities commonly in the range of 10 to 100 m/s. Upon impact, the shots generate a near-surface deformed layer containing local hardening as well as compressive residual stresses, resulting in an improved fatigue resistance. However, the dependence of shot velocity and percentage of the total area covered by shot impacts on the surface modification introduced by shot peening are not well understood.The hardness and residual stress profiles beneath shot peened surfaces were investigated using nanoindentation experiments for the situations of three different average shot velocities, corresponding to 35 m/s, 54 m/s and 66 m/s, and two surface coverages, corresponding to a single shot peening impingement and full coverage (100%). For the situation (i) of a single impingement, a new polishing procedure was developed allowing locating an isolated single impingement, verifying that the impingement was produced by a shot that impacted at normal incidence, as well as preparing the surface such that nanoindentation could be performed on the impingement's cross-section. It was demonstrated that both hardness and compressive residual stresses increased with an increase in shot velocity. The experimental residual stress results were compared to those from numerical simulations that utilized the same peening parameters as the experiments. It was observed that the experimental results demonstrated similar behavior and were of the same order of magnitude as those predicted numerically. The main difference was that the experimental results demonstrated a maximum compressive residual stress that was independent of shot velocity.For the situation (ii) of full coverage, channelling contrast imaging in a scanning electron microscope revealed that there were recrystallized grains adjacent to the shot peened edge. Additionally, the hardness and compressive residual stresses were observed to increase with an increase in shot velocity. Similarly to the single impingement, the location of maximum compressive residual stress was independent of shot velocity.</description><description>Le grenaillage est un procédé de déformation mécanique consistant à bombarder une surface métallique ductile avec de petits billes sphériques à des vitesses élevées (10 à 100 m/s). Lors de l'impact, les billes génèrent l'apparition d'une zone déformée en surface, caractérisée par un durcissement relativement important ainsi qu'un champ de contraintes résiduelles de compression, ce qui entraîne une meilleure résistance à la fatigue. Cependant, l'effet de la vitesse d'impact de la bille et de la couverture de surface sur la modification des propriétés de surface  induit par le grenaillage ne sont pas bien compris.Dans cette étude, la dureté et les contraintes résiduelles ont été étudiées en utilisant des expériences de nanoindentation pour les situations suivantes: trois vitesses de billes différentes correspondant à 35 m/s, 54 m/s et 66 m/s, ainsi que deux couvertures de surface correspondant à un seul impact et à une couverture complète (100%). Pour la situation (i) de l'étude d'un unique impact, une nouvelle procédure de polissage a été développée permettant de localiser un impact isolé. Cette procédure permet de préparer la surface de telle sorte que la nanoindentation peut être effectuée sur la section transversale de l'impact et permet de vérifier que l'impact a été produit par une bille frappant la surface avec une incidence normale. Il a été observé que la dureté et les contraintes résiduelles de compression augmentent avec une augmentation de la vitesse de la bille. Les résultats expérimentaux de contraintes résiduelles ont été comparés à ceux d'une simulation numérique en utilisant les mêmes paramètres expérimentaux de grenaillages. Il a été observé que les résultats expérimentaux montrent un comportement similaire et sont du même ordre de grandeur que ceux obtenus par simulation numérique. La principale différence est que les résultats expérimentaux ont montré une contrainte résiduelle de compression maximale étant indépendante de la vitesse de la bille.Pour la situation (ii) d'une couverture complète et à l'aide du procédé de microscopie électronique à balayage,  nous avons observé un raffinement des grains adjacents à la surface grenaillée. En outre, nous avons observé que la dureté et les contraintes résiduelles de compression augmentaient avec une augmentation de la vitesse de la bille. De même que pour l'impact isolé, la localisation des contraintes résiduelles de compression maximale était indépendante de la vitesse de la bille.</description><creator>Mann, Philip</creator><contributor>Richard Chromik (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Martin Levesque (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Materials Science</subject><title>Evaluation of surface modifications introduced by shot peening of aluminum alloy 2024-T351</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b6659.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dw54n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12500</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>