<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:58:56Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43525" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666502h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the relationship between Islam and political  culture in Pakistan in the four decades following its naissance. It assesses the  validity of the argument that a polarity has emerged in the Pakistani political  culture, consisting of Islamism and Islamic modernism. In the case of Pakistan,  Islamism refers to the use of the primary sources of Islam law, the Qur'an, hadith,  and sunnah, in crafting both policy and political institutions. Islamic modernism  refers to the systematized use of these primary sources as well as other (external)  sources, adjusted for contemporary circumstances. These ideologies, as defined here,  are gleaned from the discourse of a Pakistani ideologues, Sayyid Abu'l A 'la Mawdudi  and Fazlur Rahman. It examines the thought of Mawdudi and Rahman as the discursive  backdrop to the polarity of political culture. It then provides analysis of three  regimes which exacerbate this polarity. They include the Islamic modernist regime of  Ayub Khan, from 1958 to 1969, the quasi-Islamist regime of Zulfiqar Ali Bhutto, from  1971 to 1977, and finally the Islamist regime of General Zia ul-Haq, from 1977 to  1988.</description><creator>Karim, Jena</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Islam and state -- Pakistan</subject><subject>Pakistan -- Politics and government</subject><title>Polarization of political culture : Islam and Pakistan, 1958-1988</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nv141.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666502h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p0819</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates substrate integrated waveguide (SIW) based interconnects, components, and systems. SIWs are high performance broadband interconnects with excellent immunity to electromagnetic interference and suitable for use in microwave and millimetre-wave electronics, as well as wideband systems. They are very low-cost in comparison to the classic milled metallic waveguides as they may be developed using inexpensive printed circuit board (PCB) fabrication techniques. In this thesis, the interconnect design is studied by investigating the modes supported by SIW using fullwave simulations. Also, SIW transitions, as well as miniaturization methods to decrease the waveguide footprint are evaluated. Next, a miniaturized Wilkinson SIW power divider is developed exhibiting excellent isolation of up to 40dB between its output ports. Another SIW component investigated in this thesis is an SIW cavity resonator. A circular SIW cavity resonator fed by a microstrip line and via probe through an opening on the top cavity wall is designed. The aperture on the top wall creates a radiating folded slot and measurements show a gain of 7.76dB for this cavity-backed antenna at 16.79GHz. The antenna exhibits a bandwidth of 250MHz (return loss &gt; 10dB). With this resonator, a microwave oscillator is designed to produce a 10dBm tone. Measurements of the fabricated oscillator demonstrate a low phase noise of -82dBc/Hz. Finally, a new SIW component, i.e. tapered SIW reflector, is designed to counteract the dispersive behavior of an SIW interconnect near cutoff. Two dispersion equalization systems are implemented using either a circulator or a coupler to route the compensated reflected signal. The systems are tested when a 1Gbps pseudo-random binary signal is up-converted to 10.7GHz and launched into the SIW interconnect. Observation of the compensated output eye-diagrams reveals achievement of a lower distortion in the highly dispersive band just above the cutoff frequency.</description><description>Cette thèse examine des interconnexions, des composantes et des systèmes basés sur des guides d'ondes intégrés au substrat (GIS). Les GIS sont des interconnexions de haute performance à large bande qui possèdent d'excellentes caractéristiques d'immunité contre les interférences électromagnétiques et qu'on pourrait utiliser dans des systèmes microondes et des circuits d'ondes millimétriques. Le coût des GIS est très faible comparativement à celui des guides d'ondes métalliques communs, car leur fabrication utilise des techniques peu coûteuses de production de cartes de circuits imprimés. Cette thèse étudie, au moyen de simulations à onde entière, le design de l'interconnexion et les modes supportés par le GIS. De plus, la thèse évalue les transitions des GIS ainsi que les méthodes de miniaturisation visant à diminuer l'empreinte du guide d'onde. Ensuite, la thèse expose le développement d'un répartiteur de puissance GIS Wilkinson qui possède d'excellentes propriétés isolantes allant jusqu'à 40dB entre les bornes de sortie. La thèse examine aussi une autre composante GIS: un résonateur à cavité GIS. La thèse décrit la conception d'un résonateur à cavité GIS qui est alimenté par une ligne microbande et une sonde passées par une aperture sur le mur supérieur de la cavité. L'aperture dans le mur supérieur crée une encoche plissée rayonnante, et des mesures ont révélé un gain de 7,76dB pour l'antenne adossée d'une cavité de 16,79 GHz. L'antenne possède une bande passante de 250MHz (perte de réflexion &gt; 10dB). En plus de ce résonateur, un oscillateur micro-onde est conçu pour produire une tonalité de 10dBm. Les mesures de l'oscillateur fabriqué montrent un faible bruit de phase de -82dBc/Hz. Enfin, une nouvelle composante de GIS (un réflecteur effilé) est conçue pour compenser la caractéristique dispersive d'une interconnexion GIS près de la fréquence de coupure. Deux systèmes de correction de la disp</description><creator>Smith, Nathan</creator><contributor>Ramesh Abhari (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Substrate integrated waveguide circuits and systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sg69r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p0819</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn009z17m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is thought that a significant mechanism of stibnite (Sb2S3) oxidation in mine wastes is through contact with a mineral of greater rest potential (whereby the outer valence shell electrons operate at a higher energy level), such as pyrite (FeS2). The goal of this research is to determine if the oxidation of stibnite in an oxygenated flow through system was increased through contact with minerals of greater rest potential such as pyrite and arsenopyrite (FeAsS) and whether this electro-chemical reaction was affected by various ratios of stibnite to pyrite (or arsenopyrite) and slightly acidic (pH 5) to alkaline (7.5) pH conditions. Four column leaching experiments were carried out using various ratios of stibnite and pyrite (or arsenopyrite). When the two minerals were mixed in columns and leached with water, the treatment with the greatest amount of pyrite and least amount of stibnite (95% pyrite) had the highest cumulative amount of dissolved Sb (Exp #2- 16 730 mg Sb/kg stibnite). X-ray absorption near-edge structure (XANES) analysis of the solid phase revealed that the 95% pyrite treatment had the highest proportion of total Sb as Sb(V)-O species compared to all other mixed treatments and 100% stibnite. These results indicate that galvanic interactions had occurred between stibnite and pyrite. Using a solution buffered to pH 7.5, it was possible to determine the effect of a high pH environment on these galvanic interactions between stibnite and pyrite. Under slightly alkaline pH conditions, the 95% pyrite treatment had the highest cumulative amount of dissolved Sb (Exp #3- 18 090 mg Sb/kg stibnite) and this amount was similar to the 95% pyrite treatment in experiment #2. XANES analysis revealed a smaller proportion of total Sb as oxide species in this experiment compared to experiment #2, possibly due to the formation of a soluble Sb complex with HCO3-. In Experiment #4, the leaching with deionized water of a mixed system containing stibnite and arsenopyrite</description><description>On croit qu'un des mécanismes importants de dissolution de la stibnite (Sb₂S₃) dans les résidus miniers est par contact avec un minéral ayant un plus fort potentiel électrique, tel que la pyrite (FeS₂). L'objectif de la recherche était de déterminer l'impact du ratio stibnite vs. pyrite et l'effet du pH sur le taux de dissolution de la stibnite. Quatre essais de lessivage en colonnes ont été réalisés. Les deux premiers essais de lessivage avec de l'eau déionisée ont montré que le traitement contenant la plus forte proportion de pyrite (95% pyrite) a résulté en la plus grand quantité cumulative de Sb dissous (Exp #2-16730 mg Sb/kg stibnite). L'analyse spectroscopique par absorption des rayons-X (XANES) de la phase solide a révélé que la proportion de Sb total sous forme Sb(V)-O était plus importante dans le traitement 95% pyrite comparé à tous les autres traitements mixtes et au traitement contrôle de 100% stibnite. Ces observations indiquent que des interactions galvaniques ont eu lieu entre la stibnite et la pyrite. En utilisant une solution tamponnée à pH 7.5, il fut possible de déterminer l'effet d'un pH légèrement alcalin sur ces interactions entre la stibnite et la pyrite. Dans ces conditions, la quantité maximale de Sb dissous a été atteinte dans le traitement 95% pyrite (Exp #3-18090 mg Sb/kg stibnite), ce qui est comparable au traitement 95% pyrite dans l'expérience #2 de lessivage à l'eau. Cependant, l'analyse XANES a révélé une proportion moindre du Sb total sous forme d'oxide dans l'essai de lessivage à pH 7.5, possiblement en raison de la formation d'un complexe soluble entre Sb et HCO₃-. L'expérience #4 a testé l'impact de l'arsenopyrite sur la dissolution de la stibnite lors d'un lessivage à l'eau. Dans ce cas, le traitement 95% arsenopyrite (Exp #4-10311 mg Sb/kg stibnite) a libéré moins de Sb en solution comparé au traitement 95% pyrite de l'expérience #2, et ce résultat s'explique par la plus p</description><creator>Adelman, Jessica</creator><contributor>William H Hendershot (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Suzanne Beauchemin (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Geochemistry</subject><title>Mineral interactions in a gold mining environment: change in oxidation rate of stibnite as affected by the addition of varying amounts of pyrite in an oxygenated flow through system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b393v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z17m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bf324</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Depuis quelques années, de nouvelles méthodes ont été développées pour intégrer l'incertitude dans l'optimisation de la planification de la production de la vie-de-mine i.e. life-of-mine (LOM). Cette thèse se sert de deux méthodes d'optimisation stochastique : recuit simulé (RS) et programmation en nombres entiers stochastique (SIP); les deux méthodes sont programmées dans le cadre des besoins des applications d'exploitation de la simulation stochastique et modélisation d'incertitude. Pour le cas de RS, le deuxième chapitre de la thèse décris le cas d'un dépôt de cuivre où dix réalisations simulées sont suffisantes pour fournir des résultats stables d'optimisation de LOM. En outre, l'étude prouve que les véritables limites optimales choisies de mine sont plus grandes que celles dérivées par l'optimisation conventionnelle. Des limites stochastiquement optimisées de mine s'avèrent environ 17% plus grandes, en termes de tonnage total, que les limites optimales (déterministes) conventionnelles de mine. La différence ajoute un an d'exploitation et approximativement 10% de valeur nette additionnel (NPV) une fois comparée au NPV des limites optimales conventionnelles de mine et une cédule de production produit stochastiquement avec le même algorithme de RS. Dans le troisième chapitre de la thèse, l'optimiseur basé sur SIP est utilisé en vue d'intégration de l'inceritude dans le processus de la conception de fosses emboîtées. Les résultats montrent la sensibilité du NPV à la conception de fosses emboîtées de commencement et intermédiaires aussi bien que la conception de la fosse emboîtée du fond de la mine. La nouvelle approche a produit une augmentation de ~30% dans le NPV une fois comparée à l'approche conventionnelle. Les différences rapportées sont dues aux différents cédules de production, du taux de décapage du stérile et d'une extension des limites de la mine qui ont produit ~5.5 mille tonnes supplémentaires</description><description>Over recent years, new methods have been developed to integrate uncertainty into the optimization of life-of-mine (LOM) production planning. This thesis makes use of two stochastic optimization methods: simulated annealing (SA) and stochastic integer programming (SIP); which are implemented in the context of the requirements of mining applications through the use of stochastic simulation to model uncertainty. For the case of SA, the second chapter of the thesis documents the case of a copper deposit where ten simulated realizations are sufficient to provide stable LOM optimization results. In addition, the study shows that the selected true optimal pit limits are larger than the ones derived through conventional optimization. Stochastically optimized pit limits are found to be about 17% larger, in terms of total tonnage, than the conventional (deterministic) optimal pit limits. The difference adds one year of mining and approximately 10% of additional net present value (NPV) when compared to the NPV of conventional optimal pit limits and a production schedule generated stochastically with the same SA algorithm. In the third chapter of the thesis, the SIP based optimizer  is used with the purpose of integrating uncertainty into the process of pushback design. Results show the sensitivity of the NPV to the design of starting and intermediate pushbacks, as well as the pushback design at the bottom of the pit. The new approach yielded an increment of ~30% in the NPV when compared to the conventional approach. The differences reported are due to the different scheduling patterns, the waste mining rate and an extension of the pit limits which yielded an extra ~5.5 thousand tonnes of metal.</description><creator>Albor Consuegra, Francisco</creator><contributor>Roussos G Dimitrakopoulos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Mining</subject><title>Exploring stochastic optimization in open pit mine design</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375w67m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bf324</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375w66b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) pandemic has ravaged South Africa, the country with the largest number of HIV-positive people in the world. In 2004, the South African government began providing antiretroviral therapy (ART) to eligible people with HIV.  The program has been very successful in targeting pregnant women, and ART use has steadily increased since 2004. This study aims to assess whether this public health intervention has had a positive impact on reducing pediatric hospitalizations and in-hospital mortality at a large, tertiary care hospital in Soweto (Johannesburg). Pediatric hospital discharge summary data from two years were compiled: 2005 (just after the ART program began) and 2008 (when ART use had increased substantially). Between 2005 and 2008, there was a 16% reduction in the total number of hospital admissions, including a 23% reduction in admissions for HIV infection, 17% for tuberculosis (TB) and 13% for TB/HIV co-infection. During this same period, overall mortality in hospitalized children declined by 74%; for HIV the decline was 22%, 13% for TB and 34% in children with TB/HIV co-infection. In the absence of other explanatory evidence, this study suggests that the observed reductions in pediatric admissions and in-hospital mortality are likely due to the introduction of widespread ART in South Africa.</description><description>La pandémie du virus de l'immunodéficience humaine (VIH) a ravagé l'Afrique du Sud, le pays ayant la population sero positive la plus élevée au monde. Au milieu de l'année 2004, le gouvernement Sud-Africain a commencé à fournir la thérapie antirétrovirale aux gens éligibles atteints du VIH. Ce programme s'est avéré un succès dans le ciblage des femmes enceintes. Cette étude présente des éléments probants qui suggèrent que cette intervention en santé publique a eu un impact positif sur les hospitalisations en pédiatrie et sur le taux de mortalité à l'hôpital.  Entre 2005 et 2008 on peut noter une réduction de 16% du nombre total d'admissions, incluant une réduction de 23% du nombre d'admissions reliées au VIH, 17% à la tuberculose (TB) et 13% au VIH/TB. Pendant cette même période, le taux de mortalité a diminué de 74% au total et spécifiquement de 22% pour le VIH, 13% pour la TB et 34% chez les enfants atteints de TB/VIH. En l'absence de preuves suggérant une autre explication, cette étude suggère que la baisse du taux d'hospitalisations en pédiatrie et de mortalité à l'hôpital pourrait être due à l'introduction à grande échelle de la thérapie antirétrovirale pour traiter le VIH.</description><creator>Hillier, Kelty-Anne</creator><contributor>Madhukar Pai (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Impact of increasing antiretroviral therapy use on trends in pediatric admissions and in-hospital mortality at a large South African referral hospital</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pd36k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375w66b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nt97k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La vasculopathie est un facteur majeur dans les symptômes et la morbidité de la maladie du sclérodermie. La blessure endothéliale, dont la source reste inconnue, semble initier cette vasculopathie. Bien que l'analyse expressionnelle pourrait aider à la compréhension de la dysfonction endothéliale dans le sclérodermie, très peu de ces sortes d'études ont été réalisées. Dans ce projet, nous avons évalué l'utilisation de la technique de la microdissection à capture au laser, (laser capture microdissection; LCM), pour sélectionner les cellules endothéliales dermiques à partir de biopsies de patients et ensuite quantifier l'expression par PCR en temps réel, (real-time PCR; RT-PCR). Dans les cellules endothéliales de tissus affectés et non-affectés du même patient, nous avons mesuré les changements d'expression des gènes suivants : VEGFR-2 (récepteur 2 du facteur de croissance endothéliale), HIF-1alpha (facteur inductible par hypoxie 1alpha), et MR  (récepteur minéralocorticoïde). La technique de LCM a été adéquate pour capturer les cellules endothéliales et mesurer une expression consistante et exacte. Les gènes MR et HIF-1alpha ont tous les deux été sousexprimés dans les cellules endothéliales des tissus affectés chez la plupart des patients, tandis que VEGFR-2 a démontré une expression variable entre les échantillons. Nous avons conclu que ce résultat correspond à une dysfunction endothéliale présente chez les patients et possiblement à un mécanisme d'adaptation de long terme de cette maladie.</description><description>Vasculopathy is a major factor in the symptoms and morbidity of scleroderma. Endothelial injury, through an unknown source, is believed to initiate this vasculopathy. While expression analysis would aid in understanding endothelial dysfunction in scleroderma, few such studies have been perform. Here, we evaluate the use of laser capture microdissection (LCM) for acquiring dermal endothelial cells from patient biopsies for real-time PCR quantification. We measured expression changes of vascular endothelial growth factor receptor-2 (VEGFR-2), hypoxia-inducible factor-1alpha (HIF-1alpha) and mineralocorticoid receptor (MR) between endothelial cells from involved and non-involved skin of same patient. LCM was adequate for acquisition of endothelial cells as it provided consistent and accurate expression Both MR and HIF-1alpha were found to be underexpressed in endothelial cells from involved skin in most patients, whereas VEGFR-2 displayed varying expression between samples. We concluded that this results from abnormal endothelial function in scleroderma and a possible adaptation mechanism in long-term disease.</description><creator>Di Capua, Daniele-Mario</creator><contributor>Mark Anthony Trifiro (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Differential gene expression patterns of the vasculature in scleroderma biopsies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214p484.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nt97k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806013h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La simulation numérique des écoulements tridimensionnels visqueux turbulents et des phénomènes associés au givrage en vol reste à ce jour trop coûteux en ressources numériques quand il s'agit d'effectuer des études paramétriques, comme lors d'un processus de certification ou de l'optimisation de systèmes d'antigivrage. Dans le but de rendre ce type de simulations plus abordables, une modélisation d'ordre réduit basée sur la méthode de Décomposition Orthogonale Propre (DOP) est présentée dans cette thèse. Cette méthode constitue une approche largement répandue pour extraire une approximation de simulation CFD peu coûteuse à partir d'un nombre limité de solutions préalablement obtenues, appelées "snapshots". La DOP, munie de la méthode d'interpolation multidimensionnelle Kriging, est capable de prédire une solution intermédiaire pour trois paramètres d'entrée ou plus. Cette approche est ici appliquée à la simulation du givrage en vol. D'autres exemples d'applications présentes et futures de DOP dans les domaines du givrage en vol et du Computational Wind Engineering sont aussi présentés. La méthode de sélection des simulations CFD préalablement calculées ("snapshots") ainsi que la performance de la méthode d'interpolation Kriging sont identifiées comme étant les deux facteurs principaux affectant la qualité des approximations obtenues par DOP. La continuité des coefficients α de la DOP utilisés lors de l'interpolation Kriging est examinée.</description><description>3D fully viscous turbulent aero-icing simulation remains too computationally intensive when broad range parametric studies are needed, such as during a certification process or anti-icing systems optimization. In order to make such simulations more practical, this work presents a reduced order modeling based on the Proper Orthogonal Decomposition (POD) method which is a popular approach to extract a low-cost CFD approximation from a limited number of "snapshots". POD, equipped with multidimensional Kriging interpolation method, is able to predict the uncalculated solution at intermediate values of three and more input parameters. In this work, this approach is applied to calculate in-flight icing. Also presented are the examples of other current and future applications of POD in aero-icing including droplet impingement calculation and Computational Wind Engineering. The method of selecting the pre-computed CFD solutions (snapshots) and the performance of the Kriging interpolation method are identified as the two main factors which affect the quality of POD approximations. The smoothness of POD coefficients α assumed during Kriging interpolation is examined.</description><creator>Lappo, Vladislav</creator><contributor>Wagdi George Habashi (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical</subject><title>Real-time aero-icing simulations using reduced order model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vt74g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806013h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708w90k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La formation de faisceaux à accès simple, également appelé formation de faisceaux micro-ondes ou radiofréquences (RF), a l'avantage sur la formation de faisceaux numérique au niveau du coût et de la consommation d'énergie puisqu'elle ne requiert  qu'un récepteur infradyne et convertisseur analogique-numérique (ADC) plutôt qu'un par antenne.  Nous développons un nouvel algorithme de formation de faisceaux à accès  simple basé sur le critère d'erreur quadratique moyenne minimale (MMSE).  Cette nouvelle méthode est conçue afin de minimiser le nombre de réglages servant à estimer les pondérations optimales.  Ceci facilite la mise en œuvre pratique et rend plus convenable les applications à haut débit, là où les algorithmes de perturbation populaires nécessite un ajustement continu.  Les simulations numériques révèlent que l'algorithme proposé démontre une performance prometteuse en présence de multiples signaux d'interférences et est moins sujet que les algorithmes de perturbation aux pertes de performance causées par la résolution finie des déphaseurs et contrôles d'amplitude.</description><description>Single-port beamforming, otherwise known as microwave or radio-frequency (RF) beamforming, is advantageous over digital beamforming in terms of cost and power consumption, as the former only requires one downconversion receiver and analog-to-digital converter (ADC) in total, while the latter requires one downconversion receiver and ADC per antenna. We develop a novel, single-port beamforming algorithm based on the minimum mean-square error (MMSE) criterion. This new method is designed to minimize the number of weight changes required to estimate the optimal weights, thereby making it easier to implement in practice, and more suitable for high-data-rate applications than the popular perturbation algorithms, which require their weights be continuously switched. Numerical simulations reveal that the proposed algorithm demonstrates promising performance in the presence of multiple interfering signals, and is less susceptible to performance degradation than the perturbation algorithm when subjected to finite-resolution phase shifters and amplitude-control devices.</description><creator>Lawrence, Brian</creator><contributor>Ioannis Psaromiligkos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Adaptive beamforming for high-data-rate wireless systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831ck41p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708w90k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c087z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>I explore the complex relationships between the two metaphors of "roots" and "routes" in the process of identity constructions through an inquiry of Chinese immigrants' reflections and reflexive thinking about their immigration life experiences. I adopt a social constructivist, social cultural frame work to examine the discourses, claims, counterclaims, and voices of five Chinese immigrant adolescents in Toronto.  By presenting how these five Chinese immigrant adolescents represent, reposition, and reconstruct themselves in the Toronto urban context, I map out the "routes" they take to be who they perceive they are and are not. I examine the roles their cultural "roots" played in these processes of identity construction. This study reveals that these five Chinese immigrant adolescents' identity constructions are relational, contextual and ambivalent processes in which the discourses of race, nationality and culture are constantly emerging, altered, and renewed.  These "routes" and their cultural "roots" are mutually intertwined in these processes of identity construction.</description><description>J'étudie les rapports complexes entre les deux métaphores homonymes « roots » (racines) et « routes » (voies, routes) dans le processus de construction d'identité en analysant les réflexions et les pensées d'immigrants chinois sur leur expérience de vie. J'adopte un cadre socio-constructiviste, socio-culturel pour examiner les discours, les affirmations et contre-affirmations et les voix de cinq adolescents immigrés chinois de Toronto.  En montrant comment ces adolescents se représentent, se repositionnent et se reconstruisent dans le contexte urbain de Toronto, je trace les « routes » qu'ils empruntent pour être qui ils se perçoivent être et ne pas être. J'examine les rôles que leurs « racines » culturelles ont joués dans ces processus de construction d'identité. Cette étude révèle que les constructions d'identité de ces cinq adolescents immigrés chinois sont des processus relationnels, contextuels et ambivalents dans lesquels les discours de race, de nationalité et de culture sont constamment évoqués, modifiés et renouvelés.  Ces « routes » et leurs « racines » culturelles sont mutuellement entrelacées dans ces processus de construction d'identité.</description><creator>Liu, Chunjiao</creator><contributor>Mary H Maguire (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Education - Sociology of</subject><title>Roots and routes: a reimaging of Chinese immigrant adolescents' identity constructions in Toronto</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602108j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c087z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430513s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La projection dynamique par gaz froid, ou «cold spray», est une technologie relativement nouvelle avec laquelle des revêtements sont produits en projetant des poudres métalliques à grande vitesse, créant ainsi des liaisons particule/particule par déformation plastique intense à des températures bien inférieures aux points de fusions des poudres. Dans la présente étude des revêtements de métaux purs à cristallographie cubique faces centrées (i.e. nickel, cuivre et aluminium) ont été produits par projection dynamique par gaz froid. La microscopie électronique en transmission (MET) et la diffraction des électrons rétrodiffusés, ou EBSD (Electron Back Scattered Diffraction), ont été utilisées pour étudier les modifications de microstructures des particules de poudres durant la projection dynamique par gaz froid. L'effet de la température du gaz sur la microstructure des revêtements de cuivre ainsi que le rôle d'un traitement thermique post-déposition pour les revêtements de nickel sont aussi étudiés. Un intérêt particulier a été porté sur l'affinement de la taille de grain, la recrystallization et les mécanismes de liaison particule/particule des poudres projetées. </description><description>Cold spray is a relatively new coating technology in which coatings are produced by spraying metal powders at high velocity, generating bonding through severe plastic deformation at temperatures well below the melting point of the powders. In the present study, pure face centered cubic metals (i.e. nickel, copper and aluminum) coatings were produced by cold spray. Electron backscatter diffraction and transmission electron microscopy were used to investigate the microstructural changes of these powder particles during cold spraying. The effect of gas temperature on the microstructure of copper coatings and the role of post-cold spray heat treatment in the nickel coatings are also studied. Of particular interest are grain refinement, recrystallization and particle/particle bonding mechanisms of the cold sprayed powders.</description><creator>Zou, Yu</creator><contributor>Jerzy A Szpunar (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Stephen Yue (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Materials Science</subject><title>Microstructural studies of cold sprayed pure nickel, copper and aluminum coatings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967408h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430513s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f627d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experimental hyperbaric system was conceptualized, designed and built to explore the effect of hyperbaric treatment on the respiration rate (RR), respiratory quotient (RQ) and quality attributes of tomato. Housing five containers that could be individually pressurized from 1 to 9 atmabs, the respirometer was equipped with a flow meter, control valve, pressure transducer; CO2 and O2 gas analyzer and type T thermocouples, all connected to a data acquisition and control card. A software interface was programmed to allow control of the air flow rate through the proportional valve of the flow meter, based on a PID (Proportional, Integral, and Derivative) algorithm. Hyperbaric treatments on tomato fruit showed RR to be inversely proportional to the pressure applied: RR was reduced by 20% at 9 atmabs compared to the control (1 atmabs). At the onset of pressure application the RQ was low and increased to reach a value of approximately 1 within 120 hours. Low RQ values were caused by solubilization of CO2 in the tomato cells at the beginning of the process. Early breaker stage tomatoes were subjected to hyperbaric pressures of 1, 3, 5, 7 or 9 atmabs for different durations (5, 10 or 15 days) at 13°C, followed by a storage period of 12 days at 20oC. The effect of hyperbaric treatment on postharvest quality of tomato fruits was evaluated with an emphasis on weight loss, firmness, color, lycopene content, titratable acidity (TA) and total soluble solids (TSS). Based on firmness values, control tomatoes were no longer acceptable for consumption after 12 days of post-treatment storage. Being subjected to hyperbaric pressures of 7 and 9 atmabs for 15 days caused irreversible physiological damage to the tomatoes. Treatments of 3, 5 or 7 atmabs applied over 10 days, or 5 atmabs applied over 5 days maintained marketable firmness. The lowest weight loss occurred with treatments of 3 or 5 atmabs for 5 days, or 5 atmabs for 10 days. Lycopene content of the tomatoes was improved by hyperbaric pressure followed by 12 days of maturation. The greatest lycopene content — 28% more than in the control — was obtained for tomatoes subjected to 5 atmabs over 10 or 15 days.</description><description>Un respiromètre hyperbare expérimental a été conçu et construit pour étudier l'effet du traitement hyperbare sur le taux de respiration (RR), le quotient respiratoire (RQ) et les attributs de qualité de la tomate. Il était composé de cinq contenants qui pouvaient être individuellement pressurisés de 1 à 9 atmabs. Le respiromètre était équipé d'un débitmètre, valve, capteur de pression, un analyseur de CO2 et O2 et de thermocouples de type T. Tous les capteurs étaient reliés à une carte d'acquisition de données et de contrôle. Un logiciel servant d'interface a été programmé pour permettre le contrôle du débit d'air à travers la valve proportionnelle du débitmètre basé sur un contrôleur PID (proportionnel, intégral, dérivée). Les traitements hyperbares ont été effectués sur les tomates et il a été observé que RR était inversement proportionnel à la pression. Le RR a été réduit de 20% à 9 atmabs comparé au contrôle (1 atmabs). Au début de l'application de pression le RQ était faible et a augmenté graduellement durant 120 heures pour atteindre une valeur d'environ 1.  Les faibles valeurs de RQ ont été vraisemblablement causées par la solubilisation CO2 dans la chair des tomates au début du processus. L'effet de la pression hyperbare a été testé sur la qualité de la tomate. Les pressions utilisées étaient de 1, 3, 5, 7 ou 9 atmabs et ont été utilisées avec trois différentes durées de traitement: 5, 10 ou 15 jours, à 13°C, et suivie d'une période d'entreposage de 12 jours à 20°C. L'effet du traitement hyperbare sur la qualité postrécolte de la tomate a été étudié en mettant l'accent sur la perte de poids, la fermeté, la couleur, le lycopène, l'acidité titrable (TA), et les solides solubles totaux (TSS). Après 12 jours d'entreposage, la fermeté de toutes les tomates du groupe contrôle (1 atmabs) était à un niveau non acceptable pour la consommation. Le maintient pendant 15 jours de pressions hyperbares élevées (7 et 9 atmabs) ont causé des dégâts physiologiques irréversibles chez les tomates. Les valeurs de fermeté considérées commercialisables ont été obtenues par des traitements de 3, 5 ou 7 atmabs maintenus pendant 10 jours ou 
5 atmabs maintenus pendant 5 jours. Les plus faibles valeurs de perte de poids ont été observées avec des traitements de 3 ou 5 atmabs pendant 5 jours ou 5 atmabs pendant 10 jours. La teneur en lycopène des tomates s’est améliorée avec des pressions hyperbares suivis de 12 jours de maturation. La plus haute valeur de lycopène a été obtenue avec des tomates soumises à 5 atmabs pendant 10 ou 15 jours. Le taux de lycopène était significativement plus élevé pour ces tomates soit 28% plus élevé que celles du groupe contrôle. </description><creator>Goyette, Bernard</creator><contributor>G S Vijaya Raghavan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Agricultural</subject><title>Hyperbaric treatment to enhance quality attributes of fresh horticultural produce</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591890j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f627d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397871v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis studies the political factors of the implementation of shari'ah law to end a long and bloody conflict in Aceh, Indonesia. It argues that the Indonesian government did not mean to separate the secularist Gerakan Aceh Merdeka ('Free Aceh Movement' or GAM) from the Acehnese civilians, who are predominantly traditional Muslims and whose culture has been assimilated with Islamic teaching since the twelfth century, by granting the implementation of Islamic law in the region. This thesis provides an alternative explanation for the development of shari'ah as a resolution to the conflict in the region. Contrasting existing explanations about the implementation of shari'ah in modern politics in Aceh, this study analyzes more closely the reasons that the Indonesian government was so willing to grant the implementation of shari'ah in Aceh. It is important to note that shari'ah was part of a larger concession granting regional autonomy in order to end the three-decades of conflict in the region.  Aside from analyzing the sources of the conflict that led to the emergence of two different rebellions in Aceh (the first was a religious movement and the second was a secular ethno-nationalist revolt), this thesis will investigate the Indonesian government's motivations for granting shari'ah to the Acehnese within the secular legal system of Indonesia. This thesis will analyze the Indonesian political situation from 1997 to 1999, which led to the granting of special autonomy and additionally shari'ah to the Acehnese government. This study will also analyze the importance and the development of shari'ah in the region beginning with its initial granting in 1999 until its comprehensive implementation. The analysis is focused on two fundamental elements, Qanun (Islamic pieces of legislation) and the Shari'ah Courts of Aceh. Most importantly, and running through both elements, this thesis will show how shari'ah was used politically by Indonesian nationalists and GAM, although both sides bore ideologies that were predominantly secular.</description><description>Cette thèse explore les facteurs politiques derrière l'application de la shari'ah visant à mettre fin au long conflit dans la région de l'Aceh, en Indonésie. Nous soutenons que le gouvernement indonésien n'a pas souhaité diviser le mouvement laïque Gerakan Aceh Merdeka (« mouvement pour un Aceh libre » ou GAM) et les civils acehnais, ce dernier composé en majorité de Musulmans et associé d'emblée tant à l'enseignement islamique depuis le 12e siècle de notre ère qu'à l'introduction de la shari'ah dans la région d'Aceh. fr Cette thèse propose une nouvelle explication à l'adoption graduelle de la shari'ah comme cadre de résolution du conflit dans la région d'Aceh. S'inscrivant en contraste avec les explications existantes sur l'introduction de la shari'ah dans le contexte politique moderne d'Aceh, cette étude analyse les raisons qui ont poussées le gouvernement indonésien à donner le feu vert à l'adoption de la shari'ah dans la région d'Aceh. Notons que la shari'ah faisait partie d'une plus large concession accordant l'autonomie régionale à Aceh comme condition de règlement du conflit entre Aceh et le gouvernement central qui perdurait alors depuis trois décennies. En plus d'analyser les sources du conflit qui a mené à l'émergence des deux différentes rébellions d'Aceh (la première de nature religieuse, la seconde ethno nationaliste), cette thèse explore les motivations du gouvernement indonésien d'accepter l'adoption de la shari'ah à l'intérieur du système juridique indonésien. La période de l'histoire politique indonésienne couverte par cette étude s'étend de 1997 à 1999, soit jusqu'à l'octroi de l'autonomie politique au gouvernement acehnais et à l'adoption de la shari'ah comme cadre de résolution des conflits. Cette thèse analyse également le développement de la shari'ah dans la région, de son autorisation par le gouvernement central en 1999 jusqu'à son adoption effective. L'analyse examine essentiellement deux éléments fondamentaux, soient le Qanun (lois islamiques) et les cours shari'ah Aceh, pour démontrer comment deux groupes laïques, les nationalistes indonésiens et le GAM, ont utilisé la shari'ah pour leur stratégie politique.</description><creator>Arfiansyah, M</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>The politicization of «shari'ah»: behind the implementation of «shari'ah» in Aceh-Indonesia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zw954.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397871v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806016b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Plant cells are encased within a complex polysaccharide wall that not only strengthens the plant, but also has key roles in plant growth, cell differentiation, and defence.  The plant cell wall is comprised of a network of cellulose microfibrils interconnected by hemicelluloses; this framework is embedded in a more soluble pectin matrix.  This dynamic structure is under continual modification during plant growth and development, and its synthesis and modification requires the activity of a myriad of enzymes.  Recent research has provided insight into how plants manufacture and regulate the cell wall during development, but much remains unknown.  The mucilage secretory cells (MSCs) of Arabidopsis thaliana are used as a model to discover novel genes involved in the synthesis, secretion and modification of cell wall components, particularly pectin.  These cells synthesize copious amounts of pectinaceous mucilage during development and, upon hydration of the desiccated seed, this mucilage rapidly swells, bursts from the MSCs and surrounds the seed in a gelatinous capsule.  The patchy (pty)/beta-xylosidase1(bxl1) mutant has a peculiar phenotype where mucilage release is patchy and slow, and mutant seeds are delayed in germination.  Cloning of the mutant locus revealed a lesion in an encoded bifunctional β-xylosidase/α-arabinofuranosidase.  Chemical and immunological analyses indicate an increase in 1,5-linked arabinans, suggesting the action of AtBXL1 is required for the trimming of these chains to allow correct mucilage release.  In addition to the study of AtBXL1, an enhancer/suppressor screen of the mum4 reduced mucilage mutant was performed in order to identify novel genes involved in mucilage secretory cell differentiation.  The screen identified six novel mutants named mum enhancer (men) 1-6. Characterization of men mum4 double mutants revealed two distinct groups, those that produced similar amounts of mucilage to mum4 but failed to release it (men2, 6), and</description><description>Les cellules végétales sont encastrées dans une paroi de polysaccharide complexe qui non seulement renforce la plante mais aussi agit de façon cruciale dans les mécanismes de croissance, de différentiation cellulaire et de défense. La paroi des cellules végétales consiste en un réseau de microfibrilles de cellulose connectées par des hemicelluloses. Ce réseau est encastré dans une matrice de pectine plus solubilisable. Cette structure dynamique est en modification perpétuelle pendant le développement et la croissance de la plante. Ces changements et sa synthèse engage l'action d'une myriade d'enzymes. Des études récentes ont données de nouvelles perspectives sur comment les plantes produisent et régulent leur paroi cellulaire pendant le développement cependant beaucoup reste à découvrir. Les cellules sécréteuses de mucilage (MSCs) d'Arabidopsis thaliana sont utilisées comme modèles pour la découverte de nouveaux gène impliqués dans la synthèse, sécrétion et la modification des composants de la paroi cellulaire, particulièrement la pectine. Ces cellules synthétisent de grandes quantité de mucilage pectiné durant le développement et, après hydration de la graine disséquée, celui-ci gonfle rapidement, jaillit des MSCs entourant la graine d'une capsule gélatineuse. Le mutant  patchy (pty)/beta-xylosidase1(bxl1) présente un phénotype particulier où le relargage est épars et lent, ces graines présentent aussi un retard dans la germination. Le clonage du locus muté a révélé une lésion dans la β-xylosidase/α-arabinofuranosidase bifonctionelle transcrite. Les analyses chimique et immunologique ont indiquées une augmentation des  1,5-linked arabinans suggérant que l'action de BXL1 est requise pour l'hydrolyse de ces chaines permettant un bon relargage du mucilage. En parallèle de cette étude, un screen des enhancers/suppresseurs du mutant au mucilage réduit mum4 dans l'intention d'identifier des nouveaux gènes imp</description><creator>Arsovski, Andrej Adam</creator><contributor>Tamara Western (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Identifying novel genes involved in the synthesis, secretion and modification of cell wall components in the seed coat of «Arabidopsis thaliana»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kn52t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806016b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj1392389</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Our knowledge of limb development has increased dramatically in the last decades. However, our understanding of how gene expression is translated into morphology remains very limited. Using a variety of experimental approaches, I attempted to uncover the mechanistic factors underlying variation of digit number in tetrapods during my dissertation research. Firstly, classical embryology experiments were used to better understand how anterior and posterior axes contribute to autopodial formation. These experiments have shown that from stage HH23 in the chick (Gallus gallus), both anterior and posterior axes contribute independently to skeletal elements in the manus, which opposes some models of the evolution of limb development. To complement our understanding of limb patterning, I have also observed the earliest stage of skeletal formation, mesenchymal condensation, in a taxonomically broad sample of amniotes. These observations have allowed me to record the developmental groundstate of crocodilians, the closest extant relatives of birds. It was previously shown that the chick initially develops five digital anlagen, two of which fail to ossify. This has now been shown as well in Alligator mississippiensis, excluding the possibility that the anteriormost condensation in the chick manus is a vestigial remnant from a polydactylous ancestor. The comparative analysis of initial limb patterning has also shed new light on previous accounts of skeletogenesis, mostly based on chondrification patterns. Early stages of limb formation follow a much more proximodistal course than subsequent chondrogenesis, which has been described as following a posterior to anterior sequence in the autopodium. Furthermore, skeletal elements seem to originate from a continuous mass of condensed mesenchyme, particularly uniform in the carpal area. Individual chondrification foci initiate within the pre-existing condensations, and do not follow patterns of branching as previously described. This</description><description>Malgré que nos connaissances ne cessent d'augmenter sur le développement des membres, notre compréhension de comment les interactions génétiques et cellulaires donnent lieu a la morphologie reste limitée. A l'aide de diverses techniques expérimentales, j'ai exploré les divers mécanismes qui peuvent causer la réduction du nombre de doigts chez les tétrapodes au cours de cette thèse. Tout d'abord, des expériences d'embryologie classique on testé un modèle selon lequel les structures antérieures de l'autopode dépendent du développement initial des structures postérieures. Ces expériences ont démontré qu'à partir du stade HH23 chez l'embryon de poulet (Gallus gallus), l'axe antérieur et postérieur se développent indépendamment, puisque l'ablation de chacun de ces axes ne perturbe pas le développement de l'autre. J'ai aussi observé les patrons des stades précédant la chondrification, lors de la condensation du mesenchyme, chez plusieurs espèces ayant un nombre différent de doigts. Ces observations ont permis d'établir que cinq doigts étaient présents dans la configuration initiale de l'autopode chez les crocodiliens, les plus proches parents des oiseaux, comme il a été démontré chez l'embryon de poulet. Ceci permet d'éliminer la possibilité que la condensation antérieure présente dans le développement initial de l'aile ne soit un vestige d'ancêtres plus lointains, qui avaient plus de cinq doigts. Ces observations ont aussi permis de mieux comprendre comment s'établissent les patrons initiaux de développement des membres. Il a été trouvé que la condensation du mésenchyme progresse dans une séquence proximo-distale, ce qui est différent des séquences de chondrification précédemment décrites. Le développement du carpe survient donc avant le développement des doigts, ceux-ci prolongeant les zones de condensation à partir d'une masse cellulaire uniforme. Les blastèmes de chondrification se développent à l'int</description><creator>Heppleston, Audrey</creator><contributor>Hans Carl Larsson (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - General</subject><title>Patterns and processes of digit number reduction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm46t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1392389</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731433n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Actuellement, le Ministère de l'Éducation du Québec est en processus d'implémenter de vaste réformes curriculaires qui changeront drastiquement la façon dont les jeunes Québécois apprennent et développent leurs outils académiques, personnels et sociaux.   Dans ce vaste réforme, le Ministère de l'Éducation a mandaté que l'éducation à la santé sexuelle soit aussi réformé.  La façon plus formelle d'enseigner l'éducation à la santé sexuelle sera remplacée par une approche plus spontanée, qui sera basée sur la discussion et touchera à toute les facettes du curriculum.  Elle sera aussi la responsabilité de toute la communauté écolière.  Ainsi, il y a un besoin à comprendre comment les éducateurs et les étudiants vivront ces changements.  Il est important d'acquérir une meilleure compréhension de ce que ces individus croient fonctionne bien, ainsi que ce qui ne fonctionne pas.  En comprenant mieux ces réalités, il sera possible de d'émettre des suggestions d'amélioration ainsi que de continuer le focus établi.  En ce sens, cette thèse comprendra deux sections principales visant à accomplir ces objectifs.  La première sera une revue en profondeur de la littérature qui regarde étroitement le contexte de l'éducation à  la santé sexuelle au Québec et au Canada ainsi que les débats sur les meilleures pratiques.  La revue littéraire inclura aussi l'analyse d'un document critiquant le document du Ministère de l'Éducation, «Sex Education in the Context of Education Reform », qui a pour but de guider la réforme.  La deuxième section de cette thèse est un article de recherche, qui présente un regard phénoménologique sur les  expériences des éducateurs et des étudiants pendant qu'ils s'ajustent aux réformes curriculaires dans une école secondaire indépendante au Québec. fr</description><description>Currently, Quebec's Ministry of Education is in the process of implementing broad curricular reforms that will fundamentally change the ways in which Quebec youth learn and come to develop academic, personal and social skills. As part of the broad reforms, the Ministry of Education has mandated that the delivery of sexual health education be reformed also. The former, more formal class allotment for sexual health education is being replaced by a more spontaneous and discussion based approach that spans across the curriculum and is the responsibility of the entire school community. Thus, there is a need to understand how both the educators and students are experiencing these changes. It is important to gain a better understanding of what these individuals believe is working and what they think needs improvement. In understanding better these realities, it will be possible to make suggestions for improvement or continued focus. Accordingly, this thesis is comprised of two main sections aimed at accomplishing these objectives. The first consists of an in depth literature review that looks closely at the context of sexual health education in both Quebec and Canada as well as the debate over best practices. The literature review also includes a document analysis that looks critically at the Ministry of Education document, Sex Education in the Context of Education Reform, intended to guide the reformation process. The second section of this thesis is a research article, which presents a phenomenological look at the experiences of educators and students as they adjust to sexual health curricular reforms at an independent secondary school in Quebec.</description><creator>Dowd, Courtney</creator><contributor>Enrique Garcia Bengoechea (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Education - Health</subject><title>Sexual health education in the context of Quebec educational reform</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g558s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731433n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sg722</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mineralization of the extracellular matrix of bone is a cell-mediated process, which is tightly regulated by a delicate balance between stimulatory and inhibitory molecules. A disruption in the metabolism or levels of these mediating factors results in pathologically hypomineralized or hypermineralized bone.  The experimental results presented in this thesis describe the effects of key proteins, peptides and small-molecule ions on an osteoblast cell-culture model of bone mineralization. This study presents evidence that pyrophosphate inhibits mineralization by at least three different mechanisms that include direct binding to hydroxyapatite crystals, induction of osteopontin expression, and inhibition of alkaline phosphatase activity. The data presented also demonstrate that inhibition of mineralization by mineral-binding osteopontin and MEPE ASARM peptides is phosphorylation-dependent and that this inhibition can be rescued by enzymatic degradation of the peptides by PHEX. This result identifies a novel mechanism by which loss of PHEX activity can lead to extracellular matrix accumulation of ASARM resulting in the osteomalacia of X-linked hypophosphatasia.  Finally, the thesis describes the novel effects of a potentially physiologic modulator of mineralization, inositol hexakisphosphate, on osteoblast activity – namely, that inositol hexakisphosphate inhibits osteoblast culture mineralization, adsorbs to mineral and induces expression of osteopontin. In summary, the findings herein suggest a model whereby regulation of crystal propagation/growth within the extracellular matrix is maintained by the enzymatic removal (e.g. by alkaline phosphatase and PHEX) of mineralization inhibitors (e.g. pyrophosphate and ASARM peptides) and that these inibitors regulate mineralization by acting on both the mineral phase and on the cellular expression of mineral-regulating genes.</description><description>Minéralisation de la matrice extracellulaire de l'os est un processus de médiation cellulaire, qui est rigoureusement réglementé par un délicat équilibre entre les molécules stimulatoires et inhibitrices.  Un dysfonctionnement dans le métabolisme de ces facteurs donnera soit une déficience ou un excès des minéraux dans les os. Les résultats expérimentaux présentés dans cette thèse, décrivent les effets des protéines et des ions principaux sur un modèle de cellule-culture d'osteoblaste de minéralisation d'os. Cette étude présente les éléments de preuve que le pyrophosphate inhibe la minéralisation par au moins trois différents mécanismes qui incluent la liaison directe aux cristaux d'hydroxyapatite,  à l'induction de expression d'osteopontin et à l'inhibition de l'activité de la phosphatase alcaline. Les données présentées démontrent également que l'inhibition de la minéralisation par la liaison de minéraux osteopontin/MEPE ASARM  peptides est phosphorylation dépendante et que cette inhibition peut être sauvée par dégradation enzymatique avec PHEX. Ce résultat identifie un nouveau mécanisme par lequelle une perte d'activité de PHEX peut conduire à l'accumulation d'ASARM dans la matrice ce qui se traduit par la ostéomalacie de X-linked hypophosphatasia. Enfin, la thèse décrit les effets d'un nouveau modulateur de minéralisation, l'inositol hexakisphosphate, de l'activité d'ostéoblaste. Nous avons trouver que l'inositol hexakisphosphate inhibe la minéralisation de culture d'ostéoblastes, s'attache aux minéraux et augmente l'expression d'osteopontin.</description><creator>Addison, William</creator><contributor>Marc D McKee (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Mari Tuulia Kaartinen (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Molecular Determinants of mineralization in osteoblast cell cultures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225b44n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sg722</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644s034</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le silicium amorphe est un matériau important en particulier, pour la fabrication de matériau polycristallin pour transistor couches minces. Il fournit également un système modèle idéal pour l'étude de la dynamique de cristallisation, et à cet effet, nous avons étudié la cristallisation des films couche mince en semiconducteurs amorphes, y compris le silicium et le germanium, dans le microscope Électronique en Transmission Dynamique (METD) à Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory. La cristallisation est amorcée dans le METD par une Impulsion de laser qui dépose dans le système la chaleur suffisante pour activer la transition. Un délai variable après cette impulsion de déclenchement, l'échantillon est sondée par une impulsion de photoélectron dans le MET, produisant soit diffraction ou une image avec la résolution temporelle de nanoseconde. Ainsi, utilisant le METD nous pouvons accéder à la cinétique de la cristallisation et les détails du mécanisme de nucléation emphin situ par les diagrammes diffraction et les images de l'échantillion avec résolution temporelle sur une  échelle de nanoseconde. Dans la pélicule cristallisée de silicium, on a observé trois phénomènes distincts à mesure que le fluence incident sur l'échantillon était augmenté : pour les fluences réduits, la pellicule a subi la cristallisation l'état solide, pour la fonte à la surface, des grands cristaux radialement orientés ont été produits et quand la pellicule entier a été fondu, le silicium fondu a été fusionnés dans les gouttelettes cristallines sur la surface. La modélisation de la conduction de chaleur dans la pellicule chauffée par le laser soutient cette interprtation de l'évolution de la structure observée. Des exériences préliminaires ont  été aussi effectuées en germanium amorphe.</description><description>Amorphous silicon is an important material of particular interest in the context of thin film transistors and display technologies. It also provides an ideal model system for the study of crystallization dynamics, and to this end we have investigated the crystallization of thin amorphous semiconducting films, including silicon and germanium, in the Dynamic Transmission Electron Microscope (DTEM) at Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory. Crystallization is initiated in the DTEM by a laser pulse that deposits sufficient heat into the system to activate the transition. A variable time delay after this initiation pulse, the sample is probed by a short photoelectron pulse in the TEM, generating a diffraction pattern or image with nanosecond time resolution. Thus, using the DTEM we can gain access to the kinetics of crystallization and details of the nucleation mechanism in situ through time-resolved diffraction patterns and images of the specimen. In the crystallized silicon film, three distinct phenomena were observed as the incident fluence on the sample was increased: for low fluences, the film underwent solid state crystallization, for surface melting, large, radially oriented crystals were observed and when the entire film was melted, the silicon dewetted from the substrate and coalesced into crystalline droplets on the surface. Modelling of heat conduction in the laser-heated film supports this interpretation. Preliminary experiments were also carried out in amorphous germanium.</description><creator>McGowan, Shona</creator><contributor>Bradley Siwick (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Physics - Solid State</subject><title>«In situ» study of amorphous semiconductor crystallization by dynamic transmission electron microscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752h12c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644s034</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c7906</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Gender differences in suicidal behaviour entail a challenging paradox: more women attempt suicide than men, while more men commit suicide than women. The majority of suicide victims have a history of major depressive disorder (MDD), though only a small minority of those suffering from MDD will die by suicide. The present study aimed to explore the moderating role of gender in suicide completion, with particular focus on personality predispositions, Axis I and II psychopathology, while controlling for the effect of MDD. In the context of a case-control design, 201 suicide completers (160 men and 41 women) and 129 living controls (90 men and 39 women) with a history of MDD were recruited in Montreal, Canada. Participants were evaluated via the psychological autopsy method. Differences were found between men and women in the significant risk factors, suggesting that psychopathology and predispositions related to impulsivity-aggressivity and impulse-dyscontrol may have different relative contributions to suicide in depressed men and women.</description><description>Les différences dans le comportement suicidaire entre les hommes et les femmes, un paradoxe: Plus de femmes que d'hommes font des tentatives de suicide bien que plus d'hommes que de femmes les réussissent.  La majorité des vicitimes du suicide ont des antécédents de trouble de dépression majeur  (MDD), même si seulement une faible minorité des personnes atteintes de MDD vont mettre fin à leurs jours.  La présente étude entend relativiser l'importance du genre  chez les personnes qui se sont suicidées en mettant l'accent plus particulièrement sur les prédispositions propres à chaque individu, la psychopathologie de l'axe I et II, en contrôlant les effets du MDD.  Les cas présentés, 201 suicides (160 hommes et 41 femmes) et 129 tentatives de suicide (90 hommes et 39 femmes) ont été recrutés à Montréal, Canada.  Les participants ont été évalués selon la méthode de l'autopsie psychologique.  En ce qui a trait aux facteurs de risque, des différences ont été notées entre les hommes et les femmes, ce qui laisse entendre que la psychopathologie et les prédispositions relatives à l'impulsivité-agressivité ainsi qu'au non-contrôle-impulsif peuvent avoir contribués différement au suicide chez les hommes et les femmes en dépression.</description><creator>Dalca, Ioana Mioara</creator><contributor>Gustavo Turecki (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Mental Health</subject><title>Gender-specific suicide risk factors: a case-control study of individuals with major depressive disorder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d466c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c7906</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nf19k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Identifying genomic locations of transcription-factor binding sites (TFBS), particularly in higher eukaryotic genomes, has been an enormous challenge. Computational methods involving identification of sequence conservation between related genomes have been the most successful since sites found in such highly conserved regions are more likely to be functional, i.e. are bound and regulate protein production. In this thesis, we present such a probabilistic algorithm for predicting TFBSs which also takes evolutionary turnovers into account. Our algorithm is validated via simulations and the results of its application on ChIP-chip data are presented.</description><description>L'identification des sites de fixation des facteurs de transcription (TFBS), particulièrement sur les génomes eucaryotiques plus élevés, a été un énorme défi. Les méthodes informatiques comportant l'identification de la conservation de séquence entre les génomes de différentes espèces ont eu beaucoup de succès parce que les sites trouvés dans de telles régions fortement conservées sont probablement fonctionnels (les facteurs de transcription se rajoutent sur le génome à ces sites-là et réglent la production de protéine). Dans cette thèse, nous présentons un algorithme probabiliste pour la prédiction de TFBSs qui prend en considération également le remuement évolutionnaire. Notre algorithme est validé par l'intermédiare des simulations et le résultats de son application sur des données ChIP-chip sont présentés</description><creator>Parmar, Victor</creator><contributor>Mathieu Blanchette (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Bioinformatics</subject><title>Predicting transcription factor binding sites using phylogenetic footprinting and a probabilistic framework for evolutionary turnover</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644s02v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nf19k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k768m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation offers a reading of sacred spaces and temple imagery in the Book of Daniel using critical spatial theory. It is argued that the idea of sacred space is, in fact, one of the main concerns in Daniel and forms a running theme within the narrative. Because the allusions are often vague and buried deep within the individual stories a methodology has been chosen that foregrounds the notion of the spatial. Unlike other methodologies used to define sacred space, this approach is pre-eminently equipped to perform a depth analysis of the text. Although some elements from older models are incorporated, these have been reformulated and reconfigured into a new context, which goes beyond the traditional binary model that sharply and uncompromisingly juxtaposes the sacred and the profane. Critical spatial theory adds to the traditional historical and societal vantage points the spatial view, creating a trialectic which, rather than ending up with mutually exclusive opposites, results in an integrated system able to expose the sub-narrative underlying the actual text. Thus, the concepts of 'exile', 'kingdom', and 'dreamscape' that are usually understood in a more temporal and abstract sense are now studied as primarily spatial phenomena and brought into each other's orbit. Therefore, by adding the spatial component, new insights will be gained that show how the narrative past and future bear on what are the true present concerns 'on the ground' for those who produced the text. Furthermore, it correlates the concrete and abstract realms that are described in the text and it exposes the various power relations they contain. The notion that space is socially produced, and consequently defined through the ways it is acted upon, thought about, and moved in, is one of the key concepts of critical spatial theory. The point of departure for the argumentation in this study is the consensus view that although the finished text is a product of the mid-second century BCE, especially the court tales contain older materials that may go back to the late Persian or early Hellenistic Period. The proposed spatial analysis will be applied on three levels. The first is the world that forms Daniel's narrative frame, i.e., that of the Exile, because this was obviously meaningful to the editors. In doing so, full notice will be taken of the ancient Near Eastern realia that made up the world that is described. This is followed by the implied world of the Hellenistic era especially in Judea, which directly concerned the editors of the text. This, then, brings us to the world that remains wholly within the narrative, namely the alternate realities of the heavenly realm and dream worlds, which contain the hopes and ideals of those responsible for the text. In conclusion it will be assessed what effect these three worlds have on each other and how this relationship may contribute, in the minds of the Daniel group, to producing a fully restored world in which the human and divine both have their fixed places and space.</description><description>Cette dissertation offre une interprétation de l'espace sacré et les images du temple dans le Livre de Daniel, en utilisant la théorie critique d'espace. C'est affirmé que l'idée de l'espace sacré est une des préoccupations centrales de Daniel, un thème qui existe à travers la narration. Puisque les allusions sont souvent imprécises et sont bien cachées dans les histoires individuelles, une méthode a été choisie qui souligne l'idée de l'espace. Contrairement aux autres méthodes utilisées pour définir l'espace sacré, cette approche est particulièrement bien equipée pour une analyse dans les moindres détails du texte. Bien que quelques éléments sont incorporés des modèles plus anciens, ils ont été reformulés et reconfigurés dans un contexte nouveau, qui transcend le modèle traditionnel binaire dans lequel le sacré et le profane sont juxtaposés nettement puis d'une manière intransigeante. La théorie critique d'espace  rajoute un point de vue spatial aux points de vue historiques et sociétaux traditionnels, créant une trialectique qui, au lieu de finir par les contraires qui s'excluent mutuellement, a pour resultat un système intègre, capable de révéler la sous-narration à la base du texte. Ainsi, les concepts d' « exil, » de « royaume, » et de « scène a l'intérieur du rêve »—normalement compris dans un sens plus temporel et abstrait—sont ici compris essentiellement comme phénomènes spatiaux et se sont rapprochés. Donc, l'ajout de l'élément spatial amène un regard neuf, où le passé et le futur narratif atteignent les vrais soucis présents pour ceux qui ont produit le texte. De plus, il fait une corrélation entre les champs concrets et abstraits décrits dans le texte, en exposant leurs dynamiques de pouvoir. La notion que l'espace se construit socialement—et donc est défini par les manières par lesquelles il est influencé, considéré, et utilisé—est un des concepts clés de la théorie critique Le point de départ de l'argumentation de cette étude est l'accord général que même si le texte final est un produit du milieu du deuxième siècle avant JC, les récits de la cour contiennent des données plus anciennes qui pourraient dater de l'époche Perse ou bien de la première époche hellénistique. L'analyse spatiale proposée va être appliquée à trois niveaux. Le premier, c'est le monde qui comprend la structure de la narration de Daniel, i.e., celle de l'exil, car c'était évidemment significatif aux rédacteurs. De cette façon, l'attention sera faite aux artéfacts Proche-Orientaux Anciens qui formaient le monde décrit. Ceci est suivi par le monde implicite de l'époche hellénistique, surtout en Judée, question des rédacteurs du texte. Ensuite, nous sommes rendus au monde qui reste entièrement dans le récit, c'est à dire les réalités alternatives du royaume des cieux et le monde des rêves, qui contiennent les espoirs et les idéaux de ceux qui étaient derrière le texte. En conclusion, nous allons évaluer quel est l'effet de ces trois mondes les uns sur les autres, et comment cela pourra concourir à—dans les têtes du groupe Daniel—produire un monde complètement régénéré, dans lequel l'humain et le divin ont, tous les deux, leurs espaces fixes.</description><creator>Sulzbach-Beyerling, Carla</creator><contributor>Gerbern Oegema (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Religion, Biblical Studies</subject><title>From here to eternity and back: locating sacred spaces and temple imagery in the Book of Daniel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p2909905.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k768m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fh585</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La présente dissertation expose une recherche sur la création de systèmes pour le contrôle de la synthèse et du traitement des sons.  Les travaux portant sur le design d'instruments de musique digitaux se concentrent le plus souvent, à juste titre, sur la dimension physique de l'instrument et de l'interface: le design de senseurs, le choix de contrôleurs, l'interaction avec le musicien, etc.  Le plus souvent, on fait d'abord un choix particulier de traitement des sons, pour ensuite prendre, à tâtons, au fil d'explorations, les décisions quant à quels paramètres de l'interface physique contrôleront quels paramètres sonores.  Prenant le contre-pied de cette tendance, le but principal du présent travail est de démontrer l'importance de l'espace qui se situe entre le design d'interface physique et le choix d'algorithmes de manipulation sonore, et de présenter un nouveau cadre pour le design d'instruments qui prend mieux en considération cette part essentielle du processus de design.  Plus précisément, cette recherche adopte le point de vue selon lequel le design d'instruments devrait partir d'un contexte de contrôle musical, et que le contrôle et les dynamiques sonores devraient être considérées en tandem. Pour réaliser cette approche holiste, les différents travaux présentés dans cette dissertation adoptent des points de vue complémentaires.  À partir du cas de la musique électroacoustique, le design d'instrument est d'abord vu comme fonction du contexte musical.  Cette idée permettra une compréhension des gestes qui lie l'intention musicale perçue aux dynamiques d'un système instrumental. Le concept important de "mapping" est ensuite examiné d'un point de vue théorique et conceptuel, en mettant en relation des approches perceptuelles, systémiques et mathématiques de ce sujet. Seront élaborés à partir de ce cadre un espace de design de mapping, une analyse fonctionnelle de la littérature pertinente, l'implémentation d'outils de mapping, des designs de contrôle d'instruments, et plusieurs études perceptuelles qui explorent l'influence de la structure de mapping.  Chacune de ces études reflète une perspective de haut niveau dans laquelle les structures de contrôle sont superposées à un espace de contrôle et de paramètres de synthèse sonore de hautes dimensions.  Selon cette perspective, les dynamiques gestuelles et les réponses sonores désirées sont obtenues à partir d'une construction modulaire de couches de mapping qui sont elles-mêmes sujettes à un contrôle paramétrique.  En complément à cette conception du processus de design, ce travail est conclu avec une approche selon laquelle la création de contrôles gestuels et de dynamiques sonores sont considérés au bas niveau du modèle sonore sous-jacent.  En résulte un système adaptatif spécialisé pour les transformations basées sur le bruit, particulièrement pertinentes dans le contexte de la musique électroacoustique. Ensemble, ces différentes approches au design et à l'évaluation résultent en un cadre unifié pour la création d'un système instrumental.  Le point essentiel est que ce cadre répond à l'influence des structures de mapping et des dynamiques de contrôle sur la sensation perçue de l'instrument.  Chacun des résultats illustrent cela par une approche de haut en bas ou de bas en haut qui considère le contexte de contrôle musical, illustrant ainsi le plus grand potentiel d'articulation sonore qui peut être obtenu en les combinant dans le processus de design.</description><description>This dissertation presents research into the creation of systems for the control of sound synthesis and processing. The focus differs from much of the work related to digital musical instrument design, which has rightly concentrated on the physicality of the instrument and interface: sensor design, choice of controller, feedback to performer and so on. Often times a particular choice of sound processing is made, and the resultant parameters from the physical interface are conditioned and mapped to the available sound parameters in an exploratory fashion. The main goal of the work presented here is to demonstrate the importance of the space that lies between physical interface design and the choice of sound manipulation algorithm, and to present a new framework for instrument design that strongly considers this essential part of the design process. In particular, this research takes the viewpoint that instrument designs should be considered in a musical control context, and that both control and sound dynamics must be considered in tandem. In order to achieve this holistic approach, the work presented in this dissertation assumes complementary points of view. Instrument design is first seen as a function of musical context, focusing on electroacoustic music and leading to a view on gesture that relates perceived musical intent to the dynamics of an instrumental system. The important design concept of mapping is then discussed from a theoretical and conceptual point of view, relating perceptual, systems and mathematically-oriented ways of examining the subject. This theoretical framework gives rise to a mapping design space, functional analysis of pertinent existing literature, implementations of mapping tools, instrumental control designs and several perceptual studies that explore the influence of mapping structure. Each of these reflect a high-level approach in which control structures are imposed on top of a high-dimensional space of control and sound synthesis parameters. In this view, desired gestural dynamics and sonic response are achieved through modular construction of mapping layers that are themselves subject to parametric control. Complementing this view of the design process, the work concludes with an approach in which the creation of gestural control/sound dynamics are considered in the low-level of the underlying sound model. The result is an adaptive system that is specialized to noise-based transformations that are particularly relevant in an electroacoustic music context. Taken together, these different approaches to design and evaluation result in a unified framework for creation of an instrumental system. The key point is that this framework addresses the influence that mapping structure and control dynamics have on the perceived feel of the instrument. Each of the results illustrate this using either top-down or bottom-up approaches that consider musical control context, thereby pointing to the greater potential for refined sonic articulation that can be had by combining them in the design process.</description><creator>Van Nort, Douglas</creator><contributor>Philippe Depalle (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Marcelo Wanderley (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</subject><title>Modular and adaptive control of sound processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773w15p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh585</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pn89d7024</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse se veut une exploration de la façon dont peuvent se constituer des objets politiques sous l'Ancien Régime - un Ancien Régime français ou atlantique. En suivant un scandale colonial précis, l'Affaire de la Louisiane, il nous est possible de retracer les circuits qui définissent l'État, passant insensiblement des récits et des affrontements aux questions bassement matérielles ou hautement idéales. Débutant par une interrogation sur la nature des sources qui permettent la construction de cet objet d'étude, tant hier qu'aujourd'hui, cette thèse poursuit ensuite une enquête sur les façons dont les administrateurs d'une colonie française ont pu construire à la fois les conditions de leur obéissance au monarque ou de leur adhésion au bien public. Ces considérations ne pouvaient cependant s'élaborer hors du cadre particulier de la vallée du Mississipi, où l'héritage de la Compagnie des Indes et les leçons de l'expérience canadienne ont entraîné le Roi (ou l'État) à jouer un rôle, non seulement de régulateur, mais encore de négociant et de distributeur dans le commerce colonial. En agissant ainsi, la circulation des marchandises et leur contrôle deviennent des enjeux importants de la vie politique louisianaise. Cette thèse nuance ainsi quelque peu les interprétations récentes qui font du « rejet d'État » l'une des caractéristiques fondamentales de la société mississipienne. La vie politique louisianaise ainsi décrite en est une qui certes, prétend toucher peu d'acteurs, mais nécessite tout de même des spectateurs, de même qu'une réflexion sur les conditions d'exercice de l'autorité.  Ce faisant, l'Affaire de la Louisiane pose la nécessaire question de la distance et de la similitude.  En s'interrogeant sur la nature de l'intérêt, moteur de l'action des hommes, les administrateurs coloniaux - et quelques penseurs « ordinaires » ont souhaité introduire des bornes locales, administratives, à une autorité qui finalement s'avérait proche, trop proche, des prétentions de la monarchie absolue française.</description><description>This dissertation aims at exploring how political objects could be created during the Ancien Régime - whether qualified as French or Atlantic. By following the lines drawn by a specific colonial scandal, the Affaire de la Louisiane, it appears possible to discover the figure of the State, delineated by the often seamless transitions from narratives to physical oppositions, from the trivially material to the ethereally ideal. Beginning with an interrogation on the nature of the sources which made such constructs possible, then as now, this dissertation then moves towards a study of the ways in which administrators of a French colony could define simultaneously the conditions of their obedience to the King's will, as well as their beliefs in a Common Good. These conditions could not, however, be divorced from the specific context of the Mississippi Valley. There, the old practices of the Company of the Indies left the King (or the State) in a position where it was felt required to intervene, albeit reluctantly, in the commercial realm. Through these aggregated actions which made the King a regulator, a trader, or a retailer, the State became an important issue of Louisiana's political life. Therefore, this dissertation nuances recent interpretations which purported to make a certain rejection of the State, an inherent characteristic of French Louisiana. Louisiana's political life, as described, was one that could pretend to include few actors. Yet it required at the very least spectators, and nurtured in turn reflections upon the nature and exercise of authority. In so doing, the Affaire de la Louisiane necessarily asks the question of distance and similarities. By exploring the notion of interest as the driving force behind action, colonial administrators - and some ordinary colonial "thinkers" - could devise ways in which frontiers and limits could be drawn to a kind of authority which seemed, in the end, uncomfortably close to the pretensions of the French absolute monarchy.</description><creator>Dubé, Alexandre</creator><contributor>Catherine Desbarats (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>History - General</subject><title>Les biens publics. Culture politique de la Louisiane française 1730 - 1770</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx486.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d7024</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569500q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les macromolecules monodisperses possédant une architecture modulée constituent la clé au design de nanomatériaux efficaces et intelligents. Elles offrent un réel potentiel pour atteindre ce but, et un des défis précédemment rencontrés par cette nouvelle classe de macromolécules a été adressé par l'évolution de leurs méthodologies synthétiques. Dans cette thèse, i) des routes synthétiques inorganiques, organométalliques et organiques sont employées pour construire des dendrimères mono et bi-fonctionnels; et ii) une étude détaillée incluant une évaluation de leurs relations structure-propriété, utilisant une combinaison d'expériences incluant des calculs théoriques, ainsi que leurs applications en encapsulation moléculaire et en libération de médicaments, sont rapportées. La caractérisation géométrique de dendrimères composés d'unités d'alcool 3,5-dihydroxybenzyle (DHBA), pontées par des aminosilanes a été accomplie utilisant la méthode de mécanique moléculaire MM+ ainsi que la théorie des orbitales moléculaires semi-empirique PM3. L'optimisation des dendrimères DHBA de génération 1-5 (DG1-5) a suggéré que DG1-3 possèdent une structure relativement ouverte sans espaces internes de grandeur ou de forme particulière, tandis que DG4 et 5 possèdent une structure plus globulaire caractérisée par des cavités internes bien définies. L'encapsulation de disperse red 1 (DR1) dans les cavités des dendrimères composés d'unités DHBA pontés par des diméthylsilyles a mené à un déplacement vers le bleu du λmax de DR1, et la microscopie électronique en transmission (TEM) a démontré une forme rectangulaire pour les agrégats dendritiques comprenant DR1. L'activité catalytique de (COD)RhCl(PPh2(CH2)3OH encapsulé dans les agrégats dendritiques des generations 1-4, a indiqué une diminution significative dans la conversion catalytique de 1-decene à décane pour le dendrimère de génération 4. Subséquemment,</description><description>Monodisperse macromolecules with tailored architecture constitute the key to designing efficient and smart nanomaterials. They offer real potential to achieve this goal, and one of the earlier challenges faced by this novel class of macromolecules has been addressed by the evolutions in their synthetic methodologies. In this thesis, i) inorganic, organometallic, and organic synthetic routes are employed to construct mono- and bi-functional dendrimers; and ii) a detailed study including an evaluation of their structure-property relationships using a combination of experiment with theoretical calculations, and their applications in molecular encapsulations and drug delivery, are reported. Geometric characterization of 3,5-dihydroxybenzyl alcohol (DHBA)-based dendrimers, using aminosilanes as linkers was achieved using molecular mechanics MM+ method and the PM3 semi-empirical molecular orbital theory. Optimization of DHBA-based dendrimer generations 1-5 (DG1-5) suggested that DG1-3 have a relatively open structure with no internal spaces of any particular size or shape, while DG4 and 5 assume a more globular structure with well-defined internal cavities. Encapsulation of disperse red 1 (DR1) into the cavities of these dimethylsilyl linked DHBA-based dendrimers led to a blue shift in the λmax of DR1, and transmission electron microscopy (TEM) showed a rectangular shape of dendritic aggregates containing DR1. Catalytic activity of (COD)RhCl(PPh2(CH2)3OH) encapsulated in dendritic aggregates of generations 1-4, indicated a significant decrease in catalytic conversion of 1-decene to decane in dendrimer generation 4 upon going from a concentration below critical aggregation concentration (cac) to above cac. Subsequently, a simple divergent methodology to synthesize 1,3,5-triethynylbenzene (TEB)-based dendrimers, using amino stannanes as linkers, was developed. A theoretical evaluation of their structure suggested that they evolve into a turbine shape with benzene rings</description><creator>Hourani, Rami</creator><contributor>Ashok K Kakkar (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Chemistry - General</subject><title>Design and synthesis of dendrimers for multipurpose tasks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rd95z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569500q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032351z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is well established that vitamin D contributes to bone health. New evidence from cross-sectional and prospective cohort studies and a few clinical trials suggest that vitamin D status may play a role in functional capacity declining with age; however, there are some gaps in these studies yet to be examined. Little is known about vitamin D status in healthy, free-living, older people in North America. Older individuals may be more vulnerable due to low vitamin D intake and limited endogenous synthesis. Thus, the objectives of this thesis were to (i) determine the distribution of serum 25 hydroxy vitamin D [25(OH)D] concentrations in healthy older people living in Québec and determine how season, age, sex and supplement consumption affect this distribution; (ii)  determine to what extent  vitamin D intake from foods, supplements and proxy measure of sunlight exposure explain the variation in serum 25(OH)D concentrations, controlling for the effects of age and sex; and determine the dietary predictors of optimal concentration of 25(OH)D; and (iii) examine whether vitamin D status can predict change in functional decline capacity over 1 and 2 years, controlling for season and other potential confounders. Data for this study have been obtained from a random sampling of 405 participants from the NuAge cohort study of 1793 independently-living men and women aged 68 to 82 years at baseline. The NuAge sample is a stratified sample of participants in three age categories 70 ± 2 years, 75 ± 2 years and 80 ± 2 years with approximately equivalent numbers of men and women in each group. For objective (i), a cross-sectional design was applied. Serum 25(OH)D was assessed using radioimmunoassay. Data were analyzed controlling for age, sex, season and other potential confounders. For objective (ii), six 24-hour recalls were obtained for the same subjects as the first study also in a cross-sectional design. In addition to nutrient intake, foods were grouped into 6 food group</description><description>Il est bien établi que la vitamine D contribue à la santé osseuse. Des données récentes d'études transversales, de cohortes prospectives et d'essais cliniques suggèrent que la vitamine D pourrait jouer un rôle dans la diminution des capacités fonctionnelles avec l'âge; toutefois, certaines lacunes de ces études n'ont toujours pas été étudiées. On sait peu de choses au sujet des niveaux de vitamine D chez les personnes âgées autonomes, en bonne santé, vivant en Amérique du Nord. Ces personnes peuvent être plus vulnérables aux carences d'une part à cause d'un faible apport en vitamine D et, d'autre part, à cause d'une synthèse endogène limitée. Ainsi, les objectifs de cette thèse étaient de (i) déterminer la distribution des concentrations sériques de 25 hydroxy vitamine D [25 (OH) D] chez les personnes âgées en bonne santé, vivant au Québec et de déterminer comment la saison, l'âge, le sexe et la consommation de suppléments affectent cette distribution; (ii) de déterminer dans quelle mesure l'apport alimentaire de vitamine D, l'apport de suppléments et la saison peuvent expliquer les variations des concentrations sériques de 25 (OH) D, en contrôlant pour les effets de l'âge et du sexe, ainsi que de déterminer l'apport alimentaire idéal de vitamine D pour obtenir un niveau optimal de 25 (OH) D; et, finalement (iii) d'évaluer l'effet de l'état nutritionnel en vitamine D sur la diminution des capacités fonctionnelles pendant 1 et 2 ans, tout en prenant en compte la saison et d'autres variables de confusion potentielles. Cette étude repose sur des données obtenues auprès d'un échantillon aléatoire de 405 participants de l'étude de cohorte NuAge, composée de 1793 hommes et femmes âgés entre 68 et 82 ans au départ, vivant de façon indépendante. Cet échantillon est stratifié selon trois catégories d'âge: 70 ± 2 ans, 75 ± 2 ans et 80 ± 2 ans, avec des nombres comparables d'hommes et de femmes dans chaque gr</description><creator>Barake, Roula</creator><contributor>Katherine Gray-Donald (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>Correlates and consequences of vitamin D status in older people</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xc27h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032351z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qq00k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Initiation is the rate-limiting step in the process of translation, which is a complex process that requires the participation of numerous translation initiation factors (eIFs). The poly (A)-binding protein (PABP) interacts simultaneously with the poly(A) tail of mRNAs and the scaffolding protein eIF4G to mediate mRNA circularization resulting in the stimulation of protein translation. PABP is regulated by the PABP-interacting protein, Paip1. Paip1 is thought to act as a translational activator in 5' cap dependent translation by interacting with PABP and the initiation factors eIF4A and eIF3. In this study, the X-ray crystal structure of the middle domain of Paip1 (MPaip1; spanning 157-371) has been determined to a 1.7 Å resolution, revealing a crescent-shaped domain consisting of ten alpha helices arranged as five α-HEAT repeats. I show that the interaction of full-length Paip1 with eIF4A is very weak, suggesting that it is merely a stabilizing interaction in the translation initiation complex. Binding analysis between MPaip1 and eIF4A utilizing pull-down experiments, isothermal titration calorimetry and surface plasmon resonance, show that unlike MIF4G (the middle of domain of eIF4G), MPaip1 does not bind eIF4A. This suggests that the weak interaction between Paip1 and eIF4A is mediated by residues upstream or downstream of the middle domain.</description><description>L'initiation est l'étape déterminante de vitesse de réaction dans la traduction, un processus complexe qui requiert la participation d'un grand nombre de facteurs d'initiation. PABP (la protéine qui se lie à la queue poly(A) de l'ARNm) interagit simultanément avec l'ARNm et la protéine d'échaffaudage eIF4G, ce qui déclenche la circularization de l'ARNm et stimule la synthèse de protéines. PABP est régulée par la protéine Paip1. Paip1 est suggérée être activatrice du processus de traduction medié par la coiffe 5' de l'ARNm, par son interaction avec PABP et les facteurs d'initiation eIF4A et eIF3. Dans cette étude, la structure du domaine du milieu de Paip1 (Mpaip1, comprenant 157-371) a été résolué à travers la cristallographie par rayons X, à une résolution de 1.7 Å. Cette structure a révélé un domaine en forme de croissant, contenant 10 hélices alpha formant cinq HEAT repeats. Je montre que l'interaction du domaine complet de Paip1 avec eIF4A est très faible, suggérant qu'elle constitute simplement une interaction stabilizante dans le complexe d'initiation de traduction. Une analyse de l'interaction entre Mpaip1 et eIF4A en utilisant des expériences de pull-down, ITC et SPR, montre qu'au contraire de MIF4G (le domaine du milieu de eIF4G), Mpaip1 ne se lie pas à eIF4A. Cela suggère que l'interaction faible entre Paip1 et eIF4A est médiée par des résidues en montée ou en aval du domain du milieu.</description><creator>Kanaan, Ahmad</creator><contributor>Bhushan Nagar (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Structural analysis of the middle domain of the poly(A)- binding protein-interacting protein (MPaip1)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418n65x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qq00k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43550</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>