<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:33:12Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11325" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g815m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was designed to derive a demand function for fresh potatoes in Canada. Several demand functions were estimated by the method of least squares for the period 1940 to 1965. The following one gave the best fit: &lt;&lt;equation in text&gt;&gt; As would have been expected, fresh potato proved to be a staple food with no good substitute in either bread or in vegetables. Contrary to the general belief fresh potato is not an inferior, good, let alone a Giffen good. The demand curve shifted downward by about 3 per cent per annum. The demand functions were also estimated separately for the two periods: (i) 1940 to 1950, and (ii) 1951 to 1965. The demand was found to be more unstable in the second period than in the first.</description><creator>Islam, Nurul</creator><contributor>Handa, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1968</date><subject>Economics.</subject><title>An econometric study of the demand for fresh potatoes in Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246w12w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g815m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hs79w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The detection of glycoproteins in histological sections by light microscopy is obtained with the periodic acid-Schiff technique. In the hope of adapting this technique to the electron microscope, a three-step procedure was developed, the periodic acid-chromic acid-silver methenamine technique. This technique maintains glycoproteins as well as glycogen, with only negligible side reactions (unspecific in nature). Glutaraldehyde fixed tissues of the rat were stained with periodic acid-chromic acid-silver methenamine and examined in the electron microscope. Some saccules of the Golgi apparatus were stained in all cells examined. This part of the Golgi apparatus was referred to as the mature face in contrast to the forming face, where the saccules were unstained. In secretory cells, precursors of the secretory material were observed within the Golgi region. In these and in non-secretory cells, small vesicles and dense bodies (lysosomes) which may be of Golgi origin were also stained. Briefly, glycoproteins seem to be restricted to the Golgi apparatus and derivatives.</description><creator>Hernandez, William L.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1968</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>Presence of periodic acid-reactive carbohydrate in the Golgi apparatus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731716m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hs79w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qg42q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The relation between the mean cooling rate, T, of a solidifying magma and the total number of nuclei of phase I, ZI. formed in a unit volume of the melt is approximately: ZI α Tn is a numerical constant determined by the dominant growth-controlling process during the nucleation period. Since near the margins of large dykes or is inversely proportional to the square of the distance, y, from the contact one might expect ZI α Y-2n This relation adequately describes the observed variation of Z for clinopyroxene and plagioclase across two large dykes. In one, an olivine tholeiite the value of n is significantly greater for the clinopyroxene (0.5) than the plagioclase (0.2). In the other, a tholeiite, both minerals have the same n value (0.3). The growth-controlling mechanisms of plagioclase and clinopyroxene thus probably differ in silica-saturated melts but are the same in silica-oversaturated melts.</description><creator>Gray, Norman H.</creator><contributor>Kranck, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1968</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The growth of plagioclase and clinopyroxene crystallizaing magma</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765374157.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qg42q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623g716</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The indicator fractionation technique was used to study blood flow to the pancreas and gastrointestinal organs of the dog. No evidence for the existence of a physiological gradient in functional perfusion rate in the intestine was found. A detailed study of the haemodynamic changes occurring in experimental acute pancreatitis was undertaken. In oedematous pancreatitis, pancreatic blood flow was increased although the perfusion rate was decreased. In contrast, in haemorrhagic pancreatitis, a marked reduction in both pancreatic blood flow and pancreatic perfusion rate was found. Treatment with LMW Dextran prevented these changes from taking place. Denervation of the pancreas resulted in an increase in blood flow to the gland. The relationship between pancreatic blood flow and secretion was studied. Stimulation of the pancreas with either secretin, pancreozymin, urecholine or pentagastrin resulted in an increase in secretion rate, and also in an increase in the blood supply to the gland.</description><creator>Goodhead, Bernard</creator><contributor>MacLean, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1968</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Studies on pancreatic and gastrointestinal blood flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784p80f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623g716</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s571m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cellular responses in normal and immune lesions on the rabbit ear and back were studied by means of the Rebuck skin window technique. Development of a special means of protection was required to maintain skin windows on the rabbit back. The normal response on the back was found to differ slightly from that of the ear. On the ear antigen was applied topically to the skin window abrasions, while on the back antigen was injected intradermally to elicit classical Arthus reactions for windowing. Comparison of Arthus and control cellular responses revealed no qualitative differences, but some quantitative differences. The most striking finding was the increased percentage of basophils in the Arthus lesions. Polymorphonuclear neutrophils and red blood cells were also increased. Eosinophils were not a marked feature of the cellular exudate.</description><creator>Deutsch, Gail F.</creator><contributor>Watson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1968</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>The Arthus reaction: a study of the cellular response in rabbits utilizing the skin window technique</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462850f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s571m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n2042274</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Comparative changes in body weight, coronary functional responses, blood cholesterol levels, blood free fatty acid levels, and blood alcohol levels ,wrere studied in groups of 6 to 13 male rabbits maintained for periods of 3 to 5 months in different experiments. The animals were either 1) on a normal basic diet (Purina Chow, approximately, 150 g. with water ad lib.); 2) on the same basic diet with added cholesterol (2%) and corn oil (6%); 3) on the same basic diet with added cholesterol and alcohol in 'low' and 'high' daily oral administrations. Coronary functional responses were tested in different animals by recording the ECG changes (Lead II, and precordial V), induced by hypoxia (10% O2), standardized exercise, adrenaline (100 ug/kg, i.v. ), noradrenaline (100 ug/kg, i.v.), isoprenaline (10 ug/kg, i.v.), and vasopressin, (1.0 I.U./kg, i.v.).</description><creator>Boyaner, Harold G.</creator><contributor>Shister, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1968</date><subject>Pharmacology.</subject><title>The influence of ethyl alcohol on coronary functional responses in normal and atherosclerotic rabbits</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rm487.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n2042274</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wt66n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1910, Ewins and Laidlaw (1) found that perfusion of tyramine or tryptamine (2) through the liver of the rabbit yielded p-hydroxyphenylacetic acid and indoleacetic acid, respectively. The transformation of amine to acid was thought to be of a hydrolytic nature by these workers.</description><creator>Birnbaum, Henry</creator><contributor>Sourkes, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1968</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Cofactor requirements of rat liver mitochondrial monoamine oxidase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k5656.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wt66n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gp16q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Estradiol-17β-6,7-3H was administered to pregnant women both normal and diabetic. The specific activities of estrogen metabolites (estrone, estriol, 16-epiestriol, 16α-hydroxyestrone and 16-ketoestradiol- 17β) were measured following β-glucuronidase hydrolysis. The specific activity of urinary estriol was one-sixth and one-tenth that of estrone in two normal pregnancies and the specific activity of estrone was slightly greater or almost equal to those of 16-epiestriol, 16α-hydroxyestrone and 16-ketoestradiol-17β. The latter three were equal to each other, in normal pregnancy. In two diabetic pregnancies, the specific activity of estriol was 30% and 50% that of estrone and the specific activity of estrone was not as high as in normal pregnancy. The endogenous levels of seven estrogen metabolites (2-methoxyestrone, estrone, 16α-hydroxyestrone, 16-ketoestradiol-17β, estradiol, 16-epiestriol and estriol) were also investigated, particularly with respect to their modes of conjugation. In both normal and diabetic pregnancy the main form of conjugation with respect to total urinary estrogen was as glucuronide. However, very substantial amounts of 16-ketoestradiol-17β, 16α-hydroxyestrone and, on occasion, estrone were liberated by solvolysis, suggesting sulfate conjugation. In two diabetic pregnancies evidence was obtained for high estrone levels.</description><creator>Anuman-Rajadhon, Yuwan</creator><contributor>Hobkirk, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1968</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Some aspects of estrogen metabolism in human pregnancy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jf281.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gp16q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vb795</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phage neutralization technique is a sensitive method for the detection of anti-phage antibody. It has found its greatest usefulness in studies of antibody synthesis in which the concentrations of antibody usually have been very low. In the present study, the phage neutralization method was exploited for the detection of rabbit antibodies directed against 2,4-dinitrophenyl residues (DNP). The sodium salt of dinitrobenzene sulfonate was reacted with bacteriophage T2. Over 90% of the phage particles were inactivated in the coupling procedure. However, the surviving hapten bacteriophage conjugates (HBCs) were found to be sensitive to inactivation by anti-hapten antiserum. Thus, anti-hapten antiserum diluted by a factor of 10^5 to 10^6 caused measurable inactivation of the HBCs. This antibody assay procedure was shown to be more sensitive by a factor of 10^3 than the EDB passive haemagglutination technique. The specificity of the reaction was demonstrated by the inhibition with haptens of related structure (e.g. Ɛ-DNP-L-lysine, DNP-OH and 3,4-dinitrobenzoic acid) of the neutralization of HBCs by anti-hapten antibody. The sensitivity of this method was further increased three times by the addition of sheep anti-rabbit globulins to HBCs which had been previously incubated with rabbit anti-hapten antibody. Amounts of antibody as low as 2 x 10-3 µg were detected by this technique. In a series of experiments on in vitro antibody formation, tissue culture fluids obtained from culturing BGG-DNP immunized rabbit spleen fragments could be diluted by a factor of 10^3, and still gave 36% phage inhibition by this method.</description><creator>Yo, Sui-Lan</creator><contributor>Sehon, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Assay of anti-hapten antibody by phage neutralization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fs01v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vb795</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gk648</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many rhythmic unit discharges in the ventrobasal complex rostral to the somatic tactile zone in patients with Parkinsonian tremor were found to be deep somatic neurons subserving pressure and joint afferents from the trembling contralateral segment. Intermingled with these joint neurons, but more rostral than the pressure receptor neurons, were stretch receptor neurons responding to muscle stretch, palpation, alteration of muscle length and tension of a contralateral segment. Latency studies with receptor identification of an apparent stretch receptor in the thenar group of muscles in the hand, showed a shorter latency than the Group II joint, pressure, tactile, lemniscal afferents.</description><creator>Wong, Andrew W.</creator><contributor>Bertrand, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Neurology and Neurosurgery.</subject><title>Physiological studies and delimitation of the human thalamus during stereotaxic surgery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r4224.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk648</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n6527</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The lipid composition and metabolism of rabbit lung was studied in vivo and in slices and isolated pneumocytes in vitro. Pneumocytes were isolated from peripheral lung parenchyma with the aid of collogenase and DNAase. The lipid composition of pneumocytes resembled slices but differed from bronchiolar tissue which contained more triglyceride. Pneumocytes oxidized carbons 1 and 6 of glucose to 14C02 producing a C1/C6 ratio of 7.1, which is several times higher than with slices. Pneumocytes, like slices in vitro and the intact lung in vivo, rapidly incorporated labelled palmitate into phospholipid, principally phosphatidyl choline. Pulse-labelling studies using labelled palmitate and glycerol with lung slices indicated that diglycerides are important intermediates in lipid synthesis in rabbit lung. Increasing the medium palmitate concentration resulted in a higher rate of incorporation of labelled palmitate into rabbit lung slices; however, the simultaneous rate of incorporation of labelled glycerol was not increased.</description><creator>Wolfe, Bernard M.</creator><contributor>Rubinstein, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Lipid metabolism in rabbit lung in vitro</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xw17q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n6527</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qn01z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of type of cleft, type of operation, and time of operation on vocal structure and function was investigated. Velopharyngeal adequacy was measured by oral examination, judgments of articulation and nasality of speech, manometer blowing and suction ratios, and cineradiography. Thirty-five subjects with repaired cleft palates were assessed. Similar results were obtained for the Langenbeck and the Wardill operations. Early surgical operation (before 18 months) tended to increase the possibility of an adequate velopharyngeal mechanism producing normal speech, although this trend was statistically significant for only one measure. Vocal structure and its function was found not to vary with type of cleft. With the exception of the manometer, the measures of vocal structure and function tended to be highly correlated, demonstrating close agreement among speech judgments, oral examination, and cineradiography in the evaluation of the repaired cleft -palate.</description><creator>Thomas, Joan F.</creator><contributor>Doehring, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Human Communications Disorders.</subject><title>The effort of type and timing of cleft palate surgery on the structure and function of the vocal mechanism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mz72x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qn01z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Communication Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117s13d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>From our seventeen years experience with the clinical treatment of coronary artery insufficiency by internal mammary artery implantation and supplemental procedures, we have encountered patients in whom epicardiectomy could not be performed and thus the application of a surface omental graft would not be of any value. This was true of two groups of patients:  - 1. These with previous pericarditis subsequent to inflammatory reactions following either previous operations or myocardial infarctions. 2. These patients with so much sub-epicardial fat that epicardiectomy was not technically possible. Since the failure to remove the epicardium greatly diminishes the efficiency of the free omental graft to, form connections with the myocardial, vessels, we decided to develop intra-myocardial pathways between right and left coronary systems both in the anterior and posterior of the heart.</description><creator>Syed, Abdul K.</creator><contributor>Vineberg, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Creation of intramyocardial vascular pathways</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nf32c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117s13d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732dd14f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We have demonstrated that following sublethal clamping of the superior mesenteric artery and haemorrhagic shock a highly characteristic pattern of parenchymal degenerative changes occurs in the heart, liver, kidney, lung and brain of surviving animals. The extraintestinal lesions are strikingly similar in nature, distribution and time of appearance in both shock groups. Necrobiosis of the entire epithelial surface of the small bowel appears to be the common denominator between these two preparations. Two major conditions were identified, therefore both of which must prevail before organic lesions will result. The all important one was an ischaemic injury to the small bowel such as was produced by a period of severe hypotension or temporary occlusion of the superior mesenteric artery. The second condition was related to the nature of the intestinal content. The intestinal chyme should consist of the derivatives of normal food. If both these conditions were met we demonstrated that re-establishment of the circulation after retransfusion or removal of the occlusion, did not prevent the gradual deterioration towards intestinal necrobiosis. We feel that pancreatic proteolytic enzymes function merely as an adjunct to intestinal necrosis.</description><creator>Sutherland, Norman G.</creator><contributor>Bounous, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Small intestinal necrobiosis and its relationship to the pathogenesis of extraintestinal lesions in haemorrhagic shock and sublethal superior mesenteric occlusion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322h77g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732dd14f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p784b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:02:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In an effort to answer some of the questions left unanswered by the classical theory of disc failure, an experimental study using clinical, radiological, human cadaveric and surgical (experimental) material and methods is made. At the clinical level, a high correlation is obtained between the side of sciatica and side of the oblique posterior intervertebral facet joint as seen on roentgenograms of the lumbosacral spine in patients with back pain. Similarly, a high correlation exists between the side of sciatica, myelographic defect and the oblique posterior intervertebral joint in patients with known symptoms of back pain and sciatica. Using dissected cadaver disc-vertebra units from a random group of patients at autopsy, a lower though still significant positive correlation is obtained between the side of posterior intervertebral joint obliquity and side of annular tear in the disc. Using a calibrated strain gauge apparatus, torsional stress can rupture an intervertebral disc without causing bony fracture and moreover, compression appears to protect the disc in the presence of intact posterior intervertebral joints. Finally, using young white male rabbits, the possibility of creating intervertebral instability with attrition and extrusion of the annulus and nucleus by unilateral facetectomy is demonstrated. A programme for future studies is outlined.</description><creator>Sullivan, James D.</creator><contributor>Kahn, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Pathomechanisms of intervertebral disc failure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903308h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p784b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qq35x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:03:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Serum ionized magnesium vas measured in 56 newborns and 64 older children using the ultramicrospectrophotometric method of Rice and Lapara. When cord blood levels are compared to serum levels no appreciable change was evident during the first week of lite, although the cord blood levels tended to be slightly higher than the subsequent sera levels. No differences were noted in serum ionized magnesium in infants who were bottle fed as opposed to those who were breast fed. No significant differences could be found in levels of serum ionized magnesium between venous and capillary samples. Serum ionized magnesium was determined during 33 exchange transfusions with citrated blood given to 16 infants. In each instance there was a reduction of ionized magnesium at the end of the transfusion with an average fall to less than 60 percent of the preexchange value. With repeated transfusions the pre-exchange level became liver, so that the lowest values occurred at the conclusion of multiple exchanges performed at close intervals. This effect is the result of citrate binding of magnesium, in vitro evidence for which is presented. No clinical effects are described, but electrocardiographic changes were seen at the lowest levels. Serum ionized magnesium levels before, during, and after replacement transfusions were determined in 20 newborn infants.</description><creator>Sugden, Donald L.</creator><contributor>Harpur, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Certain aspects on magnesium metabolism in man</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903309s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qq35x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505363s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:03:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Following the intravenous administration of (7α-3H)-pregnenolone and (4-14C)-progesterone to a subject in the third trimester of pregnancy, five metabolites, namely, pregnanolone, pregnanediol, 16α-hydroxyprogesterone, 3α,16α-dihydroxy-5α-pregnane-20-one and 5α-pregnane-3α,16α,20α-triol were isolated from the glucosiduronidate fraction of urine, and 5α-pregnane-3β,20α-diol as well as an unidentified metabolite were isolated from the sulfate fraction of urine. When a trace amount of (7α-3H)-pregnenolone sulfate and (4-14C)-pregnenolone was given intravenously to a subject in the third trimester of pregnancy, three metabolites, namely, pregnanolone, pregnanediol and 5α-pregnane-3α,16α,20α-triol were isolated from the glucosiduronidate fraction of urine, and 5α-pregnane-3β,20α-diol was isolated from the sulfate fraction of urine. Both pregnenolone and pregnenolone sulfate were shown to be important precursors of urinary pregnanolone and pregnanediol. The results obtained also demonstrated a lack of peripheral 16α-hydroxylation of the administered progesterone, and the conversion of pregnenolone, pregnenolone sulfate and progesterone to neutral 16α-hydroxypregnanes in pregnancy urine.</description><creator>Stanczyk, Frank Z.</creator><contributor>Solomon, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>In vivo metabolism of pregnenolone and progesterone sulfate in pregnant subjects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mq68q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505363s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sg76q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:03:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous studies showed that &lt;&lt;Penicillium cyaneo-fulvum&gt;&gt; elaborates an antiviral substance in stationary cultures. In the present investigation, it was shown that the mould produces the antiviral agent in agitated fermentor culture. Antiviral culture filtrates were purified by precipitation of. impurities with acetone, followed by dialysis and concentration. The product was subjected to gel filtration, which resulted in a significant increase in activity, on a weight basis, when compared with non gel-filtered samples. Lyophilization resulted in a partial loss of activity of the antiviral preparation, but no change in the ultraviolet spectrum of the material. Studies on gel-filtered preparations indicated that, in contrast to previous speculation, no amino acids in any form were associated with the active substance. A small amount of ribonucleic acid was found, as well as phosphate not associated with ribonucleic acid. A significant amount of carbohydrate of a heterogeneous nature was present in antiviral preparations.</description><creator>Russ, Laurence J.</creator><contributor>Cooke, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology.</subject><title>An antiviral substance from &lt;&lt;Penicillium cyaneo-fulvum&gt;&gt;: physical and chemical studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qn027.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sg76q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fv850</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:03:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although muscular dystrophy was first described over 100 years ago, little progress has been made towards the understanding of the basic defects responsible for this affliction. Recent clinical, biochemical, histochemical, and histological studies have added knowledge and increased our understanding of this disease, but its fundamental nature is still unknown. Recent discovery of acetylcarnitylcholine in rat tissues has led us into investigating a hydrolytic product of it, namely, carnitylcholine. Injection of carnitylcholine into rat muscle caused enzyme movements from muscle to serum. This drug increased the activity of the pentose phosphate shunt in muscle and also caused an excess excretion of creatine and inorganic phosphate in the urine of experimental rats. These biochemical properties of carnitylcholine, its pharmacological actions, and its possible natural-occurrence, have led us to postulate that carnitylcholine, or some closely related substance, might be a causative factor in the etiology of Progressive Muscular Dystrophy.</description><creator>Pang, David C.</creator><contributor>Hosein, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Effects of intramuscular injection of carnitylcholine on enzyme movements in rat tissues</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jp86j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fv850</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r6296</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:03:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies of the effect of α-methyltryptophan on carbohydrate metabolism have shown that this amine acid analogue stimulates hepatic glycogenesis in the rat, in contrast to tryptophan which inhibits this process. Other differences in the actions of the two amino acids have been found: whereas tryptophan interferes with the conversion of the exogenous pyruvate into glycogen, α-methyltryptophan does not. Tryptophan promotes an increase in the assayable level of phosphoenolpyruvate carboxykinase in liver, but α-methyltryptophan causes a decrease. α-Methyltryptophan acts only in the presence of glucocorticoids. Furthermore, α-methyltryptophan accelerates in vivo the oxidation of tryptophan, an essential amino acid, thus probably creating an amine acid imbalance. Decreased utilization of amino acids for protein synthesis, together with the availability of endogenous or exogenous glucocorticoids could account for the glycogenetic property of α-methyltryptophan. Some metabolites of tryptophan were also examined. Only 3-hydroxyanthranilic acid mimicked the effect of tryptophan with respect to inhibition of glycogenesis and enhancement of phosphoenolpyruvate carboxykinase activity.</description><creator>Oravec, Michael</creator><contributor>Sourkes, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>α-methyltryptophan and hepatic glycogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892f11h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r6296</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr172133f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:03:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hydrozoa, phylum Coelenterata, having high regenerative powers, have often been employed by investigators in the study of problems of regeneration, polarity, form regulation etc. Because of their long stems, Tubularia and Corymorpha have been most often used as material, but studies have also been made on Obelia, Campanularia, Pennaria, Eudendrium, Podocoryne, Hydractinia and others. Hydras, too, have been frequently utilized, and experiments on this form were the first to be reported. [...]</description><creator>Davidson, Margaret E. M.</creator><contributor>Berrill, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Regeneration (Biology)</subject><subject>Hydromedusae.</subject><title>Regeneration in hydroids.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547v659.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172133f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xm79w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:03:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the main purposes of the science of Psychology is the prediction of human behaviour. To attain such a goal, the nature of the behaviour in question must be adequately and reliably known. Therefore, the initial step is one of observation and description, and, when the results of these activities are substantial, one may attempt to predict the behaviour of the individual. As applied to the educational field, Psychology has made extensive efforts to estimate, in advance, the lively scholastic success of the college student. In particular, the present study seeks to predict the success of a sample of McGill students in the field of engineering training. A survey of the heavy academic mortality rate in engineering colleges of many different universities will make it apparent that the purpose set for this study is decidedly a practical one. For example, at McGill University, of the class entering the first year of Engineering in 1935, only about 43% received degrees in 1939, taking account of both the Spring and Fall Convocation. [...]</description><creator>De Jersey, Murray Gordon.</creator><contributor>Kellogg, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Psychology -- Experiments.</subject><subject>Engineering.</subject><title>The prediction of engineering aptitude.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t2482.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xm79w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w289f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:03:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This investigation deals primarily with the behavior of aluminum-alloy beams in pure bending, where fibre stresses have exceeded the proportional limit of the material; and includes an extension of the bending theory to take into account plastic stress-strain characteristics. A comparison is made between experimental test data and theoretical studies based on simple tension and compression relationships. The advantage in structural analysis of using theoretical moment values in the plastic range is discussed, and practical methods of applying the plastic bending theory to light-metal design are outlined.</description><creator>De Stein, Joseph Louis.</creator><contributor>Jamieson, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>The structural value of light alloy sections in the plastic range.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nx780.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w289f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483n41z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:03:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the preparation of GR-S using the Mutual recipe considerable gel formation occurs after about 80% conversion, producing polymer of such inferior quality that the reaction must be stopped before this point has been reached. Efficient plant operation then depends upon recovery of the unchanged styrene and butadiene[...] In both the recovered butadiene and styrene, polymerization may occur to produce a polymer, which is practically insoluble in any of the usual rubber solvents. This polymer usually occurs as a deposit in the condensers, in the styrene recovery unit, while the counterpart in the butadiene recovery occurs mainly in the rerun tower. Since the insoluble polymer formed from styrene containing small amounts of butadiene is usually white and has a cauliflower-like appearance, it is known as “popcorn” polymer. Insoluble butadiene polymer is usually glassy and brittle and varies in color from white to green or brown. Both types of popcorn show such proliferative activity that at intervals, production may have to be stopped to clean the condensers mechanically. In the recovery units of the Polymer Corporation plant at Sarnia, Canada, it has been necessary on occasion, to cut the styrene condensers apart to remove the popcorn. The economic waste of such an operation is apparent. It was with a view to elucidating the mechanism of formation and growth of popcorn, with the ultimate aim of completely preventing the reaction, that the present investigation was made.[...]</description><creator>Devins, John Clarence.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The mechanism of popcorn polymer formation.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m2602.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n41z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t954s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:03:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The idea of extracting U.H.F. energy from a wave guide by means of slots, is shown to be of importance in the design of two-dimensional arrays. A description is given of the apparatus and method used in impedance measurements in wave guides. Several characteristics of slots are investigated. Graphs are drawn for the variation of the admittance of a shunt slot with the slot length, width and position on the guide. Considerable work was done on the frequency characteristics of slots, and the results are given in graphical form. An interesting and important use of slots, that of the coupling of guides, is discussed. Since this type of coupling is useful in the feeding of two dimensional arrays, its frequency characteristics were investigated. The advantage of a shunt-series coupling, over a series-series or shunt-shunt, is given in some detail.</description><creator>Dodds, John William.</creator><contributor>Watson, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Some characteristics of slots in ultra-high frequency wave guides.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451m84n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t954s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11350</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>