<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:13:51Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):6050" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vb239</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The reduction of molecular oxygen (O2) into water (H2O) provides a sustainable source of energy that fuels the synthesis of molecules and materials in nature. Myriad biochemical processes, including metabolism, plant defense, fruit browning, barnacle adhesion and mammalian pigmentation (i.e. melanogenesis) harness this energy by converting phenols into ortho-quinones, whose innate reactivity drives additional functionalization.  Since water is the only stoichiometric byproduct and ortho-quinones are exceptionally versatile synthetic intermediates, melanogenesis provides a blueprint for clean and sustainable synthesis. More than 50 years of bioinorganic studies have, however, revealed significant challenges in catalyzing the aerobic oxygenation of phenols and current methods are neither efficient nor versatile enough to be practical. This thesis details a methodology which overcome this longstanding challenge of biomimetic catalysis and describe a rapid and selective preparation of biologically active poly-substituted quinones and catechols, indole, furan and benzothiazine heterocycles and polymeric pigments under room temperature, open-flask conditions. A new approach to the direct functionalization of carbon-hydrogen (C-H) bonds that hinges on the reactivity of semiquinone-metal complexes, and selectively forms carbon-oxygen (C-O), carbon-nitrogen (C-N) and carbon-sulfur (C-S) bonds without recourse to pre-functionalization or directing group strategiesThis work also describes a bio-inspired and unified approach for the synthesis of 1,2-oxy amino arenes including 1,2-aminophenols through a direct, catalytic aerobic coupling of phenols and amines. Key to the formation of the aromatic C-N bond is a facile condensation between the amine and an ortho-quinone, which triggers redox-isomerization to an ortho-imino-phenol before a series of downstream events. Factors that govern regioselectivity during aerobic ortho-oxygenation of the phenol and condensation of the amine are discussed, and synthetic utility is demonstrated by the preparation of a structurally diverse family of immunosuppressive heterocycles and the indole alkaloid cephalandole A. Finally, this thesis also describes a bio-inspired dehydrogenation approach for the synthesis of polycyclic (hetero)arenes. The method hinges on the facile isomerization of ortho-quinones to para-quinone methides, a key event in melanogenesis. The utility of this methodology is highlighted through the synthesis of dehydroaporphine natural products, as well as polycyclic heterocycles.</description><description>La réduction de l'oxygène moléculaire (O2) en eau (H2O) fournit une source d'énergie renouvelable qui alimente la synthèse de molécules et de matériaux dans la nature. Une myriade de procédés biochimiques, incluant le métabolisme, les moyens de défenses des plantes, le brunissement des fruits, l'adhésion des bernacles et la pigmentation des mammifères (i.e. la mélanogénèse) exploite cette énergie en convertissant des phénols en ortho-quinones, dont leur réactivité intrinsèque entraîne des fonctionnalisations additionnelles. Étant donné que l'eau est le seul produit secondaire en quantité stœchiométrique et les ortho-quinones sont des intermédiaires synthétiques exceptionnellement versatile, la mélanogenèse fournit un moyen pour de la synthèse propre et renouvelable. Plus de 50 ans d'études en biochimie ont, par contre, révélés des défis d'envergure significative pour la catalyse d'oxygénation aérobique de phénols et les méthodes actuelles ne sont ni efficaces, ni assez versatiles pour être pratiques. Cette thèse détaille une méthodologie laquelle surmonte ces défis en catalyse biomimétique de longue date et décrit la préparation rapide et sélective de quinones poly-substituées, de catéchols, indoles, furanes, benzothiazines ainsi que de pigments polymériques sous des conditions à température ambiante, des conditions à flasques ouvertes. Une nouvelle approche à la fonctionnalisation directe de liens carbone-hydrogène (C-H) qui s'articule avec la réactivité des complexes semiquinone-métal et forme sélectivement des liens carbone-oxygène (C-O), carbone-azote (C-N) et carbone-soufre (C-S) sans avoir recours à une pré-fonctionnalisation ou une stratégie avec des groupes directeurs.Ce travail décrit également une approche bio-inspirée et unifiée pour la synthèse de 1,2-oxyaminoarènes incluant les 1,2-aminophénols à travers de couplages catalytiques aérobiques directs de phénols et d'amines. La clef pour la formation de liens C-N aromatiques et une simple condensation entre l'amine et l'ortho-quinone, laquelle déclenche une isomérisation rédox en ortho-iminophénol avant une série d'événements subséquents. Les facteurs qui gouvernent la régiosélectivité lors de l'ortho-oxygénation du phénol et de la condensation de l'amine sont discutés, alors que l'utilité synthétique est démontrée par la préparation d'une famille de diverses structures d'hétérocycles immunosuppresseurs ainsi que l'alcaloïde indole céphalandole  A.Finalement, cette thèse décrit aussi une déshydrogénation bio-inspirée comme approche pour la synthèse d'arènes et d'hétéroarènes polycycliques. Cette méthode fait le pont entre l'isomérisation facile d'ortho-quinones en para-quinone méthides, un événement clef dans la mélanogénèse. L'utilité de cette méthode est mise en valeur à travers la synthèse de déshydroporphines comme produits naturels, et ainsi que d'hétérocycles polycycliques.</description><creator>Esguerra, Kenneth Virgel</creator><contributor>Jean-Philip Lumb (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Bio-inspired catalytic methodologies for the synthesis of quinones and heterocycles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vn517.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vb239</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892d53t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reinforced concrete shear walls are commonly used seismic force-resisting systems in high-rise structures. Shear walls with regular openings for elevators or staircases at floor levels act as a system of two shear walls linked by concrete beams located above and below the openings. These shear wall systems are referred to as coupled walls. Ductile coupling beams are important components of ductile coupled walls due to their inherent high energy dissipation properties and stable failure mechanisms. Coupling beams with low span to depth ratios typically include diagonal reinforcement to resist shear and flexural forces induced by wind or seismic loads. In order to achieve the necessary ductility, the current CSA Standard A23.3-14 (CSA, 2014) limits the spacing between the buckling prevention ties (hoops) which confine the diagonal reinforcing bars to the lesser of 24dhoop, 6db or 100 mm. These stringent requirements for ductile diagonally reinforced coupling beams are commonly applied to moderately ductile and conventional construction cases. To simplify the construction of the coupling beams and provide realistic alternatives for the moderately ductile and conventional construction cases, the effect of an increased spacing of the buckling prevention ties in the coupling beams is investigated. Reversed cyclic loading tests were carried out on fifteen reinforcing bar specimens as well as four full-scale coupled shear wall specimens. The hysteretic response of the full-scale coupled wall specimens determined that an increased spacing of the buckling prevention ties performs adequately for the moderately ductile and conventional construction cases. Further research should be carried out to investigate the increase in resistance due to the longitudinal restraint of the coupling beams offered by the structure's floor slabs.</description><description>Les murs ductiles couplés sont des systèmes de contreventement fréquemment utilisés dans des structures gratte-ciels afin de résister aux charges latérales. Les poutres couplées sont des éléments importants dans le système de résistance latérale en raison de leur efficacité en dissipation d'énergie et leur méthode de défaillance prévisible. Les poutres couplées avec un rapport minime de portée à profondeur sont typiquement armées en diagonale. Afin d'atteindre un niveau de ductilité acceptable, les dispositions actuelles du Code CSA A23.3-14 limitent l'espacement entre les ligatures sismiques afin d'éviter le flambement des barres d'armature. Les provisions du code sont actuellement disponibles pour le cas ductile (Rd = 4.0) et sont typiquement appliquées aux poutres couplées modérément ductile (Rd = 2.5). Aucunes provisions n'existent pour le cas de construction conventionnelle (Rd = 1.5). Afin de simplifier la construction des poutres couplées ainsi que de fournir des alternatives réalistes pour les cas modérément ductile et de construction conventionnelle, l'effet d'un espacement augmenté des ligatures qui confinent les barres d'armature diagonales est investigué.Des expérimentations cycliques inversées (reversed cyclic) ont été complétées sur quinze barres d'armature et quatre systèmes de murs couplés de pleine échelle. Les comportements hystérétiques des spécimens nous permet de conclure que l'espacement des ligatures peut être augmenté pour les cas des murs modérément ductiles et de construction conventionnelle. De plus, l'effet de retenue de la dalle structurale sur les murs couplés devrait être investigué davantage.</description><creator>Howard, Brian</creator><contributor>Denis Mitchell (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Seismic response of diagonally reinforced coupling beams with varied hoop spacings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/736667282.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892d53t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c9950</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse présente une approche électrochimique pour l'étude non-invasive des systèmes biologiques, et démontre l'utilité de la microscopie électrochimique à balayage (SECM) pour la quantification du flux chimique dans les cellules vivantes.Nous commençons en explorant la présence de la D-serine dans le cerveau. Ce neurotransmetteur joue un rôle important dans le développement du cerveau et est aussi lié à plusieurs maladies pathologiques telles que la schizophrénie et la maladie d'Alzheimer. La quantification des changements locaux de la D-serine est essentielle pour mieux comprendre son rôle dans ces processus. Ainsi, un biosenseur a été développé pour détecter la D-serine avec une haute sensibilité. Le relâchement de la D-serine a été mesuré in vivo dans le cerveau d'un têtard, démontrant une concentration générale de 2.5 µM. Cependant, le point d'origine et le mécanisme de relâchement ne sont pas bien définis, nécessitant une mesure beaucoup plus localisée. Après une optimisation pour améliorer le temps de réponse et la sélectivité, le biosenseur a été utilisé avec une configuration SECM pour mesurer le relâchement de la D-serine d'un système modèle. Cette méthodologie SECM a fourni une quantification de la D-serine avec une haute résolution spatiale, et peut être utile pour investiguer le flux chimique dans d'autres échantillons biologiques. Nous avons ensuite concentré nos efforts sur la quantification de la résistance multidrogue, un processus cellulaire qui permet aux cellules cancéreuses d'expulser les drogues chimiothérapeutiques avant qu'elles puissent les tuer, ce qui diminue sévèrement le succès du traitement. La plupart des investigations sur les protéines transmembranaires, incluant la protéine associée à la résistance multidrogue (MRP1), se concentre sur l'expression pour déterminer leurs effets dans des cancers spécifiques. Les chercheurs ont été incapables d'établir une corrélation claire entre l'expression et le succès des traitements chimiothérapeutiques. Cependant, la relation entre l'expression et l'activité fonctionnelle est souvent négligée. En utilisant la SECM et des nouveaux substrats pour adhérences sélectives des cellules, l'activité fonctionnelle de la MRP1 a été mesurée dans des cellules cancéreuses individuelles. En traitant des lignées cellulaires parentales avec de la doxorubicine, une drogue utilisée dans plusieurs traitements chimiothérapeutiques, nous avons produit six populations cellulaires avec une expression croissante et déterminé leur activité fonctionnelle concurrente. Cette étude comparative a démontré que l'expression et l'activité fonctionnelle n'ont pas de corrélation directe, et suggère que la détermination de l'activité fonctionnelle devrait être priorisée pour identifier l'effet de la MRP1 sur le succès des traitements chimiothérapeutiques.</description><description>This thesis presents an electrochemical approach for the non-invasive study of biological systems, and demonstrates the usefulness of scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM) for quantification of chemical flux in live cells. We first explore the presence of D-serine within the brain. This neurotransmitter plays an important role in proper brain development, and has also been linked to several pathological diseases such as schizophrenia and Alzheimer's disease. Consequently, quantification of local changes in D-serine concentration is essential to further understanding of its role in these processes. A biosensor was thus developed for the detection of D-serine with high sensitivity. Using this microscale biosensor, the release of endogenous D-serine was measured in vivo inside the brain of Xenopus laevis tadpoles, revealing an overall concentration of 2.5 µM. However, the primary site and mechanism of release of D-serine remained unclear, requiring a more localized measurement. After optimizing for improved response time and selectivity, the biosensor was used in a SECM configuration to measure localized release of D-serine from a model system. This SECM methodology provided quantitative imaging of D-serine with high spatial resolution, and could be useful to investigate chemical flux in other biological samples. We then shifted our focus to quantitative imaging of another complex live cell process, specifically multidrug resistance. This defensive mechanism allows cancer cells to pump out chemotherapeutic drugs before they can kill the cell, severely impeding treatment success. Most investigations of transmembrane efflux pumps, including multidrug resistance-associated protein 1 (MRP1), focus on expression to determine their effect in specific cancer types. Researchers have been unable to establish a clear correlation between expression and patient survival. However, the relationship between transporter expression and functional activity is often overlooked. Using SECM with complementary redox mediators and novel cell patterning substrates, we measured MRP1 functional activity in single cancer cells. By challenging parental cell lines with doxorubicin, a drug used in many chemotherapy regimens, we produced six cell populations with increasing MRP1 expression, and measured their concurrent functional activity. This comparative study revealed that in fact MRP1 expression and functional activity do not correlate, and suggest that the measurement of functional activity should be prioritized to identify the effect of MRP1 on chemotherapy treatment success.</description><creator>Polcari, David</creator><contributor>Janine Mauzeroll (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Investigation of live cell processes using scanning electrochemical microscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33s0072.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c9950</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193c43z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le cortex entorhinal est traditionnellement vu comme une structure impliquée dans la mémoire spatiale. La découverte récente de nombreux types de neurones spatiaux supporte certainement ce point de vue. Par contre, il y a des preuves qui suggèrent que le cortex entorhinal serait impliqué dans des domaines non spatiaux tels que la modulation de l'attention. En se basant sur les connections anatomiques du cortex entorhinal, il possible de croire qu'il pourrait agir comme un filtre, en modulant l'information cognitive entre les régions préfrontales et l'hippocampe. Nous avons utilisé des résultats récents issus d'études fonctionnelles et de traçages afin d'élaborer deux divisions du cortex entorhinal. Ces deux divisions, le cortex entorhinal dorsolateral (dEC) et le cortex entorhinal ventromedial (vEC), contiennent des connexions anatomiques distinctes et contribuent à des fonctions distinctes. Le premier objectif de cette thèse était de séparer la contribution comportementale du dEC et du vEC. Le second objectif de cette thèse était d'évaluer la contribution du dEC et du vEC dans la mémoire spatiale. Le troisième et dernier objectif de cette thèse était de caractériser le rôle du dEC et du vEC dans les fonctions exécutives. Le Chapitre 1 fournit un aperçu général de l'anatomie et des connexions anatomiques du cortex entorhinal. Nous avons aussi inclus un résumé des preuves comportementales de l'implication du cortex entorhinal dans la cognition spatiale et non spatiale. Au Chapitre 2, nous avons comparé les rats avec une lésion du dEC et du vEC dans une tâche de mémoire spatiale. Nous avons trouvé qu'alors que le dEC ne semblait pas contribuer à la mémoire spatiale, la lésion du vEC a perturbé la mémoire spatiale seulement après un délai de dix minutes. Au Chaptre 3, nous avons testé des rats avec une lésion du dEC et du vEC dans une tâche qui évalue l'état général des fonctions du cortex préfrontal, la tâche des 5-Choix. Nous avons trouvé que les lésions du dEC et du vEC amélioraient la performance des animaux à accomplir la tâche. L'amélioration de la précision était accompagnée d'une réduction des comportements impulsifs seulement après une lésion du vEC. Afin d'approfondir notre évaluation du rôle du dEC et du vEC dans les processus d'attention, au Chapitre 4, nous avons testé des rats dans une tâche visuelle de flexibilité cognitive sur un écran tactile, une tâche similaire à celle utilisée chez les humains et les primates non humains. Nous avons trouvé que la lésion du dEC empêchait la formation d'un ensemble attentionnel. Des résultats fort différents ont été observés après une lésion du vEC. En effet, celle-ci a causé des comportements de persévération qui se traduisait par une augmentation du nombre d'erreurs de correction.En résumé, les résultats de toutes ces expériences nous ont permis de caractériser les contributions distinctes du dEC et du vEC dans la cognition spatiale et non spatiale. Nous avons montré que seulement le vEC semble jouer un rôle dans la cognition spatiale et que sa contribution à celle-ci semble plutôt limitée. Nous avons aussi montré que le cortex entorhinal est impliqué dans les fonctions exécutives. Plus spécifiquement, nous avons montré que le dEC semble impliqué dans la modulation de l'attention et que le vEC semble contribuer au contrôle du comportement.</description><description>The entorhinal cortex is traditionally known as a structure involved in spatial memory. The discovery of numerous neurons with spatial firing properties in recent years certainly supports this view. However, there has been evidence involving the entorhinal cortex in non-spatial domains such as attentional modulations. On the basis of its anatomical connection, the entorhinal cortex could potentially act as a gate between the prefrontal areas and the hippocampus, by modulating cognition information. We used recent tracing and functional findings to elaborate two divisions of the entorhinal cortex that would have contrasting patterns of connections and functionality, the dorsolateral entorhinal cortex (dEC) and ventromedial entorhinal cortex (vEC). The first objective of this thesis was to dissociate the behavioural contribution of the dEC and vEC. The second objective of this thesis was to evaluate the contribution of the dEC and vEC in spatial memory. The third objective of this thesis was to characterize the role of the dEC and vEC in executive functions. Chapter 1 provides an overview of the entorhinal cortex anatomy and anatomical connections. We also provide a summary of the behavioural evidence of the involvement of the entorhinal cortex in spatial and non-spatial cognition. In Chapter 2, we compared rats with a dEC and vEC lesions in a spatial memory task. We found that while dEC did not seem to contribute to spatial memory, vEC lesions impaired spatial memory impairment only after a 10 minutes' delay. In Chapter 3, we tested rats with a dEC or vEC lesion in a general 'prefrontal-dependent' task, the 5-Choice task. We found that both dEC and vEC lesions enhanced the animals' performance to complete the task. The increase in accuracy was accompanied by a reduction in impulsive behaviour only after a vEC lesion. To further our assessment of the dEC and vEC in attentional processes, in Chapter 4, we tested rats in touchscreen-based visual set-shifting task analogous to the human and non-human primate version. We found that lesion of the dEC prevent the formation of an attentional set. A very different pattern of behaviour was found after lesions of vEC which promoted perseveration by increasing the number of correction errors.Together, the results from these experiments characterized the specific contribution of the dEC and vEC to spatial and non-spatial cognition, which we show was distinct. We showed that while only vEC seems to play a role in spatial cognition, it appears its contribution might be limited. We also showed that the entorhinal cortex is involved in executive functions. More specifically, we showed that the dEC seem to be involved in aspect of attention modulations and that the vEC seem to contribute to behavioural control.</description><creator>Bouayad-Gervais, Karim</creator><contributor>Yogita Chudasama (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Jonathan Britt (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Dissociating the entorhinal cortex in spatial and non- spatial cognition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br980.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193c43z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hs22r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present thesis examined age-related differences and individual factors associated with youth's and adults' ability to produce and recognize socio-emotional expressions in the voice. Vocal cues in a speaker's tone of voice are an important source of social information, yet they remain an understudied form of emotional communication. The studies presented herein examine both the encoding and decoding of affective prosody by youth and adults. Though previous work has typified the patterns of acoustic cues used by adults when portraying "basic" emotions, such as happiness and anger, virtually no data exists on the production of emotional prosody by youth. Study 1 compared the vocal cues underlying 24 young actors' portrayals of various expressions to those of 30 adult actors, to determine whether there were age-related differences in how both age groups conveyed basic emotions (anger, disgust, fear, happiness, sadness) and social expressions of meanness and friendliness. Adults' vocal expressions were more distinct in pitch from one another than those of adolescents; given the influence of pitch cues on the identification of emotional intent in the voice (Scherer, 1996), the results of Study 1 suggest that adults' emotional prosody may be easier for listeners to decode than those of youth. Building on this result, Study 2 examined how speaker age, listener age, and the interaction between these two factors were associated with listeners' vocal decoding skills. Fifty youth and 87 adult listeners were asked to identify the intended expression in recordings produced by youth and adult actors (from Study 1). Adult listeners were more accurate in recognition than were younger listeners, aligning with previous evidence that vocal decoding skills increase with age (Brosgole &amp; Weisman, 1995). Further, consistent with our interpretation of the acoustic analyses in Study 1, adult speakers' portrayals were better recognized than youth speakers'. Lastly, Study 2 found that speaker age, listener age, and expression interacted to predict recognition accuracy. Specifically, though adult listeners outperformed youth when hearing adult portrayals of fear and sadness and most child-generated expressions, youth achieved adult-like accuracy with several adult-generated expressions (i.e., anger, disgust, friendliness, happiness, and meanness) and youth portrayals of disgust, meanness, and happiness. Adults may thus outperform youth primarily with highly-recognized expressions. More broadly, these results suggest that youth may struggle to identify peers' less skillfully enacted emotional cues in social contexts, making interpersonal interactions particularly challenging during adolescence. Given previous evidence that anxious and depressed youth struggle to navigate social interactions (Kochel, Ladd, &amp; Rudolph, 2012), Study 3 examined whether anxious and depressive symptoms were linked to vocal recognition deficits. Twenty-nine clinically referred and 28 healthy comparison youth aged 8-17 were asked to identify the intended expression in youth-generated vocal recordings. I examined associations between youth's anxious and depressive symptoms and their recognition accuracy. Results indicated that depressive symptoms were linked to reduced identification of happiness and anger, a pattern that may be particularly problematic in the context of social skills deficits and the maintenance of depressive symptoms. Study 3 also revealed a linear relationship between greater age and increased recognition accuracy, providing new evidence that vocal recognition skills continue to improve through adolescence. In sum, the current thesis mapped age-related changes in the encoding and decoding of vocal socio-emotional prosody, and examined the associations between internalizing symptomatology and the recognition of vocal affect by peers. These studies provide novel information about the development of vocal production and recognition skills in adults and youth. </description><description>La présente thèse examine des facteurs développementaux et individuels associés à la capacité à produire et reconnaître des expressions socio-émotionnelles vocales. Les indices vocaux d'un locuteur sont une importante source d'information sociale, mais sont une forme de communication émotionnelle peu étudiée. Les études présentes examinent l'encodage et le décodage de la prosodie affective par les jeunes et les adultes. Bien que des études précédentes aient caractérisé les indices vocaux utilisés par les adultes pour représenter les émotions « de base » comme la joie et la colère, la prosodie affective des jeunes est très peu étudiée. L'Étude 1 compare les indices vocaux des expressions produites par 24 jeunes acteurs à ceux de 30 acteurs adultes, pour déterminer comment les deux groupes transmettent les émotions de base (colère, dégoût, peur, joie, tristesse) et des expressions sociales de méchanceté et de gentillesse. Les expressions vocales des adultes étaient plus distinctes l'une de l'autre que celles des adolescents en terme de ton sonore. Vu l'influence de cet indice acoustique sur l'identification de l'émotion contenue dans la voix (Scherer, 1996), ces résultats suggèrent que la prosodie émotionnelle des adultes pourrait être plus facile à décoder pour les auditeurs que celle des jeunes. Pour faire suite à ces résultats, l'Étude 2 a examiné l'influence de l'âge du locuteur, l'âge de l'auditeur, et de leur interaction sur la capacité de décodage des auditeurs. Cinquante jeunes et 87 adultes ont identifié l'expression émotionnelle contenue dans les enregistrements auditifs produits par les acteurs adolescents et adultes (de l'Étude 1). Les auditeurs adultes démontrent une meilleure identification que les jeunes, concordant avec des recherches démontrant que le décodage vocal s'améliore avec l'âge (Brosgole &amp; Weisman, 1995). De plus, la prosodie émotionnelle produite par des adultes était mieux reconnue que celle des jeunes. Finalement, l'Étude 2 a noté que l'âge du locuteur, l'âge de l'auditeur, et l'expression émotionnelle interagissaient pour prédire la capacité de décodage des auditeurs. Les auditeurs adultes surpassaient les jeunes dans leur identification de la peur et de la tristesse produite par les adultes, ainsi que la majorité des expressions générées par les jeunes. Par contre, les jeunes auditeurs étaient équivalents en habileté aux adultes pour plusieurs des expressions produites par les adultes (p. ex., colère, dégoût, gentillesse, joie, et méchanceté), ainsi que le dégoût, la méchanceté, et la joie produite par les jeunes. Ces résultats indiquent que les jeunes pourraient avoir de la difficulté à reconnaître les indices émotionnels des autres adolescents, compliquant la tâche de naviguer les interactions sociales pendant l'adolescence. Puisque les jeunes anxieux et dépressifs peinent à gérer leurs relations sociales (Kochel, Ladd, &amp; Rudolph, 2012), l'Étude 3 a déterminé le lien entre les symptômes de dépression et d'anxiété chez les jeunes et leur identification de la prosodie émotionnelle. Vingt-neuf adolescents anxieux et 28 jeunes non-anxieux ont identifié l'expression présentée dans les enregistrements produits par des jeunes. Les symptômes de dépression étaient liés à des déficits dans l'identification de la joie et de la colère, ce qui pourrait être problématique pour la compétence sociale de ces jeunes et le maintien de leurs symptômes. L'Étude 3 révèle aussi une relation linéaire entre l'âge des participants et la reconnaissance vocale, suggèrant que cette habileté continue à croître pendant l'adolescence. Cette thèse trace les différences développementales dans l'encodage et le décodage de la prosodie émotionnelle, et examine les associations entre les symptômes dépressifs et anxieux et la capacité à reconnaître l'expression vocale de pairs. Ces études élucident des facteurs reliés au développement de la production et de la reconnaissance de la prosodie affective chez les jeunes et les adultes. </description><creator>Morningstar, Michele</creator><contributor>Melanie Dirks (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Age-related differences in the production and recognition of vocal socio-emotional expressions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408069k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hs22r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227ms406</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le récepteur d'aryl d'hydrocarbone (AHR) est un détecteur environemental et alimentaire jouant un rôle dans divers aspects de la biologie cellulaire et l'homéostasie des organes. En tant que facteur de transcription induit par un ligand, le AHR peut être activé par une panoplie de ligands et entraîner l'activation d'un large ensemble de gènes. L'irradation par des ultraviolets est un facteur environemental entraînant la formation d'un puissant activateur du AHR. De plus, le AHR communique avec de nombreuses voies de signalisation cellulaire pour maintenir l'homéostasie. Un nombre croissant d'études montre que le AHR est impliqué dans des voies de signalisation au travers desquelles des facteurs environementaux peuvent avoir des effets sur les réponses immunitaires. L'activation de AHR inhibe meme des infections. Toutefois, le mécanisme moléculaire par lequel le AHR agit sur la réponse immunitaire n'est pas élucidé. Comprendre les mécanismes par lesquels les macrophages de l'hote répondent aux infections est essentiel a la découverte de nouvelles voies d'intervention pour améliorer la resistance de l'hote aux infections. L'analyse du transcriptome de macrophages a révélé que l'infection par M. tuberculoisus (M.tb) induit l'activation de plusieurs enzymes liées au catabolisme du tryptophane telles que l'indole 2,3-dioxygénase 1 (IDO1) et la tryptophane 2,3-dioxygénase (TDO2) qui catalyse l'étape limitante du catabolisme de la kynurénine qui produit des ligands de AHR. L'expression induite de ces enzymes ainsi que d'autres éléments de la voie de la kynurénine ont été confirmé au niveau transcriptionnel et protéique. Le AHR et RELB sont largement exprimés et leurs niveaux augmentent davantage lors d'une infection par M.tb L'infection augmente AHR/ARNT, l'interaction avec l'ADN de AHR/RELB et stimule l'expression de gènes induit par AHR dont celui de l'interleukine inflammatoire IL1B. L'expression de gènes cibles de AHR est davantage induite par de la kynurénine exogène tryptophane. L'indirubine diminue la viabilité de mycobactéries. La comparaison de profils d'expression révèle que l'ablation de AHR décroit l'expression de nombreux gènes impliqués dans la réponse immunitaire innée dont ceux de plusieurs cytokines. Notamment, la perte de AHR entraîne la diminution d'expression des transcrits de IL23A et IL12B qui codent pour les sous-unités de l'interleukne 23 (IL23) de macrophase qui stimule la production de IL22 par des cellules lymphoides innées. Le AHR entraîne directement la transcription de IL23A dans des cellules humaines et murines au travers de régions amplificatrices en amont proches.  Dans une étude plus approfondie de facteurs environnementaux affectant la fonction de AHR, nous avons observé qu'une dose érythématique d'UVB entraîne rapidement la voie AHR dans le sang et de nombreux organes périphériques chez la souris irradiée. De plus, une quantité modérée d'UVB entraîne une augmentation du recrutement de AHR au niveau du promoteur de ses gènes cibles. Une augmentation du niveau transcriptionnel de cytokines de la réponse immunitaire innée IL22 et IL23 est observée dans differents tissus murins. In vitro, l'irradiation aux UVB induit rapidement la translocation de AHR dans le noyau et augmente l'expression de gènes cibles dans des cellules épitheliales desquamantes et des cellules myéloides. Dans des expériences ex vivo en présence de serum de souris irradiées aux UVB, l'ablation de AHR ou la présence d'un antagoniste de AHR empeche totalement l'induction d'expression de gènes cibles de AHR par les UVB tels que Cyp1a1. Cependant le recrutement de AHR au niveau du promoteur de ces gènes cibles augmente après une irradiation aux UVB.</description><description>The aryl hydrocarbon receptor (AHR) is an environmental and dietary sensor, which plays prominent roles in various aspects of cell physiology and organ homeostasis. The AHR, as a ligand dependent transcription factor, can bind a broad range of activating ligands and regulate the expression of a diverse set of genes. Ultraviolet (UV) irradiation is one of the environmental factors that induces formation of a potent AHR ligand. In addition, the AHR cross-talks with number of signaling pathways to maintain cell homeostasis. Increasing evidence has revealed that AHR is involved in pathways through which environmental factors regulate immune responses, and there is evidence that AHR activation suppresses some infections. However, the mechanistic basis for the role of AHR signaling in immune defenses is poorly characterized.  Understanding the mechanisms of host macrophage responses to infections is essential for uncovering potential avenues of intervention to boost host resistance to infection. Macrophage transcriptome profiling revealed that M. tuberculosis (M.tb) infection strongly induced expression of several enzymes controlling tryptophan catabolism. These included indole 2,3-dioxygenase 1 (IDO1) and tryptophan 2,3-dioxygenase (TDO2), which catalyze the rate-limiting step in the kynurenine catabolic pathway, ultimately producing ligands for the AHR. Induced expression of these enzymes and other components of the kynurenine pathway were confirmed at the mRNA and protein levels. The AHR and its heterodimeric partner, RELB, are robustly expressed, and AHR and RELB levels further increased during M.tb infection. Infection enhanced AHR/ARNT and AHR/RELB DNA binding, and stimulated expression of AHR target genes, including that encoding the inflammatory cytokine IL1B. AHR target gene expression was further enhanced by exogenous kynurenine, tryptophan, or indirubin and reduced mycobacterial viability. Comparative expression profiling revealed that AHR ablation diminished expression of numerous genes implicated in innate immune responses, including several cytokines. Notably, AHR depletion reduced expression of IL23A and IL12B transcripts, which encode subunits of interleukin 23 (IL23), a macrophage cytokine that stimulates production of IL22 by innate lymphoid cells. The AHR directly induced IL23A transcription in human and primary mouse macrophages through near-upstream enhancer regions.  In a further characterization of environmental signals that regulated AHR function, we found that a single minimal erythemic dose of UVB induces rapid AHR signaling in blood and multiple peripheral organs in exposed mice. In addition, UVB exposure enhanced the recruitment of AHR to the promoter of its target genes. Subsequently, the expression of AHR target genes including innate immune cytokines, Il22 and Il23, were increased in different mouse tissues. In vitro, UVB irradiation rapidly induced the translocation of AHR to the nucleus and enhanced the expression of AHR target genes in squamous epithelial and myeloid cells. In ex vivo experiments with serum from UVB-irradiated mice, AHR ablation or the presence of an AHR antagonist attenuated the UVB-mediated-increased expression of AHR target gene, Cyp1a1, to the basal levels. Consistent with these findings, the recruitment of AHR to the promoter of target genes was enhanced following UVB irradiation.  Furthermore, we provide evidence that the AHR may be a transmembrane protein. We observed some degree of homology in transmembrane region of some plasma membrane proteins with the N-terminus of the PAS-A domain of the AHR. The AHR was detected on the cell surface of different cell lines. AHR was largely localized in membrane fraction and in the presence of stimuli such as UVB irradiation, translocated to the nucleus. </description><creator>Memari, Babak</creator><contributor>John H White (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Physiology</subject><title>Mechanistic studies of aryl hydrocarbon receptor as an environmental sensor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bk79k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227ms406</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wj58d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La schistosomiase est une maladie tropicale négligeé causée par des vers plats d'eau douce. La schistosomiase est une maladie chronique qui représente une préoccupation majeure de santé publique en raison de son impact négatif sur la qualité de vie. L'administration de praziquantel est le pilier de la lutte contre la schistosomiase. Depuis longtemps, il a été reconnu que l'utilisation unique de praziquantel pour lutter contre la schistosomiase présente des limites importantes. En particulier, le traitement avec praziquantel n'empêche pas la reinfection; nécessitant ainsi l'administration constante de médicaments dans les régions endémiques, ce qui est insoutenable à long terme. Il existe donc une forte incitation pour le développement d'un vaccin contre la schistosomiase. Même un vaccin partiellement efficace pourrait réduire, de manière significative, la morbidité et la transmission de la maladie. Notre groupe a exprimé l'antigène Schistosoma mansoni Cathepsine B (Sm-Cathepsine B) comme candidat potentiel. Cette protéine est une peptidase à cystéine très immunogène trouvée dans l'intestin du parasite. L'objectif global de cette thèse était de caractériser les formulations de vaccins contenant Sm-Cathepsine B. Notre premier objectif était d'évaluer le potentiel protecteur d'une formulation de Sm-Cathepsine B contenant du CpG. Le nombre de vers adultes et d'oeufs chez les souris immunisées avec notre formulation de Sm-Cathepsine B étaient nettement inférieure à celle des souris témoins (54%-59% de niveaux de protection). Les immunisations avec Sm-Cathepsine B + CpG ont provoqué une réponse Th1 biaisée caractérisée par des taux élevés d'IgG2c, d'IFNɣ et de TNFα. Ensuite, nous avons examiné l'effet d'un adjuvant moins polarisant l'immunité. À cette fin, nous avons utilisé notre modèle animal de la schistosomiase pour tester un vaccin Sm-Cathepsine B formulé avec l'adjuvant, à base de squalène, Montanide ISA 720 VG. En utilisant cette formulation, nous avons obtenu une protection de 56% à 62%. La formulation a provoqué une réponse Th1/Th2 mixte consistant des taux élevés d'IFNɣ, de TNFα, d'IL-4, d'IL-5 et d'IgG1. Les deux formulations de Sm-Cathepsine B testées ont généré des niveaux de protection similaires. Cependant, elles ont induit des réponses immunitaires très différentes. En utilisant un test in vitro de mort parasitaire, nous avons montré que l'effet antiparasitaire chez les animaux immunisés avec Sm-Cathepsine B + Montanide nécessitait la présence à la fois de cellules CD45+ (leucocytes) et d'anticorps; suggèrant ainsi un mécanisme à médiation cellulaire dépendant d'anticorps. De manière différente, la mortalité élevée des parasites dans le groupe Sm-Cathepsine B + CpG, ainsi qu'un groupe Sm-Cathepsine B sans adjuvant, était indépendante de la présence d'anticorps; suggèrant donc un effet cellulaire dominant. L'effet antiparasitaire observé avec le groupe Sm-Cathepsine B + Montanide était dépendant de la présence de cellules T CD4+ et de cellules tueuses naturelles (NK). Les cellules T CD4+ activent probablement les cellules NK qui sont ensuite impliquées dans la cytotoxicité à médiation cellulaire dépendante des anticorps. Pour le groupe Sm-Cathepsine B + CpG, les cellules T CD8+ étaient les principaux effecteurs intervenant dans la destruction des parasites. Enfin, la mort des parasites dans le groupe Sm-Cathepsine B sans adjuvant était médiée par des cellules T CD4+. En résumé, nous avons démontré l'efficacité protectrice de deux différents vaccins contenant Sm-Cathepsine B et nous avons commencé à caractériser les mécanismes immunitaires responsable de la protection induite par nos vaccins Sm-Cathepsine B. Dans l'ensemble, les résultats de cette thèse représentent des progrès significatifs dans le développement et la comprèhension d'une formulation vaccinale potentielle contre la schistosomiase.                </description><description>Schistosomiasis is a neglected tropical disease caused by freshwater flatworms. The parasite eggs become trapped in host tissues and, as a consequence of the stimulated immune response, promote fibrosis leading to severe organ damage. Schistosomiasis is a chronic disease, and it is a major public health concern due to its significant negative impact on quality of life. Mass drug administration with praziquantel is the mainstay of schistosomiasis control. It has long been recognized that the sole use of praziquantel to control schistosomiasis has important limitations. In particular, drug treatment does not prevent re-infection; thus, requiring constant drug delivery to endemic regions which is unsustainable in the long term. Furthermore, overuse of praziquantel raises concerns of drug resistance. There is therefore a strong incentive to develop a vaccine against schistosomiasis. Even a partially effective vaccine, could significantly decrease disease morbidity and transmission. Our group has expressed the candidate vaccine antigen Schistosoma mansoni Cathepsin B (Sm-Cathepsin B). This protein is an immunogenic cysteine peptidase found in the parasite gut. The overall goal of this thesis was to characterize Sm-Cathepsin B vaccine formulations. Our first objective was to assess the protective potential of a Sm-Cathepsin B formulation containing CpG. We used a C57BL/6 mouse model of schistosomiasis. Mice immunized with our Sm-Cathepsin B formulation had significantly lower parasite burden compared to control mice (54%-59% protection levels). The Sm-Cathepsin B + CpG immunizations elicited a biased Th1 response characterized by elevated levels of IgG2c, IFNɣ, and TNFα. Next, we sought to examine the effect of a less immune-biasing adjuvant. To this end, we used the mouse model of schistosomiasis to test a Sm-Cathepsin B vaccine formulated with the squalene based adjuvant Montanide ISA 720 VG. Using this formulation, we achieved 56%-62% protection. The formulation elicited a mixed Th1/Th2 response consisting of elevated levels of IFNɣ, TNFα, IL-4, IL-5, and IgG1. Both tested Sm-Cathepsin B formulations generated similar protection levels. However, they induced very different immune responses. To fully understand the vaccine-induced protection, we needed to characterize the underlying immune mechanisms. Using an in vitro parasite killing assay, we showed that the anti-parasitic effect in the Sm-Cathepsin B + Montanide immunized animals required the presence of both CD45+ cells (leukocytes) and antibodies; thus, suggesting an antibody-dependent cell-mediated mechanism. Differently, high parasite killing in the Sm-Cathepsin B + CpG group, as well as an unadjuvanted Sm-Cathepsin B group, was independent of the presence of antibodies; thus, suggesting a dominant cellular effect. A more in-depth characterization revealed the cell populations mediating the protection induced by the different vaccine formulations. The anti-parasitic effect observed with the Sm-Cathepsin B + Montanide group was dependent on the presence of CD4+ T cells and Natural Killer (NK) cells. CD4+ T cells are likely activating the NK cells which are then involved in antibody-dependent cell-mediated cytotoxicity. For the Sm-Cathepsin B + CpG group, CD8+ T cells were shown to be the main effectors mediating parasite killing. Lastly, parasite killing in the unadjuvanted Sm-Cathepsin B group was mediated by CD4+ T cells. In summary, we have demonstrated the protective efficacy of two different Sm-Cathepsin B vaccines, and we have begun to characterize the underlying immune mechanisms mediating Sm-Cathepsin B vaccine-induced protection. Overall, the results of this thesis represent significant progress in the development and understanding of a potential vaccine formulation against schistosomiasis.    </description><creator>Ricciardi, Alessandra</creator><contributor>Momar Ndao (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Microbiology &amp; Immunology</subject><title>Preclinical characterization of the protection and immune response elicited by immunizations with Schistosoma mansoni cathepsin B</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr172071n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wj58d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322h02d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les marais salés sont des puits de carbone (C) efficaces. Au mètre carré, ils enfouissent plus de C que tout autre écosystème sur la terre. Cependant, l'activité humaine a entrainé de grandes pertes de marais salés. Des crédits de C peuvent être générés en effectuant la restauration des marais salés, mais uniquement si les réductions de gaz à effet de serre (GES) sont bien quantifiées. La recherche scientifique au sujet des GES à court terme suivant la restauration des marais est limitée à l'étude de deux marais restaurés où les GES ont été mesurés plus de six mois après le début de la restauration. De plus, les études qui mesurent les taux d'enfouissement de C sont limités principalement aux marais qui ont été restaurés il y a plus de dix ans. Cette thèse présente un résumé de la recherche qui visait à combler ces lacunes dans la connaissance. Chapitre 2 présente les résultats d'une expérience en laboratoire où des carottes de sols prélevés à partir d'un marais asséché sur l'estuaire du Saint Laurent ont été inondés avec de l'eau de l'estuaire. Les mesures des flux de gaz immédiatement après l'inondation ont révélé une faible augmentation des flux de N2O et CH4, mais une forte baisse en CO2 en parallèle suggère que l'inondation a un effet de refroidissement au niveau climatique. En plus de rétablir la capacité des sols à enfouir du C, le retour de l'inondation due aux marais sert également à enrayer les pertes de C. Le chapitre trois présente les résultats d'une étude qui évaluait l'enfouissement de C six ans après le retour de l'inondation due au marais dans un terrain endigué située à Aulac, Nouveau Brunswick. Le taux d'enfouissement de C moyen était de 1 329 g C m-2 an-1, soit cinq fois plus élevé que le taux mesuré pour un marais existant voisin. La densité de C dans le marais en redressement ne variait pas en fonction de la profondeur du sol et malgré que l'herbacée salée (Spartina alterniflora) s'est établi en 2012, la majorité du C dans le nouveau marais est présumé d'être d'origine allochtone. Pour qu'un projet de restauration de marais salée soit éligible pour la génération de crédits de C, il faut pouvoir démontrer que le C allochtone n'aurait pas été enfouit autrement ; le potentiel pour ceci est discuté.</description><description>Salt marshes are highly effective carbon (C) sinks and bury more C per square meter annually than any other ecosystem. Marsh reclamation and anthropogenic impacts, however, have resulted in extensive losses of salt marshes. Carbon credits can be generated and sold by restoring marshes, but only if C sequestration and net reductions in greenhouse gases (GHG) are reliably quantified. Research on short-term GHG flux following salt marsh restoration is limited to studies of two restored marshes which examined GHG flux more than six months after the return of tidal flooding. Similarly, studies reporting on C burial rates are limited primarily to restored marshes which are more than 10 years old. This thesis reports on research designed to address these knowledge gaps. Chapter 2 reports on a laboratory experiment in which soil cores collected from a drained agricultural marsh on the St. Lawrence Estuary were flooded with estuary water. Gas flux measurements immediately after flooding revealed small increases in N2O and CH4, but a large decline in CO2 suggesting that reflooding has an immediate net cooling effect. In addition to restoring the land's capacity to sequester C once a marsh develops, returning tidal flooding thus has the added benefit of stemming ongoing C losses. Chapter three reports on a field study which assessed C burial six years after the return of tidal flooding to a section of dykeland in Aulac, New Brunswick. The C burial rate in the restored marsh averaged 1,329 g C m-2 yr-1, more than five times higher than the rate reported for a mature marsh nearby. Carbon density in the recovering marsh was relatively similar with depth and although salt marsh cordgrass (Spartina alterniflora) became established in 2012, the bulk of the C in the new marsh deposit is assumed to be allochthonous. For marsh restoration projects to be recognized in C crediting systems it must be demonstrated that the allochthonous C would not otherwise have been sequestered; the potential for this is discussed.</description><creator>Wollenberg, Jan</creator><contributor>Gail L Chmura (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Geography</subject><title>Quantifying the short-term climate mitigation effects of salt marsh restoration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hm77k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322h02d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05ff40k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans le but de contrôler les fluctuations des grades et des contaminants, les secteurs houillers, du minerai de fer et du ciment, utilisent depuis des décennies la méthode du mélange de minerai. Le mélange de minerai adopte une méthode structurée pour bâtir des stocks de réserve dans le but de réduire les variances dans le produit récupéré. Les fonderies, centrales au charbon et les cimenteries possèdent une tolérance étroite à introduire les matières brutes dans leurs systèmes. L'efficacité du mélange est déterminée par la méthode d'empilage et de réclamation utilisée dans l'opération du mélange de minerai.Afin de déterminer l'efficacité de l'opération de mélange, un des critères utilisés dans cette thèse est l'analyse du ratio de la réduction de la variance (VRR). Pour une configuration définie, un calcul de programme a été codé dans le logiciel MATLAB. De plus, des caractéristiques multi variables de minerais peuvent être considérées. Puisque la variabilité des matières entre deux points à l'intérieur d'une distance relativement réduite est limitée, l'alimentation des matières provenant de chaque zone d'excavation démontre des tendances à l'autocorrélation. Il est possible de déterminer le nombre de couches optimales en utilisant le VRR de chaque variable en combinaison avec l'analyse composante principale. Le nombre de couches requises déterminera l'ampleur des stocks de réserve et le choix d'équipement. Un stock de réserve intérieur, monté à l'aide d'un système d'empilage avec portique en combinaison avec un récupérateur, est adopté pour l'analyse des coûts de l'opération de mélange de minerais. Les résultats de la présente thèse démontrent que les avantages économiques nécessaire pour compenser les coûts d'une opération mélange de minerais représente un faible pourcentage du prix des matières premières dans le secteur du minerai de fer. Lorsqu'on considère le volume global de production des mines de très grande taille, un petit pourcentage, à concurrence de 2%, peut avoir un impact important au niveau de la liquidité de ces entreprises.Avec que des modifications mineures, le modèle présenté, peut-être adaptée à des différentes applications. Après avoir effectué une étude sur le minerai de fer en utilisant Fe, SiO2, Al2O3 et CaO il a été déterminé que l'approche présentée, retrouve un compromis entre le coût et le niveau d'homogénéisation requis.</description><description>Bed blending operations have been used in the iron ore, coal and cement industry for decades to control the fluctuations of grades and contaminants. A bed blending operation uses a structured approach to construct stockpiles to reduce the variance of the reclaimed product. Smelters, coal fired power plants and cement plants have a narrow tolerance for the raw materials being fed into their systems. The stacking method as well as the reclaiming method used in bed blending operations determine how effective the blending is. One of the criterion used to determine the effectiveness of the blending operations is the variance reduction ratio analysis (VRR) which is used in this thesis. For given stockpile configuration and equipment characteristics, a program calculation VRR has been coded in MATLAB. Furthermore, multivariate characteristics of ore can be considered.  The material feed from each excavation area in a mining operation tends to be serial correlated as material variability between two points within a relatively small distance is limited. Using the VRR of each variable in combination with principle component analysis (PCA) the optimal number of passes can be determined. The number of passes required can be used to determine the final required size of the stockpile and associated equipment. An indoor stockpile using a gantry stacker system in combination with a drum reclaimer is used to complete an analysis of the financial cost of a bed blending operation. The results of this thesis show that the economic benefit required to offset the cost of a bed blending operation is a small percentage of the iron ore commodity pricing. When looking at the production tonnages of large mines however, small percentage numbers of up to 2% can be a large impact on cash flow of organizations. The proposed model can be applied to different application with small adjustments. To see the performance of the proposed approach, a case study on iron ore using Fe, SiO2, Al2O3 and CaO was carried out and the results showed that this approach can find trade-off between cost and the required homogenization level. This model can be applied to different application with small adjustments.</description><creator>de Werk, Marco</creator><contributor>Mustafa Kumral (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Mining and Materials</subject><title>Trade-off between cost and performance in chevron bed-blending</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04ds14b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05ff40k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn107158p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The experimental conditions of the MATH (microbial adhesion to hydrocarbons) assay for evaluating the attachment behavior of colloids to oil-water interfaces do not allow for such measurements under a non-turbulent flow. To address this, a new methodology was developed in this study. A hydrophobic membrane coated with hexadecane (model oil) was placed at the top plate of a parallel plate flow cell, and a controlled oil-water interface was created under flow. The attachment of colloids to the interface was observed in-situ with a microscope. The selected colloids were latex micro-particles (model bio-colloid) and an oil-degrading bacterial strain, Burkholderia cepacia #10856. It was observed that different environmental parameters, specifically aqueous chemistry, flow hydrodynamics, and colloidal characteristics profoundly affected the initial attachment rates (Je) of colloids to the interface. For example, colloidal Je increased with increasing ionic strength of the suspending medium. Also, Je of bacterial cells decreased as the solution pH increased, but was unaffected by the increase in ionic valence. The drag forces imposed by the applied shear rates could not detach the attached colloids from the interface. Hence, an increasing shear rate continuously increased Je as the mass flow rate was increasing. Particle Je was higher for smaller particles as the sedimentation and drag forces decreased, and diffusion increased. When the fluid density was increased to reduce colloidal sedimentation, Je increased significantly. The presence of the natural organic matter components, namely, alginate and humic acid reduced bacterial adhesion due to repulsive electrostatic and steric forces. Furthermore, the attachment of the bacterial strain to oil-coated glass beads was evaluated in packed column experiments to assess if the attachment trends were similar to those observed in the PPFC. Several environmental conditions resulted in different trends while others yielded similar trends. The attachment efficiencies in the column were about an order of magnitude higher than in the PFFC due to the differences in pore geometry and hydrodynamic conditions. Overall, this study is the first to provide quantitative assessments of the initial colloidal attachment extents and rates to oil-water interfaces under flow conditions.</description><description>Les conditions expérimentales du test MATH (adhésion microbienne aux hydrocarbures) pour évaluer le comportement de fixation des colloïdes aux interfaces huile-eau ne permettent pas de telles mesures sous un flux non turbulent. Pour remédier à cela, une nouvelle méthodologie a été développée dans cette étude. Une membrane hydrophobe revêtue d'hexadécane (huile modèle) a été placée sur la plaque supérieure d'une cellule d'écoulement à plaque parallèle, et une interface huile-eau contrôlée a été créée sous l'écoulement. La fixation des colloïdes à l'interface a été observée sur place avec un microscope. Les colloïdes sélectionnés étaient des microparticules latex (modèle bio colloïde) et une souche bactérienne dégradant l'huile, Burkholderia cepacia #10856. Il a été observé que différents paramètres environnementaux, en particulier la chimie aqueuse, l'hydrodynamique du flux et les caractéristiques colloïdales, ont profondément affecté les taux d'attachement initiaux (Je) des colloïdes à l'interface. Par exemple, le Je colloïdal a augmenté avec l'augmentation de la force ionique du milieu de suspension. En outre, les cellules bactériennes de Je diminuent lorsque le pH de la solution augmente, mais n'a pas été affecté par l'augmentation de la valence ionique. Les forces de traînée imposées par les taux de cisaillement appliqués ne pouvaient pas détacher les colloïdes attachés de l'interface. Par conséquent, un taux de cisaillement croissant augmentait continuellement le Je à mesure que le débit massique augmentait. La particule Je était plus élevée pour les particules plus petites lorsque la sédimentation et les forces de traînée diminuaient, et la diffusion augmentait. Lorsque la densité de fluide a été augmentée pour réduire la sédimentation colloïdale, Je a augmenté de manière significative. La présence des composants de la matière organique naturelle, à savoir l'alginate et l'acide humique, a réduit l'adhérence bactérienne due à des forces électrostatiques et stériques répulsives. En outre, la fixation de la souche bactérienne aux perles de verre revêtues d'huile a été évaluée dans des expériences en colonne emballée pour évaluer si les tendances de fixation étaient similaires à celles observées dans le PPFC. Plusieurs conditions environnementales ont donné lieu à des tendances différentes tandis que d'autres ont cédé des tendances similaires. L'efficacité de l'attachement dans la colonne était d'environ un ordre de grandeur plus élevé que dans le PFFC en raison des différences dans la géométrie des pores et les conditions hydrodynamiques. Dans l'ensemble, cette étude est la première à fournir des évaluations quantitatives des niveaux initiaux de fixation colloïdale et des taux aux interfaces huile-eau dans des conditions d'écoulement.</description><creator>Sultana, Sharmin</creator><contributor>Subhasis Ghoshal (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Deposition of colloids to oil-water interfaces under different environmental conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gz76p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107158p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q6778</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Internal migration is a normal but complex part of life in sub-Saharan Africa. As women's migration rises in much of Africa, we must examine the consequences of migration for the lives of women and their children. This dissertation seeks to answer a central question: How does women's migration affect family dynamics and well-being in sub-Saharan Africa? I explore two dimensions of women's internal migration, focusing on maternal health and migrant women's relationships with children.In the first paper, I examine the association of mother's migration and child fostering. Specifically, I investigate whether migrant mothers foster their children more frequently than non-migrant women in slums, and whether economic and social disadvantage impact decisions about child residence. Using data collected in two slums of Nairobi, I find migrant women are significantly more likely to foster than non-migrant women, even controlling for economic and social precariousness. Though many women living in Nairobi's slums are disadvantaged, migrants who are unmarried and have fewer nearby kin to help buffer precarious slum conditions are at greater risk of fostering. In the second paper, I explore relationships between internal migrant mothers and the children they foster. Using qualitative data I collected in Nairobi in 2011 and 2013, I build on literature on child fostering in sub-Saharan Africa, where biological mothers often have no relationship with fostered children, and research on transnational motherhood which suggests international migrants use new strategies to parent their children. I find internal migrant mothers in Kenya actively pursue motherhood through long-distance mothering like transnational mothers. Specifically, migrant mothers living in Korogocho and Viwandani, like international migrants, migrate to support fostered children, in stark contrast to fostering arrangements where financial responsibility is shifted to foster parents. In addition to provision of goods and remittances, migrant mothers rely heavily on the provision of emotional care through communication to minimize emotional distance over time and space.In the final paper, I investigate the relationship between adolescent migration and maternal care use among young mothers. Using data from Demographic and Health Surveys (DHS) from 27 countries in sub-Saharan Africa, I look at the role of place, disruption, and adaptation on whether young mothers use maternal care. Focusing on differences between non-migrants (rural, urban), lateral migrants (rural-rural, urban-urban), and non-lateral migrants (rural-urban, urban-rural), I find evidence of a strong, significant advantage in migration to urban versus rural areas. There are also lingering positive effects of urban residence for urban-rural migrants, who maintain high use of maternal care even after migration.Together, the papers of this dissertation contribute to a greater understanding of the mechanisms of women's migration for family dynamics and women's health. Through these studies, I highlight the importance of considering mother's migration on the lives of her children and in her own life. I show that migrant women in Kenya make difficult choices about child residence, choosing between exposing them to hazardous slum conditions and fostering them resulting in separation. These separations deeply affect mother-child relationships, with migrant women actively seeking innovative ways to mother children. These studies are among the first to explore dimensions of fostering among migrant women in slums, which are rapidly increasing in Africa. The final study focuses on implications of women's migration on health, targeting young mothers who are highly mobile and may experience disadvantage during these transitions. In focusing on these areas rarely examined in the context of women's migration, I demonstrate how maternal migration shapes well-being and family dynamics in sub-Saharan Africa. </description><description>La migration est un aspect normal mais complexe de la vie familiale en Afrique subsaharienne. Comme les taux de migration des femmes augmentent, il est important d'examiner les conséquences de la migration sur la vie des femmes et de leurs enfants. Cette thèse cherche à répondre à une question centrale : comment la migration des femmes affecte-t-elle la dynamique familiale et le bien-être des femmes en Afrique subsaharienne ?  J'examine deux dimensions de la migration des femmes : la santé maternelle et les relations mères-enfants.Dans le cadre du premier article, j'examine l'association entre la migration de la mère et le confiage des enfants. Je cherche à savoir si les mères migrantes confient leurs enfants plus fréquemment que les femmes non migrantes et si les désavantages influent sur les décisions. En utilisant les données recueillies à Nairobi, je conclus que le risque de confiage est beaucoup plus élevée chez les femmes migrantes que chez les femmes non migrantes, même en contrôlant pour leur précarité économique et sociale. Bien que de nombreuses femmes vivant dans les bidonvilles de Nairobi soient défavorisées, les migrantes qui ont moins de proches parents pour aider à les protéger des conditions précaires sont plus à risque de confier leurs enfants. Le deuxième article cherche à comprendre les relations entre les mères migrantes et les enfants qu'elles confient. À l'aide des données qualitatives recueillies à Nairobi en 2011 et 2013, je trouve que les mères migrantes au Kenya poursuivent activement des stratégies parentales similaires à celles utilisées par les mères transnationales. Les mères migrent souvent pour soutenir les enfants confiés, en contraste avec les stratégies de confiage où la responsabilité est souvent déléguée à la famille d'accueil. Au-delà des obligations financières, les mères migrantes comptent beaucoup sur la création de connexions émotionnelles. Dans le dernier article, j'étudie la relation entre la migration et l'utilisation des services de santé maternelle chez les jeunes mères. À l'aide des données recueillies dans 27 pays d'Afrique, j'examine le rôle de la place, de l'interruption, et de l'adaptation pour savoir si les jeunes mères migrantes ont accès aux soins de santé. En mettant l'accent sur les différences entre les non-migrants (ruraux, urbains), migrants entre zones semblables (rural-rural, urbain-urbain), et migrants entre zones dissemblables (rural-urbain, urbain-rural), j'identifie un avantage de la migration vers les zones urbaines. J'identifie aussi des effets positifs persistants de la résidence urbaine pour les migrants urbaines-rurales, même après la migration. À travers ces études, je souligne l'importance de considérer la migration de la mère sur la vie de ses enfants et dans sa propre vie. Je montre que les femmes migrantes qui se déplacent au Kenya font des choix difficiles au sujet de leurs enfants, choisissant d'une part les exposer à des conditions dans les bidonvilles et d'autre part les confier à une famille d'accueil. Ces séparations affectent profondément les relations mère-enfant, les femmes migrantes cherchant des nouvelles façons de prendre soin de leurs enfants. Ces études sont les premières à explorer les décisions concernant le confiage des femmes migrantes qui migrent vers des bidonvilles, qui se développent rapidement. La dernière étude se concentre sur les implications de la migration des femmes sur leur propre santé, ciblant les jeunes mères qui sont très mobiles et peuvent connaître un désavantage pendant ces transitions. En mettant l'accent sur ces domaines rarement examinés dans le contexte de la migration des femmes, je montre comment la migration maternelle informe le bien-être et la dynamique familiale en Afrique subsaharienne.</description><creator>Cotton, Cassandra</creator><contributor>Shelley Clark (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Sociology</subject><title>Migration and motherhood in sub-saharan Africa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c088j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q6778</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv9355467</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse est composée de cinq articles écrits durant la période de stage des chercheurs à l'Université McGill. Sur la base de M.Sc. Ces documents font des progrès vers la com- préhension de notre univers tel qu'il ressort de la théorie des cordes et sur les implications de la physique des hautes énergies pour la cosmologie. La thèse est divisée en 3 parties: (1) théorie des cordes, (2) cosmologie des cordes et (3) cosmologie. La partie (1) étudie une classe particulière d'arrière-plans dans la théorie des cordes et étudie la rupture de la supersymétrie dans ces milieux. Avec cet esprit, une partie (2) étudie la cosmologie dans ces configurations, travaillant directement dans la description en quatre dimensions. En- fin, la partie (3) s'écarte des (1) et (2) et se concentre plutôt sur les effets de la théorie des champs quantiques dans l'espace incurvé. Les implications de la stochasticité dans les équations différentielles couplées, décrivant les perturbations cosmologiques UV et IR, sont étudiées et des corrections aux observables cosmologiques sont trouvées.</description><description>This thesis comprises five papers written during the author's tenure as a PhD candidate at McGill University. Building on the author's M.Sc. work, these papers make progress towards understanding our universe as it emerges from string theory, and on implications of established high energy physics for cosmology. The thesis is split into 3 parts: (1) string theory, (2) string cosmology, and (3) cosmology. Part (1) investigates a particular class of backgrounds in string theory, and studies the breaking of supersymmetry in these backgrounds. With this mind, part (2) studies cosmology in these setups, working directly in the four-dimensional description. Finally, part (3) departs from (1) and (2) and instead focuses on quantum field theory effects in curved space. The implications of stochasticity in coupled differential equations, describing UV and IR cosmological perturbations, are studied and corrections to cosmological observables are found.</description><creator>McDonough, Evan</creator><contributor>Keshav Dasgupta (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Robert Brandenberger (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>High energy physics and the early universe</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q405x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv9355467</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816p95n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les méthodes ab initio sont devenues ces dernières décennies un puissant outil pour l'étude des propriétés de matériaux à l'échelle nanoscopique, en raison de leur capacité à s'émanciper de tout paramètre empirique et à capturer les effets quantiques avec précision. Parmi plusieurs techniques, la théorie de la fonctionnelle de la densité (DFT) s'est rapidement établie comme une des méthodes favorites pour sa relative simplicité. Les fonctions de Green hors équilibre (NEGF) sont implémentées à l'intérieur de ce formalisme pour l'adapter au problème particulier du transport électronique. En outre, la présence d'impuretés à différents niveaux de concentration peut désormais être traitée efficacement grâce au développement récent de l'approximation du potentiel cohérent hors équilibre (NECPA). Dans cette thèse, nous proposons d'appliquer la méthode NEGF-DFT/NECPA à une variété de problèmes de matériaux afin de démontrer sa précision. Nous évaluons en premier la résistance de Sharvin du Cu, une propriété fondamentale, en utilisant des méthodes de structure de bande traditionnelles pour montrer leur application limitée au domaine du transport électronique. Nous étendons ensuite l'étude des couches minces (CMs) de Cu revêtues à plusieurs revêtements pertinents, à savoir le Si, Mn, Co et Ni. La résistivité et spécularité des CMs de Cu revêtues sont calculées via NEGF-DFT/NECPA, avec des résultats supportant de récentes preuves expérimentales de la faible résistivité des CMs de Cu revêtues de Ni. Plus tard, nous abordons le problème des joints de grain (JGs) de Cu. Pour ce faire, la structure de 6 JGs de Cu particuliers est d'abord déterminée et caractérisée à l'aide de la DFT traditionnelle. La résistivité de ces 6 JGs de Cu est ensuite calculée et relatée à d'autres propriétés de JG. Comme première étape vers l'étude du dopage de JG, la résistivité de Cu solide est calculée grâce à NEGF-DFT/NECPA et est trouvée être en bon accord avec l'expérience. Toujours via cette méthode, la résistivité de JGs de Cu dopés avec 16 éléments différents est calculée et comparée avec celle des JGs de Cu purs correspondants. Les résultats démontrent la possibilité d'une résistivité réduite dans les JGs de Cu par dopage. Finalement, nous caractérisons les alliages binaires semiconducteurs InN et GaN en utilisant la DFT traditionnelle. De là, la bande interdite et le paramètre de fléchissement de l'alliage ternaire In(x)Ga(1-x)N est déterminé sur l'ensemble des concentrations d'In x, une fois de plus grâce à NEGF-DFT/NECPA.</description><description>Ab initio methods have become over the past few decades a powerful tool for the investigation of material properties at the nanoscale, due to their capacity to emancipate themselves from any empirical parameter and to capture quantum effects accurately. Amongst several techniques, the density functional theory (DFT) has quickly established itself as one of the favored method for its relative simplicity. Non-equilibrium Green's functions (NEGF) are implemented inside this formalism to adapt it to the particular problem of electronic transport. Besides, the presence of impurities at various levels of concentration can now be addressed efficiently thanks to the recent development of the non-equilibrium coherent potential approximation (NECPA).In this thesis, we propose to apply the NEGF-DFT/NECPA method to variety of material problems to demonstrate its accuracy. We first evaluate the Sharvin resistance of Cu, a fundamental property, using traditional band structure methods to show their limited application to the domain of electronic transport. We then extend the study of coated Cu thin films (TFs) to several relevant coating materials, namely Si, Mn, Co and Ni. The resistivity and specularity of the coated Cu TFs are calculated via NEGF-DFT/NECPA, with results supporting recent experimental evidences of the low resistivity of Ni coated Cu TFs. Later, we address the problem of Cu grain boundaries (GBs). To do so, the structure of 6 particular Cu GBs is first determined and characterized with the help of traditional DFT. The resistivity of those 6 Cu GBs is then computed and related to other GB properties. As a first step toward the study of GB doping, the resistivity of doped bulk Cu is computed thanks to NEGF-DFT/NECPA and is found to be in good agreement with experiment. Still via this method, the resistivity of Cu GBs doped with 16 different elements is calculated and compared to that of the corresponding pure Cu GBs. The results demonstrate the possibility of reduced resistivity in Cu GBs by doping. Finally, we characterize the semiconducting binary alloys InN and GaN using traditional DFT. From there, the band gap and bowing parameter of the ternary alloy In(x)Ga(1-x)N is determined over the whole range of In concentration x, once again thanks to NEGF-DFT/NECPA.</description><creator>César, Mathieu</creator><contributor>Hong Guo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>Ab initio study of disordered nanoelectronic devices: copper interconnects and group-III nitrides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fv08w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p95n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278w92q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Early Chinese Empires were colonial regimes. The major aim of my dissertation is to elaborate on previous interpretations of cultural change and to highlight the negotiation of identity between imperial and local agents in a colonial context.  Colonial encounters not only have occurred in modern times, but also in early Imperial China.  The state of Qin (778 BC-221 BC) conquered the entire land of Sichuan (316 BC).  This region may well have been Qin's first colony before it finally unified China and created an empire (221 BC). Forceful military acquisitions of the land and the construction of a colonial landscape reshaped the indigenous cultures.  The adoption of the metropolitan cultures (traditionally recognized as "sinicization") continued for more than five hundred years. In the past, historians have tended to view cultural change under Qin and Han colonial rule as a normative process, by which the superior metropolitan cultures were passively accepted by the "naturally" inferior, local peoples of ancient Sichuan. However, the society of ancient colonial Sichuan was dynamic, composed of complex interactions among mobile individuals and groups. Local and metropolitan identities emerged nearly simultaneously. Micro and macro identities developed in close relationship with each other and were mutually constitutive. The peoples in ancient Sichuan were not merely "sinicized," but rather that they often played an active role in constructing their local cultural identities within greater imperial world.    Studies of ancient China often take cultural contact as monolithic and portray China as a state/empire with a monotonic voice. This dissertation seeks to deconstruct the Sino-centric identity through the investigation of the contact between China and her neighbor, ancient Sichuan. I see the cultural contacts as a set of diversified, uneven and heterogeneous interactions, rather than a one-way process. This dissertation deploys an interdisciplinary approach to address this question and to produce a critical synthesis based on the methods of history and archaeology; it analyzes textual sources in the form of standard histories, local histories and inscriptional evidence; and material cultures from burials and other sites. These approaches are well integrated with each other and will be used in both macro and micro contexts. Several expressions of identity are examined including local intellectual agency, ritual practice, and the compilation of local history. </description><description>Les premiers empires chinois étaient des régimes coloniaux. L'objet principal de ma thèse repose d'une part sur l'approfondissement des interprétations précédentes relatives aux modifications culturelles et d'autre part sur la mise en lumière des négociations d'identités entre les agents impériaux et les autochtones dans un contexte colonial.  La colonisation n'a pas uniquement eu lieu pendant les temps modernes, elle existait déjà au début de la Chine impériale.  La conquête de l'ensemble de Sichuan par l'État de Qin (778 av. J.-C. – 221 av. J.-C.) a lieu en 316 av. J.-C.  Cette région est peut-être bien la première colonie de Qin, avant l'unification de la Chine et la création d'un empire (221 av. J.-C.).  Ce sont ces violentes acquisitions militaires de terres et la construction d'un paysage colonial qui ont redessiné les cultures autochtones. L'adoption des cultures métropolitaines (traditionnellement appelée « sinisation ») se poursuit ensuite pendant plus de cinq cents ans. Les historiens avaient autrefois tendance à dater la modification culturelle à l'époque des lois coloniales de Qin et Han et à les considérer comme un processus de normalisation. Les peuples autochtones de Sichuan, « naturellement » inférieurs, auraient passivement accepté les cultures métropolitaines supérieures.  La société de l'ancien Sichuan colonial était dynamique, composée d'interactions complexes entre les groupes et les individus mobiles. Les identités locales et métropolitaines sont nées presque simultanément.  Les micro- et macro- identités se sont développées en étroite liaison les unes avec avec les autres et ont été mutuellement constitutives.  La conclusion de ma thèse tend à prouver que les peuples de l'ancien Sichuan n'étaient pas simplement « sinisés », mais plutôt qu'ils ont souvent joué un rôle actif dans la construction de leurs propres identités culturelles au sein du plus grand monde impérial.Les études sur la Chine ancienne considèrent souvent le contact culturel de façon monolithique, et brossent un portrait de la Chine comme un état/empire avec une voix monotone. Cette thèse cherche à déconstruire l'identité sino-centrique en explorant le contact entre la Chine et son voisin, l'ancien Sichuan. Je conçois les contacts culturels comme étant un ensemble d'interactions diversifiées, irrégulières et hétérogènes plutôt que comme un procédé à sens unique.  Cette thèse déploie une approche interdisciplinaire permettant d'approfondir cette issue et d'aboutir à une synthèse critique en se basant sur l'histoire et l'archéologie ; elle analyse les sources textuelles, les comptes rendus historiques, les histoires locales et les preuves épigraphiques ainsi que la culture matérielle retrouvée dans les sépultures et dans d'autres sites.  Ces approches s'intègrent bien les unes aux autres et seront utilisées aussi bien dans le contexte général que dans le contexte particulier.  Plusieurs expressions d'identités seront examinées, dont l'institution intellectuelle locale, la pratique rituelle et la compilation de l'histoire locale. </description><creator>Hu, Chuan-an</creator><contributor>Robin Yates (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>East Asian Studies</subject><title>Early Chinese empires and the people without history: resistance, agency and identity of ancient colonial Sichuan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jd81b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278w92q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698b00w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alcohol use disorders are among the top two most prevalent psychiatric conditions in the Americas. Their expression is complex and their developmental pathways are varied. Understanding how individual differences in these pathways lead to the full pathology is imperative for designing and implementing effective therapeutic and preventative interventions. To investigate these pathways, we studied healthy young adults who classified as high in either anxiety-sensitivity or sensation-seeking traits (HAS and HSS, respectively). All subjects completed two functional magnetic resonance imaging sessions following the ingestion of either ethanol (g/kg) or placebo given in a double-blind, counter-balanced repeated-measures design. In the scanner, subjects performed a Face Emotion Processing Task and the Montreal Imaging Stress Task (MIST). Behavioral (performance), subjective mood, and endocrine response profiles were assessed throughout. 2-3 years later, subjects' substance use and mental health status were re-assessed. 7 propositions were made and defended: (1) HAS subjects (HASSs) were hyper-vigilant toward aversive faces, whereas HSSs were hyporesponsive or unresponsive; (2) acute social stress (MIST) induced arousal and a threat to social standing in HASSs, especially males, whereas in HSSSs, particularly males, it was perceived as a stimulating challenge eliciting energetic arousal; (3) alcohol blunted responses to aversive faces in HAS but had no effect in HSSSs; (4) alcohol-induced effects on social stress (MIST) reactivity differed as a function of personality profile, consistent with the pathways of risk; (5) escalation to alcohol misuse at follow-up was seen in HASSs who had previously exhibited the largest amygdalae activations to threatening faces under placebo and deactivation un- der alcohol; (6) escalation to alcohol or other drugs misuse at follow-up was seen in HSSSs who had previously exhibited mar- ked medial orbitofrontal activations to social stress (MIST) under placebo and diminished responses under alcohol; and (7) the predictive power of these neural responses was above and beyond other measured risk factors, These results suggest that at-risk individuals with distinct personality profiles respond differently to alcohol and stressful events, with the response patterns predicting their alcohol and illicit drug use behaviors 2-3 y to three years later.</description><description>Les troubles liés à la consommation l'alcool, constituant la plus importante condition prévalant en Amérique, ou la seconde, sont éminemment complexes et leur développement est sujet à une variabilité inter-individuelle. Comprendre comment ces développements ménent la pathologie à SA pleine expression, en fonction des personnes, est impératif pour modeler et déployer des thérapies efficaces et des interventions préventives. Le travail ci-présent se référe à une importante étude d'une population d'hommes et de femmes adultes en santé constituée de consommateurs sociaux et qui expriment fortement des traits relatif à la recherche de sensation ou bien une sensibilité à l'anxiété. Cette étude posséde deux parties: la premiére est une étude d'imagerie par résonance magnétique fonctionnelle (IRMf) présentant un groupe-contrôle placebo, en double aveugle, employant un défi d'alcohol. Dans le scanner, les sujets sont exposés un paradigme de challenge émotionnel consistant en deux tâches qui différent dans la forme et l'affect: the Face Emotion Processing Task (FEPT) et la Montreal Imaging Stress Task (MIST). Le profil de réponse a été conjointement investigué du point de vue comportemental, de la description subjective de l'humeur et du systéme endocrinien. La deuxiéme partie est une étude de suivi dans laquelle lesdits sujets ont été contactés 2 ou 3 ans aprés et ont été cliniquement testés à propos déventuelles habitudes d'utilisation de drogues et de maladie mentale. Sept propositions ont été posées et défendues: (1) les sujets sensibles à l'anxiété (ASS) sont négativement biaisés pour l'hypervigilance envers les signaux faciaux de menace, alors que les individus recherchant de sensations (SSS) étaient hyporéactifs ou non réactifs à ces signaux. (2) la composante socio-évaluative de la procédure du MIST induit un éveil soutenu et un intense sens de menace sociale s'observe chez les ASS, spécialement les hommes AS, alors que chez les SSS, particuliérement les hommes SS, elle étaient percue d'avantage comme un challenge que comme une menace, suscitant conséquemment une intense stimulation et un éveil énergique; (3) l'intoxication par l'alcool émousse pass- ablement la capacité de réaction aux visages provoquant l'aversion mais n'a pas causé de changement chez les SSS; (4) les effets, induits par l'alcool, sur la réaction au stress social (MIST) sont particuliérement prononcés chez les sujets masculins mais différent substantiellement de pattern en fonction du profil de personnalité, où l'on observe une cohérence entre les réponses des hommes intoxiqués AS et SS avec (respectivement) la régulation négative des affects et les voies désinhibitrices du risque; (5) parmi les ASS, ceux exprimant l'activation la plus prononcée de l'amygdale au visage menaçant VS neutre, sous placebo et la désactivation sous l'influence de l'alcool, ont abouti à l'abus d'alcool durant le suivi; (6) parmi les SSS, ceux affichant une activation substantielle de l'orbitofrontal médial au stress social (MIST), sous placebo et sous l'émoussement résultant de l'alcool lors de cette activation, sont ceux qui sont sujets à l'abus d'alcool et/ou d'autres drogues (typiquement la cocaïne) durant les 2-3 années suivantes; (7) la puissance prédictive des réponses neurales susnommées était supérieure à tout autres facteurs de risques mesurés. Nous concluons que les individus à risque selon les profils de personnalités distinctes répondent différemment aux différents stresseurs, et à l'alcool selon le sexe et ces stresseurs, et que la nature et l'ampleur de leur réponse prédit la réponse de la tâche liée à la consommation d'alcool et à l'abus de drogues illicites à l'égard des habitudes durant les 2-3 années suivantes.</description><creator>Abu Shakra, Malak</creator><contributor>Robert O Pihl (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>The ability of functional magnetic resonance imaging responses to alcohol and different emotional challenges to predict escalating drinking in different at-risk individuals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hj11n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698b00w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859j13x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>BackgroundHemorrhage continues to be the leading cause of death in major trauma. The concept of damage control resuscitation has gained popularity in both army and civilian setting, and early resuscitation with a high ratio plasma to packed red blood cell transfusion in a protocolized setting has been associated with improved survival, reduced complications and improved resource utilization.Research objectiveWe aim to determine if higher ratio plasma to packed red cell (FFP:PRBC) transfusion has an impact on survival in our Canadian level 1 trauma center.MethodsThis is a retrospective study incorporating all the trauma victims who received any blood transfusion in the period between July 2008 and December 2010. Of those, patients who received &gt;6 units of packed red cells in the first 24 hours were identified using the trauma and blood bank registry. Patients were divided into high plasma to packed red cell (FFP:PRBC &gt; 1:1.5) and low plasma to packed red cell ratio (FFP:PRBC &lt; 1:1.5) groups. Basic demographic data and detailed transfusion data were collected, along with in hospital mortality, hospital and intensive care unit length of stay.ResultsThe high ratio FFP:PRBC group had a lower mortality rate (22%) compared to the low ratio group (34.4%), (P=0.22). Multivariate logistic regression model identified low ratio FFP:PRBC transfusion as an independent predictor of same admission mortality (odds 10.21, 95%CI 1.33-78.28, P=0.03). Linear regression model did not identify any significant independent predictor of hospital or intensive care unit length of stay.ConclusionLower ratio FFP:PRBC massive transfusion in major trauma independently predicts mortality, and high ratio protocolized resuscitation in major trauma is recommended.</description><description>ContexteL'hémorragie continue d'être la principale cause de décès dans les traumatismes majeurs. Le concept de Damage Control Resuscitation (DCR) a gagné en popularité à la fois dans l'armée et dans l'environnement civil, et la réanimation précoce par la transfusion avec du plasma a un ratio élevé aux globules rouges emballés dans un cadre protocolisé a été associée à une survie améliorée, à des complications réduites et à une meilleure utilisation des ressources. Objectif de recherche Nous cherchons à déterminer si un ratio de plasma élevé à la transfusion de globules rouges emballés a un impact sur la survie dans notre centre de traumatologie au niveau 1 au Canada. Méthodes Il s'agit d'une étude rétrospective intégrant toutes les victimes de traumatismes qui ont reçu une transfusion sanguine entre juillet 2008 et décembre 2010. Parmi ceux-ci, les patients ayant reçu plus que 6 unités de globules rouges emballés dans les premières 24 heures ont été identifiés en utilisant le Registre de traumatisme et du Banque de Sang. Les patients ont été divisés en deux groupe, groupe avec un ratio élevé de plasma à globules rouges emballés (FFP :PRBC &gt; 1:1.5) et groupe avec un ratio faible de plasma à globules rouges emballé (FFP :PRBC &lt; 1 :1.5). Les données démographiques de base et les données transfusionnelles détaillées ont été recueillies, ainsi que la mortalité hospitalière et la durée de séjour hospitalier et en soins intensifs. Résultats Le groupe avec un ratio élevé de plasma à globules rouges emballés avait un taux de mortalité plus faible (22 %) par rapport au groupe à faible ratio (34,4%), (p = 0,22). Modèle de régression logistique multivariée a identifié la transfusion de faible ratio de plasma à globules rouges emballés comme un facteur prédictif indépendant de mortalité à la même admission (probabilité 10.21, IC 95% 1.33-78.28, p = 0,03). Le modèle de régression linéaire n'a pas identifié un prédicteur indépendant important de la durée de séjour de l'hôpital ou de la salle de soins intensifs.ConclusionLa transfusion massive avec un ratio faible de plasma à des globules rouges emballés, dans les traumatismes majeurs, prédit indépendamment la mortalité, et une réanimation protocolaire à risque élevé dans les traumatismes majeurs est recommandée.</description><creator>Alburakan, Ahmed</creator><contributor>Tarek Razek (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Surgery</subject><title>Early high ratio plasma to packed red blood cell massive transfusion in major trauma patients improves survival in a Canadian level I trauma center</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b598n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859j13x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qs16w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La livraison du fer (Fe) à la plupart des cellules se produit après la liaison de la transferrine diferrique (Tf) à ses récepteurs correspondants sur la membrane cellulaire. Les complexes Tf-récepteurs sont ensuite internalisés par endocytose, et le fer est libéré du Tf par une procédure qui implique l'acidification des endosomes. Malheureusement, le chemin post-endosomale du fer dans les cellules reste insaisissable ou est, au mieux, un sujet controversé. Il a été communément admis qu'un intermédiaire à faible poids moléculaire accompagne (chaperones) le fer dans le transit des endosomes vers les mitochondries et vers d'autres sites d'utilisation; cependant, cette intermédiaire (très recherché) qui se lie au fer n'a jamais été identifié. Nous avons démontré, en utilisant l'imagerie confocale 3D sur des cellules vivants, que la voie de distribution du fer dans les réticulocytes implique une interaction directe et transitoire des endosomes avec les mitochondries. De plus, nous avons démontré l'interaction de ces organites par un nouveau procédé dans lequel nous avons utilisé la cytométrie de flux pour analyser les réticulocytes lysées marqués avec Alexa Green Transferrin (AGTF) et MitoTracker Deep Red (MTDR). En utilisant cette nouvelle technique de subcytometry, nous avons identifié une population doublement marquée représentant endosomes interagissant avec les mitochondries. La nature dynamique de cette interaction a été montrée par des expériences de chasse dans lesquelles une diminution, dépendant du temps, de la population doublement marquée a été observée lorsque les réticulocytes ont été incubés avec Fe2-Tf sans étiquette. En outre, nous avons montré que le statut en fer des endosomes régit l'efficacité de la livraison du fer aux mitochondries par médiation des endosomes. Les expériences avec l'hème, qui est connu pour la rétroaction négatif au sujet de la libération du fer à partir Tf dans les endosomes, ralentit la production de la population doublement marquée. Ceci résulte probablement en raison d'un blocage d'export de Fe2+ des endosomes déjà associées aux mitochondries, prolongeant leur temps de séjour sur ces mitochondries. Ceci démontre que la saturation en Tf intraendosomales régit l'association entre les organites pour la livraison de fer dans les cellules érythroïdes. Nous avons utilisé différentes formes de la transferrine recombinante humaine (rTf) marqué par fluorescence, qui, soit restent liés en permanence au fer (holotransférrine recombinant; L-Fe2-rTf) ou ne peuvent pas se lier au fer (apotransferrine recombinant; L-apo-rTf ), dans des études de subcytometry d'écoulement. Ces études montrent que les réticulocytes marqués avec MTDR et L-apo-rTf ne parviennent pas à produire une population doublement marquée dans les expériences d'absorption, ce qui suggère que L-apo-rTf fluorescentes chargés d'endosomes n'interagissent pas avec les mitochondries. Fait intéressant, lorsque des lysats de réticulocytes ont été marquées avec MTDR et L-Fe2-rTf, nous avons observé une diminution de la population doublement marquée, comparé aux expériences de contrôle su le type sauvage humaine holo-Tf, indiquant qu'un échec de la libération du fer à partir de L- Fe2-rTf peut interférer avec le processus d'endocytose. Nous avons aussi mesuré l'incorporation du 59Fe du type sauvage 59Fe-Tf dans des réticulocytes et leur hème et nous avons montré que L-Fe2-rTf, comparé au Tf type sauvage, diminue de manière significative l'incorporation du 59Fe dans l'hème. Des expériences avec érythroleucémie murin et le foie foetal ont des cellules qui montrent une augmentation significative de l'amplitude du contact entre les endosomes et les mitochondries lorsque les cellules sont induites à se différencier. Dans l'ensemble, nos résultats montrent que les endosomes entrent en contact avec les mitochondries pour fournir du fer pour la biosynthèse de l'hème, non seulement dans les cellules érythroïdes, mais aussi dans leurs progéniteurs.</description><description>Delivery of iron (Fe) to most cells occurs following the binding of diferric transferrin (Tf) to its cognate receptors on the cell membrane. The Tf-receptor complexes are then internalized via endocytosis, and iron is released from Tf by a process involving endosomal acidification. Unfortunately, the post-endosomal pathway of iron within cells remains elusive or is, at best, controversial. It has been commonly accepted that a low molecular weight intermediate chaperones iron in transit from endosomes to mitochondria and other sites of utilization; however, this much sought iron binding intermediate has never been identified. We have shown, using 3D live confocal imaging, that the iron delivery pathway in reticulocytes involves a direct and transient interaction of endosomes with mitochondria. Furthermore, we have demonstrated the interaction of these organelles by a novel method in which we have used flow cytometry to analyze reticulocyte lysates labeled with Alexa Green Transferrin (AGTf) and MitoTracker Deep Red (MTDR). By using this new technique of subcytometry, we identified a double-labeled population representing endosomes interacting with mitochondria. The dynamic nature of this interaction was shown by chase experiments in which a time-dependent decrease of the double-labeled population was observed when reticulocytes were incubated with unlabeled Fe2-Tf. In addition, we have shown that the iron status of endosomes governs the efficacy of endosome-mediated iron delivery to mitochondria. Experiments with heme, which is known to feedback inhibit the release of iron from Tf in endosomes, slows the generation of the double-labeled population. This probably results due to a blockage of Fe2+ export from endosomes already associated with mitochondria, extending their resident time on mitochondria. This shows that intraendosomal Tf saturation governs interorganellar association for iron delivery in erythroid cells.Presently, we provide further evidence of an interaction between mitochondria with endosomes. Fluorescence-labeled mitochondria isolated from mouse reticulocytes with MTDR and AGTf were analyzed using 2D confocal microscopy. Results from these experiments confirmed that mitochondria are indeed in physical contact with endosomes. In addition, we have used different constructs of fluorescence-labeled, recombinant human Tf (rTf), which either remain permanently bound to iron (recombinant holotransferrin; L-Fe2-rTf) or cannot bind iron (recombinant apotransferrin; L-apo-rTf), in flow subcytometry studies. These studies show that reticulocytes labeled with MTDR and L-apo-rTf fail to produce a double-labeled population in uptake experiments, suggesting that fluorescent L-apo-rTf-laden endosomes do not interact with mitochondria. Interestingly, when reticulocyte lysates were labeled with MTDR and L-Fe2-rTf, we observed a decrease in the double-labeled population, as compared to control experiments using wild type human holo-Tf, indicating that a failure of iron release from L-Fe2-rTf may interfere with the process of endocytosis. We also measured 59Fe incorporation from wild-type 59Fe-Tf into reticulocytes and their heme and showed that pre-treatment of reticulocytes with L-Fe2-rTf, as compared to the wild-type Tf, significantly decreases 59Fe incorporation into heme.Experiments with murine erythroleukemia and fetal liver cells reveal a significant increase in the magnitude of contacts between endosomes and mitochondria when cells are induced to differentiate. Taken together our results show that endosomes come in contact with mitochondria to deliver iron for heme biosynthesis not only in erythroid cells but also in their progenitors.</description><creator>Roshan, Tariq</creator><contributor>Premysl Ponka (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Delivery of iron to mitochondria in erythroid cells for heme synthesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956j45f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qs16w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999919z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:54:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The use of restraint and seclusion to manage crisis situations in mental health settings is being widely challenged, but is still common. The rates of restraint and seclusion episodes on child mental health units are of particular concern, as they have been reported to be significantly higher than on adult units. A growing body of literature has highlighted the misuse of these control measures and the serious harms that can result from these practices (e.g. traumatization, death of the child). The use of such measures poses ethical challenges to nurses and other staff members who aim to act in the best interests of children and ensure their safety, while promoting children's capacity to manage their behavior and recognize children's agency. This study sought to examine the institutional norms, structures, practices, and corresponding moral experiences of children, parents and staff members around crisis management and the related use of control measures in order to develop care approaches that promote an optimal reconciliation of ethical concerns in child mental health. A novel methodological framework drawing on Taylor's hermeneutic philosophy—participatory hermeneutic ethnography—was developed to conduct this study, which enabled an in-depth examination of the concept of children's agency. A five-month participatory hermeneutic ethnography was conducted in a Canadian child mental health setting providing care to children aged 6 to 12 years old. Data collection involved participant observation, interviews, and documentation review. An interpretive framework was used for data analysis. The results show how the strict structure in place both prevented and contributed to crisis situations. Children were expected to comply, conform and acquiesce with staff and were generally perceived as the objects of care; and not as active agents involved in care processes. Children perceived control measures as helpful in exceptional cases when there was an imminent risk to someone's safety, and largely disagreed with their use as a consequence for bad behavior. This perspective contrasted with most of the staff members who considered control measures contributed to help the child feel safe, learn the limits in the setting, and form a trusting relationship. Parents were not part of the everyday experiences in the setting, and were confident the staff would use control measures as a last resort. The results suggest that the prevalent view of the child shared by staff members as incomplete human becomings led to the adoption and legitimization of authoritative norms, structures and practices guided largely by a behavioral approach, which sometimes led to an increased use of control measures for reasons other than imminent harm. Children experienced these controlling practices as abusive and hindering the development of trusting relationships with the staff, which impeded the implementation of a more collaborative approach that staff members sought to put in place to prevent the use of control measures. Changes in conceptions of children from objects to agents by the staff and seeking a rapprochement with children, by getting to know what is meaningful to them and try to bridge these horizons, could help build more authentic trusting relationships that might be more conducive to the implementation of collaborative approaches.</description><description>Le recours aux contentions et à l'isolement pour gérer les situations de crises en santé mentale est largement remis en question, mais pratique courante. Les taux d'épisodes de contentions et d'isolement sur les unités de soins de santé mentale avec les enfants est particulièrement préoccupant, ayant été rapportés comme étant significativement plus élevés que sur les unités de soins aux adultes. Un nombre croissant d'écrits scientifiques a mis en lumière l'utilisation abusive de ces mesures de contrôle et les dommages graves qui peuvent résulter de ces pratiques (par ex. : trauma et mort de l'enfant).  L'utilisation de telles mesures pose des défis éthiques aux infirmières et aux autres membres du personnel qui visent à agir dans le meilleur intérêt des enfants et à assurer leur sécurité, tout en favorisant la capacité des enfants à gérer leur comportement et en reconnaissant leur agentivité. Cette étude a examiné les normes institutionnelles, structures, pratiques et expériences morales des enfants, parents et membres du personnel en lien avec la gestion de crise et l'utilisation des mesures de contrôle afin de développer des approches de soins qui favorisent une conciliation optimale de préoccupations éthiques en santé mentale de l'enfant. Un nouveau cadre méthodologique s'appuyant sur la philosophie herméneutique de Taylor – l'ethnographie herméneutique participative – a été développé pour mener cette étude, ce qui a permis un examen approfondi de la notion d'agentivité chez les enfants. Une ethnographie herméneutique participative de cinq mois a été menée dans un établissement canadien de santé mentale offrant des soins aux enfants âgés de 6 à 12 ans. La collecte de données incluait l'observation participative, des entrevues et une analyse documentaire. Un cadre interprétatif a été utilisé pour l'analyse des données. Les résultats révèlent comment la structure stricte en place jouait le double rôle de prévenir les situations de crise et d'y contribuer. Les enfants devaient respecter, se conformer et acquiescer au personnel soignant et étaient généralement perçus comme des objets du soin, et non comme des agents actifs impliqués dans les processus de soins. Les enfants percevaient les mesures de contrôle comme étant nécessaires dans des cas exceptionnels lorsqu'il y avait un risque imminent pour la sécurité de quelqu'un. Ils étaient largement en désaccord avec leur utilisation comme conséquence d'un mauvais comportement. Cette perspective contrastait avec la plupart des membres du personnel qui considéraient que les mesures de contrôle contribuaient à aider l'enfant à se sentir en sécurité, à connaître les limites et à établir une relation de confiance. Les parents n'étaient pas présents au quotidien dans le milieu de soins et étaient confiants que le personnel soignant utiliserait les mesures de contrôle en dernier ressort. Les résultats suggèrent que la vision dominante de l'enfant par les membres du personnel comme des êtres incomplets en devenir a conduit à l'adoption et à la légitimation de normes, structures et pratiques guidées principalement par une approche comportementale qui a parfois entraîné une utilisation accrue des mesures de contrôle pour des raisons autres qu'un préjudice imminent. Les enfants considéraient ces pratiques comme étant abusives et empêchaient le développement d'une relation de confiance avec le personnel, entravant la mise en œuvre d'une approche plus collaborative que les membres du personnel cherchaient à mettre en place pour diminuer l'utilisation des mesures de contrôle. Un changement dans les conceptions de l'enfant par le personnel soignant – d'objets du soin à agents actifs – ainsi que la recherche d'un rapprochement avec les enfants, en apprenant ce qu'ils considèrent comme significatif et en essayant de faire le pont entre ces horizons, pourrait contribuer à créer des relations de confiance plus authentiques et propices à la mise en œuvre d'approches collaboratives.</description><creator>Montreuil, Marjorie</creator><contributor>Franco Carnevale (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Nursing</subject><title>Moral experiences of crisis management in a child mental health setting: A participatory hermeneutic ethnographic inquiry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x1771.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999919z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Ingram School of Nursing</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mz116</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:55:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Respiratory infections, including community-acquired pneumonia, are most common among the elderly and immunocompromised individuals. Legionella pneumophila (Lp) contributes to this disease burden as the leading cause of Legionnaires' disease (LD), an atypical and potentially life-threatening pneumonia whose incidence rates have seen an increase in the last decade. This water-borne bacterium is transmitted through contaminated aerosols that are emitted from a variety of water distribution systems. Lp is ubiquitous in freshwater, and notoriously persistent in anthropogenic systems, surviving a slew of disinfectants. An important knowledge gap in Legionella research is the identification of genetic factors contributing to the long-term survival of the bacterium in water, and in response to the environmental stresses encountered within aquatic systems. As a first step, the development of a reproducible proxy for a freshwater model was required. We present Fraquil as an appropriate medium for the study of Lp. Using this freshwater medium; we found that Lp is able to survive for over 6 months in 15oC water while retaining its ability to infect host cells. Another finding that merits further study is entry of Lp into a viable-but-non-culturable state at 4oC. Fraquil was further used to study a set of regulators that contribute to the bi-phasic lifestyle of Lp. As a result, we report that the LetA/S two-component system is crucial for a general transcriptomic shutdown that allows Lp to survive in water. After probing the mechanism of activation, we report that while dependent on ppGpp for expression, LetS is activated independently of this global response in water. Finally, we identified a second regulatory protein, OxyR, as a contributor to surviving oxidative stress in water. For the first time, the work presented here offers a reproducible medium to study Legionella in water, allowing better comparisons between studies and the ability to control the complexity of the water medium when exploring the effect of environmental factors on bacterial behaviour. It has been successfully used in the work presented here and elsewhere to study genetic factors that contribute to the survival of Legionella in water, an area of research that has only recently begun to be explored. Furthermore, we have identified a major contributor to the overall survival in water, the LetA/S two-component system. Finally, we have characterized OxyR which was previously found to be dispensable for responding to exogenous oxidative stress. We report that it is essential for Lp to survive oxidative stress in the water environment, likely through non-traditional mechanisms. The work presented herein broadens our knowledge about the regulatory mechanisms used by this aquatic pathogen, potentially leading the way to innovative detection and/or control methods.</description><description>Les infections respiratoires, y compris la pneumonie acquise dans la communauté, sont les plus fréquentes chez les personnes âgées et les personnes immunodéprimées. Legionella pneumophila (Lp) contribue à ce fardeau de la maladie en tant que principale cause de la maladie du légionnaire (LD), une pneumonie atypique et potentiellement mortelle dont les taux d'incidence ont augmenté au cours de la dernière décennie. Lp est transmise par des aérosols contaminés qui sont émis dans l'environnement par une variété de systèmes hydriques. Lp est omniprésent dans l'eau douce, et notoirement persistant dans les systèmes anthropiques, étant résistant à de nombreux traitement désinfectants. Les gènes qui contribuent à sa survie dans l'eau et à sa résistance aux stresses environnementaux rencontrées dans les systèmes hydriques sont peu connus. Dans un premier temps, le développement d'un modèle d'eau douce reproductible était nécessaire. Je présente le Fraquil comme modèle d'eau pour l'étude de Lp. En utilisant ce modèle, j'ai constaté que Lp est capable de survivre pendant plus de 6 mois dans cet eau à une température de 15°C tout en conservant sa capacité d'infecter les cellules hôtes. De plus, il semble que Lp entre dans un état viable-mais-non-cultivable à 4°C. D'autres études seront nécessaires pour bien comprendre ce processus. Le Fraquil a ensuite été utilisé pour étudier un ensemble de régulateurs qui contribuent au mode de vie bi-phasique de Lp. En conséquence, j'ai déterminé que le système à deux composants LetA/S est crucial pour un arrêt transcriptomique général qui permet à Lp de survivre dans l'eau. Après avoir sondé le mécanisme d'activation, j'ai trouvé que LetS est activé indépendamment de la réponse stringente. Enfin, j'ai identifié que le régulateur global OxyR contribue à la résistance au stress oxydatif dans l'eau. Pour la première fois, le travail présenté ici offre un moyen reproductible pour étudier la légionelle dans l'eau, permettant de meilleures comparaisons entre les études et la capacité de contrôler la complexité du milieu de l'eau lors de l'exploration de l'effet des facteurs environnementaux. Il a été utilisé avec succès dans le travail présenté ici et ailleurs pour étudier les facteurs génétiques qui contribuent à la survie de Legionella dans l'eau. En outre, nous avons identifié un facteur majeur de la survie globale dans l'eau, le système à deux composants LetA/S. Nous avons également caractérisé OxyR qui, auparavant, était considéré non-essentiel pour répondre au stress oxydatif exogène. Nous signalons qu'il est essentiel pour la survive de Lp au stress oxydatif dans l'eau, probablement grâce à la régulation des gènes non-traditionnels. Le travail présenté ici élargit notre connaissance des mécanismes utilisés par ce pathogène aquatique, ouvrant la voie à des méthodes novatrices de détection et/ou de contrôle.</description><creator>Mendis, Nissanka</creator><contributor>Sebastien Faucher (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Natural Resource Sciences</subject><title>Environmental and genetic factors that contribute to the adaptation and survival of «Legionella pneumophila» in water systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f617d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mz116</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n3667</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:55:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Knowledge of in-field biomass can help optimize crop production efficiency through well-informed farm management decisions and practices. In this project, research was conducted on canopy characterization to estimate the biomass of foliage-based crops, such as vegetables and forage. Emphasis was placed on nondestructive methods, such as canopy reflectance and plant height sensing for in-season resource allocation. Two feasibility studies were described in this thesis.In the first experiment, a portable tripod system with a rotation ultrasonic proximity sensor was used to estimate the in-situ biomass of baby arugula and spinach grown on a high rotation raised plot. A calibration study was conducted in Sherrington, QC by scanning the canopy profile within 50 by 50 cm areas. A correlation model was built by relating the percentile of the measured height, or average maxima within 10o angular displacements, with manually determined biomass. The generated linear regression models produced the coefficient of determination (r2) values of up to 0.80 for arugula and 0.92 for spinach. The second experiment was conducted in the farm fields of Macdonald Campus of McGill University, located in Ste-Anne-de-Bellevue, QC. An integrated sensor system comprised of an ultrasonic proximity sensor and an active canopy sensor were tested individually and in combination to estimate fresh forage biomass. The system was conducted on a variety of alfalfa and grass/legume mixtures through: 1) stationary sensor sampling and 2) on-the-go field mapping. Calibration data were obtained by using stationary samples and the interpolation of mapped data using an inverse distance weighting (IDW) method. The r2 of 0.76 and 0.65 was found when predicting biomass using NDVI and plant height measurements, respectively. However, it was observed that each sensor has advantages and mutually they can compensate for their shortcomings. Thus, plant height was less affected by changes in the field and vegetation, and it predicted biomass at full canopy coverage. NDVI was more sensitive to changes in vegetation density and vegetation type that height measurement would not be able to take into account. As such, the combined sensor regression model explained 78% of the variability using field-specific biomass-predicting calibration models.</description><description>La connaissance de la distribution de biomasse dans le champ peut aider à optimiser l'efficacité de la production végétale grâce à des décisions et des pratiques bien informées. Dans ce projet, des recherches ont été menées sur les caractéristiques de la canopée pour estimer la biomasse des cultures à base de feuillage telles que les légumes et les fourrages. Nous avons mis l'accent sur des méthodes non destructrices telles que la réflectance des couvertures et la détection de la hauteur des plantes. Deux études de faisabilité ont été conduites dans cette thèse. Dans la première expérience, un système portatif à base de trépied et ultrasons avait mesuré la hauteur du canapé pour estimer la biomasse in situ des cultivars de bébés roquettes et des épinards. Une étude d'étalonnage a été réalisée à Sherrington, Qc. en balayant le profil de la canopée dans des échantillons de 50 cm par 50 cm. Le modèle de corrélation a été construit en comparant les percentiles des hauteurs mesurées et des moyens des maxima collecté dans chaque incrément de 10 degrés avec la biomasse échantillonnée manuellement. Les modèles de régression linéaire générés ont produit des valeurs de r2 allant jusqu'à 0,80 pour la roquette et 0,92 pour les épinards.La deuxième expérience a été effectué dans les champs agricoles du campus Macdonald de l'Université McGill, situé à Ste-Anne-de-Bellevue, Qc. Un système de capteur intégré comprenant un capteur de proximité ultrasonique et un capteur de canopée actif ont été testés individuellement et en combinaison pour estimer la biomasse fourragère fraîche. Le système a été réalisé en deux parties sur une variété de mélanges de luzerne et d'herbe / légumineuses : échantillonnage stationnaire des capteurs et cartographie sur le terrain. Les données d'étalonnage ont été obtenues en utilisant à la fois des échantillons stationnaires et une interpolation de données cartographiques à l'aide d'une méthode de pesée à distance inverse (IDW). Le coefficient de détermination de 0.76 et 0.65 a été trouvé dans la corrélation de la biomasse avec les mesures NDVI et la taille des plantes, respectivement. Cependant, nous avons observé que chaque capteur avait son propre avantage et, mutuellement, ils peuvent compenser leurs défauts. Par exemple, la hauteur de la plante a été moins affectée par les changements dans le champ et la végétation et il a prédit la biomasse à la couverture de la canopée complète. NDVI était plus sensible au changement de densité de végétation et de type de végétation que la mesure en hauteur ne serait pas en mesure de comptabiliser. En tant que tel, le modèle de régression du capteur combiné a expliqué 0.78 de la corrélation avec la biomasse spécifique au champ des mélanges de fourrages de luzerne.</description><creator>Su, Yue</creator><contributor>Viacheslav Adamchuk (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>Development of proximal sensing systems for crop biomass determination</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k514q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n3667</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f387s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:55:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Efficient and effective management of supply and demand is the central challenge in power grids, and is of pivotal importance both in the technological and economical aspects. One of the interesting topics in this domain is the usage of battery energy storage systems at the end users in microgrids, so as to reduce the average cost of energy supply by exploiting electricity price fluctuations. Storing energy when its price is low and discharge it when the price is high provides users with the opportunity to gain financial benefits out of appropriate control schemes. In this thesis, we intend to determine the structure of an optimal control policy and to gain insights into the impact of some system model parameters, such as battery size, charge/discharge rate, power demand process, and cost functions on the cost savings performance that can be achieved by this policy.In the thesis, we first formulate the desired optimization problem into a Markov decision process which can be solved by dynamic programming methods. Then, existing results from previous research are presented on theoretical deductions of the shape of the optimal energy storage policy under piecewise, convex and non-decreasing cost functions. Next, a proper simulation environment is developed to verify the validity of the existing theoretical results in both idealized and non-idealized battery model scenarios. Finally, after running extensive simulations based on real-life power demand data, a parametric study is conducted in comparison to a benchmark battery-less microgrid system.</description><description>Une gestion efficiente et efficace d'approvisionnement et des demandes est le principal défi dans les réseaux électriques et joue un rôle crucial dans les aspects technologiques et économiques. Undes sujets intéressants dans ce domaine est l'utilisation de systèmes de stockage d'énergie de batterie aux utilisateurs finaux en microgrilles, afin de réduire le coût moyen de l'approvisionnement d'énergie en exploitant les fluctuations des prix d'électricité. Stocker de l'énergie lorsque le prix est bas et le décharger lorsque le prix est élevé offre aux utilisateurs la possibilité d'obtenir des avantages financiers à partir de programmes de contrôle appropriés. Dans cette thèse, nous avons l'intention de déterminer la structure d'une politique de contrôle optimale et de mieux comprendre l'impact de certains paramètres du modèle du système, tels que la taille de la batterie, le taux de charge / décharge, le processus de demande d'alimentation et les fonctions de coûts sur les performances d'économie de coûts qui peuvent être atteintes par cette politique.Dans la thèse, nous allons d'abord formuler le problème d'optimisation souhaité dans un processus de décision Markov qui peut être résolu par des méthodes de programmation dynamiques. Ensuite, les résultats existants des recherches antérieures sont présentés sur les déductions théoriques sous la forme de la politique optimale de stockage d'énergie par des fonctions de coûts par morceaux, convexes et non décroissantes. Ensuite, un environnement de simulation approprié est développé pour vérifier la validité des résultats théoriques existants dans des scénarios de modèles de batteries idéalisés et non idéalisés. Enfin, après avoir effectué des simulations étendues basées sur des données de la demande d'alimentation de la vie réelle, une étude paramétrique est réalisée par rapport à un système de microgrille sans batterie de référence.</description><creator>Lei, Ming</creator><contributor>Bouffard,François (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Mahajan, Aditya (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Optimal policies for energy storage in microgrids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r107q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f387s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634620r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:55:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Globally, over 36 million people are infected with human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1). Some individuals exposed to HIV remain persistently seronegative. Among those who become infected a subset of approximately 5% progress to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) slowly, and even fewer, i.e. &lt;1% control their viral load (VL) without treatment. Epidemiological and functional studies found that carriage of certain Natural Killer (NK) cell receptor (NKR)/human leukocyte antigen (HLA) ligand pairs is associated with slow time to AIDS in HIV-positive subjects and protection from infection in HIV-exposed seronegative subjects, implicating NK cells in HIV control. NK cells acquire anti-viral functions through a process called education, that requires signals received from inhibitory NKR (iNKRs) engaging their ligands. This thesis investigated the mechanism by which NK cells mediate inhibition of HIV replication, particularly in NK cells from donors expressing a high expression KIR3DL1 homozygous genotype with HLA-B*57 (*h/*y+B*57), which is the KIR/HLA pair that has the strongest effect on slow time to AIDS and HIV VL control. Furthermore, we analyzed the impact of expression of the iNKRs KIR2DL3, KIR3DL1 and NKG2A on NK functionality in response to autologous HIV infected cells in NK cell populations defined by these iNKRs. We extended our analyses of NK cell responses to autologous HIV infected stimuli to iNKR/HLA pairs involved in education through the above mentioned iNKRs, taking into consideration the impact of HIV infection on downmodulation of the ligands for these iNKR. In this thesis we show that NK cell education influences the potency of NK cell mediated inhibition of HIV replication. The inhibition of viral replication in autologous HIV-infected cells involves responses by the KIR3DL1+ NK cells and is, at least in part due, to the secretion of CC-chemokines by this NK cell population. Our results also show that NKG2A+ and KIR2DL3+ NK cells mediate responses to autologous HIV infected cells. We show that the responses of NK cell populations to HIV-infected cells are influenced not only by NK cell education through specific KIR/HLA pairs, but also by differential HIV mediated changes in HLA expression. Together these observations provide additional support for the importance of NK cells and populations of these cells as mediators of response to HIV-infected cells. These findings also demonstrate the dynamic role of NK cell education on aspects of NK cell functions, both in the context of broad stimulation by HLA null cells and responses to HIV-infected cells.</description><description>A travers le monde, 36 millions de personnes sont actuellement infectées par le virus de l'immunodéficience humaine de type 1 (VIH-1). Bien qu'ils soient également exposés au virus, un certain nombre d'individus restent séronégatif à long terme. Parmi ceux qui sont infectés, environ 5% progressent lentement vers le syndrome d'immunodéficience acquis (SIDA) et moins de 1% contrôlent leur charge virale en l'absence de tout traitement. Des études épidémiologiques et fonctionnelles ont mis en évidence le rôle potentiel des cellules Natural Killer (NK) dans le contrôle de l'infection virale. En effet, ces études ont montré que les individus qui co-expriment certains récepteurs présents à la surface des cellules NK, les NKR, en association avec certains ligands du complexe majeur d'histocompatibilité (CMH/HLA), sont protégés de l'infection ou progressent moins rapidement vers le SIDA si ils sont déjà infectés. Les cellules NK acquièrent leurs fonctions antivirales par un processus appelé « éducation » qui nécessite la signalisation à travers les NKR inhibiteurs (iNKRs) par leurs ligands. Dans ce travail, nous avons étudié les mécanismes par lesquels les cellules NK inhibent la réplication virale, en particulier les cellules NK issues d'individus qui expriment fortement KIR3DL1 (homozygote) et HLA-B*57 (*h/*y+B*57), un des tandems récepteur/ligand le plus fortement associé à une progression lente vers le SIDA et au contrôle de la charge virale. Nous avons analysé l'impact des iNKRs KIR2DL3, KIR3DL1 et NKG2A sur la fonctionnalité des cellules NK en réponse à des cellules T CD4+ autologues infectées par le virus (iCD4). Nous avons ensuite étudié cette réponse dans le cadre plus particulier des tandems iNKRs/HLA (mentionnés ci-dessus) impliqués dans l'éducation des cellules NK, en prenant en compte l'effet du virus sur la diminution de l'expression membranaire des ligands de ces iNKRs. Dans ce travail, nous avons alors montré que l'éducation des cellules NK influe sur leur capacité à inhiber la réplication virale. L'inhibition de la réplication virale met en jeu la réponse des cellules NK KIR3DL1+ et est, en partie, dépendent de la sécrétion de chimiokines de la famille CC par ces cellules. Nos résultats montrent également que ce sont les cellules NK NKG2A+ et KIR2DL3+ qui répondent aux iCD4, que l'éducation des cellules NK via les iNKRs mais également l'expression membranaire du HLA modulent leur capacité à répondre aux iCD4. L'ensemble de ces résultats apporte de nouveaux arguments démontrant l'importance des cellules NK en tant que médiateur de la réponse contre les cellules infectées par le VIH. Ils démontrent également le rôle dynamique de l'éducation des cellules NK sur leurs capacités fonctionnelles que ce soit dans un contexte de stimulation par des cellules n'exprimant pas de HLA ou par des cellules infectées par le virus. </description><creator>Lisovsky, Irene</creator><contributor>Nicole F Bernard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Characterization of NK cell subsets responding to HIV infected cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qp74d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634620r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150m532</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:55:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As key effector units of the cell, understanding structure and function relationships of proteins are integral to explaining physiology and, in turn, pathophysiology. With the cost of drug development soaring and success dwindling, new ways to probe protein function will be at the forefront of innovation. A protein's function is the product of its conformational dynamics, where distinct 3-dimensional conformations of a protein dictate its various effects on the cell. Though highly valuable technologies capable of reporting on protein conformation currently exist, X-ray crystallography and nuclear magnetic resonance among others, their capacity to report on dynamic events and/or in physiologically relevant assay conditions are limited.This thesis describes the development and application of biosensors capable of reporting on protein conformation in live human cells. Biosensors were developed for two classes of protein targets, ion channels – Kir3, and G protein-coupled receptors (GPCR) -  FP and AT1R, together representing the targets of a majority of current prescription drugs. The biosensor design was based on bioluminescence resonance energy transfer (BRET) and required the insertion of a bioluminescent protein and a short peptide sequences within the protein of interest. Due to the specific affinity for the peptide sequence of an organic fluorophore, fluorescein biarsenical hairpin binder (FlAsH), the latter could be used as a resonance energy transfer acceptor to probe the different conformations of the protein of interest without disrupting its function.Both panels of biosensors successfully reported on ligand-induced conformational rearrangements in the target proteins and correlated with functional effects. The GPCR biosensors were further applied to enrich our understanding of receptor dimerization and allosteric communication between proteins, in this case, the FP/AT1R heterodimer.</description><description>Comprendre la relation entre la structure et la fonction des protéines est essentiel pour expliquer la physiologie, et par conséquent, la pathophysiologie. Par ailleurs, devant le constat que le coût lié au développement du médicament ne cesse d'augmenter alors que le taux de succès diminue, de nouveaux moyens de sonder la fonction des protéines devraient être à l'avant-garde de l'innovation. Les effets sur la cellule d'une protéine s'expliquent en partie par ses propriétés dynamiques, c'est-à-dire qu'une même protéine induit des effets différents selon la conformation tridimensionnelle qu'elle adopte. Bien qu'il existe des technologies permettant d'étudier la conformation des protéines, telles que la cristallographie par rayons X et la résonance magnétique nucléaire, leur capacité à déceler des événements dynamiques et/ou à les évaluer dans des conditions physiologiques est limitée.Cette thèse décrit le développement et l'application de biosenseurs capables de détecter les changements conformationnels des protéines dans les cellules humaines vivantes. Deux classes de biosenseurs ont été développées pour étudier les protéines ciblées par la majorité des médicaments prescrits, soit les canaux ioniques – Kir3 et les récepteurs couplés aux protéines G (RCPG) – FP et AT1R. La conception des biosenseurs, basée sur le transfert d'énergie par résonance de bioluminescence (BRET), a nécessité l'insertion d'une protéine bioluminescente et d'une séquence peptidique à l'intérieur de la protéine d'intérêt. Grâce à l'affinité spécifique pour la séquence peptidique d'un fluorophore organique, une fluorescéine arsénique (FlAsH), ce dernier a pu être utilisé comme accepteur de transfert d'énergie par résonance pour sonder les différentes conformations de la protéine d'intérêt sans en perturber sa fonction. Les deux classes de biosenseurs ont détecté avec succès les changements conformationnels des protéines induits par un ligand et ces changements ont été corrélés aux effets fonctionnels de ces mêmes protéines. L'utilisation des biosenseurs de RCPG a permis d'enrichir notre compréhension de la dimérisation des récepteurs et de la communication allostérique entre les protéines, en ce cas, l'heterodimère de FP/AT1R.</description><creator>Sleno, Rory</creator><contributor>Terence Hebert (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics</subject><title>Shedding a new light on protein conformational dynamics: development and application of FlAsH-BRET conformation sensors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547v039.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m532</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s272h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:55:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Au cours de la dernière décennie, plusieurs éléments de preuve ont démontré que la transformation d'une cellule épithéliale normale en un phénotype malin nécessite l'accumulation d'événements multiples. Il apparaît de plus en plus clairement que l'acquisition d'une modification anormale de la chromatine pourrait agir conjointement avec des aberrations génétiques pour faciliter la dérégulation. Les protéines du Groupe Polycomb (PcG) sont un groupe répresseur de transcription qui rendent silencieux des gènes en modifiant la chromatine à travers une modification covalente des histones. L'amplificateur de l'homologie zeste 2 (EZH2) est une protéine PcG qui, faisant partie du complexe multi-protéines Polycomb Repressive Complex 2 (PRC2), participe à l'inhibition des gènes par tri-méthylation de la lysine 27 sur l'histone 3 (H3K27me3). Les gènes cibles de la répression opérée par H3K27me3 incluent des gènes impliqués dans des processus cellulaires fondamentaux tels que la décision du devenir cellulaire, la régulation du cycle cellulaire, la sénescence et la différenciation. De manière intéressante, les études cliniques ont signalé que la transcription Ezh2 et les niveaux de protéines sont constamment plus élevés dans des carcinomes du sein humains agressifs que dans le tissu mammaire normal.La surexpression fréquente de l'Ezh2 dans le cancer du sein à faible pronostic pourrait indiquer que l'inhibition de gènes clés par H3K27me3 joue un rôle important dans la progression de la tumeur. Cependant, le spectre connu des gènes cibles PRC2 dans le cancer du sein est incomplet et peut varier considérablement entre les différents sous-types de cancer du sein.Ce travail de recherche s'est focalisé sur les modèles biologiques pertinents de différents sous-types de cancer de tumeurs mammaires afin d'explorer la nécessité de Ezh2 pour l'initiation, la maintenance et le stade métastatique des tumeurs. Nous avons identifié un mécanisme par lequel EZH2 effectue une répression de FOXC1 pour favoriser le développement des métastases dans les cancers de tumeurs mammaires de sous-type luminale B. Peut-être plus significatif encore, nous avons démontré qu'une intervention pharmacologique pour inhiber EZH2, dans un modèle préclinique murin immuno-compétent de sous-type luminale B de cancer mammaire, prévient complètement la formation des métastases. L'utilisation de modèles PDX (Patient-Derived Xenografts) semble être le modèle préclinique humain le plus pertinent pour illustrer l'impact considérable de l'inhibition de l'activité ADN méthyltransférase de Ezh2 sur les métastases spontanées dans les cancers du sein de sous-type luminale B mais pas dans les cancers de type HER2+. La portée de ces résultats suggère que les inhibiteurs de l'activité méthyltransférase de Ezh2 pourraient être utilisés en recherche clinique comme thérapie néoadjuvante afin de supprimer l'invasion et les métastases chez les patientes atteintes d'un cancer du sein de sous-type luminal B. Nous avons par la suite exploré le rôle de EZH2 dans les cancers du sein de sous-type HER2+ pour évaluer la synergie potentielle de l'inhibition de l'activité methyltransférase de EZH2 en présence d'une thérapie visant HER2 pour améliorer la réponse des patients. La perte de Ezh2 dans le modèle murin de tumeurs mammaires ErbB2 réduit de façon significative le temps de développement des tumeurs, la prolifération des lésions hyperplasiques ainsi que la pénétrance. L'effet anti-prolifératif de Ezh2 est reproduit par l'inhibition pharmacologique de son activité méthyltransférase.  Ce résultat nous amène à supposer que les modifications peuvent être effectuées dans l'épigénome de la tumeur créant une vulnérabilité dans la détection et la destruction accomplie par le système immunitaire. Finalement, nous avons identifié que la combinaison pharmacologique de l'inhibition de Ezh2 et d'un anticorps monoclonal de HER2 freine la tumorigenèse.</description><description>Over the last decade, several lines of evidence have demonstrated that the transformation of a normal epithelial cell to a malignant phenotype requires the accumulation of multiple events; growing evidence suggests that the acquisition of abnormal chromatin modifications may act in conjunction with genetic aberrations to facilitate dysregulation. Polycomb Group proteins (PcG) are a group of transcriptional repressors that silence genes by modifying chromatin through covalent modification of histones. Enhancer of zeste homology 2 (EZH2) is a PcG protein that, as a part of the multi-protein Polycomb Repressive Complex 2 (PRC2), mediates gene silencing via tri-methylation of lysine 27 on histone 3 (H3K27me3). Interestingly, clinical studies have reported that EZH2 transcript and protein levels are consistently elevated in aggressive human breast carcinomas when compared to normal breast tissue. Immunohistochemical analysis for a range of breast cancer subtypes revealed that high EZH2 levels were associated with shorter disease-free survival and higher probability of death due to breast cancer. The frequent over expression of EZH2 in poor-prognosis breast cancer may indicate that maintaining silencing of key genes through H3K27me3 is important in tumour progression, however, the known spectrum of PRC2 target genes in breast cancer is incomplete and may vary greatly between breast cancer subtypes. This work has focused on using biologically relevant models of different intrinsic subtypes of breast cancer to explore the necessity of Ezh2 in tumour initiation, maintenance and metastasis. In this work, we identify a mechanism through which EZH2 mediates repression of FOXC1 to promote metastasis in Luminal B breast cancer. Perhaps most significantly, we demonstrate that pharmacological intervention to inhibit EZH2 in an immune-competent preclinical mouse model of Luminal B breast cancer completely prevents the formation of distal metastases. We also utilized PDX models, arguably the most relevant existing human preclinical models, to illustrate the significant effect of EZH2 methyltransferase inhibition on spontaneous metastasis in Luminal B but not HER2+ breast cancer. These findings raise the possibility that EZH2 methyltransferase inhibitors may be used in a clinical setting as a neoadjuvant therapy to suppress invasion and metastasis in Luminal B breast cancer patients.This work also explores the role of Ezh2 in HER2+ breast cancer and the potential for combining Ezh2 methyltransferase inhibition with current HER2 targeted therapy to improve patient response. Loss of Ezh2 in an ErbB2-driven mouse model significantly delayed tumour onset, reduced proliferative capacity of hyperplastic lesions and decreased tumour penetrance from 100% to 20%. The anti-proliferative effects of Ezh2 were recapitulated with pharmacological inhibition of its methyltransferase activity. Interestingly, transcriptional profiling revealed a significant increase in a tumour intrinsic viral-defense signaling pathway, leading us to speculate that modifications can be made to the tumour epigenome that lead to increased vulnerability to detection and destruction by the immune system. Finally, we report that the combination of a pharmacological inhibitor of Ezh2 and HER2 monoclonal antibody synergizes to dampen tumorigenicity in immune competent hosts, increasing apoptosis and the tumour infiltration of cytotoxic immune cell populations.Taken together, our work demonstrates the context specific function of Ezh2, even within a single disease, and highlights the therapeutic potential of inhibiting PRC2 in breast cancer. </description><creator>Hirukawa, Alison</creator><contributor>William Joseph Muller (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Biochemistry</subject><title>Genetic and pharmacological exploration of the methyltransferase Ezh2 in different breast cancer subtypes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qp75p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s272h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752k36c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:55:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Caspase-6 is a cysteinyl aspartic-specific protease that is activated during pre-clinical stages of Alzheimer disease (AD) and correlates negatively with cognitive performance. We propose that Caspase-6 inhibition may combat the age-dependent cognitive decline in AD. Several Caspase-6 inhibitors have been developed, yet none have proven to be strong enough candidates to pursue clinical trials. To address this, two novel Caspase-6 inhibitors were studied.  Methylene blue is a Tau aggregation inhibitor that has been tested in phase III clinical trials against AD. Mass spectrometric analysis demonstrates that methylene blue oxidizes Caspase-6's catalytic cysteine, which represents a novel inhibitory post-translational modification. Moreover, methylene blue and its derivatives, azure A and azure B, inhibit Caspase-1, -3, or -6 activity in vitro, in human colorectal carcinoma cells, in human neurons, or in mice at non-toxic concentrations. Methylene blue's half-maximal inhibitory concentration (IC50) against Caspase-3 and -6 is comparable to concentrations required to achieve Tau aggregation inhibition. These results suggest that methylene blue has therapeutic neuroprotective and anti-inflammatory properties through Caspase-6 and -1 inhibition, respectively, while Caspase-3 inhibition could disrupt tissue homeostasis.  The therapeutic potential of small molecule vinyl sulfone Caspase-6 inhibitors developed by New World Laboratories' (NWL) is presented. NWL compounds have IC50 values in the sub-M range and inhibit Caspase-6 in vitro, in human colorectal carcinoma cells, and in human neurons at non-toxic concentrations. Moreover, Caspase-6 inhibition prevents axonal degeneration in human neurons transfected with amyloid precursor protein. In mice overexpressing human Caspase-6, mass spectrometry reveals that NWL-117 can penetrate the blood-brain barrier. Interestingly, NWL-117 treatment restores novel object recognition in Caspase-6 mice, although changes in synaptic proteins, glial inflammation markers, or Caspase6 substrates are not evident. These experiments suggest that Caspase-6-mediated damage is reversible strengthening the rationale for continued Caspase-6 inhibitor development.  The studies presented here demonstrate that 1) oxidation and 2) vinyl methyl sulfones can effectively inhibit Caspase-6 in biological settings. These results may help future Caspase6 inhibitor development to allow clinical assessment of the Caspase-6 hypothesis in AD. </description><description>La Caspase-6, une enzyme à cystéine coupant spécifiquement après une aspartate, est activée pendant les stades précoces de la maladie Alzheimer (MA), et corrèle négativement avec la performance cognitive. Nous proposons que la Caspase-6 est une cible thérapeutique intéressante pour combattre le déclin cognitif lié à l'âge dans la MA. Plusieurs inhibiteurs de la Caspase-6 ont été développés, mais, aucun de ces inhibiteurs n'est un bon candidat pour poursuivre des essais cliniques. Pour cette raison, deux nouveaux inhibiteurs de la Caspase-6 ont été étudiés.  Le bleu de méthylène est un inhibiteur de l'agrégation de la protéine Tau qui a été testé en troisième phase d'étude clinique contre la MA. L'analyse par spectrométrie de masse a démontré que le bleu de méthylène peut oxyder la cystéine catalytique de la Caspase-6 ce qui représente un nouveau mécanisme d'inhibition par modification post-traductionnel. De plus, le bleu de méthylène et ses dérivés, azure A et azure B, inhibent l'activité de la Caspase-1, -3, ou -6 in vitro, dans des cellules de carcinome colorectal humaines, dans des neurones primaires humains, ou dans des souris à des concentrations non-toxiques. La concentration du bleu de méthylène nécessaire pour inhiber à 50% (IC50) la Caspase-3 et -6 est comparable aux concentrations nécessaires pour inhiber l'agrégation de Tau. Ces résultats suggèrent que le bleu de méthylène est neuroprotecteur et anti-inflammatoire à cause de l'inhibition de la Caspase-6 et -1, respectivement. Tandis que l'inhibition de la Caspase-3 pourrait perturber l'homéostasie des tissus.      Le potentiel thérapeutique des petites molécules vinyles sulfoniques développé par New World Laboratories (NWL) comme inhibiteur de Caspase-6 est aussi présenté. Les composés de NWL ont des IC50 &lt; 1 M et inhibent la Caspase-6 in vitro, dans des cellules de carcinome colorectal humaines, dans des neurones primaires humains à des concentrations non-toxiques. L'inhibition de la Caspase-6 empêche la dégénérescence axonale dans des neurones humains transfectés avec la protéine précurseur de l'amyloide. Dans des souris qui surexpriment la Caspase-6, l'analyse par spectrométrie de masse dévoile la capacité de NWL-117 à traverser la barrière hématoencéphalique. Notamment, des traitements avec NWL-117 rétablis la mémoire épisodique (reconnaissance d'objets nouveaux) dans les souris Caspase-6, même si la présence de protéines synaptiques, marqueurs gliaux d'inflammation, ou de substrats de Caspase-6 n'avaient pas changé. Ces expériences suggèrent que les dommages liés à l'activité Caspase-6 peuvent être réversés ce qui renforce le rationnel derrière le développement des inhibiteurs.  Les études présentées démontrent que 1) l'oxydation et 2) les vinyles sulfones inhibent la Caspase-6 dans des contextes biologiques. Ces résultats pourraient aider le futur développement d'inhibiteurs de la Caspase-6 pour permettre d'évaluer cliniquement l'hypothèse de la Caspase-6 dans la MA.</description><creator>Pakavathkumar, Prateep</creator><contributor>Andrea LeBlanc (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Characterization of novel pharmacological Caspase-6 inhibitors provides insight on developing treatments against Alzheimer disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h430r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752k36c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):6075</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>