<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:25:45Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):9250" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860988d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The recent inauguration of conservation of wild life in North America has focussed the attention of zoologists on the breeding grounds of ducks and geese on this continent. In most instances these areas are situated in Canada and it is here that the problems concerning the health of these birds are important. It is fairly safe to say that the major infestations by internal parasites are contracted in the breeding grounds due to the tremendous numbers of birds congregated in a comparatively small area. This is undoubtedly the case when infestations are present in young birds. Although our knowledge of the trematode parasites of these birds has been considerably increased during late years, by many publications in the United States, there is still a lack of knowledge concerning the distribution of species. In order to make a contribution towards a further knowledge of the internal parasites encountered in these birds a study of the parasites collected in eastern Canada during the general survey work of the Institute of Parasitology was made. The species described in this paper were unidentified specimens present in the collection of the above mentioned Institute during the winter of 1937-38.</description><creator>Cannon, Douglas Gordon.</creator><contributor>Cameron, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1938</date><subject>Parasitology.</subject><title>Some trematode parasites of ducks and geese in eastern Canada.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qs82g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860988d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bf72b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Following the discovery, about 70 years ago, that wood could be pulped by heating in bisulphite solutions, the sulphite process has grown rapidly to an important world industry. During this development, commercial improvements were stressed, and until comparatively recent times, the theoretical issues involved were largely neglected. In this field, much has been accomplished, so that a sound basis is provided for the present work. In a difficult problem such as this, complicated by the heterogeneity of wood as well as by the uncertain chemical atructures and properties of many of its constituents, close co-operation between the organic and physical chemist is desirable, and should accelerate the solution of many problems confronting the sulphite technician. The present investigation is a study of two variable conditions - temperature, and liquor composition - which influence the delignification of spruce wood in sulphite solutions. It is, therefore, a study of the mechanism and kinetics of the chemical reactions involved in the sulphite process, approached from a physico-chemical viewpoint. [...]</description><creator>Cannon, John James Richard.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>A study of the mechanism of sulphite cooking.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rh45c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bf72b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x680j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The determination of the true percentage ot sugar in sugar products and syrups is of considerable importance in industry and in nutritional studies. The multiplicity of soluble sugars makes the problem a complicated one in any cases, and ncessitates the use of a large number of separate methods. In commercial sugar products sucrose is usually the chief constituent, and methods for its determination have been widely studied. The ordinary methods for sucrose determination are, polarimetric, densimetric, and refractometric. With the exception of the polarimetric method, these have been adapted, 'by calculation, from determinations of the total solids of the saccharine material, an appropriate correction being applied where necessary for the inorganic matter present. Each of the above methods possesses certain advantages, and it is frequently desirable to employ a second method to check the accuracy of the first one used. This can be done, however, only if it is known that by both methods comparable results can be obtained (45). Comparisons have been made of pairs of methods, and in some cases the results of analysis by three methods have been published, but there ia no record of comparisons of all the methods, using sugar solutions ot known composition as standards, with the addition of artificial ash in varying amounts to approximate natural products. [...]</description><creator>Knight, Enid Patricia.</creator><contributor>McFarlane, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>A study of the effects of impurities on the accuracy of various methods of sugar analysis.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g21r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x680j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623g520</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As recently as 1933 one of the leading educational psychologists on this continent, Dr. S. L. Pressey of Ohio state University, was able to deliver with impunity a stinging indictment of professional education [...]  The investigation of some aspects of this uncharted territory constitutes the purpose of the research project reported in this thesis, the initial work of which was undertaken in 1931, two years before the publication of Professor Pressey's book. [...]</description><creator>Norris, Kenneth Everette, 1903-</creator><contributor>Kellogg, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>PSYCHOLOGY, EDUCATIONAL</subject><subject>UNEMPLOYMENT</subject><subject>PSYCHOLOGY -- MENTAL TESTS.</subject><subject>MEMORY</subject><title>The permanence of school learning as indicated by a study of unemployed men.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qv80r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623g520</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kw81w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The zinc-lead deposits belonging to the Montauban mineralized zone are in the western part ot Montauban Township, Portneuf County, Quebec, near the village or Montauban-les-Mines. The Montauban mineralized zone may be traced from lot 322, Seignory of Price, across lots 39 to 45, inclusive, and into Block C of Montauban Township. The area is about 6 miles south of Montauban, formerly known as Notre Dame des Anges, which, by rail, is 52 miles from Quebec and 125 miles from Montreal. By road, Montauban-les-Mines is 78 miles from Quebec and 160 miles from Montreal. [...]</description><creator>Wilson, Norman Leslie.</creator><contributor>Osborne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>An investigation of the metamorphism of the Orijärvi type with special reference to the zinc-lead deposits at Monauban-les-Mines, P.Q.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sz97f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kw81w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hg15k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The importance to clinical medicine and surgery of the metabolism of the hormone of the adrenal cortex is becoming increasingly more evident from the recent work of many investigators. It has long been known that in the human, destructive lesions of the adrenal cortex are responsible for the fatal disease described by Addison in 1855 and which bears his name. In Addison's disease, the symptoms and signs are pigmentation of skin and mucous membrane, gastro-intestinal disturbances, asthenia, low blood pressure, dehydration and hamoconcentration (increased sodium excretion, low blood sodium), high blood potassium and hypoglycemia in the terminal stages. [...] Adrenal cortical extracts or synthetic cortical substances administered to patients with Addison's disease will restore them to health and prolong life. Adrenalectomized animals can be maintained in good health indefinitely on cortical substances. Hyperfunction of the adrenal cortex occurs in cases of adrenal cortical hyperplasia, adrenal cortical tumors, and in Cushing's Syndrome. The clinical features of Cushing's syndrome are hypertension, localized obesity, osteoporosis, hyperglycemia, polycythemia and skin changes. The clinical features of the adrenogenital syndrome are sex-reversal or precocious maturity. While the features mentioned are the main characteristics of the respective syndromes, there are cases which show manifestations of both types of condition. [...]</description><creator>Weil, Paul Gregory.</creator><contributor>Browne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Experimental Medicine. </subject><title>The metabolism of the hormone of the adrenal cortex.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q4511.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hg15k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hv571</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In view of a revival of interest in nuclear physics at McGill and in anticipation of the building of a cyclotron, a program of construction of auxiliary apparatus was started in 1936, in which the writer took part. Delays in the progress of the cyclotron scheme led to the suggestion that some project be undertaken using naturally radioactive sources. The appearance of the work of Bohr on the nature of nuclear reactions indicated that the scattering of alpha particles by the light nuclei might be expected to provide more immediate information concerning nuclear structure than had hitherto been supposed. These considerations led the writer to select the large angle scattering of alpha particles by light nuclei as a subject for experiment. [...] Using a scattering chamber filled with hydrogen at 10 cm. pressure, designed to permit the counting of alpha particles scattered through angles up to 158º, the number scattered into a given solid angle has been compared with the corresponding number from a gold target. Assuming that the latter obeyed Rutherford's law of scattering, the departures from this law in the case of the light elements could, thus, be found. [...] Clear evidence was found in carbon and oxygen for the existence of resonance levels in the compound nuclei formed and it was possible to draw from the data some conclusions regarding the angular momenta of these excited states. [...]</description><creator>Walker, Laurence Richard.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Physics. </subject><title>The scattering of alpha particles by carbon. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139502j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hv571</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dw24x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>By the year 1855 agriculturalists had accumulated sufficient evidence to uphold the contention that phosphorus was essential in order to support plant growth. Numerous attempts have been made since that time to fractionate the categories of phosphorus in soil, and the problem is a very important and live issue to-day. [...] The purpose of this investigation was to develop a method of fractionation which could be applied to soils and soil extracts, and which would establish the nature of some of the organic and inorganic phosphorus components present in soil. [...] It has been known for many years that the total phosphorus content of soils cannot be used as a true measure of the capacity of different soils to supply available phosphorus to plant roots. On the other hand so called availability methods do give a good indication of the fertility status of soils. This has been explained by the fact that the buffered acid extracting solutions presumably dissolve a definite group of phosphorus compounds. It is also well known that acid extracting solutions dissolve widely different amounts of phosphorus from different types of soils. There is thus good evidence that the soil phosphorus does not exist in a uniform condition. The fractionation of the various forms in which phosphorus does exist in soils, is therefore a problem of vital interest. [...]</description><creator>Smith, George Ransom.</creator><contributor>DeLong, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry. </subject><title>The fractionation of soil phosphorus. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k557h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dw24x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816q48g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The colouring matter is the name applied to a coloured material believed to be present in chemical wood pulps and regarded, by workers in the field, to be of considerable importance in the bleaching of these pulps. In the production of a good quality white pulp from wood, two main steps are involved, namely the "cooking" of the wood, and the bleaching of the raw pulp obtained. [...] Of the two main types of chemical pulps used commercially, namely, (a) acid or sulphite pulps, (prepared by heating under pressure with acid bisulphite solutions), and (b) alkaline pulps (prepared by heating under pressure with aqueous alkalies), the latter present by far the greater problem from the point of view of bleaching. Kraft pulps are especially difficult to bleach to a permanent white colour. The final colour is almost always slightly yellowish despite the fact that the "chlorine consumption" of these pulps is much larger than with sulphite and soda pulps. At this point it may be advisable to define the terms kraft and sulphate, since the careless use of these terms often leads to confusion. Sulphate pulp is produced by any alkaline  "cooking" process in which the alkali lost is replaced by the addition of sodium sulphate in the regeneration of the "spent-liquor". Kraft is a type of sulphate pulp which has been intentionally undercooked to obtain a pulp of high strength. [...]</description><creator>Schwartz, Harry.</creator><contributor>Hibbert, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>The colouring matter in kraft pulp. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b4150.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816q48g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xh81k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Up to the end of the last century, the only mode of functional co-ordination in the organism which was understood was that of reflex nervous mechanism. With the discovery however of specific hormones, the concept that there might be a humoral co-ordinating mechanism began to be entertained. [...] It is now generally accepted that the specific hormones are produced in especially developed glandular organs, the glands of internal secretion, and are transported by the blood stream to distant organs where they exert their effect. [...] In contra-distinction to these, there are substances not only produced in any one organ but which are formed in many tissues as well as tissue juices, which do not require any specific type or cell. These 'tissue-hormones' are found under physiological conditions in the body, and they are supposed to act at the site of production or liberation, thus differing markedly from the specific or hormones of internal secretion. [...] Of all the tissue hormones only three are of known chemical constitution. These are histamine, acetylcholine and adenylic acid and its derivatives. [...] This thesis is concerned mainly with the metabolism of histamine, and in particular with certain aspects of the mechanism of its detoxification in the animal organism. There now follows a general review of the subject, the detailed headings of which will be found in the index. [...]</description><creator>Rose, Bram.</creator><contributor>Browne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Experimental Medicine. </subject><title>The metabolism of histamine.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988n94w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh81k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wn302</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The tachinid genus, Gonia Meigen, has long been known to contain several distinct American species. Descriptions of at least nineteen of these have been published. Determinations have been based on many different characters, of which those of the male genitalia have been favoured recently. It is, however, admittedly difficult, if not almost impossible, to describe in words slight differences in the shape or contour of such structures. Yet in no case has one of these characters been illustrated. [...] To this end the present work was undertaken. An attempt has been made to clear up the taxonomy of the group, by illustrating the genital and other significant distinguishing characters. Where possible the work has been based on an examination of type material. A complete taxonomic bibliography of the genus and each species dealt with is included.[...] It was hoped that less easily exposed structures than those previously used might prove valuable in the taxonomic work. Although no characters of taxonomic value were found, it became evident from the literature on the morphology of the male genitalia of Calyptrate Diptera that, though extensively used for taxonomy, the morphology of these structures is as yet poorly understood. [...] The taxonomy of Diptera in general cannot but be furthered by a more complete understanding for, and more uniform terminology for, the parts of these much used structures. [...]</description><creator>Morrison, F. O.</creator><contributor>DuPorte, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Entomology. </subject><title>A revision of the American species of Gonia Meigen (Diptera: Tachinidae) together with a study of the male genetalia in calyptrate Diptera based on the same genus.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d721n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wn302</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h4639</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Numerous researches during the past hundred years have been carried out to determine the structure of the lignin materials found in nearly all plants. It is well known that these substances play an important role in plant life and plant products. During this period the development of processes for the isolation of cellulose from different trees and grasses has led to the simultaneous production of huge quantities of lignin substances, the world production running into many millions of pounds. The utilization in industry of this lignin component of the plant has heretofore met with only slight success. The reason for this lack of application must be attributed to lack of information concerning its chemical structure. Previous experimental work on lignin has led to a great variety of speculations concerning its composition as well as to numerous methods for extracting it from plant materials. The work presented in this thesis gives new information concerning the structure of lignin materials obtained from maple wood by ethanolysis. [...]</description><creator>Hunter, Melvin Jasper.</creator><contributor>Hibbert, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>The ethanolysis of maple wood. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r4089.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h4639</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50h013s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Concrete is the material made from the mixing of three materials: water, cement, and aggregates. The water and cement forms the paste which, on hardening through the chemical action between water and cement, binds the aggregates into a rock-like product. Thus concrete is an artificial conglomerate with the mortar as the matrix for the stone. [...]  As the concrete is the result of the intimate arrangement of water, cement, and aggregates into a rock-like mass, its properties should necessarily be influenced by its components. Just how does each constituent part affect the character of the combined product, and what relative proportions of each must enter into the mixture to insure certain qualities, are the questions which must be answered before the design of concrete can be elevated to a scientific plane. The factors which are now known definitely to exert a distinct influence on the strength, density, and permanence of concrete were also known to its earlier users. The importance of grading was recognized. The effect of the quantity and quality of the cement and water was noticed. Besides these, the curing conditions, methods of placing, and the physical characteristics of the aggregates were known to affect the quality of the resulting concrete. Yet for a long time the relationship between these various facts remained unformulated. [...] </description><creator>Hum, Thed Klung.</creator><contributor>Jamieson, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics. </subject><title>The effects of certain factors on the properties of Portland cement concrete.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977x94v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h013s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s788m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem of fine grinding is that problem connected with the reduction of a rock material to a size such that the valuable mineral it contains may be satisfactorily extracted. Fine grinding is perhaps the most significant process in any milling operation, and forms a commensurate percentage of the unit milling cost. There has been for many years a wide divergence of opinion as to what constitute best operating conditions in a grinding plant. This divergence of opinion was mainly due to a lack of suitable methods of measuring the true efficiency of fine grinding operations. The efficiency of a fine grinding or crushing operation is the ratio of the amount of useful crushing work done to the amount of work (power) applied to the crushing operation. Modern experimental technique has made it possible to measure both of these factors, and though this technique is not available to general practise, much more certain information is being obtained for use in general practise. [...] This study has led to a knowledge of the amount of work (power) absorbed in actual crushing and grinding. The measurement of the amount of useful crushing work done was a source of embarrassment to fine grinding investigators for many years. Two diametrically opposed methods were proposed, and as both were based on theoretical calculations, neither could be eliminated until practical data had been gathered and impartially interpreted. [...]</description><creator>Brissenden, William Guy.</creator><contributor>Bell, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1938</date><subject>Mining. </subject><title>A study of certain phases of fine grinding. : (Part of an extended investigation being carried out at McGill University). --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jr870.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s788m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pd553</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The terpenes constitute an important group amongst the naturally occurring organic compounds. They vary greatly in nature and character and a very large number of them are still of unknown constitution. An interesting number of these compounds have been termed terpene aliphatic alcohols. They are comparatively small in number and although non-cyclic in nature, they are closely related to cyclic compounds and prone to cyclize under certain conditions. [...] Their general structure and chemical properties have been fairly thoroughly investigated but the question of their isomeric structures has not yet been definitely settled. A brief historical review of the chemistry of the primary aliphatic terpene alcohols, namely, geraniol and citronellol, will be given. The attention attached to these compounds is largely due to their importance in the perfumery trade. Geraniol is a colourless liquid of sweet odour, recalling that of rose and pelargonium. It is found in the free state and also in the form of its esters in a large number of essential oils. Most of the work done on its occurrence was carried out in the last decade of the nineteenth century. It was found to be a constituent of palmarosa, Bulgarian and Turkish rose oils, geranium oils, citronella oils, lemongrass oil, linaloe oil, nutmeg oil, sassafras oil, petigrain oil, lavender oil and in smaller quantities in a large number of other oils. [...]</description><creator>Bedoukian, Paul Z.</creator><contributor>Phillips, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1938</date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>Hydrogenation of geraniol and related compounds. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg58j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pd553</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526g221</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study of organic chemical reactions has been intensified greatly in recent years. Thermodynamics and statistical mechanics have contributed generous results as to the possibility of chemical reaction and to the position of equilibrium attainable. Since, however, considerations of this type are concerned with probability states, and are static in their treatment, no knowledge is obtained of the interaction processes by which chemical change takes place. Chemical kinetics, on the other hand, involves characteristics of the reactive process and, allied with knowledge available from thermodynamics and statistical mechanics, forms an efficient method of attack. Progress in this field has made rapid advances in the last decade. It is not always easy, however, to interpret experimental data by the hypotheses which theories, in this branch of chemical study, propound. [...]</description><creator>Folkins, Hillis Otty.</creator><contributor>Steacie, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Free radicals in the decomposition of hydrocarbons.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j25t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526g221</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pk25k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the past twenty years the extension of knowledge relating to the ehem1stry of high molecular weight substances has become increasingly important. The pronounced industrial advances in the realm of plastics and artificial fibres within recent years has given impetus to the search for fundamental information concerning the mechanism of polymerisation and the structure and properties of polymers either as such or in the form of co- and mixed polymers. [...]</description><creator>Fordyce, Reid George.</creator><contributor>Hibbert, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The synthesis of polyoxyethylene glycols and the relation of their viscosities to chain length.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3335331.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pk25k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042w984</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le problème des transports en est un epi remonte loin dans 1'histoire de 1'humanité. Ce problème a grandi sans cesse jusqu'à 1'heure actuelle, et il est certain ql'il continuera à devenir plus urgent et plus compliqué à l'avenir, au fur et à mesure que les différents moyens de transport deviendront plus perfectionnés et plus variés. Notre civilisation et nos déve1oppements, qu'ils soient nationaux ou internationaux, ont suivi partout le développement des communications et des voies de transport. De nos jours, les transports ont atteint une importance et une puissance énormes dans toutes les phases de la vie humaine. [...]</description><creator>Fraser, David Robert.</creator><contributor>Hemmeon, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Railroads -- France.</subject><subject>Railroads -- Canada.</subject><title>L’evolution des chemins de fer français et le probleme canadien.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05ff85x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042w984</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515r43r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] In order to try and clarify the existing impressions, the present investigation was started with a twofold purpose: 1. To separate sulphite pulp into fractions according to their fibre length which could then be examined for resinous bodies, enabling a comparison of the quantity and nature of the resinous constituent to be drawn. 2. To try, by any means which might suggest themselves, to note the effect of these groups of resinous materials on the properties of viscose solution in order to derive a relation between the nature of the resin and its influence on the suitability of viscose for coagulation in an acid bath.</description><creator>Giddings, Ernest William Garner.</creator><contributor>Phillips, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The analysis of classified fractions in certain pulps.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903287z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515r43r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z386q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Location of the Property.- The Fontana Gold Mines property has an area of one thousand acres, embracing the north half-lots of range V and the south half-lots of range VI, lots 12 to 21 inclusive, Duverny township, Quebec. The southwest corner of the township is six miles due east of the town of Amos, on the north line of the Canadian National Railway. It may be reached by a motor road that runs north from the town of Amos for about ten miles to the colonist settlement of St. Maurice de Dalquier, and thence two and a half miles east. A winter landing field for planes has been cleared on the Central Duverny property to the northeast. Purpose of the thesis.- The object of the thesis is to describe the geology of the Fontana property, with special reference to the occurrence and origin of the gold deposits of the district. The information on which the thesis is based, was collected during the writer's employment as geologist by the Fontana Gold Mlnes Ltd., extending over a period of one year. During the winter, 1938-1939, laboratory studies were carried out at McGill University. [...]</description><creator>Hart, Edward Arthur.</creator><contributor>Gill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>The geology of the Fontana gold mines property Duverny township, Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05ff866.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z386q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483n142</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Social work is a new profession and into its function there enter many people who are not professional social workers. Members of the older professions - medical, clerical, legal, teaching - and business men, their wives, their mothers, their daughters and sisters, meet with professional workers around conference tables, budget and are responsible for income, and give special services to particular social agencies. The term volunteer is older than the term social worker, and there is difference of opinion as to its scope. In some cities those people who serve on boards of management, restrict that designation to the younger people who have definite duties in the weekly routine of social agencies. Elsewhere it applies to both types of service. In this study it is used in the wider significance to include all those who serve one or more social agencies in any capacity, without financial remuneration. [...]</description><creator>Kerry, Esther Wilson.</creator><contributor>Hughes, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Social service.</subject><title>The role and function of the volunteer in social work.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591c239.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n142</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g307d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Any material used in combination with nicotine to produce a more effective kill than would be otherwise obtained by using nicotine alone, may be termed an adjuvant of the nicotine. The adjuvant may or may not have toxic qualities in itself, depending on such factors as the species of insect concerned and the meteorological conditions at the time of application. The effect which an adjuvant has upon nicotine may be due to either physical or chemical factors but more probably to a combination of both. Physically, the adjuvant may bring about more effective spreading and sticking, with greater ability to withstand cranging climatic conditions. The adjuvant may also produce a smothering effect. Chemically, as an "activator" , it may hasten the evolution of free nicotine by the reaction of the basic and acidic radicals of the soap and nicotine sulphate. An adjuvant may also act chemically by producing an affinity between itself and the surface of the solid, through chemical combination with contaminants on the surface or by dissolving protective coatings, such as wax. [...]</description><creator>Maxwell, Charles Wilmot Brown.</creator><contributor>DuPorte, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>Studies on the toxicity of nicotine in combination with various adjuvants.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g239.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g307d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128f02h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The experimental work which comprises the subject matter of this- thesis was carried out in the Metallurgicel and Ore Dressing Laboratories at McGill University. A flotation concentrate from the Beattie Mine, received at the University in the fall of 1936 was used. At the time the treatment of the ore at this property consisted of direct cyanidation followed by flotation, the flotation concentrate being shipped by rail and water to the Tacoma Smelter of the American Refining and Smelting Co. Ltd. Since the investigation concerns itself with the extraction of gold from arsenical ores by the cyanide process, a short history of the development of the cyanide process is included, as well as a summary of previous work treating arsenic ores. A review of the modern concept of the mechanism of gold solution is also included.</description><creator>Moss, Bernard Beryl.</creator><contributor>MacEwan, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Mining and Metallurgy.</subject><title>Recovery of gold from arsenical gold ores.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289n007.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128f02h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j197c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The photosynthesis of carbohydrates by the chloroplasts of green plants is an important process, and one that has received considerable study. Most of these studies have been concerned with the effect of external factors, such as light, temperature, and carbon dioxide concentration on the rate of photosynthesis by the plant. These studies have yielded valuable information, but the actual mechanism of photosynthesis is yet unknown; a new line of attack is necessary before the chemioal changes involved in the photosynthesis of carbohydrates by the whole plant can be elucidated because these changes are complicated by other processes, such as respiration, which are going on at the same time; furthermore, there are many substances present which do not play a direct part in the process. [...]</description><creator>Neish, A. C. (Arthur Charles)</creator><contributor>McFarlane, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the isolation of chloroplasts and their composition.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hv589.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j197c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nt884</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chiasma studies in Trillium were made, (a) so that more might be learned of the nature and behavior of chiasmata, and possibly of their origin, and (b) because it seemed probable that at least most chiasmata represented genetic cross-overs, and it was hoped that such a study would yield evidence on crossing-over which either could not be obtained from genetic studies or which might be of interest when compared with the results of such studies. [...]</description><creator>Newcombe, Howard B.</creator><contributor>Huskins, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Genetics.</subject><title>Chromosome studies in the Liliaceae. I. Chromatid and chiasma interference in Trillium erectum L.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fc26k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nt884</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):9275</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>