<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:05:13Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):44825" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vk85n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Photo-adducts of aldehydes and furan were transformed to substituted monocyclic oxetanes, using a modification of the Fraser-Reid-Mootoo glycosidation procedure, and the chemistry of these oxetanes was studied. The photo-adduct of 2-methylfuran and propionyloxyacetaldehyde was transformed in a one-pot reaction to oxetane 75a, which gave oxetanocin and its epimer as described. The coupling of various oxetanes of the type 75 to nitrogenous bases was also investigated. During the course of this work, it was found that epoxides of the type 23 could be transformed into bicyclic nucleosides 91 and furanosides 93. Bicyclic nucleosides 99 were also prepared, again using a modified Fraser-Reid-Mootoo coupling procedure. An investigation into the resolution of photo-adducts of aldehydes and furans was initiated.</description><creator>Hambalek, Robert J. (Robert Josef)</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Synthesis of (plus or minus)-oxetanocin and related compounds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb4949302.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vk85n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mn04r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The possibility for different kinds of adopters, along Rogers' (1962) categorization, to display different preference patterns regarding a product's features, is investigated. The moderating role of diffusion-related variables, namely a product's newness and the extent of interpersonal communication, is assessed. It is hypothesized that a respondent's evaluation of product descriptions can be influenced by the diffusion context which characterizes them. An attempt is made to show that such a context can be used to elicit different "best product" alternatives for different stages of the adoption curve and, prior to market introduction, can help predict time-dependent changes to be made to the product's features as adoption takes place.</description><creator>Cestre, Ghislaine</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Consumers -- Attitudes.</subject><subject>Consumer goods.</subject><title>Assessing consumer preferences in the context of new product diffusion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qj51j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mn04r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612p429</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study addresses the problems associated with each step of the process of retrieving radiation budgets at the top of atmosphere (TOA) and at the surface from satellite measurements in the Arctic. The data used are from the Earth Radiation Budget Experiment (ERBE) radiometer and Advanced Very High Resolution Radiometer (AVHRR), together with radiative transfer calculations. The limitations of the ERBE scene identification algorithm when applied to observations in the Arctic are investigated by comparing the scenes identified by ERBE with simultaneous and colocated AVHRR-based scenes. Considerable discrepancies are found, especially the misidentification by the ERBE scene identification method of clear fractional ice as being partly cloudy skies over open water. More accurate TOA fluxes and cloud forcing in the Arctic are derived by taking advantage of the broadband radiance measurements made by the ERBE radiometer and the more reliable scene identification deduced from narrowband multispectral measurements made by the AVHRR. Comparisons of the cloud forcing determined from the two scene identification methods show differences as large as 50 W m$ sp{-2}$ in some regions of the Arctic. The validity of the ERBE angular dependence models (ADMs) is also evaluated in the Arctic. It is found that the ADM for clear ice/snow is not reliable when applied in the Arctic during summer. The ADM for overcast skies contains systematic errors when applied to overcast conditions over ice/snow surfaces. The systematic error is removed by modifying the ADM. To estimate the surface absorbed flux from reflected flux at the TOA, a simple parameterized model is developed based on comprehensive radiative simulations. The model is independent of cloud optical thickness, surface type, and has only a moderate dependence on the presence or absence of cloud, cloud type and water vapour, but a strong dependence on solar zenith angle (SZA). Surface absorbed fluxes determined by radiative transfer calculations may generally be estimated to within 10 W m$ sp{-2}$ by the simple model from TOA reflected fluxes with knowledge of the SZA and precipitable water. Finally, narrowband-to-broadband reflectance conversion is carried out with careful attention paid to a particular statistical problem, namely, regression analysis with spatially autocorrelated satellite measurements. Both scene-dependent and scene-independent regressional models are developed to estimate broadband reflectance from the narrowband reflectances in channels 1 and 2 of AVHRR. The RMS errors in the percentage reflectances from the scene-dependent models are 1.0, 1.8, 2.0 and 3.1 for the ocean, land, ice/snow and cloud, respectively. Except for land, the scene-independent model does virtually as good a job as the scene-dependent models.</description><creator>Li, Zhanqing</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><subject>Geophysics.</subject><title>Retrieval of radiation budgets in the Arctic from satellite measurements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nv38m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612p429</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vk86x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The addition of Nb significantly retards recovery and recrystallization through solute drag and precipitation pinning effects. It is important to describe the precipitation behaviour precisely because finely distributed precipitates retard the restoration process abruptly. The isothermal precipitation behaviour has been studied frequently. However, during industrial hot deformation processing, the temperature decreases continuously, so that isothermal data cannot be applied directly to predict the precipitation under these conditions. The focus of this study is therefore on the CCP (Continuous-Cooling-Precipitation) behaviour of Nb carbonitride in austenite. To calculate the CCP behaviour, isothermal PTT (Precipitation-Time-Temperature) data in terms of the P$ sb{ rm s}$ (precipitation start) and P$ sb{ rm f}$ (precipitation finish) times are first required. In 1987, Dutta and Sellars developed a thermodynamic model to predict P$ sb{ rm s}$ times for the precipitation of niobium carbonitride, and in 1989, Liu and Jonas developed a model for titanium carbonitride. In the present work, the L-J (Liu-Jonas) model is used to calculate the P$ sb{ rm s}$ time at a given temperature from experimental data. Since the prediction models are only limited to the P$ sb{ rm s}$ times, a new calculation method for the P$ sb{ rm f}$ time, based on reaction kinetics and classical nucleation and growth theory, is proposed in this study. Two models are developed to follow the precipitation process, and the time exponent and rate constant for the kinetics are formulated for each model. The additivity rule, which was developed by Scheil in 1935, is then used to calculate the extent of precipitation during continuous cooling. Isothermal precipitation rates for 0.040% Nb steels are measured experimentally by the stress relaxation method. The CCP behaviour is then calculated and is then examined by continuous cooling testing, using a hot deformation dilatometer. Precipitates are observed by transmission electron microscopy of specimens quenched after a period of cooling at various cooling rates. The P$ sb{ rm s}$ and P$ sb{ rm f}$ times estimated from the particle size data show good agreement with the calculated CCP behaviour.</description><creator>Park, Sung-Ho, 1957-</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Modelling and measurement of the continuous-cooling-precipitation kinetics of Nb(CN) in HSLA steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zv183.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vk86x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558f10x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A field experiment was conducted on a homogeneous sandy soil and a layered soil of southern Quebec from 1988 to 1990. This was done in order to evaluate the yield response of indeterminate soybean to subsurface irrigation and to determine the performance of subsurface irrigation in a layered soil. It was found that indeterminate soybean varieties increase their yield by approximately 30% for two out of three years. Soybean are very sensitive to competition between themselves as well as with weeds. This sensitivity is increased during subsurface irrigation. Weeds were more prominent in the irrigated area. It was concluded that the soybean yields are functions of water table depth, percent weed and plant population density. The minimum allowable water table depth for soybean was found to be 45 cm. At a water table depth greater than 95 cm no yield response was observed. Water table management is not only possible but very functional in the layered soils of southern Quebec. It was found that surplus water did not drain from the irrigated area until the water table anywhere in this area was 10 cm higher than the elevation of the overflow pipe in the control chamber. It was therefore concluded that a water table depth range of 10 cm should be included in the design of the water table control system to allow for the effects of rain.</description><creator>Galganov, Yvonne T. (Yvonne Tamara)</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Soybean -- Irrigation -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Subirrigation -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Subsurface irrigation of soybean</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz56j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558f10x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763765f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>By the methods of gel electrophoresis, protein blotting, and lectin staining, we compared the cell membrane glycoproteins of the human erythroleukemia cell line K562 with those of a NK-resistant subclone (Clone I), and a Con A-resistant subclone of Clone I called "Con A-R1". Although parental K562 and Clone I cells gave identical patterns, Con A-R1 contained two major populations of fucosylated proteins. Immunological analysis by flow cytometry and histochemical staining with lectins demonstrated that in Con A-R1 the H blood group epitope appeared concurrently with the disappearance of the $ alpha$1-3 fucosyllactosamine (Le$ sp{ rm X}$) epitope. Incubation of cells in the presence of the $ alpha$1-2 fucosylation inhibitor 2-deoxygalactose resulted in a reversible loss of detectability of the H antigen. Quantitation of fucosyltransferases revealed that in Con A-R1 the total fucosyltransferase activity was increased more than 10-fold, but the $ alpha$1-3 activity was decreased 30%. These findings demonstrate a novel type of oligosaccharide modification that can occur in a cell's adaptation to the toxic effects of the lectin Concanavalin A.</description><creator>Bernier, Louise G.</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Changes in cell surface glycoproteins associated with resistance to concanavalin A in a human erythroleukemia cell line (K562)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720d56x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763765f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698832r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mechanisms regulating spinal sympathetic output to the heart and vessels have been examined using the technique of intrathecal administration of neuroactive agents at T2 and/or T9 in the rat. Antagonists and/or agonists of glycine, GABA$ sb{ rm A},$ GABA$ sb{ rm B}$ and excitatory amino acid receptors have been studied to determine how the respective amino acids mechanisms function at the spinal level to regulate sympathetic output. The results indicated that glycine, GABA$ sb{ rm A},$ GABA$ sb{ rm B},$ novel GABA, D-baclofen-sensitive, NMDA and non-NMDA receptors are involved in regulation of sympathetic output at the spinal level. Glycine, GABA$ sb{ rm A},$ GABA$ sb{ rm B},$ NMDA and non-NMDA receptors also participate in regulation of arterial pressure and heart rate under basal conditions. As D-baclofen increases only arterial pressure, it is proposed that there is a differential distribution of some receptors on the sympathetic neurons innervating different end organs. In addition, as the antagonists strychnine and APV alter either heart rate or arterial pressure, it is proposed that different receptors differ in their degree of tonic activation.</description><creator>Hong, Yanguo</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Amino acid receptors in control of sympathetic output at the spinal level - mechanisms regulating arterial pressure and heart rate</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vp337.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698832r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qq34d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In turbulent and other nonlinear geophysical processes, extreme variability is built up multiplicatively from large to small scales via cascade mechanisms generally leading to (canonical) universal multifractal fields. This thesis clarifies the distinction between "bare" and "dressed" cascade processes, the classification of multifractal singularities and the related nontrivial problem of sampling and estimation of their scale properties. It then describes the first data analysis techniques applicable to these highly variable multifractals: previously existing techniques are limited to much calmer geometric or microcanonical multifractals. The two techniques developed here (Probability Distribution Multiple Scaling and Double Trace Moment) are analyzed theoretically and numerically and are tested on turbulent and topographic data, providing the first estimates of their universal multifractal parameters, the Levy index $ alpha$ which characterizes the degree of multifractality, and C$ sb1$ (the codimension of the mean singularity) which characterizes the mean inhomogeneity of the process.</description><creator>Lavallée, Daniel</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Geophysics.</subject><title>Multifractal analysis and simulation techniques and turbulent fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236284n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qq34d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nm27g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An analysis of the nature of reflexivity--a relation which relates a thing to itself although it is regularly used to relate two different things--is followed by specific discussions of its place and functions in the writings of various philosophers. These discussions substantiate the following theses: reflexivity is a basic structure common to different phenomena; although traditionally unacknowledged, it is a useful and important concept in philosophy as well as in other disciplines; acknowledging its existence and understanding its structure deepens our understanding of philosophical systems; since, like any other philosophical tool, reflexivity can be used either legitimately or illegitimately, nothing in it is inherently flawed; a structural analysis of different types of reflexivity and the relations between them can be presented; the history of its use is marked by a tendency towards its "normalization". These discussions are intended to raise awareness and generate future studies of this important but neglected philosophical structure.</description><creator>Landau, Iddo</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Ontology -- History</subject><subject>Relation (Philosophy)</subject><title>The role of reflexivity in philosophical systems /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nx86c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nm27g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945r61c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We study the dynamics of an interface driven far from equilibrium in three dimensions. We first derive the equations of motion which describe this physics. Numerical results are then obtained for three models which simulate the growth of an interface: the Kardar-Parisi-Zhang equation, a discrete version of that model, and a solid-on-solid model with asymmetric rates of evaporation and condensation. We show that the three models belong to the same dynamical universality class by estimating the dynamical scaling exponents and the scaling functions. We confirm the results by a careful study of the crossover effects. In particular, we propose a crossover scaling ansatz and verify it numerically. Furthermore, the discrete models exhibit a kinetic roughening transition. We study this phenomenon by monitoring the surface step energy which shows a drastic jump at a finite temperature for a given driving force. At the same temperature, a finite size scaling analysis on the bond energy fluctuation shows a diverging peak.</description><creator>Grossman, Bruno</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Kinetic roughening of interfaces in driven systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jv47t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945r61c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526d181</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A method of inclusion measurement in molten metals, known as the Liquid Metal Cleanness Analysis or LiMCA, currently in use for aluminum, has been developed for high temperature and reactive industrial metals. LiMCA probe consists of an electrically insulating sampling tube with two electrodes, in- and outside the tube. The sampling tube also incorporates a small orifice through which molten metal is aspirated. As suspended inclusions pass through the orifice, and in the presence of an electric current, voltage pulses are generated. By measuring and counting such pulses electronically, the size distribution of inclusions can be obtained. The orifice, therefore, serves as an Electric Sensing Zone (ESZ) for the probe. This work presents an analysis of LiMCA's electric circuitry, and the design and operation of LiMCA probes in steels, copper and magnesium alloys.</description><creator>Kuyucak, Selçuk</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>On the direct measurement of inclusions in molten metals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161700f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526d181</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hd00j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ability of tumor necrosis factor (TNF) and lipopolysaccharide (LPS) to stimulate gene expression in bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMM) was first compared. It is demonstrated that they stimulated gene expression through distinct signal transduction pathways and that TNF stimulated gene expression through a protein kinase C (PKC)-dependent signal transduction pathway. The effect of the intracellular parasite of macrophages Leishmania donovani in BMM was then investigated. It is demonstrated that L. donovani impaired c-fos and TNF gene expression through two distinct mechanisms. The first one is indomethacin-reversible, and the second one involves the inhibition of diacylglycerol-induced PKC-dependent gene expression. A purified cell surface glycoconjugate of the parasite, termed lipophosphoglycan, selectively inhibited PKC-dependent gene expression in BMM. While the translocation of PKC from the cytosol to the membrane was normal, total cellular PKC enzyme activity was inhibited in the U937 human monocyte cell line pretreated with lipophosphoglycan.</description><creator>Descoteaux, Albert</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Leishmania.</subject><subject>Cellular signal transduction.</subject><subject>Leishmaniasis.</subject><subject>Macrophages</subject><title>Study on the effect of Leishmania donovani infection on signal transduction in macrophages</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fm33b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hd00j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623d46f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>NAD-Dependent methylenetetrahydrofolate dehydrogenase-methenyltetrahydrofolate cyclohydrolase is a mitochondrial folate-dependent enzyme apparently expressed only in transformed mammalian cells and tissues containing undifferentiated cells. The cloning of both the cDNA and the gene encoding this bifunctional enzyme have led to a better understanding of the regulation of its expression in normal and transformed cells. Southern blot analyses revealed that the gene has a similar organization in normal and transformed cells and no major rearrangement or amplification were detected. The gene encodes two messenger RNAs which differ only by the length of their 3$ sp prime$-untranslated region and are derived by the use of alternative polyadenylation signals. The detection of transcripts in transformed cells and not in normal adult tissues suggests that the gene is primarily regulated at the transcriptional level. The promoter region of the gene contains several putative cis-regulatory elements which may have an important role in the differential expression of this folate-dependent enzyme.</description><creator>Bélanger, Carole</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Folic acid</subject><title>Isolation of the cDNA and the gene encoding a folate-dependent enzyme</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430557v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623d46f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655h50j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Fan, Der-Fong</creator><date>1967</date><subject>Indoleacetic acid.</subject><subject>Cellulase.</subject><title>Studies on regulation of cellulose activity and growth in higher plants with special reference to effects of indoleacetic acid</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515p198.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655h50j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Botany</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831ck81n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Henry, Vann Courtenay Ryce.</creator><date>1967</date><subject>Agriculture, General.</subject><title>Studies on botanical and agronomic characteristics in cush-cush (Dioscorea trifida L.f.).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fc45j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831ck81n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agronomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b5919245</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Emond, Gilles.</creator><date>1968</date><subject>Plants -- Effect of chemicals on.</subject><title>L'absorption et la distribution du linuron dans le haricot et son action sur la photosynthese et la respiration.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c56s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b5919245</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c837w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Kung, Fei-Lin</creator><date>1967</date><subject>Nitrous acid.</subject><subject>Ethics</subject><subject>Trimethoxybenzene</subject><subject>Chemical reactions.</subject><title>The reaction of 1, 2, 3- trimethoxybenzene and related compounds with nitrous acid.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zf35n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c837w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kn98f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Donald, Merlin , 1939-</creator><date>1968</date><subject>Cerebral cortex.</subject><title>Electrocortical correlates of fixed-foreperiod decision tasks.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bx986.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kn98f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z165j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Goldwater, Sydney Geoffrey.</creator><date>1968</date><subject>Immunoglobulins.</subject><title>Albumin-dye and antibody-hapten interactions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vp34h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z165j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720d59r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Jue, Bruce Cameron.</creator><date>1967</date><subject>Oxidation</subject><subject>Magnetite</subject><title>Oxidation of magnetite.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2362866.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720d59r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb3979135</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fluoride concentrations in the Montreal Urban Community's untreated wastewater were analyzed in an attempt to evaluate their levels and seasonal variations. Continual hourly monitoring of the raw sewage, between June 1992 and May 1993. yielded average monthly fluoride concentrations between 0.072 mg/L and 1.984 mg/L, with an annual mean of 0.45 mg/L. Daily variations and frequency distributions showed a wider range of fluoride levels, with the maximum values possibly reaching as high as 4-fold the mean and well over 2 orders of magnitude higher than the minimum values. This suggests that significant massive point discharges occur in the sewer network. Daily monitoring of the precipitation showed that the mean fluoride concentration in liquid precipitation generally fluctuates between 0.030 mg/L and 0.741 mg/L, whereas the average fluoride specific mass in dry precipitation ranges between 0.096 kg/km$ sp2$ and 2.775 kg/km$ sp2$. Seasonal trends have been depicted for fluoride levels in both the raw wastewater and the precipitation. Groundwater sampling yielded an average fluoride concentration of 0.13 mg/L, and analysis of the melting salts used by the City revealed that these do not contain any fluoride. Data from the City's water treatment plants showed that the average fluoride concentration in their raw water is 0.20 mg/L. This is in contrast to the value of 0.13 mg/L used in the literature. Mass balance analyses have shown that the mass of fluoride resulting from infiltration and non-fluoridated waters, as well as that due to the domestic habits of the population constitute, among the identified sources, the major input of fluoride mass into the wastewater. Nevertheless, unidentified sources of fluoride, consisting essentially of industrial discharges, still account for the largest portion (${ approx50 %}$ of the total) and contribute, as an annual average, 375 kg/day.</description><creator>Choueiri, Najla F.</creator><contributor>Gehr, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal.</subject><title>Fluoride concentrations in the Montreal urban community wastewater : seasonal variations and mass balances</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gk67k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb3979135</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903083f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The service life of any concrete marine structure is influenced by the physical condition of both the above water and below water portions of structure. This requires implementing an adequate inspection, maintenance, and repair program for the entire structure. To develop an effective maintenance and repair program for the submerged portion of the structure, the causes and extent of concrete distress or deterioration must be clearly understood. This requires a selective underwater condition survey, using a range of in-situ and laboratory testing and inspection techniques, to obtain the necessary information to assess the condition of the submerged portion of the structure. The cause and extent of deterioration, site logistics, and the clients needs will dictate the methods of inspection and repair. Recent developments in concrete admixtures has made it possible to place higher quality concrete suitable for underwater repairs. This thesis provides a summary of the most common forms of concrete distress found in a marine environment, along with a state-of-the-art review of existing and recently developed underwater inspection and repair techniques. In addition, four case studies are presented to illustrate the application of the above knowledge. The first case study describes the special aspects of underwater repairs to a concrete storm surge barrier damaged during construction. The second case study summarizes the procedures used for repairing a cracked concrete gravity dam by polyurethane resin injection methods. The third case study presents the various procedures used for repairing concrete railway bridge piers in a marine environment which were damaged by severe alkali-aggregate reaction. The final case study describes underwater repair procedures and concrete investigation techniques used in repairing the piers of a highway bridge.</description><creator>D'Argenzio, Domenic</creator><contributor>Mirza, M. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Inspection and repair of underwater concrete structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rv27t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903083f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x215z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A quantitative texture analysis has been done on silicon steel specimens having different precipitate distribution in order to understand the texture development and the role of precipitates during secondary recrystallization. To improve the size and distribution of precipitates, several annealing treatments were done on specimens obtained at different stages in the production of silicon steel. Tests for magnetic properties such as core loss and permeability, were done on final product specimens which had different precipitate distribution before secondary recrystallization. It is proposed that good precipitate distribution in the sheet before secondary recrystallization leads to a higher quality final product. Grain size distribution and orientation distribution function (ODF) were obtained for the primary recrystallized specimens and for the annealed specimens, just before and just after, secondary recrystallization. From the ODF data, the probability of coincidence site lattice (CSL) boundaries were calculated up to $ Sigma$27b. The probability of CSL boundaries in specimens having good precipitate distribution was different from the probability observed in specimens having poor precipitate distribution. An etch-pit method was used to give a more detailed, quantitative analysis of the texture development. An image analyzer was used to digitize the etch pit shapes, as well as the shape of grains. A computer program was developed to calculate the grain size of different texture components, the frequency of CSL boundaries between all grains, and the frequency of CSL boundaries between Goss grains and neighbouring grains. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Lee, Kitae, 1966-</creator><contributor>Szpunar, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Quantitative analysis of texture development in Fe-3%Si during secondary recrystallization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225b87f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x215z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602155x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A survey of earthquake disaster mitigation strategies and building principles which could applied in rural areas of the Less Developed Countries. Earthquake vulnerability of traditional buildings and problems of earthquake hazard mitigation in these countries are discussed, along with some strategies that may help reduce the impact of future earthquakes. The performance of rural buildings during past earthquakes is analyzed to have a clear understanding of building behaviour during an earthquake. After the analysis, the research traces various recommendations and safe building techniques that would improve the earthquake-resistance of these buildings. Moreover, the study reviews problems often involved in implementing mitigation measures and in transferring technical information to semi-illiterate and unskilled workers, in conjunction with some methodologies on how to transfer information to the rural population. The study concludes by outlining the urgency for the need of pre-earthquake mitigation strategies and suggests some ideas to help narrow the gap which exists between the available information on earthquake mitigation measures and its application in those countries most affected by earthquakes.</description><creator>Weldelibanos, Fitsumberhan</creator><contributor>Bhatt, Vikram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Dwellings -- Developing countries -- Design and construction.</subject><subject>Earthquake resistant design -- Developing countries</subject><subject>Building -- Developing countries -- Earthquake effects</subject><title>A survey of earthquake mitigation strategies &amp; building principles for small traditional dwellings /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558f13r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602155x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720d61s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:32:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ability to fully activate the motor units of the quadriceps femoris muscle when performing an isometric maximal voluntary contraction (MVC) was assessed in 30 subjects. The twitch interpolation technique (TIT) was used to measure the increase in force superimposed on the MVC by a supramaximal shock to the femoral nerve. The superimposed force was compared to the potentiated twitch (PtP) force, and an activation ratio (A.R.) was calculated. The resting twitch (PtR) force, MVC force, and the inverse relationship between the level of voluntary force and the superimposed twitch force were also measured. Subjects were compared on the basis of activity level (15 sedentary and 15 trained) and gender (14 males and 16 females). The mean A.R. was 95% regardless of activity level or gender. Males were stronger than females but there was no difference in strength between the sedentary and trained groups. PtR and PtP force values showed the same pattern of results. The nature of the relationship between the level of voluntary force and the superimposed twitch force was curvilinear, and indicates that the TIT may not be accurate in measuring the amount of activation for a muscle as large as the quadriceps when voluntary contractions greater than 70% of the MVC are performed. The intra-subject reliability of the TIT used in this lab was acceptable (ICC = 0.78).</description><creator>Perez, Diana</creator><contributor>St. Pierre, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Can humans fully activate the motor units of the quadriceps femoris muscle when performing a maximal voluntary contraction?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494933w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720d61s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):44850</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>