<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:29:52Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10425" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v1538</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Breakdown of the blood brain barrier in acute hepatic encephalopathy is controversial and relatively new in concept. This study attempts to assess alterations of the blood brain barrier in stage IV acute hepatic coma. A two-stage bloodless keratectomy was performed in rats with electroencephalographic recordings for assessment of the level of coma. Electron microscopy was used to study the brains of normal and hepatectomized rats in stage IV coma. Peroxidase, microperoxidase, Trypan and Evans blue dye were injected to delineate changes in permeability of the blood brain barrier in stage IV acute hepatic coma. The major ultrastructural change observed was marked swelling of astrocytes, particularly in the perivascular area. Grossly, the dye injections clearly demonstrated disruption of the blood brain barrier to the dye. Ultrastructurally, the site of the leak was not defined since horseradish peroxidase and microperoxidase did not leave the cerebral circulation and enter the brain substance.</description><description>Le compartement de la barrière cérébro-mèningée dans le coma hépatique est encore un sujet de controverse et relativement nouveau. Cette étude essaiera d'évaluer les altérations de la barrière cérébroméningée au stage IV du coma hépatique. Une technique d'hépatectomie en 'deux étapes fut reproduite chez le rat avec électroencephalographie simultanée pour évaluer le niveau du coma. L'étude de la-microscopie électronique fut utilisée chez le rat normal et chez le rat hépatectomisé au stage IV. La Maccoperoxidase, la Microperoxidase, le bleu de Trypan et le bleu d'Evans furent injectés au stage IV du coma hépatique pour déterminer les changements de perméabilité au niveau de la barrière cérébro-méningée. […]</description><creator>Potvin, Martin.</creator><contributor>Hinchey, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Morphological changes in the blood brain barrier in hepatic coma.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752k948.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v1538</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311s46f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On a étudié le développement de la tolérance à l'ozone chez de jeunes sujets en bonne santé, en se servant de paramètres de fonction pulmonaire dynamique comme critères d'évaluation. Onze sujets furent exposés deux fois à 0.6 ppm d'ozone à trois jours d'intérvalle; les diminutions moyennes de valeur des paramètres de fonction pulmonaire enregistrées lors de la seconde exposition furent plus petites que celles mesurées lors de la première exposition (p&lt;0.05. excepté pour la capacite vitale forcée). On a démontré par des expériences complémentaires qu'une concentration de 0.4 ppm d'ozone (pendant 2 heures) est nécessaire à l'induction du développement d'une telle tolérance. Ce phénomène qu'on a pu observer jusqu'à 4 jours après le pré-traitement, n'a pu être visualisé que deux jours après ce même prétraitement. De plus, tel qu'indiqué par un décroissement des mesures de fonction pulmonaire lors de l'exposition "provocatrice", la protection fournie par cette tolérance n'est pas absolue. […]</description><description>We investigated the development of tolerance to ozone in young healthy subjects, using dynamic lung function measurements as assessment criteria. Eleven subjects underwent two exposures. (0.6 ppm O3) separated by a 3 day interval; the average decrements in lung function variables were significantly smaller (p&lt;0.05. except for FVC) in the second exposure, suggesting an acquired tolerance. Complementary experiments demonstrated that a threshold concentration of 0.4 ppm O3 (for 2 hours) is required to induce such tolerance and a time interval of 2 days following pre-treatment is needed to observe the phenomenon, which has still demonstrable 4 days after pre-treatment. However, tolerance was not completely protective as indicated by decreases in lung function values on "challenge" exposure. […]</description><creator>Parent, Claude.</creator><contributor>Bates, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Ozone tolerance in man.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920g0889.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311s46f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795b888</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cardiorespiratory effects of PEEP were critically re-assessed in 16 hypoxemic surgical patients. Total venous admixture was calculated in 11 of 16 patients while they breathed room air and true shunt was determined from data obtained during 100% oxygen breathing. The "non-shunt" fraction was calculated by subtracting the true shunt from the total venous admixture. Measurements were made at two levels of end expiratory pressures (0 and 10cm H20). The contribution of airway closure and distal alveolar gas trapping to pulmonary shunting was assessed in 11 of 16 patients by the nitrogen wash-out method and the hemodynamic consequences of 10cm H2O PEEP assessed in all 16 patients. It was concluded that 1) the pathogenesis of hypoxemia was not uniform in type patients studied; 2) that the effect of PEEP on the "non-shunt" fraction may complement or offset the beneficial effect on true shunting, 3) that the decrease in pulmonary shunting with PEEP was not related to re-opening of previously closed airways and 4) that 10cm H2O PEEP produced an insignificant effect on cardiac output in the patients studies.</description><creator>Omole, Charles O.</creator><contributor>Hampson, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Reassessment of cardiorespiratory effect of positive and expiratory pressure (PEEP) in hypoxemia surgical patients.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719q291.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795b888</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860997c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The acquisition of language structures by 22 hearing-impaired children in regular schools were studied. The children, whose ages ranged from 5 to 18 years, had hearing losses of more than 70 dB. They were divided into two groups of 11 each on the basis of age at which deafness was recognized and nature of early training. The first group, diagnosed between the ages of 11 months and 36 months, had participated in a parent-infant guidance program for at least two years. The second group, diagnosed between 34 to 58 months of age had entered directly into a school of the deaf. Rule of morphology, early receptive and expressive language, complex syntax reading skills and communication ability were examined.  No measurable difference in the linguistic skills of the two groups was concerned. All the subjects had reached a higher level of language achievement than similarly-aged subjects described in the literature. Most subjects had not acquired the more complex syntactical structures commonly mastered by hearing children. Better achievement by older subjects was not demonstrated. Each of the tests used was evaluated ae a tool for measuring the language of hearing-impaired children.</description><description>La présente recherche se propose d'étudier l'acquisition de structures linguistiques auprès de 22 jeunes déficients auditifs, intégrés en école régulière. Les enfants âgés de 5 à 8 ans présentent une surdité de plus de 70 dB. Ils furent divisés en deux groupes de 11 enfants chacun dépendant de l’âgé à laquelle leur surdité fut identifiée et dépendant des  mesures thérapeutiques qui furent alors prises. Appartenaient au premier  groupe les enfants dont la surdité avait été identifiée entre tes âgés de 11 et 36 mois et qui avaient bénéficié d'un programme de thérapies parents-enfant pour une durée d'au moins 2 ans. […]</description><creator>Leckie, Doris J.</creator><contributor>Ling, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Human Communications Disorders.</subject><title>Language skills in hearing-impaired children.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bs53v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860997c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Communication Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rr94m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bovine adrenal glands were perfused in vitro. Immediately after switching the perfusion medium to a Na+ - free solution, a sharp increase in catecholamine output was obtained (6-10 times over control values). This increase was linearly related to the logarithm of the extracellular Na+ concentration, and was reduced in the presence of atropine and hexamethonium thus indicating that Ach from preganglionic nerve terminals is not responsible for this release. Excess Mg2+ reduced (10 mH-Mg2+) or blocked (20 mM Mg2+) the Na+-free induced amine output both in the presence and  Ca2+ absence of extracellular Ca2+. […]</description><description>Des glandes surrénales de bovins ont été perfusées in vitro. Aussitôt après le changement du médium de perfusion pour une solution ne contenant pas de Na+, on obtient une augmentation de la libération de catécholamines (6-10 fois les valeurs contrôles). Cette augmentation est reliée linéairement au logarithme de la concentration extracellulaire de Na+, et n'est pas modifiée par la présence d'atropine et d'hexaméthonium, ce qui indique que cette libération n'est pas dûe à l'ACh venant des terminaisons nerveuses préganglioniques. Un excès de Mg2+ réduit (10 mM-Mg2+) ou bloque (20 mM Mg2+) la libération de catécholamines causée par l'abscence de Na+, en l’abscence et en présence de Ca 2+ extracellulaire.  […]</description><creator>Lastowecka, Anna.</creator><contributor>Trifaró, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</subject><title>The effect of sodium and calcium ions on the release of catecholamines from the adrenal medulla.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161929t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rr94m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wn42v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of soluble polysaccharides of agar on antibiotic susceptibility testing was studied, using five lots of Agar (Bacto Difco) and 85 strains of organisms from the Enterobacteriaceae. Washing Agar at 60°c, according to the procedure of Duckworth and, Yaphe (1971), increased gel strength and concentration of 3,6-anhydrogalactose, and decreased the magnesium and calcium ion concentration in the, five lots of commercial agar. The washing procedure provided a purified agar with a low concentration of divalent ions and, sulphated polysaccharides. The relationship between MICs in Mueller-Hinton broth and zone sizes on Mueller-Hinton Agar Were compared using both washed and unwashed agars. The correlation between MICs and zone sizes in the gentamicin assay was significantly increased when zone diameters were measured on media prepared with washed agars. Similarly an increase in correlation of lone sizes was obtained on Mueller-Hinton media prepared with five different lots of washed Agar. These correlations, however, were not as great when using neomycin and tetracycline. Washing commercial Agar removes impurities which affect antibiotic susceptibility testing, and provides an Agar which allows more reproducible results. </description><description>Les effets des polysaccarides solubles d'agar sur le test de susceptibilité antibiotique ont été étudiés à partir de cinq lots d'aqar (Bacto Difco) et da quatre-vingt-cinq lignées d'organismes d'Entérobactériacées. En lavant l'agar à 60°C, conformément su procédé de Duckworth et de Yaphe (1971), on a observé non seulement une augmentation du titre de colloide et de la concentration en anhydrogalactose- 3,6, mais aussi une diminution de la concentration en magnésium et ion calcium. […]</description><creator>Kokoskin, Evelyne A.</creator><contributor>Yaphe, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology.</subject><title>The effects of soluble polysaccharides of agar on antibiotic susceptibility testing.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967672z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wn42v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z125v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ADP-induced aggregation of rabbit platelets was used to provide supportive evidence to the fact that the biologically active component of the eosinophil-derived inhibitor (EDI) is a prostaglandin (PG). By inhibiting the ADP-induced aggregation of platelets, the EDI behaved like PGE1. Efforts were made to quantitatively estimate the amounts of PGE1 that are present within different EDI samples. After establishing that a particular EDI extract possessed inhibitory activity in, the histamine , release assay (HRA), these same extracts were then compared for their activity in bath the platelet aggregation (PAA) and rat stomach strip assay (RSSA) to that of standard PGE concentrations. Although differences were found in the absolute values of E-type prostaglandins detected by both assay systems, the discrepancies could be explained by the occasionally decreased sensitivity of a particular stomach strip preparation. In addition, PGEI and PGE2 produced an additive response in the RSSA, whereas the presence of both isomers in the PAA test sample showed antagonistic properties. […]</description><description>L'aggrégation des plaquettes de lapin, induite par l'ADP a été utilisée our mettre en évidence le fait que le compose biologiquement actif de l’inhibiteur dérivant de l'eosinophile (IDE) est une prostaglandine (PG). En inhibant l’aggrégation des plaquettes induite par l'ADP, l'IDE se comporte cbmme le PGE1. Des efforts ont été faits pour estimer quantitativement les taux de PGEI qui sont présents dans differents échantillons de IDE. Aprés avoir établi qu'un extrait particulier de IDE possèdait une activé inhibitrice dans la libération d histamine, ces mêmes extraits étaient comparés pour leur activité dans l'aggrégation des plaquettes (AP) ainsi que dans la contraction des fragments d'estomac chez le rat (CFER), à celle des concentrations de PGE standard. […]</description><creator>Timm, Martina K.</creator><contributor>Hubscher, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Studies with an eosinophil derived inhibitor (EDI) of histamine release.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw88k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z125v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w283s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is a review of electrophysiological data obtained from selected patients during 130 stereotaxic syrgical procedures performed at the Montreal Neurological Institute over the past twelve years. Various errors inherent in the stereotaxic technique have been considered in depth along with further considerations of the measurements of the roentgenological coordinates of the target structure and correction of possible sources of error prior to making a surgical lesion or plotting electrophysiological responses on diencephalic maps. A computerized method of displaying anatomical maps of the human diencephalon and storing, selecting and plotting data is presented. [...]</description><creator>Hardy, Tyrone L.</creator><date>1975</date><subject>Electrophysiologucal data</subject><title>Computer display of the electrophysiological topography of the human diencephalon during stereotaxic surgery.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/736667834.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w283s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z7090847</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The members of this family are in general of no economic importance in our region due to the fact that we do not find any injurious pests among them. On the other hand, many species are predaceous in habit, and therefore are beneficial. For this reason, we must draw attention to them in order to be able to identify these bugs and to use them in our fight against the injurious insects. [...]</description><creator>Duncan, Joseph R.</creator><contributor>DuPorte, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>The pentatomidae of Quebec (Hemiptera - Heteroptera).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765374050.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z7090847</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d5700731</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Administration of γ-hydroxybutyrate (GOBA) has been shown to block firing of dopaminergic cells in brain, with a concomitant increase in dopamine (DA). The increase of DA after GOBA was employed as an index of tyrosine hydroxylase activity in vivo. The reputed DA agonist anomorphine inhibited the rise of DA after GOBA, an inhibition which was antagonized by haloperidol. The action of anomorphine was found not to be due to inhibition of monoamine oxidase or of catechol-O-methyltransferase, but was similar to that of amphetamine. The DA agonists piribedil, apocodeine, M7, ergocornine and 2-Br-α-ergocryptine inhibited the rise of DA after GOBA. The last four, however, were not antagonized in their inhibition by haloperidol. Ergocornine, M7 and piribedil also differed from apomorphine in that the elevated DA levels in controls. These results provide strong evidence for the presence of a dopamine receptor which acts locally to inhibit dopamine synthesis. In addition, the results suggest that DA agonists do not have a common mode of action.</description><creator>Handforth, Adrian</creator><contributor>Sourkes, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Local control of dopamine synthesis in the brain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9676737.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d5700731</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rh507</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experiments were performed on unanesthetized and pentobarbital anesthetized newborn rabbits of one day or less post-gestational age, ranging in weight from 50 to 70 gms. Various gas mixtures were employed under steady state conditions to stimulate ventilation and the technique of tracheal occlusion at end-expiration was applied on random breaths. The results show that during barbiturate anesthesia, inspiratory duration is slightly shortened as barbiturate-anesthesia, a result of equally enhanced contributions of the bulbopontine and volume-related vagal reflex mechanisms. In contrast, expiratory duration was found to be independent of volume-related vagal influence, and was markedly prolonged during anesthesia. The results indicate that the new breathing pattern achieved during anesthesia is due to the effect on the timing mechanisms whereas respiratory mechanics do not appear to be affected, leaving tidal volume stability unchanged.</description><creator>Goldberg, Michael S.</creator><contributor>Milic-Emili, Dr. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>A quantitative analysis of the effect of barbiturate anesthesia on respiratory control and stability in new-born rabbits</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848t66x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rh507</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53k115f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The biology of the tarnished plant bug is known to some extent, though there is apparently no literature on its morphology. The object of this paper is to give a brief discussion of the external morphology of the immature and adult stages and also to make a contribution to the study of the biology of this well-known polyhagous insect. The history of Lygus pratensis dates as early as 1746, when Linnaeus described it as Cimex griseus. A few years later, in 1758, the same author published the tenth edition of his “Systema Naturae” and described it as Cimex pratensis. The specific name has been retained, although the insect has been placed in different genera from time to time, such as Phytocoris, Lygaeus, Miris, Capsus. Now it definitely belongs to the genus Lygus. Many species of the genus Lygus, especially that of the sub-genus Lygus, have been called the “tarnished plant bug.” This confusion is not surprising, however, since these species are so closely related and the morphological differences so small. But the fact that so many of them are called by the same common name is rather confusing. At the present time, Lygus pratensis Linn., is recognized as the tarnished plant bug and this is the species dealt with in this paper.</description><creator>Doyle, Joseph Andre.</creator><contributor>DuPorte, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>External morphology of the tarnished plant bug Lygus Pratensis Linn.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g60p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k115f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b912n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A direct participation of the adrenal cortex in the hormonal regulation both of carbohydrate metabolism and of electrolyte and water metabolism has been the subject of vigorous debate for a number of years. There is now no doubt that adrenalectomy elicits widespread disturbances both in the carbohydrate and in the salt and water balance of the organism, but there is no agreement among the various investigators as to which of these two factors is primarily responsible for the changes which ultimately lead to the death of the animal deprived of its adrenals. These changes in two very different phases of normal metabolism are so closely linked together that there is no agreement as to what the prepotent function of the adrenal cortex can be. However, since admittedly any potent extract prepared from the adrenal cortex restores both the carbohydrate and the electrolyte and water equilibrium to normal, any theory of adrenal cortical function must take both these sets of facts into consideration. [...]</description><creator>Dosne, Christiane.</creator><contributor>Selye H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>The role of the adrenals in general resistance.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r1739.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b912n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c141v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vegetable dehydration, or the scientificdrying of vegetables for domestic use has made greatprogress particularly during recent months. Contraryto popular opinion however, the demand for these vegatablesis very limited. Small quantities have beenbought for certain branches of the services, and limitedamounts have been purchased as emergency reserve rationsfor military and naval establishments (25). But keepingin mind the constantly changing conditions created by war,it is quite probable that in the future, dehydratedvegetables might be required in considerable quantity.[...]</description><creator>Morrison, Mary F.M.</creator><contributor>Crampton, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Nutrition.</subject><title>Studies on the ascorbic acid content of dehydrated vegetables and its retention in cooking.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jh60z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c141v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042x16v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Glucuronic acid is a hexose uronic acid, discovered by Wiedemann in 1876 in dog’s urine and later identified by Schmiedeberg in 1879. It is conjugated in vivo with various exogenous and endogenous substances and excreted entirely in this combined form. It does not represent the only conjugating mechanism nor even the most common conjugating mechanism, but special interest has been aroused in its metabolism with the recent finding that many of the sex hormones are excreted in conjugation with glucuronic acid.</description><creator>Croll, Diane.</creator><contributor>Browne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Metabolism of Glucuronic Acid.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096b12h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042x16v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913s89c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dimolecular reduction of hexamethyl acetone has been studiedin order to test the mobility of the tertiary butyl groups. The glycolobtained from the reaction has not been previously described andappears to constitute the first recognized case of geometrical isomerismin symmetrically substituted ethylene glycols. Attampts to carryout a pinacoline rearrangement gave a mixture of unidentified olefinesand apparent no migration of the tertiar,y butyl group. It has alsobeen shown that the glycol possesses an abnonmally low molecular weightin benzene.The results obtained differ radically from those reported byFavorsky and Nazarov, the only previous workers in this field.The benzilic acid rearrangement of ditertiarj butyl diketone hasbeen investigated. This previously unreported reaction resulted incleavage of the diketone. No evidence of tertiary butyl group migrationwas observed.</description><creator>Mowat, John Halley.</creator><contributor>Boyer, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The Action of sodium upon highly branched chain ketones.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r415q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913s89c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff365824k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In experiments conducted to determine the agreement between the Burrell and Ebright chemical method and the “increase in weight” biological method of estimating the vitamin C content of dehydrated potato and fresh lemon juice, using crystalline ascorbic acid as a control, it was found that there was agreement only in the determination of the antiscorbutic principle in the lemon juice. The lack of agreement with potato may indicate an inaccurate chemical method or a secondary, growth promoting, factor present in potato. From the levels tested it was suggested that .375 mg. of crystalline ascorbic acid or its equivalent is a minimum maintenance level, while .5 mg. is a minimum protective level from scurvy. The nutritional adequacy of the basal diet, for normal growth, is questioned, and its relation to bioassay for vitamin C is discussed.</description><creator>Collier, Barbara Catherine.</creator><contributor>Crampton, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Nutrition.</subject><title>Observations on the guinea pig growth method of vitamin C assay.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903295n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365824k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sd57d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Puisqu'il n'y a pas de critique récente qui vise atracer la vogue shakespearienne en soulignant le rôlequ'y joua Jean François Ducis, nous avons entrepriscette étude qui montrera, nous espérons, l'influence deShakespeare en France jusqu'à l'époque romantique. Dansune notice biographique nous essayerons de présenterDucis, l^omme que personne ne pouvait connaître sansl'aimer. Et puisqu'il y a toujours un rapport entrel'auteur et l'ouvrage, nous signalerons que Duels par sasensiblerie, par son penchant pour le mélodrame et pourun langage artificiel appartenait aN son siècle et au goûtdramatique d'alors bien qu'il se vantât d'être lndlsclplinableet de ne suivre autre poétique que celle de lanature. [...]</description><creator>Murphy, Marie Magdalen, Sister.</creator><contributor>Lariviere, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Ducis, J.-F. (Jean-François), 1733-1816 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 -- Adaptations.</subject><title>DUCIS : essai sur l’influence de Shakespeare en France jusqu’à l’époque romantique.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h474t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sd57d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x230b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Statistics published by the Dominion Department of Agriculture of Canada show that about 20% of the Canadian pig crop dies every year. This mortality is due to several causes -- bacterial, virus, parasitic, nutritional diseases and bad management. Diseases due to virus and bacterial infections are comparatively few and the means for their control are not lacking. However, there are disease problems of a more complex nature; these include parasitic as well as nutritional diseases. This has been previously pointed out by Watson. It is widely believed that intestinal parasites play an important role in diseases of swine. The intestinal parasite most commonly found in pigs in Canada is Ascaris lumbricoides Linn. 1758. This nematode is readily recognized by breeders and is generally believed to be an important factor in swine losses. It is this nematode that has claimed the attention of most investigators interested in the problem of swine diseases and losses. However, while a large amount of work has been carried out with regard to the exact relationship between Ascaris infection and its clinical and pathological manifestations in the host animal, this relationship is still very poorly understood.</description><creator>Choquette, L.</creator><contributor>Cameron, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Parasitology.</subject><title>Studies on ascariasis in pigs. The seasonal incidence and the effects of infection on growth, with special attention to factors of resistance to harmful infection.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612r70w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x230b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322h69s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Baudelaire a imposé une nouvelle conception de la poésie à la littérature française. L’histoire de l’évolution de sa réputation devant la critique est en quelque sorte l’histoire du triomphe de sa doctrine. Quelles furent ses idées sur la poésie? Il conviendrait de s’en faire une idée exacte avant d’entreprendre un examen de l’opinion critique. Nous pouvons diviser ces idées en deux catégories: (a) ce que Baudelaire a écrit de la poésie en générale, et (b) ce qu’il a écrit des Fleurs du Mal en particulier. [...]</description><creator>Carter, A. E. (Alfred Edward)</creator><contributor>Darbelnet, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Baudelaire, Charles, 1821-1867.</subject><title>Baudelaire devant la critique de 1857 à 1917.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dd046.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322h69s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311s47q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experimental carcinogenesis, or the experimental production of tumors in animals, is a relatively new field of research. Its beginning dates from 1915 when the Japanese workers Yamagiwa and Itchikawa first succeeded in producing papillomas and true malignant growths on the ears of rabbits after continued application of tar. This important observation at once raised the question as to the nature of the component or components in tar which were responsible for its carcinogenicity. The English workers, Kennaway, Cook and their associates, attacking the problem with this question in mind, finally succeeded in isolating 3,4-Benzpyrene which is now recognized as the active agent in coal tar. [...] In brief, we have reared frogs’ eggs in solutions of a water-soluble carcinogen, the hope being that we could observe changes in the living cells which it is difficult to do in work with larger animals such as mice. Our procedure also appeared to offer some possibilities not available in tissue culture work or in work with small free-living organisms. Specifically, in the frog embryo certain fundamental developmental processes are taking place, and thus opportunity is afforded to observe the effect of the carcinogen on an actively growing and differentiating system.</description><creator>Briggs, Janet B.</creator><contributor>Berrill, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Zoology.</subject><title>The effect of a water-soluble carcinogen on the early development of the frog.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451m79s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311s47q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763998d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A. Results of analyses of tumors produced on beets by Phytomonas turnefaciens confirm the values of previous workers and show that the tumors utilize sucrose for the synthesis of protoplasm and cell wall material rather than for storage as is the case of the normal tissue. B. The first known studies on the metabolism of living slices of plant tumors have been made. c. Comparison of the metabolism of the tumor and normal tissue (of the beet root) shows striking differences in the mode and rate of sugar metabolism. Special attention has been paid to the Pasteur Effect which is found to be markedly different in the two tissues. D. A study has been made on the effect of sodium bisulphite on the respiration and fermentation of beet tissue slices. It is found to completely inhibit respiration, partially inhibit fermentation, and to cause acetaldehyde and glyceraldehyde to accumulate.</description><creator>Neish, A. C. </creator><contributor>Hibbert, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the metabolism of normal and tumor tissues of beet roots.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk35t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763998d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hz64g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le nom de Saint François de Sales évoque bien souvent un souvenir un peu ironique: le saint le plus doucereux qui fût, à la langue fleurie plus qu’il n’est raisonnable. Si, un peu curieux, on se réfère aux jugements critiques, que trouve-t-on? Un Sainte-Beuve tout bienveillant et sympathique, résume son opinion: «fadaises séraphiques» ! Huysmans abonde dans le même sens, de même que, tout récemment, Paul Souday: «Trop de confiseries et d’images douceâtres pour dessus de boites à bonbons !» [...] Un «formateur» de conscience, c’est le docteur qui soigne la conscience malade, en redresse les déviations; puis c’est le formateur qui développe la conscience ainsi redressée et la fortifie dans le but de l’amener à agir seule. Cet ouvrage pourrait donc porter également cormne sous-titre, apposé au terrae général et consacré de «François de Sales, directeur de conscience», François de Sales, formateur de conscience». C’est ce nous allons nous attacher à mettre en lumière tout au long de ce travail.</description><creator>Beauvais, Roxane.</creator><contributor>Lariviere, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Francis, de Sales, Saint, 1567-1622.</subject><title>Saint Francois de Sales, directeur de conscience.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd473049q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hz64g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wq87b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>From service time and sorption gradient studies on sulfur dioxide and carbon tetrachloride, it was found that: ( 1) the equilibrium sorption weight could be represented by the Langmuir Adsorption Isotherm; (2) the “critical length” was a linear function of the initial concentration; (3) the length of the sorption gradient and the dead length varied as the logarithm of the initial concentration; (4) the weight of sorbed at any point in the charcoal bed increased with time according to: x = K e^-k/t and (5) the initial sorption of the gas by the first layers of the charcoal bed followed the relation: x =  Ws (1 - e^-bt ) . Studies on the amines showed that the service time - bed length plot was not linear throughout its length. Chloropicrin could be removed from charcoal with 90% efficiency by refluxing with commercial pentane. In the fluorination of sulfur, diluting the fluorine with nitrogen and cooling the reaction tube gave higher yields of disulfur decafluoride and the lower fluorides and a lower yield of sulfur hexafluoride.</description><creator>Arnell, J. C.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Gases -- Absorption and adsorption.</subject><subject>Chemical warfare.</subject><title>The mechanism of the sorption of gases by charcoal and other research in chemical warfare.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cn97z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wq87b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903296x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:28:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>From an investigation of the reduction of α-bromoisobutyrophenone with aluminum isopropoxide, products have been isolated which indicate extensive debromination and rearrangement as well as reduction of the parent substance. [...]</description><creator>Allenby, Owen Clement Wentworth.</creator><contributor>Nicholls, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Chemical reactors.</subject><title>The reduction of a-bromoisobutyrophenone with aluminum isopropoxide : the nitration of p-cymene.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hg238.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903296x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10450</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>