<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:22:53Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33525" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x44b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, the effects of an active analog of cyclophosphamide (4-hydroperoxycyclophosphamide, 4OOH-CPA), an alkylating agent and teratogen, on mouse limb development, cell death and the role of the p53 gene in this process were studied. A mouse limb bud culture system was used for this purpose. Limbs developed normally in this system and showed physiological apoptosis in a spatio-temporal-controlled manner. Drug treatment caused limb reduction malformations, increased the amount of apoptosis and triggered its occurrence prematurely, primarily in areas with physiological apoptosis. This indicated that drug-treatment might have engaged the already available program of apoptosis in the developing limb, and suggested this might be the cause of limb malformations. Next we examined the induction pattern of three proteins, cathepsin D, transglutaminase and clusterin, known to be involved in the molecular mechanism of apoptosis. The pattern of their induction suggested that cathepsin D was involved in the digestion of apoptotic debris, transglutaminase was active in preserving the cellular integrity during apoptosis, and clusterin played a role in later phases of apoptosis. Since 4OOH-CPA causes DNA damage, we studied the role of the p53 gene, a DNA-damage response gene involved in regulating cell cycle and apoptosis, in a p53-transgenic mouse model. Absence of p53 led to more severe limb malformations in the treated limbs. To investigate the reason(s) for this higher sensitivity to drug insult, cell death and cell cycle patterns were studied. While wild-type limbs showed an induction of apoptosis by drug treatment, which might be crucial in eliminating damaged cells, the null limbs were resistant to this effect. Furthermore, in response to 4OOH-CPA-treatment, the cell cycle was not arrested in p53 -/- limbs, in contrast to wild-type limbs; this arrest is necessary for DNA repair. Further investigation revealed the occurrence of necrosis in p53 -/- limbs. Thus, we</description><creator>Moallem, Seyed Adel.</creator><contributor>Hales, B. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Toxicology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Disruption of murine limb development in vitro by a teratogen : role of P53 dependent and independent cell death</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q798q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x44b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903164f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Saccharomyces cerevisiae alpha1,2-mannosidase that removes one specific mannose residue from Man9GlcNAc 2 during the biosynthesis of N-glycans is a member of the Class 1 alpha1,2-mannosidase family conserved through eukaryotic evolution. These alpha1,2-mannosidases are type II membrane proteins with an N-terminal transmembrane domain and a large C-terminal catalytic domain. High levels of recombinant yeast alpha1,2-mannosidase catalytic domain were produced using Saccharomyces cerevisiae (0.6 mg/l) and Pichia pastoris (30 mg/l) expression systems, permitting further characterization of the structural and mechanistic properties of the enzyme. Peptide analysis was applied to localize the two disulfide bonds (Cys340-Cys385 and Cys468-Cys 471) and free thiol group (Cys485). Atomic absorption analysis and equilibrium dialysis with 45Ca2+ were used to show that the enzyme binds one Ca2+ ion with high affinity. It was also demonstrated by proton nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy that the alpha1,2-mannosidase hydrolyzes the substrate with inversion of the anomeric configuration. Site-directed mutagenesis studies were used to determine the importance of the cysteine residues, the invariant acidic residues, and the putative EF hand Ca2+-binding motif. It was shown that the disulfide bond formed by the invariant Cys340 and Cys 385 residues is essential for the structural integrity of the alpha1,2-mannosidase, while the second disulfide bond and free thiol are not necessary for enzyme activity. It was also demonstrated that the EF hand motif is not the site for Ca2+ binding, whereas Asp275, Glu 279, and Glu438 are important for Ca2+ binding, and Asp86, Glu132, Glu503, and Glu526 are likely active site residues. The yeast alpha1,2-mannosidase is the only Class 1 alpha1,2-mannosidase for which both structural and mechanistic properties have been characterized, and it can serve as a model for the other enzymes of the family.</description><creator>Lipari, Francesco.</creator><contributor>Herscovics, Annette (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Structure and mechanism of action of the yeast class 1 a1,2-mannosidase involved in N-glycan biosynthesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956h64f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903164f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cv71h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis considers the design of receivers for multi-user communication systems based on asynchronous direct-sequence code-division multiple-access (DS-CDMA). Its primary aim is to improve current receiver designs which exhibit shortcomings in systems using long sequence spreading (where the spreading sequence changes with each consecutive bit). The conventional matched filter (MF) and noise-whit MF (NWMF) receivers incur a degradation in performance under power-imbalance (near-far like) conditions. Similar to that of the conventional MF (CMF), the near-far resistance of the NWMF is shown to be zero. Other receivers, including multiuser receivers, suffer from either incompatibility or excessive complexity under long sequence spreading. Motivated by the need for low-complexity receivers compatible with long sequence spreading, the thesis investigates the design of linear time-invariant (LTI) filters which maximize the signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) for bit symbol detection. It develops the chip-delay locked MF (CLMF) which requires the knowledge of interferer chip delays and signal powers; knowledge of their spreading sequences is unnecessary. Moreover, it takes advantage of the observation that multiple-access interference (MAI) is generally neither white nor stationary, but cyclostationary. Analysis of the CLMF demonstrates that it can deliver non-zero near-far resistance along with performance beyond that of the CMF and NWMF. Furthermore, the computation of the filter response is required only when an interferer signal parameter changes. The complexity of the computation grows linearly with the number of interferers. In addition, insight and directions are presented for the development of adaptive versions of the CLMF which eliminate the need for interferer signal parameters altogether. Based on the same approach used to develop the CLMF, the thesis presents a general framework from which other one-shot linear detectors can be derived. With increasing knowledge of interferer signal parameters, this approach can synthesize the NWMF, the one-shot linear minimum mean squared error (MMSE) detector and the one-shot decorrelator. Furthermore, the limiting forms of the NWMF and CLMF in the absence of background additive white Gaussian noise (AWGN) are shown to be, respectively, an inverse chip filter followed by a despreading filter (or correlator) and a decorrelator-type CLMF. The thesis also examines how additional knowledge of interferer phase-offsets, the presence of intersymbol interference (ISI) and the presence of both unlocked and chip-delay locked interferers affect filter design.</description><creator>Yoon, Young C.</creator><contributor>Leib, Harry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>SNR maximizing linear filters with interference suppression capabilities for DS-CDMA</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Young C. Yoon, 1998</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rj867.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv71h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73px72m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies were designed to investigate the expression and regulation of interstitial collagenase (MMP-1) during endochondral ossification in fetal bovine growth plate chondrocytes in vitro. Fetal bovine growth plate chondrocytes were separated into subpopulations representing different maturational stages by using a Percoll discontinuous gradient. Gene expression and synthesis of MMP-1 in these chondrocyte subpopulations were followed in serum-free cultures as they matured from the prehypertrophic to hypertrophic phenotype. However, MMP-1 mRNA expression and protein were undetectable. This expression was also undetectable in interleukin 1alpha (IL-1alpha) stimulated growth plate chondrocytes. MMP-1 mRNA and protein were however observed in IL-1alpha stimulated bovine fetal skin fibroblasts. Although MMP-1 was absent in growth plate chondrocytes, a collagenolytic activity was detectable in culture medium by using 14C labeled type II collagen. It was only seen when the chondrocytes were hypertrophic. By using the polymerase chain reaction (PCR), employing conserved sequences found in mammalian collagenase-3 (MMP-13), a novel bovine collagenase, was cloned. The cDNA and predicted amino acid sequence shared a 92% and 90% identity to the human MMP-13 cDNA and amino acid sequence respectively. MMP-13 mRNA and protein were found only when the chondrocytes became hypertrophic. The role of MMP-13 during the maturation of these fetal growth plate chondrocytes was further investigated by using a preferential carboxylate inhibitor of collagenase-3. This inhibitor reduced the generation of denatured type II collagen in chondrocyte cell layers and proteoglycan release into conditioned medium in a dose dependent manner. Also, types II and X collagen synthesis and matrix calcification were inhibited. These studies indicate that MMP-13 may play a very important role during the maturation of fetal growth plate chondrocyte in vitro and during endochondral ossification and that cellul</description><creator>Wu, Ching Hua William.</creator><contributor>Poole, A. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>The characterization of the collagenase involved during chondrocyte maturation in the bovine fetal growth plate /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq25r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73px72m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386m13b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Colletotrichum coccodes is being developed as a bioherbicide to control velvetleaf. An effective and economic process for mass production of C. coccodes sports is required for its possible development as a bioherbicide. A modified Richard's solution containing V-8 juice has been used to produce C. coccodes spores in shake flasks. However, V-8 juice is not available as a bulk commodity and is too expensive for commercial production of a bioherbicide. Soy protein and casamino acids were equal to and can replace V-8 juice for sporulation of C. coccodes . Using the Plackett-Burman experimental design, the effect of the various components in a complex medium on both the sporulation and mycelial biomass of C. coccodes were determined. Carbon concentration and carbon to nitrogen ratio as well as their interaction are critical for C. coccodes growth and sporulation. In medium containing 10 g/l carbon with C:N ratios from 10:1 to 15:1, 8 x 107 C. coccodes spores per ml were produced. Germination of the spores was 90% and they caused extensive shoot dry weight reduction of inoculated velvetleaf. C:N ratios from 10:1 to 15:1 am optimal for C. coccodes sporulation. A cyclone column bioreactor was used to investigate the effects of environmental conditions on spore yield. C. coccodes sporulation was superior with low aeration (~0.5vvm) and low pH (4.5--5.0) compared with high aeration (2 vvm) and high pH (6.5--7.5). The optimum temperature for sporulation was 24°C. C. coccodes sporulation commences when the dissolved oxygen supply becomes restricted. Spore yields of over 3.5 x 107 spores per ml can be obtained within four days from batch culture. Scale up to a 100 liter cyclone column bioreactor yielded 2.5 x 107 C. coccodes spores per ml within four days.</description><creator>Yu, Xuefeng.</creator><contributor>Watson, Alan K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Colletotrichum coccodes.</subject><title>Mass production of Colletotrichum coccodes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx51c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m13b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nz91f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The peripheral and central mechanisms mediating the modulatory effects of glucose and acute stress in rats were investigated using two versions of an appetitive win-stay task. Post-training injections of glucose, but not fructose, enhanced retention on the closed maze task. Acquisition of this task was found to be impaired by lesions of the fimbria-fornix (FF). Further experiments showed that while the celiac ganglion and the FF normally participate in suppressing the memory-enhancing effect of an acute stressor, neither structure is involved in mediating the effect of glucose on memory. Post-training injections of glucose, but not fructose, enhanced retention on the open maze task. Although acquisition of this task was not affected by FF lesions, both the celiac ganglion and the FF participate in mediating the memory-enhancing effect of glucose. Together, the results suggest that the peripheral and central mechanisms studied here are both substance- and task-specific. The modulatory effects of different types of stress, and the issue of whether task acquisition and memory modulation are anatomically distinct are discussed.</description><creator>White, Lynn H.</creator><contributor>White, Norman M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Glucose -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Stress (Physiology)</subject><subject>Rats -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Memory -- Physiological aspects.</subject><title>Task-specific effects of glucose and stress on memory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q889.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nz91f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wx53x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This qualitative case study describes the language learning experiences of four South Asian women from their perspectives and uses tools of ethnographic inquiry such as interviews, participant observations and document analysis. The socio-cultural factors affecting their language learning process and acculturation are analyzed. Key elements of the lived experiences of these South Asian females surfacing in the case study data are isolation and gender inequity. Socio-cultural identity emerges as a very influential factor in the language learning process. I understand this identity as socially constructed, contradictory, and fluid. Peirce's poststructuralist conception of social identity as multiple, a site of struggle, and subject to change is used in the theoretical framework. Her concept of "investment" is employed to describe immigrant women's involvement in the language learning process. An umbrella category termed the "weight of society" is used to explain the influences of socio-cultural norms on the language learning processes of the four research participants. Implications for immigrant language training policies and further research are suggested.</description><creator>Steinbach, Marilyn.</creator><contributor>Maguire, Mary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers.</subject><subject>South Asian Canadians -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Women immigrants -- Education -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Socio-cultural factors affecting the language learning experiences of South Asian female immigrants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd49v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx53x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p6445</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When teachers initiate the process of student-kept portfolios in high school language arts, they draw upon implicit beliefs about knowledge, learning, and teaching. This study shows that why we use portfolios is as important as how we use them. I begin by exploring the century old history of teaching high school English wherein we can identify a contrast to portfolios, what we call traditional education. The ethical, classical, grammar based and non-academic traditions have shaped our definition of the subject, as well as the content. By examining where portfolios come from in the history of teaching English, we can then uncover the beliefs that are implicit in using them. Next, I review the work of Tolstoy, Ashton-Warner and Dewey who developed innovative teaching methods based on an original set of beliefs. I connect them to beliefs that are implicit about knowledge, learning, and teaching in today's portfolio classrooms. Like these three innovators, teachers in today's portfolio classrooms have reinterpreted their role as teacher and evaluator. The portfolio teachers in this study hold common beliefs that relate to both the history of the subject and to the work of innovative educators in our past. These common beliefs, found in the concluding chapter of this thesis, are the reasons why some teachers use portfolios.</description><creator>Oelmann, Julie M.</creator><contributor>Beer, Ann (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Portfolios in education.</subject><title>Why portfolios? : history, philosophy and practice together in a portable folder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xb27k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p6445</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hb49w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This qualitative study examines alienated parents' perceptions of their own experience of Parental Alienation Syndrome (PAS). The participants were five fathers and one mother. The data were collected via semi-structured, open-ended interview questionnaires. A qualitative analysis of the data was performed for each participant in an attempt to answer the following questions: (1) Are there characteristics (e.g., number of children, number of marriages, etc.) common to alienated families? (2) Are there common themes or issues among the conflicts between couples that contribute to marriage dissolution? (3) From the lost parent's perspective, are there commonalities in the underlying causes of the alienation? (4) Are there common themes in the participants' experience of the alienation process? (5) Given the opportunity what are some things that the lost parents perceive they might do differently? The findings are discussed and the limitations of the present study are given.</description><creator>Vassiliou, Despina.</creator><contributor>Cartwright, Glenn F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Custody of children -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Children of divorced parents -- Mental health -- Evaluation.</subject><title>Parental alienation syndrome : the lost parents' perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h353v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb49w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mx153</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines how a group of culturally and linguistically diverse Toronto secondary students perceive their present and previous writing experiences, ESL instruction and theories about writing in a first and second language. Data analysis included interviews with eight students, participant observations in their ESL classroom, literacy events and analysis of their written texts.</description><creator>Lemelin, Nathalie.</creator><contributor>Maguire, Mary H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers.</subject><subject>Composition (Language arts)</subject><title>A study of eight culturally and linguistically diverse secondary students' perceptions of first and second language writing instruction and second language learning /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301301f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx153</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r729v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to determine whether traditional learn-to-swim progressions, leading to the front and back swim, were developmentally valid for children with physical disabilities. Forty children between the ages of 5 and 12 years participated in this study. The children were described according to four descriptive characteristics: disability type, functional sport classification, mode of ambulation, and need of a flotation device. The children required recommendation from their regular aquatic instructor as being comfortable in the water to participate in the study. In addition, each child had to pass a water orientation-adjustment test. The developmental validity of the progressions was assessed by testing the children on seven skills: rhythmic breathing, front float, front glide, front swim, back float, back glide, and back swim. A pass consisted of all criteria for success being met for a particular skill. The data were analyzed to determine the number of children who followed the typical progression and the number who followed an atypical progression. The results indicated that the proposed learn-to-swim progressions for both the front swim and back swim were not developmentally valid for most children with physical disabilities who were neither extremely high nor low in functional sport ability. These results are consistent with the views of ecological theory and suggest that not all children with physical disabilities will reach an end-goal using the same means. Aquatic instructors therefore, need to adapt their teaching methods to the individual strengths of their students.</description><creator>Gelinas, Joanna E.</creator><contributor>Reid, Greg (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Swimming -- Study and teaching.</subject><subject>Physical education for children with disabilities</subject><subject>Swimming for children.</subject><subject>Swimming for people with disabilities.</subject><title>The developmental validity of traditional learn-to-swim progressions for children with physical disabilities /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35696173.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r729v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj87h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated changes in self-esteem and perceived problem solving ability of academically at-risk students participating in a program called Science of Survival. The program combined adventure education and problem based learning approaches. One hundred and fifty-five male and female students, between the ages of 16 and 24 years completed the Self-Esteem Inventory and the Problem Solving Inventory at the beginning of the semester, after an adventure experience weekend, and at the end of the semester. A group of seventy-seven first year social science students, serving as a control group, also completed the inventories on the same time schedule. Self-esteem and perceived problem solving ability scores were analyzed by two one-way (treatment versus control) repeated measures (three assessments times) ANOVAs. Correlations between the two measures were also computed. Results indicated significant (p $&lt;$.05) interactions of group by time for both self-esteem and perceived problem solving ability and significant correlations. Further analysis showed the Explorations II program was effective at increasing self-esteem and perceived problem solving ability and that these two constructs are related. The control group did not change in self-esteem over the period, but showed a deterioration in perceived problem solving ability.</description><creator>Robertson, Jennifer L., 1969-</creator><contributor>Neil, Graham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Self-esteem -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Vanier College (Montréal, Quebec) -- Students -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Wilderness survival -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Case studies.</subject><subject>College students -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Case studies.</subject><title>The effects of an adventure education problem-based approach program on students' self-esteem and perceived problem solving ability /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm74b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj87h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wh75v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Girls' participation in physical education, sport and other physical activity was examined relative to their levels of Perceived Sport Competence, Body Attractiveness, Physical Self Worth and Social Physique Anxiety. Two hundred and thirteen grade 11 girls from two co-educational and two single sex Toronto high schools completed questionnaires designed to assess physical activity participation and these psychological attributes. T-tests verified that there were no differences on the psychological measures between the two types of schools. On the basis of the girls' responses, they were divided into non, low, medium and high participant groups. The relationships between physical activity participation and the selected psychological measures were analyzed by Pearson correlations. Analysis of Variance's (participant groups x psychological construct) determined where differences existed among participant groups. The results revealed that high level participants had greater Perceived Sport Competence, Body Attractiveness, Physical Self Worth levels than the participants at the lower levels. Social Physique Anxiety was unrelated to physical activity participation. Perceived Sport Competence was the best predictor of participation.</description><creator>Grisé, Suzanne M.</creator><contributor>Neil, Graham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Physical education and training -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Teenage girls -- Psychology.</subject><subject>Self-esteem in adolescence.</subject><subject>Body image.</subject><title>The relationship of perceived sport competence, body attractiveness, physical self worth and social physique anxiety to girls' physical activity participation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks203.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh75v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fd50m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The preponderance of female depression is a widespread phenomenon that emerges as early as adolescence. Two diverse lines of psychosocial research were explored in the present study with the aim of helping to explain these gender differences. The first concerned the role of two interpersonal problems, feeling overly responsible for the welfare of others and feeling unassertive in relationships, which have been linked to psychological distress in adolescents (Aube, Fichman, Saltaris, &amp; Koestner, 1997). The second focused on the differential response styles of males and females, rumination and distraction (Nolen-Hooksema, 1987). Results demonstrated that feeling overly responsible for others, and engaging in a ruminative response style were most predictive of psychological distress. As well, gender differences emerged among the older adolescents in psychological distress, feeling too responsible, and in rumination. Overall, the present findings suggested that, between the ages of 16 and 18, females become more likely than males to feel overly responsible for the welfare of others and to adopt a ruminative response style, which appears to make them more vulnerable to psychological distress.</description><creator>Di Dio, Pasqualina.</creator><contributor>Koestner, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Sex differences (Psychology)</subject><subject>Depression in adolescence.</subject><title>Explaining gender differences in psychological distress among adolescents : the roles of interpersonal problems and response styles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rg21k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fd50m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999843t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>All athletes dream of competing to their full potential. Experimenters have shown that mental preparation can enhance performance. Self-efficacy and self-confidence have also been shown to have a direct relationship with performance. The purpose of this study was to investigate the potential of team highlight videotapes as mental preparation tools designed to enhance feelings of self-efficacy and sport-confidence, which in turn might lead to enhanced performance. Three-minute video montages of successful shot-making were set to music, with key words (words chosen to encourage or to emphasize a good shot) added throughout. Forty-seven competitive female tennis players were randomly assigned to one of two groups. The highlight videotape group was shown the team highlight videotape, while the control group was shown a neutral videotape. All participants completed Vealey's (1986) State Sport-Confidence Inventory (SSCI) and the Tennis Self-Efficacy Scale for Doubles (TSESD), watched their assigned videotape and then retook the SSCI and TSESD. Participants then completed a set of open-ended questions about the procedure. The data was analyzed with a Group (2) x Level of skill (4) repeated measures design. The analysis of variance of the TSESD and SSCI scores did not reveal any significant differences between the scores of the treatment and control groups. But comments to the open-ended questions seemed to reveal increased feelings of sport confidence, motivation and arousal associated with the videotapes, suggesting that the team highlight videotapes may have potential as mental preparation tools. Additional research is warranted to further explore the potential uses of this new mental preparation tool.</description><creator>Bjorn, Kiersten</creator><contributor>Downey, Peggy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Video recordings -- Psychological aspects</subject><subject>Sports -- Psychological aspects</subject><subject>Self-efficacy</subject><subject>Women tennis players</subject><title>The effects of highlight videotapes on the self-efficacy and state sport-confidence of female tennis players</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm75m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999843t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n292n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Instruction at a distance is rapidly becoming one of the most widely used modes for teaching post-secondary learners. One of the distinctive characteristics of distance education is the emphasis on course development and the models of course development which have evolved. To date, however, the literature offers little understanding of the knowledge bases upon which current practice in distance education course development is based. Expertise in course development has not been characterized in any systematic way, and it is not known how novice and expert DE course developers differ in the way they conceptualize and go about course development. Even less is known about how course developers move toward expertise and from where they draw their understanding. The primary purpose of this study is to begin the investigation of these questions, based on data collected from multiple sources and contexts. Qualitative methods were used to collect and analyze data on the reflections of the course design process by nine participants. Participants varied in their experience level, the level of course they designed, and their role in the design process. Participants took part in a semi-structured interview and were asked to provide written responses to a practical design critique exercise. Themes or issues were allowed to emerge from the data, and were characterized along three main topics: the learner, design decisions, and evaluation. Differences between novices and more experienced participants were observed in their depth of understanding about the learner, the influence of theoretical constructs on their making design decisions, and the influence of context on the design process.</description><creator>Joly, Michelle</creator><contributor>Amundsen, Cheryl (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Lesson planning</subject><subject>Distance education</subject><title>Reflections on the course design process in distance education by practitioners with varying levels of experience</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171z939.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n292n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f300x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose was to determine the effect of Naproxen in attenuating the symptoms (muscle soreness level) and signs (plasma CK activity and muscular strength decrement) of delayed onset muscle soreness (DOMS). Twenty subjects were randomly assigned Naproxen (500 mg BID) or placebo in a double-blind, crossover design. Two testing phases, each 8 days in duration, were separated by a washout period of 7 days. Eccentric single-leg exercises were performed on Days 1, 3 and 4 to induce DOMS in the quadriceps muscles. Perception of muscle soreness, plasma CK, and knee extensor torque were evaluated throughout each phase. Following the eccentric exercise, plasma CK levels were similarly elevated in both Naproxen and placebo conditions. After DOMS had developed, Naproxen reduced the perception of soreness on Day 3 when muscle soreness was highest. Following treatments with Naproxen, peak quadriceps torque during leg extension at 60$ sp circ$/s was higher compared to placebo, however at higher velocity (180 and 300$ sp circ$/s) peak muscle torques were similar. The data indicate that therapeutic doses of Naproxen do not prevent CK release into the plasma but decreases the perception of muscle soreness and positively influences quadriceps peak torque.</description><creator>Lecomte, Jacqueline</creator><contributor>Montgomery, David L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Naproxen</subject><subject>Leg -- Muscles.</subject><subject>Myalgia</subject><title>Effect of Naproxen on delayed onset muscle soreness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w654b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f300x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cc60r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated the relationship between perspective taking and self-esteem in two groups of children between 7 and 12 years of age. Forty-six third graders (mean age = 8.3 years) and 25 sixth graders (means age = 11.4 years) completed a perspective-taking task, a locus of control scale, and a self-perception measure assessing global self-esteem and specific areas of competence. There was little empirical support for the hypotheses associating perspective taking with global self-esteem, locus of control, or competence. Competence domains were intercorrelated and associated with global self-esteem. Locus of control was significantly related to social acceptance and athletic competence. Sixth graders demonstrated superior perspective-taking ability while third graders reported higher levels of self-esteem and more satisfaction with their physical appearance. Gender was related only to behavioural conduct; girls were more satisfied with their overall behaviour. The implications of these findings for self-other development are discussed.</description><creator>Finn, Cindy A.</creator><contributor>Burack, Jacob A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Self-esteem in children</subject><title>The development of self : issues of self-esteem and perspective taking in middle childhood</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924d45q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc60r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b053v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines the issue of intercultural understanding. I explore the role played by language in constituting human subjectivity in accordance with the common insights of Ludwig Wittgenstein, Martin Heidegger, and Mikhail Mikhailovich Bakhtin, in order to: (1) affirm the complexity and fragility of the process of building understanding in fight of our immersion in specific cultural-linguistic worldviews; and (2) demonstrate that human beings are ontologically predisposed to achieve understanding, and that this ontological predisposition is enhanced by a constant and inescapable process of crossing "language boundaries" in daily life. I argue that the very manner of human induction into cultural-linguistic worldviews suggests the means by which intercultural understanding might best be fostered: through the bestowal of recognition and the cultivation of dialogical relationships. I assemble key elements of an assortment of different theories of intercultural understanding in which these techniques are assigned a central role; this exercise generates a Wittgensteinian "perspicuous representation" of the process of crafting intercultural understanding itself, and reveals the unique strengths of two convergent approaches in particular. Both the contemporary reinterpretation of the traditional ideal of intercultural understanding of the Gitxsan and Wet'suwet'en First Nations of northwestern British Columbia, and the recent writings of Charles Taylor on the subject of international human rights standards comprise variations of what I call the "shared horizons" paradigm. The great advantages of this paradigm are its ability to address the distortive effect exercised by power inequalities upon efforts to create intercultural understanding (demonstrated through a case study of the Gitzsan-Wet'suwet'en land claim), and its amenableness to a variety of distinct culture-specific normative justifications. The shared horizons approach does not offer a blueprint for achieving intercultural understanding, but rather, a modest and adaptable set of principles that can serve as the foundation for efforts to work toward the resolution of intercultural disagreements.</description><creator>Oman, Natalie Benva.</creator><contributor>Taylor, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Tully, James (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Kunz, Frank (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Political culture.</subject><subject>Culture -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Multiculturalism.</subject><subject>Ethnicity -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Intercultural communication -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Cultural pluralism.</subject><title>Sharing horizons : a paradigm for political accommodation in intercultural settings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0324736.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b053v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bn48f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>How HIV-related disease and medication affect the capacity to metabolize drugs was investigated in 110 HIV-positive patients including 43 with AIDS. The probe drugs acetaminophen (APAP), dextromethorphan (DM), and caffeine were used to assess the in vivo activities of glucuronidation/sulphation, cytochrome P450 (CYP) 2D6 and N-acetyltransferase 2 (NAT2). Genotypes, determined using PCR-based amplification and restriction fragment length analysis, were assigned for the latter 2 polymorphic pathways. Forty-five patients comprised the longitudinal component of the primarily cross sectional study. Urinary analyses for probe drugs and their metabolites and the compiled medical and treatment histories of the subjects were effected. The distribution of the NAT2 phenotype was unimodal and skewed toward slow acetylators as opposed to the 50:50 bimodal distribution expected. The genotype distribution was 52:48 slow:fast as expected. There were 18 discrepancies between genotype and phenotype: 12 slow acetylators with fast genotypes and 6 fast acetylators with slow genotypes. The role of disease progression in NAT2 expression was evident. Among patients whose genotype was fast the incidence of AIDS was higher in those with slow phenotypes (6/12) than those with fast phenotypes (2/14). Longitudinally, changes in phenotype from fast to slow were associated with progression of HIV-related disease. Neither APAP glucuronidation nor sulphation were affected by disease state or progression. The concomitant administration of dapsone appeared to decrease APAP-sulphation whereas zidovudine appeared to decrease APAP-glucuronidation. The data also indicated that APAP-glucuronidation may be reduced in patients who are underweight. The CYP2D6 genotype distribution between extensive (EM) and poor ( PM) metabolizers was 59:2 as expected. However, 2 of the patients with an EM genotype expressed a PM phenotype and 4 others were less extensive DM metabolizers than any of the patients being tre</description><creator>O'Neil, William M., 1953-</creator><contributor>Wainer, Irving W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Interindividual variation in drug metabolism among patients infected with human immunodeficiency virus and patients with acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698921f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn48f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483k94k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This qualitative interpretive inquiry investigates how mathematical meaning is constructed in a sixth grade classroom during one academic year in an English medium suburban school. Mathematical meaning is situated within Piaget's constructivist theory and Vygotsky's socio-cultural theory of the development of higher mental functions. Halliday's social theory of language use provides another theoretical framework for interpreting the daily interactions between the teacher and learners and among learners. Particular focus is on modality and the use of modal auxiliaries in teacher interrogative modals across the teaching of two strands, fractions and geometry. Data collected and analyzed includes 107 audio taped mathematics classes, participant observations of the teacher and six focal children over one school year and school artifacts such as the mathematics textbook and paper handouts. Findings indicate that the teacher used modal auxiliaries in both the fraction and geometry strands but more modals in the geometry strand. While there were similarities in the teacher's rejoinders across the two strands there were also some distinctions particular to each strand. Data sets suggest that mathematical meanings ultimately made by these learners are influenced by both personal and social factors. Teacher interrogative modals mediated understandings by encouraging multiple learner contributions which resulted in alternative strategies and thoughts being respected. Analysis of the task and activities, event flow of mathematical lessons influenced how the children perceived mathematics and how it should be accomplished Results indicate that these learners, understandings were unique and that through the power of questioning that encourages multiple learner perspectives educators may obtain insights into children's mathematical meaning making in classroom contexts.</description><creator>O'Connor, Peggy A.</creator><contributor>Maguire, Mary H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Mathematics -- Study and teaching (Elementary) -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Cognition in children.</subject><title>Construction of mathematical meaning in a 6th grade classroom : an analysis of modal auxiliaries in teacher interrogatives across the teaching of fractions and geometry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq261.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483k94k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r093</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An integrated process for education and sustainable community development has not been incorporated in countries of the North or the South. Although environmental education has been introduced into many curricula, this is only a beginning step compared to what is required to rebuild our understanding of development and set ourselves on more sustainable paths. The Barefoot College, in India has developed an education process for sustainable community development and has experience with reinventing the concepts of education and development. Their process has broad implications for educators, policy makers, academics and the general public in the South and North. The main objective of this study was to examine the essential characteristics of an education process which contribute to sustainable community development as exemplified by the Barefoot College. The participatory research data has been used to extend theoretical perspectives on sustainability and education and to reinforce new directions for research on education and sustainable communities. Students of the Barefoot College emerge as potential partners for the development of their communities. They learn skills to support themselves and to facilitate sustainable community development. Specific implications for applications of the Barefoot College process to Western education are suggested.</description><creator>O'Brien, Catherine, 1955-</creator><contributor>Ghosh, Ratna (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Community education -- India.</subject><title>Education for sustainable community development : Barefoot College, Tilonia, India</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698922q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r093</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n502t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Our primary goal in this thesis was to develop convenient methods for the synthesis of oligomeric polycyclics which could be ring-opened at elevated temperatures in the presence of a catalyst to give new classes of thermoset materials. A simple and commercially attractive approach was utilized to synthesize novolac type resins by reacting p-substituted phenols with formaldehyde using a cation exchange resin as catalyst in the presence of chlorobenzene as solvent. Novel oligomeric polycyclic carbonates were prepared by reacting the multifunctional phenol-formaldehyde resin with excess triphosgene under high dilution conditions. When the oligomeric polycyclic carbonates were heated at elevated temperatures using an initiator, a highly cross-linked network was obtained. In addition, the polycyclics were mixed with a commercial BPA polycarbonate and cured at different temperatures in the presence of a catalyst. When the mixture of BPA polycarbonate with 10 wt.% polycyclic carbonate was cured at 350ºC for 30 min. using a catalytic amount of lithium stearate, it gave a highly cross-linked network. Two series of polycyclic phosphonates were synthesized by reacting the oligomeric phenol-formaldehyde resins with phosphonic dichlorides under high dilution conditions in a polar aprotic solvent. The polycyclic phosphonates were similarly subjected to ring-opening polymerization at elevated temperatures in the presence of an initiator. The crosslinked phosphonates exhibited good flame retardance properties. Two classes of oligomeric siloxane resins were also synthesized by reacting the phenol-formaldehyde novolac type resins with dialkyl or diaryl dichloro, silanes under high dilution conditions. The formation of predominantly polycyclic siloxane structures was revealed by MALDI-TOF MS, Gradient HPLC and 1H NMR. Blends of commercial polysiloxane gums with different proportions of polycyclic siloxane resins were subjected to curing at 300ºC in the presence of KOH catalyst. Polysiloxane gums are highly unstable at 300ºC in the presence of a basic catalyst. However, the cross-linked polysiloxane gum at 30 wt.% loading of polycyclic siloxanes, was sufficiently stable at this temperature. A Bisphenol A dimer (o, o' methylene bridged) was synthesized by a single-pot reaction between formaldehyde and excess BPA using cation exchange resin catalyst. A few novel classes of oligomeric polycyclics with low melt viscosities were synthesized from this dimer under high dilution conditions. A series of co-polycarbonates of BPA were synthesized by the reaction of methylene bridged dimer with BPA and triphosgene. An alternative in-situ polymerization method was also developed to synthesize the BPA co-polycarbonates. These co-polymers containing cross-linkable cyclic carbonate moieties on the backbone, gave thermoset materials when cured at elevated temperatures in the presence of a catalyst. Low molecular weight poly(aryl ether sulfone)s end-capped with metallophthalocyanine moieties were prepared by reacting poly(aryl ether sulfone)s containing o-phthalonitrile end-groups with excess phthalonitrile and metals/metal salts in quinoline. These polymers were characterized in detail by using IR, UV-VIS, 1 H NMR and GPC techniques. Annealing studies on the polymers containing PcM end-groups were undertaken in order to investigate the occurrence of stacking of plithalocyanine rings in the melt. This study was conducted by using a Thermo-Gravimettic/Differential Thermal Analysis (TG/DTA) instrument.</description><creator>Mandal, Humayun.</creator><contributor>Hay, Allan S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Synthesis and characterization of novel polycyclic structures, precursors to high performance polymers Humayun Mandal.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3656954.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n502t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558f94z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The solubility of Zr-bearing minerals in peralkaline, H2O-saturated alkali aluminosilicate melts with or without added F reaches a maximum of about 4 and 3.5 wt.% ZrO2 respectively at approximately 57 wt.% SiO2. The saturating phase for melts with SiO2 content above this threshold is zircon. In the halogen-free experiments, the saturating phase for melts with lower silica content is wadeite (K2ZrSi 3O9), while ZrO2 crystallizes from melts with 1 wt.% added F. Experiments with Cl-bearing melts indicate no maximum solubility of Zr minerals; the solubility remains at 2 to 2.2 wt.% ZrO2 across a wide compositional range. The saturating phases in the Cl-bearing melts are the same as those of the F-bearing melts and the transition from ZrO 2 to zircon occurs at the same composition. The positive slope of the wadeite saturation curve on XZrO2-XSiO2 plots for the halogen-free melts suggests that increasing SiO2 activity increases the solubility of wadeite. Peralkaline Ti,Zr-bearing sodium aluminosilicate glasses have been analyzed by Raman spectroscopy to determine the effect of Cl on glass structure. The spectra of the Ti-bearing glasses show a significant difference between the Cl-free and the Cl-bearing composition. The Cl-free glass spectrum contains a strong, asymmetric peak at 900 cm--1 which is associated with Ti in five-fold coordination. This peak is shifted to higher frequency and becomes more symmetric with the addition of 0.3 wt.% Cl. Deconvolution of the high-frequency waveband suggests that differences between spectra result from the contribution of a peak at 945 cm--1. This peak is believed to be the result of Ti-O vibrations in fully-polymerized titanate tetrahedra. It is proposed that the addition of Cl destabilizes [5] Ti in favour of tetrahedral coordination as a result of competition between Cl and titanate groups for alkalis. 23Na NMR MAS analyses of a suite of Na-aluminosilicate glasses with Na/Al = 2 and varying SiO2 content has revealed a trend toward more negative chemical shift (greater shielding of the nucleus) as the glass structure becomes more polymerized, i.e. the average number of non-bridging oxygen atoms per tetrahedron (NBO/T) decreases. This trend is observed only for glasses with NBO/T ≤ 0.3. For more polymerized glasses no change in chemical shift is measured. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Marr, Robert A. (Robert Allen), 1965-</creator><contributor>Baker, Don R. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Williams-Jones, A. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>An investigation of Zr and Ti-bearing alkali aluminosilicate glasses : solubility experiments, Raman spectroscopy and 23Na NMR analyses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p645f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558f94z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67js949</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using a sociocultural theoretical framework, this study describes the learning experience of three re-entry adult women during their first year of academic study in a university. To situate the learning historically and culturally, cultural factors of both the students and the learning context are considered as well as interactions between the two over time. Information about the students' perspective of their experience was obtained through interviews conducted throughout the year and some textual responses are examined. The women's orientations toward learning are described using three theoretical constructs: transformative or reproductive approaches to learning, connected or separate modes of learning, and rhetorical or arhetorical approaches to text. Each of the women entered university with a different orientation to learning and each struggled to learn to respond in academically appropriate ways. In her interactions with the learning context, each experienced some disjunction and some support for her preferred ways of learning. One student, entering as an active and sophisticated learner, initially resisted academic tasks that required an arhetorical, reproductive, or decontextualized response. Another student, entering eager to apply her learning to her everyday life, responded with enthusiastic effort, compliant about meeting academic demands and sometimes suppressing her preference for rhetorical and connected learning. The third student, entering with a background as a reproductive and receptive learner, did not become engaged as a learner and avoided writing that required her to transform rather than reproduce ideas. By the end of the year, each student had shifted her pre-entry orientation, moving toward integration of her preferred approach to learning and academic ways. Writing was the activity where integration most often occurred. Changes in orientation occurred through a negotiation process. This study adds to our understanding of learning as a sociocultural process and provides a description of individuals in transition between one domain of situated cognition and another. It also shows different ways adult women respond to disjunction with their preferred ways of learning within a university setting and ways they integrate their own preferences with academic ways. Finally, it highlights students' need for guidance in achieving intersubjectivity in academic discourse as new participants in an academic community.</description><creator>Mar, Mary.</creator><contributor>Dillon, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Adult education of women.</subject><subject>Adult learning.</subject><subject>Women college students.</subject><title>Negotiating the transition of university learning : a descriptive study of the experience of three returning women students</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vj48k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67js949</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33550</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>