<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:28:53Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10125" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fm214</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Normal subjects were asked to localize parts of the concealed right resting arm and hand with the index finger of the left hand. They consistently pointed to loci which were between the real limb and the trunk of the body. Further experiments showed that these errors in localization are not affected by vibration of the tested limb but are increased by both self-produced movements and by a drastic decrease in the amount of sensory input to the tested limb as a result of a pressure cuff applied to the arm. After a normal subject looks either to his right or to his left, the perceived position of the limb approaches that direction. Non-congenitally blind subjects perceive their tested limb in a similar way to the way sighted subjects do, while congenitally blind subjects perceive their fingers to be further away from the body than they actually are. The similarities between the results of this study and phantom limb phenomena are pointed out. The results are discussed in terms of a central body schema, which might serve as a standard against which all perceived spatial relations between parts of the body are compared.</description><description>Des sujets normaux eurent pour tâche de localiser, avec l'index de la main gauche, certaines parties de la main et du bras droits, ceux-ci étant cadrés et en position de repos. Ils pointèrent de façon consistante à des endroits situés entre le vrai membre et le tronc du corps. Des expériences ultérieures montrèrent que ces erreurs de localisation ne sont pas affectées par la vibration du membre testé, et qu'elles augmentent lors de mouvements produits par le sujet ou lors d'une diminution drastique de l'information sensorielle due à une pression soutenue appliquée au bras. Lorsqu'un sujet normal regarde à sa droite ou à sa gauche, la position perçue du membre suit la même direction. Des sujets aveugles non-congénitaux répondent de façon similaire aux sujets normaux, alors que des aveugles congénitaux perçoivent leurs doigts comme étant plus loin du corps qu'ils le sont en réalité. Des similarités entre les résultats de cette étude et le phénomène des membres fant6mes sont signalées. Les résultats son discutés en termes d'un schéma corporel central servant d'étalon vis-a-vis duquel toutes les relations spatiales perçues entre les différentes parties du corps sont comparées.</description><creator>Gross, Yigal.</creator><contributor>Melzack, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1974</date><subject>Psychology.</subject><title>Central and peripheral determinants of localization of body parts.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g58n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fm214</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bf780</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pathological condition whereby localised areas of pleural thickening become radio-opaque through calcification has been recognised for at least 250 years. Early reports of these calcified pleural plaques focussed on case descriptions and on their possible association with tuberculosis, chest wounds, empyema and pleuresy. The clinical implications of them have however remained obscure and although some surgeons in the 1930's excised the calcified plaques from the pleura, the well documented lack of symptoms in persons with pleural calcification progressively rendered them of 'academic interest'. [...]</description><creator>Gibbs, Graham W.</creator><contributor>McDonald, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1974</date><subject>Epidemiology and Health.</subject><title>The epidemiology of pleural calcification.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311s43m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bf780</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pt67z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une méthodologie rationelle pour la purification et l'étude des protéines membranaires à l'état actif et non-dénaturé est décrite. Utilisant ces méthodes, le cytochrome b559, protéine assez délicate et liée solidement aux membranes a été purifiée complètement à partir de membranes grana de chloroplastes d'épinards avec un rendement total élevé. Le cytochrome b559 pur est un complexe lipoprotéinique contenant 41% de protéines et 56% (±6%) de lipides, qui consistent en quatre lipides distincts. Il contient huit petites sous-unités polypeptidiques ayant un poids moléculaire de 5600 ± 1000 Daltons par molécule (monomer). Une méthode est décrite pour la solubilisation complète et non-destructive des protéines membranaires. [...]</description><description>A rational methodology for the purification and study of active, undenatured membrane proteins is described. Using these methods cytochrome b559, a relatively "delicate", tightly-bound membrane protein, was completely purified from spinach chloroplast grana membranes with high overall recovery. Pure cytochrome b559 was a lipoprotein complex containing 41% protein and 56 (±6) % lipid (consisting of four distal lipids). It contained 8 small polypeptide subunits (mol. wt. = 5,600 ± 1,000 Daltons) per molecule (monomer). A method is described for the complete, non-destructive solubilisation of membrane proteins. This method was successfully used with beef heart mitochondria, spinach chloroplast grana, red cell ghosts, mouse Ehrlich ascites tumour cell membranes and Pseudomonad B-16 bacterial membranes. Eight cytochromes and four enzyme activities were shown to be quantitatively stable in the medium used. No protein was encountered which was irreversibly inactivated by the medium. Resolution of the proteins is described. The discovery of "autoreduction" of pure cytochrome f is reported. It was shown to be a light-dependent phenomenon inhibited by the photosynthetic inhibitor 3-(3,4-dichlorophenyl)-1, 1-dimethyl urea. A method is described for the essay of microgram quantities of the nonionic detergent Triton X-l00.</description><creator>Garewal, Harinder S.</creator><contributor>Wasserman, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1974</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Isolation, purification and study of membrane proteins: 1. Complete purification and properties of spinach chloroplast cytochrome b-559. 2. A medium and procedure for the non-destructive solubilisation of membrane proteins.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tc39t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pt67z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b909b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La stimulation du colliculus supérieur et du cortex visuel qui sont impliqués dans différents aspects de la perception visuelle, a révélé la convergence de voies efférentes de ces deux régions au niveau neuronal dans le cortex, moteur chez le chat anesthésié au chloralose. Les cellules dans cette région présentent des champs récepteurs visuels bien définis à la stimulation visuelle punctiforme, de même qu'une sensibilité aux mouvements et une certaine spécificité directionnelle. L'investigation de la distribution topographique des afférences visuelles au cortex moteur a révélé que lés cellules recevant des afférences cutanées des régions proximales des membres et de la région du tronc possèdent également des champs récepteurs visuels (72%) tandis que les unités recevant des influx des région distales du membre antérieur recoivent beaucoup moins (15%) d'information visuelle. Ces données soutiennent la masse croissante de documents tendant à montrer une organisation différentielle des systèmes neuronaux contrôlant la musculature distale et de ceux controlant la musculature de l'axe corporel.</description><description>Stimulation of the Superior Colliculus and Visual Cortex, which are involved in d1fferent aspects of visual perception, revealed convergence of efferents from these two regions at the neuronal level in the motor cortex of chloralose anesthetized cats. Cells in this area displayed well-defined visual receptive. fields to punctiform visual stimulation, along with movement sensitivity and some directional specificity. Investigation of the topographica1 distribution of visual input to the motor cortex revealed that cells with cutaneous input from the proximal areas of the extremities and the trunk are also possess visual receptive fields (72%), whereas units with cutaneous input from the distal fore limb area receive much less (15%) visual information. These findings support the growing body of evidence pointing to a differential organizat1on of the neural systems controlling the distal musculature and those controlling the musculature of the body axis.</description><creator>Garcia-Rill, Edgar.</creator><contributor>Dubrovsky, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1974</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Functional characteristics and topographical organization of visual input to motor cortex of cat.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720g89w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b909b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cn95d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aprés ouverture de la cage thoracique une méthode originale nous permet l'analyse simultanée de l'azote au niveau de la trachée et des voies aériennes périphériques. L'action cardiaque favorise la mixique entre l'air inspiré et alvéolaire produisant un déplacement vers les premières générations bronchiques de l'interface gaz-gaz lors de l'inspiration de même qu'elle permet une accumulation 5 fois plus rapide qu'en post mortem de gaz alvéolaire à un niveau donné durant l'apnée. Nous avons analysé cette relation coeur-poumon selon les constantes de temps régionales, la mixique convective, et la diffusion de Taylor. Bien qu'au débit inspiratoire employé nous obtenions un étalement linéaire substantielle (5 cm) le volume totale de mixique entre la trachée et les bronches de 4 mm demeure faible (&lt; 15 ml). C'est donc l'inhomogénéité ventilatoire marquée que nous avons mis en evidence au niveau des segments pulmonaires sous-tendus par des voies aériennes de diamètre inferieur à 3 mm qui détermine de façon prédominante la pente du plateau alvéolaire.</description><description>A new method for sampling gases within the bronchial tree of open chested animals was developed to measure N2 concentration simultaneously in the trachea and a peripheral airway during single breaths of 02. Mixing between inspired and alveolar gas was greatly enhanced by cardiac action (i) during inspiration, so that the front between the two gases extended into major airways, and (ii) during breath holding when the build up of alveolar gas in an airway was five times faster than under similar conditions post mortem. The effect of the heart action on the lung was analyzed in terms of regional time constants, convective mixing and Taylor diffusion. Inspiratory flow (200 ml/sec) between trachea and 4 mm airways produced little mixing in terms of volume (&lt; 15 ml) although linear spread was substantial (5 cm). The slope of the alveolar plateau is determined predominantly by a marked ventilation inhomogeneity existing within lung segments distal to 3 mm airways.</description><creator>Engel, Ludwig A.</creator><contributor>Joubert, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Menkes, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1974</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Ventilation distribution and gas mixing in the lung studied by intrapulmonary gas sampling.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m495b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cn95d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd3760753</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aprés homogénéisation du foie d'un rat normal (N), l'activité responsable de la formation du, facteur VII est localisée dans le surnageant post-mitochondrial (S30). Ni la fraction microsomique (P100) ni le surnageant post-microsomique (S100) ne possèdent d'activité, mais on recouvre l'activité aprés recombination des fraction P100 et S100. Dans le cas de rats rendus déficients en vitamine K (VKD), ou préalablement traités avec des anticoagulants du type coumarinque (CA), les fractions S30 ou P100 et S100 ne possèdent pas d'activité. Le facteur VII est produit après incubation de la fraction S100 (N) avec la fraction P100 (N, VKD, CA), cependant que la combinaison S100 (VKD, CA) avec P100 (N) reste inactive. L'anomalie produite par une déficience en vitamine K ou une administration d'anticoagulants coumarinique semble donc prendre la forme de l'absence ou de l'inactivité d'une composante de la fraction S100 du foie de rat. [...]</description><description>Factor VII forming activity is localized in the post-mitochondrial supernatant (S30) of normal rat liver (N) homogenates. Neither the microsomal (P100) nor post-microsomal supernatant (S100) gives activity, but activity is recovered upon recombination of P100 and S100. Corresponding S30, P100 or S100 from either vitamin K deficient (VKD) or coumarin anticoagulant pretreated (CA) rat liver, show no activity. Incubation of S100 (N), in the presence of P100 (N, VKD or CA) forms factor VII, while S100 (VKD or CA) incubated in the presence of P100 (N) is inactive. The primary defect therefore in vitamin K deficiency or after coumarin anticoagulant pretreatment, resides in the absence or inactivity of a component of the S100 in either vitamin K deficient or coumarin anticoagulant pretreated rat livers. An enzyme-substrate relation is indicated where the S100 contains the enzyme and the P100 the substrate. The activity from S100 (N) is purified by 270-fo1d after fractionation with 40-50% saturated (NH4)2SO4 and column chromatography on DEAE Sephadex A-25. The substrate for this enzyme is localized in the microsomal fraction (P100) by specific antibody techniques. This antigenic material reacts with immunological identity with either prothrombrin or the functionally inactive prothrombin-like substance (FIPL) found in plasma after vitamin K deficiency, but unlike prothrombrin (but similar to FIPL) the substrate in the P100, is not adsorbed on BaSO4. [...]</description><creator>Dworkind, Jack.</creator><contributor>Lowenthal, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1974</date><subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</subject><title>Vitamin K1 and plasma clotting factor formation: an in vitro system for the study of intracellular localization and release.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pq91p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd3760753</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05ff92b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this historical review is essentially to record the results of experimental investigations into the effect of addition agents on the electrodeposition of metals, particularly the effect of gelatine on the deposition of copper from acid copper sulphate solutions, since it is with this type of system that the majority of the recorded work has been concerned. The survey covers a period of approximately 40 years, during which time a large body or data has been accumulated and numerous theories advanced, both involving many contradictions.[...]</description><creator>Gauvin, William H.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Engineering.</subject><title>The effect of gelatin on cathode polarization during the electrodeposition of copper. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rm380.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05ff92b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vx09s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Gertrude Margaret Lowthian Bell, historian, traveller, archaeologist, author, and king-maker, lives today in the memory of the people of Iraq who are fighting to preserve that independence as a nation which she helped them to achieve. [...] In this thesis I shall discuss Gertrude Bell as a literary artist and show why her writings on the Middle East provide for the average reader an excellent introduction to that little known region. [...]</description><creator>Fry, Margaret Exie.</creator><contributor>Noad, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Bell, Gertrude Lowthian, 1868-1926 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Gertrude Bell as a literary artist.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rr922.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vx09s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42nb959</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Results are reported of investigations made on celery grown in sand cultures and fed nutrient solutionsmade up of nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium in various combinations. The experiment was of a 3 x 3 x 3 design. Medium applications of nitrogen when the plants were six inches and half grown produced increased yields. Low applications on plants approaching maturity gave good results. High phosphorus applications on six-inch and approaching maturity plants produced increased celery yields and helped to check pithiness in the plants approaching maturity. For six-inch and hal~ grown plants, a medium level of potash gave increased yields and for plants approaching maturity a high application was necessary. Treatments had a significant effect on the uptake of nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium into the plant tissue. The uptake showed somewhat similar relations to their effect on yield. Nitrogen deficiency symptoms were apparent in the low nitrogen treatments. </description><creator>Filman, Conrad Colton.</creator><contributor>Murray, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Celery</subject><title>Sand culture experiments with celery. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021j20z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nb959</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Horticulture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xf85t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The experimental research described in this thesis was undertaken by the writer to determine the efficiency of corduroy blanket and flotation concentration processes, followed by amalgamation of the two concentrates, in an attempt to develop a suitable method for recovering the gold in Lake Rowan ore. The work was carried on under the direction of Professor J. W. Bell of the Department of Mining and Metallurgy, McGill University. Acknowledgment is also made of assistance rendered by Professor G. Sproule and Mr. D. O'Shaughnessy. [...]</description><creator>Faucher, J. A. Roland.</creator><contributor>Bell, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Mining Engineering.</subject><title>Treatment of Lake Rowan gold ore. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn404.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xf85t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x4428</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] The recent Public Health report on Fundamental Cancer Research (1939) stressed the research objectives in the field of cancer. It was pointed out that there are two fundamental problems involved: One, the causal aspect of the cancer problem; the other the formal genesis - the the factors responsible for the nature of the cancer cells and their uncontrolled growth [...]. Thus, the fundamental problem of cancer is directly associated with an understanding of the processes of growth, the metabolism and functions of normal cells. It is with this broad aspect of the general cancer problem in mind that the investigation of behaviour of normal and malignant cells of the frog in vitro was undertaken. The following are the main objectives of the investigation: 1. To obtain a medium best suited to the growth of normal and malignant tissues, and observations of comparative shapes and manner of growth under similar conditions. 2. To obtain pure cultures of normal kidney epithelium and compare their metabolic properties in response to respiratory poisons, cobra venom and various extracts with those of pure cultures of malignant cells. 3. To study the cytological characters of normal and malignant cells, their reaction with other cells in the colonies, the mechanism of tissue formation and cell proliferation. 4. To investigate tolerence to high and low temperature, toxicity, hydrogen ion concentration, permeability and other factors. [...]</description><creator>Entin, Martin A.</creator><contributor>Huskins, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Hystology.</subject><subject>Developmenal cytology.</subject><title>Cytology and growth of normal and malignant tissue.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fc305.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x4428</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395wb555</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Following selective 3H-thymidine labelling of guinea pig and rat femoral and tibial marrow cells in vivo, one group of animals were sacrificed at intervals from l hour to 7 days thereafter, while the others received antigens subcutaneously into the left hind foot pads 2 - 3 days later and were sacrificed at intervals from 6 hours to 5 days thereafter. The popliteal lymph nodes and other issues were prepared for DNA-radioassay or for radioautography. The DNA-radioassay studies demonstrated a definite export of labelled cells from the marrow into the normal and antigen-stimulated popliteal lymph nodes. Radioauto-graphs revealed that the majority of these cells were small lymphocytes which migrated continuously into the nodes, within which they were distributed widely. These lymphocytes had a brief stay within normal nodes but appeared for a longer time in antigen-stimulated nodes. Some labelled large blast cells and labelled plasma cells were observed within the nodes.</description><description>Les cellules de la moelle osseuse du tibia et du fémur ont été sélectivement marquées par une injection, in vivo, de thymidine tritlés chez le cobaye et le rat. Les animaux experimentaux ont été répartis en 2 groupes: dans l'un des groupes; les animaux ont été sacrifiés à des intervalles de temps compris entre l heure et 7 jours après l'injection le thymidine. Ceux de l'autre groupe ont reçu des antigènes en injection sous-cutanée dans la pelote digitale du pied postérieur gauche. Ils ont été sacrifiés à des intervalles de temps compris entre 6 heures et 5 jours après l'injection de thymidine. Les ganglions lymphatiques poplités et les autres tissus ont été préparés d'une part pour la mesure de la radioactivité du DNA, d'autre part pour l'autoradiographie. [...]</description><creator>Brahim, Feisal.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1974</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>The migration of bone marrow lymphocytes to normal antigenically stimulated popiteal lymph nodes: radioautographic studies and DNA radioassay following selective bone marrow labelling with 3H-thymidine in vivo.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bm378.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wb555</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m496m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Structural-functional correlative studies were carried out in Sprague-Dawley rats to investigate the effects of three catecholamines, isoproterenol, norepinephrine and epinephrine, on myocardium. The findings were grouped in three categories: 1. Continuous intravenous infusion of 4-6 microgram/100 g body weight/ minute isoproterenol and norepinephrine administration produced irreversible lesions while epinephrine produced reversible cardiac muscle cell changes. Contraction band formation characterized the effect of isoproterenol, whereas myofilament lysis followed norepinephrine infusion. 2. Structural findings were related to changes in coronary microcirculation. A rise in blood pressure following norepinephrine was accompanied by an increased transendothelial passage of diffusion tracers, horseradish peroxidase and ferritin, whereas a drop in blood pressure following isoproterenol administration resulted in decreased transendothelial tracer passage. This phenomenon was reversible with the return normal levels of blood pressure. Epinephrine induced temporarily an increase in blood pressure with no changes in tracer localization. [...]</description><description>Cette étude comparative, à la fois morphologique et fonctionnelle, fut effectuée afin de vérfier l'effet de l'administration des catécholamines isoprotérénol, norépinéphrine et épinéphrine sur le myocarde du rat Sprague-Dawley. Les observations furent groupées en trois catégories: 1. L'infusion intraveineuse continue d'isoprotérénol et de norépinéphrine, à la dose de 4-6 microgram/100 g de poids corporel/minute produit des lésions myocardiques irréversibles alors que l'administration d'épinéphrine à la même dose, produit des changements myocardiques réversibles. L'effet de l'isoprotérénol se caractérise par la formation de bandes de contraction anarchique alors que l'administration de norépïnéphrine est surtout suivie de lésions myofilamentaires, lytiques.</description><creator>Boutet, Michel.</creator><contributor>More, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1974</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Etude morphologique et functionnelle des lesions myocardiques provoquees par l'administration de catecholamines chez le rat.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505349z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m496m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591c25v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La discrimination de consonnes explosives fut étudiée avec une référence particulière pour la distinction du facteur vocal/non-vocal de la parole naturelle, par rapport au moment d'initiation vocale. Quatre expériences sont décrites: 1) la discrimination des explosives vocales et non-vocales par des enfants atteints de surdité et des enfants d'audition normale. 2) la discrimination d'explosives vocales et non-vocales par des adultes d'audition normale. 3) l'entraînement d'enfants atteints de surdité pour améliorer leur discrimination d'explosives vocales et non-vocales. 4) les effets de l'entraînement de la discrimination sur la production d'explosives par les enfants atteints de surdité. Les résultats indiquèrent que: 1) les enfants atteints de surdité n'établissent pas les limites vocales/non-vocales comme les enfants d'audition normale, 2) les enfants et les adultes d'audition normale établissent les limites vocales/non-vocales d'une façon sonblable, 3) les enfants atteints de surdité peuvent être entraînés à discriminer les limites de vocalisation comme les sujets d'audition normale, 4) l'entraînement de la discrimination peut donner lieu à des changements dans la production d'explosives vocales/non-vocales par les enfants atteints de surdité. Les implications de ces résultats sont discutés présentement.</description><description>The discrimination of stop consonants was studied, with particular emphasis on the voiced-voiceless distinction of natural speech in relation to voice onset time (VOT). Four experiments are reported: (1) discrimination of voiced-voiceless stops by hearing-impaired and normal-hearing children; (2) discrimination of voiced-voiceless stops by hearing adults; (3) training hearing-impaired children to improve their discrimination of voiced and voiceless stops; and (4) the effects of discrimination training upon the production of stops by hearing-impaired children. Results 1ndicated: (1) hearing-impaired children do not establish voiced-voiceless boundaries as hearing children do; (2) normal-hearing children and adults set voiced-voiceless boundaries similarly; (3) hearing-impaired children can be trained to set voicing boundaries as hearing listeners do; and (4) discrimination training may result in changes in production of voiced and voiceless stops by hearing-impaired children. The implications of these results are discussed.</description><creator>Bennett, Clinton W.</creator><contributor>Ling, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1974</date><subject>Human Communication Disorders.</subject><title>Discrimination of stop consonants by severely hearing-impaired children.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vb67c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c25v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Human Communication Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515r51f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A heterogeneous basic complex and the surrounding and intruding rocks are described. There are few outcrops and much alteration so the description is brief and some of the conclusions based on it must be conjectural. The basic complex is discussed and interpreted as having been a layered massif or massifs, which together with the older rocks have been folded and much altered. This conclusion is reached partly on an analogy with a fairly common type of massif which is characterized as having a considerable horizontal extent in comparison with its depth, or thickness, but for which there is no general name. The conclusion is also based on certain structures which, as interpreted here, are believed to have formed in a near horizontal attitude though now in a near vertical attitude. Of three structures described, one is not uncommon in other layered massifs; the second occurs in at least three other places; and the third has not hitherto been described. These three structures show which was their top side and are used to determine which way a sequence faces [...] Many questions which arise from this discussion as to the trends of differentiation are not considered here. Mineral occurrences may be important and are discussed, though none of economic importance have been discovered. [...]</description><creator>Black, J. M. (James Murray), 1912-</creator><contributor>Osborne, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The Bell River igneous complex.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g59x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515r51f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r618p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La thyroide Auto-immune expérimentale a été induite chez le cobaye par l'injection d'extrait de thyroide et l'adjuvant de Freund. L'incorporation des matières carboniques radioactives dans les lipides seriques a été observée durant l'administration d'une surcharge graisseuse exogene ainsi que durant l'augmentation des lipides seriques endogenes resultant des injections de ttiiodothyronine. Il a été a observé que les cobayes thyroiditiques demontrent une capacite reduite pour la synthese et l'elimination des lipides sanguines meme dans l'état euthyroide. L'incapacite d'elimination des lipides sanguines mene a l'augmentation des taux de cholesterol et triglycerides lorsque l'incapacite d'elimination est accompagnée par une surcharge graisseuse.</description><description>Experimental Autoimmune Thyroiditis has been induced in gulnea pigs by injection of crude thyroid extract in Freund's adjuvant and alterations in certain aspects of lipid metabolism studied. Incorporation of labe1led carbon compounds into serum lipids was observed during the administration of an exogenous lipid load and during endogenous serum lipid increases resulting from the injection of Triiodothyronine. It has been observed that thyroiditic guinea pigs display a reduced capacity to synthesize and clear lipids from the blood stream even in the apparently euthyroid state. Impaired ability to clear serum lipids leads to increases in circulating cholesterol and triglyceride levels whenever this metabolic pathway is challenged by an increased amount of lipids in the circulation.</description><creator>Abbott, Robert T.</creator><contributor>Reesal, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1974</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Biochemical changes in experimental autoimmune thyroiditis.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j850c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r618p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tq00k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Agars from five major groups of agarophytes (Rhodophyceae) have been fractionated on DEAE Sephadex A-50 (Cl-). The results indicate that agar is a complex mixture of polysaccharides all having the same backbone structure but masked to a variable degree with charged groups, ranging from the essentially neutral agarose to highly sulfated galactans. The agarases which degrade agarose have been isolated from marine and soil bacteria. The mode of action of these agarases and the end products of the hydrolysis have been investigated. Purified bacterial agarases con be classified into two major groups, being specific for either the beta linkages, P. atlantica and strain 3A agarases; or a linkages, strain GJ1B agarase, in agarose. A proposal has been made for a practical definition of agar and agarose.</description><description>L'agar de cinq importants groupes d'agarophytes (Rhodophyceae) a été fractionné sur DEAE Sephadex A-50(Cl-). Les résultats obtenus indiquent que l'agar est un mélange complexe de polysaccharides qui possèdent tous la même structure de base masquée à des degrés différents par des groupements chargés; lesquels peuvent varier de degrés essentiellement neutres, comme dans le cas de l'agarose, à des degrés hautement chargés, comme dans le cas des galactanes sulfatés. Des agarases qui dégradent l'agarose ont été isolées des bactéries du sol et de la mer. Les modes d'action de ces agarases et les produits de leur hydrolyse ont été recherchés. Les agarases bactériennes purifiées peuvent être classifiées en deux groupes selon leur activité. Un premier groupe d'agarases est spécifique pour le liens alpha de l'agarose et provient des bactéries P. atlantica et 3A. Dans un deuxième groupe l'on retrouve l'agarase isolée de la bactérie GJ1B qui attaque les liens a de l'agarose. Finalement l'on suggère une définition pratique de l'agar et de l'agarose.</description><creator>Young, Kwan S.</creator><contributor>Yaphe, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology.</subject><title>An enzymatic and chemical study of agar.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999968w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tq00k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jx591</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vagal and mechanical aspects or ventilatory control have been studied. The behavior or vagal inspiratory inhibitory influence following lung inflations was assessed by determining the excitatory influence required to terminate apnea. It was found that, following inflation, vagal inhibitory influence declines rapidly and then attains a plateau which varies with lung volume. The duration of apnea was found to be critically affected by the course of chemical events following inflation and is therefore, unsuitable for quantitating the vagal inhibitory influence. An alternate method is described based on comparison of the unloaded tidal volume with the inspiratory pressure wave generated following occlusion of the airway at FRC. The method was validated using a technique of rapid vagal cooling. A method for quantifying the contribution of changes in blood gas tensions to rapid ventilatory compensation following elastic loading is described. These changes were found to totally account for the phenomenon in cats.</description><creator>Younes, Magdy K.</creator><contributor>Milic-Emili, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Studies on the control of ventilation.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311s44w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jx591</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jf18s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An accurate and rapid method for the determination of hemicellulose both in woody and in succulent tissues is seriously needed at the present time. Such a method is desired by many workers in such widely different fields as plant physiology, microbiology, entomology, and animal nutrition. The methods now being used, although quite inadequate, will be briefly examined. [...]</description><creator>Armstrong, John Grant.</creator><contributor>DeLong, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the hemicellulose fraction of plant tissue.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494c38p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jf18s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kd81z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une protéine (SCP) de grand pouvoir immunogène a été extraite, avec NaCl 0.lM, de la moelle épinière de boeuf, protéine qui a été localisée uniquement dans le tissu nerveux. L'analyse immuno-électrophorétique démontra trois formes moléculaires de SCP, dont deux furent retenues à l'intérieur du sac à dialyse. Ces deux formes ont démontré des mobilités électrophorétiques d'une beta1-globuline (beta1-SCP) et d'une gamma-globuline (gamma-SCP) tandis que la forme dialysable la mobilite d'une gamma-globuline. Beta1-SCP a été isolé par absorption en volume des extraits de la moelle épinière de boeuf avec DEAE-Sephadex A-50, suivie par chromatographie sur cellulose CM-52, gamma-SCP a été isolé par chromatographie des extraits sur CM-Sephadex C-25. Des cochons d'inde prealablement traités avec beta1-SCP ou gamma-SCP purifiés n'ont pas développé d'allergie encéphalomyélite après l'injection de moelle épinière our de protéine encéphalitogénique. L'immunoglobuline anti-SCP serait responsable du pouvoir protecteur de SCP.</description><description>A highly immunogenic spinal cord protein (SCP) was extracted from bovine spinal cord with 0.l M sodium chloride. SCP was detected only in bovine nervous tissues. It was also detected in human, rabbit, rat, and mouse spinal cord extracts. Immunoelectrophoretic analyses revealed that bovine SCP occurred in three molecular forms. Two forms are large enough to be retained by dialysis tubing and have the electrophoretic mobilities of a beta1-globulin (beta1-SCP) and a gamma-globulin (gamma-SCP) respectively. The dialysable form of the antigen has an electrophoretic mobility of a gamma-globulin. Beta1-SCP was isolated by batch absorption of bovine cord extracts with DEAESephadex A-50, followed by chromatography on CM-52 cellulose. Gamma-SCP was purified by chromatography of bovine spinal cord extracts on CM-Sephadex C-25. Pretreatment of guinea pigs with purified beta1-SCP or gamma-SCP prevented them from developing experimental allergic encephalomyelitis when they were challenged with bovine spinal cord or bovine encephalitogenic protein. The protective activity of the SCP is assumed to be mediated by anti-SCP immunoglobulin.</description><creator>Yo, Sui-Lan.</creator><contributor>MacPherson, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Isolation and characterization of a spinal cord protein.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mf88n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kd81z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hc87h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is known that CNS mechanisms for inhibition of sympathetic activity exist, but the underlying circuitry and cellular mechanisms are largely unknown. As an attempt to clarify these points, the inhibitory effect, on single antidromically identified sympathetic preganglionic neurons, of electrical stimulation of high threshold somatic and visceral afferents, descending fibres in the lateral funiculus of the spinal cord and depressor area of the medulla oblongata, near the obex, have been examined. With extracellular recording, inhibition was seen as a depression of spontaneous or glutamate-evoked firing and of antidromic soma invasion, unrelated to a previous excitation. All the inputs studied could inhibit glutamate-evoked activity and, less frequently, in jury discharge and antidromic soma invasion. These results suggest the possibility that the inhibition of sympathetic activity is, at least in part, by a postsynaptic mechanism operating on the sympathetic preganglionic neuron membrane. This inhibition was strychnine-resistant and picrotoxin sensitive.</description><description>On connait l'existence au niveau du SNC, de mécanismes inhibiteurs de l'activité sympathique mais on ignore en général leur organisation et leurs mécanismes cellulaires. Dans le but d'élucider ces points, on éxamina l'action inhibitrice sur des neurones sympathiques préganglionaires identifies antidromiquement, de stimulation électrique de voies afférentes somatiques et viscérales à seuil éléve des fibres descendantes du funiculus latéral de la moelle épinière et de la région dépressive du bulbe près de l'obex. Lors de l'enregistrement, extracellulaire l'inhibition se manifesta par une diminution de décharges spontanées ou produites par le glutamate et par stimulation antidromique. Tous les inputs etudiés pouvaient inhibiter l'activité produite par le glutamate, et moins fréquemment, les déscharges résultant de "injury" et de la stimulation antidromique. Ces résultats suggerent que l'inhibition de l'activité sympathique est la résultat d'un mécanisme postsynaptique agissant sur la membrane du neurone sympathique préganglionaire. Cette inhibition s'avéra strychnine-résistante et picrotoxine-sensible.</description><creator>Wyszogrodski, Issie.</creator><contributor>Polosa, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Central inhibition in the sympathetic nervous system.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g563x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hc87h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579w38h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The rate of linoleate esterification by rabbit reticulocytes was twice that of normocytes, based on cellular lipid levels. Incorporation of glucose and glycerol carbons into lipids was minimal, indicating limited de nova synthesis. Esterification occurred primarily in the plasma membranes, with a small but consistent incorporation into the mitochondria and none into the microsomes. Thus, the intracellular membranes could not explain the increased reticulocyte esterification. Esterification was independent of ATP levels and not affected by exogenous lysolecithin. ATP in human normocytes was elevated to twice the initial level by a 5 hr incubation with glucose, adenine and pyruvate or inosine in a 32 mM Pi medium. Combination of pyruvate and inosine at 96 mM Pi tripled ATP levels within 2 hr. Pyruvate stimulates the hexose monophosphate shunt by mediating reoxidation of NADPH through a partially NADPH linked lactate dehydrogenase. Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficient erythrocyte ATP levels were not elevated by incubation with glucose, adenine and pyruvate, but were when inosine replaced pyruvate. ATP and 2,3-DPG were elevated to three times the fresh cell levels in 6-week preserved erythrocytes incubated with the glucose, adenine, inosine- 96 mM Pi medium.</description><description>Le taux d'estérification du linoléate par les réticulocytes de lapin est 2 fois plus rapide que par les normocytes considérant le niveau élevé des lipides dans les réticulocytes. L'incorporation de glucose et de glycérol dans les lipides est minime indiquant que la synthèse des lipides de novo est limitée. La séparation des réticulocytes en membranes, mitochondries et microsomes a révélé que l'estérification se situe dans les membranes avec une faible mais consistente incorporation dans les mitochondries; toutefois, ceci ne peut expliquer l'augmentation de l'estérification dans les réticulocytes. L'estérification est indépendante du niveau d'ATP et non affectée par la lysolécithine de source exogène. L'ATP dans les normocytes humains s'élève a 2 fois le niveau initial par une incubation de 5 heures avec du glucose, de l'adénine et du pyruvate ou de l'inosine dans un milieu comprenant 32 mM de Pi. Une combinaison de pyruvate et d'inosine à 96 mM de Pi triple le niveau d'ATP en 2 heures. Le pyruvate stimule le shunt des pentoses par réoxidation de NADPH partiellement lié à la LDH. Le niveau d'ATP dans les érythrocytes déficient en G-6-PD n'est par élevé par l'incubation avec du glucose, de l'adénine et du pyruvate. L'ATP et le 2, 3-DPG des érythrocytes conservés durant 6 semaines sont élevés jusqu'a 3 fois le niveau des globules frais après incubation avec du glucose, de l'adénine, de l'inosine et 96 mM de Pi.</description><creator>Warrendorf, Elizabeth M.</creator><contributor>Rubinstein, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Some aspects of lipid and nucleotide metabolism in the erythrocyte.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p337c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579w38h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33s061v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present investigation has attempted to examine the cellular differentiation events which occur within T and B lymphocyte cell lines during the course of antigen-induced humoral antibody formation in the mouse. The data have supported the conclusion that the T cell line acts throughout all stages of the primary and secondary humoral antibody response to quantitatively but not qualitatively amplify the production of antibody by members of the B cell line. This amplification was demonstrated whether sheep erythrocytes or brucellin was employed as the immunizing stimulus. The data have also supported the hypothesis that the sequential production of humoral antibody of the IgM and IgG classes following antigenic stimulation occurs as a consequence of an 'intrinsic' switchover in the capacity of individual members of the B cell line to synthesize mu and gamma heavy chain class determinants.</description><description>Dans ce travail, on a tenté d'étudier les événements de différentiation cellulaire qui se produisent au sein des lignées lymphocytaires T et B durant le processus de synthèse d'anticorps humoraux en réponse à une stimulation antigénique chez la souris. Les résultats obtenus ont appuyé la conclusion que la lignée cellulaire T joue un rôle à tous les stades de la réponse humorale primaire et secondaire, rôle qui consiste à amplifier quantitativement mais non qualitativement la production d'anticorps par des membres de la lignée cellulaire B. Cette amplification a été démontrée que l'immunisation se fasse à l'aide soit de globules rouges de mouton soit de brucelline. Les résultats ont également appuyé l'hypothèse que la production séquentielle d'anticorps humoraux de type IgM et IgG en réponse à une stimulation antigénique résulte d'une modification intrinsèque dans la capacité de membres individuels de la lignée B de synthétiser les déterminants spécifiques de classe mu et gamma des chaines lourdes.</description><creator>Tingle, Aubrey J.</creator><contributor>Freedman, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Cellular differentiation events during humoral antibody formation in the mouse - a kinetic approach.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r619z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s061v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50h029p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The urinary excretion of total etiocholanolone and four delta5-3beta-hydroxysteroids viz, pregnenediol, 17alpha-hydroxy-pregnenolone, pregnenetriol and dehydroepiandrosterone isolated from the glucuronide and sulphate fractions by sequential hydrolysis, have been compared between normotensive controls and hypertensive subjects. Normotensive subjects excreted significantly more etiocholanolone, pregnenetriol and dehydroepiandrosterone sulphates while no difference was observed in the rest of the steroids. Upon the intravenous injection of pregnenolone-14C and pregnenolone-3H-sulphate, hypertensives excreted in their urine more l4C and less 3H radioactivity than. normotensives. The urinary production rates of pregnenolone and pregnenolone sulphate calculated from pregnenediol-14C-glucuronide and pregnenediol- 3H-sulphate respectively were both higher in hypertensives but only the latter difference was significant. The peripheral conversion of pregnenolone to pregnenolone sulphate in hypertensives was higher while the reverse conversion lower when compared with normotensives. The 3H/14C ratios of the pregnenediol conjugates and 17alpha-hydroxypregnenolone sulphate were higher than that injected in normotensives while hypertensives showed lower ratios.</description><creator>Tan, Eng L.</creator><contributor>Nowaczynski, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Metabolism of pregnenolone and its sulphate in normotensive control subject and patients with benign essential hypertension.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s7951.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h029p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tv580</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:24:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Un nouveau peptide lipolytique-mélanotropique (G-75/2) ayant une activité mélanotropique de 1.9 x 10^7 Unités/gm et une activité lipolytique a la dose minimale effective de 0.1 microgram dans les cellules adipeuses du lapin, a été isolé des hypophyses humaines. Il fut inactif chez le rat et on a noté une faible activité lipolytique dans le tissu adipeux humain. G-75/2 ne contient pas de Tryptophane ou de Methionine, ce qui le distingue du corps actif classique (-Met-Glu-His-Phe-Arg-Try-Gly-) trouvé chez toutes les substances 1ipolytique connues. Ce peptide est une protéine pure, a un poids moleculaire d'environ 1l,000, un point isoélectrique de 8.5 et d'Alanine comme N-terminal.</description><description>A new lipolytic-melanotropic peptide (G-75/2) having an MSH activity of 1.9 x 10^7 Units/gm and a lipolytic activity at an M.E.D. of 0.1 microgram in rabbit fat cells, has been isolated from human pituitary. It was inactive in the rat and only slightly lipolytic in human adipose tissue. G-75/2 had no Tryptophan or Methionine, therefore lacked the classical "active core (-Met-Glu-His-Phe-Arg-Try-Gly-)" found in all previously characterized lipolytic-melanotropic substances. This peptide was of pure protein content, had a molecular height of about 11,000, isoelectric point of 8.5 and Alanine as the N-terminal amino acid.</description><creator>Smith, Glennell R.</creator><contributor>Genest, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>A new lipolytic-melanotropic peptide from human pituitary.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9355980.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tv580</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10150</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>