<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:50:05Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25200" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rf19b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines a primary question raised by both Aristotle  and Thomas Aquinas: What constitutes the beginning of a human being? Aristotle and  Aquinas raise this question for very different reasons. Modern critical commentators  revisit it for their own reasons, namely for the purposes of ethical debates  surrounding conception and abortion. They frequently attribute the notions of  delayed ensoulment and quickening to Aristotle. Through examination of the primary  texts, I demonstrate that this attribution is erroneous. Aristotle contends that  ensoulment is substantially complete at conception, though subject to gradual  actualization throughout the lifespan of a human being; while Thomas suggests that  conception is a process, requiring several substantial changes before a human soul  is infused. I argue that Aquinas adapts Aristotle in accordance with his Christian  theological commitments, and modern commentators follow him to develop their own  notions of delayed ensoulment and quickening.</description><creator>Austin, Kathleen J.</creator><contributor>Deslauriers, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Kirby, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Human reproduction -- Religious aspects -- Christianity -- History of doctrines.</subject><subject>Thomas, Aquinas, Saint, 1225?-1274</subject><subject>Soul -- Christianity -- History of doctrines</subject><subject>Augustine, Saint, Bishop of Hippo</subject><title>Aristotle, Aquinas, and the history of quickening</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b672g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rf19b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35t917c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to examine what a national public  science educator does when attempting to educate the general public. This  investigation was conducted with the goal of expanding the literature on the  treatment of science in multimedia to include descriptive work on whom the general  public goes to learn science. The science educator's work in radio, television, and  print were explored through interview and content analyses with themes and patterns  emerging. The educator appeared to apply a loose formula of keeping a finger on the  public's pulse, exhibiting scientific rigor, using variables and techniques such as  props and demonstrations, including elements of popular culture, inserting  interesting facts, injecting humor, and telling stories.</description><creator>Armeni, Christina</creator><contributor>Alters, Brian J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Science -- Study and teaching</subject><subject>Schwarcz, Joseph A.</subject><subject>Popular education</subject><subject>Non-formal education</subject><title>From whom the general public chooses to learn science : a case study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r1552.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35t917c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jk990</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study focuses on the first three historiographic novels in  a projected quartet---The Virgin in the Garden, Still Life, and Babel Tower---which  historicises what we now refer to as the "crises in representation" that  occurred over the late 50s and into the 60s. I trace the figure of the  Undifferentiated Narrator, both as it is referred to and read by the characters in  the world of the novels, and as it is invoked or broken up by the forms of the  narratives themselves. My methodology is outlined in the first section, wherein I place  a reading of Byatt's work within the context of contemporary debate regarding the  ethics of representation. Then I treat each novel separately, since each is a  self-contained novelistic experiment with a different form of literary  realism. In the end I conclude that Byatt's use of polyvocality and  multiple histories help us to come to terms with nostalgia for the self-present  self, by showing us that it haunts every narrative (and anti-narrative) and is a  coercive figure in every life.</description><creator>Quarrie, Cynthia</creator><contributor>Ohlin, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Byatt, A. S. (Antonia Susan), 1936- -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Laminations : nostalgia and the undifferentiated narrator in three novels by A.S.Byatt</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903056j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jk990</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jr811</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Meredith Monk's multi-modal work incorporates theatre, dance,  film and music. Her claim is that music and specifically the voice lie at the heart  of all her work. At this core, she uses auditory gesture in wordless vocal lines to  express her meaning, usually the hidden narrative of emotion, to enable universal  intelligibility. This thesis uses the concept of gestus in the sense of Brecht and  Weill as an instrument to examine vocal gesture in three scenes in Monk's opera  ATLAS, and then relates it to her compositional process. It also studies gestus in  connection with Monk's biography and the influences on her especially Emile  Jaques-Dalcroze and Antonin Artaud.</description><creator>Pym, Rebekah</creator><contributor>Levitz, Tamara (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Monk, Meredith</subject><subject>Gesture</subject><title>The voice as gesture in Meredith Monk's ATLAS /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977v49m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jr811</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752h31k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the late 1990s, the Ministere de l'Education du Quebec (MEQ)  undertook a reform program that would reframe the educational system. Technology and  pedagogy were seen as needing realignment to better meet a student-centered,  technology-driven, lifelong learning experience. The New Reform as this new  framework is known will be fully implemented by 2008 and educators are its pivotal  agents. With Information and Communications Technologies being central to the new  reform, this qualitative study looks at educator use of the most widely used  Internet application, electronic mail. Very little research has looked at how  pervasive electronic mail has become among educators and how it is affecting their  multidirectional, multilayered roles as educators. Data originate from respondent  electronic mail, a literature review, and the author's personal experience.  Outcomes, reached through inductive analysis, reveal that educators continue to  experience difficulty manipulating electronic mail technology even though they  appreciate its multiple advantages. How electronic mail can facilitate networked  communication and educator teamwork to better translate the MEQ's new reform  successfully is the focus of this study. Implications derived from the outcomes are  discussed in view of enhancing ongoing contributions by Quebec  educators.</description><creator>McLaughlin, Louise A.</creator><contributor>Milligan, Christopher (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Electronic mail messages</subject><subject>Educational innovations</subject><title>The influence of electronic mail on communication patterns among educators /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x4626.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752h31k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jp30f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This investigation examined the effect of changes in ball  properties and cognitive demands on the performance of adolescent male athletes of  varying levels of soccer expertise. Participants moved through a course under two  conditions: decision and no decision, and with two types of soccer balls, regular  and futsal. The experts moved through the courses with both balls significantly  faster than the novices and had a lower percentage of control errors with the  regular ball but not with the futsal ball. Both groups performed significantly  slower under the decision condition, but no differences were found between  conditions in the percentage of control errors made. The novices made a  significantly smaller percentage of control errors with the futsal ball than the  regular ball, although the type of ball had no effect on their performance times.  These results suggest that the experts display better soccer skills and cognition  than the novices and that the properties of the futsal ball appear to reduce the  technical demands for the novices.</description><creator>McConnell, Kevin</creator><contributor>Neil, Graham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Soccer -- Psychological aspects</subject><subject>Cognition in adolescence</subject><subject>Soccer players</subject><title>Effect of changes in ball properties and cognitive demands on the performance of adolescent male athletes of varying levels of soccer expertise</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r156b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jp30f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hv939</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Liberation and critical theories of education believe in the  political nature of all types of education. 'The school' in the third world is  'oppressive' because it creates and perpetuates 'western-style' class hierarchies.  As such, nothing good will be secured at the marginalized groups without a drastic  shift in their socioeconomic and political condition. Consciousness-raising  non-formal adult education is 'liberation education' aimed specifically for the  disenfranchised rural poor. It helps them develop skills to discover the oppressive  elements in their lives, become aware of the causes of their destitution, and  empower them to take action to transform their realities. Previous studies have  demonstrated such programs have been successful in emancipating the poor; this  evaluative study of liberation education in southern Ethiopia has also proven to  help the target population develop a critical consciousness regarding their  impoverished and oppressed conditions and help empower them to work towards changing  their lives.</description><creator>Gilman, Lori-Ann</creator><contributor>Ghosh, Ratna (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Education -- Philosophy</subject><subject>Popular education -- Philosophy</subject><subject>Popular education -- Ethiopia</subject><subject>Ethiopia -- Social conditions</subject><subject>Critical pedagogy</subject><title>The application of liberation pedagogy : have members of rural development committees in southern Ethiopia become critically aware of their poverty after participating in consciousness-raising education?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nm070.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hv939</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451j138</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years there has been a worldwide recognition of the  disparity of HIV treatment available in the West and in Sub-Saharan Africa. The West  African nation of Senegal was early to implement measures that allowed for the  distribution of highly effective anti-HIV therapy known as Antiretroviral (ARV)  therapy to a limited number of patients. This thesis explores how patients living in  Senegal who are infected with HIV have engaged in various negotiations to obtain  access to treatment and other resources to meet the needs posed by their infection.  These negotiations are framed by various historically embedded notions of how to  engage relationships in the search for care. Strategies are also shaped by the  biopolitically-laden discourse that guides the distribution of ARV therapy. This  thesis traces the structure, evolution, and effects of patients' strategic  negotiations in response to the introduction of this therapeutic  technology.</description><creator>Gilbert, Hannah</creator><contributor>Lock, Margaret (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>AIDS (Disease) -- Patients -- Senegal.</subject><subject>AIDS (Disease) -- Treatment -- Senegal.</subject><subject>AIDS (Disease) -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>HIV-positive persons -- Senegal.</subject><title>Rallying resources : strategies of therapeutic engagement among patients living with HIV in Senegal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117p516.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451j138</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qs657</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Anne de France, or Anne de Beaujeu by marriage, was present in  history books long before she was the subject of literary studies. Regent of  France's kingdom during her brother's, Charles the VIII's, minority (1484--1491), we  know her mostly for successfully having measured herself up to her political  opponents by calling the Etats Generaux and ruling the kingdom with calculating  tactfulness. However, she also leaves a literary legacy, her Enseignements, which  she writes for her only daughter Susanne in 1504 or 1505, and which are published in  1521 in Lyon by the editor and bookseller Le Prince. Having not enjoyed great literary fortune, this text contains  many interesting attributes. To this effect, a rhetoric reading of the Enseignements  can and must be done. Even though the text recycles many of the period's  conventions, a study of the argumentative devices, most notably through the  interaction of the exempla and the counter-exempla , generates a certain virtue  ethic that is especially noticeable through the analysis of the identity defining  instance, "je".</description><creator>Cordeiro, Debby</creator><contributor>Desrosiers-Bonin, Diane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Anne, of France, 1461-1522 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Mirrors in literature</subject><title>La rhéthorique des miroirs : exemplarité dans Les enseignements d'Anne de France</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35695185.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qs657</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c815v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis argues that there is an emerging field of  international cultural policy in Canada informed by ongoing changes in the pattern  of policy making. Caught between old nationalist discourses of a unified Canadian  nation, and the rapidly changing global environment, the Canadian cultural policy  makers struggle to make Canadian culture survive both at home and abroad. In this  research, international cultural policy will refer to cultural policy designed by  the Department of Foreign Affairs and International Trade and the Department of  Canadian Heritage. Moving beyond a simple empirical analysis of policy, this thesis  adopts Tony Bennett's definition of the governmentalization of culture applying a  Foucauldian governmental rationality line of thinking. Looking at how cultural  creation is being governed through discursive formations, various  conceptualisations, techniques, institutional arrangements, participating actors and  government initiatives, this thesis maps out international cultural policy as an  emerging governmental practice in Canada.</description><creator>Cochina, Claudia</creator><contributor>Hamilton, Sheryl (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Cultural policy</subject><subject>Canada -- Cultural policy</subject><title>International cultural policy in Canada : exploring dialogues in an emerging practice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sg95c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c815v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613mz14s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the late 1970s many empty buildings in Montreal have been  adapted for residential purposes. The main focus of this thesis is to document and  analyse the most representative examples of these projects in order to define the  nature and results of the adaptive-use practice in Montreal. Due to complexity of the field, the framework for analysis must  be flexible enough to apply to different contexts and building types, yet firm  enough to solve the perpetual dilemmas intrinsic to adaptive-use design. The  attitude of this research is that the best way to do this is to learn from  architectural, social, and political history---indeed how these types of histories  interrelate to form a continuum of popular and professional opinion. The study starts the examination of the main preservationist and  adaptive-use methods with the discussion of preservationist terminology and origins  of preservationist theories in Europe. It traces them as they come to North America,  examines the roots of adaptive use for residential purposes in Manhattan, and  follows the phenomenon as it has appeared in Montreal from the sixties to present.  After tracking preservation theory and practice until this point, the parameters for  determining what is a successful adaptive-use project become clearer. (Abstract  shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Vujadinovic, Milenko</creator><contributor>Anderson, Bruce (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Buildings -- Remodeling for other use -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Case studies</subject><subject>Industrial buildings -- Remodeling for other use -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Case studies</subject><subject>Architecture, Domestic -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Historic preservation -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><title>Preserving old buildings : adaptive use for residential purposes in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s082b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613mz14s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544bp85h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Now and Forever is a thesis in two parts: a twelve-minute piece  for orchestra and a text providing an analysis of the piece. The orchestra consists  of two flutes (flute 2 doubling piccolo), two oboes, two clarinets in B-flat, two  bassoons, four horns in F, two trumpets in C, two tenor trombones, one bass  trombone, two percussion and strings. The work features the use of an original text  as the underlying program, the use of golden section proportions as a principal  organisational device, a rising semitone motive as the foundation for melodic,  harmonic and registral development, and the intermittent appearance of  micropolyphonic textures. In some passages, the harmonic series is the basis of  pitch field development, notably in section VI, which consists of an orchestral  evocation of the sounds of an aeolian harp.</description><creator>Dehler, Elizabeth</creator><contributor>Ferguson, Sean (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Orchestral music -- Scores</subject><title>Now and forever</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182k762.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bp85h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n03g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The increasingly stringent requirements of today's communication  systems and portable devices are imposing two challenges on the design of  Analog-to-Digital Converters (ADC) and delta-sigma modulators (DeltaSigmaM)  architecture in particular. The first is the extension of the input frequency range to  include applications where the input bandwidth exceeds the 1 MHz  range. This challenge in extending the operational speed of DeltaSigmaM  is further rendered more complicated by the ever shrinking transistor dimension. As  predicted by the Semiconductor Industry Association (SIA) Roadmap for CMOS  technology, the transistor dimension will reach 0.05 mum in 2011. With this dramatic  shrink in the transistor length, and as a result in the supply voltage, device  modelling becomes ambiguous and circuit non-idealities more pronounced. The design  of the main analog building blocks that minimize the time-to-market is therefore  becoming very complicated. These two issues will be addressed in this thesis, namely a new  design method that will minimize the design cycle of delta-sigma analog-to-digital  converters (DeltaSigma ADCs) intended for high-speed applications. This method will  be demonstrated efficient in the implementation of two state-of-the-art modulators  in terms of performance using a widely adopted figure of merit. The validity of the top-down design methodology was verified  through the fabrication of two prototype integrated circuits (ICs), both in TSMC  0.18 mum CMOS technology. In the first chip, a single-bit, fourth-order DeltaSigma  ADC was implemented achieving more than 12-bit resolution. The second chip further  validated the methodology to include higher resolution, in the range of 13 bits,  multi-bit DeltaSigma ADCs. The experimental results from both prototype ICs closely  mimic the system-level behavior of the designed modulator.</description><creator>Safi-Harab, Mouna</creator><contributor>Roberts, Gordon W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Low-power low-voltage high-speed delta-sigma analog-to-digital converters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d4831.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n03g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g082b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The reconstruction of 3D surface models from incomplete data is  a fundamental problem in computer vision, and has been investigated for years. The  goal of the research presented in this thesis is to examine novel ways of solving  the problem of surface reconstruction from 3D point data sets. The approach to  surface recovery presented here combines two different philosophies, that of a  parametric reconstruction approach, and that of a geometric flow reconstruction  approach. Many algorithms for surface recovery are based on either one of the two  types of approaches, but few have attempted to bring the two together in order to  combine their advantages. This thesis introduces a novel hybrid algorithm for surface  recovery. The motivation is to demonstrate that the inclusion of structural  information through the use of local data parameterization can improve the behaviour  of flow-based algorithms for surface reconstruction. The key ideas are to tailor a  curvature consistency algorithm to the case of a set of points in 3D and to then  incorporate a flux maximizing geometric flow for surface reconstruction. This hybrid  method is specifically designed to preserve discontinuities in 3D, to be robust to  noise, and to reconstruct objects with arbitrary topologies. The approach is  illustrated with experimental results on a variety of data sets.</description><creator>Savadjiev, Peter</creator><contributor>Ferrie, F. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Siddiqi, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Surface recovery from three-dimensional point data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w538r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g082b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mq366</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ferrite grain refinement is one of the best methods to improve  the mechanical properties of low carbon steels. The present work is a continuation of this past research and was  conducted using a torsion machine. The aim was to improve the understanding of the  strain levels and deformation temperatures required for UFF formation, as well as  the influence of silicon addition. Two steels were studied: a low silicon (LSi)  steel containing 0.09% C-0.02%Si-1.3%Mn-0.07%Al-0.036%Nb and a high silicon (HSi)  steel containing 0.09%C-0.48%Si-1.2%Mn-0.02%Al-0.038%Nb. In the hot torsion tests,  both steels were deformed to 5 true strain levels: 2, 2.5, 3.2, 3.5 and 4 at a  strain rate of 3/s. The Ar3 temperatures for the two steels were measured as  758°C for LSi and 776°C for HSi. It was found that at a strain level  of 4 or above, UFF was formed. The optimum deformation temperature was just above  the Ar3 and the higher the strain, the finer the ferrite grain size achieved. The  results indicated that silicon addition impedes ferrite grain size refinement.</description><creator>Sheng, Yongwei Will, 1967-</creator><contributor>Jonas, J. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Ultrafine ferrite production in low carbon steel by means of dynamic strain-induced transformation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547s03w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mq366</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741s38g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The vestibulo-ocular reflex (VOR) serves to stabilize retinal images of targets during head angular and/or linear displacements by moving the eyes at an appropriate speed and in a direction that compensates for head movements. Contrary to traditional understandings, we now know that the VOR function is not hard-wired; rather it is deeply modified by the context in which eye movements occur. Among these contexts, the fixation context is the main focus of this thesis. It has been proven, both experimentally and through geometric relationships, that the VOR gain (the ratio of eye velocity to head velocity) modulates with fixation distance. Furthermore, depending on the target distance from each eye, the VOR gain can be different for each eye. We present a bilateral model that accounts for VOR response modulations with fixation distance and is also compatible with anatomical and physiological facts. All the previous models that have been proposed for viewing-distance-related VOR response modulations use black-box mathematical representations to modulate the reflex, providing no insight into the underlying anatomy and physiology. This thesis is an attempt to show that VOR fixation-distance-dependent modifications can be achieved automatically through the physiological characteristics of the second-order neurons in the vestibular nuclei (VN), without having to apply any specific vergence encoding signals. The model presented here relies on the nonlinear behavior of the specific cells in the VN, which has been observed in prior experimental studies. The model reproduces the VOR gain that is observed at different vergence levels. It also allows for modifications in VOR dynamics by applying changes to the sensitivities of the VN cells that lie within the system loops.</description><creator>Khojasteh-Lakelayeh, Elham</creator><contributor>Galiana, H. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Modeling fixation-distance-related modulations in the vestibulo-ocular reflex (VOR)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r856p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741s38g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62f8854</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The simulation of mathematical models of mechanical systems with  closed kinematic chains involves the solution to a system of highly coupled  differential-algebraic equations. The numerical stiffness of these systems calls for  small time steps in order to insure accuracy. Real-time and interactive forward  simulations tend to be difficult to achieve for such systems, especially for large  multi-body systems with multiple links and many kinematic loops. One way to overcome  the time constraint is to distribute the load onto several  processors. The modular formulation of mathematical models is attractive  because existing models may be assembled to create different topologies, e.g.  cooperative robotic systems. Conversely, a given robotic topology may be broken into  smaller topologies with simpler dynamics. Moreover, parallel-kinematics machines bear inherent spatial  parallelism. This feature is exploited in this thesis, in which we examine the  formulation of such modular and distributed models and evaluate their performance as  applied to mechanical systems with closed kinematic chains. Three general  undistributed formulation methods are specialized to cope with distribution and  modularity and applied to a three-degree-of-freedom planar parallel manipulator to  generate distributed dynamics models. Finally, the results of case studies are reported, and a  comparison is made to highlight the salient features of each method.</description><creator>Khan, Waseem A.</creator><contributor>Angeles, Jorge (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Distributed dynamics of systems with closed kinematic chains</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182k78m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f8854</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r158w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Containment structures for aircraft engines must withstand  impacts of failed engine components, which may be traveling at extremely high  velocities. Therefore, the design of such structures requires a thorough knowledge  of material behaviour at high rates of deformation. It is well known that at strain  rates above 102 s-1, the yield stress of metals may be significantly different than  at quasi-static rates. In addition, material fracture under dynamic loading can also  differ from that at slower rates due to manifestation of different failure  mechanisms. The purpose of this study was to gain an understanding and determine the  constitutive behaviour and failure criteria for several metals used in the aerospace  industry; specifically Aluminium (6061-T6), Titanium (Ti-6Al-4V) and Stainless Steel  (Nitronic 33). An extensive procedure for determining the constitutive response and  ductility limits of those materials, at quasi-static and dynamic strain rates, was  developed relying on laboratory experiments and computational simulations. The  Johnson-Cook constitutive model coupled with a critical equivalent plastic strain  failure criterion was used in simulating the material. Results of the different  tests and simulations indicated the success of the modeling process for the 6061-T6  and Ti-6Al-4V, however considerable discrepancies were observed when simulating the  behaviour of Nitronic 33 using the Johnson-Cook model. The multiplicative nature of  the model, and the high strain hardening of this material were among the reasons the  Johnson-Cook is unable to represent the material when simulating events with high  strain and high strain rates such as punching.</description><creator>Dabboussi, Wael</creator><contributor>Nemes, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>High strain rate deformation and fracture of engineering materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k789c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r158w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25x925t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new process was developed to fabricate particulate metal  matrix composites (MMCs). The process involves two steps: (1) forming a particulate  porous compact, and (2) introducing molten magnesium or magnesium alloy (AZ91) into  the channel network by a spontaneous infiltration technique. A uniform distribution of SiC particulates in magnesium matrix  was achieved. Microsegregation existed in composites when the particle size of  reinforcement was 38 mum and 22 mum, however, when the particle size of  reinforcement was 12 mum, the microsegregation was eliminated. The interfacial reaction between SiC and Mg studied by Scanning  Electron Microscopy (SEM), microanalysis, and X-Ray Diffraction (XRD) techniques  showed that, Mg reacted with Si or SiO2 to form Mg2Si, Mg 2Si was present at the  surface of SiC after precipitation, resulting in improved wettability between Mg and  SiC. As a result of this interfacial reaction, the infiltration process became  spontaneous. The infiltration process was related to the infiltration temperature,  SiC particle size and matrix chemistry. Increasing the infiltration temperature,  decreasing the particle size of SiC resulted in more successful  infiltration. Mechanical testing conducted on composites revealed that the  hardness and Ultimate Tensile Strength (UTS) of composites increased with the  decrease of particle size of SiC and corresponded to an increase of the volume  fraction of SiC.</description><creator>Chen, Huiqiang, 1967-</creator><contributor>Drew, Robin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Fabrication of magnesium matrix composites using a spontaneous infiltration technique</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268576g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25x925t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zx119</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work focused on assessing the feasibility of using an acid  hydrolysed whey permeate for ethanol production from the yeast Saccharomyces  cerevisiae. Various temperatures, acid types and concentrations for lactose  hydrolysis were studied. The use of pressurised CO2 was also investigated. For all  conditions studied using mineral acids, the glucose produced was less than the  stoichiometric amount. During the hydrolysis using CO2, both glucose and galactose  were consumed in side reactions. These results were explained. A linear model was  developed, and satisfactorily described the rate of lactose hydrolysis for all acid  types tested. The fermentability of the hydrolysates produced was assessed in  shake flasks using the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae. For three hydrolysis  conditions, complete consumption of the hexoses present occurred. The hydrolysates  produced at low acid concentrations and temperatures and with a higher initial pH  were more readily fermented. Increasing the number of transfers decreased the  negative effect of a high temperature of hydrolysis, but not the effect of a high  acid concentration.</description><creator>Côté, Annie, 1975-</creator><contributor>Brown, Wayne (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Cameron, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Ethanol production from an acid hydrolysed concentrated whey permeate</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g083m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zx119</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257f798</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the goals of the Mackenzie GEWEX Study (MAGS) is to model  the critical components of the water and energy cycles that affect the climate of  the Mackenzie Basin. The land surface - hydrological model WATCLASS is used to  simulate the energy and water transports at and below the surface. Atmospheric input  to WATCLASS is provided by the output from the atmospheric model GEM. There may be  significant uncertainties in the GEM incoming solar radiation due largely to  difficulties in simulating clouds and their radiative properties. The question that  we address is how these uncertainties affect the simulation of the energy and water  budgets of this northern river watershed. To assess this sensitivity, two series of two WATCLASS model  runs are compared. Both runs are driven by atmospheric data from GEM for the  1998--99 water-year, but in the second run shortwave radiation fluxes retrieved from  satellite measurements replace the GEM fluxes. Land cover differs in the two series  of runs and so provides an assessment of the sensitivity to vegetation variability.  Results show that the atmospheric model overestimates the incoming solar radiation  field by 36%. This results in an increase in the basin annual average surface  temperature of about 1°C and an overestimation in net longwave radiation,  and sensible and latent heat fluxes. Snowmelt starts earlier with a decreased first  snowmelt peak in runoff and discharge hydrographs. The overall consequence is an  annual discharge underestimation.</description><creator>Voisin, Nathalie, 1978-</creator><contributor>Leighton, H. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><subject>Hydrology.</subject><title>Sensitivity of the hydrology and the energy budget of the Mackenzie River Basin to uncertainties in solar radiation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tv72j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257f798</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rf203</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:13:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Optimum nutritional levels for most commercial hardwoods of  eastern Canada are unknown. This thesis dealt with the development of a method to  determine nutritional standards using within site variation in tree growth and  foliar chemistry. To this end, sugar maple (n = 87) and red maple (n = 39) trees  were sampled in summer 2001 at the Station de biologie des Laurentides. Leaves were  sampled for nutrients (N, P, K, Ca, Mg and Mn) and tree stems were measured for  determination of basal area growth (BAG). Similar measurements for trees sampled  annually during 1995--2001 were also used to measure the effect of annual variation  on nutritional standards. A boundary line approach was used to assess tree growth  response to nutrition using nutrient concentrations and Compositional Nutrient  Diagnosis (CND) scores as predicting variables. A Basal Area Growth Index (BAGI) was  computed using the live crown ratio to correct for the effect of stand density on  BAG. An iterative and unbiased protocol was also developed to eliminate outliers.  Optimum, critical and optimal range levels were derived from quadratic models  significant at P &lt; 0.15.</description><creator>Vizcayno Soto, Gabriel</creator><contributor>Cote, Benoit (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Sugar maple -- Growth.</subject><subject>Red maple -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Sugar maple -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Foliar diagnosis.</subject><subject>Red maple -- Growth.</subject><title>Development of a method to determine tree species nutritional standards from natural variation in tree growth and leaf chemistry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dw15c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rf203</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nx586</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examined the economics of producing high value  bio-ingredients such as chitin and carotenoprotein from shrimp processing waste in  Newfoundland. The shrimp waste in the province was estimated to be at least 37000  tons annually. A survey of shrimp processing plants in the province revealed that  the waste generated was relatively pure with little or no foreign material. The  economic engineering approach was employed to estimate the production cost of chitin  and carotenoprotein at the laboratory and pilot scale levels. At the laboratory  scale where 480 kg/year of raw material (shrimp waste) was processed, the cost of  chitin and carotenoprotein was found to be $159/kg and $315/kg, respectively. At the  pilot scale level, the cost of chitin and carotenoprotem was estimated to be $125/kg  and $244/kg, respectively based on volume of 4800 kg/year. Sensitivity analysis was  carried out to establish the cost variations due to changes in the quantity of  starting raw material, labor cost and cost of laboratory supplies (chemicals and  enzymes). The cost of chitin and caroteinoprotein showed a decreasing trend with  increasing scale of production. An expert opinion survey was conducted with a  selected panel of 9 experts from the shrimp processing industry, chitin related  industry, and the academic/research community to determine the potential market of  the high-grade chitin/chitosan in Canada. The results showed that the health and  nutraceutical industry is the most promising niche for high-grade chit in/chitosan.  The survey also indicated that potential market would be high in Ontario and Quebec  due to the presence of large health and nutraceutical companies in the big  metropolitan areas of these regions.</description><creator>Tackie, Richard</creator><contributor>Simpson, B. K. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Gunjal, Kisan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Chitosan.</subject><subject>Shrimp industry -- By-products -- Economic aspects -- Newfoundland and Labrador.</subject><subject>Chitin.</subject><title>Economics of bio-ingredients production from shrimp processing waste in Newfoundland</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289j645.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nx586</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236266q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Peripheral vein infusion thrombophlebitis (PVIT) is  a complication of intravenous therapy. We hypothesized that inherited thrombophilia  may increase the risk of PVIT. Purpose. In preparation for a multi-center study of our  hypothesis, we conducted a pilot study to estimate PVIT incidence, measure the  prevalence of inherited thrombophilia, and pilot test the study  procedures. Methods. A prospective case-control study of 25 cases (patients  with PVIT) matched on catheter duration to 25 controls. PVIT risk factors and  inherited thrombophilia were assessed. Results. PVIT incidence was 14 per 1000 catheter-days. There  were no significant differences in the prevalence of the inherited thrombophilia  disorders among cases and controls (32% vs. 48%). A previous history of PVIT was  noted in 4 cases compared to 0 controls. Procedural problems included a high rate of  non-consent and inadequate communication with the laboratory. Conclusions. Though an association between PVIT and inherited  thrombophilia was not shown, a previous history of PVIT among cases supports a  biological predisposition to PVIT. Our pilot study did provide useful data on PVIT  incidence and procedural issues used to design a more definitive study of inherited  thrombophilia and PVIT.</description><creator>Tagalakis, Vasiliki</creator><contributor>Kahn, Susan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>The role of inherited thrombophilia in peripheral vein infusion thrombophlebitis : a pilot study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741s39r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236266q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73pw72d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fluid-saturated experiments were conducted to investigate the  elemental partitioning of boron among melt, aqueous vapor and aqueous liquid (brine)  in the system haplogranite-H2O-NaCl at 800°C and 100 MPa. Time series  experiments demonstrate that equilibrium was reached in about 90 hours. Runs  conducted with low-salinity fluids (0--2 wt. % NaCl) show that boron partitions  preferentially into the vapor phase over the haplogranitic melt, whereas results  from high-salinity (60--80 wt. % NaCI) experiments suggest that boron has no  preference for the brine or the melt. Excluding data from runs that may have been  conducted beneath the solvus (2 and 60 wt. % NaCl), the bulk fluidmelt partition  coefficients for low-salinity and high-salinity experiments are DB(vapor/melt) =  4.79 +/- 1.52 and DB (brine/melt) = 1.07 +/- 0.34, respectively. Integrating these  results yielded DB(vapor/brine) = 4.48 +/- 2.03, suggesting that boron partitions  preferentially into the vapor over the brine in a boiling hydrothermal fluid. This  may have important implications for mineral exploration, as boron is commonly  associated with certain metallic mineral deposits as tourmaline.</description><creator>Schatz, Oliver J.</creator><contributor>Stix, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Williams-Jones, A. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>Experimental investigation of boron partitioning among melt, brine and vapor in the system haplogranite-H₂O-NaCl at 800⁰C and 100 MPa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qs66h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73pw72d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25225</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>