<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:26:13Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34275" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237ht48v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, an indirect effect of sulfuric acid particles on Arctic climate during the cold season, from November to May, is investigated. Specifically, the research is focused on the alteration of the air mass dehydration rate due to sulfuric acid aerosols. These anthropogenic aerosols differ from natural aerosols by their poor ability to nucleate ice, their strong solubility and their reduced homogeneous freezing temperature when internally mixed with other compounds. Simulations performed with three column models and analysis of observed data at Alert (1991--94) are used to investigate an indirect effect of these aerosols on climate: the dehydration - greenhouse feedback. Each model covers different levels of physical basis and realism of their simulation. Two scenarios have been compared in the simulations: an acid aerosols scenario and a natural aerosols scenario. Results show that aerosol acidification leads to a depletion of the ice crystal number concentration and an increase of their mean size. As a result, clear sky precipitation (CSP) occurs more frequently than ice fogs during Arctic haze episodes. This result is in agreement with observations that indicate an increase by more than 50% of the weekly mean CSP frequency, when the proportion of sulfuric acid is greater than the mean observed value of 20%. Consequently, the sedimentation flux of ice crystals and the dehydration rate of the lower troposphere are accelerated. The radiative effect is a weaker atmospheric emissivity in the boundary layer, up to the height corresponding approximately to the top of the ice crystal layer. As a result, the infrared flux reaching the surface and the greenhouse effect are decreased. Simulations performed for the period 1991 to 1994 at Alert show a negative radiative forcing of about --3 W/m2 at the surface between November and May. The net result is a strengthening of the surface-based temperature inversion of 1.3°C, with a surface cooling of 0.4°C and a warming of 0.9°C at 800 hpa. The indirect effect of the dehydration - greenhouse feedback due to anthropogenic acid aerosols can explain in part the observed strengthening of the surface-based temperature inversion in the Arctic (Kahl et al., 1993).</description><creator>Girard, Éric.</creator><contributor>Blanchet, Jean-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Etude d'un effet indirect des aérosols acides en Arctique : le cycle de déshydratation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br157.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237ht48v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g6733</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The potential of surfactants for improving the yields of alpha-amylase during the solid substrate fermentation (SSF) of potato starch using pure and mixed cultures was examined. The microorganisms used in this study were Aspergillus oryzae ATCC 1011, Bacillus subtilis ATCC 21556 and Bacillus subtilis ATCC 21332. The surfactants tested were Tween 20, Tween 80, SDS and surfactin. The fermentations were carried out in perforated trays after the addition of 10% (v/w) inoculum and with temperature and humidity controlled at 30°C and 90% RH respectively. Samples were taken and analyzed quantitatively for the production of alpha-amylase and biomass and qualitatively by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) using a JSM-840 A scanning microscope at 10 kV accelerating voltage. It was possible to increase fungal alpha-amylase production by as much as 6 fold in the process with the addition of either synthetic surfactants or the biosurfactant surfactin. The bacterial alpha-amylase yields increased up to 11.5 fold in with the addition and/or the co-culture production of surfactants. The highest enzyme activity was found in the fermentation of a mixed culture of the two Bacillus strains with the addition of Tween 80. During the SSF with B. subtilis ATCC 21332 and ATCC 21556 as a mixed bacterial culture, there was also the production of surfactin in yields comparable to those obtained in a submerged fermentation. The biofilm formation as observed by SEM appeared to be associated with the presence of surfactants in the process and was not formed when no surfactants were present. The biofilm was observed as an entrapment of the bacteria in the substrate, resulting in improved access to the starch and higher production of alpha-amylase.</description><creator>Góes, Ana Paula.</creator><contributor>Sheppard, John D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Surface active agents.</subject><subject>Starch.</subject><subject>Solid-state fermentation.</subject><title>The effects of surfactants on the solid substrate fermentation of potato starch /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rg170.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g6733</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67js89f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Changes in the pituitary content of prolactin (PRL) and in the ratio of immunoreactive forms of PRL were measured during a reproductive cycle in turkey hens. Low levels of PRL were observed in pituitary glands from sexually immature, out-of-lay and moulting hens. Higher levels were present during the egg laying period and the highest levels were detected in hens expressing incubating behaviour. Two immunoreactive bands of apparent molecular weights of 24 and 27 kDa were visualised on western blots, corresponding to the non-glycosylated (NG-) and glycosylated (G-) forms of PRL, respectively. The percentage of G-PRL was about 60 in sexually immature and egg laying hens. In pituitaries from incubating, out-of-lay and moulting hens the percentage of G-PRL was about 70, 38 and 33, respectively. Thus, higher percentages of G-isoforms (27 kDa) were associated with high levels of total PRL and Iower percentages were associated with low levels of PRL content in the pituitary gland. Digestion of the isoforms with N-glycosidase F resulted in a single band with an apparent molecular weight of 24 kDa. Partial deglycosylation was achieved using neuraminidase, whereas digestion with O-glycosidase had no apparent effect on the isoforms. Thus, G-PRL has N-linked carbohydrates containing sialic acid. In order to study the in vitro release of the PRL isoforms, pituitary glands from turkeys at various physiological stages were stimulated by cVIP in a perifusion system. Total PRL content and the ratio of immunoreactive PRL isoforms in the perifusate were monitored. All the perifused pituitaries responded to cVIP stimulation by increasing the release of PRL. Two immunoreactive bands corresponding to the ones detected in pituitary extracts were detected by western blotting. The G-PRL (27 kDa) was predominant in samples from egg laying and incubating hens and the NG-PRL (24 kDa) was predominant in samples from out-of-lay and moulting hens. No change in the ratio of isoforms released was A competitive reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction assay was developed in order to semi-quantify the PRL mRNA in individual pituitary glands from turkey embryos and poults. Pituitary content and plasma levels of PRL were also monitored, and the PRL isoforms present in the pituitary gland were detected. The levels of PRL mRNA remained low until five days before hatching, increased until the day of hatch, plateaued during the first three days of age and significantly increased at two weeks of age. Similar changes were observed in pituitary content and plasma concentrations of PRL which were highly correlated. Two immunoreactive bands corresponding to the NG- and G-PRL detected in adult pituitary gland were visualised on western blots. The percentage of G-PRL in pituitary glands were 31.5, 48.6, 48.0 and 56.2 at 22 and 27 days of incubation and at I and 7 days of age, respectively. Thus, higher percentages of G-PRL (27 kDa) were associated with higher levels of total PRL in the pituitary gland.</description><creator>Bédécarrats, Grégoy.</creator><contributor>Zadworny, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Prolactin.</subject><subject>Turkeys -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Prolactin genes.</subject><title>Studies on variants of prolactin in the turkey</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q86r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67js89f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881n74b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The signal transduction pathways that mediate metabolic and mitogenic effects in primary rat hepatocytes were investigated. Transcriptional inhibition by insulin of the metabolic gene insulin-like growth factor binding protein-1 (IGFBP-1) was P13-kinase-dependent and sensitive to rapamycin, an Inhibitor of p7Os6k activation at the level of mTOR. In hepatocytes, P13-kinase contributes to p70s6k activation. Our results described the first example of an insulin-specific gene, whose regulation is both P13-kinase- and p70s6k-dependent. MAP kinases were not Involved in regulating this nuclear event. DNA synthesis by insulin was not effected by to MAP kinase signalling pathway, but was p13-kinase-dependent and sensitive to rapamycin. Thus, p13-kinase and p70s6k determine metabolic and mitogenic signalling by insulin in kw cob. DNA synthesis by EGF was also mediated by the P13-kinase/p70 s6k pathway. Unlike insulin however, EGF augmented cymc mRNA levels and this response was effected by activation of the MAP kinase pathway. Of particular Interest, EGF was without effect on hepatic IGFBP-1 mRNA despite its ability to activate P13-kinase and p70s6k to levels comparable to those observed after insulin treatment. We demonstrated that the protein tyrosine phosphatase (PTP) inhibitor, bpV(phen), triggers early signaling events identical to insulin by promoting insulin receptor kinase (IRK) autophosphorylation and activation, suggesting that bpV(phen) inhibits an IRK-associated PTP(s). Consistent with these data, bpV(phen) mimicked insulin effects on DNA synthesis and IGFBP-1 mRNA expression. In contrast to insulin however, bpV(phen) decreased IGFBP-4, as well as IGFBP-1 mRNA levels through an additional signaling pathway, unrelated to P13-kinase/p70 s6k, and it activated MAP kinases independently of their upstream activator, MEK. Thus, bpV(phen) may inhibit a PTP(s) involved in MAP kinase inactivation, and MAP kinases may mediate the inhibitory effect of bpV(phen) on IGFBP-1 and/or -4 mRNA expression. Together, these data reveal the complexity of metabolic and genetic regulation: (1) the P13-kinase/p70s6k pathway cannot, in itself, explain metabolism, and (2) multiple signaling pathways may converge to regulate a common gene.</description><creator>Band, Christian J.</creator><contributor>Posner, Barry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Insulin metabolic and mitogenic signaling in hepatocytes : the role of protein tyrosine phosphatases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k06989205.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881n74b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967532s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of the present study was to compare the effectiveness of case-based instruction and lecture-discussions in enhancing students' multicultural social work competence and their reflective self-regulation to learn multicultural social work. The sample consisted of undergraduate social work students enrolled in a multicultural social work practice course which was composed of two classes, the Special Bachelor of Social Work (SBSW) and the Regular Bachelor of Social Work (RBSW). The students in the SBSW had higher levels of education, mean age, and mean GPA than the students in the RBSW class. Each of these classes was divided into two sections. Participants were randomly assigned to these two sections in which case-based instruction in a section (n = 20 for the SBSW class; n = 19 for the RBSW class), and lecture-discussions in the other section (n = 20 for the SBSW class; n = 19 for the RBSW class) were used to teach the same course content. To control for instructor effects, the researcher and another instructor both taught the two sections of each class, one with case-based instruction and the other with lecture and discussions. The randomized pretest posttest control group design was used in this study. Case analyses scored through Cross-Cultural Counseling Inventory-Revised and student self-reports using the Multicultural Counseling Inventory were used to measure multicultural social work competence. To measure levels of students' self-regulated learning in relation to the course, students were administered the Motivated Strategies for Learning Questionnaire. The same data were collected both at the beginning of the study and at the end of the study. The length of the study was 8 weeks. Two procedures were followed to ensure treatment fidelity: two observers recorded the extent to which class plans reflecting the content and methods of instruction were implemented and students completed questionnaires evaluating the extent to which each method of instr</description><creator>Barise, Abdullahi.</creator><contributor>Amundsen, Cheryl (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Multiculturalism.</subject><subject>Social work education.</subject><title>The effectiveness of case-based instruction vs. the lecture-discussion method in multicultural social work /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nj86g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967532s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hx17w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives of this thesis were to study the generation, the modalities of propagation and the mechanism of control of limbic seizures originating in the entorhinal cortex. Entorhinal ictal-like discharges induced by bath application of 4-aminopyridine to hippocampal-entorhinal slices were initiated by a synchronous GABAA receptor-mediated potential that was associated with a transient rise in extracellular potassium. Seizure-like activity of entorhinal cortex origin, induced by either 4-aminopyridine or low-magnesium was disrupted by hippocampal interictal discharges generated in the CA3 region. Blockade of ictal activity could also be achieved through rhythmic electrical stimulation of hippocampal outputs. Schaffer collateral cut disclosed the propagation of entorhinal seizure discharges via both the traditional entorhinal-dentate gyrus perforant pathway and the direct entorhinal-CA1, temporoammonic input. The interictal-induced block of ictal activity, in the 4-aminoyridine model, did not depend on activation of GABAB receptors in the entorhinal cortex. However, Schaffer collateral cut affected the profile of GABA A-mediated synchronous potentials (that also occurred in mouse combined slices), in a way that disclosed the appearance of robust, ictal-inducing GABAA-mediated potentials. Therefore, interictal discharges could control ictal activity through (among others), a shunting-like effect on these latter potentials.</description><creator>Barbarosie, Michaela.</creator><contributor>Avoli, Massimo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>A study on the interactions between entorhinal cortex and hippocampus in rodent limbic seizures in vitro /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp831.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hx17w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q795w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to study sperm competition and mating dynamics in the snow crab Chionoecetes opilio, a genomic library was established with the goal of identifying highly polymorphic microsatellite markers. Six pairs of DNA primers were designed to amplify markers Cop3-4, Cop4-1, Cop5, Cop10, Cop24-3 and Cop111 by the polymerase chain reaction (PCR). All markers produced patterns as expected from single loci inherited in a mendelian fashion, except for Cop5 which revealed a multi-locus banding pattern. The cross-amplification of the six loci in seven additional crabs species revealed DNA polymorphisms at one or more loci for each species. Markers Cop3-4 and Cop24-3 were used to determine paternity of larvae of primiparous females both from the wild and from multiple mating experiments under laboratory settings. The two markers were also used to genotype the contents of female spermathecae in order to determine the number of number of male genotypes present. Spermathecal contents of wild-caught females were cut into several cross-sections and each section genotyped individually. Histological analysis of spermathecae was carried out to complement genetic data in order to elucidate patterns of sperm competition. Single paternity was observed for the progeny of all females. The analysis of laboratory females showed displacement was the mechanism by which single paternity was obtained by the last males to mate. The analysis of wild females revealed that their spermathecae contained on average the sperm of at least 3.7 males. Larvae appeared to be sired by males whose genotypes were found in the spermathecal cross-sections toward the blind-end of the spermathecae. This suggested that they were the first males to mate with females they guarded until oviposition, and females remated with other males thereafter. Also, a comprehensive account of the mating dynamics was carried out in a wild population of the Northwest Gulf of Saint Lawrence (Eastern Canada) and demonstrated the e</description><creator>Urbani, Nicola.</creator><contributor>Urs, Kuhnlein (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Snow crab -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>DNA -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Sexual behavior in animals.</subject><subject>Snow crab -- Spermatozoa.</subject><subject>Competition (Biology)</subject><title>Microsatellite DNA analysis of the mating system during the first breeding period of the female snow crab Chionoecetes opilio (Brachyura, Majidae)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956h60b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q795w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343t82d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The molecular mechanisms involved in the regulation of protease (PR) activity and human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) viral maturation are incompletely elucidated. To better understand the importance of the cleavage event between HIV-1 PR and reverse transcriptase (RT), we have selectively mutagenized specific residues at the junction between these genes to produce a PR-RT fusion protein in the context of a full-length proviral construct. Mutant viruses derived from COS-7 cells transfected with this construct were analyzed in regard to each of viral replication, maturation, and infectivity. Immunoblot analysis revealed that the mutation prevented cleavage between the PR and RT proteins and that both existed as a PR:RT fusion protein in each of cellular and viral lysates. Interestingly, intracellular PR that existed within the PR-RT fusion protein not only remained functionally active, bid also processed HIV-1 precursor proteins with slightly increased efficiency as shown in time-course experiments in transfected COS-7 cells. In contrast, the RT component of the fusion protein was active at wild-type levels in in vitro and endogenous RT assays. Electron microscopy revealed that mutant viruses containing the cleavage site mutation between PR and RT possessed wild-type morphology. These viruses also displayed wild-type sensitivities to inhibitors of each of HIV-1 PR and RT activities. However, viruses containing the PR-RT fusion protein were 20-times less infectious than Wild-type viruses. This defect was further pronounced when mutated Gag-Pol proteins were overexpressed as a consequence of an additional mutation that interfered with frameshifting. Thus, unlike cleavage site mutations at the N-terminus of PR, a cleavage site mutation between PR and RT did not prevent proteolytic processing and abolish infectivity; rather, viruses containing PRAT fusion proteins were viable, in agreement with the notion that C-terminal liberation of PR is not as critical for</description><creator>Cherry, Elana.</creator><contributor>Wainberg, Mark A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Viral Fusion Proteins.</subject><subject>HIV-1.</subject><subject>Protease Inhibitors.</subject><title>Trans-dominant negative inhibition of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 replication by expression of protease-reverse transcriptase fusion proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx185.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343t82d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jq46j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Virtually from the outset of the 1978--79 Islamic Revolution in Iran, scholars began to study the event from different social, political and economic angles. Yet, the rapid speed of the Revolution, its predominantly Islamic character, and the numerous changes that have occurred during the last nineteen years remain sources of mystery to many students of this area. The goals and philosophy of education and its relation to the basic foundations of the Revolution is one issue however that has been given less consideration. This thesis is an attempt to identify and study the cultural foundations and those religious values underlying the educational system of today's Iran. The study examines some of the elementary school textbooks from both the Pahlavi and Islamic Republic eras, contrasting Pahlavi educational policy, which tended towards secularization, Westernization and de-Islamization of the country, with the attempt of the Islamic Republic to Islamize all aspects of society, including schools. The study especially looks at the relation between Islamic culture, religion and the curriculum. The study stresses that school plays a fundamental role in the Islamization of the post-Revolutionary Iranian society. How one defines Islamization, however, is crucial. This concept is clarified through a scrutiny of the process of Islamization visible in textbook reform by focusing on the spiritual, moral, social and political values in some school texts.</description><creator>Zarean, Mohammad Javad.</creator><contributor>Lin, Jing (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Islamic education -- Iran.</subject><subject>Education and state -- Iran.</subject><subject>Islamic religious education -- Iran.</subject><title>Islamic values &amp; their reflection in the Iranian elementary textbooks : Islamization in post-revolutionary Iran</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35696148.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq46j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v7158</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses the relationship between the GATT/WTO and environmental protection, particularly the relevance of its principles to trade-related environmental measures (TREMs). Environmentalists generally believe that the GATT/WTO is not relevant to TREMs, arguing that the GATT does not have the mandate to deal with environmental issues. In addition, environmentalists believe that the GATT rules on non-discrimination and "like products" could act as barriers for individual countries attempting to adopt TREMs. The prohibition against creating "trade barriers" could result in the same barriers. Economists, on the other hand, generally believe that the GATT/WTO is relevant to TREMs. They argue that nothing in the GATT/WTO prohibits individual countries from adopting TREMs provided that the measures are primarily designed to achieve environmental objectives and are adopted in a legitimate manner. They also contend that the GATT does not prohibit individual countries from employing TREMs when they deal with a "product" standards. This thesis examines relevant GATT/WTO principles and cases, studies and observations made by experts on the issue of trade and environmental protection. The examination confirms the relevance of many GATT/WTO principles to TREMs, which give individual countries the flexibility to adopt TREMs. This thesis also confirms the need for new interpretations and rules to make the existing principles more relevant to TREMs. It would suffice to reinterpret and to develop several new rules.</description><creator>Maarif, Syamsul.</creator><contributor>de Mestral, Armand L. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>The relevance of the GATT/WTO to environmental policies /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848s25g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v7158</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687k03g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Voltage-gated potassium currents make important contributions to neuronal function. Postsynaptically, potassium currents regulate excitability to depolarizing inputs and determine action potential firing frequency. Furthermore, voltage-gated potassium channels are known to affect the shape of the presynaptic action potential, so as to influence calcium influx and neurotransmitter release. I have focused on the expression of voltage-gated potassium channel genes by peripheral neurons. Among my objectives were to determine which voltage-gated potassium channel genes are expressed by sympathetic neurons of the superior cervical ganglia (SCG) and measure mRNA levels for these genes during normal neonatal development and during development in culture. I found that P7 SCG neurons expressed low levels of Kv1.4, Kv2.2 and Kv3.1 mRNAs, moderate levels of Kv2.1 and Kv3.3 mRNAs, and high levels of Kv3.4 and Kv4.2. Where the expression level of Kv1.4, Kv2.1, Kv2.2, Kv3.1 and Kv3.3 mRNAs did not change significantly, neither during development in vivo nor in vitro, both Kv3.4 and Kv4.2 mRNA levels underwent significant developmental changes. I found that Kv3.4 mRNA levels increased sixfold during neonatal development, and remained expressed at high levels or increased during culture. In contrast Kv4.2 mRNA levels increased thirty-fivefold during neonatal development, but in culture Kv4.2 mRNA levels decreased to low or very low levels. Additionally, culturing SCG neurons in the presence of the cytokine ciliary neurotrophic factor (CNTF) failed to influence the in vitro developmental mRNA levels of Kv1.4, Kv2.1, Kv2.2, Kv3.1, Kv3.3 nor Kv4.2. Only the expression level of Kv3.4 was significantly increased by CNTF. I also measured the mRNA levels for Kv1.4, Kv2.1, Kv2.2, Kv3.1, Kv3.2, Kv3.3, Kv3.4 and Kv4.2 in sensory neurons of the nodose and trigeminal ganglia. I found that Kv2.1, Kv3.1, Kv3.3 were expressed at similar levels to SCG neurons, Kv3.2 mRNA was detectable, Kv1.4 an Kv4.2 and Kv1.4 likely contribute to the SCG rapidly inactivating transient current (IAf). Furthermore, changes in Kv4.2 mRNA levels may account for the developmental changes in IAf density in vivo and in vitro. Kv2.1, Kv2.2, Kv3.1, Kv3.3 and Kv3.4 channels likely contribute to the SCG slowly inactivating transient current (IAs), perhaps as heteromeric channels. Changes in mRNA levels do not account for developmental changes in IAs current density. Moreover, the increase in Kv3.4 mRNA levels in SCG neurons cultured with CNTF does not account for the sustained expression of lAf and Us. Similar to SCG neurons, Kv1.4 and Kv4.2 likely contribute to IAf on nodose and trigeminal neurons, whereas, Kv2.1, Kv2.2, Kv3.1, Kv3.2, Kv3.3 and Kv3.4 likely contribute to nodose and trigeminal IAs.</description><creator>Fraser, Andrew, 1968-</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Expression of voltage-gated potassium channel genes by neonatal rat peripheral neurons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hd910.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687k03g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jz91p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Proton Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy (MRS) is an effective technology for imaging axonal damage in the brains of multiple sclerosis (MS) patients. This is based on decreases in signals from N-acetyl groups, which come primarily from the neuronal marker, N-acetylaspartate (NAA). Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopic Imaging (MRSI) visualizes the spatial distribution of the NAA intensities in the brains of MS patients. It can be combined with conventional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) and other clinical information in order to better understand the disease pathology. This thesis comprises three independent but interconnected manuscripts concerning the application of MRSI and MRI to clinical researches in MS. (1) In the first, a statistical analysis strategy for multimodal analysis of MR spectroscopic images was developed. This method allowed for quantification of differences in images of different subgroups of MS patients and the relationship between chemical pathology, clinical disability, duration of disease, and lesions on T2-weighted MRI. (2) The statistical method was applied to serially collected MRSI data from 28 patients with MS (11 relapsing remitting (RR) and 17 secondary progressive (SP)) and 12 normal controls. Results showed that the NAA intensity was lower in the normal appearing white matter (NAVM) of MS patients than that in normal controls and the NAA intensity was 8.2% lower (p &lt; 0.01) in the NAWM of SP than of RR patients. The decrease in NAA in NAWM over time correlated strongly (p &lt; 0.001) with changes in disability in the RR subgroup. These results highlighted an association between axonal damage or loss and increasing disability in MS and suggested that accumulation of secondary axonal damage in the NAWM might be an important mechanism of functional impairment with this disease. (3) Finally, a computer package integrating spatial statistical methodologies adopted in this project and other image processing methods was developed. This package can also serve as a tool for medical imaging data organization, visualization, and manipulation. It will be used by researchers in the field to analyze functional imaging data.</description><creator>Fu, Liqun, 1964-</creator><contributor>Wolfson, Christina (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Arnold, Douglas L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Spatial statistics and their application to neuroimaging studies of multiple sclerosis patients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429b946.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz91p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vv93w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Equipment and techniques have been developed for the microstructural characterization of Zirconium Oxide films grown on Zr-2.5%Nb pressure tubes. A thin film texture apparatus was constructed and used to measure the texture and stress present in thin zirconium oxide films. The general techniques developed employ a grazing incidence geometry which allows the texture and stress present in thin films (&lt;1mum) of any type to be examined. In addition, a technique for the quantitative phase analysis of textured ZrO2 films grown on zirconium alloys using pole figure data has also been developed. Moreover, equipment was constructed to determine the relative porosity of oxide films grown on a metal substrate using an electrochemical method that measures the effective non-porous oxide thickness. The described equipment and techniques were then used to characterize a test matrix of specimens whose relative hydrogen pick-up was measured by Differential Scanning Calorimetry. The application of beat treatments to the substrates prior to oxide growth was found to have a pronounced effect upon the sharpness of the oxide texture. A correlation between the degree of sharpness of the oxide texture and hydrogen pick-up and corrosion rate of the substrate was also determined. In addition, based upon the new techniques developed it was determined that the tetragonal phase of the oxide is stress stabilized in a region close to the metal/oxide interface.</description><creator>Glavicic, Michael G.</creator><contributor>Szpunar, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Development and application of techniques for the microstructural characterization of hydrogen permeability in zirconium oxides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z46f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vv93w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128ng398</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Techniques are presented for use in FFT network analyzers to improve estimates of long lags in the impulse response. A key step involves short-term correlation of time-shifted copies of the input-output data. We introduce new Banach signal spaces for the analysis of such data. As a preliminary result, new transfer function estimation algorithms are given with bounds on the effect of undermodelling, noise and lack of empirical data in the Hinfinity norm. Comparisons with optimality are given using metric-complexity concepts. The algorithms and error calculations are implemented in MATLAB and C to realize a software network analyzer which includes error bars. As a test case, the algorithm is applied to data from the compliant hip joint of a hopping robot.</description><creator>Glaum, Michael.</creator><contributor>Charalambous, Charalambos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A function space calculus for identification and system analysis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc376.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng398</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm17j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Parathyroid hormone (PTH) and PTH-related peptide (PTHrP) stimulate signal transduction in target cells by binding to the same G protein-linked receptor (PTHR). The PTHR mediates PTH signaling in kidney and bone, and PTHrP binding to the receptor has been shown to be essential for normal endochondral bone formation in humans and mice. Expression of the murine PTHR gene is controlled by two promoters that are regulated differently. Whereas the activity of the upstream promoter (P1) is mainly restricted to the kidney, where it provides the bulk of the gene transcription, the downstream promoter (P2) is more widely active. We characterized the upstream regulatory region of the human PTHR gene and showed that its organization is very similar to that of the mouse PTHR gene. RNase protection experiments revealed, however, that the homologue of the mouse renal-specific promoter PI, is only weakly active. This observation led us to identify and characterize a third promoter P3) that is responsible for the expression of more than 80% of human renal transcripts, but is apparently not active in mouse kidney. A study of the tissue distribution of the activity of P1, P2 and P3 showed that, while P2 and P3 are widely active, function of P1 is restricted to renal tissues. This study further revealed the existence of a shorter, differentially spliced variant of P2 derived transcripts. P1 and P3 were found to be developmentally regulated, as no activity was detected at mid-gestation. Hence, expression of the PTHR gene until this stage is driven solely by P2. Furthermore, the shorter P2-specific transcript observed in adult not detected in fetal tissues, suggesting that differential splicing of PTHR mRNA is developmentally regulated as well. The observation that activity of PI and P3 is developmentally up-regulated, and the presence of P3 within a CpG island, prompted us to examine whether DNA methylation could play a role in regulating PTHR promoter function. Our results show that all three promoters are sensitive to methylation in vitro and that the methylation pattern of Pl is renal specific and is established well before the onset of PTHR gene expression. Our results suggest that while the transcriptional regulation of the PTIHR gene expression during development might be similar in mouse and human, expression in the adult is likely to be controlled by different mechanisms. We also addressed the presence of structural alterations of the 5 ' regulatory region in patients with pseudohypoparathyroidism type Ib. Genomic southern blot analysis, as well as sequencing of the three upstream untranslated exons did not reveal any deletion or point mutation that could account for the kidney specific loss of PTH response observed in these patients.</description><creator>Bettoun, Joan David.</creator><contributor>White, J. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Studies on the transcriptional regulation and differential splicing of the human parathyroid hormone (PTH)PTH-related peptide (PTHRP) receptor gene (PTHR)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r4829.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm17j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h6268</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work is a study of Tudor metrical psalmody, an historical genre or literary kind that emerged and flourished during the sixteenth century, consonant with the emergence and progress of the English Reformation(s). Working from the premise that Tudor metrical psalms were at once prayer, "poesie," and polemic, I examine the ways in which these texts participated in the social discourse of the period. After establishing that Tudor metrical psalmody is a historical genre or literary kind whose five essential characteristics bind its constituent members together, I provide two additional interpretive readings of Tudor psalmody. The second is radically materialist, arguing that the corpus of Tudor psalmody should be deciphered "as a progression of 'symbolic resolutions' of the social contradictions which initially engendered them." In other words, metrical psalm translations of the period are fantasized resolutions of the material and doctrinal struggles of the Reformation. The third reading approaches Tudor psalmody as a body of devotional works and Confessions of Faith. My point of departure is George Steiner's declaration in Real Presences that "any coherent understanding of what language is and how language performs, that any coherent account of the capacity of human speech to communicate meaning and feeling is, in the final analysis, underwritten by the assumption of God's presence." Conceived and nurtured on the front lines and, indeed, in the midst of the Reformation(s)' bloody altercations, early Tudor psalmody declared itself the vanguard in the struggle to maintain God's presence in the semiotic "prayingfield" by approaching the rite of psalm-translation as one of transubstantiation. Later psalmists of the century mediated the aesthetic demands of "poesie" and the theological priorities of strict Calvinism, thereby establishing a realm of prayer within which we now include works by devotional poets such as Donne and Herbert. This study is the first comprehensive examination of Tudor metrical psalmody as a literary kind, in addition to being the first sustained exploration of the kind's complicity in Reformation polemics. It also demonstrates that Tudor metrical psalmody underwent an evolution during the course of the sixteenth century fully consonant with the theological and aesthetic developments of the Age. For ease of reference, I have transcribed and appended to this thesis several psalms to which reference is made within the body of the thesis. Finally, I acknowledge my indebtedness to Rivkah Zim's ground-breaking volume, English Metrical Psalms: Poetry as Praise and Prayer, 1535--1601 . Considerable inspiration was gained from her work.</description><creator>Bider, Noreen Jane.</creator><contributor>Williams, David (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Borris, Ken (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>English literature -- Early modern, 1500-1700 -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Psalmody.</subject><title>Tudor metrical psalmody and the English Reformations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s183t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h6268</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bn46w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although biological data concerning the North Atlantic fin whale ( Balaenoptera physalus) have been collected since the beginning of this century, much is still unknown regarding their biology and evolution. The aim of this study was to increase our knowledge of the evolution, population structure and molecular ecology of this species using modern molecular techniques. Fin whale samples were collected in six feeding areas from the North Atlantic Ocean, the Mediterranean Sea and the Sea of Cortez (North Pacific Ocean). To facilitate the molecular analyses, two new sexing techniques were developed, and several hyper-variable microsatellite loci were isolated from humpback whale (Megaptera novaeangliae) genomic DNA. The sex as well as the genotype at six microsatellite loci was determined and the first 288 nucleotides of the mitochondrial (mt) control region sequenced in 407 samples. Population genetic and phylogeographic analyses of mtDNA and nuclear loci supported the hypothesis that North Atlantic and North Pacific fin whales constitute separate populations. However, the degree of divergence did not correlate with the rise of the Panama Isthmus and suggested the occurrence of occasional gene flow between the two oceans. The analysis of the mtDNA indicated the existence of several separate populations in the North Atlantic Ocean and Mediterranean Sea. The mtDNA analysis identified eastern and western fin whale populations, both distinct from the Mediterranean Sea fin whales. The result of the microsatellite loci analysis revealed significant levels of heterogeneity only between the most distant areas. The observed difference in the relative level of divergence at mtDNA and nuclear loci was consistent with expanding populations not yet in "drift-mutation" equilibrium, which have diverged recently. This scenario was supported by the distribution of pairwise differences among the mtDNA nucleotide sequences. The sex ratio in the samples collected from Gulf of St. Lawr</description><creator>Bérubé, Martine, 1963-</creator><contributor>Sergeant, D. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Finback whale -- Evolution.</subject><subject>Finback whale -- Molecular genetics.</subject><title>Genetic structure and molecular ecology of the North Atlantic fin whale, Balaenoptera physalus (Linnaeus, 1758)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c618.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn46w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jn207</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Orientation imaging microscopy (OIM) was performed on hot twisted polycrystalline 304 stainless steel specimens in order to study the characteristics of dynamic recrystallization (DRX) in low stacking fault energy FCC metals. Microtexture analyses were carried out and the misorientation statistics of the recrystallized areas were derived. The results revealed that multiple twinning controls the formation of new orientations. DRX macrotextures were also measured in torsion and compression. These textures are highly sensitive to the deformation (Zener-Hollomon) parameter Z. High Z values lead to overall textures controlled by nucleation, whereas, at low Z values, selective growth is more predominant. A deformation and recrystallization model based on the OIM measurements and the steady state properties is proposed. The observed strong brass-type deformation textures were simulated by introducing self hardening coefficients. The transition from single to multiple-peak flow during DRX was investigated, together with the evolution of the grain size distribution. In particular, the effect of twinning on the evolution of the latter was simulated. Finally, it is shown that the model simulates texture development during DRX very well.</description><creator>Bocher, Philippe.</creator><contributor>Jonas, John J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Dynamic recrystallization in a 304 stainless steel : microtexture measurements and models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806161c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn207</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb04b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation is concerned with surveillance, which refers to the monitoring and supervision of populations for specific purposes. Of special interest we the ways in which new technologies are augmenting the power of surveillance in the late twentieth century, and therefore influencing the privacy debate. Three things are noted about this. First, large-scale surveillance by bureaucratic organizations is a product of modernity, not of new technologies. This is evident from Part I of the dissertation, which argues that increased surveillance capacity comes as a result of specific economic and political circumstances that favour the use of technological systems of particular kinds, which invariably feature enhanced capacities. Second, surveillance has two faces; advantages appear alongside serious disadvantages. This is also evident in Part I of the dissertation which suggests that much surveillance theory is dystopian and therefore, an incomplete paradigm. Finally, new technologies facilitate some major magnification of surveillance power; some even argue that they change its character qualitatively. As such, privacy features prominently alongside discussions of electronic surveillance. This is evident in the final two parts of the dissertation which evaluate privacy as a strategy for limiting electronic surveillance. In this regard, Part II examines technical challenges to electronic surveillance, expressed through privacy law in particular, and Part III analyses mobilization challenges, which have to do with the role played by social movements in attempting to bring about broader-based change than mere legislation. Throughout the dissertation, the argument is made that surveillance has become a central feature of contemporary advanced societies and as such, it should be a major concern of both social analysis and political action. This is why the dissertation is divided into distinct, but overlapping, parts, with the first part focusing on social and critical</description><creator>Yamashita, Miyo.</creator><contributor>Robinson, Gertrude (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Privacy, Right of -- Canada.</subject><subject>Electronic surveillance -- Social aspects.</subject><title>Electronic surveillance and the prospects for privacy in Canada's private sector by the year 2000</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f299c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb04b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wh721</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Suppose G is a countable, Abelian group with an element of infinite order and let X be a mixing finite rank (rank r) action of G on a probability space, or let X be a mixing beta-local rank action of G with beta &gt; 1/2. Suppose further that the Folner sequence { Fn } indexing the towers of the beta-local X satisfies a "bounded intersection property": there is a constant p such that each Fn can intersect no more than p disjoint translates of itself. If X is finite rank, we also suppose that the cardinalities of the r Folner sequences Fin ri=1 are comparable. We show that X is mixing of all orders. When G = Z, this extends the results of Kalikow and Ryzhikov to a large class of "funny" rank one transformations. We follow Ryzhikov's joining technique in our proof: the main theorem follows from showing that any pairwise independent joining of k copies of X is necessarily product measure. This method generalizes Ryzhikov's technique.</description><creator>Yassawi, Reem Adel.</creator><contributor>Choksi, J. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Del Junco, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Multiple mixing of local rank group actions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55md57f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh721</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r947x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation consists of three essays: (I) Double Liability, Moral Hazard and Deposit Insurance Schemes, (II) Contract Costs, Lender Identity and Bank Loan Pricing, and (III) Bank Capital Structure and Differential Lending Behaviour. The first essay proposes to add double liability to a deposit insurance scheme to induce insurees (depository financial institutions) to reveal their true risk types. The second essay looks at the differential lending patterns of American banks versus Japanese banks. The third essay discusses the relationship between the characteristics of a lender and those of the borrower.</description><creator>Yan, Yuxing.</creator><contributor>Errunza, V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Bank loans.</subject><subject>Intermediation (Finance)</subject><subject>Deposit insurance -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Three essays on financial intermediation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z9490.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r947x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm63p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this work, we develop a mathematical model for a rotating Timoshenko beam, and then show its well-posedness. Further, we prove the exact controllability of its linearized model under different sets of controllers. Finally, we work out a computer simulation system for linear as well as nonlinear control problems.</description><creator>Xiong, Xiao-Jin.</creator><contributor>Schmidt, Georg (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>Modeling, control and computer simulation of a rotating Timoshenko beam</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v0265.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm63p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr35w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Upper Devonian Leduc, Nisku and Wabamun/Stettler formations (Frasnian and Famennian) were deposited on extensive carbonate platforms, and form three unconformity bounded megasequences, characterized by stacked shallowing upward meter to tens of meter-scale paracycles. Carbonates interbedded with evaporites have been extensively dolomitized. Four types of dolomites are recognized. Microcrystalline dolomites are interpreted to be of sabkha origin, characterized by fine crystals (2--70 mum) and are in part mudcracked, brecciated and contain quartz silts. Sucrosic dolomites (20--130 mum) commonly have dusty cores with clear rims. Mosaic dolomite crystals (10--140 mum) are interlocked. Dolomite rhombs (30--70 mum) occur in partially dolomitized limestones. Sabkha, sucrosic and mosaic dolomites are nearly stoichiometric, 50.2 to 53.2 mole% CaCO3, whereas, dolomite rhombs have up to 56.2 mole% CaCO 3. Different types of dolomites can not be distinguished by their isotopic compositions. They range from --6.1 to --2.5‰ PDB delta 18O, and --6.0 to +3.3‰ PDB delta13C. 87Sr/86Sr ratios vary from 0.7081 to 0.7094. Different types of dolomites appear to be facies related, and are interpreted to have formed during syndepositional and shallow burial possibly by means of reflux of evaporated Late Devonian sea water. This is indicated by (1) dolomites overlain by bedded anhydrites; (2) amount of dolomite decreasing downsection; (3) presence of dolomite clasts in transgressive shales of overlying paracycles; (4) 87Sr/86Sr ratios close to those inferred for Late Devonian sea water (0.7080--0.7083); and (5) 2 to 3‰ higher delta18O values than reefal replacement dolomite. Downward reflux of dolomitizing fluids appears to be mainly confined to meter to tens of meter-scale paracycles due largely to the presence of many anhydrite and shale permeability barriers. Large vertical reflux may have operated along or near shelf margins where several paracycles of porous facies are superimposed and impermeable anhydrites are absent. Two major pore types exist. Intercrystalline porosity occurs in sucrosic replacement dolomites with porosity up to 25%, and permeability of 1000 md. Vugs/molds are associated with mosaic replacement dolomites with lower porosity (3--18%) and permeability (&lt;100 md) than sucrosic dolomite. Anhydrite cements are the major pore-filling phases. Some anhydrite cements were subjected to later dissolution and rehydration.</description><creator>Tan, Wenbin.</creator><contributor>Mountjoy, Eric W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Origins of replacement dolomites, Upper Devonian Leduc, Nisku and Wabamun formations, southeastern Alberta western Canada sedimentary basin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mh29m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr35w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73px71b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction. Trauma triage protocols are important because they identify, at the injury scene, patients with major injuries requiring transfer to a Level I trauma center, from those with non-major injuries who could be treated at Levels II and III trauma centers. The Pre-hospital Index (PHI) is a physiological injury severity measure which may be used as a trauma triage tool. Purpose. The purpose of the present study was to: (1) prospectively evaluate the predictive ability of the PHI in identifying trauma patients with major versus non-major injuries, and (2) develop a trauma triage scale which incorporates, along with the PHI, a subset of the variables age, body region injured, mechanism of injury, comorbidity, and time between 911 call and departure of the ambulance from the injury site, so as to improve the predictive ability of the PHI-based triage instrument. Methods. This study was based on 1,291 trauma patients treated in Montreal between April 1993 and December 1996. A patient was considered to have major injuries if the patient died within seven days since hospital admission, had an intensive care unit admission within seven days, or major surgery performed within four days. Three hypothetical trauma triage protocols were developed using logistic regression analysis; where the model that describes the data best was selected according to Bayes factor approximation. In detecting major versus non-major injuries, sensitivities, specificities, positive and negative predictive values were calculated for all the cutoff points of the PHI and the triage protocols. Also, areas under the Receiver Operating Characteristic (ROC) curves were calculated and compared for these instruments. Results. The trauma triage protocol which included the variables age, body region injured, mechanism of injury, comorbidity, and PHI produced the best combination of sensitivity and specificity; of 0.95, and 0.24, respectively. This algorithm underwent a significant improvement over the PHI (area under the ROC curve: 0.76 versus 0.66, p &lt; 0.05). Conclusion. An improvement in the predictive ability of the PHI-based triage instrument was introduced after the addition of the variables age, body region injured, mechanism of injury, and co-morbidity.</description><creator>Tamim, Hala.</creator><contributor>Samfalis, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Development and evaluation of on-site triage algorithm for trauma patients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956h62w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73px71b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc18r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis focuses on the effects of temporary block of glycolysis by the competitive antimetabolite 2-deoxy-D-glucose (2-DG) on neuronal activity in the CA1 region of rat hippocampal slices. The overall aim was to investigate how synaptic transmission is suppressed when metabolism is greatly reduced by the replacement of glucose by 2-DG to provide some insight into the cellular mechanisms underlying these depressant effects. Experiments were carried out on hippocampal slices kept submerged and constantly superfused with oxygenated saline at 33--34°C. Block of glycolysis was induced by replacement of glucose by equimolar concentrations of 2-DG. Changes in synaptic efficacy and postsynaptic cell membrane properties were assessed in the initial slopes of EPSPs recorded by extra/intra or whole-cell patch recordings. The most striking observation of 2-DG induced glycolysis block is the consistent and sustained potentiation of CA1 synaptic transmission named as "2-DG LTP". Although in some respects 2-DG LTP is similar to conventional tetanic LTP, this novel type of LTP is unique in most of its features. Another finding is the reversible depression of synaptic function by 2-DG application. Adenosine receptor antagonists strongly delay or reduce this depression. In contrast, glyburide, a blocker of KATP channels, does not prevent the suppression of neuronal depression induced by 2-DG. In keeping with this only adenosine receptor blockers, but not glyburide, effectively attenuate 2-DG induced postsynaptic hyperpolarization. The evidence presented in this thesis indicates that, increased adenosine release as the result of 2-DG-induced energy deprivation, is a major cause of reversible loss of synaptic transmission and drop in membrane resistance. In addition, 2-DG LTP brings in a new concept that the regulation of glycolytic pathway plays an important role in modulation of neuronal synaptic plasticity that may contribute to learning and memory.</description><creator>Baltan, Selva.</creator><contributor>Krnjevic, Kresimir (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Long-term potentiation induced by temporary block of glycolysis in CA1 hippocampal neurons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn506.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc18r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34300</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>