<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:51:29Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94ht93x" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94ht93x</identifier><datestamp>2020-05-04T13:44:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La recherche présente a testé si l’adoption par le gouvernement de lois reflétant l’avis d’une majorité de citoyens, est associée avec des changements d’attitude de citoyen(ne)s.  Grâce à 1 million d’observations sur plus de 11 ans, nous avons examiné si la légalisation du mariage gai pour chaque état américain a été associée avec la diminution des préjugés homophobes implicites et explicites. Cinq modèles statistiques appuient fortement notre hypothèse.  Bien que les préjugés implicites et explicites étaient en diminution avant la légalisation du mariage homosexuel, les deux types de préjugés ont diminué plus rapidement après. Cet effet était modéré par le pallier de gouvernement ayant mis en œuvre la légalisation. Spécifiquement, les états ayant adopté la légalisation au niveau de l’état ont vu une diminution des deux types de préjugés après la légalisation, tandis que ceux n’ayant pas légalisé le mariage gai au niveau de l’état ont vu une augmentation des préjugés après la légalisation au niveau fédéral. Notre recherche souligne comment les lois gouvernementales peuvent influencer les attitudes individuelles, même quand ces attitudes sont fortement enracinées et sujettes aux débats sociaux</description><description>The current research tested whether the passing of government legislation, signaling the prevailing attitudes of the local majority, was associated with changes in citizens’ attitudes. Specifically, with ~1 million responses over a 11-year window, we test whether state-by-state same-sex marriage legislation was associated with decreases in anti-gay implicit and explicit bias. Results across five operationalizations consistently provide support for this possibility. Both implicit and explicit bias were decreasing prior to same-sex marriage legalization, but decreased at a sharper rate following legalization. Moderating this effect was whether states passed legislation locally. While states passing state-level legislation experienced a greater decrease in bias following legislation, states that never passed local legislation demonstrated increased anti-gay bias following federal legalization. Our work highlights how government legislation can inform individuals’ attitudes, even when these attitudes may be deeply entrenched, and socially and politically volatile</description><creator>Ofosu, Eugene</creator><contributor>Eric Hehman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2020</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Same-sex marriage legalization associated with reduced implicit and explicit antigay bias</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cq14m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94ht93x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>