<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:50:17Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t5252" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t5252</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:30:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the past few decades, Transit-Oriented Development (TOD) has emerged as a promising andinfluential planning concept throughout North America. It tries to ensure a more sustainabledevelopment by integrating land use and transport systems. Numbers of urban planners andtransportation scholars formally introduced TOD as a new concept and increased its profile in the1990s; however, the origins of this concept actually go back much further. There are somenoteworthy examples of large-scale real estate developments across North America, developedon properties owned by transit companies, with the aim of generating revenue for the transitcompany and the government. One of the most successful examples of this type of developmentis the Town of Mount Royal located in Montreal, Canada. This suburban development whichemerged at the dawn of the twentieth century predates, by almost a century, the contemporaryconcept of TOD. This paper looks at this development comprehensively and discusses thelessons learned from it. Additionally, the research looks at several recent Canadian TOD casestudies and through a comparative study reveals the successes and challenges old and newdevelopments faced within their design and operation process. Finally, the study concludes byidentifying the key lessons from old and new TODs showing how the present day TOD normshave grown out of such old communities.</description><description>Au cours des dernières décennies, Transit-Oriented Development (TOD) a émergé en Amériquedu Nord comme un concept de planification prometteur et influent. Il tente d'assurer undéveloppement plus durable par l'intégration de l'utilisation du sol et des systèmes de transport.Quelques planificateurs et chercheurs de transport urbain ont officiellement présenté le TOD etont rehaussé son image dans les années 1990; Cependant, l’idée de ce concept est beaucoup plusancienne. Il y a quelques exemples de grands projets immobiliers en Amérique du Nord qui sontdéveloppés sur des propriétés appartenant à des organismes de transport en commun dans le butde générer des revenus pour l'agence de transport en commun et le gouvernement fédéral. L’undes exemples les plus réussis et les plus notables de ce type de développement est la Ville deMont-Royal à Montréal, Canada. Ce développement de la banlieue qui a émergé à l'aube du XXesiècle précède la notion contemporaine de TOD. Cet article examine cette évolution globalementet examine les leçons tirées. En outre, la recherche porte sur plusieurs études de cas modernes deTOD canadien et par une étude comparative révèle les réussites et les défis que les anciens etnouveaux développements ont rencontrés au cours de leur processus de conception et defonctionnement. Finalement, l'étude conclut en identifiant les principaux enseignements desanciens et des nouveaux TOD et révèle si les normes actuelles de TOD sont développés à partirde ces communautés.</description><creator>Zarabi, Zahra</creator><contributor>Bhatt, V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Architecture</subject><title>Early railway suburbs and their links to contemporary transit-oriented developments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jx63m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t5252</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>