<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:50:29Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236536m" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236536m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A review of the clinical and pathological findings in 30 patients with diastematomyelia further defines the distinct pathological anatomy of diastematomyelia and further elucidates its association with a variety of other midline dysraphic anomalies. These definitions allow the formulation of an integrative, universal hypothesis on the origin of virtually all forms of spina bifida and dysraphism and cranium bifidum. The essence of the hypothesis is the formation, in early embryonic life (18-30 d.), of a sagittal cleft of the embryonic neuraxis which involves neuroectoderm, notochord, and endoderm. Incorporation of a persistent neurenteric canal is invoked to explain the origin of the neuraxis cleft. Sequential events of cleft formation, cleft healing and faulty delayed closure of the neural tube are proposed as yielding a spectrum of dysraphic anomalies, ranging from combined anterior and posterior spina bifida through open myeloceles to myelodysplasia, spina bifida occulta, and certain midline developmental tumors.</description><creator>Tutt, Henry P.</creator><contributor>Bertrand, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Neurology and Neurosurgery.</subject><title>The pathogenesis of spina bifida and dysraphism: clues from diastematomyelia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vx123.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236536m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>