<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:51:31Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dw85n" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dw85n</identifier><datestamp>2020-05-05T12:20:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The flow of incompressible turbulent wall jets over curved boundaries is examined in this thesis. The experimental portion is concerned with the flow of the jet on a concave surface of constant radius. The theoretical portion of the investigation considers jets blown over surfaces for which (i) the radius is proportional to the jet thickness; (ii) the radius is constant. The former defines flows for which the form of the velocity profiles will remain unchanged downstream. The solutions for both cases are obtained by neglecting wall friction and by assuming a turbulent shear law which is similar in form to that for curved laminar shear flow. A perturbation method of solution is used having the plane free jet as the zeroth order approximation and using a series expansion in powers of the ratio of the jet thickness to the radius of curvature. Functions are found which, when multiplied by the jet thickness-to-radius ratio, represent the correction to be made to the plane free jet profile. The agreement between theory and experiment is fairly good and modifications to the shear are suggested which may remove the remaining discrepancies.</description><creator>Guitton, Daniel. E.</creator><contributor>Newman, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering.</subject><title>Two-dimensional turbulent wall jets over curved surfaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mq94b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dw85n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>