<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:51:11Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sm379" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sm379</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:00:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The research work presented in this thesis deals with carbon nanotubes (CNTs), an allotrope of carbon with a cylindrical structure consisting of a rolled up graphene sheet. CNTs are generally produced by the decomposition of a carbon source in the presence of a metal catalyst at elevated temperatures. CNTs have outstanding properties and have attracted immense attention in both industry and academia. However, the development of commercial applications of CNTs is slow due to limitations in the large scale production of CNTs and their high cost. Another limitation is the interface resistance generated by external catalyst nanoparticles used in traditional CNT growth methods. In order to eliminate the interface resistance and simultaneously provide CNT growth over large surfaces and varying geometries, a method called direct CNT growth is established to enable the extraction of the CNT structure directly from the metal surface. The novel process for the production of CNTs developed in the present thesis is applied to planar surfaces and spherical particles made of stainless steel (SS) 304. The method is based on the establishment of nanometer scale structures at the surface which act as catalyst nanoparticles while at the same time being integral parts of the material. It uses first a mild chemical etching of the surface, followed by a specific heat treatment performed using either standard chemical vapour deposition (standard-CVD) or fluidized bed CVD (FBCVD) techniques. Acetylene (C2H2) is used as the carbon source and SS 304 acts as both the catalyst and the substrate in the growth process. This direct CNT growth with this substrate dual function eliminates the need of external catalyst nanoparticles deposited onto the surface. The active sites necessary for CNT growth are tailored on the SS itself by means of the two-step treatment process. MWNTs of 20-70 nm in diameter are produced. The CNTs are characterized by Raman Spectroscopy, Thermogravimetric analysis (TGA), Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM) and sonication. CNT purity up to 84% is attained and the catalyst is determined to be the faced-centred cubic structure of Fe in the austenite form (γ Fe). In the case of the FBCVD technique, there are at least 30 mg of CNTs produced per total gram of sample made of CNT-coated SS particles. In addition, the recovery and reuse of the SS particles is demonstrated for a second growth sequence in the FBCVD setup. Detailed characterizations of the SS surface includes X-Ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy (XPS), grain size analysis, Atomic Force Microscopy-Kelvin Probe (AFM/Kelvin) and Time-of-Flight Secondary Ion Mass Spectrometry (TOF-SIMS). In summary, XPS reveals that the etching process partially removes the Cr2O3 passive oxide layer and results in the formation of Fe2O3. Also, Fe3C is found on the surface beneath the CNTs. This iron carbide "cementite" phase is formed during the CNT growth process. Recrystallization occurs during the heat treatment step of the method and is followed by grain growth. The AFM study confirms that the etching process creates ripple-like features on the surface, which are 10-30 nm wide. In order to stabilize mechanically and structurally the CNT growth structure on the metallic support, the production of novel Diamond-like Carbon (DLC) / CNT and Titanium Nitride (TiN) / CNT nanocomposites having a porous three-dimensional architecture is also accomplished here. The "felt-like" CNTs produced in the first part of the thesis are "frozen" in DLC or TiN by Physical Vapour Deposition (PVD). The TiN/CNT nanocomposites are characterized by nanoindentation and contact angle measurements. An increase in contact stiffness values with TiN coating time is observed. The TiN coating on the non-wetting CNTs resulted in a wetting nanocomposite surface. The wetting property was found to be a function of the TiN coating thickness on the CNT structure.</description><description>La croissance des nanotubes de carbone (NTC) sur des surfaces métalliques est étudiée dans cette thèse. En général, les NTC sont synthétisés par la décomposition d'un gaz riche en carbone en présence d'un catalyseur métallique à des températures élevées. Les propriétés exceptionnelles des NTC génèrent un immense intérêt autant au niveau de la recherche que sur le plan industriel. Par contre, le développement d'applications commerciales des NTC reste limité par les contraintes de production à grande échelle et leur prix élevé. Une autre contrainte est la résistance d'interface générée par les nanoparticules de catalyseur utilisé par les méthodes de croissance traditionnelles. Afin d'éliminer la résistance d'interface et simultanément produire une croissance des NTC sur des grandes surfaces et géométries variable, une méthode de synthèse simple et directe est développée. Cette méthode est établie pour permettre l'extraction de la structure du NTC directement à partir de la surface du métal. Le nouveau procédé de synthèse des NTC développé dans cette thèse est utilisé avec des surfaces d'acier inoxydable 304 planes et des particules sphériques. La méthode développée consiste à créer des structures nanométriques à la surface du métal qui agissent comme des particules catalytiques, tout en faisant partie intégrales de cette surface. Le procédé utilise d'abord une gravure de la surface, puis un traitement thermique réalisé soit dans un réacteur de dépôt chimique en phase vapeur traditionnel (standard-CVD), ou en lit fluidisé (FBCVD). Le gaz carboné est l'acétylène (C2H2) et le catalyseur/support combiné est l'acier inoxydable 304. Cette méthode de croissance directe des NTC avec un substrat à double fonction élimine la nécessité de déposer des nanoparticules de catalyseur sur la surface du support, les sites actifs requis pour la croissance des NTC étant produits directement sur la surface de l'acier inoxydable. La méthode optimisée produit des nanotubes multi-parois avec diamètres de 20-70 nm. Les NTC sont caractérisés par spectroscopie Raman, analyse thermogravimétrique, microscopie électronique en transmission et par une étude d'adhérence. La pureté des NTC produits atteint 84%. Des mesures de diffraction électronique sur les régions catalytiques indiquent une zone riche en fer correspondant à la structure cubique face centrée de l'austénite (γ Fe). Dans le cas du réacteur FBCVD, 30 mg de NTC sont générés pour chaque gramme de produit brut (NTC + particules d'acier inoxydable). De plus, la récupération et réutilisation des particules d'acier inoxydable pour un deuxième cycle de croissance dans le réacteur FBCVD est démontrée. La surface de l'acier inoxydable est caractérisée par plusieurs méthodes. En résumé, les analyses XPS indiquent que la couche d'oxyde de chrome (Cr2O3) est partiellement enlevé par la gravure à l'acide, et de l'oxyde de fer (Fe2O3) se forme sur la surface de l'acier inoxydable. Du carbure de fer (Fe3C) est observé sur la surface de l'acier sous les zones de croissance des NTC. Ce carbure, de la cémentite, est en fait produit durant la croissance des NTC. Le traitement thermique produit une recristallisation de la surface suivit par une croissance des grains. L'étude par AFM démontre que la gravure à l'acide génère des ondulations topographiques à une échelle de 10-30 nm sur la surface de l'acier inoxydable. Les structures de NTC sur substrat métalliques sont utilisés pour produire un nano-composite formant une structure 3-D ouverte de NTC recouverts et retenues par une couche de carbone adamantin (DLC) ou de nitrure de titane (TiN). Ces couches sont faites par dépôt physique en phase vapeur (arc-PVD). Un nombre limité d'échantillons de DLC/NTC est étudié, et une étude détaillée est effectuée pour les nano-composites TiN/NTC. Cette dernière structure est caractérisée par nano-indentation et par mesure d'angle de contact.</description><creator>Baddour, Carole</creator><contributor>Jean-Luc Meunier (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>Direct growth of carbon nanotubes on metal surfaces without an external catalyst and nanocomposite production</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859k76d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sm379</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>