<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:50:13Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967675s" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967675s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:30:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes the design and construction of a variable frequency three-phase inverter using transistors as the power switching elements, particularly suited for direct coupling to on active load such as an induction motor. The problems of transistor protection and regeneration of power to the inverter power supply are considered. It is shown that these design problems may be solved by the inclusion of a fast-acting electronic over-voltage crowbar and current-limiting in the power supply. The design and construction of a power supply with these features is presented. The complete open-loop supply-inverter combination is tested to specification on a fractional horsepower induction motor and practical results are presented and evaluated.</description><description>Cette thèse decrit la conception et la construction d'un onduleur triphasé à transistors particulièrement bien adapté à l'alimentation à frequence variable d'une charge active comme une moteur asynchrone. Les problèmes pasts par la protection des transistors et le retour cie puissance de la charge vers la source continue ont été pris en consideration. Il est montré que ces problèmes peuvent être resolus grace à l'inclusion d'une limitation tant en courant qu'en tension, qui ne peut ê'tre realisée qu'avec des elements electroniques rapides. La conception et la construction d'une source de tension regulée comprenant ces protectIons est presentée. Enfin le convertisseur a été testé' en boucle ouverte sur une machine asynchrone cie l kVA et les resultats experimentaux sont discutés.</description><creator>Kenny, Brian F.</creator><contributor>Barton, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>A 1kVA variable frequency inverter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw89v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967675s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>