<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:51:11Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z9034154" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z9034154</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:00:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Des polymorphismes du gène «dystrobrevin-binding-protein-1», une séquence codant pour la protéine dysbindin-1, sont indicatif du risque potentiel pour la schizophrénie. Bien qu'une significative expression neuronale de dysbindin-1 ait été détectée pré- et post-synaptique, une diminution de dysbindin-1, notamment dans les terminaux glutamatergiques de l'hippocampe, a été rapportée dans les tissues post-mortem de schizophrènes. Ces résultats suggèrent un rôle de dysbindin-1 dans la neurotransmission glutamatergique. Utilisant le modèle de souris Sandy avec une suppression naturelle dans le gène dysbindin-1, nous avons examiné si la diminution de dysbindin-1 est médiateur de changements pré-synaptiques dans le circuit glutamatergique de l'hippocampe et se traduire post-synaptiquement en altération de la morphologie neuronale. Nous avons observé une diminution développementale des marqueurs de vésicules glutamatergiques et des changements significatifs dans la structure des épines dendritiques chez les mutants homozygotes contrairement aux contrôles. Notre étude fournit la première preuve d'un rôle développemental de dysbindin-1 dans la transmission synaptique.</description><description>Genetic analyses have revealed polymorphisms in dystrobrevin binding protein-1, a gene encoding dysbindin-1, as a potential risk factor for schizophrenia (scz). Whilst significant expression of neuronal dysbindin-1 has been detected pre- and post-synaptically, reduced dysbindin-1 expression, notably in intrinsic hippocampal glutamatergic terminals, were reported in scz postmortem tissues. Thus, suggesting a role of dysbindin-1 in glutamatergic neurotransmission. Using the Sandy mouse model with a natural deletion in dysbindin-1 gene, we investigated whether down-regulation of dysbindin-1 leads to aberrant pre-synaptic changes in hippocampal glutamatergic markers and whether these changes would translate post-synaptically in altered neuronal morphology. We observed a developmental decrease in vesicular glutamate markers and significant alterations in the structure of dendritic spines in homozygous mutants (sdy/sdy) as compared to wild-types. The present study provides the first evidence of a developmental role of dysbindin-1 in synaptic transmission.</description><creator>Marsan, Lina</creator><contributor>Sylvain Williams (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Lalit K Srivastava (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Investigating the functional role of dysbindin-1 (DTNBP-1), a susceptibility gene for schizophrenia, in synaptic transmission</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702qb56t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9034154</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>