<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:50:06Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z395p" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z395p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:30:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The acetylcholine (ACh) stores of cat sympathetic ganglia were determined following a variety of patterns of preganglionic nerve stimulation and poet-stimulation rest periods. They increased by 38% over a 20 min rest following 60 min, 20/sec stimulation and remained elevated for at least 3 hr. The increase was less with 10 min stimulation and absent with 4/sec stimulation. The excess ACh was released during stimulation in the presence of hemicholinium-3. The time course or Ach release from stimulated plasma-perfused ganglia was followed. The release rate was highest near the onset of 20/sec stimulation and declined over 5 min to a 50% lower steady value. At 4/sec the rate increased over the first 5 min to a 25% higher steady value. These findings are discussed in relation to the hypothesis of preferential release of newly synthesized transmitter and the two compartment model of transmitter storage.</description><creator>Fitch, Stephen G.</creator><contributor>Birks, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1974</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>The synthesis, storage and release of acetylcholine in the superior cervical ganglion of the cat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290d69j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z395p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>