<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:51:30Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xj181" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xj181</identifier><datestamp>2020-05-04T13:54:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ne au debut du dix-septieme siecle, Ie theAtre kabuki n'a connu sa premiere floraison comme art dramatique complexe que pendant I'epoque Genroku(1688-1704). Grace a la survivance de nombreux textes-scenarios, l'epoque Genroku est aussi la premiere periode dans l'histoire du kabuki dont l'analyse detaillee est possible. Pour ces raisons, le Genroku kabuki est depuis toujours un objet d'etude prefere parmis les specialistes de l'histoire du theAtre au Japon. Mais ces etudes, quoiqu'elles soient souvent basees sur des recherches historiques considerables, ont ete, pour la plupart, determinees par les mames projets ideologiques qui ont soutenu les autres formes du discours intellectuel dans le Japon moderne.[...]</description><description>Scholars are in agreement that the kabuki theatre did not attain its first flowering as a complex dramatic art until the Genroku period (16881704). The Genroku period is also the earliest for which detailed study of the plays has been possible, due to the large number of playbooks that have survived. For these reasons, Genroku kabuki has long been an object of scholarly attention among Japanese theatre historians. This scholarship, however, has for the most part been shaped by the same ideological concerns that underlie other forms of Japanese intellectual discourse in the modern period. In the Meiji period (1868-1912), for example, efforts were made to find in kabuki a Japanese equivalent to the Western theatre; while in the postwar era, in light of the critique of feudalism following the national defeat, the trend has been to see kabuki as an example of popular culture, one with roots in older indigenous cultural traditions and which not only enjoyed a special relationship with the urban commoner class, but which functioned as a form of resistance to feudal authority.[...]</description><creator>Lee, William James.</creator><date>1996</date><subject>Kabuki.</subject><subject>Kabuki plays.</subject><subject>Theater and society -- Japan.</subject><title>Genroku kabuki : cultural production and ideology in early modern Japan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qw176.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xj181</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Comparative Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>