<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>ualberta_ukrainian_studies</identifier>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://uofa.ualberta.ca/arts/research/canadian-institute-ukrainian-studies" target="_blank"&gt;The Canadian Institute of Ukrainian Studies (CIUS)&lt;/a&gt; is a prominent centre of Ukrainian studies outside Ukraine and an integral part of the Faculty of Arts at the University of Alberta. Founded in 1976, it provides an institutional home for Ukrainian scholarship in Canada. CIUS is dedicated to the development of Ukrainian studies in Canada and supports such studies internationally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CIUS consists of a number of centres, programs, and projects whose activities range from research to publishing, developing materials for Ukrainian-language education, organizing conferences, lectures, and seminar series, and awarding graduate and undergraduate scholarships and research grants. СIUS also contributes to the Canadian government’s cooperation with Ukraine and to the cultural and educational development of community groups in Canada by providing specialists and resources for their activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this collection of digitized works published by the Canadian Institute of Ukrainian Studies (CIUS) you can find such items as the CIUS series of Research Reports and the Journal of Ukrainian Studies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <hidden>true</hidden>
  <mediatype>collection</mediatype>
  <title>The Canadian Institute of Ukrainian Studies Collection</title>
  <collection>university_of_alberta_libraries</collection>
  <publicdate>2016-05-18 13:00:55</publicdate>
  <uploader>admin-andrea-mills@archive.org</uploader>
  <addeddate>2016-05-18 13:00:55</addeddate>
  <collection>toronto</collection>
  <collection>texts</collection>
  <num_recent_reviews>5</num_recent_reviews>
  <num_top_dl>5</num_top_dl>
  <show_browse_collection_link>true</show_browse_collection_link>
  <show_hidden_subcollections>true</show_hidden_subcollections>
</metadata>
