<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p3940"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Scottish industrial labourer during the Anglo-French wars 1792-1815</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Straka, Waclaw. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The main features of Scottish history during the eighteenth century consist of the economic revival followed by social changes which in turn precipitated the political awakening of the mass of the people. Prior to the Union and even well into the eighteenth century Scotland remained very poor. This state of poverty to a lesser or greater degree was common to all. If the farmer, the artisan, cottagers and labourers suffered poverty the gentry experienced acute and chronic lack of money. In this predominantly agricultural country both the lowly and the high-born concentrated most of their energies to eke out from the land as best an existence as possible.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kk80d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p3940</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xj466"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The reactions of active nitrogen with boron trichloride, germanium tetrachloride, and germane</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Storr, Catherine. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During the latter years of the nineteenth century, it was observed that when some gases, or mixtures of gases, were excited by an electrodeless discharge, a luminescence or afterglow with a continuous spectrum was produced. In 1900, Lewis reported that nitrogen subjected to a condensed discharge gave an afterglow different from those previously obtained from other gases. He described it as a “rich chamois yellow fog”. It lasted for several seconds after the discharge had been turned off, and its spectrum consisted of narrow bands. Several years later, Strutt, who later became Lord Rayleigh, observed that the spectra of elements and compounds excited in the presence of the yellow nitrogen were the same as those produced by other methods.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g376t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xj466</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77fw24g"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Preparation, maintenance, and use of master specifications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stickel, Alfred. W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The process of preparing Project Specifications concentrates on the presentation of excerpts from a region of knowledge, selected and re-composed to fill a given set of requirements. It can be broken down into five steps: i. A survey of drawings to produce a List of Requirements. ii. Arrangement of Requirements to form tentative Sections. iii. Consultation of source material for the Rough Draft. iv. Elimination of inconsistencies to make up the Final Draft. v. Typing of the Final Draft.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Balharrie, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524js46z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fw24g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Architecture</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avd66w335b"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>ita</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Languages</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L’Anti-Machiavelli di Innocent Gentillet</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stewart, Pamela. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Scopo di questo saggio non è di raccontare la storia di un uomo, ma di fornire un contributo alla storia di un libro. Sarà, tuttavia, opportuno, come introduzione al nostro studio, dare un breve cemno della vita di Innocent Gentillet e delle sue opere. Tralasciando i particolari, spesso incerti e oscuri, della sua vita, ci fermeremo soltanto sulla linee generali e sui documenti dai quali esse si desumono. I biografi di Gentillet concordano nel dire - ed è anzi questo uno dei pochi punti sui quali sono d'accorda - che egli nacque a Vienne, nel Delfinato, nella prima metà del XVI secolo. Si ignora la data della sua nascita.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>D’Andrea, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v9355.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w335b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Romance Languages</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bj51z"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The stratospheric wind regimes of the 1958-59 winter</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Steiner, Harold. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Vertical cross sections along the 80W meridian from the surface to 35 km (circa 5 mb) are presented for each fifth day of the 1958-1959 winter season. The synoptic features of the stratosphere as shown by the cross sections - are discussed in monthly résumés in sufficient detail to furnish a generalized picture of the seasonal changes. An objective method for determining the peak winds in jet streams is formulated and results from this method compare favourably with meso-scale data from aircraft probes. The baroclinity of the troposphere and lower stratosphere and its relation to the Ferrel westerlies are discussed. Boundary conditions for the crests of the Ferrel westerlies on summer and winter type wind profiles are presented and shown to be quasipermanent in nature.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hare, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c615q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bj51z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Meteorology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afq977z64b"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics and Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>India’s neutralism in theory and practice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Steinberg, Blema. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It has become a truism of international politics to say that the power configuration in the atomic age is vastly different from that which existed during the 18th and 19th centuries--the classical era of European interstate relations. But in what way does it differ and how do these differences affect the position of the would-be neutralist in the mid-20th century? In the belief that hypotheses about both these questions are essential to an understanding of neutrality and its progeny, neutralism, this chapter offers some propositions about the structure of international politics in the pre-atomic and atomic eras.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brecher, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9033629.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977z64b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics and Political Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mr05n"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies in the marine amphipoda of eastern and northeastern Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Steele, Donald. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since 1947 the Fisheries Research Board of Canada has been conducting an investigation of the marine resources of eastern Canadian arctic waters. As part of this study, a large number of benthic, pelagic and littoral marine animals have been collected, mainly during the expeditions of the M.V. 'Calanus' (Dunbar and Grainger, 1952; Grainger, 1954; Grainger and Dunbar, 1956; Grainger and Hunter, 1959). The marine amphipods taken in the years 1947-1950 in Ungava Bay have already been studied (Dunbar 1954) and one hundred and fourteen species identified. In 1956 I began the study of the marine amphipods obtained by the 'Calanus' during 1951 to 1957 in Hudson Strait, Frobisher Bay, northern Hudson Bay and Foxe Basin.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dunbar, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515r96s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mr05n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Zoology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bq17v"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of turbojet engines for hypersonic propulsion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sreenath, Ananthapur. V.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis contains the results of a theoretical analysis of the performance of an inverted turbojet cycle as a thrust power unit. This system is compared with a conventional turbojet with and without reheat and pre-cooling. Within the limitations of the analysis it is seen that the domain of air breathing engines for propulsion can be extended to hypersonic vehicles. The inverted turbojet is an economical cruising engine for hypersonic vehicles at Mach numbers 5-6. However a conventional turbojet with pre-cooling and reheat can power a vehicle throughout the range of Mach 0 to Mach 6.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mordell, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70n0109.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bq17v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s390n"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Human adaptation in the Mackenzie delta: a study in facilitating the adjustment of the Northern Indian and Eskimo to rapid social change</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Spence, Ian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is a preliminary plan for an active research project which sets as its goal the better understanding of ways to improve human adaptation to cultural change in the Mackenzie delta. A theoretical framework is developed which focuses on processes of adaptation, especially those which operate on a community level. This framework is applied to information compiled through library research and field observation; first, to detailed descriptions or the changing Eskimo and Indian cultures, then to the settlements of Aklavik and Inuvik. The results which are derived therefrom are applied in the building or an experimental project designed to test Community Development procedures as a means of improving adaptation. Survey plans have been developed to measure the relative improvement in the experimental and the control projects.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Moore, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dd59s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s390n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149t26k"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The partial reduction of hematite to magnetic iron oxide</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sopko, Michael. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The iron and steel industry has been and still is faced with rising capital and operating costs. The capital cost of a blast furnace complete with coking ovens and all other raw material facilities is in the order of fourty million dollars and up. In addition each ton of raw material carries the cost of removal from the pit or mine, possible beneficiation costs, plus the high cast of transportation. These costs, it is to be noted, are also increasing. To meet this challenge the industry decided to embark on a twofold program of research.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacEwan, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j4619.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149t26k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Metallurgical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tq580"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L’hélicoptère ses différentes utilisations ses problèmes juridiques</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Son, Dinh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Depuis toujours, l'homme a envié la facilité avec laquelle l'oiseau se meut dans les airs, et inlassablement il fait des recherches et des expériences qui lui permettraient d'en faire autant. A l'heure actuelle, de véritables cargos volants, pesant plus de 100 tonnes, se déplacent dans l'air à des vitesses 2 ou 3 fois supérieures a' celle du son. Mais l'avion à ailes fixes n'est pas la solution suprême que recherche l'homme, parce qu'il ne pourra jamais se libérer de certaines servitudes qui lui sont inhérentes: il est et restera esclave de la vitesse et de l'infrastructure.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rosevear, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dx023.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tq580</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Air and Space Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap5547w095"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Paramagnetic resonant-relaxation in potassium chromicyanide</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith, Peter. W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Resonant relaxation times for the +3/2  +1/2, +1/2  -1/2 and -1/2   - 3/2 transitions in single crystals of K3Cr(CN)6 at liquid helium temperatures have been measured for nominal chromium concentrations of 0.1%, 0.5%, 1% and 5% using a saturation method. Experimental points are found to fit a theory which is similar to that used in nuclear magnetic resonance work. The spin-lattice relaxation times round for all three transitions decrease with concentration or the paramagnetic salt in the diamagnetic K3Co(CN)6 dilutant. The spin-spin relaxation time appears to remain practically independant of the concentration in this range. Results round for the spin-spin relaxation times agree within the experimental error with those found by other recent experimenters. Spin-lattice relaxation times quoted in recent literature for the +1/2  - 1/2 transition in K3Cr(CN)6 vary greatly, and it is thus of little use to compare these results. They are, however, or the same order of magnitude as our values.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Woonton, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zs070.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547w095</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77fw25r"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the mechanism of rust formation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith, Gordon. W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The wastage of metals due to corrosion has become an important engineering problem in recent years. The growing demand for, and increasing cost of materials, and the cost of shutdown and labour involved in making replacements, makes every effort to understand corrosion worthwhile. The annual cost of corrosion in Canada has recently been set at $300 million (1). This figure is only approximate, because an estimate of this type is extremely difficult to make. A breakdown of the figure is given in Table I.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yates, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w336m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fw25r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Metallurgical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795c42v"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The spread of response within the mammalian brain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith, Grant. K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The work described in this thesis has had as its aim the development of quantitative techniques for the study of the moments at which neurons in the mammalian cerebral cortex produce action potentials both in the presence and absence of externally applied stimulation. In support of the usefulness of these techniques as tools in biological research exploratory experiments are to be described in which a quantitative estimate was made of the influence exerted by a stimulus upon neurons in locations classically considered to be remote from the sphere of influence of the stimulus. In the course of these experiments several analytical techniques have been applied to the action potentials continually generated by neurons in the unstimulated brain.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burns, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860b420.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795c42v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289n563"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Success and failure in the first year: an investigation of factors distinguishing successful from failing freshman students in the Institute of Education, McGill University, 1958-1959</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith, David. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As the student population in the universities has increased over the past thirty years and failing students have abounded in more conspicuous numbers, interest in the problem of failure has grown sharply. Inquiries into and reports on the causes for failure have been legion, and a complete review of them is beyond the scope of this paper. However, investigations of various types can be identified, and this review of the literature will be limited to a summary and assessment of a few of the more representative reports.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crook, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021j730.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289n563</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301501v"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular size and configuration of carboxymethyl cellulose in aqueous solutions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sitaramaiah, Gullapalli</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this section a short outline of the general background to the macromolecular studies of cellulose and derivatives is given. Some of the more important investigations so far undertaken on CMC are also briefly presented here. Finally, a brief account of the hydrodynamic theories as well as certain special aspects of the experimental techniques are given in order to anticipate the interpretation of the results.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mason, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gp608.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301501v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abv73c420d"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Density, viscosity and surface area relationship in grinding</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sirois, Louis. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The first attempts to rationalize comminution were made by Rittinger in 1867 and Kick in 1885 (1, 2, 3, 4). Rittinger postulated that: “The increase of the surfaces exposed is directly proportional to the force required.” Kick countered that: “The energy needed for producing analogous changes of configuration in geometrically similar bodies of equal technological state varies as the volumes or weights of these bodies.” According to Rittinger, since the surface formed in each stage is double, the energy required to produce each successive stage increases in geometric progression, the ratio being two.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Salman, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rm82j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c420d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mining Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9c67wr426"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The forms of land tenure in 15th century Roumania</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sinder, Alan. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Roumanian princes were despots, and because there was considerable Byzantine influence in the two sister principalities, the rulers copied the absolutism and the form of government of this Empire. The absolute power of the rulers was limited by the fact that the two original Roumanian dynasties ruled for three centures but did not produce many capable leaders. Since there were no established laws of succession (any member of the princely families could be elected ruler by the assemblies of nobles and clergymen), many struggles for power took place which weakened the authority of the Roumanian princes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mladenovic, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd376128x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wr426</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515r972"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the pathogenesis of experimental atherosclerosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Silver, Malcolm. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>When one looks at atherosclerotic plaques in an artery on the autopsy table, one is viewing a group of lesions that have been present for an unknown length of time and may have bad a multiplicity of causes. Perhaps this white fibrous plaque was initiated fifty years ago and has existed since then. Perhaps it lost lipid during a period of regression. That ulcerated atheroma may have slowly accumulated lipid following a surface thrombosis five years before death. A yellow plaque which could have developed following an intimal injury may have increased in size by short episodes of lipid accumulation associated with haemorrhage into its substance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McMillan, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365865t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515r972</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1z40kx457"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of petroleum development on the Alberta economy, 1947-1957</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sievwright, Eric. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1947, after years of deficits culminating in debt default by the mid nineteen thirties, the Provincial Government of Alberta was fortuitously granted a new and substantial source of revenue, based on the major oil discoveries of that year. This thesis is a critical analysis of the way in which the Provincial Government handled this new revenue source. In view of the bleak fiscal history preceding World War II, it is not surprising that short-term tax considerations were given a high priority.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Armstrong, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9356519.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kx457</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s391x"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On some reducible Diophantine equations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shtern, Isreal. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Although Diophantine analysis has occupied mathematicians from antiquity to our own times, there exist few general methods for the complete solution of Diophantine equations in rational integers. In this paper we illustrate the method developed by E. Rosenthall for the complete solution of reducible Diophantine equations. This method involves, as a first step, the solution of an equation in ideals belonging to subfields of some normal extension, then passing from ideals to integers belonging to the extension considered. In some particular cases, additional restrictive conditions must be satisfied before a solution may be obtained.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rosenthall, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wr43g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s391x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j462k"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Shell-side characteristics in a leak-proof heat exchanger</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Short, Bernard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A model, two-dimensional leak-proof, heat exchanger was built. Local shell-side, heat transfer coefficients were measured in a typical section between two segmental baffles. Three baffle spacings, with five flow rates at each spacing, were used. The results indicate that the crossflow region can be divided into a dead zone and flow zone. The size of these sub-zones is a function of the area ratio, Ar, and thus the average coefficient is also a function of Ar.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stachiewicz, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cf47m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j462k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn3015024"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on initiating stage of epidermal carcinogenesis in mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shinozuka, Hisashi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cancer is a disease recognized in antiquity. Its name, “Kapkivos”, a crab, was derived from the ancient description of breast cancer. Until the Nineteenth Century, it was entirely within the therapeutic province of the physician and surgeon. According to Bett (1957), Bernard Peyrilhe (1735-1804) was the first to conduct a systemic experimental investigation of the causation of cancer, in which he attempted to identify its toxin, and to trace the spread of the disease in order to devise better methods of treatment. Although more than two hundred years have passed since Peyrilhe's attempt, research into the cause of cancer is still one of the most intricate scientific activities of modern times.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ritchie, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tg67b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3015024</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579w911"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of air flow on the insertion loss of a side-branch filter</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Serbyn, Myroslav. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In acoustic structures part of the sound energy transmitted by a duct is often diverted into sidebranch tubes or resonators. Even a single side branch has an important effect on the transmission of sound in the main duct. The most prominent example of this is an acoustical side-branch filter. Such filters are used in exhaust mufflers, various types of wind tunnels, jet-engine test cells, air-conditioning systems, and other applications where objectionable noise components have to be eliminated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Howes, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nj35k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579w911</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acf95jf79h"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hydrogen exchange between cellulose and water</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sepall, Ola. K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the discovery by means of X-ray diffraction that cellulose is partially crystalline, the arrangement of the molecules in various types of native and regenerated cellulose has been the subject of intensive study using a variety of experimental methods. This thesis describes an investigation of the hydrogen exchange reaction between cellulose and water and its possible relation to the crystallinity and other aspects of the fine structure and the reactivity of the cellulose. Since present concepts of molecular order in cellulose have been described in many texts, only those aspects which are of interest to the present work will be briefly reviewed here.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mason, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70n011k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jf79h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>