<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m3512"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A screen of one's own : québéçois cinema, national identity, and the alternative public sphere</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacKenzie, Scott</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation explores the connections between image-making practices, discourses of nationalism, Quebecois cinema and the possibility of the cinema functioning as an alternative public sphere. The thesis draws upon sociological theories of nationalism, political theory, film theory, critical theory and cultural critique in order to reconsider the potential political power of the cinematic image. After surveying contrasting theories of nationalism, the thesis addresses itself to Jurgen Habermas' concept of the public sphere and the revisions of this concept undertaken by contemporary social and political theorists. The use-value of the concept of the public sphere in relation to film theory is then explored. Beginning with pioneering work of Leo-Ernest Ouimet in the silent era and continuing on through to the video activism of Societe nouvelle and the "post-referendum" cinema of Denys Arcand and Robert Lepage, this thesis traces recurring instances of the cinema functioning as a contestatory and alternative public sphere in Quebecois culture.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hjort, Mette</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t374k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m3512</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nationalism -- Québec (Province) -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Motion pictures -- Québec (Province) -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>French-Canadians -- Ethnic identity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9306t088m"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fast shape memory alloy actuators</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lafontaine, Serge R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis techniques for fabricating fast contracting and relaxing shape memory alloy (SMA) fibers are presented. Shape memory alloy fibers have demonstrated the largest stress and highest power to mass ratio of any known actuator technology. However their practical application has been plagued by three major drawbacks, namely: (1) relatively slow expansion of the material despite rapid contraction; (2) problems of mechanically and electrically connecting to the material due to the violent nature of their contractions; and (3) low efficiency in the conversion of electrical energy or heat into mechanical energy. The work associated with this thesis has led to solutions to the first two problems allowing even sub-millisecond contraction-expansion cycle times, and fibers to be attached via light weight but high strength and high conductivity joints. The properties of these fibers are extensively studied. Both linear and rotary actuators are built using these fibers. A new technique is presented to mount nickel-titanium (NiTi) SMA fibers. NiTi alloys are not readily bonded, soldered, brazed or welded to other materials. The new method employs metal deposited on the fiber or between two fibers or between fibers and other parts, creating metallic attachments that are mechanically sound and electrically conductive. Furthermore a new process for the three-dimensional microfabrication by localized electrodeposition and etching has also been developed. This latter process, combined with the first process, can be used to integrate NiTi alloys in micro-mechanisms. The good electrical contacts as well as mechanical contact provided by the new attachment mechanisms are important, since they allow the rapid methods to be employed. Several apparatus were built to study the response of NiTi fibers, in particular to very fast current pulses. Experimental results were obtained to describe the response of the fibers, such as their speed, hysteresis, stiffness and resistivity, and show how these variables change dynamically as a function of time, temperature and stress. Other measurements important for the design of new actuators were done, such as those of efficiency when fast actuation with large current pulses is used. In the third part of the thesis a novel application for fast fiber actuators is presented in the form of a fast rotary motor for in-the-wheel car rotary motors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hunter, Ian W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f012.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t088m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ang451k347"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the metal biosorption process utilizing Sargassum seaweed biomass</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kratochvíl, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The innovative process of removal of toxic heavy metals from water by biosorption, using the dead biomass of Sargassum marine alga packed in flow-through columns, was examined. The mechanism of uptake of Cu 2+, Zn2+, Cd2+, Fe2+, and Cr(III) by the biomass was identified as ion exchange taking place at the weakly acidic functional groups embedded in the cellular matrix of the seaweed. After pretreatment with mineral acids, the cation exchange capacity of the biomass was approximately 2.3 meq/g of biomass dry weight which is comparable to the metal binding capacities of commercial ion exchange resins. The issues related to the biosorption process design, optimization, and limits of applicability were addressed by (1) evaluating different ionic cycles for biomass in columns at different normalities of the feed, (2) assessing the interference of iron in biosorption of a toxic metal, and (3) analyzing the effects of competitive binding of several toxic metals in the flow-through column including the metal elution order and the overshoots of the concentrations of toxic species in the column effluent over their feed levels. The column models, previously developed for ion exchange, such as the Equilibrium Column Model (ECM) and the Mass Transfer Column Model (MTCM) were used to fit the experimental data and to predict the service time of biosorption columns treating binary and multi-metal mixtures. The application of the theory of ion exchange to describing and assessing the process of metal sequestering by biomass in flow-through columns represents an original work. The investigation into the removal of hexavalent chromium by Sargassum biomass revealed that the latter could take up approximately 60 mg/g (2.3 meq/g) at pH 2 while reducing some of the Cr(VI) to Cr(III). A combined ion exchange-redox mechanism of Cr(VI) removal was proposed whereby, at pH &gt; 2, the Cr(VI) is assumed to be taken up from water primarily by an anion exchange mechanism, while at pH &lt; 2 the reduction of Cr(VI) to Cr(III) controls the binding of chromium to the seaweed. The effect of pH on the Cr(VI) removal was explained through the dependence of the reduction potential of HCrO4- ions on the pH of the liquid.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Volesky, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br17s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k347</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Environmental</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cz245"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic factors affecting life span in the nematode Caenorhabditis elegans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lakowski, Bernard C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The nematode worm Caenorhabditis elegans has become a model system for the analysis of the genetics of aging. Previously, mutations in four genes, age-1, clk-1, daf-2 and daf-28 had been shown to lengthen adult life span. Based on the molecular genetic analysis of these genes, the sole function of the dauer genes age-1, daf-2 and possibly daf-28 is to regulate the activity of the forkhead-like transcription factor daf-16. daf-16 may determine life span by regulating the transcription of genes that are necessary for resistance to stresses, especially oxidative stress. Mutations in clk-1 affect behavioral and developmental timing as well as increasing mean and maximum life span. I show that mutations in the genes clk-2, clk-3 and gro-1 affect many of the same processes as clk-1 and that these four genes interact to determine the length of development and adult life span. These four Clock genes lengthen life span in a manner that is distinct from that of the dauer genes. clk-1 has been cloned and has been implicated in the regulation of metabolism. This suggests that Clock mutants may live long because they have reduced metabolic rates. I also show that mutations in 7 genes that affect feeding behavior, eat-1, eat-2, eat-3, eat-6, eat-13, eat-18 and unc-26 lengthen life span. This effect is presumably due to reduced caloric intake (caloric restriction) which has been shown to lengthen the life span of a wide variety of animals. eat-2 lengthens life span by a mechanism that is distinct from that of the dauer mutants but may be similar to that of the Clock mutants. This suggests that caloric restriction may also reduce metabolic rates, possibly through down-regulation of the Clock genes. These results indicate that life span in C. elegans is a polygenic trait, influenced by many different physiological processes. The study of genes that affect aging in C. elegans provides support for the antagonistic pleiotropy and free radical theories of aging.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hekimi, Siegfried</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n0366.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz245</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Longevity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603r023w"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Finite-element and experimental analyses of the response of the cat eardrum to large static pressures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ladak, Hanif M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Currently available mathematical models of the eardrum are limited to low pressure levels owing to the assumption of linearity between stimulus (applied pressure) and response (eardrum displacement). In this work, the response of the cat eardrum to large static pressures is measured with a moire interferometer, and the data are modelled using the finite-element method. Experimental data indicate that eardrum response with a normal mobile malleus is nonlinear, asymmetric and hysteretic. Measurements with a fixed malleus permit investigation of eardrum behaviour without the confounding effects of the middle-ear ossicles. Artifactual banding in measured displacement patterns is investigated by means of numerical simulations. Artifacts in moire interferometry arise from ignoring height-dependent fringe-plane spacing, modulation, reflectivity and magnification when reconstructing surface shape. Systematic errors induced by these assumptions are small: their effects are not apparent in shape measurements, but do show up as bands in displacement images. The fixed-malleus data are modelled using the finite-element method to assess the importance of geometric nonlinearities at high pressure levels. Individualized finite-element models are created from shape data for each eardrum. Results indicate that geometric nonlinearity combined with nonuniform mechanical properties shows promise in describing eardrum response at high pressures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Funnell, W. Robert J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft110.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r023w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Audiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s1617993"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Model weighting adaptive control</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gendron, Sylvain</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The main exercise of this thesis is the formulation of a mathematical framework for analyzing an existing industrial adaptive control algorithm labeled Model weighting adaptive control (MWAC). The algorithm is then analyzed under this framework. The exercise is complemented by a set of algorithmic additions aimed at solving questions that so far had remained open (e.g. the treatment of undermodelling errors). Those solutions, on the other hand build on results derived from the analysis. A key result for analyzing the algorithm is that when an external excitation is applied (in the form of a control task such as a setpoint change), the adaptive controller behaves, in a short time that follows the application of the excitation, as a linear equation whose parameters are completely known at design time. It follows that during this short period, the input signal provided to the estimation subsystem is at least partially known (except for disturbances) and that the estimation virtually takes place in open loop. Using this information and assuming boundedness of the disturbance signals, it is possible to bound the behaviour of the adaptive system at an early stage. With the MWAC algorithm, the plant model is formed by making a weighted sum of a finite number of possible plant models. It is shown that, under adequate conditions and in a time corresponding to the apparent plant delay, the plant model will "jump" to a neighborhood of the true plant. The size of this neighborhood will depend in part on how sharply the bad models are discriminated from the good models. On the other hand, disturbances will smooth the weight map towards a uniform distribution. The sharpness or smoothness of the weight map can be measured online by computing the sum of the square root of all the weights in the set. The remarkable property of this measure is that an upper bound on the distance between the true plant and its model can be found which an affine function of the measure. The effect of external disturbances such as measurement errors can be reduced by an external excitation of sufficient magnitude. This is not true however of disturbances caused by undermodelling errors which are almost always present to a lesser or greater degree. Two solutions are proposed to counteract this undesirable effect. The first method consists in bandpass filtering the input/output data in such a way that the frequency content of the data is consistent with data obtained from some first order plus delay (FOPD) model. The second method adjusts the sampling period online such that a compromise between satisfying the FOPD assumption and the coarseness of the control is obtained.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Belanger, Pierre R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b280w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1617993</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811km42p"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Worry and the traditional stress model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gagné, Marie-Anik</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mental well-being of individuals has been studied for centuries. Yet a full understanding of the causal mechanism of mental distress has not been achieved. The prevalence of depression in women has spurred much of the research in this area. The goal of this dissertation is to contribute to the understanding of the determinants of women's mental and physical functioning. The means to this end is to incorporate a concept from each of the following disciplines, sociology and psychology. The sociological discipline lends the stress model to this research, while psychology contributes the concept of worry. To date, sociologists have not studied the effects of worries on women's mental health, while psychologists have not included socio-demographic indicators and stress variables in their studies of worry. The purposes of this dissertation are to add worry to the Traditional Stress Model, explore the determinants of worry, and observe the consequences of worry on mental distress and physical functioning. A community sample of 170 mothers is employed to test the hypothesis that adding worry to the Traditional Stress Model, while controlling for socio-demographic indicators, stress, social support, and coping measures, will significantly increase the explanatory power when predicting the Total Mood Disturbance Score (TMDS) and the Total Physical Health Score (TPHS). Results from a series of multiple regressions indicate that worry measures do significantly contribute to the understanding of the TMDS and TPHS. Other conclusions are also reached regarding several determinants of women's mental and physical functioning included throughout the analyses. In the case of married women, a measure of their marital status is a better indicator of their TMDS and TPHS than a measure of their social support from friends and family. In the case of employed women, the most significant indicator for both the TMDS and TPHS is their level of employment stress. Research and policy implications emerge from these results. For example, general practitioners should be trained to detect employment or marital stress, and poor mood states which are likely to affect their patients' perceptions of their mental and physical health.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Smith, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c598.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km42p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women -- Mental health -- Sociological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stress (Psychology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- Health and hygiene -- Sociological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Worry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3t945s588"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The forgotten tool : a socio-historical analysis of the development and use of mechanical molecular models in chemistry and allied disciplines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Francoeur, Eric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis offers a detailed socio-historical exploration of the practice of molecular modelling in chemistry and allied disciplines. This exploration leads to observations and conclusions that are of relevance to the sociology of science in general and to the issue of representation in scientific practice, in particular. After a general introduction in chapter one, chapter two offers a review of the science studies' literature relevant to the topic, namely the literature on representation and on experimental practices in the sciences. The lack of sources dealing with the issue of physical modelling is highlighted. Chapter three, through specific cases studies, presents the argument that the circulation of structural concepts and accounts in chemistry has been historically associated with the circulation not only of graphical representations, but also of physical models. Implications of this argument for a semiotically-centred view of scientific practice are discussed. Chapter 4 discusses the role of models as a research tool. Through various historical cases, it shows how physical models have been central in the process of defining, exploring and intervening on the domain of molecular-structures as accessed through laboratory manipulations. The work of molecular modelling is presented in particular as the experimental articulation of structural constraints within clearly defined research settings. Chapters five and six analyse the development of three specific modelling systems from the late 1930s to the mid-1960s. These chapters show these developments as contingent processes based on the involvement of elite researchers and both private and public institutions. It shows in particular how these modelling systems were made relevant across individual research sites by providing not only a technical solution to the problem of assembling model structures, but also by incorporating specific structural constraints. Finally, it is argued that these systems are one of</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cambrosio, Alberto</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k06989230.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s588</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Teaching -- Aids and devices -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Molecules -- Models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry -- Study and teaching -- Audio-visual aids -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azw12z713g"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular studies using amastigote-specific genes in Leishmania</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ghedin, Elodie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Leishmania is a dimorphic parasitic protozoan which exists as a flagellated promastigote in the sandfly vector and as an intracellular amastigote in the phagolysosomal compartment of mammalian host macrophages. It is the amastigote form that is responsible for the pathology in susceptible vertebrate hosts. Leishmania donovani is responsible for visceral leishmaniasis, the most severe form of the leishmanial diseases. We have investigated the antibody response against an amastigote-specific protein, A2, which is developmentally expressed in L. donovani during promastigote-to-amastigote cytodifferentiation. A2 is conserved in L. donovani and L. mexicana species but not in other Leishmania species tested. We have shown that this characteristic contributes to its potential as a useful specific diagnostic antigen for visceral leishmaniasis. Developmental expression of A2 involves A2 mRNA untranslated regions (UTRs) and we have demonstrated that A2 UTRs can regulate expression of exogenous suicide genes throughout the Leishmania life cycle. We have shown that the A2 gene regulatory system has potential for the generation of developmentally attenuated L. donovani strains. Finally, we have performed a preliminary characterization of a gene, A2rel, that is tandemly associated with A2 genes in the genome. Contrary to A2 genes, the A2rel gene is well conserved in the Leishmania species. Although A2rel does not share sequence similarity with any known leishmanial genes characterized to date, it does appear to share characteristics with membrane-bound glycoproteins.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Matlashewski, Greg</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx17n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z713g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Leishmania -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Leishmaniasis -- Molecular aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zq28b"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The evolution of alternative morphologies : an empirical investigation in the wing dimorphic cricket, Gryllus firmus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Crnokrak, Peter</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Successional changes in a habitat may result in bottlenecks where few individuals in a population survive. During such events, changes in the genetic architecture of traits are predicted to occur as is subsequent inbreeding depression. In two literature reviews, I document that, (1) dominance variance increases in traits that are subject to strong selection and, (2) inbreeding depression is substantially higher in the wild as compared to captive populations. In addition to these changes, successional pressures may also result in the evolution of morphologies that allow organisms to avoid unfavourable conditions. A common dimorphism in insects is wing dimorphism, in which the macropterous morph is long-winged (LW), has functional flight muscles and is flight-capable while the micropterous morph (SW) has reduced wings and cannot fly. Due to the energy required to maintain the flight apparatus, macropterous individuals are predicted to have less energy available for reproduction. Trade-offs to macroptery have been documented in female insects. Gryllus firmus is a wing-dimorphic cricket of the southeastern USA. Although there are well established trade-offs between macroptery and reproduction in female crickets, no trade-offs have been demonstrated in male crickets. The prediction is that LW males, because they have to expend energy to maintain the flight apparatus, will call less and therefore attract fewer females than SW males. To be evolutionarily important, the traits involved in the trade-off; call duration, wing morph, wing muscle condition and lipid weight should have significant heritabilities and be genetically correlated. I found that SW males attracted significantly more females than LW males (mean % = 70% (SW) 30% (LW)). A significant difference in time spent calling was found between SW and LW males and as the difference in calling time between males increased, the likelihood of a female choosing the longer-calling male also increased. All the traits ha</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roff, Derek A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096884b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq28b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dimorphism (Animals)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gryllus -- Evolution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gryllus -- Morphology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqz20sv506"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Translational control mechanisms spanning the beginning, middle, and end of the mRNA</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Craig, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The initiation of mRNA translation in eukaryotes is a highly regulated process that impacts on the study of oncology, virology, and molecular embryology. Translation requires several eukaryotic initiation factors (eIFs) that promote binding of ribosomes to the mRNA. Phosphorylation of eIF2, the factor that binds the initiator methionyl-tRNA, occurs in response to a variety of cell stresses, and results in inhibition of translation. The dsRNA-activated protein kinase PKR mediates phosphorylation of eIF2alpha upon viral infection, and possesses anti-viral and anti-proliferative properties. We studied the role of an insert sequence located between kinase subdomains IV and V of PKR, for both kinase activity and binding of the pseudosubstrate K3L from vaccinia virus. While deletion of the kinase insert sequence resulted in a loss of kinase activity, it was not required for K3L binding. The K3L binding site was identified between subdomains V and VI, which likely also corresponds to the eIF2 binding site. While PKR inhibits viral protein synthesis, the La autoantigen is a cellular protein that potentiates cap-dependent translation of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), and cap-independent translation of poliovirus (PV) RNAs. Translation of both RNAs required the C-terminal portion of the La protein, which contains a dimerization domain. Addition of the dimerization domain caused a dose-dependent decrease in HIV and PV RNA translation in vitro, thus suggesting that La protein functions as a dimer during translation. Other regulators of translation include the 3' polyadenylate {poly(A)} tail of the mRNA and poly(A) binding protein (PABP). An interaction cloning approach was used to probe the function of PABP in mammalian cells, and a novel PABP-interacting protein (PAIP-1) was identified. PAIP-1 has homology to eIF4G and interacts with both PABP, and the RNA helicase eIF4A. Overexpression of PAIP-1 resulted in enhanced translation, possibly via bridging the 5' and 3' end</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sonenberg, Nahom</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xb30w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sv506</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acf95jd047"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Trace element partitioning between amphibole and basaltic melt</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dalpé, Claude</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effects of composition, pressure and oxygen fugacity on partition coefficients between amphibole and hydrous basaltic melt were studied at 1.5 to 2.5 GPa and 1000 to 1130°C. Partition coefficients (D i = concentration of element i in amphibole/concentration of i in melt) of large-ion-lithophile elements (LILE: Rb, Sr, Ba), high-field-strength elements (HFSE: Y, Zr, Nb, Ta, Hf), and rare-earth elements (REE: La to Lu) were determined between amphiboles and coexisting quenched melts created by partial crystallization of seven different starting compositions in a piston-cylinder high-pressure apparatus. Trace elements were analyzed by laser-ablation, microprobe inductively coupled plasma-mass spectrometer (LAM-ICP-MS). The effects of premium, temperature and oxygen fugacity on the partition coefficients are minor, but statistically measurable. Amphibole composition affects partitioning of these trace elements by a maximum factor of 3.5 in the range of pressures and temperatures studied with an oxygen fugacity range of 2 orders of magnitude above and below nickel-nickel oxide buffer. Experiments specifically investigating the role of Ti demonstrate that a positive correlation exists between amphibole VITi 4+ content and DBa, D Sr, DTa, D Zr, DLa, DCe, DPr, and DNd. Increasing pressure from 1.5 GPa, to 2.2 or 2.5 GPa (depending upon composition) increases DLILE, but decreases DHFSE and DREE. Raising the oxygen fugacity at 1.5 or 2.5 GPa by 3 orders of magnitude increases DRb, DBa, DLa, and D Nd, whereas DTi, D Hf, and DZr decrease; however, the maximum difference between partition coefficients measured at low and high oxygen fugacities is only a factor of 1.7. All of the effects of composition, pressure, and oxygen fugacity reflect the control of crystal chemistry on the partitioning of trace elements between amphibole and basaltic melt. No effects of melt composition were discerned in this study. The measured partition coefficients were used to investigate tr</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baker, Don R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q90b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jd047</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53wx546"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modular forms, quaternion algebras, and special values of L-functions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Daghigh, Hassan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Let f be a cusp form of weight 2 and level N. Let K be an imaginary quadratic field of discriminant, --D, and A an ideal class of K. We obtain precise formulas for the special values of the L-functions associated to the Rankin convolution of f and a theta series associated to the ideal class A , in terms of the Petersson scalar product of f with the theta series associated to an Eichler order in a positive definite quaternion algebra. Our work is an extension of the work done by Gross [7]. The central tools used in this thesis are Rankin's method and a reformulation of Gross of work of Waldspurger concerning central critical values.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Darmon, Henri</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j966w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx546</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d56zz30q"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular genetic analysis of Wilms' tumor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bardeesy, Nabeel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Wilms' tumor, a childhood malignancy of the kidney, is one of the most common pediatric tumors. The disease occurs in both sporadic and hereditary forms and is associated with a number of congenital disorders. Wilms' tumor appears to be genetically heterogeneous although only a single Wilms' tumor suppressor gene, designated WT1, has been isolated to date. WT1 encodes a zinc finger protein and is mutated in a subset of Wilms' tumors and in patients with Denys-Drash syndrome (DDS), an association of Wilms' tumor and severe genitourinary defects. This thesis reports a mutational analysis of WT1, detailing the spectrum and frequency of mutations in sporadic Wilms' tumors. Most WT1 mutations were homozygous and were predicted to cause premature termination of translation, suggesting that tumorigenesis associated with WT1 involves a two-hit mechanism. The mutational status of WT1 was determined in patients with variable expressivity of the DDS phenotype in order to assess potential genotype/phenotype correlations. Patients with less severe developmental anomalies had germline mutations predicted to result in truncated WT1 proteins, while those with full manifestation of DDS were characterized by missense mutations in the zinc finger region. This demonstrates that different mutations in WT1 are associated with specific effects on genitourinary development. We investigated the biochemical properties of WT1 and assessed the effects of some naturally occurring mutations. A number of studies have provided evidence that WT1 may be involved in RNA metabolism. We used an iterative selection method to identify potential RNA ligands to WT1. Specific, high affinity ligands were isolated. Mutational analysis elucidated structural features necessary for the RNA-protein interaction. These ligands may reflect RNA sequences targeted by WT1 in vivo. Since our studies demonstrated that WT1 mutations are restricted to a minority of Wilms' tumors, the understanding of mechanisms underlying Wilms' tumorigenesis required the identification of other genes which contribute to this malignancy. We studied the involvement of the p53 gene tumor suppressor, a critical regulator of abnormal cellular growth and genetic stability. P53 mutations were restricted to the rare anaplastic subtype of Wilms' tumor, a genetically unstable histological variant associated with poor prognosis and resistance to therapy. P53 mutations occurred as late events, associated with malignant progression. The association of p53 mutations with anaplasia allows rationalization of the clinicopathological features of this histological variant, indicating that p53 may regulate genome integrity and chemosensitivity of human cancer cells in vivo.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pelletier, Jerry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc868.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz30q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aht24wm03z"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>George Grant and the theology of the cross : the Christian foundations of his thought</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Athanasiadis, Harris</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Until his untimely death in 1988, George Grant was considered the foremost political philosopher Canada had produced. He was a critic of technological globalization who perceived early on its destructive potentialities on all facets of life, public and private. His writing focused on how the development of technological globalization endangered national sovereignty, undermined indigenous cultures and traditions, and threatened individual and communal rights. What is less known about Grant is the importance of faith in his life and how it informed his thought. Indeed, even though Grant did not write about his faith to any great extent, he claimed that it was the inspirational centre of everything he thought and wrote. This thesis will attempt to uncover the substance of Grant's faith and how it informs his thought. Grant was a Christian and a Protestant whose faith is best expressed in the words of Martin Luther: "A theologian of glory calls evil good and good evil. A theologian of the cross calls the thing what it actually is." (Luther's Works, vol. 31, p. 40) This quote is not incidental. Grant found in Luther's words and the theological orientation Luther named a "Theology of the Cross," the basis of his critical and constructive critique of the contemporary realities that concerned him. But even though Luther gave the words for this theological orientation, its significance in shaping Grant's thought was developed through his struggle with other theologians and philosophers, the most influential of whom was Simone Weil. This thesis will be an attempt to define this theological orientation as expressed by Luther, how Grant came upon it through formative influences and experiences along with formal studies in theology and philosophy, how Simone Weil gave intellectual and existential voice to this orientation in him, and how it informed Grant's perspective on all the thinkers he struggled with and all the issues that preoccupied his thought. Finally, this thesis</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hall, Douglas John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt50b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wm03z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Christianity -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grant, George Parkin, 1918-1988 -- Religion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Philosophical theology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Philosophy and religion</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75df328"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Measurement of diaphragm myoelectric activity in humans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beck, Jennifer, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is about the development and evaluation of a standardized method to measure the crural diaphragm electromyogram (EMG) in humans, with an esophageal electrode. In order for the diaphragm EMG to be physiologically relevant, its measurement and analysis require objective control of the disturbances and filter effects which can influence the sigma. One issue of importance is the maintenance of diaphragm-to-electrode positioning throughout the inspiration. In the present work, we describe a cross-correlation algorithm by which the position of the diaphragm along a multiple army esophageal electrode can be determined at any instant during a breath, and a second algorithm, the "double subtraction technique", which further minimizes the detrimental effects of diaphragm movement. The double subtraction technique also results in the improvement of the diaphragm EMG signal to noise ratio by 2 dB. By implementing these algorithms, we demonstrate in healthy subjects that there is no artifactual influence of lung volume/chest wall configuration on the diaphragm EMG frequency content nor on the diaphragm EMG signal strength during voluntary isometric contractions of the diaphragm. This is in contrast to the electrically elicited diaphragm compound muscle action potentials which are severely influenced by changes in lung volume. We also show that the volume-activation relationship of the diaphragm (required change in activation for changes in lung volume at a given tension) is directly related to the length-tension properties of the muscle. During dynamic, voluntary breathing maneuvers, we could find no evidence for an increase in diaphragm EMG signal strength when inspirations from functional residual capacity to total lung capacity (TLC) were performed at increasing inspiratory flow rates (velocities of shortening) up to 1.4 l/s. To account for anatomical and physiological differences between subjects, we demonstrate that the diaphragm EMG signal strength can be no</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grassino, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8382275.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df328</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128c65c"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigation of semileptonic B meson decays to p-wave charm mesons</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bellerive, Alain</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents an investigation of semileptonic B meson decays with a narrow P-wave charm meson in the final state. The data sample consists of 3.29 x 106 BB¯ events collected with the CLEO II detector at the Cornell Electron-positron Storage Ring. The P-wave charm mesons are reconstructed in the chain of decays: D0J→D*+p- ,D*+→D0p+,D 0→K-p+ or D0→K-p+p 0 . Study of the decay B-→D*+p0ℓ -nℓ&amp;d1; reveals useful information about the deficit observed in inclusive charm semileptonic B decays and the effective couplings of the W boson to heavy quark mesons. The results obtained for the exclusive semileptonic product branching fractions are BB-→D0 1ℓ-nℓ &amp;d1;B D01→D*+p - = (0.373 +/- 0.085 +/- 0.052 +/- 0.024)% and BB-→D*0 2ℓ-nℓ&amp;d1; BD*0 2→D*+p- &lt; 0.16% (90% C.L.). The assumption BD01→D* +p- = 67% and BD*02→D *+p- = 20% implies BB-→D01 ℓ-nℓ&amp;d1; (0.56 0.13 +/- 0.08 +/- 0.04)% and BB-→D*0 2ℓnℓ&amp;d1; &lt; 0.8% (90% C.L.). These results indicate that at least 18% of the total B semileptonic rate is still unaccounted for by the observed exclusive decays, B&amp;d1;→D0ℓ- n&amp;d1;ℓ, B&amp;d1;→D*ℓn &amp;d1;ℓ,B&amp;d1; →D1ℓn&amp;d1; ℓ, and B&amp;d1;→D*2 ℓn&amp;d1;ℓ . Furthermore, the first measurement of the q 2 spectrum for B-→D01ℓn &amp;d1;ℓ is presented. The present analysis also suggests that the Λ QCD/mQ corrections beyond the HQS prescriptions might be significant in the theoretical treatment of the dynamics of B semileptonic decays to excited charm mesons.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Macfarlane, David B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nj91b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128c65c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988m82w"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Medical pluralism : disease, health and healing on the coast of Kenya, 1840-1940</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Malowany, Maureen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Kenya Coast is populated by Africans, Arab-descendants, Indians and Europeans. As part of the Indian Ocean trading network, the predominantly Muslim Coast is an unusually rich site for investigating the historical interface of distinct medical systems---Islamic, ayurvedic and indigenous---which gave rise to an ever-evolving situation of 'medical plurality'. This thesis addresses medical knowledge, practice and authority on the Coast from the mid-nineteenth to mid-twentieth centuries. The Coast is significant because of the variety of populations which inhabit the area, the early development of Muslim institutions for learning, and the Coast's isolation from white settler-dominated central Kenya, which allowed its populations a relative degree of political and social autonomy. Particularly crucial for the Coast in this period is the intersection of African migration to the cities, the resulting pressures placed upon urban populations, and changes in disease patterns and intensity. This combined with contests over land appropriation among elites form a backdrop to the Colonial State's attempts to provide sanitation and public health to growing urban communities. Local responses to disease and colonial public health initiatives point to the intersection of multiple medical understandings and practices on the Coast. This thesis explores the continuities of indigenous medical systems, the resulting inability of Western medicine to gain uncontested orthodoxy, and questions the conceptualization of 'traditional medicine' as a static, homogenous system. Interactions within various 'traditional medicines' are explained to show how indigenous healing and therapeutics have drawn on both formal, text-based and informal, experiential medical knowledge; coexisting and, in some periods, converging with external medical authorities. Nineteenth century Western scientific medicine remained one of a multiplicity of choices available to local populations. Not until the advent of institutionalized Western medicine did Western medical practice become more widely accepted. Africans' encounter with Western science occurred primarily through British colonial attempts to regulate housing and purify the water supply. The impetus to provide better health for East Africans peaked in the 1920s as the British sought to generate a "productive" labour force. It is the reconciliation of economic demands, increasing populations and inadequate medical support that provides the background for the investigation of changing patterns of health and disease.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Echenberg, Myron</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p646q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988m82w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Public health -- Kenya -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Medicine -- Kenya -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pj129"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Contributions to automated-theorem-proving and formal methods with applications to control systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mackling, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Part 1. We show that the standard notions of tautology and subsumption can be naturally generalized, (so that refutation completeness is preserved with respect to the associated deletion), within the context of (a specified set of) modified deduction rules for binary clausal resolution-refutation which build-in the reflexivity, symmetry, transitivity and predicate substitutivity axioms for equality. To this end, first a resolution system, PC&lt;, in which equality has no special status, is introduced and its refutation completeness under subsumption and tautology deletion shown. The generalized notions of subsumption and tautology, Sigma0-subsumption and Sigma 0-tautology, respectively, are then formulated and analyzed. EPC &lt;, a system which provides an adequate deductive context for refutation completeness under deletion with respect to these generalized notions, is then introduced. To prove this completeness, some technical notions (principally, to allow an induction) are introduced, and a number of technical results are obtained. Additionally, some clause "normalization" techniques including generalized forms of replacement factoring and a form of demodulation, are suitably formulated, and the preservation of refutation completeness with the further introduction of these normalization procedures is shown. Some refinements for the rules are offered, as well as a possible further generalization for subsumption, and a generalized form of a special case of replacement resolution, folding. Part 2. We present and analyze some primitives for the analysis and control specification of nondeterministic finite state machines (FSMs), analogous to the Reachability and Current State Estimate Set primitives, introduced as basic predicates, in COCOLOG [8, 9, 7, 38]. In terms of these predicates, an aggregation method for the hierarchical decomposition of a FSM is given, in terms of centered covers of the state space, whereby a hierarchical control may be synthesized and applied. A special class of covers is presented which possesses lattice theoretic properties generalizing the results of [13, 42, 41, 43, 40, 3]. A broader class of (so called) regular covers is introduced which, though lacking closure under any similar lattice operations, is sufficient to guarantee, in an obvious sense, the completeness of the abstraction, (which guarantees meta-level controllability under appropriate circumstances). Other cover classes, suitable for controllable FSMs are then introduced, and the lattice theoretic properties are therein recovered.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Caines, P. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r418.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj129</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s189g"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Syntactic and semantic structures in cocolog logic control</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martínez-Mascarúa, Carlos Mario</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The research presented in this thesis is formulated within the Conditional Observer and Controller Logic (COCOLOG) framework. COCOLOG is a family of first order languages and associated theories for the design and implementation of controllers for discrete event systems (DESs). The opening part of this thesis presents a high level formulation of COCOLOG called Macro COCOLOG. First, we present the theory of Macro COCOLOG languages, a framework for the enhancement of the original COCOLOG language via definitional constructions. Second, we present the theory of Macro COCOLOG actions, a framework for the enhancement of COCOLOG allowing the utilisation of hierarchically aggregated control actions. In this thesis Macro COCOLOG is applied to a pair of examples: the control of the motion of a mobile robot and the flow of water through a tank. The next question addressed in the thesis is the possibility of expanding the original COCOLOG theories in various ways concerning the fundamental issues of the arithmetic system and the notion of reachability in DESs as expressed in COCOLOG. Specifically, the fundamental nature of the reachability predicate, Rbl(·,·,·), is explored, and found to be completely determined by notions axiomatised in subtheories of the original COCOLOG theory. This result effectively reduces the complexity of the proofs originally involving Rbl(·,·,·). Following this line of thought, two sets of Macro languages and associated theories are developed which are shown to be as powerful (in terms of expressiveness and deductive scope) as the original COCOLOG theories and hence, necessarily, as powerful as Markovian fragment COCOLOG theories. A final result along these lines is that the control law itself (originally expressed in a set of extra logical Conditional Control Rules) can be incorporated into the COCOLOG theories via function symbol definition. The efficient implementation of COCOLOG controllers serves as a motivation for the final two chapters of the thesis. A basic result in this chapter is that a COCOLOG controller may itself be realized as a DES since, for any COCOLOG controller, it is shown that one may generate a finite state machine realizing that controller. This realization can then be used for real time (i.e. reactive) control. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Caines, Peter E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z20c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s189g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, System Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qk521"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>D-brane bound states and two-dimensional black holes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Michaud, Guy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present thesis contains research in two related avenues of theoretical physics. We first present supersymmetric low-energy background field solutions of D-brane bound states in type IIA and type IIB theories. We derive new solutions describing two parallel D-branes which have a difference in dimension of two, using a procedure which involves rotations and T-duality transformations. We also present original supersymmetric background field solutions in which the D-branes are at angles to each other. These solutions are distinguished by the presence of an Hermitian metric on the internal compact space, and again, T-duality transformations are used to build more supersymmetric configurations of D-branes at angles. The second part of the research presents a two-dimensional model of gravity which possesses black hole solutions. We study Hawking radiation and we explicitly show that it has a mass-dependent temperature. Semiclassical issues are also investigated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Myers, Robert C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881n78f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk521</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac247dt83p"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the mechanisms of mRNA binding to ribosomes in eukaryotes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haghighat, Ashkan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The binding of eukaryotic ribosomes to mRNA is a complex process that is considered to be rate-limiting in translation initiation, and consequently a key target for translational regulation. Ribosome binding to mRNA is facilitated by the 5' cap structure, m7GpppN (where N is any nucleotide). The initiation factor eIF4F plays a key role in regulating translation rates. eIF4F is a three-subunit complex composed of eIF4E, the cap-binding protein; eIF4A, an RNA helicase; and eIF4G (p220), which bridges eIF4E and eIF4A, and enhances dramatically the interaction of eIF4E with the mRNA 5' cap structure. eIF4F in conjunction with another initiation factor, eIF4B, is thought to unwind the mRNA 5 '-secondary structure to facilitate the binding of mRNA to ribosomes The activity of eIF4F, and the regulation of mRNA binding to ribosomes is tightly correlated with the growth status of the cell. Recently, proteins that interact with eIF4E, termed 4E-BPs, have been identified; these proteins link translation initiation and growth promoting signal transduction pathways. Phosphorylation of 4E-BPs in response to insulin and mitogens decreases their affinity for eIF4E. 4E-BPs compete with eIF4G for binding to eIF4E through binding domains that share common sequence motifs. Consequently, 4E-BPs restrain eIF4E from forming an active cap-binding complex, eIF4F, and prevent subsequent binding of 40S ribosomal subunit to capped mRNAs. Under these conditions, the binding of eIF4E to the mRNA cap structure is extremely inefficient. As a result, cap- and eIF4E-dependent translation is downregulated. Modulation of eIF4F activity is also observed following infection by certain viruses. One of the most dramatic examples of this occurs upon picornaviral infection. As we report here, eIF4G alone is a relatively poor substrate for cleavage by the rhinovirus 2A proteinase (2Apro). However, an eIF4G-eIF4E complex is cleaved efficiently by the 2Apro suggesting that eIF4F is a preferred target for di</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sonenberg, Nahum</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn3013030.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dt83p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xt51m"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Learning to teach in higher education : a descriptive case study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gryspeerdt, Danielle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Several recent theoretical frameworks describe the process of learning how to teach in higher education in terms of change over time (Shulman, 1986, 1987; Sherman, Arminstead, Flower, Barksdale, &amp; Reif, 1997; Ramsden, 1992; Sprague and Nyquist, 1989). The existing research on changes in teacher thinking, feeling, and practice focuses almost exclusively on teachers at the elementary and secondary levels; research concerning these concepts in higher education is rather scant Researchers have studied a complex array of issues from various perspectives using a variety of methodologies. This study followed a pre-structured case methodology (Miles, 1990) and describes in rich detail the process involved in learning to teach in higher education. The two participants in this study were graduate students in Linguistics in their final year of doctoral studies. They were followed for one semester while each taught an undergraduate course in linguistics. Data sources included-five semi-structured interviews, course documents, field notes, and videotapes of classroom activities. The trustworthiness of data and subsequent interpretations were established through attention to Lincoln and Guba's (1985) elements of trustworthiness. The learning process they incurred while learning how to teach was documented for each using pattern coding techniques (Miles &amp; Huberman, 1984). A change process network was created for each participant to display the findings. Findings were then compared with theoretical frameworks and research approaches in the current literature. The findings of this study demonstrate the complexity of the process of learning to teach and the usefulness of the proposed frameworks and research approaches in describing and explaining the process. Furthermore, by being able to characterize this learning process, faculty developers can be more informed as to how best to intervene to maximally facilitate this process.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Amundsen, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cc63k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt51m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Teachers -- Training of</dc:subject><dc:subject>College teaching</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p205w"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Toward testing a general theory of addictions : an examination of gambling, risk-taking, and related personality variables in adolescents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gupta, Rina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The three reported studies examine the possible etiology of gambling behavior and its correlates in adolescents with respect to motivational factors, predisposing factors as assessed by personality, depression and risk-taking traits, and by testing Jacobs' (1986) General Theory of Addictions which specifies a path toward the development of an addiction. Furthermore, the validity of the Arnett Inventory of Sensation Seeking (AISS) (Arnett, 1994) as a sensitive measure for assessing risk-taking in adolescent gamblers is assessed. Findings offer support for the premise of an addictive personality with problem and pathological gamblers differing from the norm on several personality dimensions including Excitability, Conformity, Self-Discipline, and Cheerfulness as assessed by the High School Personality Questionnaire. Furthermore, this group of adolescent problem gamblers was characterized by depression, high risk-taking, and tendencies toward dissociation. Support for Jacobs' General Theory of Addictions was ascertained, and the AISS was found to be a useful instrument for evaluating risk-taking among adolescents as it pertains to gambling behavior.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Derevensky, Jeffrey L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m840r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p205w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Compulsive gambling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Risk-taking (Psychology) in adolescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Addicts</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88cj339"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>ita</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Italian</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'inamoramento de Orlando : dallo spettacolo al romanzo</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gritti, Valentina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Due to the lack of a critical approach that takes into account the theatrical aspect of Boiardo's poem, we have undertaken a semiotic analysis that brings forth some peculiarities of the poem's theatrical performance, most of which stem from the traditional "cantari". The intertextual comparison between the principle "cantari epico-cavallereschi" and the "Inamoramento de Orlando" permits us to reevaluate the importance of these sources, that are, in our opinion, essential to the comprehension of the poem. However, these sources have not been, to date, considered determining by literary critics. In addition, we highlight the various aspects of communication between the narrator and his audience. Finally, the analysis of the rhetorical structure of the poem (proems, epilogues, narrative connectors, commentary, orality) allows us to propose an hypothesis of double reception of the "Inamoramento de Orlando " as well as a double reading of the poem, both as a theatrical representation and as a novel. This provides Boiardo's poem with its special trait of "open text".</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Predelli, Maria Bendinelli</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q584g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj339</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Boiardo, Matteo Maria, 1440 or 41-1494. Orlando innamorato</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>