<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r769c"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Novel roles of Neurexin in regulating «Drosophila» visual circuit function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Izawa-Ishiguro, Arianna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les molécules d’adhérence cellulaire sont des éléments essentiels dans les subtilités d’intégrité synaptique et de la fonction du circuits neuraux. En raison de leurs natures conservées au cours de l'évolution parmi des systèmes vertébrés et invertébrés, ils peuvent donc être examinés entre espèces différentes pour comprendre leurs rôles et interactions dans la base moléculaire de la maladie neurologique humaine et du développement des troubles. Le système oculaire de Drosophila melanogaster s’avère être un système modèle précieux pour définir ces molécules en raison de sa relative simplicité de connectivité neurale et de sa similarité structurelle reconnaissable à ses homologues mammifères. Chacun des huit neurones photorécepteurs (R1-R8) qui constituent les unités individuelles de ce circuits oculaires a besoin de son propre sous-ensemble de ces molécules d’adhérence pour méditer le développement et la fonction des circuits. Des études récentes dans le laboratoire Rao révèlent de nouveaux rôles de deux molécules d'adhésion Borderless (Bdl) (un membre des protéines transmembranaires de la famille IgSF9) et Dnlg2 (l'homologue mouche de la neuroligine) dans les photorécepteurs R8. Dnlg2 et Bdl s'associent et sont nécessaires pour promouvoir le transport axonal des vésicules synaptiques (SV) dans les axones des photorécepteurs R8. Puisque la neurexine est un partenaire de liaison trans-synaptique bien connu de la neuroligine chez les vertébrés et les invertébrés, je fais l'hypothèse que les homologues de la neurexine chez la drosophile (Dnrx) sont également impliqués dans la régulation du transport des SV dans les axones R8. En effectuant une analyse de perte de fonction et de type de cellule spécifique, j'ai trouvé que Dnrx-1 agit à la fois pré- et post-synaptique dans la régulation du transport axonal des composants SV. Fait intéressant, les interactions trans-synaptiques médiées par Dnrx-1 sont également nécessaires pour spécifier l'identité du sous-type R8. Ces résultats apportent un éclairage nouveau sur la fonction des protéines bien connues de la famille des neurexines</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cell-adhesion molecules are critical components in the intricacies of synaptic integrity and neural circuitry function. Due to their evolutionarily conserved nature among vertebrate and invertebrate systems, they can therefore be investigated across different species to understand their roles and interactions in the molecular basis of human neurological disease and disorder development. The Drosophila melanogaster visual system proves to be a valuable model system to characterize these molecules due to its relative simplicity of neural connectivity and recognizable structural similarity to its mammalian counterparts. Each of the eight photoreceptor neurons (R1-R8) that constitute the individual units in this visual circuitry require their own subset of adhesion molecules to mediate circuit development and function.Recent studies in the Rao lab reveal novel roles of two adhesion molecules Borderless (Bdl) (a member of the IgSF9-family transmembrane proteins) and Dnlg2 (the fly homolog of neuroligin) in R8 photoreceptors. Dnlg2 and Bdl associate with each other and are required for promoting axonal transport of synaptic vesicles (SV) in R8 photoreceptor axons. Since neurexin is a well-known trans-synaptic binding partner of neuroligin in both vertebrates and invertebrates, I hypothesize that the homologs of neurexin in Drosophila (Dnrx) are also involved in regulating SV transport in R8 axons. By performing loss-of-function and cell-type-specific knockdown analysis, I found that Dnrx-1 acts both pre- and post-synaptically in regulating axonal transport of SV components. Interestingly, Dnrx-1-mediated trans-synaptic interactions are also required for specifying R8 subtype identity. These results shed new light on the function of the well-known neurexin family proteins</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yong Rao</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j3451.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r769c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s919m"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Enhancement of chickpea and aquafaba quality by high pressure processing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>ALSalman, Fatemah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The first part of the research is focused on the effect of high pressure treatment on reduction of chickpea soaking and cooking time through effective hydration. HP treatment allowed to reach the desired hydration percentage (≈ 90-93%) in less than an hour where similar results could be reached with overnight soaking without HP processing. HP-soaking with multiple cycles resulted in higher hydration rate and softer texture, 48N for pre-soaked HP treated samples and 70N for HP treated samples without pre-soaking compared to 368N of untreated samples. High-pressure-treated samples improved chickpeas quality by reducing tannin content to around 26.7% and phytic acid content to around 16.7% from initial levels in addition to enhancing their textural properties. FTIR supported the effect of HP on chickpea hydration. Using pressure cooker gave desired textural properties in 20min that could not be reached within 60min in conventional cooking.With the second part, the focus was on aquafaba, its characterization, evaluation and optimization of its functional and antinutritional properties. The results showed that chickpea to water ratio and cooking time had significant effects on most of the responses. Optimal conditions were 1.5: 3.5 chickpea to water ratio cooked for 60 min in a pressure cooker. Regarding comparing aquafaba optimized condition with aquafaba from cans, results showed that aquafaba from cans had higher phytates content, protein content on a dry basis, foaming properties, oil holding capacity compared to our optimized conditions, principle reason being the long thermal processing times at much higher temperatures.The third part of research was to evaluate the factors affecting aquafaba rheological and thermal properties. The optimal conditions were 2:3 chickpea to water ratio cooked for 60 min where viscosity and elasticity were the maximum at that point confirming network formation. Regarding aquafaba thermal properties, higher temperature of denaturation (Td) was for samples cooked for 60 min which is an indication that more than 50% of the protein has already denatured so the protein is more stable. The fourth part of research focused on the influence of high-pressure processing (HPP) on aquafaba proteins. HPP improved aquafaba emulsion capacity and stability compared to the control sample. DSC results supports the results of high hydrophobicity through the increase in the degree of denaturation where both played a role for enhancing emulsion properties. HPP could also reduce protein aggregates by 33.3%, while β- sheets decreased by 4.2- 87.6% in which both are correlated to increased protein digestibility. α-helices dropped by 50%.The fifth and last chapter focused on improving carbohydrates fraction in aquafaba by HPP. HPP with different pressure levels and aquafaba concentration increased viscosity as well as strengthened gel structure by increasing elasticity (G’). By comparing HP-treated samples to the control, we found that starch digestibility was enhanced from 24.3 to 26.9% (RDS), 0.8 to 4.1% (SDS), 25.1 to 31.5% (TDS), and 3.8 to 4.4% (RS). Crystallinity increased by FTIR and XRD measurement</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La première partie de la recherche se concentre sur l'effet du traitement à haute pression (HP) sur la réduction du temps de trempage et de cuisson des pois chiches grâce à une hydratation efficace. Le traitement HP a permis d'atteindre le pourcentage d'hydratation souhaité (≈ 90-93%) en moins d'une heure où des résultats similaires pouvaient être atteints avec un trempage d'une nuit sans traitement HP. Le trempage HP avec plusieurs cycles a entraîné un taux d'hydratation plus élevé, et 48N pour les échantillons traités HP pré-trempés et 70N pour les échantillons traités HP sans pré-trempage, contre 368N pour les échantillons non traités. Les échantillons de pois chiches traités à haute pression avaient une qualité améliorée en réduisant la teneur en tanin à environ 26,7% et la teneur en acide phytique à environ 16,7% par rapport aux niveaux initiaux en plus d'améliorer leurs propriétés texturales. FTIR ont démontré l'effet de HP sur les échantillons de pois chiches. L'utilisation d'un autocuiseur a donné les propriétés texturales souhaitées en 20 min qui ne pouvaient pas être atteintes en 60 min en cuisine conventionnelle.Dans la deuxième partie, l'accent a été mis sur aquafaba sa caractérisation, et l'évaluation et l'optimisation de ses propriétés fonctionnelles et anti-nutritionnelles. Les résultats ont montré que le rapport pois chiches / eau et le temps de cuisson avaient des effets significatifs sur la plupart des réponses. Les conditions optimales étaient un rapport de pois chiches à eau de 1,5: 3,5 cuit pendant 60 min dans un autocuiseur En ce qui concerne la comparaison de l'aquafaba condition optimisée avec l'aquafaba en conserve, les résultats ont montré que l'aquafaba en conserve avait une teneur en phytates plus élevée, une teneur en protéines plus élevée sur une base sèche, des propriétés moussantes, et une capacité de rétention d'huile supérieure à nos conditions optimisées; la raison principale étant les longs temps de traitement thermique à des températures beaucoup plus élevées.La troisième partie de la recherche a évalué les facteurs affectant les propriétés rhéologiques et thermiques de l'aquafaba. La les conditions optimales étaient un rapport pois chiches / eau 2: 3 cuit pendant 60 min où la viscosité et l'élasticité étaient maximales à ce point, confirmant la formation du réseau. En ce qui concerne les propriétés thermiques de l'aquafaba, une température de dénaturation (Td) plus élevée a été observée pour les échantillons cuits pendant 60 min, ce qui indique que plus de 50% de la protéine s'est déjà dénaturée, de sorte que la protéine est plus stable. La quatrième partie de la recherche s'est concentrée sur l'influence du traitement à haute pression sur les protéines aquafaba. Le HP a amélioré la capacité et la stabilité de l'émulsion aquafaba par rapport à l'échantillon témoin. Il a été prouvé par DSC en augmentant le degré de denaturation, qui est indicatif d'une hydrophobicité plus élevée, que les propriétés de l'émulsion ont été améliorées. Le HP pourrait également réduire les agrégats de protéines de 33,3%, tandis que les feuillets β diminuaient de 4,2 à 87,6%, les deux étant corrélés à une digestibilité accrue des protéines. Les hélices α ont chuté de 50%. Le cinquième et dernier chapitre s'est concentré sur l'amélioration de la fraction des glucides dans l'aquafaba par HP. HP avec différents niveaux de pressurisation et concentration en aquafaba a augmenté la viscosité ainsi que la structure du gel renforcée en augmentant l’élasticité (G’). En comparant les échantillons traités par HP au témoin, nous avons constaté que la digestibilité de l'amidon était considérablement améliorée de 24,3 à 26,9% (RDS), 0,8 à 4,1% (SDS), 25,1 à 31,5% (TDS) et 3,8 à 4,4% (RS). La cristallinité est passée de 6,9 × 10-1 dans l'échantillon témoin à 8,0-8,4 × 10-1 pour les échantillons sous pression en mesurant le rapport de 1048/1022 cm-1 par FTIR et par mesure XRD</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hosahalli Ramaswamy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bk40n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s919m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pm62x"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communications Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Imparing Life: Electroshock weaponry, non-lethality and affective governance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bensari, Chahinez</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine la construction du Taser en tant que technologie de contrôle social non mortelle, suggérant que celle-ci dépend en partie de l’attention portée aux cas où l’arme a causé la mort pour légitimer sa capacité à sauver des vies en temps normal. De plus, certains discours corporatifs et scientifiques convergent afin de désavouer la douleur causée par électrochoc en tant que torture psychique et corporelle de par les notions de blessure qu’ils présentent. J’explore comment la littérature scientifique et biomédicale sur les effets de l’électricité sur le corps humain ignore l’expérience affective du corps et de ses sens afin de discuter la façon dont Axon, le principal producteur de Tasers instrumentalise l’importance de protéger la vie d’individus appréhendés dans le discours public articulé par ses représentants et exploite et amoindrit celle-ci électriquement. J’entreprends cette analyse matérielle- discursive afin de comprendre comment Axon comprend la douleur et le mal produits au travers de rencontres avec son arme à chocs électromusculaires. Cette thèse complique le caractère « sûr » des effets de l’électrochoc en examinant si le dommage «négligeable » qui découle de l’incapacitation forcée du corps humain pourrait être précisément ce qui garantit l’efficacité du Taser à mettre fin aux altercations policières. En évaluant les implications biopolitiques de l’institutionnalisation d’une technologie qui simultanément exploite et dénie les capacités sensorielles corporelles par le biais d’un cadre binaire de non/mortalité, cette thèse soulève des questions quant au statut du corps humain et de ses sens en tant que moyens exploitables pour assurer l’ordre social aux États-Unis contemporains</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis examines how the Taser’s construction as a non-lethal technology of social control rests in part on the focus on cases in which it has caused death to legitimate its power as a life-saving technology otherwise. And in another, on the ways in which corporate and scientific discourses converge to disavow the causing of pain by electroshock as a form as bodily and psychic torture through the understandings of injury they present. I investigate how scientific and biomedical literature on the effects of electricity on the human body disavows the body’s affective experience of its senses to discuss how Axon, the main manufacturer of Taser weapons, instrumentalizes the importance of protecting apprehended individuals’ lives in the public discourse enacted by its representatives at the same time as its weapons electrically harness and undermine it. I undertake this material-discursive analysis to understand how Axon itself understands harm and pain produced through the human body’s encounter with its electromuscular shock weapon. This thesis complicates Axon’s framing of the “safe” effects of electroshocking by examining whether and how so-called negligible injuries and suffering caused by forcibly incapacitating the human body may be what the company uses to guarantee its device’s “efficiency” in ending altercations. In assessing the biopolitical implications of the institutionalization of a technology that simultaneously harnesses bodily sensory capacities and disavows them through a binary of non/lethality, this thesis raises critical questions regarding the status of the human body and its senses as exploitable means for securing social order in contemporary America</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carrie Rentschler</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Yuriko Furuhata</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593v0875.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pm62x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Art History and Communications Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xx410"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Time-resolved terahertz spectroscopy on organometallic halide perovskites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lan, Yang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Durant la dernière décennie, les pérovskites organométalliques à halogénure (POH) ont attiré un immense intérêt partout dans le monde, comme étant un nouveau matériau semiconducteur prometteur pour les applications photovoltaïques et opto-électroniques. Parmi leurs propriétés exceptionnelles, un faible taux de recombinaison et une insensibilité générale aux défauts demeurent à expliquer. La formation de grand polarons dans les POH est parmi les mécanismes proposés. Jusqu’à maintenant, aucune évidence directe n’a démontré un tel couplage électron-phonon.Dans ce travail, nous utilisons la spectroscopie multi-THz à résolution temporelle (STRT) basée sur un plasma d’air, produit par un laser à deux couleurs, ayant un spectre en fréquence couvrant l’entièreté de la région THz afin de fournir une évidence directe de la formation de polarons dans les POH. Nous avons étudié la dynamique des porteurs de charge après une photoexcitation du gap d’un monocristal de méthylammonium plomb-triiodure (MAPI) à la température de la pièce. Nos résultats démontrent que les porteurs de charge photoexcités sont corrélés au réseau via un battement quantique cohérent entre un seul mode de phonons optique longitudinale (LO) effectif à ∼3.7 THz et la fréquence THz de sonde sur une échelle de temps sous la picoseconde après l’excitation. Nous avons étudié davantage la dynamique des porteurs de charge dans la phase orthorhombique du MAPI à basse température. Par contre, aucun battement quantique évident n’est observé. Une oscillation cohérente hautement amortie apparaît plutôt dans la réflectivité THz transitoire autour de 0.9 THz pour des fréquences sondes comprises dans la bande Reststrahlen. Ceci suggère que la dynamique des porteurs de charges dans la phase orthorhombique du MAPI n’est probablement pas complétement corrélée a un seul phonon LO distinct. Un exciton lié à un défaut est également observé autour de 7-8 THz ce qui indique des corrélations excitoniques pour des porteurs de charges photoexcités dans le MAPI</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Organometallic halide perovskites (OHP) have attracted tremendous world-wide interest over the past decade, as novel semiconducting materials for the photovoltaic and optoelectronic applications. Among their exceptional properties is an unusually low recombination rate and a general insensitivity to defects, which remain to be explained. Among the proposed mechanisms is large polaron formation in OHPs, however to date no direct evidence for such charge-lattice coupling has been shown.In this work, we utilize time-resolved multi-terahertz (THz) spectroscopy (TRTS) based on a two-color laser induced air plasma with spectrum covering the entire THz region, to provide direct evidence of polaron formation in OHPs. We investigate the charge carrier dynamics after band edge photoexcitation of single crystal methylammonium lead triiodide (MAPI) at room temperature. Our results show photoexcited charge carriers are correlated to the lattice via a coherent quantum beat between a single eﬀective longitudinal optical (LO) phonon mode at ∼ 3.7 THz and the THz probe frequency for sub-picosecond time scales after photoexcitation.We further study charge carrier dynamics in the low temperature orthorhombic phase of MAPI, however no clear quantum beat is observed. Instead, a highly damped coherent oscillation in the transient THz reﬂectivity at∼0.9 THz is revealed for probe frequencies within the reststrahlen band. This suggests charge carrier dynamics in orthorhombic phase of MAPI is not likely to be fully correlated to a single,distinct LO phonon. A defect bound exciton is also observed at 7-8 THz and indicatesexcitonic correlations for photoexcited charge carriers in MAPI</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David Cooke</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mark Sutton</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j3469.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xx410</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j565m"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The development of soft robots capable of surface traction modulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wu, Qiyang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'auteur implique une nouvelle technologie, l'adhésion électrostatique, dans des robots mous pour réaliser la fonction de montée. Dans le travail à base d'élastomère, l'adhésion électrostatique est appliquée à un robot souple quadrupède en incorporant un tampon d'adhérence mince et conforme (en PDMS et encre Ag / AgCl) sur chaque jambe du robot. Avec l'aide de l'adhérence inhérente au PDMS, les expériences montrent que le tampon d'adhérence peut fournir un changement assez important (jusqu'à 3,1 N) de la force de friction entre la jambe du robot et le substrat correspondant. Le robot peut avancer, reculer ou rester au même endroit à l'aide de la régulation des forces de friction induites par l'adhésion électrostatique. Un modèle cinématique simplifié est développé pour le robot quadrupède pour expliquer le rôle important joué par les forces de frottement, et par conséquent, pour montrer le potentiel prometteur de l'adhésion électrostatique dans le développement de robots mous d'escalade. Dans ce travail, la présence d'adhérence électrostatique permet non seulement au robot de changer la direction de déplacement sur le plan horizontal, mais rend également le robot capable de grimper sur une surface glissante inclinée plutôt que de glisser vers le bas.Afin de surmonter les problèmes posés par la gravité, l'auteur développe un robot doux à base de papier qui réalise à la fois une montée horizontale et verticale sur un substrat placé à 90 degrés. Le robot, fabriqué à partir de papier et d'alliage à mémoire de forme (SMA), peut être contrôlé pour grimper aux murs sous certaines combinaisons de modèles d'activation d'adhérence électrostatique et de contraction du SMA. L'adhérence électrostatique est appliquée à l'aide d'une structure en papier avec des électrodes interdigitées intégrées. Cette structure, entièrement compatible avec le robot à base de papier, est capable de produire des forces d'adhésion fortes et fiables (la force de friction résultante peut être aussi élevée que 1,65 N sur des substrats spécifiques), et elle peut être facilement allumée et éteinte à l'aide d'un commercial convertisseur haute tension. Le SMA intégré dans le robot est utilisé pour déformer le corps du robot et induire des déplacements contractuels tout en étant activé. Un modèle SMA à ressort de polarisation appliqué à ce robot est simulé et comparé aux résultats expérimentaux, qui montre une précision de prédiction relativement bonne. Avec les structures ci-dessus, nous démontrons la capacité de marche et d'escalade de ce robot avec une vitesse de locomotion de 1 mm / s. L'escalade sur un mur vertical dans les deux directions verticale et horizontale est réalisée.De plus, une version non attachée du robot d'escalade à base de papier est développée pour rapprocher le robot de certaines tâches. Afin d'intégrer toute l'électronique, la taille du robot est plus grande que la version captive pour renforcer sa capacité à maintenir des poids et à lutter contre la gravité. Un minuscule microcontrôleur, Attiny84, est utilisé pour contrôler l'activation du SMA et l'activation / désactivation des plots d'adhésion. Chaque plot a un MOSFET haute tension individuel pour contrôler sa force d'adhésion. À l'aide du MOSFET haute tension, le couple de chute est beaucoup plus faible qu'auparavant et le problème de la puissance de sortie du petit microcontrôleur est également résolu. Avec les structures ci-dessus, nous démontrons la capacité de marche et d'escalade de ce robot avec une vitesse de locomotion de 0,6-0,8 mm / s. L'escalade sur un mur vertical dans les deux directions verticale et horizontale est également réalisée. Pendant ce temps, depuis sa propriété non liée, ce robot a le potentiel d'effectuer des tâches telles que la détection de surface et la vidéosurveillance, ce qui rend le robot souple plus proche de l'application réelle</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The author involves a new technology, electrostatic adhesion, into soft robots to realize the climbing-up function. In the elastomer-based work, the electrostatic adhesion is applied to a quadruped soft robot by embedding a thin and compliant adhesion pad (made of PDMS and Ag/AgCl ink) onto each leg of the robot. With the help of the inherent stickiness of PDMS, experiments show the adhesion pad can provide a quite change (up to 3.1 N) of the friction force between robot leg and corresponding substrate. This friction change allows the robot to change its moving pattern under the same control sequence. The robot can move forward, backwards, or stay in the same place with the help of regulating friction forces induced by electrostatic adhesion. A simplified kinematic model is developed for the quadruped robot to explain the important role played by friction forces, and consequently, to show the promising potential of electrostatic adhesion in developing wall-climbing soft robots. In this work, the presence of electrostatic adhesion not only allows the robot to change the moving direction on horizontal plane, but also makes the robot capable of climbing up an inclined slippery surface rather than slide down. However, a vertically 90-degree climbing is not realized on this quadruped robot since the robot’s pneumatic actuation will produce a large falling torque under gravity which will break the attachment of legs to substrate.In order to overcome the problems brought by gravity, the author develops a paper-based soft robot which realizes both horizontal and vertical climbing on a 90-degree vertical-placed substrate. The robot, made from paper and shape memory alloy (SMA), can be controlled to climb walls under certain combinations of activation patterns of electrostatic adhesion and contraction of the SMA. Electrostatic adhesion is applied using a paper structure with embedded interdigitated electrodes. This structure, fully compatible with the paper-based robot, is able to output strong and reliable adhesion forces (the resultant friction force can be as high as 1.65N on specific substrates), and it can be easily turned on and off using a commercial high-voltage converter. The SMA embedded in the robot is employed to deform the robot body and induce contracting displacements while being activated. A bias-spring SMA model applied to this robot is simulated and compared with experimental results, which shows relatively good prediction accuracy. With above structures, we demonstrate the walking and climbing ability of this robot with a locomotion speed of 1 mm/s. The climbing on a vertical wall along both the vertical and horizontal directions is achieved.In addition, an untethered version of the paper-based wall-climbing robot is developed to make the robot closer to perform certain tasks. In order to embed all the electronics, the size of the robot is made larger than tethered version to strengthen its capability of holding weights and fighting against gravity. A tiny microcontroller, Attiny84, is employed to control the activation of SMA and the turning on/off of adhesion pads. Each pad has an individual high-voltage MOSFET to control its adhesion force. With the help of high-voltage MOSFET, the falling torque is much lower than before, and the problem of the small microcontroller’s output power is also solved. With above structures, we demonstrate the walking and climbing ability of this robot with a locomotion speed of 0.6-0.8 mm/s. The climbing on a vertical wall along both the vertical and horizontal directions is also achieved. Meanwhile, since its untethered property, this robot has the potential to perform tasks such as surface detection and video surveillance, which makes soft robot closer to real-life application</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Xinyu Liu</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mr81g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j565m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2b88qh682"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An efficient numerical framework for sensitivity analysis for unsteady flows</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yang, Liu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The adjoint method is an efficient approach to computing sensitivities, and has been successfully applied in many fields. However, this approach has not seen widespread acceptance for unsteady problems primarily due to very large storage requirements of present algorithms. The fundamental challenge in unsteady adjoint approaches is the need to integrate the equations in reverse time, which requires all previous flow solutions to be available during the backwards integration. The straightforward treatment of storing all previous flow solutions is prohibitive for simulations with a large number of grid points and time steps. To alleviate this challenge, we propose to compress the flow solutions and store only the reduced bases and expansion coefficients. The flow solutions are recovered when needed in solving the unsteady adjoint equations. In this work, an unsteady discrete adjoint-based approach has been developed. Both continuous and discrete forms of the unsteady adjoint are presented and an adjoint solver based on the latter is validated against finite-difference based sensitivities. A novel adaptive-multi-window compression algorithm has been proposed, where the reduced bases are generated by solving a Proper Orthogonal Decomposition (POD) problem of a matrix consisting flow solutions within a time window. We propose an innovative algorithm that employs an error indicator to determine whether the current bases are sufficient to represent the solution at new time steps; thus saving both computational and storage cost. We apply the unsteady adjoint-based framework to evaluate sensitivity of functionals for turbulent flows in hydraulic turbine draft tubes. We conduct this research within a numerical framework based on the compressible Reynolds-averaged Navier-Stokes equations coupled with the stiffened gas equation of state to model incompressible flow, and a low-speed preconditioner to accelerate convergence. A secondary novel contribution, is an extended eddy-preserving limiter scheme to capture strong turbulent vortices within draft tubes. The numerical framework is first verified on three-dimensional vortex advection cases and then applied to flow simulations in a bulb turbine draft tube. Finally, sensitivities computed with the use of full and compressed flow solutions are compared to demonstrate the feasibility of the approach</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La méthode adjointe est une approche efficace pour calculer des sensibilités. Il a été appliqué avec succès dans de nombreux domaines. Toutefois, cette approche n’a pas été largement acceptée, principalement en raison des très grandes besoins de stockage des algorithmes actuels. Le défi fondamental des approches adjointes instationnaires est la nécessité d'intégrer les équations en temps inverse, ce qui nécessite que toutes les solutions précédentes des écoulements soient disponibles pendant l'intégration en arrière. Le simple stockage de toutes les solutions précédentes est prohibitif pour les simulations avec un grand nombre de mailles et de pas de temps.  Pour résoudre ce problème, nous proposons de compresser les solutions des champs d’écoulement et de ne stocker que les bases réduites et les coefficients de dilatation. Les champs d’écoulement sont reconstruits lorsque cela sont nécessaires pour résoudre les équations adjointes instationnaires. Dans ce travail, une approche adjointe instationnaire sous forme discrète a été développée. La forme continue et la forme discrète des équations adjointes instationnaires sont présentées et un solveur adjoint basé sur ce dernier est valididé en comparant avec les sensibilités calculées par la méthode des différences finies. Un nouvel algorithme de compression adaptative à fenêtres multiples a été proposé, dans lequel les bases réduites sont générées en résolvant un problème de décomposition orthogonale propre (POD) d'une matrice composée de solutions d’écoulement dans une fenêtre temporelle. Nous proposons un algorithme innovant qui utilise un indicateur d'erreur pour déterminer si les bases actuelles sont suffisantes pour représenter la solution à de nouveaux pas de temps; économisant ainsi les coûts de calcul et de stockage.Nous appliquons le cadre basé sur la méthode adjointe instationnaire pour évaluer la sensibilité des fonctions aux écoulements turbulents dans les aspirateurs des turbines hydrauliques. Nous menons cette recherche dans un cadre numérique basé sur les équations moyennes de Reynolds compressibles couplées à l'équation d'état « Stiffened Gas » pour modéliser l'écoulement incompressible et à un préconditionneur à faible vitesse pour accélérer la convergence. Une contribution secondaire est un schéma étendu avec limiteur préservant les tourbillons pour capturer les vortex turbulents forts dans les aspirateurs. Le cadre numérique est d'abord vérifié sur des cas de l'advection de tourbillon en trois dimensions, puis appliqué à des simulations d'écoulement dans un aspirateur d'une turbine bulbe. Enfin, les sensibilités calculées en utilisant les solutions complètes et de solutions compressées sont comparées pour démontrer la faisabilité de l'approche</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sivakumaran Nadarajah</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tk949.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qh682</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8336h614s"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Developing efficient redox-based tools for direct functionalization of phenols and aryl ketones</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Qiu, Zihang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis focuses on the development of redox-based tools to directly functionalize simple unprotected phenols’ Csp2-OH bonds and to realize the reductive coupling reaction of aryl ketones (pinacol coupling reaction).In chapter 1, an overview of recent advancements regarding Csp2-O functionalization of phenol and its derivatives will be introduced, especially focusing on the relatively less-activated ones such as aryl methyl ethers, diphenyl ethers, etc. This chapter will describe the phenol Csp2-O functionalization sorted by the types of bond formations, such as C-N, C-B, C-Si, C-P, C-Sn, C-H, C-F and C-C bond formations, where the key mechanisms involved are demonstrated and discussed. Besides, our group’s achievements utilizing redox-based tools to functionalize phenols and aryl ethers will be incorporated in this chapter as well.In chapter 2, the core designs and an overview of my research work during the Ph.D. study will be presented and meanwhile, the logical connections between each of my research projects will be discussed.The chapter 3 will discuss how to realize a formal aromaticity-transfer coupling reaction between phenols and pyrrolidines/indolines to afford the N-cyclohexyl pyrroles/indoles catalyzed by Pd/C with NaBH4 as the hydride donor. In this transformation, the aromaticity of phenols is formally passed on to the pyrrolidine or indoline units.The chapter 4 will discuss how we developed a direct conversion of phenols to primary anilines with hydrazine being utilized as both amine and hydride donors under the catalysis of simple Pd/C.The chapter 5 will introduce how we realized a light-enabled metal-free pinacol coupling protocol by hydrazine being used as a clean HAT reductant:  only traceless non-toxic N2 and H2 gases were produced as by-products in this transformation, solving long-lasting metal waste issues in traditional pinacol coupling reactions.The chapter 6 will discuss the potential future research based on the transformations developed in this thesis.Finally, chapter 7 will summarize the contribution to fundamental knowledge of the research work demonstrated in the whole thesis</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse porte sur le développement d’outils basés sur l'oxydo-réduction pour fonctionnaliser directement les liaisons Csp2-OH de phénols simplement non protégés et pour réaliser une réaction de couplage réductrice d'arylcétones (réaction de couplage pinacolique).Au chapitre 1, un aperçu des récents progrès en matière de fonctionnalisation de la liaison Csp2-O du phénol et de ses dérivés sera présenté, en se concentrant spécialement sur les dérivés du phénol relativement moins activés tels que les éthers d'aryle de méthyle, les éthers de diphényle, etc. Ce chapitre décrit les fonctionnalisations de la liaison Csp2-O du phénol classées par types de formations de liaison, telles que les formations de liaison C-N, C-B, C-Si, C-P, C-Sn, C-H, C-F et C-C, où les principaux mécanismes impliqués sont démontrés et discutés. En outre, les réalisations de notre groupe utilisant des outils basés sur l'oxydo-réduction pour fonctionnaliser les phénols et les éthers d'aryle seront également intégrées à ce chapitre.Au chapitre 2, en présentant quelques-uns des travaux clés de notre groupe qui ont inspiré la mise en place de la recherche de mon doctorat, les concepts de base et un aperçu de mes travaux de recherche au cours de la thèse étude seront présentés et les liens logiques entre chacun de mes projets de recherche seront discutés.Le chapitre 3 expliquera comment réaliser une réaction de couplage catalysée par Pd/C avec NaBH4 comme donneur d’hydrure permet le transfert formel d’aromaticité entre phénols et pyrrolidines/indolines pour obtenir les N-cyclohexyl pyrroles/ indoles. Dans cette transformation, l’aromaticité des phénols est formellement transmise aux unités pyrrolidines ou indolines.Le chapitre 4 expliquera comment nous avons mis au point une conversion directe des phénols vers des anilines primaires en utilisant l’hydrazine comme donneur à la fois d’amine et d’hydrure avec comme simple catalyseur le palladium sur charbon.Le chapitre 5 expliquera comment nous avons réalisé un protocole de couplage pinacolique sans métal et activé par la lumière en utilisant l’hydrazine comme agent réducteur propre pour le transfert d’atome d’hydrogène: Les seuls sous-produits étant les gaz non toxiques et sans trace N2 et H2 – ce qui permet de résoudre les problèmes des déchets métalliques liés aux réactions de couplage pinacolique traditionnelles.Le chapitre 6 traitera de la recherche potentielle future basée sur les transformations développées dans cette thèse.Enfin, le chapitre 7 résumera comment les travaux de recherche présentés dans l’ensemble de la thèse contribuent à la connaissance fondamentale</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chaojun Li</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429f953.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h614s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322k190"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modeling electronic transport in disordered mesoscopic systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhou, Chenyi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'objectif de cette thèse est d'étendre le cadre théorique du transport électronique pour incorporer les effets quantiques dans les systèmes mésoscopiques désordonnés. Nos méthodes théoriques sont développées sur la base de la technique de perturbation formulée avec les fonctions de Green hors d'équilibre. En utilisant l'hamiltonien de l'espace réel ainsi que des paramètres du réservoir thermique, nous cherchons à calculer la structure électronique et le courant de charge en tenant compte des différents effets quantiques. Les trois effets mésoscopiques désordonnés les plus importants et les plus répandus sont abordés, viz. la localisation faible, la relaxation d'énergie et l'effet de Altshuler-Aronov (AA), qui donnent lieu à des corrections de la description classique par Drude du transport électronique. Des méthodes théoriques spécialisées sont développées pour les effets physiques respectifs. Pour la localisation faible, nous développons un schéma de diagramme basé sur Cooperon en utilisant la technique dite du fermion dual (DF) afin de prendre en compte les processus d'interférence non locaux qui ont été négligés dans l'approximation du potentiel cohérent (CPA), qui prévaut. Des simulations numériques ont montré que, par rapport à la CPA, notre méthode de DF donne des résultats plus précis pour les propriétés de transport de fils quantiques désordonnés, et qu'elle est notamment capable de prédire l'effet de magnétorésistance négatif, ce qui est la signature de localisation faible. La relaxation d'énergie dans les fils en interaction est abordée avec un schéma auto-cohérent GW-CPA. À l'aide de cette méthode, nous étudions comment la distribution de l'énergie des électrons en interaction évolue sous l'effet de l'interaction croissante et de l'intensité du champ externe. De plus, le même schéma de calcul est également utilisé pour simuler l'effet de traînée de Coulomb entre des fils parallèles. On discute la dépendance intéressante du courant de traînée sur les potentiels chimiques des réservoirs. En ce qui concerne l'effet de AA, la formulation diagrammatique originale d'Altshuler et Aronov est généralisée au formalisme de Keldysh dans l'espace réel. Ensuite, les calculs théoriques et numériques montrent que pour un fil hors d'équilibre, l'effet AA conduit à des corrections de DOS anormales à ses énergies de Fermi respectives, et que l'ampleur de ces corrections (locales) dépend de la position. L'effet AA sur les propriétés de transport est également analysé, ce qui mène à des comportements non triviaux aux tailles de système et tensions</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The aim of this thesis is to extend the theoretical framework of nonequilibrium electronic transport to incorporate quantum effects in disordered mesoscopic systems. Our theoretical methods are developed based on the diagrammatic perturbation technique formulated with the Keldysh nonequilibrium Green's functions. Given the real-space Hamiltonian of the transport system together with thermal reservoir parameters, we seek to compute the electronic structure and the charge current taking the various quantum effects into account. Following this methodology, the three most important and ubiquitous disordered mesoscopic effects are addressed, viz. weak localization, energy relaxation, and the Altshuler-Aronov (AA) effect, all of which give rise to corrections to the classical Drude description of electronic transport. Specialized theoretical methods are developed for the respective physical effects. For weak localization we develop a Cooperon-based diagrammatic scheme using the so-called dual fermion (DF) technique in order to take into account nonlocal interference processes which have been neglected in the prevailing coherent potential approximation (CPA). Numerical simulations have shown that, compared to CPA, our DF method yields more accurate results for transport properties of disordered quantum wires, and that in particular it is able to predict the negative magnetoresistance effect which is a signature of weak localization. The energy relaxation in disordered interacting wires is tackled with a self-consistent GW-CPA scheme. Using this computational method we study how the energy distribution of interacting electrons evolves under increasing interaction and external field strengths. In addition, the same computational scheme is also employed to simulate the Coulomb drag effect between parallel quantum wires. The interesting dependence of nonequilibrium drag current on the chemical potentials of reservoirs is discussed. As to the AA effect, the original diagrammatic formulation by Altshuler and Aronov is generalized to the real-space Keldysh formalism. Then, both theoretical and numerical diagram calculations show that for a disordered wire at nonequilibrium the AA effect leads to anomalous DOS corrections at its respective Fermi energies, and that the magnitudes of these (local) DOS corrections are position-dependent. The AA effect on transport properties is also analyzed, which shows nontrivial behaviors with respect to system sizes and bias voltages</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hong Guo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935730r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322k190</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4t64gs70t"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bubble size measurement via wave phase conjugation: a numerical study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Modarreszadeh, Seyedamirreza</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La mesure des caractéristiques de bulles de gaz dans un fluide fait partie des tâches essentielles et délicates dans de nombreuses applications industrielles. On a récemment émis l’hypothèse que de telles mesures pourraient être conduites de manière plus efficace et précise en utilisant un dispositif de conjugaison de phase (Wave Phase Conjugation ou WPC en anglais) en raison de ses propriétés intéressantes telles que la rétro focalisation du signal et la compensation des distorsions de phase. Dans le travail ici présenté, nous étudions l’application de cette technique pour la mesure de la taille des bulles par modélisation numérique.Pour cela, nous proposons un modèle physico-mathématique général du WPC magnétoa-coustique, prenant en compte la propagation des ondes à la fois dans les zones solides (le conjugateur lui-même et les autres régions solides, le cas échéant) et dans les zones fluides entourant le conjugateur. Les ondes acoustiques dans les zones solides sont supposées avoir un comportement linéaire, tandis qu’elles peuvent être aussi bien linéaires que non linéaires dans les zones fluides. Dans l’objectif de résoudre avec précision ces ondes transitoires à haute-fréquence, ayant généralement de courtes longueurs d’onde, des schémas d’ordres élevés dans les domaines spatiaux et temporels sont nécessaires.Les équations gouvernantes 2D/axisymétrique du modèle sont discrétisées sur un maillage triangulaire non structuré à l’aide d’une version modifiée de la méthode discontinue nodale de Galerkin (NDG). Celle-ci utilise des bases différentes non colocalisées pour les solutions et les flux. Le schéma de Runge-Kutta (RK) de troisième ordre à forte conservation de la stabilité (Strong Stability-Preserving ou SSP en anglais) est ensuite utilisé pour l’intégration temporelle. Afin d’éviter toute réflexion non physique aux limites extérieures du domaine de calcul, la méthode de la couche presque parfaitement adaptée (Nearly Perfectly Matched Layer ou NPML en anglais) est employée. Une attention particulière est portée sur la modélisation de la réflexion et de la transmission des ondes à l’interface des matériaux.Le modèle de Keller-Miksis (KM) est utilisé pour simuler les vibrations des bulles soumises à des ondes acoustiques. Par la suite, en utilisant la méthode de moyenne des volumes, les effets de la dynamique des bulles sont pris en compte dans les équations régissant les fluides par ajout d’un terme source témoignant des variations des propriétés physiques locales avec la fraction volumique du gaz. Différents ensembles de bulles sont étudiés dans le modèle 2D/axisymétrique : un nuage plan de bulle, un nuage de couche de bulles, une seule bulle et un nuage sphérique de bulles. Après validation du modèle numérique à l’aide des cas de test représentatifs, l’interaction de la dynamique des bulles avec le procédé WPC est examinée au travers de plusieurs indicateurs descriptifs tels que le facteur d’amplification du signal (Γ), l’intensité (I), et l’intensité relative (I*).Les résultats montrent que même les signaux générés par les réponses brutales d’une seule bulle n’ont pas d’influence significative sur le processus de modulation. D’autre part, les ondes diffusées par les nuages plans de bulles, dans lesquels les bulles sont non synchronisées physiquement, sont suffisamment importantes pour influencer le processus de modulation à condition que la fréquence de stimulation soit proche de la fréquence physique des bulles. Pour les nuages de bulles réalistes, le processus de modélisation est presque préservé ; cependant, les ondes conjuguées passant au travers du nuage présentent quelques signatures de la dynamique du nuage. Par exemple, les signaux dont la fréquence est supérieure à la fréquence physique des bulles sont considérablement atténués. Dans l’ensemble, cette étude démontre que la technique basée sur le WPC possède un potentiel prometteur pour la mesure des dimensions des bulles</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Measuring characteristics of gas bubbles in a fluid is among essential and challenging tasks in many industrial settings. It has been recently conjectured that such measurements could be more efficiently and accurately carried out by using a Wave Phase Conjugation (WPC) device due to its useful relevant properties, such as signal retro-focusing and compensation for phase distortions. In the present work, this technique in application to bubble size measurements is investigated via numerical modeling.For this aim, a general physico-mathematical model of magneto-acoustic WPC is proposed, which includes wave propagation both in solid zones (the conjugator itself and other solid regions, if present) and in fluid zones surrounding the conjugator. Acoustic waves in the solid zones are assumed to behave linearly while in the fluid zones the waves may be either linear or non-linear. To accurately resolve these high-frequency transient waves, which have typically short wavelengths, high-order schemes in both time and space domains are required.The 2D/axisymmetric governing equations of the model are discretized on an unstructured triangular mesh with a modified version of the Nodal Discontinuous Galerkin (NDG) method, which employs non-collocated solution and flux bases. The third-order Strong Stability-Preserving (SSP) Runge-Kutta (RK) scheme is then used for integration in time. To avoid any false reflections from the outer boundaries of the computational domain, the Nearly Perfectly Matched Layer (NPML) technique is adopted. Special attention is paid to the modeling of wave reflection and transmission at material interfaces.A comprehensive set of test problems addressing all facets of the proposed numerical model is used for verification via comparison with available analytical solutions. After the establishment of the accuracy, performance, and reliability of the proposed model, realistic WPC cases are numerically simulated for the linear and weakly non-linear fluid flow regimes. The main WPC properties, such as retro-focusing and parametric resonance, are observed in the numerical experiments with good accuracy.To simulate vibrations of bubbles subjected to acoustic waves, the Keller-Miksis (KM) model is employed. Then, by using the volume-averaging approach, the effects of bubble dynamics are incorporated into the fluid flow governing equations via adding a source term describing variations of local physical properties with the gas volume fraction. Different bubble sets are investigated within the 2D/axisymmetric model: a bubble-plane cloud, a bubble-layer cloud, a single bubble, and a spherical bubble cloud. After verification of the numerical model by evaluating some representative test cases, the interaction of bubble dynamics with the WPC process is examined using a number of descriptive indicators, such as the signal amplification factor (Γ), the intensity (I), and the relative intensity (I*).The results show that even the signals generated by violent responses of a single bubble have no significant influence on the modulation process. On the other hand, the scattered waves from bubble-plane clouds, in which the bubbles are non-physically synchronized, are strong enough to affect the modulation process if the stimulation frequency is close to the natural frequency of bubbles. For realistic bubble clouds, the modulation process is almost intact; however, conjugate waves, which pass through the cloud, have some signatures of cloud dynamics. For instance, signals with frequencies higher than the natural frequency of bubbles are significantly diminished. Overall, this study demonstrates that the WPC-based technique has a promising potential to be used for measuring bubble dimensions</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Evgeny Timofeev</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kz34x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gs70t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988q290"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Philosophy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Group agency, interference and domination: Renewed normative grounds for collective rights</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Litalien, Eliot</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les principales tentatives de justification des droits collectifs pour les minorités culturelles ou nationales disponibles dans la littérature, parmi lesquelles on peut compter les théories multiculturalistes libérales comme celle de Kymlicka ou Patten, échouent à atteindre de façon cohérente leur objectif. Dans cette thèse, je développe ainsi une nouvelle justification pour de tels droits collectifs, une justification qui se bâtit sur des fondements normatifs distinct de ceux proposés par le multiculturalisme libéral.Dans le premier chapitre, je passe en revue les arguments sur lesquels se fondent les théories multiculturalistes de Kymlicka et Patten et je soutiens qu’ils présentent d’importants et, à tout le moins dans le cadre théorique multiculturaliste, insurmontables problèmes. D’abord, ni l’approche de Kymlicka ni celle de Patten ne peut traiter adéquatement les demandes de certains groupes culturels ou nationaux qui sont pourtant supposés être les principaux sujets de leurs théories. De plus, je soutiens que ceux deux auteurs fondent de manière problématique leur approche respective sur la notion de culture et sur sa valeur.Dans le second chapitre, je mets en place les premières pièces d’un argument pour des droits collectifs pour les minorités culturelles ou nationales qui évitent ces inconvénients. Je soutiens que certains groupes se qualifient en tant qu’agent parce qu’ils satisfont les critères de l’agentivité mis en place par la « conception standard de l’agentivité ». Pour expliquer comment, j’offre une explication fonctionnaliste de l’agentivité collective selon laquelle certains groupes peuvent réaliser des états de fait qui fonctionnent comme des (ou jouent le rôle des) intentions dans l’explication des actions du groupe.Au troisième chapitre, je me tourne vers des questions normatives et avance deux points principaux. Le premier, un point conceptuel, est que certains groupes, parce qu’ils sont des agents, peuvent être sujets à de l’interférence et de la domination. Le second, un point normatif, est que l’interférence et la domination qui peuvent avoir lieu à l’échelle collective constituent un problème moral significatif parce qu’elles ont des conséquences sur l’agentivité des membres d’un agent collectif. Je conclus en suggérant que nous avons donc de bonnes raisons de protéger les agents collectifs contre l’interférence et la domination.Finalement, dans le quatrième chapitre, je reviens à la philosophie politique et boucle l’argument. Avec l’exemple des peuples autochtones au Canada, je montre comment des groupes culturels ou nationaux peuvent se qualifier en tant qu’agents et comment ils peuvent se retrouver, en tant qu’agents collectifs, dans des situations de domination ou rencontrer de l’interférence. C’est en construisant sur ce cas concret que je soutiens que ce dont les agents collectifs comme les peuples autochtones—à savoir, les groupes culturels ou nationaux—ont besoin pour être adéquatement protégés contre l’interférence et la domination sont des droits légaux à l’auto-détermination qui sont véritablement collectifs</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The main attempts to justify collective rights for cultural or national minorities that are available in the literature, among them those of liberal multiculturalists such as Kymlicka and Patten, have failed to coherently do so. In this dissertation, I offer a new justification for such collective rights, a justification that is built on normative grounds wholly different from those of liberal multiculturalism.In Chapter 1, I explain the arguments that lay at the foundations Kymlicka’s and Patten’s multiculturalist theories and argue that they fail in important and, at least in the multiculturalist framework, insurmountable ways. Most problematically, neither Kymlicka’s nor Patten’s approach can adequately address the claims made by some of the cultural or national groups that are, purportedly, the subjects of their theories. Moreover, I argue that both authors problematically ground their respective approach in the notion of culture and of its value.In Chapter 2, I put in place the first pieces of an argument for collective rights for cultural or national minorities that avoid those drawbacks. I argue that some groups qualify as agents because they satisfy the criteria of agency set by the “standard conception of agency.” To explain how it is so, I offer a functionalist account of group agency according to which certain groups can realize states of affairs that function as (or play the role of) intentions in the explanation of the group’s actions.I turn in Chapter 3 to normative questions and make two central claims. The first, a conceptual claim, is that certain groups, because they are agents, can be subject to interference and domination. The second, a normative claim, is that the interference or domination that happens at the collective level is a significant moral problem because it will have adverse consequences on a group’s members’ agency. I conclude by arguing that we therefore have good reason to protect group agents from interference and domination.Finally, in Chapter 4, I come back to political philosophy and bring the argument home, as it were. Through the example of Indigenous peoples in Canada, I show how cultural or national groups can qualify as agents and how they can be, as group agents, in a situation of domination, in addition to being often interfered with. It is by building on that concrete case that I argue that what group agents like Indigenous peoples—namely, and more generally, cultural or national groups—need to be adequately protected against interference and domination are (genuinely) collective legal rights to self-determination</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daniel Weinstock</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Natalie Stoljar</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386q06j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988q290</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d570200x"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Thermal properties of structure one hydrates using density functional theory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mathews, Samuel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans certaines conditions, l'eau et les petites molécules gazeuses forment des hydrates de gaz solides et cristallins. Les hydrates de gaz ont déjà été examinés dans l'industrie pétrolière en raison de leur des problèmes d'assurance de débit et sont actuellement examinés en tant que conteneurs potentiels de gaz naturel et d'hydrogène, ainsi que dans les processus de séparation. La recherche sur les propriétés thermiques a été centrée sur la capacité thermique et le coefficient de dilatation thermique, expérimentalement et théoriquement. En utilisant le Vienna ab initio Simulation Package (VASP) pour faire des calculs de théorie de la densité fonctionnelle (DFT), cette recherche a permis de combler l'écart entre la simulation et l'expérience en calculant les propriétés thermiques des hydrates de gaz sI.La capacité thermique à volume constant, la capacité thermique à pression constante, le coefficient de dilatation thermique volumétrique et le paramètre Grüneisen des hydrates de méthane, de l'éthane, du dioxyde de carbone et des hydrates sI vides, et de la glace hexagonale, en fonction de la température de 0 à 300 Kelvin ont été calculés. La capacité thermique à volume constant était inférieure à celle des valeurs de la littérature calculées avec la dynamique moléculaire (MD). DFT a reproduit les valeurs expérimentales de la capacité thermique à pression constante pour les hydrates et la glace bien à basse température. DFT a sous-estimé le coefficient de dilatation thermique dans tous les cas. Les hydrates d'éthane et de dioxyde de carbone ont démontré un comportement nettement différent par rapport au méthane et aux hydrates vides et à la glace hexagonale. Le paramètre Grüneisen a été calculé pour tous les systèmes. DFT a surestimé la valeur du paramètre pour les hydrates remplis et la glace hexagonale par rapport aux valeurs expérimentales de la glace hexagonale</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Under certain conditions, water and small gaseous molecules form solid, crystalline gas hydrates, members of a larger class of structures called inclusion compounds or clathrates. Gas hydrates have previously been examined in the petroleum industry due to their propensity to cause flow assurance and safety issues and currently are examined as potential natural gas and hydrogen containers, as well as in separation processes to selectively capture flue gases. Thermal properties research has been centered around heat capacity and thermal expansion coefficient, experientially and theoretically. By using the Vienna ab initio Simulation Package (VASP) to solve the Schrödinger Equation in the context of Density Functional Theory, this research brought the gap between simulation and experiment by calculating the thermal properties of sI gas hydrates, using Phonopy paired with VASP, and to provide nanoscale insight into macroscale behavior.The constant volume heat capacity, the constant pressure heat capacity, the volumetric thermal expansion coefficient, and the Grüneisen parameter of methane, ethane, carbon dioxide, and empty sI hydrates, and of hexagonal ice, as functions of temperature from 0 to 300 Kelvin were calculated using DFT. The constant volume heat capacity was lower than when compared with literature values calculated with MD. DFT replicated experimental values of constant pressure heat capacity for hydrates and ice well at low temperatures. DFT underestimated the thermal expansion coefficient in all cases. The ethane and carbon dioxide hydrates demonstrated behavior that was markedly different when compared to methane and empty hydrates, and hexagonal ice. The Grüneisen parameter was calculated for all systems. DFT overestimated the value of the parameter for filled hydrates and hexagonal ice when compared to experimental hexagonal ice values</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alejandro D. Rey</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Phillip Servio</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68km604.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d570200x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8s45qf229"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Highly homogeneously structured lithium-ion storage electrodes via electrophoretic deposition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Uceda, Marianna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L’amélioration des performances electrochimiques des batteries Li-ion est déterminante pour l’atteinte des objectifs de développement durable établis par la communauté scientifique. Parmi les mesures prises en ce sens est la miniaturisation des matières électrochimiquement actives vers les dimensions nanométriques. Cependant, l’utilisation des nanotechnologies amène de nouveaux défis à l’étape de l’enduction lors de la fabrication des électrodes destinées aux batteries Li-ion; l’enduction n’est pas adaptée aux matériaux nanométriques et bidimensionnels puisque qu’elle introduit des problématiques liées à la rhéologie. Ainsi, ce projet a comme objectif d’évaluer et de concevoir une technique d’enduction alternative utilisant les principes de la déposition électrophorétique (DEP). En premier lieu, des particules nanométriques de titanate de lithium carbonées (LTO) et de noir d’acétylène ont été enduits avec succès comme anode composite via la DEP en utilisant le styrène-butadiène (SB) dispersé dans un mélange d’acétonitrile et d’eau. Les travaux de recherche ont permis de caractériser et d’optimiser les effets de la densité de courant sur le mouvement des particules et la croissance du dépôt sur le substrat d’aluminium. Ce film est épaisse et mésoporeuse. La performance des électrodes ainsi fabriquées a été comparée à celle d’électrodes fabriquée selon la méthode conventionnelle d’enduction. Les analyses en microscopie électronique à balayage (MEB) et la cartographie en spectroscopie dispersive en énergies des rayons-X (EDX) ont montrées que les électrodes provenant de la DEP présentent une excellente mixité des composés carbonés et du LTO. De plus, il a été déterminé via la microscopie électronique par photoémission (MEPE) couplée à la spectroscopie de structure près du front d'absorption de rayons X (XANES) que le liant de SB s’avère être bien dispersé à travers l’enduit.Dans un deuxième temps, la DEP a été utilisée pour fabriquer des anodes faites d’une nano-couche d’un matériau composite de LTO et d’oxyde de graphène réduit (OGr). Pour ce faire, une matrice composée d’hydrate de titanate de lithium (LTH) bidimensionnel et d’oxyde de graphène (OG) a été d’abord déposée électrophorétiquement puis recuit à haute température en atmosphère réductrice afin d’induire une transformation topotactique du LTH en LTO et du OG en OGr.  L’imagerie et la topographie EDX des électrodes en coupe transversale ont démontré qu’elles sont formées d’un enduit uniforme contenant l’OGr agissant comme agent conducteur ainsi que d’agent liant servant à organiser les feuillets nanométriques de LTO en un film adhérent. Par conséquent, les électrodes obtenues par DEP ont démontrées des performances électrochimiques supérieures aux électrodes conventionnelles.La dernière étude concerne le niobate de titane (TNO, TiNb2O7) qui s’avère être un matériau anodique prometteur pour remplacer le LTO puisqu’il peut livrer de hautes densités de courant. Des électrodes de TNO/OGr sans agent liant ont été fabriquées en adaptant le procédé par DEP précédemment développé pour le TNO. Par ailleurs, en plus des propriétés liantes et conductrices de l’OGr, il a été déterminé qu’il amenait aussi une contribution pseudo-capacitive à l’emmagasinage des ions lithium dans l’électrode. La plus grande homogénéité des électrodes DEP a permis d’obtenir de meilleures performances électrochimiques en termes de capacité de cyclage et de rétention de cette capacité. Plus précisément, il a réduit les pertes de capacité en comparaison aux électrodes PVDF de composition similaire.En sommes, suite à l’étude d’une nouvelle méthode intégrée de fabrication des électrodes ainsi que l’analyse de leur performances électrochimiques, la DEP s’avère être une technologie supérieure aux méthodes standards avec de grands potentiels d’application en fabrication avancée des électrodes de batteries Li-ion</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Improving lithium-ion battery performance is key in facilitating a green sustainable future. This has led to nanosizing of active materials as means to improve their conductivity by reducing the lithium-ion diffusion length. However, nanomaterials introduce a new challenge during the casting stage of lithium-ion battery electrode fabrication. This technique is unsuited for handling both nanosized and 2D-shaped materials as they introduce rheological challenges. Additionally, the current commercially available casting technique requires the use of a toxic and expensive organic solvent. Thus, the focus of this work was to investigate and design an alternative coating process using electrophoretic deposition (EPD). The work comprises three studies.In the first study, carbon-coated lithium titanate (LTO) nanoparticles and acetylene black were successfully made into highly-conductive composite anodes via EPD employing styrene butadiene rubber (SBR) as binder in an appropriately selected  acetonitrile/water medium. The investigation characterized and optimized the effect of current density on particle movement and deposit growth producing thick mesoporous films on aluminum substrate. The EPD electrode performance was compared to electrodes prepared via the conventional tape-casting. For EPD electrodes, SEM imaging and EDS mapping showed excellent intermixing of carbon components and the active material.  Via photoemission electron microscopy (PEEM) coupled with X-ray absorption near edge structure (XANES) it was revealed the SBR binder to be well dispersed within the coating, which translated to the electrode achieving superior rate cycling performance thanks to enhanced conductivity enabled by the hetero-assembling power of electrophoretic deposition.In the second study, EPD was innovatively applied to fabricate binder-less nanolayered lithium titanate and reduced graphene oxide (rGO) composite coatings as high-performance Li-ion anodes. This was accomplished by electrophoretically depositing 2D shaped lithium titanate hydrate (LTH) and graphene oxide (GO) precursors and subsequent high temperature reducing annealing to induce the topotactic transformation of LTH into LTO and GO into the so-called rGO. As graphene is difficult to successfully suspend, using the functionalized precursor circumvented this problem. The EPD electrodes are compared to conventionally prepared electrodes with rGO and carbon black. Cross-sectional imaging and EDS mapping showed the EPD electrodes contained a homogeneous coating with the rGO acting as a conductive medium and binder which helped organize the LTO nanosheets into a well built and adherent film. As a result, the EPD nanolayered electrode was found to exhibit superior electrochemical performance in terms of power capability, cyclability and impedance when compared to conventionally prepared electrode. The final study featured titanium niobate (TNO, TiNb2O7), this material is a promising replacement anode material for LTO with the potential to deliver higher capacities. Binder-less TNO/rGO electrodes were made through adapting the EPD method developed for the second study – co-depositing TNO and GO followed by high temperature annealing to induce GO to rGO transformation. The final composition of EPD coatings contained 18 wt% rGO which was compared to conventionally prepared electrodes containing 18 wt% rGO and 10 wt% rGO. The rGO was determined in addition to acting as binder and conductive component to have pseudocapacitive contributions to lithium-ion storage. The improved homogeneity in the EPD electrodes allowed better performance in terms of capacity level and retention, i.e. reduced capacity fade in comparison to PVDF-built electrodes of similar composition. Overall, through these integrated electrode construction and electrochemical performance analysis studies, EPD is shown to be a superior coating technology with great application potential in manufacturing advanced LIB electrodes</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>George Demopoulos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p2586.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qf229</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mining and Materials</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zg476"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Shifting gendered labour: The role of women’s groups and formalized education in Kenya</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>LeBlanc, Laurence</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les responsabilités de travail établies selon le sexe du travailleur font référence aux différentes attentes des rôles traditionnellement considérés « féminin » ou « masculin ». Cette division du travail entre les genres est inculquée dans les différentes sociétés à travers des processus de socialisation. Ces processus s’appliquent au travail domestique et solidifient les attentes féminines versus masculines reliées à cet environnement. La recherche dans ce domaine suggère que l’évolution des circonstances socio-politiques peuvent modifier ces normes et attentes en matière de travail selon le genre. Le centre du Kenya est une région qui connaît divers changements socio-politiques, ce qui en fait une région appropriée pour explorer ces questions. Cette thèse explore deux changements socio-politiques dans les comtés de Samburu et de Laikipia, situés au centre du Kenya : (1) un nombre grandissant de groupes de femmes qui s’impliquent dans des activités rémunératrices incluant la possession de terres agricoles et (2) le taux d’éducation formelle croissant des femmes dans les régions rurales du Kenya. Comment ces changements socio-politiques influencent-ils les responsabilités professionnelles liées au genre dans les foyers pastoraux ? Quelle est la perception de l’impact de ces changements socio-politiques sur les définitions de la « féminité » ?  Trois mois de recherche sur le terrain complétée durant l’été 2019 ont mené à la conclusion que ces facteurs simultanément renforcent et amènent à re-questionner les attentes des responsabilités de travail selon le genre. Plus précisément, les groupes de femmes impliqués dans des activités rémunératrices et l’éducation formelle en croissance ont un impact sur trois types de travail féminisé: le travail domestique, le travail familial et le travail sexuel.  Bien qu’émancipateurs dans certains cas, ces changements peuvent également conduire à des reconstitutions défavorables des hiérarchies des genres. Etant donne que la « féminité » est un concept étroitement lié au travail selon le genre, ces changements socio-politiques semblent êtres des facteurs clés dans la façon dont la féminité est (ré)imaginée, même si elle est parfois chargée de tension. Ceci supporte la notion que les normes reliées au genre du travailleur ne sont pas stagnantes, et que le travail associé au genre n’est pas un phénomène « naturel » mais bien le résultat d’un processus de socialisation</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Gendered labour responsibilities refer to divides in labour expectations for what is traditionally considered “feminized work” and what is traditionally considered “masculinized work.” Across geographies, gendered labour is naturalized through socialization processes. These processes crystallize feminized and masculinized expectations for domestic responsibilities. Scholarship suggests that changing socio-political circumstances can shift gender norms and gendered labour expectations. Central Kenya is a region experiencing a juncture of various socio-political changes, making it a fitting region for exploring questions about the malleability of gendered labour expectations. This thesis explores two socio-political shifts in Samburu and Laikipia Counties in North-Central Kenya, namely the increased propensity for women’s groups to be involved in income earning and land-owning activities, and rising rates of formalized education for women in rural Kenya. How do these socio-political shifts impact gendered labour responsibilities within pastoralist homes? What are the perceived impacts of these socio-political shifts on definitions of “womanhood”? Three months of participatory fieldwork conducted in the summer of 2019 suggest that these factors simultaneously reinforce and challenge gendered labour expectations in uneven and contested ways. Specifically, women’s groups and formalized education impact three kinds of feminized labour, namely domestic labour, family labour, and sexual labour. Although emancipatory in some cases, these shifts can also lead to adverse reinstitutions of gendered hierarchies. Since “womanhood” is a construct closely linked to gendered labour, these shifts appear to be key factors in how “womanhood” is reimagined, even if sometimes fraught with tension. This supports the notion that gender norms are not stagnant, and that gendered labour is not “natural” but socialized</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Khalid Medani</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741x24z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zg476</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440z16w"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of East Asian Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Map of the soul: Data-based body play across media in K-Pop</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rols, Amélie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Throughout the past decade, Hallyu, the “Korean Wave”, has taken the global pop music scene by storm. Credits are due in part to international fans who, by word of mouth and abundant engaging derivative works, helped spread idol groups’ popularity online. Since many of these fans never see their idols in the flesh, idols are now making themselves more available through an increasing number of channels, including live-streams or mobile games. Bodies play a central role in the highly digitally mediated relationship between fan and idol; consequently, idol bodies are under constant scrutiny by management companies, mass media, and fans. In this thesis, I argue that idol bodies, physical and digitized, are fragmented and reconstructed by industry and fans in order to create “perfect” personas. I conclude that this landscape promotes a neoliberal ideology through flat aesthetics and self-care, often to the detriment of idols’ and fans’ health. I hope to raise awareness to the destructive ways technology and bodies are mashed up in K-Pop</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Tout au long de la dernière décennie, Hallyu, la «vague coréenne», a pris d'assaut la scène mondiale de la musique pop. Le mérite revient en partie aux fans internationaux qui, par le bouche à oreille et les nombreuses œuvres dérivées engageantes, ont contribué à diffuser la popularité des groupes d'idoles sur les réseaux sociaux. Étant donné que bon nombre de ces fans ne voient jamais leurs idoles en chair et en os, les idoles se rendent désormais disponibles via un nombre croissant de filières, comme les diffusions en streaming direct, ou les jeux mobiles. Les corps jouent un rôle central dans cette relation entre fan et idole hautement médiatisée; par conséquent, les corps des idoles sont constamment surveillés par leurs agences, les médias, et leurs fans. Dans ce mémoire, je soutiens que les corps des idoles, aussi bien physiques que numérisés, sont fragmentés puis reconstruits par l'industrie elle-même ainsi que les fans, afin de créer des personnages «parfaits». Je conclus que ce contexte promeut une idéologie néolibérale à travers l’esthétique du plat et du soucis de soi, souvent au détriment de la santé des idoles et des fans. J'espère mettre en lumière la façon destructrice dont la technologie et les corps sont mélangés dans la K-Pop</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gal Gvili</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Michelle Cho</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r771d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440z16w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>East Asian Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A79408265w"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of beam parameters on femtosecond laser induced surface structures on titanium and copper</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Biswas, Sanchari</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le micro-usinage au laser femtoseconde (fs) est capable de créer une grande variété de microstructures hiérarchiques en une seule étape sur tout type de matériaux, en toutes conditions, et sans avoir recours à un environnement sous-vide ou à des salles blanches. Ainsi, au long des années, le micro-usinage au laser femtoseconde est devenu une technique émergente d’ingénierie de surface. Puisque le résultat du micro-usinage dépend de plusieurs paramètres, pour exercer plus de contrôle sur le résultat, il est désirable de comprendre comment ces paramètres influencent la formation de structures de surface. Cependant, jusqu’à présent, la majorité des études s’est concentré sur la compréhension des effets des paramètres de micro-usinage sur le seuil d’ablation avec une analyse limitée de la formation de structures. De plus, une grande partie des études se concentre sur l’effet des paramètres telle la fluence, la vitesse du balayage ou le nombre de balayages. Encore, peu d’analyses qui se concernent avec les effets des paramètres du rayon laser tel la fréquence et la longueur d’onde existent. Cette thèse a pour objectif de montrer les effets des paramètres du rayon laser sur la formation de structures afin d’adresser les lacunes qui existent présentement. Afin d’analyser l’effet de la fréquence, des structures créées par micro-usinage de surface métalliques, a base de titane (Ti) et cuivre (Cu), a 1 et 10 kHz ont été comparées. Il a été découvert que l’effet de la fréquence sur le seuil de formation des structures dépend fortement des propriétés des matériaux telle la constante de couplage électron-phonon (e-ph) et la conductivité thermique (k). Sur le cuivre, les seuils de formation de structures ont baissé tandis que sur le titane les seuils de formation ont augmenté en fonction de la fréquence. Cette opposition a été attribuée aux différentes propriétés des matériaux et à la dynamique de fusion qui en dérive. Par micro-usinage du Ti à 10 kHz, la couche en fusion créée par une impulsion laser persiste jusqu’à l’arrivée de l’impulsion suivante. Cette couche agit comme un matériau diélectrique vis-à-vis de l’impulsion suivante, et ainsi augmente le seuil de formation de structures. Cependant, sur le Cu, la couche en fusion est rapidement resolidifiée, et aucune phase diélectrique n’est observée. De plus, l’effet de la fréquence sur la texture de surface a été étudié par analyse lacunaire. Les structures sur les deux métaux qui ont été fabriquées à des fluences relativement basses ont des lacunarités plus élevées après fabrication à 10 kHz. Au contraire, les structures fabriquées à des fluences plus élevées ont des lacunarités plus élevées après fabrication à 1 kHz. Ensuite, l’effet de la longueur d’onde sur la formation de structures a été examiné. Des échantillons de Ti et Cu ont été micro-usinés a quatre longueurs d’onde différentes dans le domaine UV-VIS-IR (275 nm, 400 nm, 800 nm, et 1200 nm). Ceci a permit d’enregistrer l’évolution des structures sur tout le long du spectre de longueurs d’onde. L’effet de la longueur d’onde sur le seuil de formation des structures a aussi été déterminé. Il a été découvert que le seuil de formation de structures dépend fortement du spectre d’absorption du matériau. Intéressement, en contraste avec les résultats d’ablation a impulsion unique ou une corrélation positive est observée entre le seuil d’ablation et la longueur d’onde, nos résultats pour le seuil de formation de structures démontrent une corrélation négative avec l’absorption du matériau tout au long du spectre de longueur d’ondes.  En somme, cette thèse contribue au savoir actuel concernant les interactions entre les lasers fs et les matériaux en adressant les lacunes qui existent en ce qui concerne l’effet des paramètres des rayons laser sur les résultats de micro-usinage</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Femtosecond (fs) laser micromachining has the ability to impart a large variety of hierarchical microstructures in a single processing step on all types of materials, under any ambient condition and without the requirement of clean room or high vacuum facilities. Thereby with years, fs laser micromachining has become an emergent surface engineering technique. Since the nature of the micromachining outcome strongly depends on several micromachining parameters, in order to exercise control over the machining outcome, it is desirable to understand how these parameters influence surface structure formation. However, the major focus of existing research has been on understanding the effects of micromachining parameters on single or multiple pulse ablation threshold with limited discussion on structure formation. Furthermore, most reports discuss the effect of parameters such as the fluence, or scan velocity or number of scans. Again, limited reports exist that outline the effect of laser beam parameters such as the pulse repetition rate and the laser irradiation wavelength. This thesis aims to show the effect of the beam parameters (the repetition rate and irradiation wavelength) on structure formation in pursuit of bridging the gaps in literature.To analyze the effect of repetition rate, structures resulting from micromachining metallic samples, titanium (Ti) and copper (Cu), at 1 and 10 kHz repetition rate were compared. It was discovered that the effect of repetition rate on the structure thresholds strongly depend on the material properties such as the electron-phonon (e-ph) coupling constant and the thermal conductivity (k). On Cu, the structure thresholds decreased whereas on Ti the structure thresholds increased with the increase in repetition rate. This opposing trend was attributed to the opposing material characteristic and the resultant melt dynamics. When machining Ti at 10 kHz, the melt layer induced by one laser pulse persists until the next pulse arrives. The melt layer acts as a dielectric for the subsequent pulse, thereby increasing the structure thresholds. On Cu, however, the melt layer quickly resolidifies, and no such dielectric-like phase is observed.Additionally, the effect of repetition rate on surface texture was carried out through lacunarity analysis. Structures on both metals that were fabricated at relatively lower fluence had higher lacunarity when micromachined at 10 kHz. On the contrary, structures that were fabricated at higher fluence had higher lacunarity when micromachined at 1 kHz.Next, the effect of irradiation wavelength on structure formation was examined. Ti and Cu samples were micromachined at four different wavelengths in the UV-Vis-IR range (275 nm, 400 nm, 800 nm and 1200 nm). This conveniently allowed to map the structure evolution along the entire wavelength spectrum. The effect of irradiation wavelength on the structure thresholds was also determined. It was discovered that the structure thresholds strongly depend on the material's absorbance spectra. Interestingly, in contrast to results from single spot ablation where a positive correlation is found between the ablation threshold and wavelength, our results for the structure thresholds rather demonstrate a negative correlation with a material's absorbance across the wavelength spectrum.Additionally, several other new surface structures were fabricated and reported for the first time, among which the formation mechanism of ‘aggregate’ structures, one of the new surface structures, is presented in this thesis.Altogether, this thesis contributes to the current knowledge on the (fs) laser-material interaction in the direct (fs) laser micromachining technique by addressing the gaps that exist in determining the effect of laser beam parameters on the micromachining outcome</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anne-Marie Kietzig</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483p725.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79408265w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az316q590x"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The dynamics of multiple ecosystem services: Improving models for better management of multifunctional landscapes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rieb, Jesse</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>People around the world depend on ecosystems to provide them with a variety of benefits, known as ecosystem services (ES). These can include provisioning services, such as food or timber, regulating services such as carbon sequestration or erosion control, and cultural services, such as recreation or spiritual value. The ecosystem services concept is a powerful tool for conserving ecosystems and supporting people’s wellbeing, in part because quantification of these benefits allows them to be more easily compared with other costs and benefits and because it demonstrates how conservation of ecosystems can bring real, tangible benefits to people. Decision-makers from governments, NGOs, and corporations are increasingly turning to ES as a way to make decisions that better protect the health and wellbeing of ecosystems and people. ES are provided by complex webs of interacting social and ecological components and processes, and decision-makers rely on ES models to make sense of this complexity. In order to be broadly useful to decision-makers who wish to protect the health and well-being of ecosystems and people, ES models must be capable of providing clear and accurate information about when, where, and how ES are provided. To make this even more challenging, ES models must also be general enough to be applicable in different environmental and social contexts, and must be simple enough to be used by non-experts. While current ES models have made great progress in quantifying and visualizing the contributions of nature to human wellbeing, there are still areas where they fall short of meeting decision-makers’ needs. In this thesis, I focus on two of these gaps, the spatial and temporal dynamics of ES and the co-production of ES by natural and human drivers, with the aim of developing a better understanding of these aspects of ES provision that can eventually lead to improved ES models.I begin by evaluating the state of current ES models to identify gaps and opportunities for advances. Through reviewing the ES modelling literature and a workshop involving ES modelling experts, I identify three main gaps—spatial and temporal dynamics of ES, connecting ES to beneficiaries, and the co-production of ES by natural and human drivers—where current models do not fully meet the needs of decision-makers. The remaining chapters of my thesis contribute to filling these gaps. I then look at the spatial distribution of multiple ES in the Montérégie region of Québec to better understand how the configuration of landscapes affects the provision of multiple ES and their interactions. This work provides evidence that landscape configuration may influence the strength and direction of ES interactions, and may serve as a management tool for enhancing synergies and reducing trade-offs among ES. Next, I analyze data on the provision of three ES—agriculture, water purification, and nature recreation—and their drivers to better understand the relationships between natural and human drivers of ES co-production, showing how these relationships tend to be non-linear. Finally, I build a simulation model to explore the long-term consequences of different ES management decisions. Using the model, I show how different assumptions about dynamics and interactions among the drivers of ES provision can lead to different long-term outcomes for ES provision. Overall, my thesis provides important insights into the spatial and temporal dynamics of the social-ecological systems that produce multiple ES, in order to lead to better ES models and improved management for ecosystems and people</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La population humaine compte sur les écosystèmes pour l’approvisionnement de nombreux avantages, connus sous le nom de services écosystémiques (SE). Ceux-ci peuvent inclure des services d'approvisionnement comme la nourriture ou le bois, des services de régulation comme la séquestration du carbone ou le contrôle de l'érosion, et des services socioculturels comme les bénéfices récréatifs et spirituels. Le concept de SE est un outil puissant pour les décideurs des gouvernements, des ONG, et d'entreprises qui intègrent de plus en plus les SE pour préserver les écosystèmes et de promouvoir le bien-être des gens. La comparaison et quantification scientifique permet de mesurer les coûts et les bénéfices et démontre que la conservation de l'environnement peut fournir des avantages réels et tangibles pour la santé des gens et le bien-être des écosystèmes.Les SE sont fournis par des réseaux complexes des composants et procédés, socio-écologiques, qui interagissent entre eux-même, et les décideurs dépendent des modèles des SE pour déchiffrer cette complexité. Pour être utile dans les décisions, les modèles des SE doivent être claires et précises sur quand, où, et comment les SE sont approvisionnés. De plus, il faudrait que les modèles des SE soient assez générales pour être applicables dans des nombreux contextes, et assez simple pour être utilisés par des non-experts. Bien que les modèles des SE se sont améliorés avec la quantification et la visualisation des contributions de la nature au bien-être humain, il reste encore quelques domaines où ils ne répondent pas encore aux besoins des décideurs. Dans cette thèse, je me concentre sur deux de ces lacunes, les dynamiques spatiales et temporelles des SE et le co-approvisionnement des SE par des facteurs naturels et anthropiques. Le but de cette étude est de développer une meilleure connaissance des aspects de l’approvisionnement des SE, qui peuvent éventuellement contribuer à améliorer les modèles des SE.Je commence premièrement par évaluer l’état actuel des modèles des SE pour identifier les lacunes et les opportunités d'avancement. J'identifie trois lacunes majeures lors d'une revue littéraire sur les modèles des SE et lors d'un atelier impliquant les experts de la modélisation des SE—les dynamiques spatiales et temporales des SE, les liens entre les SE et leurs bénéficiaires, et le co-approvisionnement des SE par des facteurs naturels et anthropiques—où les modèles actuels ne répondent complètement aux besoins des décideurs. Les chapitres suivantes contribuent à combler ces lacunes. Ensuite, j’étudie la distribution spatiale de plusieurs SE dans la région de la Montérégie au Québec pour mieux comprendre comment la configuration du paysage impacte l’approvisionnement de plusieurs SE et leurs interactions. Les résultats nous montrent que la configuration du paysage peut influencer la magnitude et la direction des interactions entre SE, et pourrait servir d’outil de gestion pour renforcer des synergies et diminuer les compromis entre SE. Ensuite, j’analyse des données sur l’approvisionnement de trois SE, l’agriculture, la purification de l’eau, et la récréation plein air, et ses facteurs pour mieux entendre les relations entre les facteurs naturels et anthropiques du co-approvisionnement des SE. Je démontre que ces relations sont souvent non-linéaires. Donc, je construis un modèle de simulation pour évaluer les conséquences à long terme des différents décisions de gestion. En utilisant ce modèle, on observe que les différentes scénarios relatives aux dynamiques et interactions entre les facteurs qui affectent l’approvisionnement des SE peuvent causer des résultats différents sur l’approvisionnement des SE. Le but de ma thèse est de fournir les données essentielles sur les dynamiques spatiales et temporelles des systèmes socio-écologiques qui fournit plusieurs SE. Cette contribution servira à améliorer les modèles et la gestion des SE pour le bien-être gens et les écosystèmes</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elena Bennett</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mv38k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q590x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Natural Resource Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g683m"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>III-Nitride nanocrystals for green photonics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rashid, Roksana Tonny</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La photonique verte est la clé pour relever les défis énergétiques et environnementaux auxquels nous sommes confrontés. Les semi-conducteurs III-nitrure ont des propriétés uniques qui peuvent être exploitées pour réaliser des dispositifs et des systèmes photoniques verts de nouvelle génération. Leur bande interdite d’énergie couvre presque tout le spectre solaire, ce qui en fait un matériau idéal pour les LED et les lasers fonctionnant dans les domaines bleu, vert et rouge, ainsi que pour la récupération de l’énergie solaire. Cependant, les épilayers classiques au nitrure III ont quelques problèmes fondamentaux. Il est très difficile d'incorporer une composition à haute teneur en indium. Par conséquent, la performance des LED vertes à base de GaN est pire qu’un fonctionnement dans le spectre bleu, ce qui mène à ce que l’on appelle le fossé écart en photonique. Pour ces mêmes circonstances, l’existence de dispositifs photovoltaïques efficaces utilisant des matériaux à base de GaN n’a pas été prouvée. La réalisation de ces dispositifs et systèmes à haute efficacité répondra à certains des grands défis auxquels nous sommes confrontés, notamment la production d'énergie, la fiabilité, la distribution et l'utilisation. Par conséquent, il est essentiel de développer de nouveaux matériaux semi-conducteurs à base de nitrure III pour réaliser des dispositifs et des systèmes photoniques écologiques. Dans cette thèse, nous avons étudié la croissance et la structure fondamentale ainsi que les propriétés électriques et optiques des hétérostructures InGaN/GaN par épitaxie de faisceaux moléculaires (MBE) pour des applications dans les émetteurs de lumière verte et la photosynthèse artificielle. Grâce à l’utilisation de techniques d’épitaxie de zone sélective (SAG), les réseaux de points dans le noyau-coquille InGaN / AlGaN ont été développés avec une taille, un espacement et une morphologie précieusement contrôlés. Nous avons démontré, pour la première fois, que toutes les diodes vertes au laser à émission de surface épitaxiale peuvent présenter une très faible densité de courant de seuil ~ 400 A/cm2 à température ambiante. Nous avons également exploré le potentiel des nanocristaux à base de GaN pour le développement de dispositifs de photosynthèse artificielle destinés à la conversion du CO2 en combustibles propres, y compris le syngaz, une combinaison de CO et de H2, l'un des principaux combustibles solaires du futur. Nous avons étudié la conception et les performances de cellules photoélectrochimiques et photochimiques pour la production de gaz de synthèse. Un nouveau record de référence d'efficacité de 1.88% de l'énergie solaire par rapport au gaz de synthèse a été atteint en intégrant des particules de co-catalyseur Au/Pt sur des réseaux de nanofils de GaN dans une cellule photoélectrochimique. Afin d'utiliser le spectre solaire visible abondant, nous avons conçu une hétérostructure de nanofils InGaN/GaN multi-bandes, qui est décorée avec les nanostructures uniques noyau/coque Au/CrOx. Les hétérostructures d'ingénierie InGaN/GaN peuvent présenter un rendement de conversion de l'énergie solaire en gaz de synthèse d'environ 0.91% dans une simple cellule photochimique à une étape. Cette thèse établit l'utilisation de nanocristaux de nitrure III pour des émetteurs de lumière verte à haute efficacité énergétique et pour la production de combustible solaire</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Green photonics, i.e., photonic devices and systems that can operate at high efficiency and with reduced energy consumption and minimum environmental impact, holds the key to address the energy and environmental challenges we face. III-nitride semiconductors have unique properties that can be exploited to realize next generation green photonic devices and systems. Their energy bandgap can cover nearly the entire solar spectrum, making them an ideal material for LEDs and lasers operating in the blue, green and red, and for solar energy harvesting. However, conventional III-nitride epilayers have some fundamental issues. It is very difficult to incorporate high indium composition. As a result, the performance of GaN-based green LEDs is much worse than those operating in the blue spectrum, leading to the so-called “green gap” in photonics. On the same circumstances, there has been no demonstration of efficient photovoltaic devices using GaN-based materials. The realization of these devices and systems with high efficiency will address some of the grand challenges we face, including energy generation, reliability, distribution and utilization. Therefore, it is essential to develop novel III-nitride semiconductor materials to realize green photonic devices and systems.In this thesis, we have investigated the molecular beam epitaxial (MBE) growth and fundamental structural, electrical and optical properties of InGaN/GaN heterostructures for applications in green light emitters and artificial photosynthesis. With the use of selective area epitaxy (SAG), InGaN/AlGaN core–shell dot-in-nanowire arrays have been grown with precisely controlled size, spacing, and morphology. We have demonstrated, for the first time, all epitaxial surface-emitting green laser diodes, which can exhibit a very low threshold current density ~400 A/cm2 at room temperature. We have further explored the potential of GaN-based nanocrystals for the development of artificial photosynthesis devices for the conversion of CO2 to syngas, a combination of CO and H2 and one of the prominent future solar fuels. We have investigated the design and performance of photoelectrochemical and photochemical cells for syngas production. A new benchmark record of 1.88% efficiency for syngas generation has been achieved by integrating Au/Pt co-catalyst particles on GaN nanowire arrays in a photoelectrochemical cell. In order to utilize the abundant visible solar spectrum, we have designed a multi-band InGaN/GaN nanowire heterostructure, which is decorated with the unique Au/CrOx core/shell nanostructures. The engineered InGaN/GaN heterostructures can exhibit a energy conversion efficiency of ~0.91% in a simple, one-step photochemical cell. This thesis establishes the use of III-nitride nanocrystals for energy efficient green light emitters and solar fuel production</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thomas Szkopek</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Zetian Mi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qp34q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g683m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nk29n"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Concurrent rhythms of prosody and syntax in the neurophysiological tracking of sentence structure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Glushko, Anastasia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The current doctoral thesis evaluates processing of sentence constituents using a novel electrophysiological approach to studying high-level language processing: namely, frequency tagging. The extant research results indicate it is debatable whether and how the hierarchical syntactic structure of language (Chomsky, 1959, 1995) is processed by language users. Principal difficulties in evaluating syntactic structure processing online are methodological in nature. They include the need to rely on studies of grammatical error processing as well as the frequent alignment of syntactic structure with other layers of sentential information (e.g., prosody and semantics). The first concern was recently addressed by Ding, Melloni, Zhang, Tian, and Poeppel (2016) who presented spoken sentences with isochronous structure (e.g., a two-syllable noun phrase followed by a two-syllable verb phrase) to their participants. This experimental design allowed them to ‘tag’ the frequencies at which phrases and sentences appeared in the speech stream: prominent EEG spectral power peaks were elicited at the exact (‘tagged’) frequencies of syntactic constituents. The results were taken as evidence for cortical tracking of hierarchical syntactic structures and the approach was said to be promising for studying syntactic processing in diverse populations. Crucially, however, the relative role of various layers of sentential information in the elicitation of observed effects in frequency tagging studies of sentence processing has yet to be understood. In Manuscript 1, I addressed this question by investigating concurrent processing of overt and covert (i.e., implicit, subvocalized) prosodic information on the one hand, and syntactic structure on the other using a frequency tagging paradigm (across three experiments). We applied several prosodic contours to two types of syntactic structures tagging contrasting frequencies in each case. The prosodic contours were applied either overtly, via manipulating the speech signal of the sentences, or covertly, by asking participants to imagine a specific prosodic contour. We demonstrated that overt and covert prosody processing does indeed contribute to the elicitation of spectral power peaks at tagged sentence constituent frequencies. Further, we describe the interactive effects of syntax and prosody directly evident from the EEG responses at the tagged sentence constituent frequencies in perfectly grammatical sentences: When prosodic structure aligned with syntactic phrasing, the spectral power peak at phrase frequency was enhanced compared to a neutral prosodic condition without prosodic cues. When prosody and syntax were misaligned, responses at the sentence frequency were suppressed.In Manuscript 2, we undertook a methodological investigation of the frequency tagging technique as applied to sentence processing, which included data simulations and (re-)analysis of real data. After providing an overview of the technique, we first address the role of non-syntactic and syntactic variables (other than prosody) in the elicitation of spectral power peaks at frequencies of sentence constituents in previous frequency tagging studies. Thereafter, we demonstrate potential caveats of various approaches to data analysis in these studies. Based on our investigation, we discuss the potential for use of the frequency tagging technique in studying sentence processing.This dissertation contributes to our understanding of sentence processing by demonstrating concurrent and interactive low-frequency cortical tracking of prosodic and syntactic structures of sentences in the case of both overt and covert prosody. The work outlines the potential, as well as the constraints, of the frequency tagging technique as used in sentence processing research, and allows us to situate this approach within the spectrum of other neurolinguistic methods</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La présente thèse de doctorat évalue le traitement des constituants des phrases au moyen d’une nouvelle approche électrophysiologique permettant d’étudier les mécanismes sous-jacents de l’analyse linguistique de haut-niveau, que l’on nomme le marquage de fréquence (“frequency tagging” en anglais). Jusqu’ici, l’existence et le fonctionnement du traitement des structures syntaxiques de la phrase (Chomsky, 1959, 1995) ont été largement débattues. Les principales difficultés concernant leur évaluation sont méthodologiques: elles sont liées à la nécessité de se reposer sur le traitement d'erreurs grammaticales, et aussi à la superposition fréquente de la structure syntaxique avec d'autres niveaux d'information linguistique (ex. la prosodie et la sémantique). Le premier point a été récemment abordé par Ding, Melloni, Zhang, Tian et Poeppel (2016), qui ont présenté en modalité auditive des phrases avec une structure isochrone (ex. un syntagme nominal de deux syllabes, suivi d’un syntagme verbal également bisyllabique). Ce dessin expérimental a permis de “marquer” les fréquences, qui dans le signal de parole, correspondent aux syntagmes et aux phrases. En d’autres termes, des pics de densité spectrale du signal EEG ont été observés aux mêmes fréquences que les constituants syntaxiques. Ces données semblent attester du pistage cortical des structures syntaxiques, et l’approche expérimentale utilisée s'avérait prometteuse pour étudier le traitement de la syntaxe dans des populations diverses.Cependant, les rôles respectifs des différents niveaux d’information linguistique sur les effets observés dans les études de marquage de fréquence sont assez mal compris. Dans le Manuscrit 1, nous avons étudié cette question en implémentant un paradigme de marquage de fréquence qui examine, à travers trois expériences, le traitement concomitant de la prosodie explicite et implicite d’une part, et de la structure syntaxique d’autre part. Nous avons imposé plusieurs contours prosodiques sur deux types de structures syntaxiques qui marquent des fréquences distinctes. Les contours prosodiques étaient appliqués soit explicitement, grâce à la manipulation du signal acoustique, soit implicitement, en demandant aux participants d’imaginer un contour prosodique particulier. Nos résultats montrent que la prosodie explicite et implicite contribuent effectivement à l’induction de maximums de densité spectrale suivant le marquage de constituants de la phrase. De plus, nous observons une interaction entre la syntaxe et la prosodie: quand la structure prosodique est alignée sur la syntaxe, les pics observés à la fréquence des syntagmes étaient plus larges en comparaison à la condition sans indices prosodiques. Lorsque la prosodie et la syntaxe n’étaient pas alignées, les réponses à la fréquence des syntagmes étaient éliminées.Le Manuscrit 2 est une évaluation méthodologique de la technique du marquage de fréquence appliquée au traitement de la phrase, incluant des simulations de données et des (ré-)analyses de données réelles. Nous avons d’abord questionné le rôle des variables syntaxiques et non-syntaxiques (autres que la prosodie) dans l’élicitation de pics de densité spectrale à la fréquence des constituants. Ensuite, nous avons mis en lumière des biais potentiels liés à plusieurs approches d’analyse de données dans les études existantes, et discuté le potentiel de la technique de marquage de fréquence pour étudier le traitement de la phrase. Cette thèse démontre les effets coopératifs et intéractifs du pistage cortical des structures syntaxiques et prosodiques pour la prosodie implicite et explicite. Elle contribue à notre compréhension des mécanismes sous-jacents au traitement de la phrase. Le présent travail souligne le potentiel, mais aussi les contraintes associés à la technique du marquage de fréquence telle qu’utilisée pour la recherche sur la traitement du langage, et permet de situer cette approche sur le spectre des méthodes en neurolinguistique</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Karsten Steinhauer</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xr076.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nk29n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap26771013"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Methods for real-time simulation of systems of rigid and flexible bodies with unilateral contact and friction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hewlett, Joseph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Fast, accurate and stable simulation algorithms targeting mechanical systems have long been a major concern for engineers, computer scientists and physicists. Many important applications of dynamics exist, ranging from exploring the behaviour of physical systems, to designing new mechanical systems and objects with applications to manufacture, design, computer graphics and fundamental research. Real-time numerical integration methods are needed in interactive simulation, such as found in simulation environments for training, haptic devices, and other interactive virtual environments, which simulate large, complex systems whose models cannot be handled symbolically. In this thesis we are interested in the problem of simulating large, fairly complex systems in real-time. Consequently, first-order integration methods are studied, given that it is currently not possible to solve a large number of highly nonlinear problems quickly enough to perform numerically stable, high-order accuracy numerical integration in real time. Also, due to the time constraints at play, numerical stability must be prioritized over accuracy, as large integration time steps are required. The types of applications mentioned above tend to require the simulation of systems involving articulated rigid bodies and contact, as many of the mechanisms that are operated by humans are of this type. To that end, our first systems of interest are open chains of rigid bodies, as explored in Chapters 3 and 4.The contribution of Chapter 3 is a generalization of the geometric stiffness method. The original method is only applicable to systems with a flat configuration space, thereby ruling out real-life dynamic behaviour, such as rigid body rotation. The geometric stiffness method is extended to cover the case of an arbitrary configuration space. Furthermore, a monitoring method is developed to dynamically alter the extent of the energy dissipation due to the geometric stiffness term, which allows for good enough control of dissipation so as to let the analyst reach a better compromise between energy conservation and stability than with the geometric stiffness term alone. The contribution of Chapter 4 on chains of rigid bodies is a method of selection of constraint stabilization parameters. The stabilization coefficients are related to the stiffness and damping coefficients that relax the system constraints, whereby the constraints are integrated over a smaller time step using an asynchronous integration method. This allows a physically-based choice of stabilization coefficients, and a guarantee of energy consistency, with, on average, an improvement in constraint satisfaction.In Chapter 5, the real-time simulation of flexible bodies is investigated. Due to the constraints upon the integration method, i.e., speed and stability, we necessarily limit ourselves to first-order time-stepping integration methods. The first part of this section demonstrates a fast first-order method for the integration of models involving flexible bodies, which are described using the Absolute Nodal Coordinate Formulation (ANCF). The integration method can stably integrate ANCF elements over a large range of stiffness values. The key novel contribution is a set of stabilization terms, which only require the computation of the first derivatives of the strain. The method does not depend on any tunable parameters, the only variable introduced in the discretization and stabilization of the method being the time step itself. The integration method is then extended to arbitrary ANCF elements. This includes cable elements, shell elements and volumetric elements with arbitrary shape functions.In Chapter 6, an integration algorithm for ANCF elements in nonsmooth systems is developed. Four different approximations of the Coulomb friction model are compared and contrasted against each other. The four different models are adaptations of a penalty method with regularized Coulomb friction, the box..</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les algorithmes de simulation rapides, précis et stables pour les systèmes mécaniques sont depuis longtemps l’intérêt des ingénieurs, informaticiens et physiciens. Plusieurs applications dynamiques importantes existent, de l’exploration du comportement des systèmes physiques, jusqu'à la conception de nouveaux systèmes mécaniques et objets ayant des applications en fabrication, conception, et recherche fondamentale. Des méthodes temps réel d’intégration numérique sont requises pour les simulations interactives, tels que les environnements d'entraînement, les dispositifs haptiques ainsi que d’autres environnements virtuels qui simulent des systèmes larges et complexes pour lesquels les modèles ne peuvent pas être définis symboliquement. Dans cette thèse, nous sommes intéressés au problème de la simulation en temps réel des systèmes larges et relativement complexes. Par consèquent, nous recherchons les méthodes d’intégration du premier ordre, tout en, considérant qu’il n’est pas possible, à l'heure actuelle, de résoudre un grand nombre de problèmes hautement non linéaires assez rapidement pour rèaliser des intégrations numériques en temps réel qui soient stables et précises. De plus, en raison des contraintes de temps, la stabilité numérique doit être priorisée par rapport à la précision, puisque de grands intervalles de temps sont nécessaires. Le type d’application mentionné ci-dessus, la simulation de systèmes impliquant des corps rigides articulés et des contacts, puisque plusieurs mécanismes opérés par les humains sont de ce type. À cet effet, nos premiers systèmes d’intérêt sont les chaînes de corps rigides, tel qu’exploré dans les Chapitres 3 et 4.La contribution du Chapitre 3 est une généralisation de la méthode de rigidité géométrique. La méthode originale est seulement applicable aux systèmes ayant un espace de configuration plan, excluant ainsi des comportements dynamiques nécessaires tel que les rotations de corps rigide. La méthode de rigidité géométrique est étendue afin de couvrir le cas d’un espace de configuration arbitraire. De plus, une méthode de contrôle est développée afin d’altérer dynamiquement la dissipation d’énergie causée par le terme de la rigidité géométrique, ce qui permet un bon contrôle de la dissipation, permettant ainsi aux analystes d’obtenir un meilleur compromis entre conservation d’énergie et stabilité qu’avec le terme de rigidité géométrique seulement. La contribution du Chapitre 4 pour les chaînes de corps rigides est une méthode de sélection des paramètres de contrainte de stabilisation. Les coefficients de stabilisation sont reliés aux coefficients du rigidité et d’amortissement qui relâchent les contraintes du système, où les contraintes sont intégrées sur un plus petit intervalle de temps en utilisant une méthode d’intégration asynchrone. Ceci permet de choisir les coefficients de stabilisation en fonction de la physique, ainsi qu’une garantie de la consistance de l’énergie, ce qui, en moyenne, améliore la satisfaction des contraintes.Au Chapitre 5, la simulation temps réel des corps flexibles est ètudièe. En raison des contraintes impliquées dans la méthode d’intégration, c'est-à-dire, la rapidité et la stabilité, nous nous limitons aux méthodes d’intégration par intervalle de temps de premier ordre. La première partie de cette section démontre une méthode d’intégration rapide de premier ordre pour les corps flexibles qui sont décrits en utilisant la Formulation par Coordonnèes Absolues des Nœuds (FCAN). Cette méthode peut intégrer stablement des éléments FCAN sur une grande plage de valeurs de rigidité. La contribution est un ensemble de termes de stabilisation qui requiert uniquement le calcul de la première dérivée de l’élongation. Cette méthode ne dépend d’aucun paramètre ajustable; la seule variable introduite dans la discrétisation et stabilisation de la méthode est l’intervalle de temps. La méthode d’intégration est ensuite étendue aux éléments FCAN arbitraires. Ceci inclut..</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jorge Angeles</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jozsef Kovecses</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq978041d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p26771013</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn999c115"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Targeted and non-targeted analysis of plastic-related chemicals in food</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tian, Lei</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les substances chimiques associées aux plastiques (abrév. PRCs) sont définies comme un groupe incluant les monomères, les antioxydants, les additifs, mais aussi tout produit de dégradation des plastiques ou de ces composés. La présence des PRCs dans les aliments et les effets potentiels sur la santé humaine ont créé des préoccupations pour la santé des consommateurs. A date, la surveillance des PRCs dans les aliments s’est concentrée sur l’analyse ciblée et la quantification de résidus spécifiques, basées sur des outils comme la chromatographie en phase (HPLC) ou gazeuse (GC) couplée a la spectrométrie de masse (MS). Ainsi, le bisphénol A (BPA) et plusieurs phthalates ont été détectés dans divers types. Des outils analytiques sont désormais nécessaires pour protéger la santé des consommateurs afin de passer au crible et identifier les PRCs dans les aliments, en incluant non seulement les composés « connus » mais aussi ceux « inconnus ». Récemment seulement, des approches non-ciblées sont apparus pour la recherche des résidus chimiques et restent à être validés pour le domaine des PRCs. L’objectif principal de cette recherche est de développer et d’optimiser des approches non-ciblées pour l’étude des PRCs dans les aliments, avec comme emphase l’étude de l’influence du traitement post-analyse des données sur l’identification des résidus traces. Dans le Chapitre 3 de cette thèse, une méthode non-ciblée, base sur la spectrométrie de masse en tandem quadripolaire/a temps de vol (HPLC-QTOF-MS) a été optimisée pour évaluer la migration chimique de résidus depuis les bouteilles d’eau en plastique réutilisables.  Les résultats indiquent que toutes les bouteilles d’eau testées ne contiennent pas de BPA, ou d’analogues du BPA. L’effet du traitement post-analyse des données sur la détection des composes a été étudié de manière systématique, et les résultats ont confirmés que les paramètres doivent être optimisés pour l’extraction et l’identification des composés. La méthode optimisée a été appliquée efficacement pour identifier le téréphtalate mono méthyl dans des simulants alimentaires en contact avec les bouteilles en TritanTM. Dans le Chapitre 4, une méthode non-ciblée a été optimisée pour évaluer les PRCs et d’autres contaminants environnementaux dans une matrice biologique alimentaire complexe (des filets de brochet). Par une méthode ciblée, aucun des analogues du BPA n’ont été détectés dans des échantillons de brochets de deux sites du Saint-Laurent dans la région de Montréal, suggérant que peu ces résidus ne s’accumulent pas dans les muscles des poissons pêchés a ces deux sites. La méthode non-ciblée a permis d’identifier dans les extraits de brochet des substances d’importants pour l’environnement et la santé des consommateurs. Dans le Chapitre 5, une méthode non-ciblée a été optimisée pour le criblage des PRCs dans différents types d’aliments (poisson, poulet, thon en conserve, légumes, pain et beurre).Divers contaminants ont été détectés, notamment le BPA, le bisphénol S (BPS), l’adipate de bis(2-éthylhéxyle), l’adipate de dibutyle, le méthacrylate d'hexadécyle et l’Irganox®1076. Ces résultats montrent pour la première fois le BPS dans les échantillons de poisson et de poulets au Canada. Enfin, dans le Chapitre 6, la méthode non-ciblée a été appliquée à la dégradation thermique du BPA et du BPS dans l’eau (matrice modèle) et des muscles de poisson (matrice réelle). Le BPA et le BPS ne se dégradent dans l’eau (&lt;0.1% de dégradation) mais se dégradent dans le poisson (environ 35% pour le BPA et le BPS). Les produits de dégradation dans les matrices de poisson dopées, sont différents de ceux observés dans les matrices contaminées naturellement. En conclusion, cette recherche montre que l’approche non-ciblée est critique pour comprendre la présence et le devenir des PRCs dans les aliments, et les résultats contribuent à raffiner l’évaluation des risques pour la santé pour les consommateurs</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Plastic-related chemicals (PRCs) are substances related to plastics including the initial components of the plastics (e.g. monomers, antioxidants, additives) and the degradation products of plastics. The occurrence of PRCs in food and their potential adverse health effects have raised concerns about the health of consumers. To date, the surveillance of PRCs in food has mostly focused on the targeted screening and quantification of specific residues using tools such as high performance liquid chromatography (HPLC) or gas chromatography (GC) coupled with mass spectrometry (MS). For example, bisphenol A (BPA) and several phthalates have been detected in different types of food. To ensure food safety though, it is now acknowledged there is a need for analytical tools able to screen and identify not only “known” PRCs in food, but also the new “unknown” compounds. The main objective of my research is to develop and optimize a non-targeted method to investigate PRCs in food with an emphasis on the investigation of the influence of data processing parameters on the identification of trace residues in food. In Chapter 3, a non-targeted workflow was optimized based on the HPLC hyphenated to quadruple time-of-flight MS (HPLC-QTOF-MS) analysis to investigate leachable residues from reusable bottles.Results indicated that all tested bottles are free of BPA, and the bisphenol analogues were not applied as BPA replacement in these bottle manufacture. The effect of data post-processing parameters on the feature extraction in non-targeted analysis was also systematically investigated, and results confirmed that these parameters need to be carefully optimized to extract all the features and identify them accurately. The optimized method was effectively applied to identify monomethyl terephthalate at trace levels in food simulants in contact with TritanTM bottles. In Chapter 4, the non-targeted workflow was developed and optimized for the analysis of PRCs as well as other environmental contaminants in a complex food matrix (pike fish fillets). None of the bisphenol analogues used for targeted method validation were detected in pike samples suggesting that these chemicals do not accumulate at detectable concentrations in muscle of pike naturally-exposed in the St. Lawrence River at two sampling sites. The non-targeted workflow was shown to accurately identify chemicals of high environmental and health concern in pike muscle extracts. In Chapter 5, the optimized non-targeted workflow was applied to screen PRCs in different types of food (namely fish, chicken, canned tuna, leafy vegetables, bread and butter). A range of contaminants in different food matrices were detected and identified, including BPA, bisphenol S (BPS), bis(2-ethylhexyl) adipate, dibutyl adipate, hexadecyl methacrylate and Irganox1076. BPS was first reported in Canadian fresh fish and chicken breast samples. In Chapter 6, the optimized non-targeted workflow was applied to study the thermal degradation of BPA and BPS in water (model matrix) and fish muscles (real food). BPA and BPS did not degrade in water (less than 0.1% degradation) but degraded in fish matrix (about 35% degradation in fish for both BPA and BPS). The degradation products in spiked fish samples are different from those in incurred group. Overall, this research demonstrated that non-targeted analysis is crucial in understanding the occurrence and the fate of PRCs in food, and the results of the present research will contribute to refining current food safety risk assessments</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stephane Bayen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72pc732.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999c115</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613n294h"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Desautels Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The analyses of the impact of location, time and variety based product availability in fast-fashion retailing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ergin, Elcin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse se concentre sur l'étude de la disponibilité des produits et de la dynamique des ventes dans le cadre de la vente au détail à la mode avec trois projets de recherche. Dans la première étude, nous nous concentrons sur l'analyse de l'impact des pénuries de produits sur les ventes dans les points de vente voisins dans le cadre d'une chaîne de magasins de vente au détail à mode rapide. Notre analyse révèle que les ventes d'un article particulier dans un magasin de référence augmentent lorsque ce même article connaît des ruptures de stock dans les magasins voisins, en particulier pour ceux qui sont physiquement plus proches du magasin de référence. Ces résultats suggèrent qu'il existe un effet du subsitution des produits entre les magasins et qu’il se dissipe avec la distance. La preuve de ces effets de substitution de produits intra-entreprise a également des implications managériales. Premièrement, les modèles de subsitution des produits présumés d'un magasin à l'autre varient selon le type d'emplacement, la substituabilité des produits est plus prononcée pour les points de vente focaux situés dans les rues que pour les points de vente situés dans les centres commerciaux. Dans le deuxième projet, l'impact des pénuries de produits est étudié en utilisant un ensemble de données plus granulaire qui contient également les informations sur la taille des articles. Ces données plus granulaires permettent de construire de nouveaux modèles qui peuvent également éclairer sur le timing de ces ruptures de stock. Nous effectuons également plusieurs analyses contrefactuelles basées sur nos résultats empiriques. Les résultats montrent que les revenus peuvent être améliorés de 2% à 3% selon le prix et le niveau des stocks lorsque le changement de magasin potentiel est pris en compte lors des décisions d'allocation des stocks. Dans le projet final, les introductions de nouvelles variétés de produits et la dynamique des ventes sont examinées à l'aide d'un autre ensemble de données qui couvre les ventes quotidiennes de la boutique en ligne d'un détaillant de mode. Cet ensemble de données comprend deux dates spécifiques où le détaillant a fait une expérience en fusionnant les inventaires des magasins physiques et des magasins en ligne. Ces expériences nous permettent d'étudier l'impact des introductions massives de produits de nouvelles variétés de modèles, de couleurs et de tailles sur les ventes</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis focuses on investigating product availability and sales dynamics under the fast-fashion retailing setting with three research projects. In the first study, we focus on analyzing the impact of neighboring outlets’ product shortages on a focal store’s sales in the setting of a multi-store fast fashion retailing chain. Our analysis reveals that sales for a particular item at a focal store increases when that same item experiences stock-outs in neighboring stores, especially so for neighboring stores that are physically closer to the focal store. These findings suggest that there is substitutability across stores and that this substitutability dissipates with physical distance. Evidence of these intra-firm product substitution effects also carries some managerial implications. In particular, inferred product substitutability patterns across stores vary depending on the location type, in that product substitutability is more pronounced for focal outlets located on streets as compared with outlets located in malls. In the second project, the impact of product shortages is studied by utilizing a more granular dataset which also contains the size information. This more granular data enables to construct new models which can also shed light on the value of the timing of these stock-outs. We also perform several counterfactual analysis based on our empirical findings. The results show that revenues can be improved by 2% to 3% depending on the price and inventory levels when the potential store switching is taken into account at inventory allocation decisions. In the final project, the new product variety introductions and sales dynamics are examined by using another dataset that covers the daily sales of the online store of a fast-fashion retailer. This dataset includes two specific dates where the retailer did an experiment as merging inventories of physical stores and online stores. These experiments enable us to investigate the impact of massive product introductions of new model, color and size varieties on sales</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mehmet Gumus</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vq340.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n294h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Management</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207tt65s"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Loss of community stability as a coherent ecological impact of a changing climate</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hutchison, Chantal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les modèles climatiques montrent à une écrasante majorité que 98 \% de la terre a connu son plus haut niveau de réchauffement au cours du XXe siècle. Au cours de cette période, une pléthore d'études ont démontré des impacts importants sur le biote. L'objectif de ma thèse est d'étudier la stabilité des communautés écologiques aux changements climatiques observés et prédits. Le changement climatique est souvent utilisé comme synonyme de déstabilisation dans le contexte des systèmes écologiques. L'un de mes objectifs est d'étudier si des types spécifiques d'organisation écologique amplifient ou atténuent la déstabilisation potentielle due à des types spécifiques de changement climatique. Je considère deux types de communautés très déséquilibrées: une forêt tropicale plantée et un réseau trophique saisonnier de la toundra arctique. La biodiversité peut fournir des mécanismes permettant d'amortir le fonctionnement de la communauté aux conditions environnementales changeantes. Dans mon premier chapitre, j'utilise des données d'une forêt plantée tropicale, âgée de c. 15 ans, pour étudier la stabilité des communautés d'arbres à travers un gradient de richesse en espèces aux événements climatiques extrêmes au cours de cette période. En utilisant une procédure d'amorçage, je développe une méthode statistique pour la détection de la réponse au stress dans la croissance et la mortalité de la communauté comme mesure de stabilité. Dans les communautés monospécifiques, contrairement aux richesses plus élevées, la croissance est fortement régulée par les extrêmes climatiques et la mortalité est plus élevée pendant une longue période de sécheresse. En utilisant des indicateurs de perte de résilience ou de ralentissement critique, je montre que pour les extrêmes de sécheresse rencontrés lors de l'expérience, il peut y avoir un effet de la diversité sur la perte de résilience, les communautés d'une seule espèce étant plus sujettes à la mort massive. Dans mon deuxième et mon troisième chapitres, je considère un réseau alimentaire simplifié de la toundra arctique dans une communauté fortement saisonnière sur l'île Bylot (lemming-renard-oie-hibou) où la biodiversité varie dans le temps en raison des espèces migratrices. Pour finalement étudier la stabilité aux conditions climatiques changeantes de l'Arctique, un modèle qui saisit la saisonnalité de la communauté est nécessaire. Sans intégrer la saisonnalité dans la modélisation du réseau trophique, en particulier pour les communautés à haute altitude ou latitude, les prévisions concernant les impacts du changement climatique peuvent être incertaines. Je construis un modèle multi-saison de la dynamique de la biomasse prédateur-proie basé sur un cadre de systèmes dynamiques hybrides (HDS) qui permet d'inclure à la fois la dynamique rapide (c.-à-d. la migration) et lente (c.-à-d. le prédateur-proie). Chaque saison est associée à un équilibre stable différent pour capturer un réseau trophique dont la topologie change avec la saison. Nous estimons les coefficients d'interaction hivernale pour l'HDS sur la base des données estivales de 1993 à 2018 afin de générer des séries chronologiques à long terme qui correspondent aux tendances observées dans les fluctuations de la biomasse des espèces. Je montre que les modèles multi-saisons, par rapport aux modèles qui n'intègrent pas la saisonnalité, peuvent révéler des interactions indirectes entre migrants et résidents. De plus, je détermine que la saisonnalité empêche les prédateurs migrateurs spécialisés de surexploiter les proies disponibles, ce qui suggère que la topologie du réseau trophique qui change dans le temps peut stabiliser la dynamique des communautés. Dans mon troisième chapitre, je développe des outils théoriques basés sur la théorie de la stabilité HDS afin d'étudier la stabilité en utilisant le modèle que je développe dans mon deuxième chapitre pour une communauté saisonnière avec des migrations..</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Climate models overwhelmingly show that 98% of the Earth experienced its highest level of warming during the twentieth century. During this period, a plethora of studies have demonstrated significant impacts on biota. The focus of my thesis is to study the stability of ecological communities to changes in climate, both observed and predicted. Climate change is often used synonymously with destabilization in the context of ecological systems. One of my objectives is to study whether specific types of ecological organization amplify or dampen potential destabilization due to specific types of climate change. I consider two types of highly non-equilibrium communities: a tropical planted forest and a seasonal Arctic tundra food web. Biodiversity may provide mechanisms through which to buffer community functioning to changing environmental conditions. In my first chapter, I use data from a ca. 15 year-old tropical planted forest experiment to study the stability of tree communities across a gradient of species richness to extreme climate events during this period. Using a bootstrapping procedure, I develop a statistical method for the detection of stress response in community growth and mortality as a measure of stability. In one-species communities, in contrast to higher richnesses, growth is strongly regulated by climate extremes and mortality is higher during a long period of drought. Using indicators of loss of resilience or critical slowing down, I show that for the drought extremes experienced at the experiment there may be an effect of diversity on loss of resilience, with one-species communities being more prone to massive die-off. In my second and third chapters, I consider a simplified Arctic tundra food web in a strongly seasonal community on Bylot Island (lemming-fox-goose-owl) where biodiversity varies temporally due to migrating species. To ultimately study stability to changing climatic conditions in the Arctic, a model which captures the seasonality of the community is necessary. Without integrating seasonality in food web modelling, especially for communities at high altitudes or latitudes, predications about the impacts of climate change may be uncertain. I construct a multi-season model of predator-prey biomass dynamics based on a hybrid dynamical systems (HDS) framework which allows inclusion of both fast (i.e. migration) and slow (i.e. predator-prey) dynamics. Each season is associated with a different stable equilibrium to capture a food web whose topology changes with season. We estimate winter interaction coefficients for the HDS based on summer data from 1993 to 2018 to generate long-term time-series which match observed patterns in species biomass fluctuations. I show that multi-season models, compared to models which do not incorporate seasonality, can expose indirect interactions between migrants and residents. Furthermore, I find that seasonality prevents specialist migratory predators from overexploiting available prey potentially suggesting that temporally changing food web topology may stabilize community dynamics. In my third chapter, I develop theoretical tools based on the HDS stability theory in order to study stability using the model I develop in my second chapter for a seasonal community with migrations. These tools accomplish two goals: 1) to separate the contribution of biomass coming from migrants and from residents and 2) define a measure of resilience which applies to systems with more than one equilibrium depending on the length of time spent in that season. I then use historical and projection data from Representative Concentration Pathway (RCP) climate scenarios to estimate summer season length for low, moderate, and high emissions scenarios. Two mechanisms contribute to the stability in seasonal systems. The first is the length of time spent in summer..</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dominique Gravel</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Peter Edwin Caines</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Frederic Guichard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cn079.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tt65s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cg19n"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nonlinear dynamics of inverted flags: A theoretical and experimental investigation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tavallaeinejad, Mohammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Il a été observé que les drapeaux inversés --- des plaques minces élastiques encastrées-libres soumises à un fluide s’écoulant axialement et dirigé de l’extrémité libre vers l’extrémité encastrée ---  présentent expérimentalement et en simulations numériques un battement à grande amplitude au-delà d’une vitesse critique. La poursuite des recherches sur la dynamique de ce système est motivée, d’une part, par sa présence dans certains systèmes mécaniques et biologiques et, d’autre part, par la très riche dynamique qu'il engendre.Dans la présente thèse, notre objectif est de développer des modèles analytiques non linéaires pour le comportement dynamique et la stabilité des drapeaux inversés.Plus précisément, deux modèles aérodynamiques théoriques sont proposés, en fonction du rapport de forme du drapeau (c'est-à-dire du rapport de sa hauteur par sa longueur).Pour un rapport de forme asymptotiquement faible, où la longueur du drapeau est supposée infinie, les forces du fluide sont calculées à l'aide de la théorie des corps élancés; Une extension de cette dernière aux rotations de grande amplitude du plan médian de la plaque ainsi que la théorie non linéaire des lignes portantes de Bollay sont utilisées pour dériver les forces liées aux fluides appliquées sur la plaque.Pour les rapports de forme élevés, où la hauteur du drapeau est supposée être beaucoup plus grande que sa longueur, l’application des théories d'écoulement bidimensionnel est pertinente; dans le cas présent, le flot de fluide non visqueux est modélisé par une formulation quasi-stationnaire de la théorie aérodynamique instationnaire de Theodorsen, utilisant également l'analogie de succion du bord d'attaque de Polhamus pour modéliser les effets de séparation de flot du bord d'attaque à des angles modérés.Sur le plan structurel, le drapeau est modélisé selon une théorie de poutre d'Euler-Bernoulli géométriquement exacte, en supposant que le drapeau est inextensible.Un cadre hamiltonien est utilisé pour dériver les modèles non linéaires de milieu continu fluide-élastique en termes d'angle de rotation de la section transversale du drapeau.La discrétisation dans l'espace est réalisée selon la technique de Galerkine.La formule de différenciation arrière de Gear et une technique de continuation par pseudo-longueur d’arc sont utilisées pour résoudre les équations discrètes obtenues.D'après les résultats numériques, il a été constaté que l'équilibre statique non dévié des drapeaux de faible rapport de forme est stable avant la bifurcation de fourche sous-critique.Pour les drapeaux ayant un rapport de forme élevé, cependant, l'équilibre statique stable non dévié est soumis à une bifurcation de fourche supercritique qui est associée à une divergence statique (flambement) du drapeau.À des vitesses d'écoulement plus élevées, au-delà de la bifurcation de fourche, une bifurcation de Hopf supercritique se matérialise, générant un mouvement de battement autour de l'équilibre statique dévié. À des vitesses d'écoulement encore plus élevées, le mouvement de battement devient symétrique autour de l'équilibre statique non dévié. De manière intéressante, il a également été constaté que les drapeaux lourds peuvent présenter des battements de grande amplitude juste après l’équilibre statique initial, à condition qu’ils soient soumis à une perturbation suffisante.Les résultats numériques suggèrent qu'une instabilité fluide-élastique pourrait être le mécanisme sous-jacent du mouvement de battement des drapeaux inversés à rapport de forme élevé. En d'autres termes, le battement peut être considéré comme une vibration auto-excitée.Enfin, des expériences avec des plaques flexibles en porte-à-faux en écoulement axial inverse ont été menées dans une soufflerie subsonique à fin d'étudier l'effet de différents paramètres du système sur la stabilité et le comportement dynamique global des drapeaux inversés</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Inverted flags -- clamped-free elastic thin plates subjected to a fluid flowing axially and directed from the free end towards the clamped end -- have been observed experimentally and computationally to exhibit large-amplitude flapping beyond a critical flow velocity. The motivation for further research on the dynamics of this system is partly due to its presence in some engineering and biological systems, and partly because of the very rich dynamics it displays.In the present thesis, our goal is to develop nonlinear analytical models for the dynamics and stability of inverted flags. More specifically, two theoretical aerodynamic models are proposed, according to the flag aspect ratio (i.e. height-to-length ratio).For asymptotically small aspect ratio, where the length of the flag is assumed to be infinite, the fluid forces are calculated using slender body theory; an extension of elongated-body theory to large-amplitude rotations of the plate mid-plane along with Bollay's nonlinear wing theory are employed to formulate the fluid-related forces acting on the plate.For high aspect ratios, where the height of the flag is assumed to be much larger than its length, two-dimensional flow theories are relevant; in this case, the inviscid fluid flow is modelled via the quasi-steady version of Theodorsen's unsteady aerodynamic theory, also utilizing the Polhamus leading edge suction analogy to model flow separation effects from the leading edge at moderate angles of attack.On the structural front, the flag is modelled via a geometrically-exact Euler-Bernoulli beam theory, assuming the flag to be inextensible. A Hamiltonian framework is employed to derive the nonlinear fluid-elastic continuum models in terms of the rotation angle of the flag cross-section. Discretization in space is carried out via the Galerkin technique. Gear's backward differentiation formula and a pseudo-arclength continuation technique are employed to solve the resultant discretized equations.It was found from numerical results that, for flags of small aspect ratio, the undeflected static equilibrium is stable prior to a subcritical pitchfork bifurcation. For flags of high aspect ratio, however, the undeflected stable static equilibrium is subjected to a supercritical pitchfork bifurcation, which is associated with static divergence (buckling) of the flag. At higher flow velocities, past the pitchfork bifurcation, a supercritical Hopf bifurcation materialises, generating a flapping motion around the deflected static equilibrium. At even higher flow velocities, flapping motion becomes symmetric, around the undeflected static equilibrium. Interestingly, it was also found that heavy flags may exhibit large-amplitude flapping right after the initial static equilibrium, provided that they are subjected to a sufficiently large disturbance.Numerical results suggest that a fluidelastic instability may be the underlying mechanism for the flapping motion of high aspect ratio inverted flags. In other words, flapping may be viewed as a self-excited vibration. Finally, experiments with cantilevered flexible plates in reverse axial flow were conducted in a subsonic wind tunnel to shed light on the effect of different system parameters on the stability and global dynamics of inverted flags.The experimental observations are compared withthe simulation results obtained via the proposed models. Reasonably good agreement with theoretical predictions was obtained</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mathias Legrand</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Michael P. Paidoussis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827h35v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cg19n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab5644x11n"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Powder spreading and tribocharging for additive manufacturing powder bed fusion processes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alchikh-sulaiman, Basel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite the wide applications of powder metallurgy in the additive manufacturing (AM) technologies, the effect of powder characteristics (particle size distribution PSD, surface morphology, etc.) on the spreadability and packing factor in electron beam powder bed fusion (EB-PBF) is not well investigated. Powder spreadability and flowability are controlled by adhesive forces, friction forces (particle-particle interactions due to surface condition and topography) and coulombic forces (van der Waals forces, electrostatic and tribocharging). Currently, there are no standard procedures to measure spreadability. In this thesis, a technique has been proposed to study spreadability in which a single layer of powder is spread by a standard method, ‘frozen’ in the as spread condition by ‘contact-sintering’ and then characterized using white-light interferometry (coherence scanning interferometry). In addition, this thesis concentrates on the effect of powder properties (composition and particle size distribution) on tribocharging, since this is a significant effect in spreadability has not been well documented. A powder rheometer is used to detect tribocharging effects for different AM metallic powders. This work presents a technique to study tribocharging generated inside the powder rheometer. A tribocharging evolution is identified, comprising three ‘periods’: (i) incubation, (ii) transition, and finally (iii) the electrostatic equilibrium. These characteristics are explained on the basis of powder/vessel interactions and powder/powder interactions. The results are also used to add commercial purity titanium, Ti-6Al-4V and Inconel 718 to the triboelectric series. It is also shown that there is a strong effect of the rheometer vessel material on tribocharging characteristics. Finally, the possible effect of tribocharging on spreading is discussed</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Malgré les nombreuses applications de la métallurgie des poudres dans les technologies de fabrication additive (FA), l’effet des caractéristiques des poudres (distribution granulométrique PSD, morphologie de surface, etc.) sur l'étalement et le facteur de remplissage dans la fusion par lit de poudre à faisceau d'électrons (EB-PBF) n'est pas bien étudié. L’étalement et la coulabilité de la poudre sont contrôlées par des forces adhésives, des forces de frottement (interactions particules-particules dues à l’état de surface et à la topographie) et des forces coulombiques (forces de van der Waals, électrostatiques et triboélectriques). À l’heure actuelle, il n’existe pas de procédures standard pour mesurer l'étalement. Dans cette thèse, une technique a été proposée pour étudier l'étalement dans laquelle une seule couche de poudre est étalée par une méthode standard, 'congelée' dans l’état de propagation par ‘frittage par contact ‘puis caractérisée à l’aide d’interférométrie à la lumière blanche (interférométrie de numérisation de cohérence).En outre, cette thèse se concentre sur l’effet des propriétés des poudre (composition et distribution granulométrique) sur le triboélectriques, puisqu’il s’agit d’un effet significatif sur l'étalement n’a pas été bien documenté.  Un rhéomètre à poudre est utilisé pour détecter les effets triboélectriques sur différentes poudres métalliques FA. Cette recherche présente une technique permettant d’étudier le chargement triboélectrique généré à l’intérieur du rhéomètre à poudre. Une évolution tribochargée est identifiée, comprenant trois « périodes »: (i) incubation, (ii) transition, et enfin (iii) l’équilibre électrostatique. Ces caractéristiques sont expliquées sur la base des interactions poudre/navire et des interactions poudre/poudre. Les résultats sont également utilisés pour ajouter du titane de pureté commerciale, du Ti-6Al-4V et de l’Inconel 718 dans la série triboélectrique. Il est également démontré qu’il y a un fort effet du matériau du navire de rhéomètre sur les caractéristiques de triboélectriques. Enfin, l’effet possible de la triboélectriques sur l'étalement est discuté</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stephen Yue</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dr58f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644x11n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mining and Materials</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010v38k"><ual:graduationDate>2020</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exploring the perception of violin qualities: student- vs. performance-level instruments, strings and soundpost height</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fu, Lei</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le violon a atteint sa forme actuelle après plusieurs siècles de développements empiriques et certains des instruments les plus renommés actuellement ont été fabriqués il y a plus de 300 ans. Il est ainsi assez remarquable que notre compréhension de la qualité d’un violon et de ce qui y contribue reste limitée. Cette thèse décrit trois expériences perceptives qui ont été mises en place pour mieux comprendre les relations entre les qualités perçues d’un violon et sa structure physique.           Des travaux antérieurs [Saitis et al., 2012; Fritz et al., 2012b, 2014] ont montré que les musiciens n’étaient généralement pas d’accord entre eux en termes de préférence lors de l’évaluation de violons au-dessus d’un certain prix (1300 $ CAD). La première étude perceptive s’est intéressée à examiner si l’accord entre les musiciens lors d’essais comparatifs était plus grand pour des violons d’entrée de gamme que pour des violons « de concert », si des différences perceptives significatives pouvaient être mises en évidence entre les deux catégories de violons et s’il existait des caractéristiques vibro-acoustiques qui pourraient expliquer ces différences. Les résultats montrent que les violons de concert ont été évalués, de manière significative, plus positivement que les violons d’étude, aussi bien en termes de préférence que sur les critères clarté, richesse et équilibre.            Les deux autres études ont exploré les sources de désaccord entre musiciens à travers deux modifications spécifiques du violon. Comment les cordes influencent la perception des qualités d’un violon fut l’objet de la deuxième étude. Deux violons, de qualité sonore et de jouabilité très similaires ont été utilisés. Ils étaient initialement montés avec des cordes Dominant. Les participants devaient jouer les deux violons puis décrire et évaluer les différences au cours d’une session intitulée D1-D2. Ensuite, à l’insu des participants, les cordes du violon 2 étaient changées pour un autre modèle (Kaplan ou Pro-Arté) et les musiciens devaient réévaluer les différences entre les deux violons (session D1-K2 ou D1-P2). Les résultats n’ont pas montré de différences significatives entre les diverses conditions expérimentales, à l’exception des évaluations de différence de brillance qui sont significativement plus élevées dans la session D1-D2 que dans la session D1-P2.           La troisième étude consistait en des tests de jeu mais aussi d’écoute (pour explorer comment des modifications de la hauteur de l’âme (pour une position donnée de l’âme) influencent les qualités perceptives d’un violon et quel est le seuil de modification en-dessous duquel luthiers et violonistes ne perçoivent pas de différences. A cet effet, une âme en fibre de carbone de longueur ajustable a été utilisée. Durant le test de jeu, les participants commençaient par évaluer les qualités d’un violon donné, dont la longueur de l’âme était modifiée par un expérimentateur, afin de déterminer la longueur optimale pour chacun d’entre eux. Dans un deuxième temps, l’expérimentateur modifiait, ou non, la longueur de l’âme, dans une plage de ± 0,1 mm autour de la longueur optimale, et les participants devaient dire, si le réglage avait été modifié ou pas. Les résultats montrent que la longueur optimale pour chaque sujet varie entre 0.132 mm et 0.616 mm de plus que la longueur de départ de l’âme (53 mm), un intervalle bien compris entre les valeurs extrêmes qui ont été testées (de 0 à 0.66 mm). La plus petite variation de longueur pouvant être détectée au-dessus du seuil de chance est de 0,044 mm pour les musiciens et 0,088 mm pour les luthiers. Durant le test d’écoute, les sujets devaient écouter 16 paires d’enregistrements via une interface sur ordinateur et spécifier, pour chaque paire, si le réglage du violon était le même ou non pour les deux enregistrements. Les résultats montrent que la différence de longueur pouvant être détectée au-dessus du seuil de chance est d’environ 0,066 mm</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The violin has reached its current, highly refined form over centuries through empirical methods, with some of the most valuable instruments being made more than 300 years ago. It is thus perhaps remarkable that very little is understood about violin quality and what particular aspects of the instrument are most important in the perception of violin qualities. This thesis reports three perceptual experiments that were designed to help better understand the relationship between a violin’s perceived qualities and its physical structure.            Previous studies [Saitis et al., 2012; Fritz et al., 2012b, 2014] have shown a general lack of agreement among players in terms of violin preference when evaluating instruments intended for intermediate to advanced players ($1300 CAD and higher). The first experiment of this thesis explored whether there would be greater perceptual agreement when comparing violins meant for entry-level vs. advanced players, whether there would be significant perceptual differences between these two categories of violins and whether some structural vibration characteristics could be found to explain these differences. The results showed that performance violins were on average rated significantly higher than student violins in terms of preference and the three attribute criteria clarity, richness and balance.            The second and third studies of this thesis investigated the origin of the disagreement among players through two specific modifications to the violin. The second study investigated how different strings affect the perception of violin qualities. Two violins of the same make with similar sound quality and playability were employed. They were both strung with Dominant strings initially. Subjects played the violins, described and rated the difference (on eight criteria -responsiveness, power, resonance, brightness, clarity, richness, balance and overall quality) between the two violins during a session labeled D1-D2. Subsequently, the strings of violin 2 were changed to a different brand (Kaplan or Pro-Arté), unbeknownst to the players, and players had to re-evaluate the differences between the two violins (session D1-K2 or D1-P2). Results showed no significant differences between the experimental conditions except that the brightness difference ratings obtained in D1-D2 were found to be significantly higher than those in D1-P2.            The third study involved both playing and listening (using recorded sounds) experiments to investigate how changes in soundpost height (for a fixed soundpost position) affect the perceptual qualities of the violin and what is the threshold of change below which players and luthiers do not perceive differences. A height-adjustable carbon fibre soundpost was employed. During the playing experiment, subjects played, in a first phase, a provided violin on which the soundpost height was modified by the experimenter in order to find their optimal soundpost height. Then, in a second phase, the experimenter varied the soundpost height randomly in ten trials (including cases where no change was made) within a range of approximately ± 0.1 mm around their optimal height. The results showed that the subjects’ optimal soundpost heights varied from 0.132 mm to 0.616 mm relative to the original soundpost height (53 mm), reasonably well inside the extreme soundpost heights that were tested (0 mm and 0.66 mm, relative to the original height). The smallest height variation that could be recognized above chance level was about 0.044 mm for players and 0.088 mm for makers. During the listening experiment, subjects listened to 16 pairs of recordings through a computer interface and were asked, for each pair, whether the violin set-up was the same or different. The results showed that subjects in the listening experiment could differentiate soundpost heights with a difference of about 0.066 mm at better than chance levels</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Claudia Fritz</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Gary Scavone</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752n22f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010v38k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>