<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vf54p"><ual:graduationDate>1976</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Isolation, structure, and activity of ragweed pollen antigens Ra3, Ra4, and Ra5</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roebber, Marianne G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A column chromatographic method was developed for sequential isolation of antigens Ra3, Ra4, and Ra5 from short ragweed pollen. Two major forms of antigen Ra3 (1 and II) were separated and round to have the same mol wt (12,000 daltons) and amino acid composition. Their variable carbohydrate content (7%-20%) could be reduced to 3% by preparative acrylamide gel electrophoresis. Antigen Ra3 was shown to be allergenically independent of antigen E by direct skin test or by histamine release from leucocytes of ragweed sensitive patients. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Une méthode de chromatographie sur colonne a été développée pour isoler successivement les antigènes Ra3, Ra4 et Ra5 à partir du pollen de Jacobée. Les deux formes principales de l'antigène Ra3 (I et II) ont été separées; la même composition en acides aminés ainsi que le même été poids moléculaire ont été démontrés pour ces deux formes. Leur contenu variable en hydrate de carbone (7-20%) a pu être réduit à 3% par électrophorèse sur gel acrilamide préparatif. L'antigène Ra3 a une activité allergénique indépedante de celle de l'antigen E. Les épreuves par application directe sur la peau de patients sensibles au Jacobée et par libération d'histamine de leurs leucocytes supportent cette conclusion. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Goodfriend, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gr37k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vf54p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gk495"><ual:graduationDate>1941</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L’aviation dans la litterature contemporaine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dwyer, Florence Mary</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bien que l'idée essentielle de voler existe dans le cerveau humain depuis vingt-cinq siècles au moins , l'aviation est en réalité une nouvelle profession. Il appartenait à notre époque de voir la réalisation de rêves parsemés à travers les âges et c'est le XXe siècle qui témoignera de l'admirable progrès et du développement de l'aviation, une des plus grandes choses que l'humanité ait connues. Pour se rendre compte de l'importance de l'aviation, on n'a qu'à lire les journaux ou à ecouter la T.S.F. Le nombre d'hommes et de femmes qui s'engagent dans l'aviation s'accroit constamment. Et le jour arrive, à cause de la guerre actuelle, où la force militaire d'un pays sera mesurée à la puissance de son aviation. L'aspirant-aviateur - qu'il ambitionne de devenir pilote de transport, pilote de chasse, pilote d'essais, pilote de raid ou simplement pilot privé ou sportif - doit se pénétrer de l'idée d'affronter la mort, et une mort le plus souvent instantanée. Il lui faut aussi compter avec les accidents, en depit des progrès de l'aviation, et, avant de s'engager dans l'aviation, se rappeler le grand effort, physique et moral, que ce métier lui imposera. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Furness, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k824b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk495</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>LITERATURE -- HISTORY AND CRITICISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>LITERATURE, COMPARATIVE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AERIAL NAVIGATION</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021j196"><ual:graduationDate>1941</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Heat of reaction of gaseous sulphur dioxide on moist wood</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Duncan, Robert Daman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During recent years in these laboratories attention has been given to the possibilities of pulping wood with sulphur dioxide gas, under conditions which differ widely from any of the conventional methods of sulphite cooking. While undertaken originally as a method which afforded studies of the effects of the reaction products on sulphite cooking, the outlook developed to be one of the commercial feasibility of such a process. The essential features are that wood (moisture, 66%) is charged to a digester which is then evacuated and subsequently brought up to reaction temperature. Gaseous sulphur dioxide is then admitted to the digester under considerable pressure and the cooking continued in this manner for several hours. If development was to progress along these lines, the heat requirement of such a process becomes of extreme importance. Excessive temperature changes as the result of the heat of the reaction would present engineering difficulties in heat transfer through a mass of nearly dry chips if the process was attempted on a commercial scale. As a result this investigation was commenced with the immediate object of establishing the sign and, to some degree at least, the magnitude of the heat effects produced during the process of delignification of moist spruce wood in a highly concentrated medium of su1phur dioxide gas. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maass, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462841g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021j196</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514np527"><ual:graduationDate>1976</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Metabolism of rat serum lipoproteins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Noel, Simon-Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La technique de perfusion de foie de rat avec un milieu artificiel a été utilisée pour étudier l'incorporation d'un acide aminé dans la portion protéique des lipoprotéines. La sécrétion des VLDL est de 6 à 10 fois plus grande que celle des HDL. Les LDL ne sont pas sécrétés comme tels. La distribution de la radioactivité dans chaque peptide des VLDL et des HDL est différente. Les VLDL contiennent 3 principaux constituants correspondant chez l'homme a apoB, "Arginine-rich peptide" et apoC. Par contre, les HDL ne contiennent que 2 constituants principaux correspondant à "Arginine-rich peptide" et apoA. Un modèle in vitro a été mis au point pour l'étude du catabolisme des chylomicrons et des VLDL. Dans un première étape, des coeurs de rat isolés ont été perfusés avec des chylomicrons pour simuler l'hydrolyse initiale des triglycérides des chylomicrons par la lipoprotéine lipase. Les restes de chylomicrons ainsi produits (Sf &gt; 400) contiennent un plus faible pourcentage de triglycérides mais un pourcentage supérieur de monoglycérides et de diglycérides. Pendant la perfusion de coeur, il y a perte des polypeptides du groupe C et possiblement du groupe A. Dans une deuxième étape, des foies de rat isolés ont été perfusés avec ces restes de chylomicrons pour simuler la capture rapide des restes de chylomicrons qui se produit in vivo. Plus de-85% des triglycérides des restes ,de chylomicrons disparaît de la fraction Sf &gt; 400 pendant la perfusion de foie comparé a seulement 25% dans le cas des triglycérides des chylomicrons non-traités. la majeure partie des protéines marquées a l'Iode-125 qui disparaît est recouvrée dans le foie.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Liver perfusions were used to study the secretion of the protein moiety of 1ipoproteins. Rat livers were perfused with an artificial erythrocyte-albumin-Krebs-Ringer medium containing a labelled amino acid precursor. It was shown that the release of VLDL protein was 6-10 times greater than that of HDL. LDL protein was not secreted to any significant extent. The pattern of the radioactivity incorporated into each of the peptides of VLDL and HDL was found to be different. Newly secreted VLDL contained 3 main components corresponding to human apoB, Arginine-rich peptide and apoC. In contrast; HDL contained only 2 main components corresponding to human Arginine-rich peptide and apoA. A two step in vitro model was set up to study the catabolism of chylomicrons. In the first step, thoracic duct chylomicrons were perfused through an isolated beating rat heart to mimic the initial hydrolysis of chylomicron triglycerides by lipoprotein lipase. The resulting chylomicron remnants (Sf &gt; 400) were shown to contain a decreased percentage of triglycerides but an increase of monoglycerides and diglycerides. The polypeptides of the C group and perhaps of the A group were found to be lost during the heart perfusion. In the second step, these remnants were perfused through an isolated rat liver to mimic the hepatic uptake of chylomicron remnants that occurs in vivo. It was found that &gt; 85% of remnant triglycerides disappeared from the Sf &gt; 400 fraction during the liver perfusion compared to only 25% in the case of untreated chylomicrons. Most of the 125I-labelled remnant protein which disappeared from the Sf &gt; 400 fraction was recovered in the liver.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rubinstein, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q0149.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np527</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xh88h"><ual:graduationDate>1941</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Zoology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies in the Arctic plankton, comprising a faunistic survey of certain of the marine planktonic groups collected in the Canadian eastern arctic, and an investigation of the breeding cycles of five of the most important species in the eastern arctic and in west Greenland</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dunbar, M. J. (Maxwell John).</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>[...] There is a great deal more to be done in the Canadian arctic. Large portions of the area between Alaska and Greenland are still blank on the biological map. Scientific activity in this region, with the exception of the Canadian Arctic expedition and the Fifth Thule expedition, has been very restricted and in part somewhat casual. The zoological collections of the Canadian Arctic expedition added much to the knowledge of the north, but they were not very rich in marine material. [...] For these reasons I was very glad of the opportunity, in 1939, to go as marine biologist on the Canadian Eastern Arctic Patrol, in the Hudson's Bay Company ship "Nascopie". [...]. The work is a study in the Plankton of the coastal water, the fjords and inlets, not the open water. The large oceanographic expeditions have gained much knowledge of the open water and the depths beyond the continental shelves. They carry apparatus designed for such work, and the intimate investigation of the coastal water is left to others. The need for the detailed study of the coastal waters is pointed out by Steuer (1933). Russell (1936) emphasized this amongst other suggestions for the planning of future plankton expeditions. He adds that "especial attention should be paid to a study of the life histories of some of the larger arctic-boreal/ species such as Sagitta elegans and Clione limacina". [...] </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wynne-Edwards, V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tc38j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh88h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Marine plankton -- Arctic regions</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440w81s"><ual:graduationDate>1976</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis of amylase by rat exocrine pancreas</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Matos-Medina, Ana N.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A radio-immunochemical method was developed to accurately measure the content, rate of synthesis and degradation of rat pancreatic amylase. The method was used to study the effect of starvation on rat pancreatic amylase metabolism. Starvation did not significantly change the content and rate of synthesis of total pancreatic protein, but caused a significant decrease in the content of amylase and in the rate of incorporation of 3H-L-leucine into amylase. Evidence was obtained which indicated that these changes were due to a decrease in the rate of synthesis of amylase. To test the possibility that a translational control of amylase synthesis was involved, a cell-free protein synthesizing system was developed. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Une méthode radio-immunochimique a été développée pour mesurer de façon précise le contenu et le taux de synthèse et de dégradation de l'amylase pancréatique chez le rat. Cette méthode a ensuite servi à une étude de l'effet du jeûne sur le métabolisme de l'amylase pancréatique. Le jeûne n'affecte pas le contenu ou le taux de synthèse des protéines considérées globalement, mais il diminue de façon significative le contenu d'amylase et le taux d'incorporation de la L-leucine, marquée au tritium (3H), dans l'amylase. Pour étudier s'il s'agissait d'un contrôle translationel de la synthèse d'amylase, un système isolé de synthèse de protéines a été développé. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tenenhouse, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150n02s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440w81s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89d965t"><ual:graduationDate>1976</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the replication of bacteriophage phiX174</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McFadden, Grant</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The replication of bacteriophage phiX174 was analyzed in various Escherichia coli mutants carrying one or more of the following mutations: polA, polB, polC (also called dnaE), dnaG and lig ts7. Synthesis of the parental replicative form (RF) in vivo was found to occur discontinuously and require the host polynucleotide ligase and the dnaG gene product; DNA polymerase I also contributes to this reaction. Semiconservative replication of the RF requires the polC gene product (i.e. DNA polymerase III) and the dnaG gene product; polynucleotide ligase is necessary to repair discontinuities found exclusively in the complementary strand. Progeny viral strand DNA synthesis requires DNA polymerase III and the dnaG protein; ligase may be required to circularize full-1ength linear strands. In vitro, parental RF synthesis was found to occur in E. coli rendered permeable to low molecular weight compounds by treatment with toluene; this synthesis had a requirement for high concentrations of ATP.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La réplication du bactériophage phiX174 a été analysée dans divers mutants de Escherichia coli possédant une ou plusieurs des mutations suivantes: polA, polB, polC (appelée aussi dnaE), dnaG et lig ts7. Il été trouvé que la synthèse in vitro de la forme réplicative (RF) parentale est discontinue et demande la participation de la polynucléotide ligase et du produit du gène dnaG de la cellule hôte; l'ADN-polymerase I contribue aussi à cette réaction. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denhardt, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848t633.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d965t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83m250t"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Supraspinal and spinal control mechanisms in respiration</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Iscoe, Steve</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In anaesthetized, paralyzed, ventilated and vagotomized cats, stimulation of somatic afferent nerves at fixed times in the respiratory cycle could delay or advance the onset of the next respiratory phase. Repetitive stimulation produced sustained increases in respiratory frequency, entrainment of the frequency of the respiratory oscillator to that of stimulation occurring in half of the cats. These observations demonstrate the existence of a reflex pathway which may account for the locking of respiratory frequency to the period of rhythmic muscular activity. In anaesthetized, non-vasotomized spontaneously breathing T1 spinal cats, the mouth pressure at which phrenic motoneurones were recruited was measured during airway occlusion. The threshold pressure of recruitment of a motoneurone was constant at a given end tidal CO2. No unit was recruited at a pressure greater than 70% of maximum. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Chez le chat anesthésié, vagotomisé, curarisé et ventilé par respirateur, la stimulation de nerfs somatiques afferents peut retarder ou avancer le debut de la prochaine phase respiratoire. Un stimulus répétitif augmente la fréquence respiratoire; chez la moitié des chats étudiés, il y'eut synchronisation entre la fréquence respiratoire et celle du stimulus. Ces observations démontrent l'existence d'une voie réflexe responsable de la synchronisation entre la fréquence respiratoire et celle de l'activité motrice. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Polosa, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92gb323.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m250t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117s01m"><ual:graduationDate>1976</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The structure of the limiting membrane of seminiferous tubules in the rat and monkey</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hermo, Louis S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The limiting membrane of rat and monkey seminiferous tubules was investigated by light and electron microscopy. The myoid layer of the rat limiting membrane in addition to myoid cells, contained cells with a pale staining cytoplasm referred to as light cells. These cells were also observed in the interstitial space and on occasion between the adventitial layer and outer lamella of the limiting membrane. Hence it appeared that some of these cells miqht enter the limiting membrane from the interstitial space. The morphological features of the light cells were such that they could not be classified as monocytes, macrophages or lymphocytes. They did, however, bear resemblance to the granular leucocytes of the epididymis and hence appeared to belong to the same class of cells. The exact identity of these elements remains to be clarified. In whole mounts of rat tubules, light cells were readily identified by their polymorphous, "C"-shaped nucleus. Quantitative studies on these cells revealed that they were a numerous and regular component of the limiting membrane, but that they varies in number during the cycle of the seminiferous epithelium. It also showed that they were capable of dividing and degenerating and that they were sensitive ta X-rays. In the limiting membrane of monkeys, light cells were also present in addition to myoid cells. The distribution of collagen, elastin and microfibrils was also investigated and described.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La membrane limitante des tubes séminifères du rat et du singe a été étudiée en microscopie optique et électronique. Chex le rat, au niveau de la couche des cellules myoides, on trouvé des cellules avec un cytoplasme pâle et qui présente certaines caractéristiques des leucocytes. Ces cellules sont présentes dans le tissu conjonctif intertubulaire ou dans l'adventice de la, membrane limitante ce qui suggère un passage de certaines de ces cellules de l'espace intertubulaire dans la membrane limitante. Ces cellules claires ne sont pas les précurseurs dès cellules myoides et ne peuvent être identifiées comme étant des macrophages, des monocytes ou des lymphocytes typiques. Elles ressemblent cependant aux leucocytes agranulaires présents dans l'épithélium épididymaire dont la nature exacte reste à être déterminée. En microscopie optique les cellules claires sont facilement identifiables dans des tubes séminifères disséqués et montés in toto. Une étude quantitative de ces cellules claires nous montre qu'elles sont fréquentes et que leur nombre varie, au cours du cycle de l'épithélium séminifère. De plus ces cellules Se divisent et dégénèrent et par conséquent doivent se renouveler. Elles sont également sensibles aux rayons-X. Chez le singe des cellules claires sont également présentes parmi les cellules myoides de la membrane limitante. Dans cette membrane, la distribution du collagen, de l'élastine et de microfibrilles conjonctives a également été analysée.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clermont, Y.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zx42k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117s01m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5712m9905"><ual:graduationDate>1976</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"Darkness deepening darkness": studies in romantic tragedy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gottlieb, Erika</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis contends that the five tragedies of the major Romantic poets are failures as tragedy because they were generated from an allegorical impulse rather than from a dramatic one. Plot and character are used merely to externalize the poet-playwright's inner conflict concerning belief in Nature's divinity and man's perfectibility. On a stage set for Gothic melodrama, in effect, each play turns into a spiritual drama. Union between hero and heroine with the father's blessing affirms Man's perfectibi1ity in a paradisiac cosmos; it symbolizes harmony between Adam, Eve, and their Father, or between Man, Nature and the Spirit. The villain's victory, however, shatters the hope for affirmation; it stands for the victory of Satan, or demonic Alienation. While the plays resolve the conflict in the negative, none represents a consistently tragic vision. This is due to the playwright's commitment to metaphysical optimism and epistemological idealism. All the plays end in despair without catharsis, in "darkness deepening darkness."</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cole, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qg30x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m9905</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English Literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abv73c359d"><ual:graduationDate>1976</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The neurophysiological mechanism of the generation of pathological slow waves in the electroencephalogram</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ball, Graham J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It was found that localized delta waves could be produced in cerebral cortex overlying a circumscribed white matter lesion. Generalized delta activity could be produced by a lesion in the mesencephalic reticular formation. Cortical gray matter lesions and subcortical white matter edema produced no delta waves. Thus, some cortical differentiation, possibly interruption of cholinergic fibers, seems to be required to produce delta waves. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Il fut démontré que des ondes delta localisées peuvent être produites dans le cortex cérébral recouvrant une lésion circoncrite de la substance blanche. Des ondes delta généralisées peuvent être produites par une lesion dans la formation réticulée mésencéphalique. Des lésions de la substance grise corticale ainsi que l'oedéme de la substance blanche sous-corticale ne produient par d'ondes delta. Donc une certaine déafferentation corticale, peut-être une interruption des fibres cholinergique, semble être requise pour la production d'ondes delta. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gloor, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w2817.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c359d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117s02w"><ual:graduationDate>1976</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hepatic microsomal lipid peroxidation and its effects on drug metabolism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Renton, Kenneth W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During development of rats, hepatic microsomal NADPH dependent lipid peroxidation increased to reach a maximum activity at 25 days of age and then declined to adult activity by six weeks of age. Increased activity in 25 day old tats resulted in a greater decrease in the ability of microsomes to N-demethylate aminopyrine after preincubation under conditions which promoted lipid peroxidation. Although total NADPH oxidase activity was similar in 25 day old and adult rats, NADPH oxidase activity, which was specific for lipid peroxidation, was increased in 25 day old rats. Microsomal NADPH dependent lipid peroxidation reduced the magnitude of type I and type II spectral binding without affecting the qualitative aspects of the spectra or the absolute amount of cytochrome P-450. It is proposed that decreased drug oxidation following lipid peroxidation in microsomes is due to decreased binding of substrate to cytochrome P-450. NADPH dependent lipid peroxidation was demonstrated for the first time in human hepatic microsomes. Compared to the rat, human microsomes were resistant to decreases in drug oxidation which result from lipid peroxidation. Evidence is presented which supports the concept that NADPH dependent lipid, peroxidation can occur in vivo. The iron involved in NADPH dependent lipid peroxidation reaction, participates in a bound form even when added from an exogenous source, The problem of iron contamination in studies of microsomal lipid peroxidation is discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dan le cours du développement des rats, l'activité maximale de peroxidation des lipides (dépendante du NADPH) par les microsomes hépatiques est atteinte à l'âge de 25 jours, et elle décline ensuite au niveau adulte d'activité à six semaines d'âge: l'activité accrue chez les rats âgés de 25 jours résulte eu une plus grande diminution de l'habileté des microsomes à N-déméthyler l'aminopyrine, après une préincubation dans des conditions favorisant la peroxidation des lipides. Bien que l'activité totale de la NADPH oxidase soit similaire dans les rats de 25 jours et les rats adultes, l'activité de la NADPH oxidase spécifique pour la peroxidation des lipides est accrûe dans les rats de 25 jours. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eade, N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494c37d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117s02w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j412c"><ual:graduationDate>1976</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Changes with age in bone marrow small lymphocytes and other cell populations in normal and neonatally thymectomized mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Miller, Sandra C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lymphocytes and other cell populations in the bone marrow of growing (0 - 16 wk) C3H mice were quantitated by marrow volume measurements and differential cell counts. Small lymphocyte numbers were highest at 2 - 4 wk (600 x , 10^3/mm^3), falling by half from 4 wk to 12 wk. Granulocytic cells were most numerous at 8 - 16 wk. Erythroid cells declined from 2 wk to 12 - 16 wk with a transitory rise at 8 wk. Computer analysis of the rate of disappearance of unlabelled cells following continuous infusion of 3H-thymidine defined two kinetic patterns of marrow small lymphocytes with age: (1) cells with rapid exponential renewal whose incidence and turnover rate were highest at 4 wk (93%; T 1/2 = 14 hr. respectively), and declined thereafter, and (2) slowly renewed cells, some of which survived at least 10 wk, were maximal in incidence (22%) and numbers (61 x 10^3/mm^3) in adult mice. After neonatal thymectomy, marrow lymphocytes and erythroid cells attained normal numbers at 2 wk but declined thereafter. Thus, mouse marrow contains a major of population of rapidly renewed small lymphocytes, maximal in numbers in young animals and apparently thymus-independent in early post-natal development, while a slowly renewed subpopulation increases with age.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les lymphocytes et autres types cellulaires de la moelle osseuse de souris en croissance (0 - 16 semaines) ont été analysées quantitativement par histométrie. Le nombre des petits lymphocytes atteint un maximum à l'âge de 2 - 4 semaines. Les granulocytes atteignent leur nombre maximum à l'âge de 8 - 16 semaines tandis que le nombre de cellules érythroides après une faible augmentation transitoire à 8 semaines diminue progressivement de 2 à 12 semaines après la naissance pour se stabiliser par la suite. L'analyse des indices de marquage chez des animaux injectés de 3H-thymidine a révélé qu'il y a deux populations des lymphocytes distinctes cinétiquement, i.e.: (1) les lymphocytes qui se renouvellent rapidement (T 1/2 = 14 h) et qui constituent la majorité ou 93% de la population lymphocytaire chez des animaux âgés de 4 semaines, (2) les lymphocytes qui se renouvellent plus lentement et dont le nombre atteint un maximum chez l'adulte alors qu'ils forment 22% de la population des lymphocytes. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Osmond, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt412.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j412c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02871010b"><ual:graduationDate>1976</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Chemical synthesis of 18-hydroxydeoxycorticosterone and some aspects of its biological activity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Ming P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une synthèse simple du 18-0H-DOC (20,21-dihydroxy-18,20-époxy-delta4-prégnèn-3-one) via la 18 hydroxyprogestérone fut accomplie. Un procédé amelioré pour la préparation de la l8-hydroxyprogesterone à partir de l'acétate de deoxycorticostérone a été développé. La conversion de la 18-0H progestérone en 18-0H-DOC fut effectuee par une nouvelle synthèse comprenant deux étapes. Plusieurs stéroides ayant la structure 18,20-cyclohémicétal et 18,20-cyclobutanol furent isolés et identifiés, et leurs spectres de masse analysés. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A simple synthesis of l8-0H-DOC (20,2l-dihydroxy-18,20-epoxy-delta4-pregnen-3-one) via 18-hydroxyprogesterone was accomplished. An improved procedure for the preparation of 18-hydroxyprogesterone starting from deoxycorticosterone acetate was developed. The conversion of 18-OH progesterone to 18-OH-DOC was achieved by a new, two-step synthesis. Several steroids with 18,20-cyclohemiketal and 18,20-cyclobutanol structures were isolated and identified, and their mass spectra analyzed. 18-0H-DOC was found to be a hypertensive agent equipotent with deoxycorticosterone in the unilaterally nephrectomized rat maintained on saline. In the adrenalectomized rat, 18-OH-DOC caused sodium retention, affected potassium excretion only at a high dose, and the ratio of the retention of water to sodium was greater than observed with deoxycorticosterone. 18-OH-DOC did not exert a negative feedback effect upon the pituitary adrenal axis of rat but, rather, caused an increased corticosteroid output. It reduced carrageenan-induced edema in the rat paw. A derivative of metopirone, 2-methyl-1,2-bis(3'-pyridyl)-1-pro-panol was synthesized from metopirone and was found to cause a three fold enhancement of the biotransformation of deoxycorticosterone to 18-OH-DOC by the rat adrenal in vitro.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Birmingham, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pt66p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02871010b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n204222r"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation of plasticity in the human vestibulo-ocular reflex arc</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gonshor, Aron</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude a été entreprise pour étudier l'adaptation à long terme du réflexe vestibuloocculaire (R.V.O.). La répétition de mouvements prolongés de rotation unidirectionnelle de là tête entraîne une baisse progressive du R.V.O. induit. Toute fois une telle diminution ne semble pas survenir au cours des mouvements spontanés de la vie de tous les jours. Les expériences ont été entreprises pour tester la possibilité que ces changements ne surviennent que lorsqu' ils sont fonctionnellement avantageux. Au cours de la première phase expérimentale le gain du R.V.0. (vitesse angulaire des yeux/vitesse angulaire de la tête) a été mesuré chez 8 sujets exposés les yeux ouverts dans l'obscurité pendant une heure, 3 jours consécutifs, à une oscillation sinusoidale horizontale de fréquence égale à 1/6 herz et de vélocité égale à 60 degrés per second. Ces valeurs sont situées dans la zone présumée de rapidité de transmission dans le canal semicirculaire de l'homme et sont donc probablement dans less limites normales de stimulation naturelle. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This study is an investigation of long-term adaptation in the human vestibulo-ocular reflex (VOR). Repetition of prolonged unidirectional head rotation leads to progressive decline of the reflexly induced VOR. Yet such decline does not appear to occur during the natural movements of everyday life. The following experiments investigated the possibility that such changes only occur when they are functionally advantageous. In the first major experiment, the VOR gain (eye angular velocity/head angular velocity) was measured in eight subjects, with eyes open in the dark, and exposed on 3 consecutive days to 1 hour of horizontal sinusoidal oscillation at 1/6 Hz and 60°/sec velocity amplitude. These values lie within the presumed range of velocity transduction in the human semicircular canal, and hence probably within the range of natural stimulation. The results showed no significant changes of VOR gain throughout the experiment. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jones, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214s29j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204222r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236527n"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Protein secretion from the rat exocrine pancreas: role of calcium, carbachol and the cyclic nucleotides</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fast, Diane K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La libération de protéines par le pancréas exocrine du rat a été stimulée in vitro par le carbachol ou l'AMP cyclique dibutyrylé (DBC); la sécretion occasionnée par la combinaison de ces deux agents est plus grande que la somme de leurs effets respectifs. L'effet du carbachol ou du DBC, seuls ou combinés, est dépendant de la concentration extracellulaire de calcium, bien que la libération de protéines soit augmentée par la combinaison carbachol plus DBC à faibles concentrations de calcium extracellulaire. Le manganèse ou le lanthanum inhibent la sécrétion stimulée par le carbachol, ou le carbachol plus DBC, à concentrations optimales de calcium, mais pas la sécrétion causée par le carbachol plus DBC à faibles concentrations de calcium. Le carbachol stimule cependant que le DBC reduit la sortie de 45Ca, dans des morceaux de pancréas préalablement marqués. Les résultats indiquent que le carbachol active un récepteur muscarinique, dans une étape dépendante du calcium extracellulaire; ceci résulte en une concentration plus élevée de calcium ionisé dans le cytoplasme, ce qui est essentiel pour le processus de sécrétion. Le calcium cytoplasmique n'est pas dérivé de sources extracellulaires, mais il provient probablement de sites intracellulaires de storage. Le DBC augmente l'effet du carbachol en conservant le calcium intracellulaire pour fins d'utilisation dans le processus de sécrétion.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Protein release from the rat exocrine pancreas was stimulated in vitro by carbachol or dibutyryl cyclic AMP (DBC); secretion caused by a combination of these two agents was greater than the sum of their individual effects. The secretory effect of carbachol or DBC, alone or in combination, was dependent on the concentration of extracellular calcium, although protein release was increased by carbachol plus DBC at small concentrations of extracellular calcium. Manganese or lanthanum inhibited protein release stimulated by carbachol or carbachol plus DBC at optimal concentrations of calcium but not that caused by carbachol plus DBC at small concentrations of calcium. Carbachol stimulated and DBC reduced efflux of 45Ca from prelabelled pancreas pieces. The results indicate that carbachol, in a step dependent on extracellular calcium, activates a muscarinic receptor; this results in an increase in the concentration of cytoplasmic ionized calcium, which is essential for the secretory process. This cytoplasmic calcium is not derived from extracellular sources but probably comes from intracellular stores. DBC potentiates the effect of carbachol by conserving intracellular ionized calcium for utilization in the secretory process.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tenenhouse, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gw80f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236527n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956j96x"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Health</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Methods of assessing radiographic progression in the pneumoconioses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eyssen, Gail E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The main aim was to evaluate methods of assessing radiographic progression of pneumoconiosis (lung dust disease) for investigating relationships with dust exposure in individual subjects. It was found that only two methods needed to be compared:- (i) side-by-side reading of all five films in known temporal order; and (ii) independent randomised reading. The standard (ILO U/C 1971) classification was used, except that for method (i) the scales of abnormality were elaborated four-fold. Five chest radiographs, spanning c. 20 Years, for 283 workers in the Quebec chrysotile producing industry were assessed by four film readers of international repute. The new scales were employed with reasonable success, but the standard scales were inadequately exploited. "Concertina effects" were complex, progression in side-by-side reading being stretched about as often as squeezed. They did not disqualify this method of reading, which produced lower inter-observer error and higher correlations of progression with measures of exposure. The stated aim was thus achieved by choice of method (i). As previously, correlations were greater on the inclusion of the status of the earliest film as predictor. Inclusion of further variables led to higher correlations, but only artifactually.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le but principal était d'évaluer les différentes méthodes d'estimation de la progression radiographique de la pneumoconiose afin d'examiner la relation entre cette progression et l'exposition des sujets à la poussière. Il fut décidé qu'il était nécessaire de comparer seulement deux méthodes: (i) la lecture côte à côte de cinq films placés dans un ordre temporel connu; et (ii) la lecture indépendante de films choisis d'une façon aléatoire. La classification courante (ILO U/C 1971) fut utilisée mais cependant avec la méthode (i) les échelles de malformation furent augmentées quatre fois. Cinq radiographies de poitrine, embrassant à peu près 20 ans, de 283 travailleurs dans l'industrie chrysotile du Québec furent examinées par quatre lecteurs de films de réputation internationale. Les nouvelles échelles furent employées avec un succès raisonnable alors que les échelles courantes furent insuffisamment utilisées. Les "concertina effects" furent complexes, la progression selon la lecture côte à côte étant augmentée presqu'aussi souvent qu'elle fut réduite. Ces effets n'ont pas causé le rejet de cette méthode de lecture car elle produisait moins d'erreurs entre les observateurs ainsi que de plus grandes corrélations entre la progression et la quantité d'exposition. Nous sommes alors parvenu à nos fins avec la méthode (i). Comme auparavant, les corrélations étaient plus glandes lorsque la condition indiquée par le premier film était incluse en tant que prédiseur. L'inclusion d'autres variables a également apporté des corrélations plus grandes mais celles-ci n'étaient pas justes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McDonald, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053k309.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956j96x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epidemiology and Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zh441"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanism of phiX174 RF replication: specific initiation sites for synthesis of DNA</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eisenberg, Shlomo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The structure of phiX174 replicative form (RF) DNA isolated at 9 minutes after infection from phiX-infected Escherichia-coli cells was investigated. This DNA contained gaps which could be filled in in vitro using [alpha-32P] deoxynucleoside 5'-triphosphates, T4 DNA polymerase and T4 DNA ligase. Treatment of the "gap-labelled" RF II DNA with R. Hind restriction endonuclease and competition-annealing analyses were used to locate the gaps on the phiX genome. The following observations were made: 1. The location of the gaps found in the viral strand was restricted to the cistron A region on the phiX genetic map. 2. The gaps in the complementary strand appeared at many places on the genome. Comparison of the pyrimidine tracts present in the gap region and of the average base composition of the gaps in the viral and complementary strand DNA, to the pyrimidine tracts and base composition of the intact strands, confirmed the non-random location of the gap in the viral strand, and indicated a non-random distribution of the gaps in the complementary strand DNA. I conclude that the synthesis of both strands of phiX RF DNA is initiated at specific initiation sites during the semiconservative process of RF replication. There is one site for the initiation of viral strand synthesis in the cistron A region, and there are many, specific initiation sites for the synthesis of the complementary strand DNA. From these data I infer continuous and discontinuous synthesis of the viral and complementary strand respectively.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Il a été procédé à l'étude de la structure de la forme réplicative II (RF II) de l'ADN du bactériophage phiX174 isolée 9 minutes après l'infection de Escherichia coli par ce bactériophage. Cette forme réplicative contient des "gaps" (discontinuité d'une longueur d'un ou plusieurs nucléotides) qui peuvent être résorbés in vitro en utilisant des désoxynucléotide 5'-triphosphates marqués au 32P en alpha, l'ADN-polymérase du bactériophage T4 et l'ADN-ligase de T4. Le traitement de telles molécules marquées au 32p par l'endonucléase restrictive R. Hind ainsi que des analyses mettant en jeu des réassociations compétitives ont permis de situer ces "gaps" sur le génome de phiX. Il a été observé que: 1. la localisation du "gap" trouvé sur le brin viral est limitée à la région du cistron A sur la carte génétique de phiX. 2. les "gaps" propres au brin complémentaire du brin viral appraissent à différents endroits sur le génome. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denhardt, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397c332.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zh441</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1j92gb33c"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Formation of steroids in human pregnancy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brisson, Gilles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In a first study, the rate of excretion of lbeta-hydroxyandrostenedione was investigated using two pools of human late pregnancy urine and was found to be 0.8 and 1.0 microgram per day. In the second part of the thesis the metabolism of 3H-dehydroisoandrosterone was investigated in human fetal adrenal maintained in monolayer culture and the factors regulating the growth of the cells and the formation of dehydroisoandrosterone sulfate were studied. Dehydroisoandrosterone was metabolized to androstenedione and androstenediol to a small extent in both primary and initial subcultures of human fetal adrenals. Dehydroisoandrosterone was extensively converted to its sulfate only in primary cell cultures but hot in initial subcultures. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans une première étape, nous avons mesuré à deux reprises chez la femme enceinte, au dernier trimestre de la grossesse, le taux d'excrétion urinaire de la l-hydroxyandrosteneioe et les résultats obtenus ont été: 0.8 et 1.0mcg par jour. Dans une deuxième phase, nous avons étudié d'une part, le métabolisme de la H3-déhydrodsoandrostérone par la surrénale de foetus humain maintenu en culture et d'autre part, les facteurs responsables de la croissance cellulaire et de la formation du sulfate de déhydroisoandrostérone. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Solomon, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x4410.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92gb33c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn999967m"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Thyroxin and development of hepatic microsomal drug oxidation and electron transport in man and rats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aranda, Jacob V.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nous avons étudie l'ontogénèse des oxidases hépatiques à function mixte chèz l'homme, et l'influence des hormones thyroidiennes sur l'ontogénèse de ces enzymes chez le rat. Durant la période néonatale chez l'homme, on observe une déficience significative de l'aminopyrine-N-danethylase, de l'aniline-p-hydroxylase, de l'NADPH oxidase, NADPH cytochrane c reductase et du cytochrome P-450, tandis que l'NADPH cytochrome P-450 reductase n'est pas mesurable.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The neonatal phase of the ontogenetic pattern of hepatic microsomal mixed function oxidases (HMMFQ) in man and the influence of thyroid hormone on this ontogenetic pattern in rats were studied. In the neonatal period in man, there is a significant deficiency in the activity of hepatic microsomal aminopyrine N-demethylase, aniline p-hydroxylase, NADPH oxidase, NADPH cytochrome c reductase and in the amount of cytochrome P-450 and no measurable activity of NADPH cytochrome P-450 reductase. All of these enzymes except aminopyrine N-demethylase significantly correlated with postconceptional age indicating that significantly developmental events occur during the newborn period. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eade, N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tg149.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999967m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50h026v"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Equilibrium between copper, zinc and chlorine at high temperatures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Christie, George Lyal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The work to be described in this thesis belongs to the larger body of chemical and metallurgical literature usually referred to as metal displacement equilibria. Many systems of this group have been investigated from a purely practical viewpoint. The results obtained have formed the bases of many metallurgical industries. Another group of investigations have been undertaken from a more theoretical viewpoint. The interpretation of these data has been that of pure physical chemistry. Investigation of liquid and solid alloy systems and of the heat and free energy of formation of such systems has led to theories regarding the nature and causes of abnormalities in these systems. Attempts have been made to correlate the results obtained with differences in atomic radii and the tendency towards compound formation. These investigations of a more theoretical nature have thus formed a very substantial link between the work of the industrial metallurgist and that of the physical chemist. [...] The present investigation, while undertaken as a problem in the field of physical chemistry may have a practical application. It is not the intention of the writer to stress this application but rather to indicate that in this investigation practical and academic interests run parallel. If the equilibrium is favourable, all or part of the zinc in scrap brass may be recovered as a useful product and leave a residue of copper that may be purified by more conventional methods.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maass, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c5724.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h026v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9306t234q"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A correlated light and electron microscope study of hyperplasia and neoplasia in the thyroid gland of rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Adams, J. Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A correlated light and electron microscope study ls presented of hyperplasia and neoplasia in rat thyroid glands exposed to X-irradiation, prolonged dietary iodine deficiency, or both. The following tissues are examined and compared: normal thyroid; hyperplastic thyroid; thyroid tumour nodule; modified hyperplastic thyroid near tumour nodule; parathyroid infiltrated by thyroid tumour nodule; and thyroid tumour extend1ng throughout a thyroid lobe. Original observations relating to the architecture and cytology of these tissues are reported and discussed. These observations concern: contiguity between thyroid follicles; folllole proximity to blood vessels; light cells; luminal colloid; psammoma bodies; intraluminal cells; microlumina; cell interdigitations; basal lamina; virus-like particles; follicular cell height; lipid droplets; rough and smooth endoplasmic reticulum; apical vesicles; dense bodies; mitochondria; colloid droplets; atypical apical protrusions; microfilaments; nucleus; interface between neoplastic and non-neoplastic cells; and neoplastic characteristics in hyperplastic cells.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nadler, N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nb941.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t234q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655k56m"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An intracellular study of the actions of anesthetics on spinal monosynaptic transmission</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zorychta, Edith</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le parcours monosynaptique spinal du chat nous a servi de modele pour déterminer quel est le site de la dépression de transmission synaptique centrale causée par l'éther, l'halothane et la procaine. L'analyse du quantum des PPSE provoqués par la stimulation d'une fibre unique, faite à l'aide de diverses techniques d'informatique, nous a permis de déterminer les actions pré- et postsynaptiques de chaque drogue. Des concentrations d'éther et d'halothane qui produisent l'anesthésie chirurgicale du chat diminuent le contenu moyen du quantum sans influencer la conduction dans les fibres afférentes ou l'amplitude du potentiel unitaire. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The spinal monosynaptic pathway in the cat was used as a model to determine the site(s) at which ether, halothane and procaine depress central synaptic transmission. Pre- and postsynaptic actions of each drug were determined by quantal analysis of EPSPs evoked by stimulation of a single la fiber, using a variety of computer techniques. Concentrations of ether and halothane that produce surgical anesthesia in the cat were shown to decrease the mean quantum content without affecting the unit potential amplitude or conduction in afferent fibers. These results support the hypothesis that general anesthetics depress central synaptic transmission by a direct action on the transmitter release mechanism. Procaine did not affect the transmitter release mechanism or subsynaptic sensitivity, but blocked afferent conduction, presumably at the intraspinal branches. All three drugs decreased the electrical, excitability of some cells, while no drug significantly altered the resting potential or the input resistance of the motoneuron membrane.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Esplin, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451m777.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655k56m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nf18j"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of vertical linear accelerations on motor controls in the cat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Watt, D. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Experiments have been performed to examine the effects of vertical linear accelerations on motor control in the cat. Examination of electromyographic activity in 2 opposing pairs of muscles in the neck and hindlimb of alert cats undergoing sudden, unexpected falls has demonstrated that electrical activation of all muscles tested occurred in 2 distinct phases. The earlier was otolith-dependent, whereas the later activity apparently did not originate in the labyrinth. Smooth landings from short falls were not possible in the absence of either phase of the response. Observation of the head and neck of the above cats while falling demonstrated a stereotyped pattern of movement, consisting of a lack of rotation of the bead and a progressive dorsiflexion of the neck. It was unaltered by loss of 8th nerve function, and therefore loss of the earlier phase of emg activity in the neck muscles, and could be predicted by an elementary mathematical model based on simple physical principles. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'objectif de cette thèse est d'examiner les effets d'accélérations verticales linéaires sur le contrôle de la motricité chez le chat. L'activité électromyographique de deux paires de muscles antagonistes situés soit dans le cou soit dans une des pattes arrière de chats éveillés a été mesurée. Cette expérience s'effectue en laissant tomber les chats en chute libre. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jones, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pq90d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nf18j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881q131"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Selective stimulation of cell-mediated immune responses in mice immunosuppressed by a graft-versus-host reaction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Treiber, William</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The immunosuppressive effect of the graft-versus-host (GVH) reaction was studied in Fl mice injected with parental lymphoid cells. Suppression of the humoral immune response to sheep red blood cells (SRBC) in mice undergoing GVH reactions (GVH mice) was shown to depend upon the strength of the GVH reaction and its duration at the time of sensitization with SRBC. Adrenalectomy and castration of mice prior to the induction of a GVH reaction did not reduce the immunosuppressive effect, suggesting that immunosuppression results from immunological factors rather than from a general stress response. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'effet immunosuppresseur de la reaction du greffon contre l'hôte (GVH) a été étudié chez des souris hybrides F1 injectées avec des cellules lymphoides d'origine parentale. Il a été observé que le degré de suppression de la réponse humorale aux globules rouges de mouton (SRBC) causée par la reaction GVH varie suivant la vigueur de la réaction GVH et aussi en fonction de l'intervalle séparant l'induction de la GVH de la stimulation antigénique. L'adrendlectomie et la castration des souris hybrides F1 avant l'injection des cellules paréntales n'ont pas réduit l'intensité de l'immunosuppression suggérant que celle-ci est due à des facteurs immunologiques plutôt qu'à un état de stress. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lapp, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fv72x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881q131</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>