<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8s45qb50v"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Time-distance as a factor in the delivery of school bus services to households in the Eastern Townships School Board, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fox, Michael John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>For students and their families that live within the regional school system of Quebec, travel to school by bus has become a "fixed" activity. Households operate within a complex system of time, distance and accessibility constraints in adapting to the impact of this fixed bus schedule. This study focuses on the impact of this daily bus ride on the perceptions and behaviours of these households. The Household Activity-Travel Simulator (HATS) technique, developed at Oxford University, was adapted to a survey of 64 households in the Eastern Townships School Board of Quebec. Households were selected according to time-distance from the two English secondary schools in the region. The interview/survey solicited student and family responses and behaviours with respect to the daily bus trip. The study tests six related hypotheses on the effects of such large time units devoted to riding a bus. The hypotheses search for relationships between travel time and the daily activity schedules of students and their families. Through a number of quantitative and qualitative measures, the study concludes that the bus trip has an effect on students and, to a lesser degree, on their families.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f755s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qb50v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>School buses</dc:subject><dc:subject>School children -- Transportation -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000168v"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional design and shade adaptation in Acer species</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lei, Thomas T. (Thomas Ting)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This is a broad, quantitative comparison of 12 maple species, representing both canopy and subcanopy growth forms, grown under two ecologically relevant light environments. The maple seedlings responded mainly to light intensity; light quality plays only a minor role in the induction of shade characteristics. While a light-mediated trade off between light and dark reactions of photosynthesis was evident at the chloroplast level, this did not lead to similar differences in assimilaton rates. Gap-grown seedlings showed no apparent compromise in photosynthetic response to dim light and lightflecks. Seedlings of subcanopy trees trade off wood strength for increases in plant size while canopy seedlings sacrifice plant size for wood strength. The demand for greater wood strength in seedlings of canopy trees appears to pose a strong developmental constraint that delays maturation. Free of this constraint, subcanopy species can devote more resource to reach adult size quickly and at an earlier age.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806148t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000168v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plants -- Effect of light on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Maple -- Growth</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741t44t"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Euclidean algorithm for Galois extensions of the rational numbers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Clark, David Alan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Let K be a totally real, quartic, Galois extension of $ doubq$ whose ring of integers R is a principal ideal domain. If there is a prime ideal p of R such that the unit group maps onto $(R/{ bf p} sp2$)*, then R is a Euclidean domain. This criterion is generalized to arbitrary Galois extensions. Let E be an elliptic curve over a number field F. Suppose ($F: doubq rbrack le 4$ and $F(E lbrack q rbrack ) not subseteq F$ for all primes q such that F contains a primitive $q sp{ rm th}$ root of unity, then the reduced elliptic curve $ tilde{E}(F sb{ bf p})$ is cyclic infinitely often. In general, if $ Gamma$ a subgroup of $E(F)$ with the range of $ Gamma$ sufficiently large, there are infinitely many prime ideals p of F such that the reduced curve $ tilde{E}(F sb{ bf p}) = Gamma sb{ bf p}$, where $ Gamma sb{ bf p}$ is the reduction modulo p of $ Gamma$.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k4269.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t44t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rw07j"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Metabolism of leukotriene B4 and other hydroxylated eicosanoids by the 12-hydroxyeicosanoid dehydrogenase10,11-reductase pathway</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wainwright, Sandra L. (Sandra Lee)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Leukotriene B$ sb4$ (LTB$ sb4)$ has previously been reported to be metabolized by porcine polymorphonuclear leukocytes (PMNL) to 10,11-dihydro-LTB$ sb4$ and 10,11-dihydro-12-oxo-LTB$ sb4$ (Powell, W. S., &amp; Gravelle, F. (1989) J. Biol. Chem. 264, 5364-5369). The 10,11-dihydro-LTB$ sb4$ fraction, prepared as described above, was resolved into two components by normal-phase (NP) high pressure liquid chromatography (HPLC). These products were identified as 10,11-dihydro-LTB$ sb4$ and 10,11-dihydro-12-epi-LTB$ sb4$ by gas-chromatography mass-spectrometry (GC-MS) and by co-chromatography with authentic chemically synthesized compounds. In the presence of NAD$ sp+,$ a microsomal 12-hydroxyeicosanoid dehydrogenase converted LTB$ sb4$ to 12-oxo-LTB$ sb4,$ which was identified by GC-MS. This enzyme catalyzes the initial rate-limiting step in the formation of dihydro metabolites of LTB$ sb4.$ 12-Oxo-LTB$ sb4$ was rapidly metabolized to 10,11-dihydro-12-oxo-LTB$ sb4$ by a cytosolic 10,11-reductase in the presence of NADH or NADPH. LTB$ sb4$ was not converted to any products by this fraction. 12(S)-Hydroxy-5,8,10,14-eicosatetraenoic acid (12(S)-HETE) was metabolized by intact porcine PMNL to 12-oxo-5,8,14-eicosatrienoic acid, 12(R)-hydroxy-5,8,14-eicosatrienoic acid and 12(S)-hydroxy-5,8,14-eicosatrienoic acid, which were identified by GC-MS and nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy. The latter two compounds were separated by NP-HPLC following derivatization with methoxy-(trifluoromethyl)phenylacetic acid and were identified by co-chromatography with authentic compounds. 12(S)-HETE was metabolized by 12-hydroxyeicosanoid dehydrogenase, in the presence of NAD$ sp+,$ to 12-oxo-ETE, identified by its chromatographic and UV spectral properties. 13-Hydroxy-9,11-octadecadienoic acid (13-HODE) was metabolized by porcine PMNL to 13-hydroxy-9-octadecenoic acid and 13-oxo-9-octadecenoic acid which were identified by GC-MS. Specificity studies indicated that the porcine PMNL 12-hydroxyeicosanoid dehydrogenase preferentially oxidizes substrates with a 12-hydroxyl group preceded by at least two conjugated double bonds and followed by a 2-cis-octenyl group.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r265.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw07j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atd96k428v"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on mammalian 25-hydroxyvitamin D3-24-hydroxylase</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mandla, Suzan (Suzan G.)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes three studies on mammalian 25-hydroxyvitamin D$ sb3$-24-hyroxylase (24-hydroxylase), the first enzyme in the C24-oxidation pathway, a major catabolic pathway for vitamin D metabolites in kidney and other target tissues for vitamin D hormone. The first study examines the involvement of protein kinase C in the regulation of 24-hydroxylase activity in mouse kidney. Evidence is presented supporting a stimulatory role for protein kinase C in the regulation of constitutive, but not inducible, renal 24-hydroxylase. The kinase is also implicated in the aberrant expression of renal vitamin D metabolism in the mutant X-linked hypophosphatemic (Hyp) mouse. The second study investigates the mechanism(s) by which forskolin, a classic activator of adenylate cyclase, inhibits 24-hydroxylase activity in mouse kidney. Both the traditional cAMP-dependent mechanism and a novel cAMP-independent mode of action are observed. A direct interaction between forskolin and the substrate binding site of 24-hydroxylase is suggested for the latter based on kinetic analyses and structural similarities between the diterpene and the steroid substrate for the hydroxylase. The third study addresses the structural relationship between renal 1-hydroxylase and renal and target cell 24-hydroxylase(s) by assessing 24-hydroxylase activity in patients with vitamin D dependency rickets type I (VDDR-I), a Mendelian disorder of 1-hydroxylase function. Both constitutive renal 24-hydroxylase, indirectly ascertained through measurement of circulating levels of relevant vitamin D metabolites, and inducible target cell 24-hydroxylase, directly measured in cultured skin fibroblasts, are shown to be intact in VDDR-I patients undergoing calcitriol therapy. These findings suggest that the 1- and 24-hydroxylase activities likely represent or contain distinct gene products.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f290w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k428v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rickets</dc:subject><dc:subject>Metabolism, Inborn errors of</dc:subject><dc:subject>Protein kinases</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053h67j"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interrelationships of endothelial and smooth muscle cells to elastic laminae in the mouse aortic wall during development : an ultrastructural, immunohistochemical and radioautographic study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Davis, Elaine C. (Elaine Caroline)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The association of endothelial and smooth muscle cells to elastic laminae in the developing mouse aortic wall was investigated by electron microscopy and immunohistochemistry. Early in development, bundles of contractile filaments traverse the long axis of the cell obliquely to anchor in membrane-associated dense plaques on either side. From these sites, microfibrils extend in the same direction to link the cell to the adjacent elastic laminae. The microfibrils become infiltrated with elastin to form elastin extensions, which together with the intracellular contractile filaments bundles, forms a "contractile-elastic unit". The ordered arrangement of contractile-elastic units revealed in the adult vessel provides a mechanism for the transmission of tension throughout the vessel wall. During development, endothelial cells are similarly connected to the subjacent elastic lamina by filamentous structures. These "endothelial cell connecting filaments" show morphological feature similar to microfibrils. Immunolocalization of fibrillin, a constituent protein of microfibrils, to the connecting filaments provides further evidence for their microfibrillar nature. These results suggest that microfibrils may play an important role in cell anchorage and the maintenance of tissue integrity. A longterm radioautographic study was performed to provide quantitative data concerning the stability of aortic elastin. Results from this study demonstrate the remarkable longevity of elastin in the aortic wall and suggest that, like elastin, cell to elastic lamina connections remain stable throughout development and exist as functional structures in the adult vessel.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q68t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h67j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axp68kj033"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Religion and Philosophy in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A philosophical study of values and valuing in sexuality education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Morris, Ronald William</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The enthusiasm for a positivistic approach to sexuality education has begun to subside. Recognizing that sexuality is more than a biological phenomenon, and that education is more than just information, sexuality educators throughout North America are now acknowledging the importance of values. There are two problems, however, with the philosophical orientation on values within the literature. The first problem is the pervasive view that teachers should remain neutral to facilitate value clarification. The commitment to neutrality is often based on an appreciation and respect for pluralism, on the subjective nature of values, and on the integrity of persons. The commitment to neutrality, however, confuses pluralism with relativism, subjectivity with subjectivism, and integrity with validity. The second problem is the conceptualization of sexual-values education as a solution to problems like unwanted teenage pregnancy and sexually transmitted diseases. This view of sexuality education reduces education to schooling, valuing to decision-making, and sexuality to problems arising from coitus. It evaluates the success of educational efforts according to strictly utilitarian criteria. In this thesis, sexual-values education is reconceptualized as a life-long process, and a successful sexual-values education is redefined by its capacity to be celebrational, hospitable, meaningful, and life-enhancing.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fz34m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj033</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sex instruction -- Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z249c"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Adaptation of processing technologies in the bakery industry in Kenya</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rono, Henry Kipkogei</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This was an investigation of the ways in which firms, in the developing nations during the 1980's, have adapted production technologies in their efforts to expand the production capacities and to contribute towards the nation's capability for self-sustaining industrial operations. The study was undertaken in the bakery industry in Kenya, between 1984 and 1991, in two phases that involved a survey of 82 firms and an in-depth case study of six firms. One of the principal aims of the study was to identify a more promising strategy between the small-scale operations and the Big-Push model. The argument in this study, however, is that these two models of economic growth are subject to limitations that arise essentially from their lack of treatment of the attributes of entrepreneurs as determinant factors. Examined under the modified versions of these models are the effects of the varied characteristics of the entrepreneurs, the nature of investment and location of the firms on the types and the levels of equipment adopted, capacity utilization, labour requirements and ways for skills development. Results indicate that the modified models, to incorporate entrepreneurs among the casual factors, improve prediction of the nature of investment as well as adaptation of the production technologies. With regard to the relative advantages, it was found that while small-scale operations encouraged adoption of locally manufactured equipment and utilization of considerably higher ratio of skilled labour, they are significantly constrained by limited capabilities for adoption of advanced equipment. In contrast, whereas large-scale operations adopted modern equipment and absorbed substantially greater number of the labour force, they exerted overwhelming negative impact on local technical capabilities and entrepreneurial activities. In light of these findings it is suggested that medium size operations that offset extreme disadvantages of the two conventional models would be more favourable with respect to adaptation of the production technologies for purposes of achieving self-sustaining industrial operations in the context of the developing countries. In addition, attention should be given to policy measures that enable entrepreneurs to acquire capabilities for undertaking competitive industrial enterprises, particularly adoption and management of technically efficient techniques. One of the potential approaches is promotion of the cooperative industrial endeavour through which recent entrepreneurs can mobilize resources and operation skills</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x5593.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z249c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bakeries -- Kenya</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cc48g"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The sīra of the prophet Muḥammad in the repertoire of the contemporary Egyptian Maddāḥin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abdel-Malek, Kamal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This is an interpretive study of the life of the Prophet Muhammad as it is artistically depicted in the repertoire (especially the narrative ballads) of fifty-one contemporary Egyptian maddahin (singers of eulogies in honour of the Prophet Muhammad, sing. maddah). The elements of this repertoire, as diverse as narrative ballads, classical odes, Qur'an chanting, and the melodies of the secular songs of well-known Egyptian singers, do not exist as discrete units but rather as a lively tawlifa (blend)--to use a common term in Colloquial Egyptian Arabic (CEA). This study is about blends where discrete units lose their borderlines and leak into one another, about phenomena which are "betwixt and between" the perceived scholarly categories which confidently delineate boundaries between elite and popular Islam, the historical and the legendary Muhammad, the sacred and the profane, orality and writing, standard and colloquial Arabic. In order to understand the process which marks the making of the people's Muhammad, the study deals with the sources and the contents of the repertoire of the Egyptian maddahin. The performance of these singers as well as their interaction with the audience are also considered. The "legendary" material in this repertoire is attested as historical by many authoritative and well-recognized "orthodox" authors of the past. Classical Arabic, classical poetic forms, philosophical notions, long believed to be the exclusive possessions of the learned, are freely utilized in the ballads and popular songs under study. The people's Muhammad appears as both a commanding figure, empowered by the supernatural, and a touchingly vulnerable human being; God's ascetic messenger and a man who savours life's lawful pleasures; an eloquent speaker who utters Qur'an-like terse Arabic and a lovingly familiar figure who also uses local patois. Bipolarity, beloved of many scholars, is seriously challenged by the art of the Egyptian maddahin. A renewed effort has to be made to discover more valid categories which will take into account the intermediary combinations (Mischbildungen) characteristic of that art.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085m92d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc48g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Muḥammad, Prophet, d. 632</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sacred vocal music -- Egypt</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9880vs56m"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A time resolved x-ray study of spinodal decomposition in aluminium-zinc</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mainville, Jacques</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Time resolved small angle x-ray scattering (SAXS) using synchrotron radiation was applied to the study of the kinetics of spinodal decomposition (SD) in an AlZn binary alloy at critical composition quenched into the immiscible region. These millisecond time scale measurements, performed at the National Synchrotron Light Source (Brookhaven National Labs., N.Y.), constitute the first direct experimental verification in a binary alloy of the theory proposed by Langer, Bar-on and Miller in 1975 for SD. A scheme based on the composition distribution functional is proposed to account for the decomposition taking place during the quench. The interatomic mobility, a free energy gradient coefficient and two coefficients that suffice to determine a coarse-grained (intensive) free energy have been obtained in the framework of this theory. The mobilities obtained compare well with tracer diffusion measurements reported in literature. A dependence of the coarse-grained free energy coefficients on the coarse-graining length is found and a procedure is proposed to uniquely choose the values of these coefficients based on the predicted integrated intensity from the equilibrium concentrations and on the measured integrated intensities. Late-stage coarsening regimes were also investigated. In these regimes, growth exponents higher than the value 1/3 predicted by the Lifshitz-Slyozov-Wagner theory are obtained. These higher values, comprised between 0.40 and 0.45 are consistent with predictions that alloys in which elastic effects are important can present a transition regime from a $t sp{1/3}$ growth law to a $t sp{1/2}$ law. The structure factors do not quite scale. They also present a shoulder at high wavevectors, a feature not reported before in metallic alloys.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw22x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vs56m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354g90q"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of a salespeson's utilities on optimal sales force compensation structures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rouziès-Ségalla, Dominique</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Marketing analytical studies of optimal salesforce compensation policies typically rely on a set of restrictive assumptions. In this paper, a model of decentralized salesforce compensation is developed, wherein some of the classical assumptions are challenged. Response Surface Methodology is used to optimize decentralized compensation policies over a set of simulated conditions. The proposed approach is then illustrated with two empirical applications in artificial and real settings. The objective is to provide some preliminary evidence about decentralized structures and to recommend salesforce compensation policies.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw136.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354g90q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sales management</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sales personnel -- Salaries, etc</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225c65m"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation of the psychoeducational assessment process : the influence of assessors' theoretical oritentation and previous experience on their interpretations of a students' case-file</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fine, Esther Karen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study investigated the reasoning processes used by psychoeducational assessors in interpreting a typical case-file. The methodology used was one adapted from studies of problem-solving skills in other domains. In the models of reasoning derived from these studies, expertise was associated with extensive use of causal reasoning and with a high level of integration between a selectively narrow body of information and the proposed solutions. It was hypothesised that the reasoning processes used by experienced psychoeducational assessors would show similar properties. In addition, it was hypothesised that experienced and trainee assessors could be differentiated by: (a) the degree of affinity shown to a theoretical orientation in psychology, (the degree of affinity shown by the experienced assessors being greater than that shown by the trainees), and (b) the numbers and types of inferences generated from case-file information. The influences of the referral information and subjects' preconceived notions of educational exceptionality on assessment were also considered. Two groups of 12 subjects each participated in the study; experienced school psychologists (designated the experts), and trainees in psychoeducational assessment (designated the novices). Think-aloud protocols were obtained from the subjects as they interpreted the case-file. A scale for assessing relative preferences for theoretical orientations in psychology was administered to all subjects. Transcriptions of the think-aloud protocols were segmented and coded according to predetermined inference categories. The case-file text and subjects' coded protocols were used to set out formally representations of subjects' reasoning. The experts and the novices were compared for adherence to theoretical orientation, the numbers and types of inferences generated, and the reasoning strategies employed. No differences were found between the two groups for the variables analysed. However, for some of the experts, but not for the novices, well-integrated reasoning was associated with adherence to initial theories about the case. Consistencies across both groups of subjects in the types of inferences made and the use of case-file information are suggestive of a case-specific approach to assessment. Assessors appear to emphasise a student's academic strengths and, at the same time, to attend to affective problems. Relatively little attention is paid to physiological factors. The variability in the data collected indicates that there are few criteria against which to gauge expertise in psychoeducational assessment. There was no indication that assessors test their diagnostic theories systematically. It is suggested that, in this domain, reasoning strategies of review and revision are desirable and that representational models of expertise should reflect these strategies.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v18t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225c65m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychological tests</dc:subject><dc:subject>Educational psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychodiagnostics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acz30pv253"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of clay compatibility to heavy metal transport in permeability testing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cabral, Alexandre R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A clay-contaminant compatibility study was performed using: (a) two materials: a kaolinitic clay and a 90% fine sand/10% bentonite mixture (S/B); (b) concentrated solutions of two heavy metals--Pb and Zn; and (c) a flexible wall (triaxial cell) and a rigid wall (consolidation cell) permeameter. Compatibility was analyzed in terms of changes in the measured coefficient of hydraulic permeability (k) due to percolation of the concentrated heavy metal solutions, and in terms of the capacity of compacted clays to retain heavy metals. Testing procedures and sample characteristics were kept as similar as possible for two apparatuses as a means of comparing their performances. Permeability test results indicated that the k-values for kaolinite $(2 - 5 times10 sp{-7}$ cm/s) were independent of the apparatus employed, among several other parameters. k-values obtained for S/B tested in the rigid wall permeameter remained in the range of $2 - 6 times10 sp{-9}$ cm/s independently of the initial hydraulic gradients applied and of the concentration of the contaminant solution. For S/B tested with the flexible wall, however, the measured k-values varied significantly depending on: (a) the initial hydraulic gradient applied; (b) the saturation and compaction procedures adopted; (c) the concentration of the contaminant solution; and (d) type of contaminant used $(k sb{Zn} &gt; k sb{Pb}).$ Differences in performance between the two permeameters were mainly attributed to the more efficient saturation of triaxial samples. Following permeability test, the samples were sliced and chemical analyses were performed to evaluate the adsorption characteristics of the compacted materials. In the case of compacted kaolinite, adsorption characteristic curves (ACC) were constructed. ACC constitute a more realist approach to the description of the partitioning of contaminants between the solid and liquid phases in a barrier system, as compared to linear adsorption isotherms obtained from batch equilibrium tests (soil solutions). This has major implications in the definition of the retention parameter to be employed in contaminant transport modelling. Retardation factors calculated based on distribution coefficients $(K sb{d})$ obtained for ACC were found to correlate better to those obtained directly from breakthrough curves than retardation factors calculated based on $k sb{d}$ taken from linear adsorption isotherms. Chemical analyses of both the compacted samples and the leachate collected indicated that triaxial cell samples adsorbed more contaminant than consolidation cell samples. This was associated with the saturation of the sample. As observed in previous works, Zn was found to be more mobile than Pb due to its lower selectivity for clay surfaces. For increased reliability, mass balance calculations were performed. Small discrepancies between amounts introduced and detected were attributed to experimental errors and to limitations in the 'extracting' procedure followed. Larger discrepancies were associated to high affinity adsorption.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t791h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv253</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azp38wf394"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Finline discontinuity analysis using vectorial finite elements</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Foo, Senglee</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, a numerically efficient three-dimensional finite element scheme is used to analyze arbitrarily-shaped discontinuities in inhomogeneous-dielectric-loaded waveguides. Special emphasis is placed on discontinuity problems in finlines and related structures. A simple but accurate recursive algorithm, the boundary-marching method, for modeling uniform waveguides of arbitrarily-shaped cross-section is developed for the analysis. This algorithm is used to generate the matrix representations of various waveguides, including the unilateral finlines. It is shown that, by using the substructure formulation and the matrix representation of the uniform guide, the finite element mesh of the discontinuity problem can be truncated to a proximity very close to the discontinuity without compromising with the result accuracy. Finally, characteristics of inductive strips in unilateral finline are evaluated using the finite element scheme. The scattering parameters of the inductive strips obtained with the finite element method agree with published measurements and other numerical solutions to within a few percent with a relatively small number of elements. Various effects of the manufacturing process, such as the effect of mounting grooves, finite metalization thickness and deflection of dielectric substrate, on the discontinuity parameters are studied in detail using the finite element scheme.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg17x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wf394</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m338h"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The context of dominance : a cross sectional study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shamsie, Jamal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The persistence of dominance depends upon the capability of a firm to maintain such a position after it has been able to acquire it. Yet most of the existing research has been relatively unsuccessful in identifying specific factors that are likely to allow any firm to effectively deal with all forms of competitive challenges over an extended period of time. As such, the goals of this research were to investigate the persistence of dominance across several different types of industry contexts. On the whole, the results suggest that differences in the persistence of dominance can be linked to the characteristics of each industry context. In large part, these differences can be attributed to the strategies that must be pursued by the dominant firms in order to maintain the specific types of advantages that can be effectively used in each of the three types of industry contexts that could be identified.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rj72w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m338h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Market share</dc:subject><dc:subject>Competition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A000001694"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Na, Sr and Sb interactions in Al-Si alloy melts and their effects on modification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Weixing, 1957-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Na, Sr and Sb are the elements commercially used to modify the silicon phase in Al-Si foundry alloys. Interactive effects which occur during modification resulting from the mixing of modifiers in alloy melts are studied from many different aspects to identify the conditions for the occurrence of negative effects on modification, to study the modifier interaction mechanisms, and to devise ways to eliminate negative effects. Metallographic studies have shown that antimony exerts deleterious effects on sodium or strontium modification of both A356 and A413 alloys. The deleterious effect of antimony has been quantified for various levels of sodium and strontium. The effect of antimony is more severe at higher antimony concentrations in the melt. No negative effects on modification occur in the combined presence of sodium and strontium. Modifier interaction mechanisms were investigated by means of electron beam analysis, and the results were analyzed from the viewpoint of thermodynamics and crystallization. Certain antimony compounds are found in antimony treated Al-Si alloys. These antimony compounds play an important role in modifier interactions. Many interaction mechanisms are possible between antimony and strontium. The interactions may result in the formation of ternary or binary compounds. Duplex particles often form by the heterogeneous nucleation of Al$ sb4$Sr on the substrate of antimony compounds. In the study of sodium and antimony interaction mechanisms, similar duplex particles are also found. Other products from sodium and antimony interactions are a sodium-antimony binary compound and its oxide. When all three modifying elements are mixed together, all of the above interaction mechanisms are possible. Al$ sb4$Sr can heterogeneously nucleate on Na$ sb3$Sb forming an inclusion containing all three of the modifying elements. Negative effects arising from antimony can be eliminated by using a suitable excess of sodium or strontium. Orthogonal tests show that a combination of sodium and strontium is preferable to overcome the influence of antimony on modification. Mechanical property tests have shown that the influence on mechanical properties from the interactions of antimony with other modifiers can be overcome. Improved mechanical behaviour is guaranteed under relatively long periods of melt holding when using the optimum combination of sodium and strontium to treat antimony containing melts.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc06z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000001694</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3j3333932"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The christology of T.T. Shields : the irony of fundamentalism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Parent, Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation examines the christological thought of Thomas Todhunter Shields between the years 1894 to 1930, along with its influence on his view of the Bible and of the Christian's role within his/her culture. T. T. Shields was one of the most prominent Fundamentalist leaders in the 1920's. While a popularizer rather than an academic his thought merits study due to his influence within Fundamentalism and his reputation for being one of the more "thoughtful" of Fundamentalists. Shields' christology was monophysitic and docetic leading, in time, to a full blown christo-monism which effectively removed Christ from his mediatorial role. In place of Christ, Shields virtually substituted the Bible; and the characteristics that he had attributed to the Christ (viz., transcendence of error and 'the human element') he now attributed to the Scriptures. Shields' christology also resulted in a truncation of his conception the church, particularly with respect to the question of Christian mission.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f2915.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3333932</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Shields, T. T. (Thomas Todhunter), 1873-1955</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fundamentalism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jesus Christ -- Person and offices</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vm62j"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hidden Markov models, maximum mutual information estimation, and the speech recognition problem</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Normandin, Yves</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Hidden Markov Models (HMMs) are one of the most powerful speech recognition tools available today. Even so, the inadequacies of HMMs as a "correct" modeling framework for speech are well known. In that context, we argue that the maximum mutual information estimation (MMIE) formulation for training is more appropriate vis-a-vis maximum likelihood estimation (MLE) for reducing the error rate. We also show how MMIE paves the way for new training possibilities. We introduce Corrective MMIE training, a very efficient new training algorithm which uses a modified version of a discrete reestimation formula recently proposed by Gopalakrishnan et al. We propose reestimation formulas for the case of diagonal Gaussian densities, experimentally demonstrate their convergence properties, and integrate them into our training algorithm. In a connected digit recognition task, MMIE consistently improves the recognition performance of our recognizer.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bg70r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vm62j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53wx43p"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Popular music as cultural commodity : the American recorded music industries 1976-1985</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Straw, Will, 1954-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation is an analysis of historical change within those cultural industries involved in the production and dissemination of popular music. Through an analysis of the relationship between the recording and radio industries within the United States, during the period 1976-1985, the manner in which crises within these industries arise and are resolved is traced. The emergence of such musical forms as "disco" and "New Wave", and the manner in which these forms have been integrated within the functioning of the music-related industries, are central concerns of the dissertation. At the same time, more general theoretical hypotheses concerning the role played by taste in the creation of audiences for different categories of popular music are elaborated and employed within the study of specific musical genres.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns543.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx43p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Popular music -- United States -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Popular music radio stations -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sound recording industry -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Music -- Social aspects -- United States</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq524jq40w"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hot ductility and strength of five microalloyed steels in the temperature range 8000c-solids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guillet, Alain M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tensile testing was carried out on five microalloyed steels in order to investigate the hot ductility behaviour between 800 and 1300$ sp circ$C, and between 1400$ sp circ$C and the solidus temperature. The influence of an increase of the carbon content up to the peritectic composition ($ approx$0.14 wt%) in Nb-Ti-Al bearing steels, and the effect of microalloying additions (Al, Al-Nb-Ti and, Al-Nb-Ti-V-Cr) were examined. Above 1400$ sp circ$C, intergranular embrittlement occurs by incipient melting at the grain boundary at temperatures between 0 and 30$ sp circ$C below the solidus. The increase in the carbon content from 0.7 to 0.14 wt% leads to a decrease of the grain boundary incipient melting temperature, although the bulk solidus temperatures for all the steels remain more or less constant at about 1500$ sp circ$C. This is explained by the grain boundary segregation behaviour of carbon. Above 1400$ sp circ$C, fractography reveals that the grain size in the steel with the peritectic composition (0.14 wt% C) is coarser than that of the low carbon grades (0.07-0.1 wt% C). This effect is attributed to: (i) the higher $ sb{ rm Y}/ delta$ transformation temperature in the steel with the peritectic composition, thus allowing more grain coarsening, and (ii) the lower amount of $ delta$ ferrite, which reduces the pinning effect of this phase on austenite grain growth. In the Cr containing steel the relatively low degree of segregation also produces a coarser structure than that of the Nb/Ti/Al steel. In the temperature range 800-1300$ sp circ$C, the ductility is strongly dependent on prior heat treatment. For the Nb-Ti-Al bearing steels, an increase of the carbon content up to 0.14 wt% slightly affects hot ductility after direct heating and annealing at 1330$ sp circ$C. However, after sensitizing at 1480$ sp circ$C the width of the ductility trough is increased in the 0.14 wt% C steel. For the C-Mn-Al steel, the ductility is the lowest following the direct heat treatment because of the presence of a greater volume percent of AlN precipitates at the grain boundaries compared to the Nb-Ti-Al steels. In contrast, after annealing and sensitizing, the C-Mn-Al grade displays the highest ductility because of the sluggish rate of precipitation of AlN in austenite. Finally, Ti additions to Nb containing steels improve the ductility because some of the Nb is combined with TiN particles both as complex TiNb(C,N) and by precipitating as NbC on existing particles. The addition of V to the Nb-Ti-Al steels (which contains also Ni and Cr) increases the ductility because of the retardation of Nb(C,N) precipitation. However, after the sensitizing treatment, at low test temperatures, the V containing grade displays the lowest ductility because of the coarser grains. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rm943.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq40w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar781wh66w"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Component processes of simultaneous interpreting</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dillinger, Michael L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The component processes specific to simultaneous interpreting and common to interpreting and listening were investigated. Experienced conference interpreters and inexperienced bilinguals performed aural-to-oral simultaneous interpreting of a narrative and a procedure from English into French and then gave a free recall of each immediately afterwards. A comparison group of bilinguals performed a simple listening task with the same materials. The texts were on an unfamiliar topic (positron emission tomography) and differed only with respect to frame type. Experience showed a main effect on interpreting measures, (experienced interpreters performed more accurately), and interacted with text-structure variables that indexed proposition generation, but did not affect recall. Task did not have a main effect on recall and interacted weakly with text-structure variables. Text and Text-structure variables had very strong effects both for the interpreting and the recall measures. The results were viewed as evidence that interpreting involves the same component processes as normal listening comprehension rather than constituting a specialized comprehension skill. Analyses of text-structure variables provided evidence for influence of high-level conceptual processing and other component processes both on line and off line. Since there was no evidence that interpreting interfered with comprehension, the qualitative on-line measures possible in the interpreting task appear to be generalizable to comprehension under more usual circumstances.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg50c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh66w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Comprehension</dc:subject><dc:subject>Translating and interpreting -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abr86b4907"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Petticoats in the pulpit : early nineteenth century methodist women preachers in Upper Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Muir, Elizabeth Gillan, 1934-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Women preached and itinerated in different Methodist traditions in the first half of the nineteenth century in Canada. By the middle of the century, many of them had relinquished the pulpit and they soon disappeared. In the United States of America, women preachers also met with resistance, but well before the twentieth century some Methodist women had been ordained. Although many aspects of the Canadian and American contexts were similar, women preachers experienced a somewhat different reception in each country because of the contrasting political climate. Whereas the American Methodist churches reflected the more liberal atmosphere of their country, the Canadian Methodist Episcopal church intentionally adopted the more reactionary stance of the British Wesleyans in order to gain respectability and political advantage. The other Canadian Methodist churches gradually imbibed this conservative atmosphere, and as a result, Canadian women were eventually discouraged from a preaching role. This dissertation recovers the history of a number of nineteenth century Methodist women preaching in Canada, examines their British heritage and the experiences of their American sisters, and suggests reasons for the Canadian devolution.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g445s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b4907</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Methodist Church -- Ontario -- History -- 19th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women clergy -- Ontario -- History -- 19th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ontario -- Church history -- 19th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Methodist Church -- Ontario -- Clergy -- History -- 19th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0v8382186"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Primal access recognition of visual objects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bergevin, Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We present PARVO, a computer vision system which addresses the problem of fast and generic recognition of unexpected 3D objects from single 2D views. After more than twenty years, the field of computer vision has still not produced any clear understanding of how this complex high-level visual capability is even possible. On the other hand, the human visual system is an existence proof that such a competence is attainable, as demonstrated informally by everyone's daily experience, and more formally, by the results of various psychological studies. Recently RBC, a new human image understanding theory, has been proposed on the basis of some of these psychological results. However, no systematic computational evaluation of its many aspects has yet been reported. Such an evaluation is essential if the theory is ever to play a role in the progress of the computer vision field. The PARVO system discussed in this thesis is a first step towards this goal since its design respects and makes explicit the main assumptions of the proposed theory. It analyses single-view 2D line drawings of 3D objects typical of the ones used in human image understanding studies. It is designed to handle partially occluded objects of different shape and dimension in various spatial orientations and locations in the image plane. The system is shown to successfully compute generic descriptions and then recognize many common man-made objects.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps00c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v8382186</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ang451k215"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The reign of the caliph al-Qādir billāh (381/991-422/1031)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tholib, Udjang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation tries to study the reign of al-Qadir billah, the `Abbasid caliph who assumed power in 381/991. It deals with political, economic and religious aspects of his reign in an attempt to give a balanced description of his achievement. When al-Qadir was appointed caliph the `Abbasid caliphate had already declined politically and economically. The political decline was caused mainly by the soldiers' intervention in politics since the reign of al-Mutawakkil (232/847--247/851) onwards and the take over of the state administration and military control by the amir al-umara. The economic decline resulted from two important factors: first, it was caused by a great decrease in revenues coming from the lands since they were now held by the newly emerging principalities. Second, it was due to the military iqṭas which prevailed during Buwayhid rule and damaged the lands so badly that they could no longer be cultivated. With this political and economic decline al-Qadir was unable to face the encroachment of the Buwayhids. However, with the support of the Ghaznavids and the increasing weakness of the Buwayhids, al-Qadir tried to exert himself. In 390/1000 he sent a letter to the new qaḍi of Jilan asking him to exhort the people to be loyal to the caliph. He rejected Baha' al-Dawla's appointment of the Sharif al-Musawi to the post of the qaḍi al-quḍat in 394/1003. In 401/1010 he ordered Baha' al-Dawla to crush a deviant ally of the `Abbasids, Qirwash b. Muqallad. He criticized Musharrif al-Dawla's initiative to renew the oath of allegiance of the soldiers in 414/1023 without his permission. And during the conflicts in (419/1028) between the soldiers and the Buwayhid amirs, he succeeded in reconciling both parties and prevented them from fighting. Finally, al-Qadir was also able to appoint his successors without first consulting the Buwayhid amirs. Realizing that his temporal power was limited, al-Qadir embarked on the Sunnite restoration and made a serious attempt for this purpose. In 408/1017 he demanded that the Ḥanafite-Mu`tazilite jurisconsults and qaḍis make public renounciation of Mu`tazilism and Rafiḍism and banned any Discussion and instruction of all other allegedly Deviant Doctrines. In 420/1029 he wrote three epistles in which he acknowledged the excellence of Sunnite orthodoxy, condemned Mu`tazilism and declared that those who believed in the createdness of the Qur'`ān as fasiq. All these epistles which were obviously inspired by the ideas of the Ḥanbalite Traditionalists were called al-I`tiqad al-Qadiri (the Profession or Creed of al-Qadir). In maintaining his caliphate, al-Qadir established good relations with scholars of the four schools of law, most significantly with the Malikite al-Baqillani, the Shafi`ite al-Mawardi and the Ḥanbalite Abu Ya`la. Finally, al-Qadir contributed to the literary Development of the theory of the Sunnite imamate.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Little, Donald P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x58x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k215</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Qādir billāh, Caliph, d. 1031</dc:subject><dc:subject>Abbasids</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqv33rz29q"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Three essays on trade, resource and environment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tian, Huilan, 1964-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation comprises three essays under the title "Three Essays on Trade, Resource and Environment". The first essay develops a model of international duopoly involving competition both in prices and in levels of environmental friendliness, and studies the implications of government policies. It is shown that, contrary to the conventional wisdom, a regulatory increase in the minimum required level of environmental friendliness of the imported goods may harm the home firm, and may result in an increase in the volume of imports. It may also have adverse effects on the environment. Whether consumers lose or gain from such a regulatory increase depends on consumption spillover effects. We also show that, under certain conditions, the duopoly's equilibrium choice of levels of environmental friendliness is socially optimal. The second essay investigates the properties of the dynamics of population and resource in a model where the objective function is to maximize the utility level of the least advantaged generation. Unlike in models with a utilitarian objective where the typical outcome is a unique steady state, it is found in our model that there is a continuum of steady states. Which steady state will be approached depends on the initial conditions. We show that for relatively large values of the resource stock, each steady state is conditionally stable in the saddlepoint sense; but for small values of the resource stock, the approach path to a steady state is non-monotone in the state space. Along the approach path to a steady state, the implicit discount rate varies over time. The third essay extends the existing literature on regulation of polluting firms by taking into account the dynamics of investment in pollution abatement capital. It confirms that, under perfect competition, a Pigouvian tax can create the correct incentive for firms to invest and guide firms to achieve the social optimum. This tax path is time consistent. However, when there is a large polluter with price taking behavior, while an efficient and time consistent tax path exists, it is no longer subgame perfect unless the damage cost function is linear in emission. A non-linear taxation rule needs to be designed to achieve the socially optimal outcome. In the case of monopoly, a pair of instruments, an emission tax and a production subsidy, can lead the monopolist to achieve the social optimum. However, if pre-commitment is not possible, it is shown that linear feedback rules cannot achieve the first best outcome.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Long, Ngo Van</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Cairns, Robert D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988m69b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz29q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Environmental economics -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>