<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vk523"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La traduction en mineur : étude de la complicité culturelle et linguistique du Québec et de l'Écosse par le biais de la traduction d'oeuvres dramatiques</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laurence, Anouk</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Guid Sisters, la traduction de la pièce Les Belles-Sœurs de Michel Tremblay en « Scots », dialecte écossais, par Bill Findlay et Martin Bowman, a connu un immense succès critique des deux côtés de l'Atlantique, en plus d'être considérée comme une réussite traductologique.  Sachant que le parcours inverse, la traduction en « joual » de l'adaptation théâtrale du roman écossais Trainspotting, par Martin Bowman et Wajdi Mouawad, s'est aussi révélé probant, on démontre que l'ethnocentrisme patent de ces traductions n'entre pas en conflit avec le décentrement préconisé par certaines approches traductologique.  Les similarités sociopolitiques et linguistiques entre les peuples québécois et écossais, mais aussi leurs différences, permettent un échange traductionnel bilatéral qui  stimule un dialogue  entre ces cultures  minoritaires, intrinsèquement décentrées face aux cultures française ou anglaise dominantes.  Les traducteurs Findlay et Bowman ont encouragé ce dialogue en discutant ouvertement de leur démarche dans  divers articles spécialisés, contribuant à mettre en valeur le rôle du traducteur comme co-auteur des textes traduits.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The translation into Scots of Michel Tremblay's Les Belles-Soeurs under the title The Guid Sisters by translators Bill Findlay and Martin Bowman, met with great critical success on both sides of the Atlantic; it was moreover considered an achievement in translation studies.  It was followed by the translation into « joual » of the stage adaptation of the Scottish novel Trainspotting by Martin Bowman and Wajdi Mouawad, which was also a success.  This thesis demonstrates that the obvious ethnocentrism of these translations does not contradict the decentering theories popular in translation studies.  The sociopolitical and linguistic similarities between the Québécois and the Scottish people, together with their differences, allow for a bilateral translational exchange that stimulates dialogue between these minority cultures, intrinsically decentered with respect to the dominating French and English cultures.  Findlay and Bowman have further contributed to this dialogue by openly discussing their translation strategies in many articles and, in this way, have actively participated in foregrounding the role of translators as co-authors of translated texts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gillian Lane</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x64m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vk523</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Canadian (French)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xm348"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>MicroPET detection of 5-HT1A autoreceptor binding in the nucleus raphe dorsails of the rat using (18F)MPPF as radioligand</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Levesque, Melissa Luce</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La neurotransmission anormale de la sérotonine (5-HT) a été associée à différentes psychopathologies.  Différents mécanismes pourraient être défectueux, comme l'internalisation du récepteur 5-HT1A, situé sur les neurones sérotonergiques du noyau raphé dorsalis (NRD) (autorécepteurs) et les neurones non-sérotonergiques des domaines de projection du NRD comme l'hippocampe (hétérorécepteurs).  Une fois activé, l'autorécepteur 5-HT1A est internalisé, un processus démontré chez le rat par la microscopie électronique.  Pour l'étude courante, nous avons utilisé la microTEP pour mesurer la liaison du [18F]MPPF à l'autorécepteur dans le NRD du rat suivant son internalisation, incitée par la fluoxétine.  Bien que l'internalisation ait été démontrée dans un sous-échantillon de rats en utilisant la microscopie électronique, la microTEP n'a pu détecter la baisse de liaison anticipée de l'autorécepteur dans le NRD suite à l'administration de fluoxetine.  Nous proposons que la résolution de la microTEP, combinée à la taille du NRD du rat, ne permettent pas de détecter l'internalisation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Abnormal serotonin (5-HT) neurotransmission has been associated with different psychopathologies.  Faulty mechanisms that underlie abnormal 5-HT function may include the internalization of the 5-HT1A receptor, located on dorsal raphe nucleus (DRN) serotonin neurons (autoreceptors) and non-serotonin neurons in areas of projection such as hippocampus (heteroreceptors).  Upon activation, the 5-HT1A autoreceptor is internalized, a process demonstrated in rat using immuno-electron microscopy.  In the current study, we assessed whether labeling of [18F]MPPF, a selective 5-HT1A receptor antagonist, could be detected and measured using microPET in the DRN of rat following fluoxetine mediated internalization of the 5-HT1A autoreceptor.  Although internalization was demonstrated in a subsample of rats using immuno-electron microscopy, microPET did not allow for detection of the expected 35% decrease in 5-HT1A autoreceptor labeling in DRN following fluoxetine administration.  We propose that the resolution of the microPET scanner, in combination with the anatomical size of the rat DRN, does not permit detection of internalization.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Laurent Descarries</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Chawki Benkelfat</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763725g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xm348</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225b45x"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'article 29 de la convention de Montréal : clef de voûte de la responsabilité du transporteur aérien international</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chassot, Laurent</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le présent mémoire a pour objet l'étude de l'article 29 de la Convention pour l'unification de certaines règles relatives au transport aérien international, conclue le 28 mai 1999 à Montréal (« Convention de Montréal »). Cette disposition occupe une place centrale dans la responsabilité du transporteur aérien international, que régit le traité précité, en ce qu'elle répartit en la matière les rôles entre droit conventionnel et droit interne. L'article 29 exerce cette fonction d'interface de trois manières : premièrement, il traite du fondement de la responsabilité du transporteur aérien international ; deuxièmement et principalement, il prévoit l'exclusivité du régime mis en place par la Convention à l'égard de tout autre titre de responsabilité ; exception à ce principe d'exclusivité, il opère troisièmement renvoi au droit supplétif applicable pour la détermination de la qualité pour agir et du préjudice réparable. Cette étude se propose d'examiner tour à tour ces trois aspects et les questions qu'ils soulèvent.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The present thesis deals with Article 29 of the Convention for Unification of Certain Rules for International Carriage by Air, signed at Montreal on 28 May 1999 ("Montreal Convention"). Article 29 is a central provision in the scheme of liability of the international air carrier, because it assigns the respective roles of treaty and domestic law in this area. The provision exercises its interface-function between the Convention and the underlying domestic law in three ways: firstly, it deals with the basis of the claims in international carriage by air; secondly and mainly, it sets the principle of exclusivity of the Convention's liability scheme, with regard to any other basis of claim however founded; thirdly, as an exception to the former principle, it reserves the application of domestic law as to the questions of the standing to sue and the definition of recoverable damages under the Convention. The present work will examine in turns these three aspects and the legal issues they raise.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ludwig Weber</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>H. Patrick Glenn</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fh542.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225b45x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad217qp97g"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La phosphorylation des protéines de la famille Elmo par les récepteurs Tyr03, Axl et Mer : un mécanisme potentiel pour l`activation de la GTPase Rac et la promotion de la migration cellulaire</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gauthier, Rosemarie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les protéines de la famille Elmo agissent de concert avec la GEF Dock180 pour médier l'activation de la GTPase Rac. Fonctionnellement, le complexe Elmo/Dock180 est impliqué dans la migration cellulaire, la phagocytose et la fusion cellulaire. Les mécanismes moléculaires permettant l'activation de la signalisation via Elmo/Dock180 sont peu connus. Nous avons démontré que les récepteurs kinases à tyrosine de la famille TAM (Tyro3/Axl/Mer) phosphorylent Elmo. Les kinases TAM régulent la migration cellulaire, la phagocytose et elles sont impliquées dans les processus métastatiques des tumeurs. Nous avons déterminé les tyrosines phosphorylées sur Elmo par les kinases TAM. De plus, nous avons démontré une interaction physique entre les TAM (Tyro3 et Axl), Elmo et Dock180. Notre étude dévoile la relation TAM/Elmo/Dock180 pouvant expliquer, en partie, l'activation de Rac, la réorganisation du cytosquelette, la migration cellulaire et le potentiel invasif des tumeurs associés à la signalisation par les récepteurs TAM.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Elmo proteins act with Dock180 to mediate evolutionarily conserved Rac activation during cell migration, cell-cell fusion and phagocytosis. Molecular events leading to the activation of the Elmo/Dock180 pathway are poorly understood. In our study, we demonstrate that Elmo proteins are substrates of the TAM (Tyro3/Axl/Mer) kinases family. The TAM kinases have been previously described as regulators of cell migration and phagocytosis. They are also believed to be central mediator of cell invasion in various types of tumors. Using mass spectrometry, we identified tyrosine residues phosphorylated on Elmo1 protein by Tyro3. We also uncovered that Elmo1 physically interacts with Tyro3 and Axl, but not with Mer. We demonstrate the formation of a trimolecular complex including the receptor Tyro3, the Elmo1 protein and the GEF Dock180.  This complex may control Rac activation during cell migration and invasion. Our study uncovered a novel pathway that may explain how TAM kinases mediate cell invasion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jean-Francois Cote</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f390s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qp97g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bh64j"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Adapting the existing regime for the contemporary world to achieve global civil aviation safety: a developing country perspective</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ahmad, Md</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La sécurité dans le domaine de l'aviation civile a été et demeure en danger, à cause du défaut de conformité et d'application des normes législatives et réglementaires. Afin de remédier à ces défaillances, des initiatives unilatérales et multilatérales ont été lancées. Ce mémoire traite de ces deux types d'initiatives, et en conclut que bien que ces mécanismes soient utiles, aucun d'entre eux n'est en mesure d'assurer une sécurité totale dans le domaine de l'aviation civile. Par ailleurs, les initiatives unilatérales de « mise sur liste noire » nuisent aux pays en voie de développement, qui sont financièrement et techniquement faibles, à tel point, que ces pays affaiblis, deviennent handicapés de manière permanente, allant jusqu'à remettre en cause la poursuite de leur activité aéronautique, ce qui représente un aléa au niveau mondial. Afin d'adapter le régime actuel au monde contemporain, et d'atteindre un niveau de sécurité total dans le domaine de l'aviation civile, cette thèse réexamine et suggère quelques propositions de réforme qui pourraient être utiles.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Due to lack of compliance with and enforcement of legal and regulatory norms concerning civil aviation safety, the global civil aviation safety has remained and continues to remain at risk. To remedy this deficiency, both multilateral and unilateral initiatives have been launched. This thesis discusses on both of those initiatives and concludes that, although useful mechanism, none of these can ensure complete global civil aviation safety. Most importantly, "Blacklisting" under those unilateral initiatives is harming the financially and technically weak developing countries to such an extent that those feeble countries are becoming permanently disabled even to continue their aviation activities which is hazardous for the entire world. To adapt the existing regime for the contemporary world to achieve global civil aviation safety, this thesis reviews and suggests some useful reform proposals.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Armand De Mestral</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nk92k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bh64j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418n64n"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of novel substrates and inhibitors of protein tyrosine phosphatase 1B</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stuible, Matthew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La protéine tyrosine phosphatase 1B (PTP1B) a été longtemps étudiée en tant que modulateur de signalisation métabolique.  En plus du récepteur de l'insuline, qui est une cible physiologique clée de PTP1B, un grand nombre de recepteurs et de tyrosine-kinases associées aux recepteurs ont été rapportés comme substrats de PTP1B.  Bien que l'hyperactivation de plusieurs de ces kinases est associée au cancer, les souris déficientes en PTP1B ne sont pas prédisposées au développement de tumeurs. En fait, la déficience en PTP1B confère une résistance à certains types de cancers, mais les mécanismes responsables de ceci ainsi que d'autres effets cellulaires de PTP1B ne sont pas bien caractérisés. En étudiant les fonctions de PTP1B au niveau moléculaire, deux phosphoprotéines ont été identifiées comme substrats : la cortactine et STAM2. La cortactine régule la dynamique du cytosquelette d'actine alors que STAM2 est impliqué dans le tri des récepteurs tyrosine kinases (RTKs) ubiquitinés vers la voie de dégradation lysosomale. Pour les deux substrats, la phosphorylation de certains résidus tyrosines était régulée par PTP1B et la mutation de ces sites affectait la réponse cellulaire à différents stimuli. Ces nouveaux substrats de PTP1B peuvent contribuer aux effets connus de déficience en PTP1B notamment la signalisation des RTKs, la migration cellulaire et le développement de tumeurs. PTP1B ainsi que les autres membres de la famille d'enzymes PTP sont considérés comme des cibles prometteuses pour le développement de médicaments. Par contre, les inhibiteurs de PTP les plus efficaces à ce jour sont fortement chargés ce qui limite la perméabilité cellulaire.  Comme approche alternative qui pourrait aider nos études de fonction, un nouvel inhibiteur compétitif et non-chargé de PTP1B a été identifié. Ce composé inhibe efficacement PTP1B dans des essais cellulaires ainsi qu'un sous-ensemble de PTPs in vitro. Une série de dérivés ont été testés et des études de docking moléculaire ont été faites afin de mieux comprendre les groupes fonctionnels importants de cet inhibiteur et d'identifier son site d'action probable. En identifiant la cortactine et  STAM2 comme substrats de PTP1B, cette thèse de recherche a contribuée significativement à notre compréhension d'événements moléculaires régulés par PTP1B.  En outre, la caractérisation d'un inhibiteur fourni un outil biochimique pour étudier la fonction des PTP et peut servir d'échafaudage pour le développement de médicaments.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Protein tyrosine phosphatase 1B (PTP1B) has been studied extensively as a modulator of metabolic signaling. In addition to the insulin receptor, which is a key physiological target of PTP1B, a number of other receptor and receptor-associated tyrosine kinases have also been reported as PTP1B substrates. Although hyperactivation of several of these kinases is associated with cancer, mice lacking PTP1B are not prone to tumorigenesis. In fact, PTP1B deficiency confers resistance to particular types of cancer; however, the mechanisms responsible for this and other cellular effects of PTP1B remain poorly characterized. With the aim of better understanding its functions at a molecular level, two phosphoproteins, cortactin and STAM2, were identified as substrates of PTP1B. Cortactin regulates actin cytoskeletal dynamics in various contexts while STAM2 is involved in sorting ubiquitinated receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs) to the lysosomal degradative pathway following their activation. In both cases, the phosphorylation of specific tyrosine residues was regulated by PTP1B, and mutation of these sites affected the cellular response to different stimuli. These novel targets could each contribute to the known effects of PTP1B deficiency on processes including RTK signaling, cell migration, and tumorigenesis. PTP1B and other members of the PTP enzyme family are considered promising drug targets. However, to date, the most effective in vitro PTP inhibitors have tended to be highly charged, limiting cellular permeability. As an alternative approach that could aid our functional studies, a novel, uncharged, competitive inhibitor of PTP1B was characterized.  This compound effectively inhibited PTP1B in cell-based assays as well as a subset of other PTPs in vitro. A series of derivatives were tested and molecular docking studies were performed in order to understand its important functional groups and identify its likely site of action. Through the identification of cortactin and STAM2 as PTP1B targets, this thesis research has contributed significantly to our understanding of the molecular events regulated by PTP1B.  Furthermore, the characterization of a small-molecule inhibitor provides a biochemical tool for probing PTP function, which could also be used as a scaffold for future drug development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michel Tremblay</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b3987.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418n64n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5h73pw51n"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quality-of-service routing for Voice-over-IP in service overlay networks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Hong</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Voix sur IP (VoIP) est un service dont la popularité crôıt avec le développement de la convergence entre les services dans les réseaux dits de nouvelle génération. Dans cette thèse, nous nous appliquons à améliorer la qualité des services de VoIP grâce au routage au niveau la couche application en utilisant des réseaux dédiés. Dans cette thèse, nous procédons à l'étude des délais de bout en bout du réseau Internet, qui sont le facteur impactant le plus sur la qualité de la VoIP. Nous analysons, modelons et synthétisons des traces de délais de bout en bout, aﬁn de découvrir un potentiel intérêt relatif à leur utilisation dans le cadre du routage au niveau le la couche application utilisant des réseaux dédiés. En nous appuyant sur l'étude des traces de délais de bout en bout, nous montrons que la qualité de la VoIP peut être améliorée et stable en utilisant un couple de routes diverses, au lieu d'une seule route. Nous donc proposon un centre de fusion de données qui utilise notre approche pour trouver le meilleur couple de routes diverses. Cette méthode optimise le routage source conjointement avec adaptation play-out au niveau du récepteur. Il faut transmettre des délais des-dites distributions de tous les liens au niveau le la couche application pour estimer des distributions de tous les couples de routes possibles. Nous proposons de transmettre uniquement les paramètres du modèle de la distribution des délais, aﬁn de réduire des côuts de communication. Nous prouvons que cette méthode peut trouver le meilleur couple de routes à une faible erreur. Comme la technique centralisée requiert une grande puissance de calcul, nous proposons une solution de routage divers extensible en ligne, qui utilise l'apprentissage distribué au- tomata activement sonde des délais de bout en bout et détermine la meilleure paire de diverses voies de VoIP basé sur l'état de l'apprentissage d'automates. Nous avons dé- montré l'extensibilité et l'optimalité de cette approche par les simulations, et démontré l'optimalité de l'approche par l'utilisation de la méthode de convergence faible de Kushner. Nous montrons que la qualité de la VoIP est ameliorée, passant d'une qualité inacceptable à une qualité acceptable. De plus, nous proposons une méthode pour détecter les défaillances du lien et de sa récupération sur la base de paramètres de l'apprentissage d'automates, qui permettent une réduction considérable du temps de récupération à la suite de la défaillance d'un lien. En somme, cette thèse démontre que la proposition de la diversité de routage centralisé approche est eﬃcace pour améliorer la qualité de la VoIP en termes de R-facteur pour les petits réseaux de la couche application, et que l'apprentissage de un couple de routes diverses avec des méthodes de détection de défaillance oﬀre un extensible, eﬃcace et robuste solution pour services de VoIP grâce au grands réseaux de la couche application.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Voice-over-IP (VoIP) becomes more and more popular with the development of service convergence in the next generation network. This thesis focuses on improving VoIP quality with application-layer routing in service overlay networks. Internet end-to-end delay is one of the most important impairments on VoIP quality. We therefore analyze, model and simulate it to better understand it and thus to discover potential advantages of routing in service overlay networks. Based on the investigation of the Internet end-to-end delay, we find that VoIP quality on a pair of diverse paths is better and more stable than that on a single path. We therefore propose a novel centralized data fusion approach to search for the best pair of diverse paths. This method jointly optimizes source routing with adaptive play-out scheduling at the receiver. It requires transmitting the delay distributions of all the overlay links for estimating the delay distributions of diverse paths. We propose to transmit only the model parameters of the link delay distributions to reduce the communication overhead. It is shown that the best pair of diverse paths can be estimated with a small error. Nonetheless, the centralized approach is computationally expensive. We therefore propose an online diverse routing method, which uses distributed learning automata to actively probe path delays and to determine the best pair of diverse paths for VoIP based on the state of the learning automata. We have demonstrated the scalability and the optimality of the approach by simulations, and proven the optimality of the approach using Kushner's weak convergence method. VoIP quality has been shown to improve from unsatisfactory levels to satisfactory levels. In addition, we propose a method to detect and recover from link failures based on the state of the learning automata. Considerable improvement in link failure recovery time has been achieved. In sum, this work demonstrates that the proposed centralized diverse routing approach is effective to improve VoIP quality in terms of R-factor for small overlay networks, and that the proposed distributive diverse routing approach together with the link failure detection scheme provides a scalable, effective and robust solution to VoIP routing for large overlay networks.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael Rabbat</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Lorne Mason</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45q936t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73pw51n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9z9030362"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pitch discrimination and melodic memory in children with autism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stanutz, Sandy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Objectif: Les recherches actuelles démontrent que les personnes autistiques discernent mieux la hauteur des sons et ont une meilleure mémoire des sons individuels. La présente étude vise à étendre la recherche aux enfants d'âge scolaire en comparant, chez les enfants autistiques par rapport aux enfants qui se développent normalement, le discernement de la hauteur des sons et la mémoire mélodique. Méthodologie:  Vingt-cinq enfants autistiques ainsi que 25 enfants ayant un développement normal, tous âgés de 8 à 12 ans, ont participé à l'étude. Placés dans deux contextes différents, les enfants ont effectué des tâches faisant appel à leur capacité de discerner la hauteur des sons. Dans le premier contexte, les enfants devaient indiquer si deux sons étaient semblables ou différents lorsque les deux sons étaient les mêmes ou lorsque l'un d'eux avait été modifié pour être plus aigu ou plus bas de 25, 35, ou 45-cents. Dans l'autre contexte, les enfants devaient dire si deux sons mélodies étaient les memes ou si elles étaient différentes lorsque chacune des melodies étaient la mêmes ou si elles étaient différentes lorsque la sensible de chacune des melodies étaient soit la même, soit qu'elle avait été modifiée pour être plus aigue ou plus basse de 25, 35, ou 45-cents. En outre, les enfants devaient aussi se remémorer des mélodies qui, la semaine précédente, avaient été associées à des images d'animaux au cours d'une tâche de familiarsation. Toutes les tâches accomplies par les enfants au cours de l'étude ont été effectuées sur ordinateur. Résultats: Les enfants autistiques ont mieux réussis que les enfants ayant un développement normal et, cela, dans les deux contextes de discernment de la hauteur des sons. Ils ont aussi été supérieurs lorsqu'il a fallu se remémorer des melodies une semaine après qu'elles eurent été associés à des images d'animaux. Conclusions: Les enfants autistiques ont démontré que leur jugement de la hauteur des sons et et leur mémoire mélodique étaient meilleurs que ceux des enfants ayant un développement normal. Ces habiletés pourraient être innées étant donné que la majorité des participants á l'étude avaient une formation musicale limitée. Par ailleurs, ces habiletés pourraient être le signe d'un processus développemental different des attributs auditifs des enfants autistiques, ces différences développementales des perceptions auditives pouvent comporter une capacité d'adaptation à certains contextes musicaux.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Objective: The current research indicates that those with autism have an excellent memory for pitch. Persons with autism have better pitch discrimination and memory for individual notes. The purpose of this study was extend this research in school aged children, comparing pitch discrimination and melodic memory of children with autism to that of typically developing children. Method: Twenty-five children with autism between the ages of 8-12 and 25 typically developing children within the same age range participated in the study. Children completed pitch discrimination tasks in two differing contexts. In one context, children were asked to indicate whether two pitches were the same or different when the two pitches were either the same or one note of the pair had been altered so that it was 25, 35, or 45-cents sharp or flat. In the other context, children were asked to discriminate whether two melodies were the same or different when the leading tone of each melody was either the same or had been altered so that it was 25, 35, or 45-cents sharp or flat. In addition, children were also asked to recall melodies one week after they were paired with pictures during a familiarization task. All the tasks in the study were formatted on computer. Results: Children with autism outperformed typically developing children in both pitch discrimination contexts. Children with autism were superior to typically developing children when remembering melodies one week after they had been paired with animal pictures. Conclusion: Children with autism demonstrated better pitch discrimination and melodic memory than typically developing children. These abilities may be genetic, as the majority of the participants in the study had limited music training. Alternatively, these abilities could be reflective of a different developmental process in the auditory modality of children with autism whereby developmental differences in auditory perceptions may be adaptive in some musical contexts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Joel Wapnick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429957v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9030362</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap2676w04x"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Measuring mitotic spindle dynamics in budding yeast</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Plumb, Kemp</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La régulation du cycle cellulaire et la prolifération  de générations viables requièrent à la fois la reproductibilité et la coordination des différents processus complexes en jeu dans un environnement toutefois dominé par l'agitation thermique. Un exemple essentiel est l'assemblage et la migration du fuseau mitotique qui doivent avoir lieu correctement avant même la ségrégation des chromosomes. Le fuseau mitotique est une structure transitoire composée de deux pôles séparés par des filaments de protéines  appelés les microtubules, auxquelles  est rattaché le matériel génétique de la cellule. Le fuseau mitotique est notamment impliqué dans l'alignement des chromosomes, puis leur ségrégation vers des pôles opposés de la cellule ; d'où la nécessité d'un positionnement spatial précis et temporellement coordonné  du fuseau mitotique pour assurer la division correcte du matériel génétique entre les cellules mère et fille. Dans ce mémoire, je décrirai les techniques de microscopie confocale par fluorescence ainsi que les algorithmes automatisés d'analyse d'image, que j'ai mis en oeuvre pour observer et analyser la dynamique spatiale en temps réel du fuseau mitotique chez la levure  bourgeonnante. Les programmes développés permettent de localiser dans l'espace tridimensionnel des structures subcellulaires et de détecter leurs déplacements au cours du temps. Le marquage par protéines fluorescentes des pôles du fuseau mitotique et de la membrane cellulaire a permis de quantifier la dynamique du fuseau mitotique dans un système de coordonnées pertinent pour la division cellulaire. Je décrirai des simulations numériques de signaux fluorescents de ces structures subcellulaires qui m'ont permis de caractériser la fiabilité et de quantifier la précision des programmes d'analyse. Je terminerai ce mémoire par la description d'un dispositif microfluidique permettant à la fois la culture de cellules et la caractérisation de leur dynamique à l'échelle individuelle, et ce  sur de longues échelles de temps. Les outils développés au cours de cette thèse et présentés dans ce mémoire offrent la possibilité d'analyses quantitatives nouvelles des processus hors équilibre en jeu chez les cellules vivantes en général.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In order to carry out its life cycle and produce viable progeny through cell division, a cell must successfully coordinate and execute a number of complex processes with high fidelity, in an environment dominated by thermal noise. One important example of such a process is the assembly and positioning of the mitotic spindle prior to chromosome segregation. The mitotic spindle is a modular structure composed of two spindle pole bodies, separated in space and spanned by filamentous proteins called microtubules, along which the genetic material of the cell is held. The spindle is responsible for alignment and subsequent segregation of chromosomes into two equal parts; proper spindle positioning and timing ensure that genetic material is appropriately divided amongst mother and daughter cells. In this thesis, I describe fluorescence confocal microscopy and automated image analysis algorithms, which I have used to observe and analyze the real space dynamics of the mitotic spindle in budding yeast. The software can locate structures in three spatial dimensions and track their movement in time. By selecting fluorescent proteins which specifically label the spindle poles and cell periphery, mitotic spindle dynamics have been measured in a coordinate system relevant to the cell division. I describe how I have characterised the accuracy and precision of the algorithms by simulating fluorescence data for both spindle poles and the budding yeast cell surface. In this thesis I also describe the construction of a microfluidic apparatus that allows for the measurement of long time-scale dynamics of individual cells and the development of a cell population. The tools developed in this thesis work will facilitate in-depth quantitative analysis of the non-equilibrium processes in living cells.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maria Kilfoil</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25x906m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676w04x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr171x666"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>What is "good" quality oral French? language attitudes towards "differently" accented French in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Piechowiak, Alicia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The following thesis used a modified version of the matched guise technique to investigate French second language and French Immersion teachers‟ attitudes towards different French accented speakers. A total of thirty-four raters were asked to judge equally competent speech samples derived from five accented speakers: European, Québécois, Lebanese, Haitian and Anglophone. Raters judged the speakers using a four point Likert scale and providing qualitative data in the form of comments on 6 oral quality criterion derived from the Conseil Supérieur de la Langue Française and 3 prestige criterion derived from previous research (Giles, 1974; Labov, 1966; Lambert et al., 1960). The mixed method evaluations indicate that accent and the affiliated socially constructed stereotypes play a strong role in how different accented speakers are perceived in terms of oral capacities and prestige despite their equally competent performances. Likewise the data shows evidence that the formerly stigmatized reputation of the Québécois accented speaker has shifted towards a population that may be described as immigrants from some of the former French colonies or non-native speakers. Key words: Language attitudes, Quality language, Matched guise technique, French Language.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le présent mémoire se propose d‟analyser les différentes attitudes linguistiques que peuvent avoir des professeurs de français de langue seconde et de français en immersion à l‟égard d‟orateurs dotés d‟un accent différencié en français. Pour ce faire, et conformément à la « matched guise technique » mise initialement au point par Lambert (1960), un échantillon composé de 34 évaluateurs s‟est vu demandé d‟évaluer -à partir d‟enregistrements radiophoniques- la prestation orale de cinq orateurs de compétences linguistiques en tous points égales si ce n‟est la présence d‟accents représentatifs de leurs origines respectives à savoir: L‟Europe, le Québec, le Liban, Haïti et le Canada anglophone. L‟évaluation de la performance des orateurs s‟est effectuée au moyen d‟une grille de Likert en quatre points tandis que des données qualitatives complémentaires ont pu être recueillies sous la forme de commentaires de six critères de qualité orale définis par le Conseil Supérieur de la Langue Française et trois critères tirés de recherches précédentes (Labov, 1966 ; Lambert et al., 1960). Cette méthode mixte d‟évaluation suggère que l‟accent et plus particulièrement les stéréotypes qui lui sont associés, a une très forte influence sur les façons dont sont perçus des orateurs dotés d‟un accent différencié tant sur le plan de la qualité orale qu‟au niveau du prestige alors que leur compétence linguistique est pourtant équivalente. Si les résultats obtenus dans le cadre de cette étude semblent suggérer une revalorisation de l‟accent « Québecois », ceux-ci nous indiquent en revanche une détérioration de la perception de la compétence linguistique à l‟égard d‟une population que l‟on pourrait qualifier « d‟immigrants ». Mots clés: Attitudes linguistiques, Qualité de la langue, "Matched guise technique", Langue Française.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carolyn E. Turner</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mekhala Sarkar</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mv58g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171x666</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Bilingual and Multicultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483j780"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of Coxsackie and Adenovirus receptor in the central nervous system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zheng, Luyu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Coxsackie and adenovirus receptor (CAR), a newly described regulator of neurite outgrowth in the developing central nervous system (CNS), is an adhesion molecule of the immunoglobulin superfamily. CAR is highly expressed in the developing brain, but its level is down-regulated in adult nervous system. Recently, CAR has been demonstrated to mediate homophilic cell-cell adhesion in tumor cell-lines and to be a transmembrane component of the tight junction in epithelial cells. We observed that neurons grown in the presence of soluble CAR have longer neurites compared to BSA control. Furthermore, the presence of soluble CAR was able to overcome the inhibitory effect of cytokines (TNFα) and restore the neurite length to control level. In addition, using hippocampal neuron cultures prepared from CAR embryos in which exon 2 of CAR is flanked by LoxP sites ("CAR-flox"), and infected with the adenovirus AdV-CRE-GFP or control vector (AdV-BFP), we demonstrated that both neuron survival and neurite length were affected by knockown of CAR expression. It has been shown that general knockout of CAR results in embryonic lethality; by breeding CAR-floxed mice (a generous gift of Jeffrey Bergelson, U. Pennsylvania) to synapsin-1-Cre transgenic mice we have developed conditional knockout mice in which CAR is deleted specifically in the nervous system. Here, we report some morphological alterations observed in animals lacking CAR in the CNS. The results of this study will further our understanding of the role CAR plays in developmental processes in the brain.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le récepteur du coxsackievirus et de l'adénovirus (CAR) est une molécule d'adhérence de la famille immunoglobuline. CAR est exprimée dans le cerveau avant la naissance, mais le niveau est réduit dans le cerveau adulte. Récemment, il a été montré que CAR est nécéssaire pour l'adhérence entre les cellules tumorales, et qu'il est aussi un composant de la jonction transmembranaire des cellules épithéliales. Nous avons observé que les neurones mis en culture en présence d'une forme soluble de CAR dévelopent des prologements cellulaires plus longs comparés aux neurones qui sont en présence de BSA. En outre, la présence de la forme soluble de CAR neutralise l'effet inhibiteur du cytokine TNFα.  En utilisant des neurones hippocampiques préparé à partir d'embryons CAR dans lequel l'exon 2 de CAR est flanqué de sites loxP (CARFLOX), et infecté par l'adénovirus AdV-CRE-GFP ou vecteur contrôle (AdV-BFP), nous avons démontré que la survie des neurones et la longueur des neurites ont été affectés par la diminution de l'expresssion de CAR. Nouse avons aussi croisé les CARFLOX avec des souris transgéniques exprimant la recombinase Cre sous le contrôle du promoteur de la synapsine I afin de produire des souris dans lesquelles l'expression de CAR serait en baisse spécifiquement dans le système nerveux central. Nous rapportons ici quelques altérations morphologiques observées chez ces animaux. Les résultats de cette étude permettra d'approfondir notre compréhension du rôle que CAR joue dans les processus de développement du cerveau. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Josephine Nalbantoglu</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb4948977.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483j780</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pn31t"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gaston Miron: posture et postérité d'un poète</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Buchinger, Julie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'écrivain n'est pas seulement un être fait de chair et d'os; il est également, depuis le romantisme, un personnage public qui arrive avec ses fictions, ses costumes, ses poses et ses tics, un « look », une « posture » (Alain Viala, Jérôme Meizoz). Ce mémoire de maîtrise, qui porte sur Gaston Miron, voudrait en faire la démonstration en s'attachant au personnage singulier que forgèrent le poète et la critique entre 1953 (année du lancement de Deux Sangs aux éditions de l'Hexagone) et 2008 (année de la parution de l'album musical Douze hommes rapaillés chantent Gaston Miron). C'est à comprendre la construction de la posture de Miron et l'édification de sa légende que ce travail souhaite contribuer. Nous chercherons à montrer comment son attitude a façonné sa personnalité littéraire, son identité auctoriale, et a fondé sa spécificité au sein du monde littéraire québécois. La plupart des études portant sur la posture d'auteur ont pour objet d'analyse un corpus autobiographique. Nous chercherons à élargir ce corpus en étudiant également des poèmes de Miron, des articles de journaux et des hommages rendus au poète, un essai, un documentaire, ainsi qu'un album comprenant des poèmes mironiens mis en chanson. Ces documents nous permettront d'étudier certains aspects encore à peu près ignorés des travaux sur la posture d'auteur, notamment le rôle que jouent les pairs, les médias et les commentateurs de l'oeuvre mironienne dans la fabrication de sa posture, et la prise en charge par cette communauté de la légende mironienne après sa mort.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Not only is the writer a human being made of flesh and blood, he is also, since Romantism, a public character with his own fictions, costumes, poses and mannerism, his own looks and posture. This is what this Master's thesis, which deals with Gaston Miron, aims to demonstrate by studying the singular character constructed by the poet and critics alike between 1953 (year of Miron's first publication, Deux sangs, published by l'Hexagone) and 2008 (year of publication of the musical album Douze homes rapaillés chantent Gaston Miron). This study will contribute to the understanding of the construction of his posture and of the edification of his legend. We will try to show how his attitude shaped his literary personality, his writer's identity and participated in creating his specificity within Quebec's literary society. Most of the studies about the writer's posture analyze autobiographical texts. We will broaden such a corpus by also studying Miron's poems, numerous articles and tributes to the poet, an essay, a documentary, as well as a musical album which features some of Miron's poems sung by various artists. These documents will enable us to study certain aspects that have so far not been taken into account in the studies regarding the author's posture, in particular the role played by peers, media and commentators of Miron's work in the construction of his posture, and the appropriation of Miron's legend after his death by this same community.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pascal Brissette</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8381023.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn31t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Canadian (French)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924c18m"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interactions among micronutrient status, infection, and growth in Panamanian preschool children</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Irwin Kristmanson, Dorian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In developing countries, the coexistence of malnutrition and intestinal parasitism contributes to growth faltering. Interrelationships among malnutrition, infection, and growth were explored in 328 indigenous Panamanian preschool children. Dietary and infection predictors of height-for-age z-score (HAZ) were identified in the dry and rainy seasons, the impact of stunting and vitamin A deficiency (VAD, serum retinol ≤0.70umol/L) on Ascaris reinfection was assessed, and associations between growth, infection, serum vitamin D and cytokines were explored. Ascaris infection intensity did not predict HAZ, but diarrhea negatively predicted vitamin A status and HAZ. Stunted children (HAZ &lt; -2 SD) consumed more sugar and fiber, less dairy, vitamin B12, and fat, and, if vitamin A-deficient, were more susceptible to Ascaris reinfection. VAD was prevalent (&gt;80%) despite supplementation, and 27% had insufficient serum vitamin D. Both were associated with elevated pro-inflammatory cytokines. Nutritional status, stunting, and reinfection rates may be improved in this population through comprehensive interventions that focus on diet quality, food security, and reducing diarrheal disease, particularly during the rainy season when food insecurity increases.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans les pays en voie de développement, la coexistence de la malnutrition et du parasitisme intestinal mène souvent à des retards de croissance. Une étude a été menée auprès de 328 enfants autochtones panaméens d'âge préscolaire afin d'examiner  l'influence des retards de croissance et des carences en vitamine A sur la réinfection parasitaire d'Ascaris, ainsi que la relation entre la croissance linéaire des enfants et les concentrations sérique en cytokines, vitamines A et D. Nous avons aussi déterminé les prédicteurs de retards de croissance pendant la saison sèche et la saison des pluies. La sécurité alimentaire diminue pendant la saison des pluies, et la diarrhée est associée au manque de vitamine A et aux retards de croissance linéaire. Les enfants de petite taille consomment  plus de sucre et de fibres, moins de produits laitiers, de vitamine B12, et de lipides. Les enfants ayant une carence en vitamine A sont plus susceptibles d'être réinfectés par le parasite Ascaris. Les carences en vitamine A sont répandues (&gt;80%) en dépit de la supplémentation, et 27% ont un niveau sanguin de vitamine D insuffisant. Des approches systémiques, qui incluent un régime de qualité, assurent la sécurité alimentaire et diminuent l'incidence des épisodes de diarrhée, surtout pendant la saison des pluies, pourraient s'avérer plus efficaces pour améliorer la croissance et les carences nutritionnelles chez les enfants de cette population que de simples interventions de supplémentation en micronutriments.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marilyn Scott</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Kristine G. Koski</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m700k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c18m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avd66w0335"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electric signals and species recognition in gymnotiform fish</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fugère, Vincent</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les gymnotes sont des poisons faiblement électriques d'Amérique du Sud utilisant leur électro-sens à des fins de navigation, d'approvisionnement et de communication. Les décharges électriques varient énormément d'une espèce à l'autre et pourrait ainsi être utilisées pour la reconnaissance des espèces. Nous avons quantifié la décharge de plusieurs espèces et avons utilisé des analyses discriminantes afin de vérifier si les décharges sont spécifiques aux espèces selon différents paramètres. La forme de la décharge semble plus spécifique que la fréquence de celle-ci. Pourtant, en réalisant des expériences comportementales avec le gymnote Apteronotus leptorhynchus et des stimuli de différentes espèces, nous avons découvert que le comportement des sujets varie beaucoup en fonction de la fréquence du stimulus alors que, contrairement à ce que nous avions prédis, la forme de la décharge du stimulus n'eut aucun impact mesurable sur les comportements moteurs ou communicatifs des sujets.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Gymnotiformes are South American weakly electric fish that produce weak electric organ discharges (EOD) for orientation, foraging and communication purposes. Because EOD properties vary widely across species, electric signals could serve a species recognition function. We quantified the electric signals of various species and used discriminant function analyses to verify whether these signals are species-specific based on different signal parameters. We found that the EOD waveform was a more specific cue than EOD frequency. Using Apteronotus leptorhynchus as a focal species, we complemented these measurements with playback experiments using stimuli of different species (varying in frequency, waveform, or both). In both a free-swimming experiment and a communication assay with restrained fish, we found that the subjects' behaviour was strongly influenced by the frequency of the stimuli but, opposite to what we predicted, the waveform of the stimuli had no measurable effect on either communication or locomotor behaviors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rudiger Krahe</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rp15j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w0335</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Zoology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap5547r791"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dissociation between behavioural and biochemical measures of mu and delta opioid receptors in rat central nervous system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pradhan, Amynah Amir Ali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The opioid receptor family is comprised of three members: mu,  delta and kappa, all of which are G protein coupled receptors, primarily acting  through Galphai/o subunits. Clinically, mu opioid receptor (MOR) agonists are used  in the treatment of moderate to severe pain. delta opioid receptor (DOR) agonists  are being developed as alternative analgesics, since stimulation of this receptor  results in fewer adverse side effects. Characterization of behaviourally relevant mu  and delta opioid receptors, as well as interactions between them, will provide a  better understanding of opioid agonist-induced analgesia. Although the behavioural knockdown after antisense targeting of  MOR has been well characterized, few studies have examined the corresponding in  vitro changes. Thus, the first aim of this thesis was to determine the  neuroanatomical extent of MOR knockdown after pretreatment with peptide nucleic acid  antisense in rats. Antisense pretreatment completely inhibited antinociception by  the mu agonist DAMGO, but produced no detectable ex vivo changes in brain or spinal  MOR labelling or functional responses. This study suggests that there may be a  small, critical population of MORs that mediate antinociceptive responses to  agonist. The second aim of this thesis was to compare the CNS  distribution of functional DOR with radioligand binding. DOR labelling was  determined autoradiographically using an agonist, ([125I]deltorphin II) and an  antagonist ([ 125I]AR-M100613) radioligand. In adjacent tissue sections, functional  DORs were detected using deltorphin II-induced [35S]GTPgammaS binding. Overall,  radioligand binding did not strongly predict the magnitude of [35S]GTPgammaS  responses, and this weak association is possibly explained by a paucity of DORs on  the cell surface and/or heterogeneity in G protein receptor coupling. The highest  [35S]GTPgammaS responses were found in the basal ganglia, while areas involved with  pain perception (spinal cord, brain stem, and periaqueductal grey) possessed low  [35S]GTPgammaS responses. The low deltorphin II-induced [35S]GTPgammaS binding in  pain-related areas could explain the moderate degree of antinociception produced by  delta agonists relative to their mu counterparts. Thus, the third aim of this thesis  was to investigate two pharmacological treatments (short- and long-term morphine  pretreatment) that are reported to enhance behavioural responses to delta agonists.  As previously observed by others, short-term exposure to morphine resulted in  sensitization to spinally administered delta agonists. In contrast, long-term  morphine pretreatment resulted in profound tolerance to the antinociceptive and  locomotor stimulant effects of deltorphin II. After chronic morphine pretreatment,  there was no detectable change in DOR labelling or [35S]GTPgammaS responses in the  brain or spinal cord, suggesting that changes in downstream regulators may be  responsible for this tolerance.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dg174.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547r791</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqb98mf97b"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comparative genetic study of tuberculosis and asthma susceptibility</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poon, Audrey Ho Yee</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The worldwide rates of asthma have been increasing in the past  twenty years, coinciding with a decreasing prevalence of tuberculosis in the major  asthma endemic regions. The hygiene hypothesis proposes that in countries with  better hygiene, reduced exposure to pathogens is responsible for the rising  prevalence of allergic diseases. Mycobacterium tuberculosis , the cause of  tuberculosis (TB), is thought to be a critical effector of the hygiene hypothesis  since it can skew the immune system away from developing into an atopy associated  immune profile. Hence, absence of exposure to M. tuberculosis might remove  suppression of asthma development. Based on the hygiene hypothesis, we reasoned that genetic  factors that predispose to TB should be protective for asthma/atopy and vice versa.  Consequently, we tested genetic variants for (1) asthma risk based on known genetic  effects in TB susceptibility, and (2) TB risk based on known genetic effects in  asthma susceptibility. To identify genetic variants for asthma risk, we tested for  nonrandom transmission of genetic variants of the Vitamin D Receptor (VDR) and the  Natural Resistance Macrophage Protein 1 (NRAMP1) genes, two known TB susceptibility  genes, in an asthma family-based cohort of French Canadian. To identify genetic  variants for TB risk, we tested for distribution differences of genetic variants of  several asthma associated genes: interleukin 4 (IL-4), IL-4 Receptor A (IL4RA),  tumour necrosis factor A (TNFA ), lymphotoxin A (LTA) and VDR in TB cases and non-TB  controls recruited in Mexico. Only VDR variants showed a risk modulating effect and  where analyzed in more detail in the present thesis. In a North-Eastern Quebec asthma family-based cohort, of the 12  VDR variants tested 6 genetic variants located between intron 2 and 3' UTR we found  to be strongly associated with asthma (0.0005 &lt; p &lt; 0.01) under an  additive model. Haplotype specific genetic effects were also observed for asthma  (0.0004 &lt; p &lt; 0.01). By contrast, no variants of the NRAMP1 gene were  observed to be associated with asthma in this French Canadian asthma cohort. In the  final set of experiments, I tested asthma associated genes for their impact on risk  of TB disease. In a Mexican case-control study, 14 VDR variants tested, we observed  2 genetic variants at the 5' end of the gene to be associated (p &lt; 0.05) with  either susceptibility to TB, M. tuberculosis infection or disease progression. No  associations were observed between genetic variants of IL4RA, TNFA and LTA, and TB  or TB related phenotypes. These findings clearly identified VDR as asthma and TB  susceptibility gene. However, since the genetic variants associated with asthma  differ from those associated with TB it remains unclear how these variants influence  the immune system to promote asthma but not TB, and vice versa. Although TB has been  proposed as a suppressing force for asthma, other than VDR, we could not detect any  genetic effect of TB susceptibility genes in the asthma study, nor effects of asthma  susceptibility genes in the TB study. We interpret these findings as evidence  against counter-selection of asthma and TB susceptibility gene  variants.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676w081.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mf97b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386j66z"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The mechanical behaviour of chemically-treated PVC geosynthetic membranes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yu, Qifeng, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Geosynthetics that are usually made of Poly(vinyl) Chloride  (PVC) are used as components of engineered barriers in landfill applications. As a  component of an engineered barrier scheme, it is used to mitigate the migration of  hazardous and toxic mixtures of chemicals that can diffuse through the clay layer in  the engineered barrier. The integrity of the geosynthetic layers that are in  frequent contact with these chemicals is therefore of interest to the overall waste  containment strategy. This thesis conducts a coordinated investigation that will  allow the characterization of the deformability properties of geosynthetic  materials, subjected to various levels of exposure to ethanol. Chemical alteration  can take place by modifications to the fillers or plasticizers that contribute to  both strength and ductility of the geosynthetics. The uniaxial tests conducted on a  chemically-treated PVC geosynthetics, exposed to ethanol, point to the reduction in  flexibility or embrittlement of the material. The results of the experiments  conducted in connection with this research program indicate that, in its natural  condition, the PVC geosynthetic is capable of undergoing moderately large strains,  the constitutive behaviour of which can be modelled through the phenomenological  hyperelastic theories by appealing to a strain energy function of the Mooney-Rivlin  form. Unlike natural rubber at moderately large strains, which is virtually void of  irreversible phenomena and strain-rate effects, the PVC geosynthetic exhibits a  strong rate-dependency and irreversible effects; furthermore, the irreversible  strains themselves can be within the realm of moderately large strains. The  chemically-treated PVC geosynthetic, however, displays a dominant yield behaviour  after chemical exposure: the material completely loses its large-strain  deformability characteristics after prolonged chemical exposure. X-ray fluorescence  techniques point to the loss of the plasticizer a In general, the constitutive model development for both the  untreated and chemically-treated PVC results in correlations of satisfactory quality  that permits the use of the models in the study of boundary value problems involving  the indentation of PVC geosynthetic membranes. It serves as a useful method for  calibrating the constitutive responses of the PVC geosynthetic determined from  conventional uniaxial testing and provides a useful assessment of the out-of-plane  deformability of PVC geosynthetic as a result of the loss of flexibility due to  chemical exposure. The success of reasonable predictions of the experimental  response by computational modelling then allows a further simulation of the  situations that involve localized loading of PVC geosynthetics during either  placement and construction or during the operation of the landfill, particularly in  situations susceptible to chemical exposure.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wd17w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386j66z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vk55x"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Telomere maintenance in human cells : implications in cancer and ageing diseases</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cerone, Maria Antonietta</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Telomeres are protective structures at the end of eukaryotic  chromosomes essential for indefinite cell proliferation. Their disruption causes  activation of DNA repair pathways, growth arrest and/or cell death. In normal cells  telomere shortening during cell division has been proposed to act as a tumor  suppressor mechanism to block the proliferation of cells at risk of undergoing  malignant transformation. Overcoming this proliferative block by activating a  mechanism to maintain telomeres is a necessary requirement for unlimited  proliferation and tumor progression. Human cells have two mechanisms for telomere  maintenance: a more common one based on telomerase and a rarer one based on  recombination called ALT. Here we report the isolation of an immortal human cell line that  maintains short telomeres in the absence of biologically active telomerase and key  features of active ALT. Our results suggest that the mechanisms of telomere  maintenance in human cells may be more diverse than previously thought and have  important implications for the development of anti-cancer strategies based on the  inhibition of telomere maintenance. Due to widespread distribution of telomerase in human tumors and  its absence in most normal cells, telomerase is the main target of these anti-cancer  strategies. However, targeting telomerase per se or in combination with anti-cancer  drugs is not sufficient to trigger rapid cell death of tumor cells. On the other  hand, disturbances in telomere capping do not require telomere shortening to induce  growth arrest and may act more quickly. Our goal was to investigate the feasibility  of a new approach based on the combination of telomere destabilization and  chemotherapeutic drugs. Our results show that interfering with telomere maintenance  enhances the susceptibility of human tumor cells to anti-cancer drugs independently  of their telomere lengths and mechanisms to maintain them. Finally, given the involvement of telomeres in maintaining  genomic stability, we investigated the mechanism by which mutations in the  telomerase RNA subunit contribute to autosomal dominant dyskeratosis congenita, a  premature ageing disease associated with mutations in the telomerase holoenzyme. Our  data strongly indicate that the clinical manifestations of this disease may be  caused by telomere shortening due to haploinsufficiency of telomerase activity and  provide a direct correlation between disturbances in telomere length maintenance and  human disease.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z5752.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vk55x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290992q"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The encyclopedic imagination in the Canadian artist figure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Purdham, Medrie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The "encyclopedic imagination" describes an artist's  conviction that a work of art must be expansive and inclusive to a point of total  embodiment. The artist (or dramatized artist figure) implies that the work of art  must give a total account not only of the subjective life of the artist but of the  reality to which the representing self responds. The focus of this study is not on  any work's encyclopedic achievement (for the artist's inclusive ideal always remains  well outside the actual capacity of the work), but on the relationship of the ideal  of aesthetic all-inclusiveness to a problematic ideal of encompassing selfhood for  the representing personality. Following an introduction that establishes modern and postmodern  conceptions of the notion of aesthetic totality, this dissertation describes, in six  Canadian works, the (untenable) radicalization of the self through the  "encyclopedic" ideal. Chapter one considers Ernest Buckler's The Mountain  and the Valley (1952) and notes that the protagonist's drive towards total  representation is costly to his sense of authentic temporality. Chapter two  identifies "total embodiment" as the governing poetic principle of P. K.  Page's The Hidden Room (poems c.1942-1997), and suggests the relation of this ideal  to Page's apparent creative crisis. Chapter three examines the ethics of  all-inclusive representation in Leonard Cohen's Beautiful Losers (1966) and argues  that the novel's vision of the world incorporated into a single body is a reflection  of both the totalitarian politic of One Man and of apocalyptic-beatific "total  identity." Chapter four looks at Margaret Atwood's Cat's Eye (1988) in terms of  the trope of the "perverse museum" in Atwood's oeuvre. The novel's  treatment of representation as exhibition figures identity as a matter of insatiable  demonstration. Chapter five considers the "life-long" poems of Louis Dudek  (Continuation c.1971-2001) and bpNichol (The Martyrology 1967-1988) as particularly  marked cases of works that must continue until they have enfolded a coherent  world-view into an all-encompassing subjectivity. Each chapter stresses the counterintuitive quality of the  "encyclopedic" ideal and demonstrates that a total yet coherent  representation of the world seems inversely proportional to a coherent yet total  representation of the self.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613mz01q.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290992q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Canadian literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Imagination</dc:subject><dc:subject>Artists -- Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fp395"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Melting and crystallization behavior of linear low-density polyethylene</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Feng, Lijun, 1966-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The melting and crystallization behavior of linear low-density  polyethylene (LLDPE) is of great scientific and industrial importance. It depends  strongly on polymer molecular structural characteristics and processing conditions,  and determines polymer application properties. In this work, we study three  different types of LLDPE polymers: metallocene-based LLDPEs (m-LLDPEs),  Ziegler-Natta-based LLDPEs (ZN-LLDPEs), and m-LLDPE blends. A generalized equation is introduced to clarify conceptual  definitions of polymer melting temperatures. It incorporates the effects of  comonomer volume, crystal length, folding surface free energy and enthalpy of  fusion. It is successful in describing the characteristic melting temperatures of  various alpha-alkene-ethylene copolymers. The proposed equation is used, along with  melting traces obtained by differential scanning calorimetry (DSC), to estimate the  crystal size number distributions. Furthermore, the melting temperature  characteristics are identified, using crystal size number  distributions. The crystallization behavior of LLDPEs is studied by polarized  light microscopy (PLM) and DSC. A modified Hoffman-Lauritzen (MHL) expression is  proposed for the linear crystallization kinetics by replacing the equilibrium  melting temperature, Tm0, with the melting temperature of the crystal stem with the  maximum possible length, TmC,n*. The concept of the effective nucleation induction  time is introduced, in order to employ the Avrami equation to analyze the overall  crystallization kinetics during the initial crystallization stage. The MHL analysis suggests the presence of three crystallization  regimes: regimes III and II, and a special regime IM. The Avrami exponents are  respectively 2, 1.5, and 1 in these regimes. The typical optical morphology of  LLDPEs is spherulitic. As the crystallization temperature increases, the morphology  changes from spherulites without ring bands, to ring-banded spherulites and  sometimes to irregular structure with rough ring bands. These structural  characteristics seem to correspond to MHL regimes. Non-linear spherulitic growth behavior is observed in regimes II  and IM. This behavior is explained by the reduction of the concentration of  crystallizable ethylene sequences in the melt phase. The MHL expression may be still  used to analyze non-linear growth crystallization kinetics by employing a variable  TmC,n*.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zr20s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fp395</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A44558d773"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Therapeutic maintenance of the M184V mutation in the reverse transcriptase gene of human immunodeficiency virus type-1 by nucleoside analogue inhibitors : implications for clinical management</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Petrella, Marco</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The research for this doctoral dissertation was undertaken to:  (1)establish a rationale that is supported by published laboratory and clinical data  for prospective clinical investigation of the therapeutic maintenance of the M184V  mutation in human immunodeficiency virus type-1 (HIV-1) reverse transcriptase (RT)  in antiretroviral therapy-experienced patients with virological failure, and, (2)to  study the relative effectiveness of various nucleoside analogue reverse  transcriptase inhibitors (NRTIs) that are structurally-unrelated to 3TC in selecting  and/or maintaining M184V in tissue culture and whether continuous exposure to  therapeutic levels of 3TC is the only means of attaining this objective.  Accordingly, we have evaluated the ability of zalcitabine (D.C.), didanosine (ddI),  abacavir (ABC) and the novel nucleoside analogue SPD754, in addition to 3TC, to  maintain the presence of M184V in tissue culture and have shown that each of SPD754,  ABC and 3TC were able to preserve M184V in mixed dual infections consisting of  wild-type viruses and clinical isolates in which the M184V mutation was present  either alone or in a genetic background consisting of several other  resistance-conferring mutations in the RT gene. Moreover, M184V could also be  maintained in these cultures when a subtherapeutic concentration of 3TC (i.e., 0.05  muM) was used. In contrast, neither ddI nor D.C. were able to maintain M184V to the  same extent as the other drugs tested after up to ten weeks of tissue culture in  mixtures of wild-type viruses and isolates containing only M184V, especially when  the latter represented a minority species in the viral population. The M184V  substitution in HIV-1 RT develops rapidly following initiation of therapy with 3TC  and confers high-level phenotypic resistance to this drug and a related analogue,  FTC, both in vitro and in vivo. Interestingly, the proximity of the M184V mutation  in relation to the polymerase active site is also respons</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x74v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558d773</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Virology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m217j"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification and characterization of the novel homedomain-containing transcription factor PREP2</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haller, Klaus, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Transcription factors encoded by the Hox gene family are  conserved throughout the animal kingdom. Their differential spatial and temporal  expression is crucial for axial patterning in early embryonic development. The  affinity and specificity of DNA-binding by the homeodomain (HD)-containing HOX  proteins is raised by interaction with cofactors. The  three-amino-acid-loop-extension (TALE) class of HD-containing proteins comprises  HOX-cofactors which are further categorized into subfamilies including the PBC  family, the MEIS family and the PKNOX/PREP family. HOX-cofactors belonging to the  TALE class have been shown to form dimeric or trimeric complexes with other TALE  family members and with HOX proteins to regulate Hox target genes. It is the  composition of these complexes that controls their stability, target gene  selectivity and recruitment of coregulators, and finally determines Hox-dependent  developmental programs. We used the proto-oncoprotein PBX, which belongs to the PBC  family, to identify new PBX-interacting partners in a yeast-two-hybrid approach. In  this process, we identified a novel member of the PREP family, which we designated  PREP2. PREP2 is ubiquitously expressed during embryonic development and exists in  multiple isoforms that localize to different subcellular compartments as revealed by  two antibodies that we raised against the N and C-terminus of the protein. The  subcellular distribution is regulated by several non-exclusive mechanisms including  active nucleocytoplasmic transport, cytoplasmic retention, protein-protein  interaction as well as phosphorylation. Most strikingly, the actin as well as the  tubulin cytoskeleton seem to be involved in this regulatory process, hence  representing a novel means of regulation for a TALE class protein. In an attempt to  identify the various PREP2 isoforms, we cloned and characterized a splicing variant  -PREP2/E12- that has the potential to act as a dominant negative. Interestingly,  PREP</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462593m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m217j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anc580n042"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of hydrogel platforms for increased QCM-D biointerface sensitivity in real-time immunoassay of sepsis-related biomarkers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carrigan, Shawn D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This doctoral thesis describes the development of novel rapid  deposition hydrogel platforms that serve as biointerfaces for real-time immunoassay  using quartz crystal microgravimetry (QCM). Biointerface development was undertaken  with the goal of developing a simple system relying on affordable technology to  achieve real-time immunoassay performance equivalent to more complex and involved  protocols. The primary advantage of the hydrogel biointerfaces developed  herein lies in their rapid preparation using affordable, non-toxic reagents.  Compositions developed over three sequential development cycles rely on chemically  cross-linking carboxymethylcellulose, which serves to covalently immobilise  recognition elements through amine coupling, to polyethyleneimine. The various  compositions require 10 minutes or less to deposit, a substantial improvement over  competing self-assembled monolayer protocols requiring incubations ranging from  hours to days using highly toxic reagents. Additional benefit lies in the  immunoassay functionality of the biointerface, as these compositions excel in the  traditional performance criteria of surface regeneration, minimisation of  non-specific protein binding, and assay detection limit. The peak detection limit achieved using a sandwich assay for a  17 kDa cytokine was 25 ng/mL in buffer and 500 ng/mL in a 1:3 serum dilution, with  generic immunoassay capability for other cytokines demonstrated. Reusability of the  developed biointerfaces is equally strong, with up to twenty regeneration cycles  demonstrated without diminished sensitivity. Finally, mass-based estimates of  non-specific serum adsorption indicate that the composition developed during the  final design iteration equals the performance of the best protein-resistant  biointerfaces currently available in the literature.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816n040.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580n042</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591898r"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Application of hyperspectral remote sensing in stress detection and crop growth modeling in corn fields</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Karimi-Zindashty, Yousef</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study used hyperspectral data to determine nitrogen, weed,  and water stresses in a corn (Zea mays L.) field in southwestern Quebec, and  incorporated these data in crop growth models for better crop growth simulation  under stressful conditions. In 2000, aerial hyperspectral images (72 wavebands, ranging from  407 to 949 nm) were acquired, and analyzed using a stepwise approach to identify  wavebands useful in detecting weed and nitrogen stresses. Discriminant analysis (DA)  was used to classify different weed and nitrogen treatments and their combinations.  This analysis showed greater classification accuracy (nearly 75%) than those  obtained with artificial neural networks (58%) or decision tree algorithms (60%), at  the initial growth stages, the time when remedial actions are most needed to  alleviate weed and nitrogen stresses. To explore the possibility of improving nitrogen stress  detection in corn in the presence of a confounding water stress, ground-based 2151  narrow-waveband reflectance values (350 to 2500 nm), were collected in 2002. Using  DA with the chosen subset of narrow-wavebands, a classification accuracy of greater  than 95% was obtained. For crop growth monitoring, the STICS model was evaluated for  yield and biomass estimation in cornfields under different stressful growth  conditions using the data collected from 2000 to 2002. Measured yield, biomass, and  leaf area index (LAI) were used for both calibration and validation of the model.  High correlation coefficients between the measured and estimated grain yield (0.96),  biomass (0.98), and LAI (0.93) indicated that the model has good potential in the  simulation of corn growth. The model was also linked with LAI values estimated from  the hyperspectral observations using the Support Vector Machines technique. Coupling  STICS with remote sensing resulted in an overall improvement in the simulation of  corn yield (6.3%) and biomass (3.7%). A new approach was developed to apply crop growth models for  yield estimation in weedy areas. The proposed method first corrects the  measured/estimated LAI values in weed infested fields for weed effect, and then uses  the corrected LAI values as input to the crop growth model. The results showed that  the crop yield and biomass predictions were correctly simulated by this  method.* *This dissertation is a compound document (contains both a paper  copy and a CD as part of the dissertation).</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247ds605.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591898r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Corn -- Effect of stress on -- Québec (Province) -- Remote sensing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Québec (Province) -- Growth -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multispectral photography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kb256"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interactions between the energy-transducing protein TonB and the outer membrane receptor FhuA from Escherichia coli</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khursigara, Cezar M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Iron is an essential element required by most organisms. To  acquire iron, Gram-negative bacteria utilize siderophores; compounds that bind iron  and form soluble complexes. Escherichia coli imports siderophores via specialized  transport systems. A model siderophore receptor system requires the integral outer  membrane (OM) receptor FhuA, which facilitates transport of hydroxamate siderophores  ferricrocin (Fc) and ferrichrome. Transport of siderophores by FhuA to the periplasm  and into the cell requires energy provided by the proton motive force and delivered  by the cytoplasmic membrane protein complex TonB-ExbB-ExbD. Energy is transduced  from this complex by protein-protein interactions between TonB and FhuA. Although  this system has been extensively studied, much remains unclear about interactions  between TonB and FhuA. Sedimentation velocity analytical ultracentrifugation (AUC)  experiments involving mixtures of recombinant TonB and FhuA were conducted to  determine the oligomeric state of TonB-FhuA complexes. These experiments  demonstrated that wild-type TonB-FhuA proteins form a 2:1 (TonB:FhuA) complex, and  that this complex is more abundant when FhuA is pre-incubated with the siderophore  Fc. Deletion of the N-terminal region of TonB also demonstrated a 2:1 complex  stoichiometry with FhuA, but in much lower abundance. Deletion of a highly conserved  proline-rich region within TonB resulted in the formation of a 1:1 complex,  suggesting a novel role for this domain in the formation of a functional 2:1  complex. Affinities of interaction between wild-type and mutant TonB and  FhuA proteins were measured by surface plasmon resonance (SPR). SPR data revealed  that wild-type TonB-FhuA interactions are comprised of multiple interaction sites,  and undergo an intermediate rearrangement event prior to the formation of the 2:1  complex. Deletions of TonB domains do not disrupt this rearrangement, but do  decrease affinity. FhuA cork domain deletions also identified novel sites important  for stable interactions. Information of TonB-FhuA interactions derived by AUC and SPR  described herein has contributed greatly to the purification and crystallization of  TonB-FhuA co-complexes. Overall, these complementary biophysical techniques have  provided important mechanistic details into the protein-mediated transport of iron  into Gram-negative bacteria, and will provide a conceptual framework of TonB-FhuA  that will help in elucidating aspects of the high-resolution structure of the  complex.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k36k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kb256</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>