<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag732df13c"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identifying the novel GTPase function of FLCN and characterizing its role in aging</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ghazi, Abbas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Birt-Hogg-Dube syndrome (BHD) is an inherited neoplasia syndrome that predisposes affected individuals to skin hamartomas, lung cysts, pneumothorax and renal carcinoma. Mutations within the BHD locus (also known as FLCN) have been found associated with the disease. Almost all mutations in BHD patients cause a truncated FLCN protein product suggesting a loss-of-function mechanism leading to tumor formation. FLCN is highly conserved across species from yeast to humans suggesting an important biological function. Earlier this year, the exact molecular function of FLCN was still unclear. However, with the aid of the first crystal structure of folliculin carboxy-terminal domain we provide the first insight into the function of folliculin as a novel GTPase. Interestingly this GTPase activity is lost in a naturally occurring disease-causing mutant (C1844G). We then characterize the role of FLCN-1 in the nematode Caenorhabditis elegans in an attempt to determine the signalling pathway(s) to which FLCN-1 belongs. We report a novel role of FLCN-1 in C. elegans aging as a component of the insulin/IGF-1 signalling pathway. FLCN-1 regulates lifespan via a mechanism that is AAK-2/AMPK, DAF-16/FOXO and autophagy dependent. We demonstrate that FLCN-1 negatively regulates AAK-2 phosphorylation independent of the constitutively active PAR-4 kinase. Moreover, flcn-1 null mutants have elevated levels of β oxidation of fatty acids, mitochondrial respiration and ROS generation all of which are dependent on AAK-2. We hypothesis that ROS generation stimulates autophagy activation as a downstream mechanism required for lifespan extension of flcn-1 null mutants.  Taken together, these studies are aimed to identify the functional role of FLCN and to clarify its metabolic role in relation to AMPK in order to better understand its tumor suppressor function.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le syndrome de Birt-Hogg-Dubé (BHD) est un syndrome néoplasique héréditaire, qui rend les personnes atteintes plus susceptibles de développer les maladies telles que les harmatomes de la peau, kystes pulmonaires, pneumothorax et carcinomes rénaux.  Des mutations dans le locus BHD au niveau du gène de la folliculine (FLCN) sont souvent associées à cette maladie. La majorité des patients présentent des mutations entrainant la troncation de la protéine FLCN, suggèrant un mécanisme de perte de fonction qui entraine la formation de tumeurs. Très conservée à travers les espèces de la levure à l'homme, la FLCN semble avoir une fonction biologique importante, cependant son mécanisme d'action est encore obscure. Néanmoins l'obtention récente de la structure cristallographique du domaine carboxyle terminal de la folliculine suggère qu'elle pourrait fonctionner telle une GTPase. Chose intéressante, cette activité GTPase est perdue naturellement chez les malades portant la mutation C1844G. Afin de déterminer dans quelle voie de signalisation la folliculine appartient, nous avons analysé son rôle chez le nématode Caenorhabditis elegans. Nous rapportons ici le nouveau rôle de la FLCN-1 dans le vieillissement de C. elegans, comme étant un acteur de la voie de signalisation insuline/IGF-1.  La FLCN-1 régule la durée de vie à travers un mécanisme dépendant de l'AMPK/aak-2, FOXO/DAF-16 et de l'autophagie. Nous démontrons qu'elle régule négativement la phosphorylation de AAK-2 indépendamment de la kinase constitutivement active PAR-4. Chez les mutants nul flcn-1, les acides gras B oxydes, la respiration mitochondriale ainsi que la production de ROS présentent des niveaux élevés, qui dépendent de AAK-2.  Nous proposons que la production de ROS stimule l'activation de l'autophagie, nécessaire pour l'extension de la durée de vie des mutants flcn-1 nul. Ainsi, nos études ont permis d'identifier le rôle fonctionnel de la FLCN et de clarifier son rôle métabolique en lien avec l'AMPK, permettant de mieux comprendre sa fonction de suppresseur de tumeur.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Arnim Pause</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h3800.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732df13c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>