<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abv73c3648"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The metabolism and the effects of chronic carbon tetrachloride intoxication</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kanics, Lewis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Halogenated hydrocarbons are widely used as industrial solvents for fats and oils. Therefore they present a potential health hazard when used without adequate ventilation. Acute intoxication of carbon tetrachloride is defined as the result of a single large dose. On the other hand chronic CCl4 intoxication is the result of repeated administration of CCl4. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rubinstein, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pg955.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c3648</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak930c139t"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Protein synthesis in tissue cultures treated with mouse plasmacytoma ribonucleic acid</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hathaway, Audrey</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There has long been speculation as to the mechanism by which antibody molecules acquire their specificity. In the decade between 1951 and 1961 the central role of the nucleic acids in the regulation of prote in synthesis was recognized and various molecular types of ribonucleic acids (RNA) were isolated and characterized. The existence of a messenger RNA which could carry the information for protein synthesis from the nuclear deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) of the cell to the ribosomes of the cytoplasm where protein synthesis occurred was predicted. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vas, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jp769.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c139t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Microbiology and Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483n26v"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Metabolism of the isolated perfused guinea pig heart</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gailis, Laimonis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The function of the heart is to maintain the aortic pressure high enough to ensure a sufficient flow of blood to all the organs of the body. Since the blood flow cannot be interrupted without damage ensuing, the heart must of necessity be continually beating. The heart is the most consistently active of all the muscles. Though some (such as the wing muscles of insects and birds) may be capable of greater activity, they do not, as the heart does, sustain it uninterrupted throughout the life of the organism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Quastel, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hj60k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n26v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vf567"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Centrally initiated cardiovascular adrenergic drug responses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gagnon, Denis J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>While it is tempting to assign to noradrenaline in the brain a chemical transmitter role, similar to that in the peripheral sympathetic system, its exact physiological significance in brain functions and its possible role in central nervous system drug action are still unsolved problems. Ho1tz (1950) should that noradrenaline is the predominant catecholamine in the central nervous system. Vogt (1954) demonstrated that both adrenaline and noradrenaline ("sympathin") are unevenly distributed throughout the central nervous system, and that the brain stem, especially the hypothalamus, contains highest amounts of the amines. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Melville, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c140k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vf567</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225f227"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The mechanism of action of nitroglycerin in angina pectoris</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fam, Wadie M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The term angina pectoris was first introduced to the medical literature by William Heberden (1768). "Before the time of William Heberden, there appeared in the literature descriptions of many cases which have been cited as instances of angina pectoris. The best of these 2 was that by Edward Hyde, the Earl of Clarendon (1609-1674).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McGregor, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tq03d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225f227</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A73666782v"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ganglioside analyses in serial sections of brain and in isolated neurones</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Derry, D. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is now considerable evidence to support the specific neuronal localization of gangliosides. The distribution of gangliosides in subcellular fractions from adult and developing rat brain shows that gangliosides are concentrated in nerve-ending particles and dendritic membrane fractions. The ganglioside concentration in mature white matter is one-sixth to one-tenth that of grey matter. However, the gangliosides in white matter do not appear to be a part of myelin but a constituent of the axonal space or axoplasm. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wolfe, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451m78h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666782v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cf04t"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Streptococcal glomerulonephritis immunological studies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Day, Noorbibi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The immunological explanation of streptococcal glomerulonephrHis in man is suggestive but inconclusive. Experimental models to produce renal disease with beta hemolytic streptococci or their products have been studied by various investigators, particularly by Reed and Matheson (1954a, 1954b, 1959 and 1960). In their studies diffusible substances produced during growth in Todd-Hewitt medium have been implicated. The active substance in the diffusates can be precipitated with ammonium sulphate at 60-75 per cent saturation. [...]Microbiology and Immunology.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reed, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117s060.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cf04t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Microbiology and Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p340p"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Frequency and distribution of purine nucleotide clusters in DNA</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cape, Ronald E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is now generally accepted that the sequence of nucleotide moieties in DNA is the stable genetic message in ail organisms except RNA viruses. Nucleotide sequence in DNA is believed to function as a blueprint or template; various kinds of RNA molecules are "transcribed" from DNA and their nucleotide sequence is determined by that of the DNA template. These RNA molecules participate intimately in the execution and control of protein synthesis and their nucleotide sequence is of primary importance in fulfilling this role. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Spencer, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wz933.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p340p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asj1395107"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Progesterone metabolism in the previable human fetus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bird, Charles E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During tho last ten years a large number of publications have been devoted to problems of steroid metabolism in the human fetus. Much of tho interest in this area was stimulated by the review article of Lanman (1) in which no re-emphasised the unique physiological and anatomical features of the fetal none of the adrenal. He also pointed out that this structure was present in simians and more recently it has been described in the armadillo (2). [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Solomon, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m31v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1395107</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xw03c"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Drying rates and turbulent mixing in spray drying</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baltas, L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The unit operation of spray drying has been in use for over half a century. It is widely employed in the chemical and allied industries to dry thermo-sensitive materials because the temperature of the drying particles remains relatively low and the residence time ls short. Because of the high transfer rates which can be obtained and because a granular dry product is frequently very desirable, spray drying is being used to process an ever increasing list of materials, not all of them being thermo-sensitive. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gauvin, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mf91z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xw03c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60d068m"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Neural control of female reproductive function in the garden snail &lt;&lt;Helix Aspersa&gt;&gt;</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Antkowiak, Tomasz T.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'innervation neurale des gonades est présente chez plusieurs espèces de mollusques et de mammifères. Cependant, nous connaissons peu de choses sur la fonction d'une telle innervation. Je presente des preuves qu'une branche du nerf intestinal comportant plusieurs milliers de fibres axonales procure une innervation sensorielle de l'ovotestis de l'escargot terrestre Helix aspersa. Je démontre une correlation entre le nombre d'ovocytes mûrs dans les gonades et la fréquence de pics d'activité afférente dans le nerf. Je propose que cette innervation fonctionne pour prévenir le système nerveux central lorsqu'une quantité adéquate d'ovocytes matures est disponible pour l'oviposition. Je suggère que les signaux afférents provenant de l'ovotestis ainsi que d'autres organes reproductifs périphériques permettent le réglage d'une variété de signaux moteurs efférents provenant du système nerveux central. De plus, je propose que de telles réponses réflexes dirigent les changements physiologiques secondaires impliqués dans l'oviposition. Finalement, je propose un plan hypothétique pour expliquer le contrôle neuronal de l'ovulation chez H. aspersa.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The neural innervation of gonads has been observed in numerous molluscan and mammalian species. However, little is known about the function of such innervation. I present evidence that a branch of the intestinal nerve made up of several thousand axon fibers provides sensory innervation to the ovotestis of the terrestrial snail Helix aspersa. I demonstrate a correlation between the number of mature oocytes in the gonad and the frequency of afferent spike activity in the nerve. I propose that this innervation functions to notify the central nervous system when an adequate supply of mature oocytes is available for oviposition. I suggest that afferent signals from the ovotestis and other peripheral reproductive organs mediate the timing of various efferent motor outputs from the central nervous system. I further propose that such reflex responses mediate the secondary physiological changes involved in oviposition. Finally, I present a hypothetical outline to explain the neuronal control of ovulation in H. aspersa.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chase, R.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053k36z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d068m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amw22v869s"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Communications</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Communications</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The social shaping of RU486 in Canada: a preliminary case study and sociotechnical analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Campbell, Patricia A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Because they occur in the contentious public arena that surrounds abortion, the development, introduction, and use of RU486, also known as "the abortion pill," provide a valuable opportunity for understanding how sociotechnical analysis can contribute ta the study of communication phenomena. The essay presents a preliminary case study of RU486 in Canada, drawing on an earlier U.S. study performed by Adele Clarke and Therese Montini (1993), supplemented by Bruno Latour's actor network theory and Ruth Schwartz Cowan's framework for linking gender, technology and public policy. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Parce qu'ils prennent place dans le débat public qui entoure l'avortement, le développement, l'introduction, et l'adoption de la pilule RU486, aussi connue sous le nom de pilule d'avortement, présentent une occasion valable de comprendre comment l'analyse socio-technique peut contribuer aux phénomènes de l'étude de la communication. Cet essai présente une étude de cas préliminaire de la RU486 au Canada, basée sur une étude américaine précédente par Adele Clarke et Therese Montini (1993), complétée par la théorie du réseau d'acteurs par Bruno Latour et l'approche proposée par Ruth Schwartz Cowan qui fait le lien entre le genre, la technologie, et la politique publique. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crowley, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085p292.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v869s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pk34j"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'illusion du spectre visible</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rose, François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'illusion du spectre visible is a piece for soprano, flute, clarinet, french horn, violin, cello and piano. The basic concept of this composition which is d1vided into four sections is the crystallisation of timbre. This state is achieved when the color, harmonic rhythm, and actual rhythm of a sound become periodic and in phase. The treatment of the sound is achieved through the control and manipulation of its frequency content, its spatialisation and in the evolution of its duration time. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Illusion du spectre visible est une oeuvre pour soprano, flute, clarinette, cor, violon, violoncelle et piano. Le concept de cette piece qui est divisée en quatre sections, est la cristallisation du timbre, moment atteint lorsque la couleur d'un timbre ainsi que ses rythmes harmonique et temporel devenus periodiques, entrent en phase. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rea, J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096b117.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pk34j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tq04p"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Democracy and the Canadian political process: a study of political parties and their role in the democratic process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Turner, Cindy-Anne E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le débat entre les theoreticians democrates, classiques et institutionnels, s'est souvent concentré sur le raIe des citoyens dans le processus politique. Ce projet revise les activités politiques d'un citoyen et l'apport de ce dernier à la démocratie canadienne. L'analyse de cette étude porte sur une réduction apparente de la participation de nos partis politiques par le biais d'une revue de la démocratie interpartis et des différents groupes d'intérêts. Le débat postmatérialiste/matérialiste est amené comme discussion pour expliquer la croissance des groupes d'intérêts et de lobbyistes comme moyens alternatifs d'exprimer leurs intérêts respectifs.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The debate between the classical and institutional democratic theorists has often focused on the role of citizens in the political process. This paper reviews the political activities of the individual citizen, and how those activities contribute to Canadian democracy. This study's analysis includes a discussion of the apparent decline of political party participation through a review of intra-party democracy and interest groups. The post-materialist/materialist debate is discussed as an explanation for the growth of interest/pressure groups as alternative modes of interest articulation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gibbins, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236533s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tq04p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vp042"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Translation regulation of a 1.3-kb mRNA in rat L6 muscle cells during myogenesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Meadus, William J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is an investigation of the translational regulation of an mRNA coding for a 4O-kDa polypeptide (P-40) in rat L6 cells during myogenesis. In rat myoblasts, 70-80% of the P-4O mRNA is associated with polysomes but in terminally differentiated myotubes, only 10-20% of the P-40 mRNA is translated. The process of terminal differentiation therefore coincides with the translational regression of P-40 mRNA. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bag, J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qc82b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp042</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xp78r"><ual:graduationDate>1988</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Confluence for piano and orchestra</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sexton, Brian R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis consists of two main parts. The first part is the musical score of an original composition for piano and full orchestra entitled "Confluence. This is a single movement work of approximately thirteen minutes duration. The second part is an essay containing a detailed aesthetic, conceptual and technical analysis of the musical work.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La présente thèse comporte deux grandes sections. "Confluence" constitue la première section, composition originale pour piano et grand orchestre; il s'agit d'une œuvre en un mouvement d'une durée approximative de treize minutes. La seconde section, sous forme d'essai, présente une analyse détaillée de cette œuvre musicale, des points de vue esthétique, conceptuel et technique. </dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752k930.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xp78r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axs55mf927"><ual:graduationDate>1986</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cigarette smoking and the risk of breast and endometrial cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Levi, Fabio</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans le cadre d'une étude cas-témoins conquite à Milan, Italie, on a étudié la relation entre la consommation de cigarettes et le risque de cancer du sein et de l'endomètre. Au total, 1,105 cas hospitaliers de cancers mammaires et 357 de l’endomètre ont été comparés, respectivement, à 1,279 et 1,122 témoins admis pour des affections aigues dans les principaux hôpitaux de la ville. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Data from a case-control investigation conducted in Milan, Italy, were analyzed to evaluate the relation between smoking habits and the risk of breast and endometrial cancer. A total of 1.105 breast and 357 endometrial hospital-based cancer cases were compared to 1,279 and 1,122 controls, respectively, admitted for a large spectrum of acute conditions to major University or general hospitals in the greater Milan area. Compared to never smokers the age-adjusted relative breast cancer risks were 0.99 (95 % confidence interval (CI) = 0.71-1.37) for ex smokers, and 0.85 (96% CI = 0.70-1.04) for current smokers. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>La Vecchia, C.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Decarli, A.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zf24p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mf927</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r856z"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An analytic approach to unit commitment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Meriched, Ali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the present study a new analytic approach, based on the generalized lagrange multipliers method for the solution of the static unit commitment if thermal unit has been Investigated. The conditions for optimum unit commitment in this approach are reduced to a set of analytic conditions defining curves, termed switching curves which govern the switching of the system units and characterize a relatively small number of combinations of constant unit commitment. The optimum schedules can, be analytically studied in terms of the load the reserve margins and the associated lagrange multipliers corresponding to the system incremental cost and the reserve incremental cost respectively. This analytic approach termed the switching curve concept provides a new and unique insight into the unit switching mechanism not available from purely numerical, techniques as well as gaining a physical interpretation for optimum unit in terms of the system incremental costs. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette étude présente une approche analytique pour résoudre le problème de répartition à court terme d'un ensemble  de moyens de production thermique. La version statique du problème a été considérée et les principal résultats ont été obtenus à partir de la méthode généralisée des multiplicateurs de Lagrange .Les conditions d'optimalité obtenues sont réduites a un ensemble de conditions analytiques définissant des courbes appelées courbes de commutation qui régissent le mécanisme de la mise en marche et d'arrêt des groupes et basée sur celles-ci. Une interprétation physique est déduite en fonction des couts marginaux donnant des résultats satisfaisant économiquement. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Galiana, F.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150n06w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r856z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83m2556"><ual:graduationDate>1984</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fermentation of the hot red pepper (Capsicum frutescens): a microbiological study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Arocha, Jose I.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ground hot red pepper mash. With 8% salt was stored ln wooden and plastic container at 22°C for 52°C days and several microbiological and physico-chemical tests were performed on samples taken regularly throughout storage. A fermentation is believed to occur during the first months of storage. The organisms responsible for that were Candida spp and Pediococcus spp. During that period, pH decreased from 5.5 to 4.4 and titratable acidity Increased from 0.47 to 0.90%. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Une pâte de piments rouges moulus, contenant 8% de sel a été entreposée dans des contenants de bois et de plastique pendant 22°C pour à 52°C. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Idziak, E.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021j22h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m2556</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c574p"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of: "Path of Light" an opera in one act</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hermann, Byron G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The analysis of "Path of Light" will investigate the basic relationships between music and drama present in a genre such as opera. A synopsis of the libretto will be given so that a clear understanding of the dramatic situations to be conveyed by the music will be apparent. This will be followed by an analysis of how the music integrates with the text to articulate these relationships. This section of the analysis will include a detailed look at: rhythmic structures, pitch and mobile development, harmonic structure, orchestration details, including the concept and realization of the tape part of the score, as well as the tape's function and integration into the overall dramatic work. The importance of this interaction of all the visual aspects of the drama i.e. lighting, set design and acting instruction with the music will also be demonstrated.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'analyse de "Path of Light" portera sur les rapports fondamentaux entre la musique entra l'aspect dramatique qui existent dans un genre tel que l'opéra. Un résumé du livret sera fait pour qu'il s'en dégage une compréhension claire des situations dramatiques évoquées par la musique. Je passerais ensuite à une analyse de l'intégration de la musique avec le texte afin d'élucider ces rapports. Cette partie de l'analyse traitera de façon approfondie les points suivants: les structures rythmiques, les détails de l'orchestration y compris le concept et la réalisation des parties pour bande magnetique, ainsi que la fonction et l'intégration des bandes dans l'ensemble de l'œuvre dramatique. L'importance de l'interaction des aspects visuels du drame avec la musique, soit l'éclairage, les décors, les directives données aux interprètes, sera aussi expliquée.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hambraeus, B.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vp05b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c574p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axp68kk349"><ual:graduationDate>1979</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Entrapment characteristics in a recirculating eddy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anestis, Ioannis D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is concerned with the study of pollutant effluents discharged from a side channel into rivers or coastal cross currents. Experiments were carried out to study the reattachment of the jet effluent and the entrapment of pollutant in the recirculating eddy immediately downstream of the discharge channel. The flow was simulated in the laboratory by discharging dyed water from a side channel perpendicularly into an open channel crossflow. Geometric characteristics of the reattachment eddy were obtained from flow visualization. The transient variation of dye concentration in the eddy was determined from a series of light absorption probes, which were developed specifically for this investigation. Attempts were made to characterize the entrapment process by overall parameters such as retention time and average steady-state concentration. The results were correlated through a convenient set of dimensionless variables which were derived from approximating the jet effluent as a point source of momentum flux. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le sujet de cette thèse est l'étude de la décharge des effluents polluants d'un canal secondaire débouchant dans une rivière ou encore émergeant dans des courrants côtiers. Des expériences ont été faites pour étudier comment le jet d'effluents est capté par le courrant principal et comment les polluants sont retenus par le tourbillon de recirculation immédiatement en aval du canal de décharge. L'écoulement a été simulé au laboratoire en envoyant de l'eau t, teintée depuis un canal secondaire déboudrant perpendiculairement, dans un canal principal en circulation ouverte. Les charactéristiques géometriques du tourbillon de recirculation sont obtenues par visualisation. La variant en régime non établi de la concentration en colorants a été mesurée dans le tourbillon à l'aide de sondes spécialement mises au point pour cette étude. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chu, V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204225k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kk349</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8623j2064"><ual:graduationDate>1979</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry and Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Neuronal regulation of adrenal ornithine decarboxylase</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ramirez-Gonzalez, Maria D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The role of the central nervous system in the regulation of adrenal ornithine decarboxylase (ODC) activity has been studied. Medullary and cortical tissues were separated and the enzyme activities measured in vitro. Many factors affecting ODC activity were analyzed separately and in combination: pharmacological (oxotremorine, methylatropine, reserpine); surgical (splanchnicotomy, spinal cord transection); hormonal (hypophysectomy); and environmental cold exposure, restraint). […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le rôle du, système nerveux central dans la régulation de l'ornithine d'carboxylase des surrénales (ODC) a été étudié. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sourkes, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gk53r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j2064</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychiatry and Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sd55v"><ual:graduationDate>1977</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Meteorology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The evolution of Montreal's precipitation: climate</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leduc, Richard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'évolution des précipitations à Montréal est examinée en utilisant les observations journalières de l'observatoire de l'Université McGill pour la période 1872 à 1972. En utilisant des variables annuelles et intra annuelles telles les moyennes saisonnières, mensuelles ou quotidiennes un schème olimatologique est construit. La distribution temporelle des valeurs mensuelles anormales et la réalité des normales de pluie pour des p:riodes plus courtes sont examinées de même que la distribution (sur vingt années) des séquences de jours pluvieux. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The evolution of Montreal's precipitation using McGill University Observatory daily observations for 1872 ta 1972 is investigated. A climate picture is composed using annual and intra-annual related variables such as seasonnal, monthly or daily mean values. Anomalous monthly amounts time distribution are examined and the reality of shorter periods rainfall normals discussed as well as the distribution (over twenty years) of wet sequences. Further, twenty-four hour rain and snow classes are defined and their annual distribution analysed. By using a filtering technique, total precipitation, rainfall and snowfall trends are put into light and their reality statistically discussed. A qualitative comparison with four neighbouring stations is made and an hypothesis concerning regional precipitation behaviour is advanced. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vowinckel, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395wb56f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sd55v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Meteorology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988p03n"><ual:graduationDate>1977</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pulmonary dysfunction following hemorrhagic shock in swine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sugg, Joe H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le dysfonctionnement pulmonaire consécutif à un traumatisme et à un choc constitue un problème clinique grave. Dans son livre intitulé Post-Traumatic Pulmonary Insufficiency (22) le Dr Francis D. Moore affirme que "parmi les sujets adultes qui ont été gravement blessés… environ un tiers des décès est provoqué avant tout par une défaillance progressive respiratoire". Le Dr Moore souligne par ailleurs que parmi les deux autres tiers aussi, quelques-uns révèlent d'inportants éléments d'insuffisance pulmonaire, bien que les décès résultent surtout d'une implication directe des , organes vitaux ou de septisémie. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Pulmonary dysfunction following trauma and shock is a serious clinical problem. In his book titled, Post-Traumatic Pulmonary Insufficiency (22). Dr. Francis D. Moore states that "among adult patients who have been severely injured ... about 1/3 of the fatalities are due primarily to progressive respiratory failure." He goes on to point out that some of the remaining 2/3 also exhibit important elements of pulmonary insufficiency, although they die primarily as a result of direct involvement of vital organs or sepsis. Moore goes on to say that "disease in the lungs, therefore, becomes an importance in the death of 30-50% of adult patients who die under intensive care today, following an initial episode of trauma, hemorrhage, major operation, burn, or shock. […]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02871015q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988p03n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88ck769"><ual:graduationDate>1977</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Oral Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Clobetasol 17-propionate and impacted mandibular third molar surgical edema</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sternthal, Barry</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une étude à double-insue, utilisant de la crème au propionate de clobetasol 17, a été realisée sur trente sujets en bonne santé. Elle ava~ pour objectif de determiner l'influence d'un corticosteroide en application locale sur un oedème chirurgical faisant suite à l'extraction de troisième molaires inferieures incluses. L'observation de l'oedème post-chirurgical mesuré à la fois par des manifestations cliniques et d'une façon tridimentionnelle par des "physioprints" préopératoires et postopératoires pris sous des conditions identiques, a démontré une diminution sensible de cet oedème sur le coté ayant reçu le propionate de clobetasol ,17. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A double blind study employing clobetasol 17-propionate cream was carried out to determine the influence of a topical corticosteroid on surgical edema following the removal of impacted mandibular third molar teeth in thirty healthy subjects. Measurement of postsurgical edema which was determined both by clinical impression and in a three dimensional fashion according to preoperative and postoperative physioprints taken under reproducible conditions demonstrated a significant reduction in postsurgical edema on the side that received the clobetasol 17-propionate. An increased incidence of postoperatlve infection was encountered bilaterally during the investigation. The composition of of the cream rather than the steroid component appeared to be the contributing factor. Modification of the cream used in this study to perhaps a more soluble form might reduce the incidence of infection and thus enable its use as a suitable agent in the management of surgical edema in oral surgery.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bentley, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rm401.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ck769</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Oral Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>