<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pf07n"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Student engagement in technology rich classrooms and its relationship to professors' conceptions of effective teaching</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gebre, Engida</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The benefit of computer related tools in supporting student learning is influenced by the engaging nature of the learning environment and the design of the learning activities. Professors have considerable role in the design of learning environments and activities and the way they design the environment is found to depend on their conceptions of teaching. However, professors' conceptions of (effective) teaching have not been studied in relation to technology use and student engagement. This dissertation study examined a) professors' conceptions of effective teaching and their perceived technology use in technology rich classrooms, and b) the nature and extent of student engagement in these classrooms and its relationship to professors' conceptions of effective teaching. Semi-structured interviews were used to obtain data from 13 professors who were teaching in active learning classrooms in a large research university in Eastern Canada in winter 2011. Interview questions focused on capturing professors' conceptions of effective teaching in relation to the course they were teaching in the classroom, their expected learning outcomes for students, their instructional strategies, and the role they saw for computers and the type of software they used and/or expected their students to use in relation to the course. Following interviews with the professors, a survey was administered to their students in the end of the term. The instrument, Student Engagement in Technology Rich Classrooms (SETRC) was developed to determine aspects and extent of student engagement in the context. Two hundred thirty two students consented to participate in the research and completed the paper copy of the survey.  Analysis of interview data using a holistic inductive approach with constant comparison resulted in three conceptions of effective teaching—transmitting knowledge, engaging students, and developing learning independence. Transmitting knowledge highlighted organizing and presenting subject matter to students. Engaging students focused on student involvement in various activities such as discussion, presentation, collaboration, and hands on exercises. Developing learning independence and self-reliance related to holistic development of students as professionals and independent learners. This third conception also considered effective teaching to be designing learning environments with more emphasis on students' involvement.  Principal component analysis with varimax rotation was applied to the student survey data. The analysis resulted in four components of student engagement: cognitive and applied engagement, social engagement, reflective engagement, and goal clarity. Subsequent multivariate analysis considering professors' conception as independent variable and the four student engagement components as dependent variables yielded significant relationship between professors' conceptions and student engagement. Students in classrooms of professors who consider effective teaching to be developing learning independence/self-reliance reported the highest score on cognitive and applied engagement; the score was the least for students in classrooms of professors who consider effective teaching to be transmitting knowledge. The difference was statistically significant. Concerning social engagement, students in classrooms of professors who consider effective teaching to be engaging students reported the highest score among the three groups and it was significantly higher than scores of students in classrooms of professors who consider effective teaching to be transmitting knowledge. Analysis results did not show any significant different in terms of reflective engagement and goal clarity. The study has implication for understanding conceptions of effective teaching in relation to computer use, determining students' course/classroom level engagement, and designing and assessing technology rich natural learning environments.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les avantages de technologies d'information et de communication (TICs) comme support d'apprentissage dans le milieu éducatif sont influencés par la qualité engageante de l'environnement d'apprentissage et le design des activités d'apprentissage. Les professeurs jouent un rôle considérable dans le design d'environnements et d'activités d'apprentissage. Il a été démontré que leur conception d'enseignement influe sur le design des environnements d'apprentissage. Cependant, les conceptions d'enseignement (efficace) que possèdent les professeurs n'ont pas été étudiées jusqu'à lors en ce qui a trait à l'utilisation des TICs et l'engagement étudiant. Cette thèse de doctorat a étudié a) les conceptions d'enseignement efficace de professeurs et les perceptions de leur utilisation de technologie dans des salles de classe richement équipés en TICs, et b) la nature et l'étendue de l'engagement étudiant dans ces salles de classe et sa relation aux conceptions d'enseignement efficace des professeurs.Des entrevues semi-structurés furent employés pour obtenir des données de 13 professeurs qui enseignaient dans des salles de classe d'apprentissage active d'une grande université de recherche dans l'Est canadien durant l'hiver 2011. Les questions d'entrevue étaient centrées sur la capture des conceptions d'enseignement efficace des professeurs en relation aux cours qu'ils enseignaient dans cette salle de classe, leurs attentes vis à vis les résultats d'apprentissage des étudiants, leur stratégies d'enseignement, et le rôle qu'ils percevaient pour l'utilisation des TICs par eux-mêmes et les étudiants dans leurs cours. Suite aux entrevues, un sondage a été mené auprès des étudiants à la fin du trimestre. Le questionnaire, Student Engagement in Technology Rich Classrooms (SETRC) a été développé pour déterminer certains aspects de l'engagement étudiant et son étendue dans ces contextes. Deux cent trente-deux étudiants ont accepté de participer dans la recherche et ont complété la copie papier du sondage. L'analyse des données d'entrevue procéda dans une optique holistique par l'entremise d'une approche inductive avec comparaison constante et résulta dans trois conceptions d'enseignement efficace—la transmission des connaissances, l'engagement étudiant, et le développement de l'autonomie apprenante. La transmission des connaissances soulignait l'organisation et la présentation du contenu d'apprentissage aux étudiants. L'engagement étudiant centrait sur la participation des étudiants dans diverses activités telles que la discussion, la présentation, la collaboration, et les exercices pratiques. Le développement de l'autonomie apprenante était relié au développement holistique des étudiants comme des apprenants professionnels et indépendants. Cette troisième conception prenait aussi en compte le design des environnements d'apprentissage avec un plus grand accent sur l'engagement étudiant.L'analyse des composantes principales avec rotation varimax fut appliquée aux données de sondage des étudiants. L'analyse résulta en quatre composantes: l'engagement cognitif et appliqué, l'engagement social, l'engagement réflexif, et la clarté et la précision des objectifs. Une analyse multivariée subséquente qui considérait les conceptions des professeurs comme variable indépendante et les quatre composantes de l'engagement étudiant comme variables dépendants a identifié des relations significatives entre les conceptions des professeurs et l'engagement étudiant. Les étudiants des cours de professeurs qui considéraient l'enseignement efficace comme le développement de l'autonomie apprenante avaient les plus hauts scores sur l'engagement cognitive et appliqué; le score le plus bas était réservé pour les étudiants des cours de professeurs qui considéraient l'enseignement efficace comme la transmission des connaissances. La différence était stastiquement significative. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robert J. Bracewell</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Alenoush Saroyan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fs26q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pf07n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s592c"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anisotropic soft matter models for plant cell walls</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Murugesan, Yogesh Kumar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis uses theory and simulation to elucidate the principles and mechanisms that govern the thermodynamics, material science, and rheology of biological anisotropic soft matter that are involved in growth/self-assembly/material processing in plant cell walls, a multi-functional biological fibrous composite. The plant cell wall can be considered as a reinforced biological membrane consisting of cellulose microfibrils (CMFs) of high tensile strength embedded in a polysaccharide matrix. These CMFs in the extracellular matrix are oriented instrategic directions and generate commonly observed textures such as line, ring, helix, crossed helix and helicoids. The orientation of CMFs governs the physical properties of wood, controls the shape of the cell and contributes to themorphology at the tissue and organ level. Two models are used in this thesis, depending on the concentration of CMFs.At concentration of CMFs below Onsager critical limit, we develop an integrated mechanical model that describes nematic liquid crystalline self-assembly of rigid fibers on an arbitrarily curved 2D fluid membrane to demonstrate the possibility of the CMF orientation imparted by the interaction between membrane curvature and embedded fiber order. This curvature driven planar self assembly model can predict and explain the observed line, ring and helical cell wall textures. These predictions are partially validated through available experimental observations. An integrated shape and nematic order equation developed in this thesis gives a complete model whose solution describes the coupled membraneshape and fiber order state. The validated model is then used to analyze the structure and mechanics of biological and biomimetic fiber-laden membranes of variable curvature. The statics of anisotropic fiber-laden membranes developed inthis model is integrated with the planar nematodynamics of fibers and the dynamics of isotropic membranes to formulate a viscoelastic model to study dynamic remodeling of plant cell wall during growth and morphogenesis. The novel coupling between in-plane fiber orientation and order and membrane curvature formulated this thesis has the potential to open up a novel venue to control two dimensional anisotropic soft matter with tailored functionalities. When the concentration of the CMFs exceeds Onsager's critical fiber concentration threshold, the interaction between these CMFs results in theiralignment in a specific direction as an attempt to minimize the excluded volume of the CMFs. A mathematical model based on the Landau–de Gennes theory of liquid crystals is used to simulate defect textures arising in the domain of chiralself-assembly due to the presence of secondary phases such as pit canal and cell lumens. In addition to providing information on material properties and length scales that cannot be experimentally measured in vivo, the simulated transient defect pattern confirms for first time the long postulated formation mechanism of helicoidal plywoods through liquid crystalline self-assembly. The model is further extended to investigate defect textures and liquid crystalline (LC) phases observed in polygonal arrangement of cylindrical particles embedded in a cholesteric liquid crystal matrix. These validated findings provide a comprehensive set of trends and mechanisms that contribute to the evolving understanding of biological plywoods and serve as a platform for future biomimetic applications.The integration of soft matter physics theories and models with actual biological data for plant cell walls provides a foundation for understanding growth, form, and function and a platform for biomimetic innovation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse utilise la théorie et la simulation pour élucider les principes et mécanismes qui gouverne la hermodynamique, la science des matériaux, et la rhéologie de la matière biologique molle anisotropique qui est impliquée dans ledéveloppement/auto-assemblage/la transformation des parois cellulaires de plantes, un composite biologique fibreux multifonctionnel. Les parois cellulaires de plantes peuvent être considérées comme des membranes biologiques renforcées consistant en des microfibres de cellulose (CMFs) de hautes ténacités contenues dans une matrice de polysaccaride. Ces CMFs dans la matrice extracellulaire sont orientés dans une direction stratégique hélices et des hélicoïdes. L'orientation des CMFs gouverne les propriétés physiques du bois et contrôle la forme des cellules. Deux modèles sont employés dans cette thèse dépendamment de la concentration en CMFs. A la concentration de CMFs dessous la limite critique de Onsager, nous développons un modèle mécanique intégré qui décrit un auto-assemblage de fibres rigides de type cristal liquide nématique sur une membrane courbée bidimensionnelle arbitraire afin de démontrer la possibilité de l'orientation des CMFs indue par les interactions entre la courbature de la membrane et l'organisation fibrillaire intrinsèque. Cette auto-assemblage planaire indus par la courbature peut prédire et expliquer les lignes, annaux et textures hélicoïdales observées dans les parois cellulaires. Ces prédictions sont partiellement validées au travers d'observations expérimentales publiés. Une équation décrivant l'ordre nématique et la forme intégrée qui a été développé dans cette thèse fournis un modèle complet dont la solution décrit le couplage entre l'alignement des fibres et la forme de la membrane. Le model validé est par la suite utilisé à fin d'analyser la structure et la mécanique de membrane fibreuses biologiques et biomimétiques de courbatures variables. La statique des membranes fibreuses anisotropes développés dans ce modèle est intégrée avec la némato-dynamique planaire des fibres et la dynamique des membranes isotropes afin de formuler un modèle viscoélastique pour étudier le remodelage dynamique des CMF durant leur développement et morphogénèse. Le nouveau couplage entre l'orientation fibrillaire planaire et l'ordre ainsi que la courbature de la membrane formulé dans cette thèse à le potentiel d'ouvrir de nouvelles avenues pour contrôler l'ordre bidimensionnel de matière molle selon des propriétés bien définies. Quand la concentration en CMFs excède la limite critique en fibre de Onsager, l'interaction entre les CMFs résulte en un alignement dans une direction spécifique qui tente de minimiser le volume exclu de CMFs. Un modèle mathématique basé sur la théorie de Landau de Gennes des cristaux liquides est utilisé pour simuler les textures de défauts survenant dans un chirale d'auto assemblage du à la présence de phases secondaires tel que les lumens cellulaires. En plus de fournir de l'information sur les propriétés matériels et les ordres de grandeurs qui ne peuvent être mesuré expérimentalement in vivo, les motifs des défauts transitoires simulés confirment pour la première fois le mécanisme de formation des assemblages hélicoïdaux. Le modèle est de plus étendu pour investiguer les textures de défauts et les phases liquides cristallines (LC) observées dans les arrangements polygonaux de particules cylindriques inclus dans des matrices de cristaux liquide cholestériques. Ces découvertes validées fournissent un ensemble de mécanismes qui contribues à faire évoluer la compréhension des assemblages lamellaires biologiques et servent de plateforme pour de futur développement d'applications biomimétiques. L'intégration des théories et des modèles de la matière molle avec des données biologique concrète pour les parois cellulaires fournissent des fondement pour la compréhension du développement, de formation et fonctionnalité ainsi qu'une plateforme pour l'innovation biomimétique</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alejandro D. Rey</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Damiano Pasini</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429d84c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s592c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010t50n"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Landscape-scale assessment of soil properties, water quality and related nutrient fluxes under oil palm cultivation: a case study in Sumatra, Indonesia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Comte, Irina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La rapide expansion de la culture du palmier à huile en Asie du Sud-Est soulève maintes interrogations sur ses impacts environnementaux. Les planteurs doivent désormais assurer de hauts rendements tout en minimisant leurs impacts. Les impacts environnementaux associés à la déforestation lors de la phase initiale d'établissement d'une plantation sont déjà bien documentés. En revanche, les impacts d'une plantation mature sur la qualité de l'eau a été très peu étudiée. Le palmier à huile est généralement cultivée sur des sols tropicaux peu fertiles d'où la nécessité de forts apports de fertilisants, apports susceptibles de menacer les écosystèmes aquatiques. En Indonésie, les petits planteurs n'utilisent que des fertilisants minéraux tandis que les industriels appliquent, en plus des fertilisants minéraux, des fertilisants organiques issus de leurs usines. Les caractéristiques du sol et la gestion de la fertilisation des palmeraies sont susceptibles d'influer sur la fertilité du sol et sur les transferts de nutriments vers les rivières. Etant donné que les plantations s'étendent généralement sur plusieurs milliers d'hectares, l'effet de la gestion de la fertilisation sur la réponse du sol et les transferts de nutriments vers les rivières nécessite des études à l'échelle du paysage. Celles-ci doivent tenir compte tant de la variabilité du sol au sein de la plantation que de la variabilité des séquences de fertilisation pluriannuelles. Le premier objectif de cette étude est (i) de réaliser une revue de littérature sur les pratiques agricoles utilisées dans les palmeraies ainsi que sur les processus hydrologiques impliqués dans les transferts de nutriments vers les rivières, (ii) d'évaluer l'effet de séquences pluriannuelles de fertilisation minérale et organique sur la réponse du sol, tenant compte de la variabilité des sols, (iii) de caractériser et quantifier les processus hydrologiques dominants impliqués dans le transfert de nutriments, (iv) et enfin d'évaluer l'effet de la gestion de la fertilisation et des caractéristiques du sol sur la qualité des eaux souterraines et sur les flux de nutriments vers les rivières. La zone d'étude est située dans le centre de Sumatra, en Indonésie. Le climat y est tropical humide et les sols peu fertiles (Ferralsols). Il s'agit d'un paysage de 100 km² incluant une plantation villageoise de 1500 ha et une plantation industrielle de 4 000 ha, pratiquant une gestion raisonnée de la fertilisation. Cette étude a montré une amélioration significative des propriétés chimiques des sols suite à des applications continues de fertilisants organiques, avec une amélioration encore plus sensible sur les sols sablo-limoneux que sur les sols limoneux. Une gestion spatiale de la fertilisation à l'échelle de la plantation devrait compléter la gestion à la parcelle pour une meilleure stratégie d'application des fertilisants adaptée à la variabilité des sols au sein de la plantation. Le suivi multi-site sur un an de la qualité des eaux de surface dans le paysage a montré des niveaux de concentrations de nutriments en deçà des limites maximales recommandées par les standards indonésiens. Dans cette étude de cas, la culture d'une palmeraie mature ne semble pas avoir contribué à l'eutrophisation des cours d'eaux. Les raisons en seraient la dilution du système par la forte pluviosité locale, et la pratique d'une fertilisation raisonnée. L'évaluation des flux de nutriments a montré que les sols sablo-limoneux étaient plus sensibles que les sols limoneux aux pertes de nutriments et que la fertilisation organique pouvait réduire significativement ces pertes. Le renouvellement rapide des eaux souterraines induit une grande réactivité du système aux intrants qui peuvent être rapidement drainés vers les cours d'eau. Des apports massifs de nutriments (fertilisation non raisonnée) ou des pesticides liés à la matière organique dissoute pourraient donc entraîner un risque de pollution en aval de l'agrosystème. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The rapid expansion of oil palm cultivation in Southeast Asia raises environmental concerns. Oil palm growers in Indonesia are faced with the challenge of sustaining high yields to keep pace with the growing global demand for oil and fats, while reducing the environmental impacts of oil palm cultivation. Environmental impacts associated with the deforestation at the initial phase of an oil palm plantation establishment are well documented, however the impacts of mature oil palm plantation on water quality remain poorly investigated.  Oil palm is a perennial crop cultivated predominantly on weathered tropical soils, so high fertilizer input is necessary to sustain high yields, which is expected to endanger neighboring aquatic ecosystems. In Indonesia, 39 % of oil palm planted area is owned by smallholder farmers, who rely on mineral fertilizers to support oil palm production, and 52 % are large private plantations operated by private industries.  In addition to mineral fertilizers, industrial plantations also apply mill byproducts as organic fertilizers. Soil characteristics and fertilizer management in oil palm plantations were expected to alter the soil fertility status and nutrient loads to waterways. Oil palm plantations generally extend over thousands of contiguous hectares, so the effect of fertilizer management on the soil response and nutrient loads to waterways requires landscape-scale studies accounting for soil variability and long-term fertilization sequences across the plantation. The first objective of the thesis was to (i) perform a literature review that provides an overview of the agricultural practices in oil palm plantations as well as hydrological processes involved in the nutrient transfers to waterways. Then I aimed to (ii) assess the effect of long term mineral and organic fertilizer sequences on the soil response, considering different soil types, (iii) characterize the dominant hydrological processes involved in the nutrient fluxes to waterways, and (iv) assess the effect of fertilizer management and soil characteristics on groundwater quality and nutrient fluxes to streams. The study area was located in Central Sumatra, Indonesia, which has a tropical humid climate and weathered soils (Ferralsols). The study area was a landscape including a 4000 ha industrial plantation and a 1500 ha smallholder plantation using rational fertilizer programs. Low-fertility Ferralsols responded significantly to continuous applications of organic fertilizers, with greater improvement on coarser-textured soils, compared to repeated applications of mineral fertilizers. I proposed that spatial fertilizer management at the landscape-scale should complement the current plot-scale fertilizer management to get higher nutrient use efficiency and improve soil fertility in an oil palm plantation. One year multi-site monitoring of stream water quality showed nutrient concentrations below Indonesian standards for water quality. In this case study, mature oil palm cultivation did not contribute to the eutrophication of aquatic ecosystems. This was ascribed to nutrient dilution in streams from the high rainfall as well as high nutrient demand by oil palm that was met with a rational fertilizer program. Assessment of nutrient fluxes from baseflow showed that loamy-sand uplands were more sensitive to nutrient losses than loamy lowlands, and organic fertilization helped to reduce nutrient losses to streams. The study also showed high dissolved organic matter content in streams, likely from natural sources. Oil palm agroecosystems in the study area are characterized by fast groundwater renewal indicating the potential for inputs to be quickly transported from soils to the streams. This may be of concern when unbalanced fertilizer management leads to over-application of nutrients or persistent agrochemicals like pesticides bind to dissolved organic matter, since they will be susceptible to contribute to nonpoint source pollution in streams.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Joann Karen Whalen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dh062.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010t50n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gx16m"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Information and its importance in head and neck cancer care</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>D'Souza, Violet</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les cancers de la tête et du cou (T &amp; C), constituent un groupe hétérogène de tumeurs malignes qui se présentent dans la bouche, le nez, le pharynx et le larynx. Ils sont les huitièmes cancers les plus fréquents dans le monde. Les personnes qui reçoivent le diagnostic d'un de ces cancers ont souvent de grands besoins d'information qui ne sont pas comblés. En dépit d'une grande quantité d'écrits prônant la nécessité de passer d'une approche « à solution unique » vers une approche sur mesure tout en fournissant des informations aux patients atteints de cancer, la majorité des hôpitaux fournissent des informations de manière ad hoc. L'objectif principal de cette étude était d'étudier les effets d'un ensemble complet d'information sur mesure multimode (ECIMM)  sur l'anxiété, la dépression, la satisfaction à l'égard des soins reçus et la connaissance du cancer chez les patients atteints de cancer T &amp; C.  Notre objectif secondaire était de décrire et de comparer les expériences des patients atteints de cancer T &amp; C qui reçoivent des informations sur leur cancer et leur traitement à ceux de deux hôpitaux ayant des approches différentes de diffuser l'information. Nous avons utilisé des méthodes de recherche mixtes intégrées conçues dans un essai non randomisé contrôlé dans lesquelles nous avons imbriqué une étude qualitative pour répondre aux objectifs secondaires mentionnés précédemment. L'ensemble du projet a été mené auprès des patients atteints de cancer T &amp; C de stade III et IV dans les hôpitaux participants. L'étude a reçu l,'approbation éthique du Comité de protection des personnes et des comités d'éthiques locaux des hôpitaux participants. Un total de 103 personnes atteintes de cancer du T &amp; C ont pris part à l'étude quantitative, à laquelle 96 participants ont reçu une évaluation au tout début de l'étude et des évaluations de suivi. Un sous-échantillon de 11 participants de l'étude principale et de 2 infirmières pivots y ont pris part à l'étude qualitative. Les données quantitatives et qualitatives ont été recueillies en même temps. Les résultats de notre étude montrent que les participants qui ont bénéficié de l'intervention ont connu des niveaux significativement inférieurs d'anxiété, des niveaux supérieurs de connaissances sur le cancer, sont davantage satisfaits de l'information qu'ils ont reçue et ont eu une bonne expérience pour ce qui fut de recevoir de l'information, si on les compare aux sujets qui ont reçu les soins normaux. Par conséquent, nous concluons que le ECIMM est un adjuvant potentiellement bénéfique pour les soins contre le cancer T &amp; C.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Head and Neck (H&amp;N) cancers are a diverse group of malignant tumors arising in the mouth, nose, pharynx and larynx. They are the 8th most common cancers in the world. Individuals who receive a diagnosis of these cancers often have enormous unmet informational needs. In spite of a large quantity of literature advocating the necessity to move from "one size fits all" to a tailored approach while providing information to cancer patients, the majority of hospitals provide information in an ad hoc manner. The primary aim of this study was to investigate the impacts of a multimedia based tailored information service on H&amp;N cancer patients' anxiety, depression, satisfaction and cancer knowledge ratings. Our secondary aim was to describe and compare the experiences of H&amp;N cancer patients' receiving information concerning their cancer and treatment at two hospitals with different approaches to deliver information. We used an embedded mixed methods research design within a non-randomized controlled trial within which we nested a qualitative study to address the aforementioned secondary aims. The project was conducted with stage III and IV H&amp;N cancer patients at the participating hospitals. Ethical approval was obtained from the Institutional Review Board and the Research Ethics Boards of the participating hospitals. The test hospital delivered the Multimode Comprehensive Tailored Information Package (MCTIP) and the control hospital received the normal care. A total of 103 individuals with H&amp;N cancer took part in the quantitative study, out of which 96 participants completed baseline and all follow up evaluations. In the qualitative study, a subsample of 11 participants of the main study and 2 Nurse Pivots took part. Quantitative and qualitative data were collected concurrently. Our study findings show that the participants who received the test intervention experienced significantly lower levels of anxiety, had higher levels of cancer knowledge, were better satisfied with the information they received and had a good information provision experience in comparison to the subjects who received the normal care. Therefore, we conclude that MCTIP is a potentially beneficial adjuvant in H&amp;N cancer care. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul J. Allison</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qq633.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gx16m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848t943"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The anisotropic space-time scaling of the atmosphere: turbulence and waves</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pinel, Julien</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis addresses the problem of understanding and quantifying the variability of the atmosphere over wide ranges of space-time scales. We present empirical tests of a scaling model, the 23/9D model, which is an intermittent and anisotropic generalization of classical laws of turbulence - such as the Kolmogorov law - which describes how the statistical properties of atmospheric fields vary with spatial scales. We first address this problem for vertical sections for which there is still an ongoing debate about the nature of atmospheric dynamics: whether it is isotropic with a break in the horizontal scaling or anisotropic, but in a scaling manner. We make the first direct estimate of the joint horizontal-vertical structure function using wind velocity data measured on 14500 aircraft flights segments and demonstrate that it strongly supports the 23/9D model. We also study the consequences of this spatial anisotropy for the full horizontal space-time statistics. By considering that small structures are advected by larger turbulent ones and by considering averages over the latter, we theoretically obtain scale functions (which are generalizations of the notion of scale) which allow us to estimate structure functions and spectra. We test these predictions using geostationary satellite infrared data over the range 5 km to ~10000 km, 1 hour to 2 months. We found that our model could accurately reproduce the 3D (kx, ky, ω) spectral density over the range 1 hour to ~ 4 days and 30 km to ~5000 km. To obtain a more complete description of the statistics, we also found that our model accurately describes atmospheric radiance turbulent flux statistics (including infrared and passive microwave imagery over scale ranges of 100 km to 20000 km, 1 day to 1 year) with only small deviations at small and large scales. We finally show how to include atmospheric waves considered as strongly nonlinear phenomenon driven by turbulent fluxes and constrained by scaling symmetry, thus extending the 23/9D model. The theoretical development proposed is based on an effective turbulence - wave propagator which corresponds to a fractional and anisotropic extension of the classical wave equation propagator with dispersion relation similar to those of inertial gravity waves (and Kelvin waves) yet with anomalous (fractional) order Hwav/2. Using geostationary MTSAT IR radiances, we estimated the parameters finding that Hwav ≈0.17 (the classical value =2).</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse s'intéresse au problème de comprendre et de quantifier la variabilité de l'atmosphère sur de grandes gammes d'échelles spatio-temporelles. Nous présentons des tests empiriques d'un modèle ''scaling'', le modèle 23/9D, qui est une généralisation intermittente et anisotrope des lois classiques de la turbulence - telle la loi de Kolmogorov - qui décrivent comment les propriétés statistiques des champs atmosphériques varient avec l'échelle spatiale. Nous abordons d'abord le problème pour des sections verticales par rapport auxquelles un débat sur la nature de la dynamique atmosphérique continue toujours: l'atmosphère est-il isotrope avec une brisure de symetrie d'échelle dans l'horizontal ou est-il décrit par une symétrie d'échelle, mais anisotrope ? Nous présentons le premier estimé direct de la fonction structure horizontale-verticale sur des vitesses de vent mesurées sur 14500 segments de vols d'avions et démontrons qu'elle supporte fortement le modele 23/9D. Nous étudions également les conséquences de cette symétrie d'échelle anisotrope sur les statistiques dans l'espace horizontal-temporel. En considérant que les plus petites structures turbulentes sont "advectées" par les plus grosses et en considérant un moyennage sur ces dernières, nous obtenons une forme théorique pour la fonction d'échelle (qui est une généralisation de la notion d'échelle), ce qui nous permet d'estimer les fonctions structure et les spectres. Nous testons ensuite ces prédictions à l'aide de données de rayonnement infrarouge prises par des satellites geostationnaires sur l'intervalle 5 km ~ 10000 km, 1 h ~2 mois. Nous avons trouvé que notre modèle pouvait précisement reproduire la densité spectrale 3D (kx, ky, ω) sur l'intervalle 1 h à ~ 4 jours et 30 km à ~5000 km. Afin d'obtenir une description statistique plus complète, nous avons également trouvé que notre modèle décrit précisement les statistiques des flux turbulents de rayonnements atmosphériques (dans l'infrarouge et pour les micro-ondes passives sur la gamme d'échelles 100 km a 20000 km, 1 jour a 1 an) avec seulement de légères déviations à petites et grandes échelles. Finalement, nous démontrons comment inclure les ondes atmosphériques, considerées ici comme un phénomène fortement non-linéaire dirigé par les flux turbulents et contraint par la symétrie d'échelle; étendant donc le modèle 23/9D. Les développements théoriques présentes sont basés sur un propagateur effectif turbulence-ondes qui correspond a une extension fractionnaire et anisotrope du propagateur de l'équation d'ondes classique avec une relation de dispersion similaire à celle des ondes gravitationnelles inertielles (et des onde sde Kelvin), mais d'ordre anormal (fractionnaire) = Hwav/2 . À l'aide de données infrarouge du satellite géostationnaire MTSAT, nous avons estimé les paramètres du modèle, trouvant Hwav ≈0.17, (la valeur classique étant =2).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shaun MacDonald Lovejoy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mn351.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848t943</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Atmosperic Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n681p"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Applications of new phosphorus-based 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition reagents in nitrogen heterocycle synthesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Morin, Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the study of phospha-Münchnones, a new class of 1,3-dipole. These 1,3-dipoles have been previously demonstrated to be accessible in a one-pot reaction of imines, acid chlorides and organophosphorus reagents, and participate in 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition reactions. The objective of the research described in this thesis is to both understand the reactivity of these dipoles, and exploit their cycloaddition with alkynes and alkenes to synthesize pyrroles and 2-pyrrolines with high regio-, diastereo- and enantioselectivity. Chapter 2 focuses on understanding the factors that control regioselectivity in 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition reactions of phospha-Münchnones with alkynes, as well as the related mesoionic heterocycles Münchnones and Münchnone-imines.  While each of the dipoles are established to participate in 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition reactions, until now, no general rules regarding the factors that control regioselectivity have been described. Cycloaddition reactions of the above mentioned dipoles are examined with a range of unsymmetrical electron poor and electron rich alkynes, and by comparing the behavior of these related dipoles, trends are observed in regioselectivity that relates to the alkyne ionization potential. In conjunction with Prof. Houk and Dr. Krenske at UCLA, DFT calculations were performed that provides a rational for the different behaviors of each of these dipoles. Importantly, these 1,3-dipoles display divergent regioselectivity, which can be exploited to synthesize a variety of pyrroles with high selectivity through the use of the appropriate reactant. Similarly, the rational on regioselectivity also allows the prediction of regioselectivity for a wide scope of alkynes. In Chapter 3 we explore the effect of the organophosphorus unit in phospha-Münchnones on their structure, reactivity and regioselectivity. X-ray crystallographic studies demonstrate the significant role of the PR3 unit on the ground state structure of these dipoles and their reactivity.  In addition, the results of the theoretical investigation of Chapter 2 are exploited to show how changes in the phosphorus substituents can be used to fine tune regioselectivity of alkyne cycloadditions without modifying the substituents on the final product.   In Chapter 4, phospha-Münchnone cycloaddition with alkenes is explored. Different phosphites and phosphonites are tested for their ability to mediate intramolecular cycloaddition with alkenes, and optimum results are obtained with (2-catechyl)PPh. Polycyclic 2-pyrrolines are generated in rapid cycloaddition reactions, in a modular fashion from easily accessible starting materials: olefin-tethered imines, acid chlorides and phosphonites. In addition, the reaction proceeds with high diastereo- and regioselectivity. The utility of this reaction has been extended to other products, including in situ reduction of the 2-pyrroline to pyrolidines, or oxidation to form pyrroles. In Chapter 5, a new way to control the enantioselectivity in 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition reactions is described.  By the use of (R)-BINOL-based phosphites, a phospha-Münchnone can be prepared that is easily accessible, modular, yet requires no additional steps to install or remove the chiral fragment.  As such, this provides a straightforward approach to control chirality in 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition reactions.  This has been used to generate polycyclic pyrrolines and pyrrolidines with three or four stereogenic centers in one pot, and up to 99% ee. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse décrit l'étude du phospha-Münchnone, une nouvelle classe de 1,3-dipôle. Il a été démontré précédemment que ces 1,3-dipôles peuvent être facilement générés à partir des imines, des chlorures d'acides et de composés organophosphorés et peuvent être utilisés dans des réactions de cycloadditions 1,3-dipolaires. Le but de cette recherche est à la fois de comprendre la réactivité de ces dipôles et de les exploiter dans des réactions de cycloadditions avec des alcynes et des alcènes pour synthétiser des pyrroles et des 2-pyrrolines de façon hautement régio-, diastéréo- et énantiosélective. Le Chapitre 2 focalise sur la compréhension des facteurs qui contrôlent la régiosélectivité des réactions de cycloadditions 1,3-dipolaires avec les phospha-Münchnones et les alcynes ainsi qu'avec des hétérocycles mésoioniques analogues, les Münchnones et les Münchnones-imines. Malgré que chacun de ces 1,3-dipôles soit reconnu pour sa participation aux réactions de cycloadditions 1,3-dipolaires, aucune règle générale concernant les facteurs qui contrôlent la régiosélectivité n'a été encore établie jusqu'à maintenant. Grâce à l'étude des cycloadditions de ces trois 1,3-dipôles avec une gamme d'alcynes asymétriques électron pauvres et électron riches, et par la comparaison des comportements de ces 1,3-dipôles, des tendances au niveau de la régiosélectivité en fonction du potentiel d'ionisation de l'alcyne ont pu être observées. Conjointement avec le Pr. Houk et le Dr. Krenske à L'UCLA, des calculs DFT ont été réalisés et fournissent une explication logique sur les différents comportements de ces dipôles. De plus, ces 1,3-dipôles présentent des régioselectivités divergentes qui peuvent être exploitées pour la synthèse d'une variété de pyrroles avec de hautes sélectivités grâce au choix du réactif approprié. Cette étude permet également la prédiction de la régiosélectivité pour une large gamme d'alcynes. Dans le Chapitre 3, l'effet de l'unité organophosphorée sur la structure, la réactivité et la régiosélectivité du phospha-Münchnone est étudié. Les études aux rayons-X cristallographiques démontrent le rôle important de l'unité PR3 sur l'état fondamental et la réactivité de ces 1,3-dipôles. De plus, les résultats de l'étude théorique du Chapitre 2 sont exploités pour varier de façon logique les substituants du phosphore afin d'améliorer la régiosélectivité des cycloadditions d'alcynes sans modifier les substituants du produit final. Dans le Chapitre 4, la cycloaddition du phospha-Münchnone avec des alcènes est explorée. Différents phosphites et phosphonites sont testés pour leur capacité à participer aux cycloadditions intramoléculaires d'alcènes, et les résultats optimaux sont obtenus avec le (2-catechyl)PPh. Les 2-pyrrolines polycycliques sont générées dans des réactions de cycloadditions rapides, de façon modulaires et à partir de réactifs facilement accessibles : des imines contenant un alcène, des chlorures d'acyles et des phosphonites. De plus, la réaction procède avec une haute régio- et diastéréosélectivité. L'utilité de cette réaction a été étendue à d'autres produits, avec la réduction in situ des 2-pyrrolines en pyrrolidines, et avec l'oxydation en pyrroles. Dans le Chapitre 5, une nouvelle façon de contrôler l'énantiosélectivité des réactions de cycloadditions 1,3-dipolaires est décrite. Grâce à l'utilisation d'un phosphite substitué par un groupement (R)-BINOL, un nouveau phospha-Münchnone peut être synthétisé avec l'avantage d'être facilement accessible, modulaire, et ne requiert aucune étape supplémentaire pour installer ou enlever le fragment chiral. Cela offre une approche simple pour contrôler la chiralité des réactions de cycloadditions 1,3-dipolaires et générer des pyrrolines et des pyrrolidines polycycliques avec trois ou quatre centres stéréogènes de façon « one-pot » et jusqu'à 99% ee.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bruce A. Arndtsen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nz09s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n681p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w810p"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The epigenetics of suicide: the impact of early-life adversity on brain DNA methylation signature</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Labonté, Benoit</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le suicide est un problème qui résulte de l'interaction entre plusieurs facteurs. Un de ces facteurs, l'adversité durant l'enfance se définissant par une histoire d'abus sexuel et/ou physique de même que par la négligence parentale, est un des facteurs de risque les plus importants en ce qui à trait à l'augmentation des risques de développer des comportements dépressifs et suicidaires à l'âge adulte. Or, si une histoire d'abus augmente les risques de dépression et de suicide, les mécanismes responsables de ces effets comportementaux demeurent néanmoins méconnus. De récentes avancées laissent présager que l'impact comportemental d'une histoire d'abus serait transmis par des mécanismes épigénétiques. En effet, de nombreuses études suggèrent que le stress au cours du jeune âge chez les rongeurs interfère avec l'établissement des schémas de méthylation dans les régions régulatrices des gènes ce qui, en retour, modifie les niveaux d'expression des gènes et induit des changements comportementaux semblables aux symptômes de la dépression. Fait important, des changements semblables ont également été rapportés chez l'humain. Malgré tout, l'ampleur des modifications épigénétiques induites par une histoire d'abus durant l'enfance, de même que leurs conséquences comportementales, demeurent toujours inconnues. Cette thèse vise à améliorer notre compréhension du suicide en élucidant un mécanisme potentiel, soit les mécanismes épigénétiques, par lequel le stress au cours du jeune âge augmenterait la vulnérabilité aux troubles de l'humeur et au suicide. Nous avons premièrement poursuivit la caractérisation des changements de methylation de l'ADN induits par une histoire d'abus dans la région régulatrice du gène du récepteur des glucocorticoides, un des gènes les plus fréquemment associés au stress, la dépression et le suicide. Nous avons ensuite opté pour une approche globale visant à identifier l'ensemble des modifications de methylation de l'ADN dans les régions promotrices de l'ensemble du génome dans le cerveau des suicidaires avec ou sans histoire d'abus durant l'enfance. Nos résultats révèlent la présence de nombreux changements de methylation de l'ADN dans plusieurs gènes impliqués dans la régulation comportementale. Nos résultats supportent également l'implication de plusieurs autres gènes affectés spécifiquement par une histoire d'abus durant l'enfance. Les travaux de cette thèse ont également mis l'emphase sur l'impact fonctionnel de ces altérations sur l'expression des gènes et la régulation de l'activité transcriptionnelle des régions promotrices affectées. Dans l'ensemble, ce travail détaille et définit les mécanismes moléculaires par lesquels l'environnement induit des changements comportementaux conférant une vulnérabilité envers les troubles de l'humeur et les comportements suicidaires.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Suicide is a problem resulting from the interaction between several factors. Among these factors, early-life adversity, characterized by child sexual and physical abuse as well as parental neglect, is one of the strongest risk factors for depression and suicidal behaviors. While it is clear that child abuse increases the risk for depression and suicide, the mechanisms mediating these effects are still unknown. Recent evidences suggest that epigenetic mechanisms may be involved in mediating the effects of early-life adversity on behavior. Early-life stress in animals has been shown to alter DNA methylation in genes regulatory regions what, in turn, has been associated with changes in gene expression and behavioral modifications. Importantly, similar changes have been reported in several genes in the human brain. However, although epigenetic modifications have been found in several genes, the extent of epigenetic changes induced by early-life adversity is still unknown and their impacts on increasing suicide risk are unclear. This thesis aims at expanding our understanding of suicide by investigating one potential mechanism by which early-life adversity may increase vulnerability to mood disorders and suicide, namely epigenetic regulation of gene expression. We first expanded our characterization of DNA methylation alterations induced by early and adult-life stress in the regulatory regions of the glucocorticoid receptor gene which is one of the most consistent alterations associated with stress, depression and suicidal behaviors. We then opted for a genome-wide characterization of DNA methylation alterations found in the brains of suicide completers with and without a history of child abuse using microarray analyses focusing on gene promoters throughout the genome. Our findings revealed several DNA methylation alterations in genes with known roles on behavioral regulation and identified several new genes and networks which may be specifically altered by early-life adversity. We also characterized the functional impact of these alterations on gene expression and promoter transcriptional activity. Overall, this work identifies and characterizes the molecular mechanisms by which environment induces behavioral changes conferring vulnerability toward mood disorders and suicidal behaviors. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gustavo Turecki</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jf62b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w810p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abv73c4084"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Information Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of information use strategies on ill structured-domain graduate learning tasks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Weerapura, Kaushilya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La présente thèse est une étude interdisciplinaire, centrée sur l'utilisateur, portant sur l'utilisation de l'information stratégique.  Dans le cadre de contextes d'apprentissage complexes, notamment dans les domaines mal structurés, les avantages tirés de l'information obtenue répondent à trois fonctions.  La première est la construction de sens à partir de fragments d'information pour obtenir un portrait cohésif global.  La seconde est l'intégration du sens construit dans les structures de connaissances de l'apprenant.  La troisième est l'intégration du tout pour atteindre les objectifs d'apprentissage.  La littérature en sciences de l'information regroupe ces trois fonctions sous l'appellation « utilisation de l'information ».  Les stratégies relatives à ces fonctions permettent à l'apprenant de surmonter les défis qui découlent de l'utilisation de l'information dans de tels contextes.  La thèse présente une enquête qualitative sur l'influence des stratégies pertinentes à l'utilisation de l'information dans le cadre de tâches d'apprentissage dans des domaines mal structurés. L'étude naturaliste a été conçue pour découvrir la nature générale du processus d'utilisation de l'information et l'influence des stratégies dans ce processus.  Une approche et centrée sur l'utilisateur a permis d'examiner le processus d'utilisation de l'information de neuf étudiants aux études supérieures de la Faculté de l'éducation de l'Université McGill au cours d'un semestre.L'enquête a porté sur deux tâches d'apprentissage dans des domaines mal structurés.  La première tâche comportait une série de critiques réflexives sur les lectures obligatoires du cours.  Ces critiques étaient distribuées tout au long de la session et chacune d'entre elles portait sur un aspect théorique du cours.  La deuxième tâche était un travail de session où l'étudiant devait proposer une recherche basée sur les aspects théoriques présentés dans le cadre du cours.  Cette proposition exigeait des apprenants qu'ils synthétisent la théorie et utilisent les connaissances acquises dans le cours pour proposer une nouvelle recherche propre aux sciences de l'éducation.  Les deux tâches faisaient appel à des processus cognitifs de niveau supérieur.  Les critères relatifs aux tâches justifiaient l'approche et ont permis l'étude détaillée des stratégies, en plus d'offrir une contribution originale, théorique et pratique, pour les sciences de l'information.Les deux cadres conceptuels de l'étude comptent parmi les contributions théoriques.  Le premier cadre conceptuel offre un aperçu du processus d'utilisation de l'information approprié dans le cadre de tâches d'apprentissage dans des domaines mal structurés.  Le second cadre conceptuel démontre l'influence des stratégies dans le processus.  Les deux cadres théoriques peuvent être utilisés comme pierre d'assise pour d'éventuelles études sur le comportement informationnel.Du point de vue pragmatique, ces cadres conceptuels peuvent être utilisés pour concevoir des programmes éducatifs afin d'améliorer le rendement des étudiants.  L'approche centrée sur l'utilisateur permet de tenir compte de la subjectivité de l'étudiant et son intégration dans les programmes.  Ainsi, le cadre conceptuel pour les stratégies d'utilisation de l'information pourrait servir à informer les apprenants sur les techniques de construction de plans de stratégies dynamiques et optimales qui s'adapteront à leurs objectifs d'apprentissage et aux stades progressifs de l'utilisation de l'information.L'enquête repose sur une approche interdisciplinaire.  Dans un premier temps, l'approche de la construction de sens (sensemaking) de Dervin (1983) et la théorie de la flexibilité cognitive de Spiro (1987) ont guidé l'enquête.  Dans un second temps, l'aspect stratégique du processus d'utilisation de l'information se base principalement sur la littérature des sciences de l'éducation, notamment la perspective orientée stratégie de Pressley (1989) comme assise théorique.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This dissertation presents a user-centred, interdisciplinary study on information use strategies.  In complex learning contexts such as ill-structured-domains, there are three ways of using information.  The first is to make sense of the information fragments to construct a cohesive whole.  The second is to integrate this newly constructed whole into the learner's existing knowledge structures.  The third is to make use of this integrated entity to achieve the learning goals.  The Information Science literature refers to this three-fold process as "using information".  A number of strategies can be applied to using information in order to help learners address the challenges of using information within these complex contexts.  This dissertation study is a qualitative inquiry on the influence such strategies can have on using information to complete ill-structured-domain learning tasks.This was a naturalistic study designed to better understand both the general nature of the information use process and the influence of strategies on this process.  The study consisted of a user-centred study that examined the information use process of nine graduate students enrolled in the faculty of Education at McGill University over the period of an academic semester.  This investigation focused on two graduate level ill-structured-domain learning tasks.  The first was to produce a set of reflective critiques on the required course readings over the course of the term, one for each theory studied.  The second task was a final term paper that proposed research based on the theories studied in the course.  Learners were required to synthesize the theories and the course content in order to propose a research study relevant to the field of Education.  Both tasks required the use of higher order thinking skills.  The information use strategies used by students during these two tasks were studied in order to better understand their nature and thus make an original contribution towards theory and practice in the Information Science. The two frameworks developed by this study represent theoretical contributions.  The first framework provides an overview of the information use process in an ill-structured-domain learning task.  The second framework demonstrates the influence of strategies on this process.  These two frameworks could be used as springboards for future Information Science research.These frameworks could also be used to design instructional programs in such a way as to improve student performance.  This represents a contribution to professional practice.  The user-centered approach provides insights on factoring in user subjectivity into these programs.  The framework for information use strategies can help inform learners on how to construct dynamic and optimal strategies and plans that are best adapted to their learning goals and to the progressive stages of using information.A number of interdisciplinary propositions guided this investigation.  The investigation of the information use process was predominantly guided by Dervin's (1983) “sensemaking approach” and Spiro's (1987) "cognitive flexibility theory".  The analysis of strategies in the information use process relied mostly on the Education literature and employed Pressley's (1989) "strategy oriented perspective" as the key theoretical concept.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kimiz Lutfiye Dalkir</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580r12c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c4084</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Higher</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290f00t"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biased allosteric regulation of the Prostaglandin F2α receptor: from small molecules to large receptor complexes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Goupil, Eugénie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs) represent the largest family of cell surface receptors, and thus some of the most important targets for drug discovery. By binding to the orthosteric site where endogenous ligands bind, agonists and antagonists differentially modulate signals sent downstream from these receptors. New evidence suggests that GPCRs possess topographically distinct or allosteric binding sites, which may differentially modulate agonist- and antagonist-mediated responses to selectively affect distinct signalling pathways coupled to the same receptor. These sites may either positively or negatively regulate receptor activity, depending on the pathway in question, and thus can act as biased ligands, leading to functional selectivity (or ligand-directed signalling). Another way of allosterically regulating GPCR signalling is through receptor oligomerization, which has recently emerged as a common mechanism for regulating receptor function. The GPCR for prostaglandin F2α FP, is implicated in many important physiological responses, such as parturition, smooth muscle cell contraction and blood pressure regulation. Therefore, evaluating the potential use of allosteric modulators of FP to fine-tune PGF2α-mediated signals, as well as generating a better understanding of its putative oligomerization partners would be of significant pharmacological and clinical interest. In this thesis, I studied the impact of modulating, in both heterologous (HEK 293 cells) and homologous (osteoblast, myometrial or vascular smooth muscle cells) systems, downstream cellular responses of FP by 1) an orthosteric, but biased ligand, previously characterized as a neutral antagonist 2) an allosteric molecule, designed based on the extracellular domains of FP, which had biased signalling properties and, 3) heterodimerization with a receptor partner, the angiotensin II type I receptor, where I demonstrated the asymmetrical organization of this new signalling unit both in vitro and in vivo. Overall, my thesis unveils important roles for biased, allosteric ligands and receptor oligomerization in modulating FP signalling. This work also demonstrates the importance of understanding distinct receptor conformations, and their effects on cellular responses, which are adopted when GPCRs are allosterically modulated, to design better therapeutics with improved efficacy profiles and reduced side effects.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les récepteurs couplés aux protéines G (RCPGs) repésentent la plus grande famille des récepteurs exprimés à la membrane plasmique et sont aussi considérés comme étant des cibles imporantes dans la découverte de nouveaux médicaments. Lorsque des agonistes ou antagonistes se lient au site de liaison endogène d'un RCPG, ou site orthostérique, ces derniers peuvent en moduler les signaux déployés en aval. De nouvelles évidences suggèrent que les RCPGs possèdent des sites de liaison topographiquement distincts des sites orthostériques, appelés sites allostériques. Ces sites allostériques sont suspectés de sélectivement réguler les différents sentiers de signalisation induits lorsque les récepteurs sont liés, de manière concomitante, par des agonistes ou antagonites. De plus, ces sites allostériques peuvent réguler de manière positive ou négative les différentes activités d'un RCPG, et donc être considérés comme étant des ligands biasés, menant à ce qui est appelé la sélectivité fonctionnelle (aussi connue sous le nom de signalisation dirigée par le ligand). Une autre façon de réguler les signaux des RCPGs, qui est présentement vue comme un autre mécanisme contrôlant leur fonction, est l'oligomérization de ces derniers avec d'autres RCPGs, phénomène pouvant être aussi considéré comme de l'allostérisme. Le RCPG pour la prostaglandine F2α, FP, est impliqué dans plusieur réponses physiologiques d'importance, telles la parturition, la contraction des cellules musculaires lisses, ou même la régulation de la pression sanguine. En somme, l'évaluation des différentes façons par lesquelles les signaux de FP peuvent être altérés, soit par l'utilisation d'un modulateur allostérique, soit par l'oligomérisation avec d'autres RCPG, est considérée primordiale d'un point de vue clinique et pharmacologique.Dans cette thèse, j'ai étudié les impacts de la modulation des réponses en aval de FP dans des systèmes hétérologues (cellules HEK 293) ou homologues (cellules ostéoblastiques, myométriales ou musculaires lisses vasculaires), lorsque celui-ci était régulé par 1) un ligand orthostérique, mais à fonctions biaisées, connu précédemment comme un antagoniste neutre, 2) une molecule allostérique, inspirée des domaines extracellulaires de FP, étant aussi capable de propriétés de signalisation biaisées et par 3) l'hétérodimérisation de FP avec un autre récepteur- « partenaire », le récepteur à l'angiotensine II, pour lequel j'ai démonté la présence d'une organisation asymétrique de cette nouvelle « unité » de signalisation, in vitro et in vivo.De manière générale, ma thèse soulève le rôle des ligands biaisés ou allostériques, ainsi que de l'oligomérisation, dans la modulation des signaux cellulaies dirigés par FP. Le travail accompli démontre aussi l'importance de comprendre les différentes conformations, et leurs effets sur les réponses cellulaires, prises quand les RCPGs sont modulés, afin de générer de meilleurs médicaments ayant une meilleure efficacité, mais aussi des effets secondaires plus minimes. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stephane Laporte</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Terence Hebert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956k476.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290f00t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s834h"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Matrix fixed charge density modulates exudate concentration during cartilage compression</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ko, Lok Shun</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le potentiel d'écoulement est due à la présence de charges fixes négatives sur les glycosaminoglycanes de la matrice extracellulaire du cartilage. Son évaluation arthroscopique peut potentiellement détecter les lésions localisées et fournir de l'information diagnostique quantitatif. La filtration d'électrolyte est également un phénomène découlant des glycosaminoglycanes. Généralement supposé négligeable malgré un manque de validation expérimentale, il peut être important pour la conception et l'interprétation des measurements du potentiel d'écoulement et pour le choix des suppositions de modélisation. L'objectif de cette thèse est donc de quantifier le phénomène de filtration d'électrolyte et d'estimer son effet sur les mesures de potentiel d'écoulement. La concentration de chlorure dans l'exsudat de cartilage comprimé a été mesurée et le contenu de GAG a été colorimétriquement dosé. Des études pilotes ont indiqué qu'une vitesse de déformation de 8x10^(-3) s^(-1) était appropriée afin d'éliminer les préoccupations d'évaporation d'exsudat ainsi que du dommage à l'explant (à haute et basse vitesses, respectivement). La concentration d'exsudat des explants équilibrés dans 1x PBS et soumis à une deformation de 37,5, 50 et 62,5% était significativement (p&lt;0.05) inférieure à celle du bain, avec claire dépendance sur la magnitude de déformation. Elle était également significativement inférieure lorsqu'une deformation de 50% a été appliquée après l'équilibrage en 0,5, 1 et 2x PBS. La différence relative avec le bain semblait augmenter avec la diminution de la concentration de celui-ci (p=0,065 entre 0,5 et 2 PBS). La baisse de concentration de l'exsudat a corrélé négativement avec le contenu de glycosaminoglycanes post-compression, alors qu'aucune différence n'a jamais été détectée dans l'exsudat des explants d'agarose. Nos résultats démontrent que la concentration d'exsudat de cartilage comprimé est dilué par rapport au bain en raison de la présence des charges fixes. Cette différence mène à la génération de potentiels de diffusion durant la mesure du potentiel d'écoulement, surtout sous les conditions de haute déformation et de faible vitesse de deformation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Streaming potentials arise from the presence of negative fixed charges in cartilage extracellular matrix glycosaminoglycans. Arthroscopic assessment of these potentials can potentially detect localized surface lesions and provide quantitative diagnostic information. Electrolyte filtration is also a phenomenon arising from glycosaminoglycans. Commonly assumed negligible despite a lack of experimental validation, it can be important for design and interpretation of streaming potential measurements and choice of modeling assumptions. The objective of this thesis was therefore to quantify electrolyte filtration and estimate its effect on streaming potential measurements. Chloride ion concentration in exudate of compressed cartilage was measured and explant GAG content was colorimetrically assayed. Pilot studies indicated that an appropriate strain rate for experiments was 8x10^(-3) s^(-1) in order to eliminate concerns of exudate evaporation and explant damage (at low and high strain rates, respectively). Exudate concentration of explants equilibrated in 1x PBS was significantly (p&lt;0.05) lower than bath at strains of 37.5, 50 and 62.5%, with clear dependence on magnitude. Exudate concentration was also significantly lower than that of the bath when 50% strain was applied after equilibration in 0.5, 1 and 2x PBS while the relative difference seemed to increase with decreasing bath concentration (p=0.065 between 0.5 and 2x PBS). Decreasing exudate concentration correlated negatively with increasing post-compression GAG concentration, while no difference between exudate concentration and bath concentration was ever observed for compression of uncharged agarose gel controls. Findings show that exudate from compressed cartilage is dilute relative to bath due to the presence of matrix fixed charges. This difference leads to the generation of extraneous diffusion potentials during streaming potential measurements, particularly under conditions of low strain rates and high strains. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thomas Quinn</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j239p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s834h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak643b4567"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Medical Physics Unit</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Scatter artifact correction in cone-beam CT images</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Watson, Peter</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les images de tomodensitométrie à faisceau conique (CBCT) souffrent d'une qualité d'image inférieure en partie due aux rayonnement diffusés. Dans cet ouvrage, un algorithme Monte Carlo rapide et précis fut appliqué sur des images CBCT cliniques. En utilisant un logiciel de transport de particules à base Monte Carlo pour transporter des photons dans un CBCT où les données n'ont pas été corrigés, la contribution des photons diffusés primaires et secondaires pour chaque image fut estimée. En utilisant cet estimé, une correction fut apportée sur les données du CBCT. La méthode de correction CBCT a démontré sa capacité de mitiger les artéfacts introduient par la diffusion des photons. Les images corrigées ont montré une plus grande précision pour la reconstruction des coéfficients d'atténuation. Ces résultats suggèrent que la méthode proposée pour corriger des images CBCT fut un succès pour l'amélioration de la qualité d'images CBCT réelles, et insinuent une utilisation able des images CBCT en radiothérapie adaptative.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cone-beam computed tomography (CBCT) images suffer from poor image quality, in a large part due to scattered x-rays. In this work, a fast and accurate Monte Carlo based scatter correction algorithm was implemented on real CBCT data. A fast Monte Carlo simulation developed in the EGSnrc framework was used to transport photons through an uncorrected CBCT scan. From the simulation output, the contribution from both primary and scattered photons for each projection image was estimated. Using these estimates, a subtractive scatter correction was performed on the CBCT projection data. Implementation of the scatter correction algorithm on CBCT phantom scans was shown to help mitigate scatter-induced artifacts, such as cupping and streaking. The scatter corrected images were also shown to have improved accuracy in reconstructed attenuation coefficient values. These results suggest that the proposed scatter correction algorithm is successful in improving image quality in real CBCT images, and are promising results towards the reliable use of CBCT images in adaptive radiotherapy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jan Peter Frans Seuntjens</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z429.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b4567</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Radiation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax059cb867"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the regulation of the matrix metalloproteinase-3 and its role in metastasis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Seccareccia, Erica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les métastases sont responsables de la majorité des décès causé par les cancers. Les facteurs biologiques qui déterminent le site des tumeurs secondaires ne sont pas bien compris, mais pourraient aider au traitement de cette maladie. Les métalloproteinases de la matrice (MMPs) sont responsables de la dégradation de la matrice extracellulaire et en plus, elles sont des régulateurs du microenvironnement. Une corrélation a déjà été montrée entre le profil des MMPs chez les tumeurs primaires et les sites où vont s'implanter les métastases. Dans cette étude, on a examiné le rôle de la MMP-3 dans la capacité à former des métastases d'une lignée cellulaire dérivée de carcinome des poumons de Lewis (M27). De plus, on a examiné les signaux de transduction responsables de la régulation de la MMP-3 dans un environnement où l'expression du récepteur au facteur de croissance à l'insuline (IGF-I) était altérée. Précédemment, on a demontré que l'expression de l'IGF-IR (M27R) régulait négativement l'expression de la MMP-3 et ceci a abrogé les métastases aux poumons. Ici, on démontre que l'expression d'IGF-IR régule négativement l'expression de la kinase IκB ε (IKKε). La surexpression d'IKKε dans les cellules M27R (M27R/IKKε), reconstitue partiellement l'expression de MMP-3 dans les cellules M27R. En addition, l'expression de MMP-3 dans ces cellules peuvent être stimulées suite à l'ajout de phorbol 12-myristate 13-acetate (PMA). Cette stimulation dépendait sur la kinase des protéines C (PKC) α et sur le facteur de transcription, p65. Finalement, la reconstitution de l'expression de la MMP-3, dans les cellules M27R, a permis à celles-ci de former des métastases dans les poumons. L'ensemble de nos résultats démontre qu'IKKε participe dans la régulation de l'expression de la MMP-3 et de plus que la MMP-3 serait impliquée dans la formation des métastases aux niveaux des poumons.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cancer metastasis is the major cause of death from malignant disease. The biological factors that dictate the secondary site(s) of a primary tumor remain largely unknown, yet their understanding would greatly facilitate the management of malignancy. Matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) are responsible for the degradation of the extracellular matrix and regulate the tumor microenvironment. The expression of specific MMPs in primary tumors has been correlated with the extent and site of metastatic disease and may therefore potentially be predictive of the preferred site of metastasis. In this study, a subline of the Lewis lung carcinoma (M27 cells) was used to study the role of MMP-3 in lung metastasis as well as elucidate the signaling pathways that regulate its expression in a cellular context where expression of the insulin like growth factor-I receptor (IGF-IR) is altered. Previous work demonstrated that following ectopic expression of the IGF-IR in M27 cells (M27R cells) MMP-3 expression was downregulated and this coincided with a loss of lung metastasis. Here it is shown that the ectopic expression of the IGF-IR downregulates the expression of IκB kinase ε (IKKε). Reconstitution of IKKε expression (M27R/IKKε cells), partly restored MMP-3 expression in M27R cells and furthermore, it sensitized MMP-3 expression levels to induction by phorbol 12-myristate 13-acetate (PMA). This induction was, in turn, dependent on protein kinase C (PKC) α and the transcription factor p65. Finally, reconstituting MMP-3 expression in M27R cells enabled their metastasis to the lungs. Collectively, our results implicate IKKε as a regulator of MMP-3 expression and implicate MMP-3 in lung metastasis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Penina Brodt</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451n056.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059cb867</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd3761139"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic variability of test-day urea nitrogen and lactose in milk of Jersey, Brown Swiss and Ayrshire cattle breeds in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bajwa, Imran</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le Programme d'analyse des troupeaux laitiers du Québec (Valacta, Québec, Canada) a fourni une imposante base de données de relevées laitiers au jour du contrôle pour des vaches ayant vêlé entre janvier 2000 et mai 2007. Cette base de données contenait 919,814 relevées de production laitière au jour du contrôle provenant de 45520 vaches de race Ayrshire sur 956 fermes laitières, 133,690 relevés provenant de 7493 vaches de race Jersey sur 910 fermes laitières, et 118,996 relevés de 5693 vaches de race Suisse Brune sur 476 fermes laitières. Les relevées au jour du contrôle pour les trois premiers rangs de vêlage une fois édités servirent à faire l'estimation de paramètres génétiques grâce à une méthode de maximum de vraisemblance restreint. Pour chacun des trois premiers rangs de vêlage, les paramètres génétiques de six caractères laitiers, soit le rendement en lait, gras, lactose, et protéine totale, la cote de cellules somatiques et la teneur en azote uréique (TAU), furent estimés à l'aide de divers modèles de régression aléatoire de jour du contrôle. Des modèles de régression aléatoire, utilisant des polynômes de Legendre de 2e à 4e ordre ou une fonction Wilmink avec un terme exponentiel variant de ¬-0.01 to -0.09 en pas de 0.02, servirent à l'estimation des niveaux d'héritabilité quotidiens de chacun de ces caractères. Des modèles de régression aléatoire à deux variables de jour du contrôle pour animaux avec polynômes de Legendre comme coefficients de régression, servirent à l'estimation des corrélations génétiques et environnementales entre les caractères du rendement laitiers. L'exactitude des modèles de régression aléatoire à simple variable furent comparés selon le critère d'information Bayésien (CIB), le critère d'information de Akaike (CIA), la somme des carrés résiduelle, et l'erreur absolue moyenne. Les modèles utilisant les polynômes de Legendre pour les effets fixes et aléatoires furent parmi les meilleurs, tandis que pour certains caractères la fonction Wilmink mena à des estimées irréalistes de l'héritabilité. Pour les vaches de race Ayrshire cows, les héritabilités estimées moyennes furent de 0.39, 0.30 et 0.41 pour la TAU et de 0.39, 0.20 et 0.33 pour le rendement en lactose, pour les 1e, 2e, et 3e rangs de vêlage, respectivement. Pour les vaches de race Suisse Brune estimées moyennes furent de 0.28, 0.26 et 0.13 pour la TAU, et 0.30, 0.20 et 0.42 pour le rendement en lactose, pour les 1e, 2e, et 3e rangs de vêlage, respectivement. De façon semblable, pour les vaches de race Jersey, les héritabilités estimées moyennes furent de 0.26, 0.20 et 0.14 pour la TAU, et 0.42, 0.51 et 0.12 pour le rendement en lactose, pour les 1e, 2e, et 3e rangs de vêlage, respectivement. À l'exception faite de la cote de cellules somatiques, avec laquelle la corrélation génétique était très petite mais positive, des corrélations génétiques négatives mais proches de zéro existèrent entre la TAU et les autres caractères du rendement pour le 1e rang de vêlage des vaches de la race Ayrshire. Pour les 2e et 3e rangs de vêlage les corrélations génétiques furent petites et positives, à l'exception de celles pour la cote de cellules somatiques au 3e rang de vêlage, où la corrélation génétique était positive et modérée. Donc, en général, la corrélation génétique et la corrélation environnementale entre la TAU et les autres caractères de rendement furent proches de zéro. Ces mêmes corrélations furent positives et élevées entre le rendement en gras, protéine et lactose du lait pour les trois premiers rangs de vêlage des trois races. A l'exception du 1e et 2e rang de vêlage de la race Jersey où les corrélations entre la TAU et la cote de cellules somatiques s'avérèrent positifs mais proches de zéro, les corrélations entre la cote de cellules somatiques et les autres caractères s'avérèrent négatifs, variant de modéré à élevé.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A large dataset of test-day milk records for cows having calved between January 2000 and May 2007, was obtained from the Quebec Dairy Herd Improvement Programme, Valacta, Quebec, Canada. This dataset contained 919,814 test-day milk yield records from 45520 Ayrshire cows on 956 dairy farms, 133,690 records from 7493 Jersey cows on 910 dairy farms, and 118,996 records from 5693 Brown Swiss on 476 dairy farms. Test-day records from the first three parities after editing served in the estimation of genetic parameters using a Restricted Maximum Likelihood method. The genetic parameters of six milk yield traits — milk, fat, lactose and protein yields, somatic cell score, and milk urea nitrogen (MUN) — were estimated using various random regression test-day models in the first three parities separately. Random regression test-day animal models for a single trait with Legendre polynomials of 2nd to 4th order and the Wilmink function with an exponential term of  0.01 to  0.09 with a step size of 0.02 were used for the estimation of daily heritability of the traits. Bivariate random regression test-day animal models with Legendre polynomials as regression coefficients served to estimate genetic and permanent environmental correlations among the milk yield traits. Single-trait random regression models were compared using BIC, AIC, residual sum of squares and mean absolute error. The models using Legendre polynomials for the fixed and random effects were among the best models; the Wilmink function resulted in unrealistic heritability estimates for some of the traits. For Ayrshire cows, mean heritability estimates were 0.39, 0.30 and 0.41 for MUN and 0.39, 0.20 and 0.33 for lactose yield, in the 1st, 2nd and 3rd parities, respectively. For Brown Swiss cows, mean heritability estimates were 0.28, 0.26 and 0.13 for MUN, and 0.30, 0.20 and 0.42 for lactose yields, in the 1st, 2nd and 3rd parities, respectively. Likewise, for Jersey cows, mean heritability estimates were 0.26, 0.20 and 0.14 for MUN, and 0.42, 0.51 and 0.12 for lactose yield, in the 1st, 2nd and 3rd parities, respectively. The largest heritability estimates were obtained for the Ayrshire breed in the first parity and the lowest estimates were obtained for the Jersey and Brown Swiss breeds, particularly in the later parities. Genetic correlations of MUN with other yield traits were negative and near zero in the 1st parity for Ayrshire cows, with the exception of SCS, where the genetic correlation was positive and near zero. In the 2nd parity the genetic correlations of MUN with other yield traits were positive and low. In the 3rd parity the genetic correlations of MUN with other yield traits were positive and low, except the genetic correlations with SCS, which was positive and moderate. The genetic and permanent environmental correlations between MUN and other yield traits were close to zero. The genetic and permanent environmental correlations among milk fat, protein and lactose yields were positive and high in the first three parities for the three breeds. The genetic correlation and permanent environment correlation between SCS and all other traits were negative and moderate to high except in the 1st and 2nd parity for the Jersey breed, where genetic correlations between MUN and SCS were positive and near zero.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roger I. Cue</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311s87p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd3761139</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Animal Culture and Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1g05fg31t"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of risk-index tool to predict surgical site infections</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Karellis, Angeliki</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les infections du site opératoire (ISO) constituent une des plus fréquentes complications à la suite d'une chirurgie. Les ISOs ont plusieurs conséquences chez le patient incluant un séjour prolongé à l'hôpital, des coûts d'hôpitaux plus élevés, un risque plus accru de requérir des soins intensifs ainsi qu'un risque de morbidité et de mortalité plus élevé. Il existe trois types d'ISOs : ISO incisionelle superficielle, le plus commun néanmoins le moins sérieux, ISO incisionelle profonde et ISO d'organe et/ou d'espace, le plus dangereux des trois. À cause de l'émergence accrue des bactéries résistantes aux antibiotiques, les traitements de certaines ISOs sont inefficaces chez la majorité des patients avec une ISO. En conséquence, plus d'attention doit être fournie avant et pendant la chirurgie afin de prévenir à tout prix les ISOs au lieu de se concentrer sur les traitements de cettes infections. Les données pris de la littérature scientifique ont identifié des facteurs de risque qui prédisposent les patients chirurgicaux pour le développement des ISOs. Cependant, aucun modèle de risque valide n'a été produit afin de quantifier le risque de développer un ISO. Les données pour cette étude ont été obtenues grâce à la base de données NSQIP (National Surgical Quality Improvement Program) établie à l'Hôpital Général Juif et incluent les patients qui ont subi une chirurgie à cet hôpital entre novembre 2009 et décembre 2011. Nous avons choisi d'utiliser la base de données NSQIP puisqu'elle est prospective, impartiale et compréhensive. Des analyses bivariées et des régressions logistiques multivariées ont été employées afin d'identifier les cinq facteurs de risque suivants qui sont indépendamment et significativement associés avec le risque d'un ISO : le sexe male, l'hospitalisation du patient, l'hypertension, l'usage de corticostéroïdes et la dépendance (partielle ou totale) pour des activités quotidiennes avant la chirurgie. Des modèles de régression logistique avec une analyse de courbe ROC ont été utilisés pour développer un outil de pointage de risque pour ISO et délimite les catégories en incréments de risque. Les patients avec un score inférieur de 43.17 sont considérés des patients à risque minime de développer un ISO, ceux avec un score entre 43.17 et 63.40 ont un risque modéré d'acquérir un ISO et ceux avec un score de 63.40 ou plus haut ont un risque élevé pour le développement d'un ISO. Comparé à des patients qui ont un risque minime, les patients avec risque modéré ont un risque relatif de 3.96 fois (p&lt;0.001, 95% CI=2.58-6.08) de développer un ISO et les patients à risqué élevé ont un risque relatif de 6.48 (p&lt;0.001, 95% CI=4.16-10.10) d'acquérir un ISO. Dans cette étude, un outil de risque simple afin de quantifier le risque d'ISO à l'hôpital Général Juif a été développé. L'outil possède la validité externe pour la population de cet hôpital. La validation pour les autres populations sera requise dans des études futures.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Surgical site infections (SSI) are one of the most common complications following surgery. SSIs can incur many consequences for the patient including extended hospital stay, increased hospital costs, increased risk of entering the ICU as well as increased risk of morbidity and mortality. There are three types of SSIs: superficial incisional SSIs, the most common yet the least severe, deep incisional SSIs and organ/space SSIs, the most life-threatening. Due to the high emergence of resistant bacteria, treatment with common antibiotics is ineffective in the majority of patients with an SSI. Therefore, more attention must be paid preoperatively and intraoperatively to prevent SSIs rather than to treat these infections. The data of the literature have identified risk factors that predispose surgical patients to SSIs, however validated risk-index tools have not been developed to quantify the risk of SSI. The data for this study was obtained from the NSQIP (National Surgical Quality Improvement Program) database established at the JGH and included patients undergoing surgery at this institution between November 2009 and December 2011. The database was selected because it is prospective, non-biased and comprehensive. Bivariate analyses and stepwise multivariate logistic regression were used to identify the following five risk factors that were independently and significantly associated with the risk of an SSI: male gender, inpatient status, hypertension, corticosteroid use and partial or total dependence for everyday activities prior to surgery. Logistic regression models with an ROC curve analysis were used to develop a risk scoring tool for SSI and limits for incremental risk categories. Patients with a score below 43.17 were at low-risk, those with a score between 43.17 and 63.40 were at moderate-risk and those with a score above 63.40 were at high-risk for SSI development. Compared to low-risk patients, moderate-risk patients had a relative risk of 3.963 (p&lt;0.001, 95% CI=2.58-6.08) of developing an SSI and high-risk patients had a relative risk of 6.48 (p&lt;0.001, 95% CI=4.16-10.10) of acquiring an SSI. Overall, approximately 3% of low-risk patients, 10% of moderate-risk patients and 16% of high-risk patients of the NSQIP database developed any type of SSI. In this study, a simple risk tool for quantifying SSI risk created at the JGH was developed. The tool has external validity for the JGH population. Validation in other populations will be required in future studies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Sotirios Sampalis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429d85n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fg31t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1n79h786x"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Urban Planning</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Incorporating issues of social justice and equity into transportation planning and policy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Manaugh, Kevin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La planification des transports au 20e siècle a été principalement fondée sur l'objectif de la mobilité : les systèmes de transport ont été vus avant tout comme un moyen sécuritaire, rapide et efficace de mettre en réseau des personnes et de transporter des marchandises. Cependant, au fil du siècle, les mouvements culturels, sociétaux et écologiques ont peu à peu changé la façon dont les planificateurs perçoivent le transport en général et le transport en commun spécifiquement. Plusieurs préoccupations se chevauchant ont profondément modifié le rôle que les urbanistes et les élus attribuent au transport et à l'aménagement du territoire. La dégradation de l'environnement, la pollution atmosphérique, la congestion routière, l'avenir énergétique, et les changements climatiques, ont radicalement redéfini les priorités du transport. Ces préoccupations ont conduit à un intérêt croissant pour le transport en commun et pour le transport actif, la marche et le vélo, apparaissant de plus en plus comme des solutions potentielles aux problèmes environnementaux.Cependant, en dehors de ces préoccupations environnementales, des questions importantes se posent en matière de redistribution et de justice sociale. Les nouvelles infrastructures de transport offrent des avantages évidents tels que l'accès facilité a une destination voulue, la stimulation du développement économique ou la réduction des temps de déplacement. En outre, bien que diverses valeurs et idéaux sous-tendent une politique, ceux-ci peuvent influencer de manière contradictoire les décisions prises en matière de planification des . Cependant, de nombreux objectifs ayant trait aux questions d'équité sociale sont «intangibles» en matière de résultats quantifiables. Cela les rend difficiles à présenter à la population, ce qui conduit à des décisions aux gains potentiels plus grands en terme de capital politique que ne le sont des objectifs de progrès social difficilement mesurables.À la lumière de ces préoccupations, cette thèse vise à répondre à quatre questions de recherche: •Comment les municipalités et les organismes de planification du transport équilibrent le traitement des objectifs économiques, sociaux et environnementaux dans les plans de transport?•Comment ces décisions influencent les résultats, en particulier en ce qui concerne l'équité sociale?•Comment les méthodes de mesure actuelles, la compréhension du transport actif et le potentiel piétonnier d'un quartier peuvent être améliorés afin de mieux en saisir les  des objectifs généraux?•Comment ces résultats seront utilisés à l'avenir pour améliorer la prise de décision? Cette thèse met en évidence l'importance d'adopter des méthodes multidimensionnelles et des approches mixtes lors de l'examen des questions complexes et des processus urbains ; elle contribue à l'enrichissement de la connaissance de trois façons:•Par l'identification d'un ensemble d'indicateurs qui rendent compte des facteurs d'équité sociale dans la planification des transports et dans la prise de décision;•Par l'élaboration des méthodes permettant d'évaluer une infrastructure de transport en utilisant des mesures d'accessibilité qui se concentrent sur les destinations souhaitées par les résidents;•Par une meilleure compréhension de la façon dont les gens et les ménages de différentes catégories socio-économiques «répondent» à des paramètres d'accessibilité locale et régionale. Alors que la plupart, sinon toutes les études ne font qu'utiliser les facteurs socio-économiques, mon travail se concentre directement sur ces facteurs, avec pour objectif principal de les mettre au premier plan.Ce faisant, cette recherche participe à une prise de conscience de l'importance des objectifs d'équité sociale reliés au transport et souligne le rôle que ces objectifs peuvent jouer dans les processus décisionnels.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>For most of the 20th century transportation planning goals were almost entirely mobility-based; transportation systems were primarily seen as a means to efficiently, safely, and quickly connect people and freight to desired destinations. However, as the century progressed, cultural, societal and ecological movements had major impacts on how planners perceive transportation networks and public transit more specifically. Several overlapping concerns have altered the role that planners and policy-makers see for transportation and land use planning. Environmental degradation, air pollution, traffic congestion, an unsure energy future, and global climate change, for example, have drastically redefined priorities for planners and policy-makers. These concerns have led to an increasing interest in public transit and active transportation—walking and cycling—as potential solutions to many environmental problems. Concurrent to these shifts, concerns of social equity and environmental justice have also entered the transportation planning framework. However, while transportation planning goals have shifted in recent decades to encompass social justice and environmental goals, many of these aims do not have clear indicators or accepted ways of measuring progress. In addition, while these diverse values and ideals do often underlie policy, they can have contradictory influence on transportation planning decisions. Transportation benefits include, what might be termed "tangible" or easily measured outcomes, however, many goals that address issues of social equity have "intangible" outcomes. Not only are the former easier to measure and to present to the public, but they often have more political capital than more socially progressive goals. While a rich body of research has explored these issues, most current planning documents do not make explicit that these conflicts of value exist. The concern from an equity planning standpoint is that very real and important environmental concerns will lead away from the other important roles that transportation systems can play in providing equitable outcomes. In light of these concerns, this dissertation sets out to address four research questions: •How do municipalities and transit agencies balance economic, social, and environmental goals and objectives in transportation plans?  •How do these decisions affect outcomes, particularly with regards to social equity?  •How can current methods of measuring and understanding active transportation and neighbourhood walkability be improved to better capture these wide ranging objectives?  •How can these findings be used to improve decision-making in the future?This dissertation highlights the importance of adopting a multi-dimensional and mixed methods approach to examining complex urban issues and processes, and contributes to knowledge in three ways:•Identifies a set of indicators that capture elements of social equity in transportation planning and decision-making;•Develops methodologies to measure outcomes of transportation infrastructure using accessibility measures that focus on the desired destinations of residents; and•Deepens the understanding of how people and households of different socio-economic status “respond” to measures of local and regional accessibility. While most—if not all—studies do "control for" socio-economic factors, my work makes these factors the primary focus.In doing so, this research brings awareness of important transportation-related social equity goals and increases the role that these goals may play in decision-making processes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ahmed Elgeneidy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fw07t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h786x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Urban and Regional Planning</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rm729"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La posture énigmatique de Wajdi Mouawad</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beauvais, Julie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this master's thesis is to study the enigmatic figure of Wajdi Mouawad, looking into the dramatic quartet Le Sang des promesses, the interviews the author gave over time, as well as his physic appearance and his public acts. We look to, with the help of the Meizoz's theory, better understand the "posture" of the writer, claimed as here as in France. The first chapter treats, with the metaphoric figure of the looter, the dramatist's propensity to take over other people's words, their speech and even the story of a people for the benefit of his own work. The second chapter shows interest for searches Mouawad makes, as an archeologist, in his past and to the origin of literature, all this building traces he would like to let to posterity. The third chapter addresses the dramatic author's ambivalence, which like the image of the God Janus, seems to have many contradictory faces. As we learned through this study, it is impossible to crack the mystery surrounding the enigmatic "posture" of the Libanese-Quebecer writer. However, it is obvious that Mouawad stages his own life the same way he stages his plays.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le but de ce mémoire est de se pencher sur la figure énigmatique de Wajdi Mouawad, et ce, en étudiant le quatuor dramatique Le Sang des promesses, les entretiens qu'il a accordés au fil du temps, ainsi que son apparence physique et ses agissements en public. Nous tentons, à l'aide de la théorie de Meizoz, de mieux comprendre la posture de cet écrivain acclamé ici, comme en France. Le premier chapitre aborde, à l'aide de la figure métaphorique du pilleur, la propension du dramaturge à s'approprier les mots des autres, leur parole et même l'histoire d'un peuple pour le bénéfice de sa propre entreprise. Le deuxième chapitre s'intéresse aux fouilles que Mouawad fait, tel un archéologue, dans son passé et à l'origine de la littérature, et ce, tout en fabriquant des traces qu'il aimerait laisser à la postérité. Le troisième chapitre s'attaque à l'ambivalence de l'auteur dramatique qui, à l'image du dieu Janus, semble avoir plusieurs visages contradictoires. Au terme de cette étude, nous comprenons qu'il est impossible de percer le mystère de la posture énigmatique de l'écrivain libano-québécois. Toutefois, il est clair que Mouawad se met en scène, qu'il écrit son histoire à la manière de ses pièces.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alain Farah</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sn75n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rm729</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Canadian (French)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b944x"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Selective wet chemical etching of erosion resistant coatings from titanium alloy substrates: mechanism and optimization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chaudhury, Rabib</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Titanium aluminum nitride (TiAlN) is a type of erosion resistant ceramic coating that is applied to metal parts subject to high wear environments. Adding this coating helps protect the underlying substrate from these adverse conditions. Sometimes the coating layer must be removed and a new layer re-applied. The overarching goal of this project is to successfully remove the TiAlN coating from titanium alloy substrates through wet chemical etching. In meeting this goal, the following objectives must be met: the process must be fast, selective (i.e. does not adversely affect the underlying substrate), operate isothermally, and make use of chemicals that are environmentally friendly. A combination of hydrogen peroxide, potassium oxalate, and ethylenediaaminetetracetic acid (EDTA) was found to accomplish the stated objectives. Hydrogen peroxide and potassium oxalate are responsible for removing the coating and producing titanium metal ions in solution. The role of EDTA is to form coordination complexes with these metal ions so as to reduce their reactivity with hydrogen peroxide in solution. The etching process was optimized for selectivity. A kinetic model was built using a modified differential technique and Arrhenius plots. It was determined that selectivity increases with increasing temperature and potassium oxalate concentration while it decreases with increasing hydrogen peroxide concentration. Sensitivity analysis shows that selectivity is much more prone to change with changing hydrogen peroxide concentration. Surrogate modeling using a Least Squares-Support Vector Machine model confirms the trends predicted by the kinetic model except that selectivity seems to peak when varying potassium oxalate concentration. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Titanium aluminum nitride (TiAlN) est un type de revêtement céramique résistant à l'érosion qui est appliqué à des pièces métalliques soumises à des environnements à forte usure. L'ajout de ce revêtement permet de protéger le substrat de ces conditions défavorables. Parfois, la couche de revêtement doit être retiré et une nouvelle couche réappliqué. L'objectif principal de ce projet est de réussir à enlever le revêtement TiAlN à partir de substrats en alliage de titane par 'wet chemical etching'. Pour atteindre cet objectif, les objectifs suivants doivent être atteints: le processus doit être rapide, sélective (c'est à dire ne pas nuire au substrat titanium), de s'opérer dans une manière isotherme, et faire usage de produits chimiques qui sont respectueux de l'environnement. Une combinaison de hydrogen peroxide, potassium oxalate et de l'acide ethylenediaaminetetracetic (EDTA) a été trouvé pour atteindre les objectifs. Hydrogen peroxide et de potassium oxalate sont responsables de l'élimination du revêtement et produire des ions métalliques de titane en solution. Le rôle de l'EDTA est de former des complexes de coordination avec ces ions métalliques de manière à réduire leur réactivité avec le hydrogen peroxide  en solution. Le processus a été optimisé pour la sélectivité. Un modèle cinétique a été construit en utilisant une méthode différentielle modifiée et  des parcelles d'Arrhenius. Il a été déterminé que la sélectivité augmente avec la température et la concentration de potassium oxalate alors qu'il diminue quand la concentration de hydrogen peroxide augmente. L'analyse de sensibilité montre que la sélectivité est beaucoup plus enclin à changer avec la concentration de hydrogen peroxide. Modélisation de substitution (Surrogate Modeling) en utilisant un modèle Least Squares-Support Vector Machine confirme les tendances prédites par le modèle cinétique, sauf que la sélectivité semble culminer en variant la concentration d'oxalate de potassium.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dimitrios Berk</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zm15x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b944x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795c281"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors affecting the distribution, abundance and condition of an invasive freshwater bivalve in a thermal plume</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Castaneda, Rowshyra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Asian clam, Corbicula fluminea, is a freshwater bivalve that has recently invaded artificially heated waters downstream of the Gentilly-2 nuclear power plant in the St. Lawrence River.  C. fluminea is one of the world's most invasive molluscs, owing to its ability to rapidly establish dense populations in new areas.  Its physiological requirements have apparently restricted its global distribution to waterbodies whose temperatures remain above 2ºC throughout the year; however, recent invasions suggest that the clam may be adapting to lower temperatures.  Using published data, I have identified patterns of the distribution and population densities of C. fluminea in artificially heated and natural (non-heated) waterbodies.  Densities of C. fluminea populations do not differ between artificially heated and non-heated waters, but exhibit a positive trend with latitudinal distance such that peak densities occur in middle latitudes.  The occurrence of C. fluminea in United States rivers below 40oN is positively correlated with human population density.  At local scales within the St. Lawrence River, temperature, flow velocity, turbidity and depth were identified as factors that affect the distribution and density of C. fluminea.  Furthermore, the clam was restricted to sites within the thermal plume of the Gentilly-2 power plant, and its body condition and reproductive status varied in time and space.  The presence of C. fluminea in St. Lawrence River raises the question of whether the species can use the thermal plume to adapt to colder conditions and spread further in the river, especially as warming trends continue.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La petite corbeille d'Asie, Corbicula fluminea, est un bivalve subtropical d'eau douce qui a récemment envahi la panache thermique de la centrale nucléaire Gentilly-2 (CNG2) du fleuve Saint-Laurent.  C. fluminea est un des mollusques les plus envahissant du monde, en raison de sa capacité rapide à former de nouvelle population dense.  Ses besoins physiologiques semblent limiter sa distribution mondiale à des plans d'eau maintenant une temperature de plus de 2ºC au courant de l'année; néanmoins, des envahissements récents suggèrent que la palourde s'adapte à des températures plus basses.  Utilisant des donnés publiés, j'ai identifié des types de distribution et de densité de C. fluminea dans des eaux chauffés artificiellement et non-chauffés.  Les densités de C. fluminea ne diffèrent pas entre les deux types d'eau, mais démontrent une relation positive avec la distance latitudinal, où les densités maximales sont atteintes aux latitudes centrale.  La présence de C. fluminea dans les rivières Américaines se situant au sud du 40ºN est positivement corrélée avec la densité de la population humaine.  À l'échelle locale du fleuve Saint-Laurent, la température, le courant d'eau, la turbidité et la profondeur ont été identifiés comme facteurs affectant la distribution et la densité de C. fluminea.  De plus, la palourde était limitée aux sites du panache thermique de la CNG2, et sa condition et son statut réproductif varient en temps et espace.  La présence de C. fluminea dans le fleuve Saint-Laurent soulève des questions sur la possibilité de l'espèce d'utiliser la panache thermique afin de s'adapter à des conditions plus froides surtout si les tendances de réchauffement continuent.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anthony Ricciardi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nm697.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795c281</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Ecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010t51x"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis, characterization, and performance of graphene nanoflakes as a non-noble metal catalyst in polymer electrolyte membrane fuel cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pascone, Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Un des objectifs de la recherche sur les catalyseurs pour les piles à combustible à membrane électrolyte polymérique (PCMEP) est de trouver une alternative moins coûteuse au platine. En raison d'une cinétique lente, le platine est surtout utilisé dans la couche de catalyseur au niveau de la cathode pour la réaction de réduction de l'oxygène (RRO). Les nanomatériaux de carbone fonctionnalisés se présentent comme de bons candidats pour le remplacement du platine en raison de leur faible coût, d'une excellente conductivité électrique et d'une résistance chimique aux milieux acides et basiques. Dans ce travail, les nanoflocons de graphène (NFG) constitués en moyenne d'une dixaine de plans de graphène empilées, ont été utilisés comme support aux atomes de fer pour créer un catalyseur métallique non noble.  Lors d'une première étape, le catalyseur à base de fer a été synthétisé. Les étapes de synthèse comprennent la production des NFG dans le plasma de méthane, l'adsorption de l'acétate ferrique, et la pyrolyse dans une atmosphère riche en ammoniac. La structure du catalyseur a été caractérisée tout au long des étapes de synthèse, et il a été constaté qu'un pourcentage de 0,28 % en atomes de fer ont été incorporé aux structures NFG. Cependant, la méthode de synthèse utilisée a provoqué une baisse générale de tous les paramètres cristallins calculés: la pureté a diminué de 28%, la taille des cristallites a diminué d'un facteur 2, et la taille moyenne des plans de graphène d'un facteur 4. La caractérisation a été également effectuée sur la couche de catalyseur après avoir été exposée à l'environnement PCMEP, révélant que les paramètres cristallins sont effectivement améliorés avec la durée d'exposition. Au bout de 100 heures, la pureté  a augmenté de 32%, la taille des cristallites de 25%, et la taille moyenne des plans de graphène de 107%. L'exposition à l'environnement de PCMEP a réduit les dommages causés aux NFG pendant les étapes de synthèse. Le catalyseur synthétisé a été utilisé pour la RRO dans un PCMEP avec une surface active de 1 cm2. Un courant de 150 mA/cm2 a été observé pour une tension appliquée de 0,5 volts et une masse de catalyseur de 1 mg. Lorsque le courant est normalisé par rapport à la quantité de métal présent, le résultat de 11,8 A/mg de métal surpasse les catalyseurs à base de platine les plus utilisés dans l'industrie. Les catalyseurs au platine ont des valeurs allant de 3 à 14 A/mg de platine. Dans les expériences de stabilité, pour une tension appliquée de 0,5 Volts, aucune perte de courant n'a été observée à la fin des 100 heures de l'expérience. Cela représente une grande amélioration par rapport aux autres catalyseurs à base de fer, qui montrent une perte de 45% dans des conditions expérimentales identiques. La stabilité accrue de la structure du catalyseur démontre l'avantage d'utiliser des NFG par rapport à d'autres nanomatériaux de carbone, grâce à leurs cristallinité élevée et leurs grandes longueurs cristallines.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>One of the goals in catalyst research for proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs) is to find a cost-efficient alternative to platinum. Due to sluggish kinetics, the major requirement of the platinum comes from the catalyst layer used for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Functionalized carbon nanomaterials present themselves as good candidates for the replacement of platinum due to their low cost, excellent electrical conductivity, and chemical resistance to acidic and basic environments. In this work, graphene nanoflakes (GNFs), which are nanopowders consisting of stacked graphene sheets, were used to support atomic iron as a non-noble metal catalyst. In the first stage of the study the iron-based catalyst was synthesized. Synthesis steps include the production of GNFs in methane plasma, adsorption of ferric acetate, and pyrolysis in ammonia-rich atmosphere. The catalyst structure was characterized at various stages throughout the synthesis steps and it was found that 0.28 atomic percent of iron could successfully be incorporated onto the surface. However, the synthesis method employed caused a general decrease to all calculated crystallinity parameters: purity decreased by 28%, crystallite size decreased by a factor of 2, and the average length of graphene plane decreased by a factor of 4. Characterization was also performed on the catalyst layer after it had been exposed to the PEMFC environment, revealing that the crystallinity parameters actually improved with respect to exposure time: after 100 hours purity increased by 32%, crystallite size increased by 25%, and the average length of graphene plane increased by 107%. Exposure to the PEMFC environment repairs the damage done to the original GNFs during the synthesis steps. The synthesized catalyst was used in the catalyst layer for the ORR of a PEMFC with a 1 cm2 active surface. A current of 150 mA/cm2 was observed at an applied voltage of 0.5 Volts with a catalyst loading of 1 mg. When the current is normalized with respect to the amount of metal present, the result of 11.8 A/mg of metal catalyst from the present catalyst out-performs most platinum-based catalysts being used in industry; current platinum catalyst have values ranging from 3 to 14 A/mg of platinum. In stability experiments, no losses were observed at the end of 100-hours long experiments performed at an applied voltage of 0.5 Volts. This represents a great improvement over comparable iron-based catalysts, which show a 45% loss under identical test conditions. The increased stability of the catalyst support structure demonstrates the advantage of the high crystallinity and large crystalline lengths of the GNFs in comparison to other commercial carbon blacks.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dimitrios Berk</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jean-Luc Meunier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bg11t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010t51x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqz20sx33z"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis of CdSe-decorated carbon nanotubes for a photovoltaic device</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jorge, Larissa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Afin de répondre à nos besoins énergétiques grandissants, de nouveaux matériaux et de nouvelles structures sont en développement dans le but de fabriquer des cellules photovoltaïques (PV). Plusieurs nanostructures sont intégrées dans ces cellules PV pour augmenter leur performance. Ces nanostructures peuvent répondre à des besoins spécifiques tels qu'un spectre d'absorption de la lumière plus large ou une plus grande conductivité électrique. Par contre, des processus de fabrication complexes empêchent le développement de cette technologie. Dans ce projet, nous proposons l'utilisation d'une structure 3D de nanotubes de carbone (NTCs), synthétisés directement sur un substrat métallique, et décorés par des nanoparticules de CdSe. Des méthodes simples de fabrication qui ne font pas appel à la chimie en solution ont été choisies afin de diminuer les déchets chimiques et éviter les difficultes inhérentes à la dispersion de nanomatériaux en solution. Dans une chambre à vide, une cible faite en CdSe est irradiée par un laser pulsé Nd:YAG haute énergie menant à la formation d'une plume en expansion contenant du Cd et du Se. Les atomes à l'intérieur de la plume se condensent pour former des nanoparticules qui se déposent par la suite sur le substrat désiré. Les nanoparticules de CdSe obtenues ont un diamètre entre 2 et 6 nm et se retrouvent dans les deux phases crystallines typiques au CdSe soit hexagonale (wurtzite) et cubique (sphalerite). La composition des NPs est de 54% atomique pour le Cd et 46% atomique pour le Se. Il a été observé que les NPs augmentent de taille lorsque la pression durant l'ablation de la cible est augmentée entre 0.1 et 4620 Pa. Cependant, cette taille n'est pas influencée par des changements dans la fluence de l'impulsion entre 0.48 et 2.36 J/cm^2. Les spectres d'absorption de la lumière des NPs indiquent une large distribution de tailles des NPs produits. En recouvrant les NTCs avec des NPs de CdSe pendant différentes périodes de temps allant de 100 s à 90 min, des NTCs recouverts d'une monocouche de NPs de CdSe jusqu'à une couche micrométrique sur les NTCs ont été fabriqués. Cette nanostructure a été testée dans une cellule photoélectrochimique (PEC). Ces mesures ont révélé que la couche de CdSe sur les NTCs est photoactive mais dû à certains problèmes dans la cellule, une quantité insuffisante de courant a été produit par ce système pour qu'il puisse être utilisé en tant que cellule photovoltaïque. Premièrement, une interaction entre les NTCs et la solution ont causé des instabilités dans la cellule ne permettant pas la reproductiblité dans les mesures effectuées. Deuxièmement, le courant obtenu sans illumination de la cellule était très élevé. Ce courant pourrait provenir d'une fuite indésirée d'électrons de la couche de CdSe vers la solution due à une résistance électrique trop élevée des électrons vers le circuit électrique de la cellule PEC.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>To answer the growing energy needs around the globe, novel materials and structures are being investigated to fabricate photovoltaic (PV) cells. Different types of nanostructures are being incorporated in PV cells to increase their performance since these structures can be tailored to answer specific needs related for example to larger light absorption wavelength range or very high electrical conductivity. However, complex fabrication processes hinder the development of this technology. In this work we propose the use of a 3-D carbon nanotube (CNT) network grown directly from a metallic substrate and decorated with CdSe nanoparticles (NPs) acting as the photoactive electrode for a PV cell. Simple fabrication methods that require no wet chemistry have been chosen to diminish waste and avoid the difficulties inherent to dispersing nanomaterials in liquids. More specifically, in a vacuum chamber, a CdSe target is irradiated using a high energy nanosecond pulsed Nd:YAG laser to form an expanding vapor plume that subsequently condenses into NPs which are deposited on the desired substrate. CdSe NPs between 2 and 6 nm in diameter were produced, in the two common crystalline phases for CdSe,  hexagonal (wurtzite) and cubic (sphalerite). The composition of the NPs was 54% atomic Cd and 46% atomic Se. It was observed that the size of the NPs increases with increasing pressure from 0.1 to 4620 Pa, but the laser fluence, from 0.48 to 2.36 J/cm^2, had no impact on the size of the NPs. Light absorption spectroscopy suggested that the NPs produced had a large size distribution. Coating the CNTs with CdSe for different amounts of time, from 100 s to 90 min, produced CNTs with a CdSe coating only a few nanometers thick up to two micrometers. Photoelectrochemical measurements using this heterogeneous nanostructure as the working electrode revealed that the CdSe coating was slightly photoactive. However, due to insufficient photocurrent generated, no power could be drawn from this cell. The first problem found was an interaction between the CNTs and the solution which caused variability in the cell. The second problem was a very large dark current which may be attributed to leaking of electrons from the CdSe to the solution due to a large resistance for transport of electrons to the outer electrial circuit. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sylvain Coulombe</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jean-Luc Meunier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vf834.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sx33z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad217qt32g"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structural and functional characterization of Argonaute MID domains</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Frank, Filipp</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les petits ARNs s'associent aux protéines de la famille des Argonautes (AGO) et les guident vers les acides nucléiques ciblés par l'appariement de leurs séquences. La plupart des petits ARNs sont formés à partir d'ARN précurseurs à double brins. Il est critique que le bon brin de ce duplex soit choisi et qu'il s'associe à l'AGO approprié. Ces processus sont appelés 'sélection du brin' et 'triage du petit ARNs' (ou 'triage par l'Argonaute') et sont fortement influencés par l'identité du nucléotide se trouvant à l'extrémité 5' du petit ARN. Le domaine MID de l'AGO, étant le site de liaison avec le nucléotide 5', a été proposé d'avoir évolué afin d'interagir préférablement avec certains nucléotides 5' et de discriminer les autres. Ainsi, on croit que les domaines MID dirigent la sélection du brin et le triage du petit ARN en faisant appel à des interactions spécifiques avec le nucléotide 5'. J'ai résolu les structures cristallines du domaine MID de l'AGO2 humain (hAGO2) en complex avec des nucléosides monophosphates (NMPs), ces derniers imitant le nucléotide 5'. Les structures cristallines ont permis d'identifier des contacts spécifiques entre une boucle rigide de la protéine, appelée la 'boucle de spécificité au nucléotide', et la base des nucléotides U or A, mais pas C ou G. Les constantes de dissociation obtenues par des expériences de titration par RNM sont en accord avec les structures cristallines et la préférence observée chez le domaine MID d'hAGO2 reflète la distribution des nucléotides à l'extrémité 5' des micro (mi)ARNs, qui sont les principaux partenaires de liaison de cette protéine AGO. J'ai ensuite caractérisé les interactions spécifiques au nucléotide des domaines MID d'Arabidopsis thaliana (at)AGO1, atAGO2, et atAGO5. Des expériences de titration par RNM ont confirmé que ces protéines montrent une préférence pour U, A, et C, respectivement. De plus, les structures cristallines ont révélé que les boucles de spécificité au nucléotide adoptent des conformations considérablement différentes dans chacun de ces domaines MID. Les structures du domaine MID d'atAGO1 en complexe avec des NMPs ont révélé le fondement structural de la spécificité de l'interaction avec U ou C, et non A et G.Nombre d'études ont mêlé le domaine MID d'hAGO2 à la répression traductionnelle entremise par les miARNs par des interactions directes avec la coiffe à l'extrémité 5' de l'ARN messager. Par l'utilisation d'analogues de la coiffe, j'ai démontré que l'interaction est non-spécifique et n'est pas physiologiquement pertinente car elle est localisée dans le site de liaison avec le nucléotide 5'.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Small RNAs associate with Argonaute (AGO) proteins and guide them to their target nucleic acids via sequence specific interactions. Most small RNAs are formed from a double-stranded precursor. It is critical that the correct strand of this duplex is chosen and associates with an appropriate AGO protein. These processes are referred to as 'strand selection' and 'small RNA sorting' (or 'Argonaute sorting') and they are strongly influenced by the identity of the nucleotide found at the small RNA 5' end. The AGO MID domain, which is the site of interaction with the 5' nucleotide, was proposed to have evolved to preferentially bind certain 5' nucleotides and discriminate others. Therefore, the MID domains are believed to direct small RNA sorting and strand selection via specific interactions with the 5' nucleotide.I have solved the crystal structures of the MID domain from human AGO2 (hAGO2) in complex with nucleoside monophosphates (NMPs), which mimic the 5' nucleotide. The structures identified specific contacts between a rigid loop in the protein, which we termed the 'nucleotide specificity loop', and the nucleotide base of U or A, but not C or G. Dissociation constants from NMR titration experiments are in agreement with the crystal structures and this bias we observed in the hAGO2 MID domain reflects the distribution of nucleotides at the 5' end of miRNAs, which are the main binding partners for this AGO protein. I then characterized nucleotide-specific interactions in the MID domains of Arabidopsis thaliana (at)AGO1, atAGO2, and atAGO5. NMR titration experiments confirmed that these proteins display a bias towards U, A, and C, respectively. Furthermore, crystal structures revealed that the nucleotide specificity loop adopts strikingly different conformations in each of these MID domains. Structures of the atAGO1 MID domain in complex with NMPs revealed the structural basis for specificity of interaction with U or C and not A or G. A number of studies had implicated the MID domain of hAGO2 in miRNA-mediated translational repression via direct interactions with the mRNA 5' cap structure. Using cap-analogues I demonstrated that the interaction is non-specific and not physiologically relevant since it is located in the 5' nucleotide binding site.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nahum Sonenberg</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Bhushan Nagar</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j70n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qt32g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d570106c"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>CMOS contact and phase imaging of biochemical sensor microarray</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Daivasagaya, Daisy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse, nous présentons deux systèmes pour détecter l'oxygène gazeux (O2). Tout d'abord, nous décrivons un microsystème compact  à senseur luminescent qui est basée sur l'intégration directe d'éléments de senseur avec un filtre optique polymère qui est placé sur un imageur circuits intégrés (CI) à faible énergie de type Complementary metal oxide semi-conductor (CMOS). Le second système est un système portatif qui permet de détecter la différence de phase fluorométrique. Ce système est basé sur un circuit intégré à puce unique qui permet de générer des signaux sinusoïdal en  utilisant la synthèse directe de signaux digitaux et l'extraction de l'angle de phase du signal luminescent, provenant des films du senseur, en  utilisant des transformées de Fourier discrète sur ce signal. Pour la détection du dioxygène, les senseurs mesure l'intensité d'émission des luminophores tris (4,7-diphényl-1, 10 - phénanthroline) ruthénium (II) ([Ru(dpp)3]2+) à l'état excité encapsulés dans des sol-gel provenant de micro film xérogel. Le microsystème compact à senseur luminescent comprend un filtre optique polymère à base de polydiméthylsiloxane (PDMS), qui est mélangée avec le colorant Soudan-II. La surface du filtre PDMS est moulée pour ainsi incorporer les réseaux de microstructures pyramidales qui servent à concentrer les signaux des senseurs optiques sur les photodétecteurs. Les réseaux de senseur à base de xérogel sont imprimés par contact sur le dessus des microstructures PDMS pyramidales qui agissant comme des lentilles. L'imageur CMOS utilise une matrice  de 32x32 (1024 éléments) servant de pixels actifs et chaque un de ces pixels comporte un phototransistor à gain élevé pour convertir les signaux détectés optiques en courants électriques. La corrélation de circuit d'échantillonnage double, l'adresse de pixel, et les circuits de commande numérique d'intégration de signaux sont également résolue par la puce. Les données sont lues par l'imageur en tant que signaux codé en série. Les capteurs CMOS fournissent une plateforme utile pour le développement des systèmes miniaturisés pour l'analyse fiable et précis des composantes chimiques gazeuse et aqueuse par des moyens optiques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In this Thesis, we present two systems for gaseous oxygen (O2) sensing. First, we describe a compact luminescent sensor microsystem that is based on the direct integration of sensor elements with a polymeric optical filter and placed on a low power Complementary Metal-Oxide Semiconductor (CMOS) imager Integrated Circuit (IC). The second system is a hand-held scale phase fluorometric system. This system is based on a new single-chip integrated circuit that can perform the activities of sinusoidal signal generation using Direct Digital Synthesis and phase angle extraction of the detection luminescence signal from the sensor films using Discrete Fourier Transform. For O2 sensing, the sensors operate on the measurement of excited-state emission intensity of O2-sensitive luminophores tris(4,7-diphenyl-1,10- phenanthroline) ruthenium(II) ([Ru(dpp)3]2+) encapsulated in sol-gel derived xerogel thin-films. For the compact luminescent sensor microsystem, we incorporate a polymeric optical filter that is made with polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS) that is mixed with color die Sudan-II. The surface of the PDMS filter is molded to incorporate arrays of pyramidal microstructures that serve to focus the optical sensor signals on to the photodetectors. The xerogel sensor arrays are contact printed on top of the PDMS pyramidal lens-like microstructures. The CMOS imager uses a 32x32 (1024 elements) array of active pixel sensors and each pixel includes a high-gain phototransistor to convert the detected optical signals into electrical currents. Correlated double sampling circuit, pixel address, digital control and signal integration circuits are also implemented on-chip. The CMOS imager data is read out as a serial coded signal. The developed CMOS sensor microsystems provide a useful platform for the development of miniaturized, analytically reliable, and accurate optical chemical gaseous and aqueous sensors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vamsy Chodavarapu</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278x79c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d570106c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rh82h"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Adaptive reactionless control of a space manipulator for post-capture of an uncooperative tumbling target</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nguyen Huynh, Thai Chau</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une augmentation alarmante du nombre de satellites et de débris orbitaux autour de la Terre a engendré un besoin grandissant de développer des technologies pour l'entretien des satellites en orbite et afin de disposer des débris existants. Cette thèse porte sur une solution constituée d'un satellite de service muni d'un manipulateur robotisé qui lui permet de s'arrimer au satellite ciblé et en maintenir le contrôle afin de compléter les opérations requises. Plus spécifiquement, cette étude porte sur la phase après la saisie d'un satellite culbutant avec un moment angulaire inconnu et ayant des propriétés inertielles inconnues. Un aspect critique à l'étude est le maintien d'un niveau minimal de liens dynamiques entre le satellite capturé et la base du manipulateur afin de préserver son orientation spatiale tout en estimant les propriétés inconnues de la cible, et ce, sans autres systèmes de contrôle d'attitude. Tout d'abord, la cinématique et la dynamique d'un manipulateur en apesanteur sont analysées avec une attention particulière sur les liens mécaniques entre le manipulateur et le satellite de service à sa base. Ensuite, un concept déjà établi pour la manipulation sans réaction est introduit par une méthode de contrôle du noyau de réaction, unique aux manipulateurs spatiaux. Sur cette fondation, une nouvelle méthode de contrôle adaptative et sans-réaction est proposée qui produit des trajectoires de manipulation qui minimise les perturbations à la base. L'algorithme permet de générer ces trajectoires tout en faisant face à l'incertitude quant aux propriétés inconnues de la cible. De plus, une méthode d'estimation en ligne basée sur le moment cinétique est développée pour identifier les paramètres inertiels à la suite de l'arrimage. Ces deux méthodes, de contrôle et d'estimation, peuvent être utilisées de concert jusqu'à l'identification des paramètres inconnus ou jusqu'à ce qu'une méthode de stabilisation puisse être appliquée. Afin de vérifier la validité et la faisabilité de la méthode proposée, une plate-forme de co-simulation entre MSC.Adams et Simulink est utilisée pour simuler un système planaire en plus d'un système tridimensionnel représentant le "Engineering Test Satellite VII". Les résultats démontrent que le manipulateur peut éxécuter des mouvements sans-réactions tout en identifiant les paramètres inertiels, pour un éventail de dimensions du satellite ciblé.Afin de rendre la méthode proposée plus pratique, une technique de résolution des redondances est formulée au sein de l'algorithme de contrôle adaptatif sans-réaction pour permettre d'accomplir une tâche secondaire en simultané. Par exemple, une projection du gradient est utilisée pour éviter les limites physiques du manipulateur. La performance de cette combinaison est vérifiée par des simulations qui démontrent que les perturbations à la base peuvent être minimisées tout en respectant les limites du manipulateur après la saisie d'un satellite culbutant. Finalement, un concept préliminaire pour une plateforme expérimentale planaire est présentée. Cette plateforme crée une surface presque sans friction à l'aide d'une table à coussind'air qui peut supporter un manipulateur à trois degrés de liberté et un satellite-maquette. Ce concept préliminaire inclut les principales dimensions, la sélection des actionneurs, capteurs, et contrôleurs.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The increasing number of satellites and space debris in the Earth orbit has created an urgent need to develop robotic technologies for on-orbit servicing and space debris removal. The system solution investigated in this thesis involves a servicer (base) with an attached robotic manipulator and this system must dock to, or get a hold of the target satellite in order to conduct the required operations. In that context, the problem of post-capture of a tumbling target with unknown inertial properties and angular momentum, by using a space manipulator, is addressed. In particular, a critical aspect investigated is how to maintain minimum coupling between the manipulator-target and the base in order to keep the base attitude unchanged while estimating the unknown properties of the target -- this without the use of attitude control devices. First, the kinematics and dynamics of a free-floating space manipulator are analyzed where particular attention is given to the coupling motion between the arm and the base. Then, the previously developed concept of reactionless manipulation is introduced by presenting the reaction null-space control method, which is unique to free-floating space manipulators.Next, motivated by the reaction null-space control method, a new Adaptive ReactionLess Control algorithm to produce arm motions with minimum disturbance to the base is proposed. The algorithm aims to generate the reactionless manipulation in the presence of uncertainty as a result of capturing an unknown target. In addition, the online momentum-based estimation method is developed for inertia parameters identification, after the space manipulator grasps an unknown tumbling target. The combined control/identification scheme is intended to segue from the instant of capture till the unknown parameters are identified and/or the available stabilization methods can be applied properly. To verify the validity and feasibility of the proposed concept, MSC.Adams/Simulink co-simulation platform is employed to implement a planar base-manipulator-target model as well as the three-dimensional model of the Engineering Test Satellite VII system. The numerical results show that the space manipulator is able to perform reactionless motion while the inertial parameters of the target are identified, for a range of target sizes relative to the base. To make the proposed control scheme practical, a redundancy resolution technique is formulated within the adaptive reactionless control algorithm to integrate a secondary manipulation task, while executing the reactionless motion in the post-capture scenario. In particular, the gradient projection method is employed and implemented to avoid the physical joint limits of the manipulator. The performance of the algorithm is verified through simulations of the two aforementioned models, thus demonstrating that minimum disturbance on the base and joint limits avoidance can be achieved after capture of an unknown tumbling target. Lastly, a preliminary design for a planar test-bed that can serve for experimental validation of the proposed algorithms is presented. The design utilizes an air-bearing table to create a near frictionless surface which would support a base-3-DOF manipulator and a target satellite mock-up. The design includes the dimensioning and sizing of the main components, and selection of actuation, sensing and control hardware. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Inna Sharf</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58ph37g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rh82h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301485p"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Testing propagule pressure theory: maritime transport &amp; invasion by fouling species</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lacoursière-Roussel, Anaïs</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'introduction des salissures biologiques exotiques a sévèrement perturbé les écosystèmes marins. La théorie suggère qu'un apport de propagules élevé augmente le risque d'envahissement. C'est ainsi que les recherches se sont concentrées à évaluer la probabilité que les navires commerciaux et les petites embarcations transportent des espèces exotiques. Malgré son importance, peu d'études empiriques supportent l'effet de l'apport de propagules sur le succès d'envahissement. Pour les salissures biologiques marines, l'incertitude entre les vecteurs et les voies de transports entrave particulièrement notre capacité à calculer l'apport de propagules entrant par les voies maritimes, limitant ainsi notre compréhension du succès d'envahissement. L'objectif de ma thèse est d'apporter une meilleure compréhension de la relation entre l'apport de propagules provenant du transport maritime et la distribution spatiale des salissures exotiques. À partir de données empiriques, (1) j'ai déterminé l'importance relative des caractéristiques des bateaux de plaisance et l'exposition des propagules environnantes sur la probabilité de la colonisation des coques, (2) j'ai démontré le rôle respectif des navires et des plaisanciers dans le processus d'invasion et (3) j'ai décrit la relation entre l'apport de propagules et la diversité des populations et des communautés. Bien que les bateaux de la côte est du Canada sont moins colonisés que les bateaux de la Nouvelle-Zélande, la propagation des salissures exotiques pourrait être facilitée au Canada par un plus grand trafic entre les marinas. L'exposition aux propagules environnantes prédit davantage l'encrassement biologique des coques que les caractéristiques des bateaux. La génétique des populations de l'ascidie Botryllus schlosseri suggère qu'il y a eu plusieurs introductions dans les ports de la côte est du Canada. Facilité par les plaisanciers, le tunicier s'est ensuite dispersé progressivement autour de ceux-ci. Les indices de diversité soutiennent la relation positive entre l'apport de propagules et le succès d'envahissement et cela autant au niveau des communautés (c.-à-d. la richesse inter-spécifique) qu'au niveau des populations (c.-à-d. diversité génétique). La diversité est significativement corrélée au nombre d'arrivées des navires, mais n'est pas corrélée au nombre de déchargements et au volume de l'eau de lest. Ces relations suggèrent une plus grande importance de l'encrassement des navires que l'eau de lest comme voie d'introduction des salissures exotiques. Cette thèse démontre que les petits bateaux et les navires influencent grandement les processus d'invasions des salissures biologiques des régions côtières du Canada. Cette recherche souligne également que les modèles de propagation des salissures exotiques devraient fonder leurs prémisses sur l'exposition des propagules locales, les caractéristiques des bateaux et l'activité nautique régionale. La nécessité de décrire avec précision les relations entre l'apport de propagules et le succès d'envahissement est l'un des grands défis écologiques afin d'améliorer notre compréhension sur les changements rapides actuellement observés dans nos écosystèmes marins.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introductions of exotic fouling species have severely disrupted marine ecosystems. Theory suggests that high propagule pressure increases the probability of successful establishment. Likewise, empirical studies have shown the importance of ships and boats for transporting exotic species. However, few empirical studies have demonstrated the effect of propagule pressure on invasion success. For marine fouling species, uncertainty about vectors and pathways further impedes our ability to calculate propagule pressure and to understand establishment success. My goal was to better understand the links between propagule pressure from maritime activities and the spatial distribution of exotic fouling species. Using empirical data, I (1) determined the importance of boat characteristics and propagule exposure on boat fouling, (2) demonstrated the roles of commercial shipping and recreational boating in the invasion process, and (3) tested the effect of propagule pressure on population and community diversity. Although boats on the east coast of Canada were less fouled than New Zealand boats, boat-mediated spread may be facilitated in Canada by greater movement of boats among marinas than in New Zealand. Propagule exposure better predicted boat fouling than did boat characteristics. The spatial genetic structure of the colonial tunicate, Botryllus schlosseri, suggests that ships have frequently introduced it to the east coast of Canada and that secondary spread occurs gradually around individual ports, facilitated by recreational boating. The diversity of invasive species within commercial ports is positively related to propagule pressure and invasion success at both community (i.e. inter-specific richness) and population levels (i.e. genetic diversity). Diversity was significantly correlated to the numbers of ship arrivals but not to ballast water discharge events or the volume of ballast water discharged. This suggests that hull biofouling is a more important pathway than ballast water for exotic fouling species. Both boats and ships have influenced the invasion process of fouling species in Canadian coastal areas. The research also underlines the point that predictive models for the spread of biofouling species should be based on regional boating patterns, boating characteristics, and local propagule exposure. Defining relationships between propagule pressure and invasion success is one of the great challenges to understanding the rapid changes occurring in marine ecosystems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Frederic Guichard</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Christopher McKindsey</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qt33r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301485p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Ecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nj18x"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The biomechanics of ascending aortic aneurysms: The effect of measurement technique</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wener, Evan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An ascending aortic aneurysm is a pathologic enlargement of the ascending portion of the aorta. Comorbidities of dilation include aortic valve disease and connective tissue disorders. If the ascending aorta exceeds a threshold diameter, open heart surgery is recommended. This is a traumatic procedure and the recovery is demanding.  As our population ages and with improved technologies to diagnose the disease, the number of cases will increase every year. Understanding the mechanics of ascending aortic tissue will help cardiac surgeons make timely decisions on when to intervene. There are many ways to characterize the mechanical properties of aortic tissue. In this study, we used biaxial and uniaxial tensile testing with an optical tracking system to record the Green-Lagrangian (Green strain) strain. Engineering and true stiffness values were calculated and compared along with patient characteristics. Aortas were classified by valve type as healthy, tricuspid, bicuspid type 1 and bicuspid type 2. The results show that diseased tissue does behave differently than healthy tissue indicating that a local remodeling does occurs to the aortic wall. There are also differences in the mechanics between the types of diseased valves suggesting that valve type also affects the way the aortic wall responds to the disturbed hemodynamic environment. Correlations between stiffness and patient characteristics show that no matter which experimented technique or method of stiffness calculation is used, relationships are generally conserved. The only difference is the magnitude of the elastic modulus. The conclusions drawn from the data would not change whether biaxial or uniaxial experiments were performed. However when comparing engineering and true stiffness, only 7/12 covariances were similar and therefore the conclusions are inconsistent. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Un anévrisme de l'aorte ascendante est un agrandissement pathologique de l'aorte ascendante. Les comorbidités de dilatation incluent les maladies de la valve aortique et du tissu conjonctif. Si l'aorte ascendante dépasse un diamètre seuil, la chirurgie à cœur ouvert est recommandée. Il s'agit d'une procédure traumatique et la récupération est exigeante. Comme notre population vieillit et que les technologies pour diagnostiquer la maladie se sont beaucoup améliorées, le nombre de cas décelé va augmenter chaque année. Comprendre les mécanismes du tissu aortique ascendant aidera les chirurgiens cardiaques à prendre les bonnes décisions au bon moment. Il y a plusieurs façons de caractériser les propriétés mécaniques du tissu aortique. Dans cette étude, nous avons utilisé les essais de traction biaxiale et uniaxiale avec un système de suivi optique pour enregistrer la souche Green-Lagrange (souche verte). Valeurs de rigidité d'ingénierie et de vrai ont été calculées et comparées avec les caractéristiques des patients. Les aortes ont été classées en 4 types de valves : bonne santé, tricuspides, bicuspides de type 1 et bicuspides de type 2. Les résultats montrent que les tissus malades sont différents des tissus en bonne santé qui indiquent qu'un remodelage local se produit sur la paroi aortique. Il existe aussi des différences dans le mécanisme des différents types de valvules qui suggèrent que le type de valve affecte également la façon dont la paroi aortique répond à l'environnement perturbé hémodynamique. Les corrélations entre les caractéristiques de rigidité et le patient nous montrent que quelque-soit la technique ou la méthode de calcul utilisée pour la rigidité, les relations sont généralement conservées. La seule différence est la grandeur du module d'élasticité. Les conclusions tirées de ces données ne changeraient pas, peu importe le type d'expérimentation effectué; biaxiale ou uniaxiale. Cependant, lorsque l'on compare la rigidité d'ingénierie et de vrai, seulement 7 covariances sur 12 sont similaires et les conclusions sont contradictoires.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Richard L. Leask</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cv15d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj18x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>