<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw6634486f"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Wordsworth's spots of time : a psychoanalytic study of revision</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Macdonald, Shawn E. (Shawn Earl)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the introductory definition of spots of time, Wordsworth claims that these important childhood episodes are virtuous and worthy of celebration. This definition is incongruous with the episodes considered independently, because they reveal themselves as essentially disturbing memories. As he revised the spots of time, Wordsworth attempted to mitigate the disturbing nature of the episodes, betraying his need to repress certain undesireable aspects of the early texts. The following study is a Freudian reading of Wordsworth's spots of time in their various stages of revision. The Introduction to this study addresses some of the problems of interpretation. Chapter One places a Freudian reading of Wordsworth within the context of previous scholarship. Chapter Two is a close reading of the earliest spots of time as informed by Oedipal memories. Chapter Three examines Wordsworth's attempt, through revision, to repress these Oedipal memories.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859g81n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634486f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Wordsworth, William, 1770-1850 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gh433"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mass selective capture by an RFQ trap of externally injected ions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Davey, Louise</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A system for mass-selective capture of ions by a Paul trap was designed and tested. An Paul trap and associated electronics have been assembled and tested, selectively trapping the ionic clusters C$ sp{+} sb2$ and C$ sp{+} sb3$ from a pulsed laser ion source. The ions were injected at 90 eV, trapped, extracted and detected, several parameters related to these processes were investigated. Simple models of the injection mechanism employed and for evaluating the pseudo-potential well depth of the ion trap are proposed. The overall efficiency of the ion injection system has been evaluated and compared to other methods of ion capture by an RFQ trap from an external source.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r893t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gh433</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Electricity and Magnetism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848r71c"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'univers romanesque d'Émile Ajar ou Le refus de la norme</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lafond, Hélène</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1973, Emile Ajar published his first novel, Gros-Calin, and his very unusual style drew public attention. In fact, the name of Emile Ajar conceals a famous writer, Romain Gary. He endeavours to escape from the iron grip of criticism and attempts to renew his writing by resorting to an assumed name. This thesis is based on the fictitious world of Emile Ajar and the rejection of societal norms. A close study of the composition of this fictitious universe permits the reader to unravel its particular nature. The first chapter explains the structure of the various tales and their characteristics such as the relationship between the narrator and the narrative, between the narrator and the reader, and between the subject and the means used by the hero to relate his experience. This analysis discloses how the author conceals the threads of his tale to captivate his audience more successfully. The second chapter presents society as it is; its characteristics, symbols and the hero's response to this environment. The last chapter explores the characteristics, symbols and the behaviour of the hero in a world characterized by antisocietal values. It reveals the importance and the meaning of this "antisociety" and Emile Ajar's rejection of the status quo.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jc56s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848r71c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gary, Romain -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gary, Romain -- Pseudonyms</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cb95n"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>John Donne's Apocalypse</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Holmes, Michael M. (Michael Morgan)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores John Donne's vision of the Apocalypse as revealed by his religious poetry and prose. Donne believed himself to be alive in the last age of the world; however, he rejected historicist interpretations of the Apocalypse. Instead, he located the conflict with sin and death within the individual soul. Donne was concerned to create an image of the sinful soul restored to unity with the divine through its own exertions and by God's grace, free from social and political constraints. The Apocalypse presented Donne with a paradigm of unity which he appropriated in order to represent the interconnexion of God and humankind, as well as to situate himself within a present unfolding of ultimate conformity. Knowledge of the role of the Apocalypse in Donne's self-presentation, provides an awareness of the extent to which Donne understood himself to be an active participant in the fulfilment of the Providential design.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053h137.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cb95n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Donne, John, 1572-1631 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1z40kt97c"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The conscription movement in Great Britain 1899-1914</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hendley, Matthew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is an examination of the Conscription movement in Britain between 1899-1914. The introduction briefly examines British efforts at home defence before 1899 and the existing historiography on the Edwardian Conscription movement. Chapter One studies the impact of that conflict's manpower problems. In particular, it looks at the ad hoc wartime efforts to expand the Army and the subsequent rise of the National Service League. Chapter Two studies the non-military goals of the Conscription movement. It considers the attraction of conscription as the foundation of both greater physical efficiency and social reform, especially before 1906. The final chapter studies the use of sensationalist invasion scares and calls for home defence to further the cause of the Conscription movement. Particular attention is given to the invasion scare of 1908-09 and the rise of the Territorial Force after 1906.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ch76w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kt97c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Draft -- Great Britain</dc:subject><dc:subject>Great Britain -- Military policy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az316q265z"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Heartland</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Krysler, Gary</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thesis is a short novel, HeartLand, followed by a critical afterword. The events of the novel constitute a reconstruction of the first-person narrator's past. Jeffrey Adam Wood is seven years old when he is orphaned and taken to live with his three spinster aunts, who are sectarian fundamentalist Christians of peculiar stripe. Juxtaposed to Jeffrey's episodic recollections are 'dreams' he invents and imposes on his aunts as a kind of apocalyptic and cathartic revenge. Thematically, HeartLand is a contemplation of how time alters memory, belief, and individual identity. The required critical afterword is in two parts. The first provides a background to fundamentalism, with an emphasis on how American culture influenced its development. The second considers how, in literature, cultural forces encroach upon even the most sectarian individuals; this is done by focusing primarily, and briefly, on Theodore Dreiser's An American Tragedy.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zp57k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q265z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fundamentalism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956h12p"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Elasto-viscoplastic modelling of rock excavations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rizkalla, Maged Kamal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The first part of the thesis describes the concepts of viscoplasticity as a continuous plasticity theory highlighting different kinds of yield functions, plastic potentials and visocplastic constitutive laws. A 2-dimensional elasto-viscoplastic finite element model for stress/stability analysis of mining excavations has been developed for use on microcomputers. An iterative explicit time stepping scheme is implemented. The program uses automatic time-step calculator based on equations giving a limit on the time step in an attempt to prevent numerical instability when common forms of isotropic yield functions and plastic potentials are used in the viscoplastic solution. When the input data are read parallel to the analysis undertaken the user can simulate compound behaviour by stopping the analysis, examining the results graphically and restarting it again and possibly implementing a certain decision in the subsequent appended input. This also imposes no limit on the number of time stations at which instantaneous changes like elements cut, elements backfilled, loads added or simply outputs are required. The program is equipped with graphical pre- and post- processors.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494963m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h12p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geotechnology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1v53jz27n"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Italian</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Languages in contact : error analysis of Italian childrens' compositions in a multilingual context</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Samperi-Mangan, Jacqueline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Children of Italian immigrants in Montreal are in contact with many languages and kinds of speech. French and English are used publicly, formal Italian is studied in heritage classes, a dialect of the family's region of origin is used at home, and a kind of koine is frequently used in interactions with other Italian immigrants. The contact of these languages produces various kinds of interferences. These lead a child to make errors when he tries to use the Standard Italian code. In this research, children's compositions are examined for errors which in turn are analysed and classified. The causes of these errors are investigated and statistics are presented to indicate the frequency of errors or the power of various causes. An effort is made to show all the different errors and interferences that occur, and to discover a pattern of their causes. The data put forth might eventually serve as a base for further studies on the pedagogical prevention or correction of errors in the teaching of Standard Italian as adapted to the specific situation in Montreal.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924c90b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz27n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Italian language -- Errors of usage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Italian language -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Italian language -- Foreign words and phrases</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axw42n916f"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of divorce on perceived self-efficacy and behavior in elementary school children</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pagani, Linda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigates the influence of family configuration and environment on children's adjustment. Half of the seventy-six elementary school age participants were from families where separation and divorce had occurred, and the remaining children were from intact families. Children's self-efficacy was assessed using the Harter Self Perception Profile (Harter, 1985). Parental perceptions of children's behavior and specific family environmental characteristics were obtained by employing the Child Behavior Checklist (Achenbach &amp; Edelbrock, 1983), Family Environment Scale (Moos &amp; Moos, 1986) and Overt-Hostility Scale (O'Leary &amp; Porter, 1980). Children from homes where parental divorce had previously occurred were compared to children from intact families in terms of self-efficacy and behavior. Children from divorced homes demonstrated lower levels of perceived self-efficacy in cognitive and behavioral domains. No differences in parental perceptions of children's total behavior problems between groups were found. Comparative differences in family social climate characteristics of cohesion, control, and active-recreational orientation were found in divorced versus intact families.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tq434.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n916f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Children of divorced parents</dc:subject><dc:subject>Child psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>School children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A73666559n"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of visual andor auditory stimulation on akinesia in Parkinson's disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Toomey, Moira</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Idiopathic Parkinson's disease (IPD) is a severely disabling neurodegenerative disorder. The akinesia symptom dramatically alters the lifestyle of individuals with IPD. A within-subjects design was used to study the effects of sensory stimulation on akinesia. Twelve male, non-institutionalized parkinsonian subjects were tested. All demonstrated akinesia and were right-handed. Reaction time and movement time measures were recorded on an Apple 2e computer. The task entailed reached from a release switch to a target switch while three sensory stimuli (visual, auditory and concurrent visual and auditory) were used randomly during three different environmental conditions (open, physical constraint and stress). It was found that the concurrent use of visual and auditory stimuli in an open environmental condition significantly decreased the movement times and total reaction times. Therefore the use of sensory stimulation improves a reaching movement in subjects with IPD. The use of such stimuli would alter the person's disabilities and improve their functional status.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j9208.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666559n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75r8943"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Images of feminine beauty in advertisements for beauty products, English Canada, 1901-1941</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mawhood, Rhonda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is a study of magazine advertisements for beauty products in Canada between 1901 and 1941. It looks at the use of cosmetics and the growth of advertising in the context of the development of North American consumer culture, highlighting the role of gender in that culture. The period studied is divided in two by the mid-1920s to reflect changes in advertisers' views of consumers--from rational decision-makers to irrational creatures driven by their emotions--and in ideals of feminine beauty, as the use of cosmetics became an essential part of the ideal perpetuated by advertising. The thesis attempts to show the link between business history and cultural history by demonstrating how marketing professionals co-opted cultural trends in order to create effective advertising, and how traditional relationships and values were modified by the purchase and use of mass-marketed goods.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse est une étude des annonces publicitaires pour les produits de beauté dans des revues à grand tirage au Canada entre 1901 et 1941. Elle examine l'usage des cosmétiques et la croissance de la publicité dans le contexte du développement d'une culture nord-américaine de la consommation, mettant l'emphase sur le rôle des sexes dans cette culture. Le milieu des années 1920 représente une rupture entre deux périodes. Cette division souligne la transformation de la conception que les publicitaires avaient des consommateurs, passant de gens qui prenaient des décisions rationnelles, a des créatures irrationnelles, motivées par leurs émotions. Le milieu des années 1920 marque également un changement dans les idéaux de la beauté féminine: l'idéal promu par les publicitaires exigeait l'emploi des cosmétiques. Cette thèse tente de démontrer le lien entre l'histoire du milieu des affaires et l'histoire de la culture, en illustrant comment les publicitaires cooptèrent les mouvements culturels afin de créer une publicité efficace, et comment les relations et valeurs traditionnelles furent modifiées par l'achat et l'usage des produits commercialises.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311q39m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r8943</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women in advertising -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Advertising -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Advertising -- Cosmetics -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am039k6213"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Drawing bridges : public/private worlds in Russian women's fiction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mooney, Susan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis questions how Russian women's identity is attached to the textual use of public/private spaces in contemporary literature by Russian women writers by drawing from feminist theories. I. Grekova and N. Baranskaia portray female protagonists in their everyday lives, public and private worlds overlapping. While these heroines create stable support systems with other women, male figures enter as interruptive forces in women's lives. Hospital settings in several works by Russian women allow comparisons between women's fictional hospital experiences and those of Muscovite women interviewed. In L. Petrushevskaia's stories, women protagonists' identities are linked to the uncertain quality of locale and the tenuous relationships which transpire in it. Russian women's identity expressed in fiction may change as the self-perceptions of a younger generation of Russian women writers evolve toward a new, gendered concept of self.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Westphal, Sarah</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Roll, Serafima</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50ts74z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k6213</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Russian literature -- Women authors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women authors, Russian</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab2773w87x"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le réseau intertextuel dans le poème Primorskij Park Pobedy d'Anna Axmatova</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lozowy, Eric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Axmatova wrote the poem Primorskij park Pobedy in 1950 for Slava miru, a collection of verses that glorified Stalin. This poem was included in all her books that were published before her death (1966), apparently to please her censors. A few specialists that are trying today to establish a canonical and definitive version of her poetical works believe that Primorskij park Pobedy cannot be treated as a real Axmatova poem. The exclusion of a "parasitical" element seems unjustified if we conceive Axmatova's poetical works not as a complete Book, that is a definite and homogenous whole, but as a variable unity with undetermined limits. When we read Primorskij park Pobedy through an intertextual network, the superficial meaning of the poem cracks and collapses. The text becomes open: under a trivial and official meaning is concealed an infinity of possible meanings. Our thesis explores this polysemy by showing how Axmatova's poem can generate a system of intertextual relations.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q267h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773w87x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Akhmatova, Anna Andreevna, 1889-1966 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225c13v"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La nourriture dans l'oeuvre romanesque de Georges Bernanos</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wong Chong, Stephen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The presence or absence of food in the novels of Bernanos lie within a highly meaningful system of values and images. From a list of references to food, we will define the nature and role of food in Bernanos' novels. Then we shall try to bring out the symbolic system which organizes the various elements of this theme in one coherent whole. Thus we will see that food, scarce in this work, is always associated with evil, or tends to disappear in a system of images related to sin. As for food acceptable in the eyes of Bernanos, it also eventually loses its material quality by becoming metaphors of the spiritual world.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fs51r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225c13v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bernanos, Georges, 1888-1948 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r6761"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A survey of carrot diseases on muck soils in the Montreal area and evaluation of partial resistance to Cercospora blight in carrot cultivars</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Arcelin, Rachel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During the summer 1988 and 1989, surveys were conducted on the muck soils, South of Montreal to estimate the prevalence and incidence of the carrot diseases. Cercospora blight was the most prevalent disease; 91% and 96% of the fields and 99% and 92% of the plants sampled were diseased in 1988 and 1989, respectively. In decreasing order of occurrence the diseases present were: Crown gall, Alternaria blight, Root Knot, Sclerotinia rot and Aster yellows. Greenhouse and field studies were carried out to evaluate partial resistance to Cercospora blight in 111 carrot cultivars based on the mean incubation period (MIP), the proportion of leaf area diseased (PLAD), and the sporulation / mm$ sp2$ lesion area (SPO). Significant differences among varieties were observed for all the parameters studied under greenhouse conditions and a significant negative correlation was found between PLAD and MIP (r = $-$0.29). Resistance equivalents were calculated for the PLAD, as proportions of the cultivar Dagger, so that they could be incorporated in a fundamental forecast model.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x510n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r6761</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Carrots -- Disease and pest resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cercospora</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carrots -- Diseases and pests -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jv93x"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the preservation of mammalian embryos in the supercooled state</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fuku, Eiji</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Firstly, exposure of compacted morulae (CM) and early blastocysts (EB) to methanol (M) or glycerol (G) for 1 h at room temperature followed by culture in standard culture medium showed that the embryos tolerated up to 12 to 24% methanol or 24 to 48% glycerol. Next, the effects of stage of embryo (CM vs EB), preservation temperature and concentration of 1:1 M:G on embryo survival were tested. EB survived longer than CM under all conditions. Increased concentrations of cryoprotectants (M and G) increased the survival of supercooled embryos, but survival was decreased with the storage temperature. Replacing G with propanediol (P) significantly increased blastocyst survival at lower temperatures. Exposure for 1 h to $&gt;$ 0.6 M of sucrose or trehalose at room temperature suppressed growth in culture, but dehydration in up to 0.4M sucrose before supercooling (in M:P) increased survival at $-$5 or $-$10$ sp circ$C, survival increasing with dehydration. Finally, demi-embryos and intact embryos were cultured to the blastocyst stage, stored at $-$5$ sp circ$ for 48 h, then cultured for 24 h and transferred into pseudopregnant recipients.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935413g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jv93x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mice -- Embryos</dc:subject><dc:subject>Embryology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Supercooling</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak643b234s"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le sechage des balles de foin denses à basse température</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guertin, Léon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Rectangular bales of hay measuring 35 x 46 x 84 cm baled to a density ranging from 145 to 172,4 kg/m$ sp3$ were dried on a dryer which can contain 4 300 bales for a total weight of approximately 130 tons. A 1,2 meter fan activated by a 60 kw L.P. Gaz engine insured an air flow of 840 m$ sp3$/min at 625 Pa of static pressure. This research has clearly demonstrated that approximately 50% of the drying air flowed between the bales placed on the dryer. By increasing the flow of air, the drying rate of the bales of hay was also increased. The results obtained prove of the effect of both temperature and relative humidity of the air on drying capacity. Finally, the dryer was more efficient when ten (10) rows of bales were dried at one time rather than 5. It would be desirable to develop a mathematical model to produce a computer simulation of drying applied to bales of hay. Efficient strategies to improve drying procedures of densely baled hay could thus be developed.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d536v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b234s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hay -- Drying</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jv92n"><ual:graduationDate>1986</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Income splitting among family members : the attribution rules</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Adelman, Ian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is a study of certain means available to taxpayers who wish to split their income with other members of their family and thereby reduce their taxes. There are essentially four sections to the study: (a) a description of the Canadian system of taxation of the family and the reasons why the Income Tax Act treats each individual as a separate unit for income tax purposes as opposed to recognizing the family unit itself as the basis for taxation; (b) an analysis of the tax consequences of loans and transfers of property between spouses; (c) an analysis of the tax consequences of loans and transfers of property to children under the age of 18 years; and (d) an analysis of the concept of indirect payments. The principal conclusion of the study is that the means available to split income among family members are limited, especially in view of the recent amendments to the Income Tax Act to gradually eliminate the "family loan" method of splitting income.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w168.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jv92n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5t34sk67j"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Meteorology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A diagnostic study of the summer southern hemisphere circulation of the CCC general circulation model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Su, Lin, 1966-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The medium scale planetary wave regime, consisting largely of zonal wavenumbers 5-7, frequently dominate the summer Southern Hemisphere tropospheric circulation. We perform a diagnostic study of this circulation as simulated by the Canadian Climate Centre (CCC) general circulation model (GCM). The analysis of Hovmoller diagrams, space-time and zonal wavenumber spectra shows that the CCC GCM is able to simulate the observed medium scale wave regime. The zonally averaged meridional eddy heat and momentum transports and the associated baroclinic and barotropic energy conversions are also examined. The distributions of the transports on the vertical plane agree well with observations. When compared to the observed summer 1979 distributions, some quantitative differences remain: the vertical structure of the heat transport is too baroclinic, while the momentum transport tends to be too weak. The baroclinic and barotropic conversions all show a medium scale wave signal. The time evolution of the Richardson number of the mean flow suggests that the medium scale wave is due to a finite amplitude baroclinic instability.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73px168.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sk67j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78td26p"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aspects of pion propagation in hot and dense nuclear matter</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Yongjiang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Some important aspects of pion propagation in hot and dense nuclear matter are investigated by considering the dominant p-wave pion nucleon interaction including the $ Delta$-isobar channel. We find that for zero temperature nuclear mater, the static approximation in the computation of the pion branch dispersion relation is not adequate in general. In the finite temperature nuclear matter up to T = 50MeV, the pion propagation does not change much comparing to that in the zero temperature medium, but the pion absorption through the first order pion-nucleon interaction, on the other hand, increases significantly as the temperature goes up. We also give a formula to determine the critical nuclear matter density $ rho sb{c}$ and when $ rho &gt; rho sb{c}$ is satisfied, a minimum exists in the corresponding pion branch.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s133m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td26p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p833g"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Time-scale modification of speech : a time-frequency approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sylvestre, Benoit</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Time-scale modification (TSM) is a process whereby signals are compressed or expanded in time in a manner which preserves their original frequency characteristics. This work explores TSM algorithms for sampled speech. A known approach (2) which is based on the short-time Fourier transform (STFT) is first reviewed, then modified to provide high-quality TSM of speech signals at a lower computational cost. The proposed algorithm resembles the sinusoidal speech model (SSM) based approach (9), yet incorporates new phase compensatory measures to prevent excessive structural deterioration of the time-scaled signal. In addition, a novel incremental scheme for modifying polar parameters results in substantial computational savings.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q268s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p833g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw0892b98r"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>High-Tc Bi oxides by crystallization of an amorphous precursor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tessier, Pascal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The amorphization of the Bi-Sr-Ca-Cu-O system by mechanical alloying starting from the individual oxides is examined. Several reactions concur to finally yield an amorphous matrix containing nanocrystalline copper oxide precipitates. Annealing the amorphous material leads, in a first step, to a crystalline solid solution, and, in a second step, to a low-Tc superconducting phase. Long term annealing allows the formation of the 85K superconducting phase.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vh783.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892b98r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289k277"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Religion and Philosophy in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Alan Watts' theological anthropology and its implications for religious education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hinz, William</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To those individuals who felt alienated and disillusioned by traditional Western forms of religion, Alan Watts offered a different way of looking at the world and a new understanding of what it means to be religious. Borrowing heavily from Taoism, Zen Buddhism, Vendanta Hinduism and other Eastern traditions, Watts argues that our widely accepted notion of a person as an active, willing agent existing as a lonely island of consciousness is an illusion rooted in social and linguistic conventions. In place of the typical Western image of God as an external personal being governing the universe by means of his omnipotent will and omniscient intellect, Watts argues in favour of the Eastern image of God as the mysterious depth and ground of all being. If education is concerned with the task of enabling a person to grow and mature as a full human being and religion is concerned with fostering the uniquely human capacity to be fully present and open to the mystery and wonder of existence, then it follows that being educated and becoming religious are part of the same process. For Watts, religious education is characterized not according to a specific content but rather an underlying set of values which promote an awareness of humanity's interrelationship and interdependence with the rest of the universe.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182m34r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289k277</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religious education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Watts, Alan, 1915-1973 -- Views on religion</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar781wh17z"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Conjunctive housing : housing in mixed-use complexes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fung, Augustine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the idea of conjunctive housing as a viable alternative for habitation within the urban context. It traces the historical origins of housing in conjunctive use with other functions. Various examples of this type of housing are cited extending from its beginnings during the classical era right up to the twentieth century. The study of the mixed land use concept in urban areas calls for a more comprehensive analysis of the validity of conjunctive housing as an alternative to the ever increasing suburbanization. This idea transcends the notion of landuse efficiency, and underscores the importance of promoting inner-city living. Conjunctive housing represents a time-tested approach which deviates from various other conventional housing patterns. An exhibit of several types of mixed-use establishments is provided, together with a probe into its generic forms which demonstrate the numerous planning options. This thesis is an attempt to reiterate the concept of conjunctive housing, especially in response to the contemporary trend of urban living, as a viable solution for housing urbanites, a concept which may even prove to promote a socially superior mode of urban lifestyle.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r895c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh17z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Land use, Urban</dc:subject><dc:subject>Housing</dc:subject><dc:subject>City planning</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd375x462"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Transnationalism and democracy in Brazil</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rioux, Michèle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In Brazil, the coincidence of massive growth and growing inequalities was also combined with an authoritarian regime. This coincidence led the dependency scholars to link the Brazilian economic model and the repressive and authoritarian nature of the political regime. However, the Brazilian democratization process, taking roots in the mid-70s, reformulated the issue. Indeed, while remaining committed to transnationalism, a democratization process was underway. This paper argues that the democratization process is consistent with, and even motivated by, the regulation imperatives of the regime of accumulation. However, these regulation imperatives limit the nature and scope of democratic reforms. Nevertheless, transnationalism also lay the foundations for more progressive and democratic option to emerge in formal politics and in civil society.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nz239.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375x462</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Brazil -- Economic policy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Brazil -- Politics and government -- 20th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>