<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93h122p"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Perceptual coding of narrowband audio signals</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Najafzadeh-Azghandi, Hossein</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>New applications such as Internet broadcast and communications, consumer multimedia products, digital AM broadcast and satellite networks are emerging, Those applications require moderate audio quality without annoying artifacts at bit rates below 16 kbit/s. Although speech coders provide high speech quality at bit rates around 8 kbit/s, they perform poorly when encoding audio signals. In this thesis, we present a novel transform coding paradigm based on the characteristics of the human hearing system. The proposed encoder, i.e., Narrowband Perceptual Audio Coder (NPAC), can accommodate a wide range of narrowband audio inputs without annoying artifacts at bit rates down to 8 kbit/s. NPAC employs a variety of algorithms to remove the perceptually irrelevant parts and statistical redundancies of the input signal. The new algorithms used in NPAC include a perceptual error measure in training the codebooks and selecting the best codewords, perceptually-based bit allocation algorithms and an adaptive predictive scheme to vector quantize the scale factors. The proposed encoder has moderate complexity and delivers good quality for narrowband audio inputs at around 1 bit/sample. Informal subjective tests have been conducted to compare the performance of NPAC with an 8 kbit/s commercially-available audio Coder. The tests results show that NPAC performs better for both music and speech inputs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kabal, Peter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m1037.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h122p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b7836"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intraseasonal and interannual variability of sea ice in the Gulf of St.Lawrence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Yongxiang, 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Intraseasonal and interannual variability of sea-ice cover (SIC) in the Gulf of St. Lawrence, including the time of first ice presence (TFIP), time of last ice presence (TLIP), and sea-ice duration (SID), were investigated, using weekly sea ice observations from 1963--1996. For the intraseasonal variations of sea ice, it was found that SIC in different sub-regions displays contrasting features. The largest intraseasonal variations of SIC occur in the Strait of Belle Isle region and in the southwestem Gulf, where the mean SIC is largest and SID is longest. For the interannual variability of sea ice, the largest variability of SIC occurs in the area off mid-Newfoundland, where the mean SIC is small. For the TFIP and TLIP, the largest interannual variability occurs in the area off western Newfoundland and along coasts in the northeast sector of the Gulf, respectively. In addition, sea ice appeared earlier in the coastal regions and disappeared later over the entire Gulf in severe ice years; while sea ice appeared later in the central and eastern Gulf and disappeared earlier over the entire Gulf in light ice years. Several of the forcing factors influencing sea ice variability in the Gulf of St. Lawrence were examined and mechanisms controlling this variability were discussed. It was found that surface air temperature (SAT), the eastward wind component (u-wind), sea surface temperature (SST), sea surface salinity (SSS), mixed layer depth (MLD), total river runoff, the ocean circulation pattern, and sea-ice advection from the Labrador Sea, all play important roles in explaining sea ice variability in the Gulf. However, the relative contributions of these factors to the observed sea ice variability differ in different subregions. Quantitative relationships between sea ice variability and various forcing factors were investigated using statistical analysis and a simplified Hibler's sea-ice model. Both approaches indicated that the December--April averaged SAT, u-wind, and November SST all contribute to the variability of December--June SIC in the Gulf, with SAT playing the most important role. The analysis also indicated that the dependence of SIC on various forcing factors varies with geographical location. For example, SAT influences sea ice variability mainly in the central Gulf, while the u-wind component effects SIC mainly in the eastern Gulf. In addition, statistical analyses also suggest that SSS values present in the previous November play an important role in determining SIC variability. The linear regression between SIC and three independent variables: December--April SAT, November SST and SSS, accounts for 81% of the total SIC variance. The statistical analysis and model study also indicated that December SAT, u-wind, November SST, and MLD control the time of first ice presence, with SAT and SST playing the dominant role. The linear regression between TFIP and three independent variables (u-wind, SST, and SSS) accounts for 76% of the total TFIP variance. For TLIP, both SAT and u-wind play an important role.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ingram, Grant R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs631.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b7836</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical Oceanography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021g94b"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Static and dynamic properties of epileptogenic lesions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Li Min, 1964-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A series of studies were undertaken with the aim of assessing the static and dynamic profiles of the most common types of epileptogenic lesions: hippocampal sclerosis and cortical developmental malformations. Neuronal metabolic dysfunction measured by proton magnetic resonance spectroscopic imaging (1H-MRSI) overlaps the structural lesion displayed by magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), The extent of neuronal metabolic dysfunction, however, tends to be wider than the MRI-visible lesion and may reflect the intrinsic nature and extent of the original epileptogenic damage. In addition, neuronal metabolic dysfunction and synchronized neuronal firing often coincide spatially and vary together in intensity possibly reflecting the severity of the epileptogenic process. Non-foreign tissue lesional, temporal lobe epilepsy (TLE) syndrome is a heterogeneous condition, which displays a spectrum of neuronal damage. The different patterns of neuronal damage measured by MRI volumetry (MRIVol) and 1H-MRSI enable accurate probabilistic prediction of TLE lateralization and discrimination of TLE from extra-TLE. Furthermore, both MRIVol and 1H-MRSI have a prognostic value in surgical TLE patients, which can be used to streamline surgical candidates. The neuronal damage is present in the early stages of the epileptogenic process in patients with localization related epilepsy. This process is dynamic and shows a slow progressive neuronal loss and dysfunction in TLE patients, which is not related to seizure burden. Neuronal metabolic dysfunction, lesions, spikes, cognitive decline, and psychiatric disorders are part of the epileptogenic process. These different domains parallel each other in a given time, although their pathophysiological processes are distinct. Thus seizures and neuronal damage co-exist but are not causally related. Normalization of neuronal metabolic function is seen in post-operative seizure-free patients, with a recovery half time of six months. However, the process of neuronal recovery does not occur in patients who are seizure-free due to antiepileptic medication. The epileptogenic process causes disruption of normal neuronal network and in order to reverse this disruption the epileptogenic area must be isolated or resected surgically. The epileptic state is a translation in time of the activity of the epileptogenic process. Seizures, stereotyped behavioral manifestations, are the hallmark of the epileptogenic process, Absence of seizures, however, does not reflect inactivity of the epileptogenic process, Neuronal damage as measured by NAA/Cr can serve as a surrogate marker of the epileptogenic state.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Arnold, D. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999836d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g94b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pc13c"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A high speed optical surface coordinate measurement system and its applications to dynamic measurements</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Yong, 1965 May 3-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Currently there is no standard whole-field methodology to measure the transient out-of-plane deformation of a surface under dynamic events. In this work, a whole-field high-speed optical surface measurement system has been developed, which yields absolute Cartesian coordinates (xyz) as measurement results. A high-speed digital camera coupled with the grating projection and Fourier transform is used to measure 3D surface deformations with the maximum sampling rate up to 1000 Hz and the exposure time of each frame up to 50 musec. A calibration technique has been utilized to convert the direct measurable values---phase, phi, and image indices (i, j)---into 3D Cartesian coordinates (xyz). In addition, all Cartesian coordinates are with respect to a fixed coordinate system, which is virtually associated with the sensor head. Therefore, the rigid body movements (rotation and translation) of the surface can be detected. The measurement accuracy +/-50 mum is verified with several tests by using standard objects. The dynamic surface deformation during polymer membrane inflation tests is investigated by using the proposed optical measurement system. Effects of various factors, such as the temperature and the airflow rate, are studied. Regarding the characterization of material constants by using the bubble inflation technique, the potential problems, which are caused by ignoring the nonuniformities of temperature distribution and the thermo-warping, have been studied. A finite-element model, which can account for the nonuniformities of temperature distribution and the thermo-warping, has been employed to simulate the inflation deformation. A more accurate way to characterize the material constants is accomplished by combining the optical measurement system and a finite-element model that can account for the nonuniformities of the temperature distribution and the thermo-warping.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nemes, J. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m09r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc13c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A37720f51r"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structural and functional studies of an ACYL-ACP thioesterase from bioluminescent bacteria</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Jun, 1966 Mar. 15-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Vibrio harveyi myristoyl-ACP thioesterase (LuxD) differs from most thioesterases in substrate specificity, turnover rate and rate limiting step with the deacylation step occurring at a very slow rate. A serine residue, Ser114, which is the central serine in the sequence A-x-S-x-S and not part of the standard G-x-S-x-G consensus motif, has been identified as the active site nucleophile. Ser114 together with His241 and Asp211, form a catalytic triad with a mechanism similar to that of the esterase/lipase family. Tryptophan fluorescence of the V. harveyi thioesterase and its tryptophan mutants showed that there is a ligand induced conformational change during acylation of the enzyme and that the fluorescence of tryptophan 213 is specifically enhanced on substrate binding. A chimeric LuxD, constructed from Photobacterium phosphoreum LuxD and Vibrio harveyi LuxD was shown to be hyperactive compared to its parental LuxDs. Studies of this chimera revealed that the carboxyl-terminal half of the thioesterase is the part of the molecule involved with interaction with the synthetase component of the fatty acid reductase complex responsible for synthesis of aldehyde substrate for the luminescent reaction.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Meighen, Edward</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q83x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720f51r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anc580p226"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hierarchical supervisory control systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hubbard, Paul J., 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents two approaches to the hierarchical supervisory control of discrete event systems (DES) modelled as finite deterministic automata. First, a hierarchical control theory based on the aggregation of states is presented that differs from the standard approach to hierarchical supervision which mainly employs formal language methods. A high-level (i.e. aggregated) deterministic automaton model is defined that uses notions of dynamical consistency (DC) in the definition of high-level transitions. A Trace-DC condition is then defined on any given state-space partition which ensures that (i) trajectories in the low-level system are always represented in the high-level system, and (ii) trajectories in the high-level model are realized by trajectories in the low-level system. It is also shown that the Trace-DC condition ensures low-level controllable behaviours (languages) are represented as high-level controllable behaviours. The (Non-Blocking) In-Block-Controllability condition on partitions is then defined that ensures that behaviours that are expressly controllable in the high-level model can be achieved through the control of high-level transitions between blocks combined with local state - feedback controls in each block. A so-called vocalised lifting algorithm is proposed for the construction of Trace-DC partitions. It is shown that this formulation of hierarchical supervision satisfies conditions of hierarchical consistency from the literature on formal language-based hierarchical supervisory control theory. The approach is illustrated with several examples of manufacturing production lines, including a re-entrant transfer line and a line with two sequential queues. An application to the embedded control of home appliances (washing machines) which motivates the approach is summarised. Second, a notion of systems of interacting finite deterministic automata is formulated via a newly proposed multi-agent ( MA) product. The transition relation of the MA product is shown to be the intersection of the transition relations of two associated products, the vector state-dependent synchronous product and the simultaneous product. It is shown also that the language accepted by the MA product is the intersection of the so-called embedded constraint language of each agent. The supervision of one agent by another is then considered and it is shown that the standard finite automata realization for a supervisor can be employed as the model for the supervising agent. A line of research is then initiated on the centralised, decentralised and hierarchical supervision of MA product systems. It is shown that the MA product of behaviours that are individually and independently controllable with respect to each agent forms a controllable behaviour in the MA product system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Caines, Peter E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h34g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p226</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anc580p21x"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Chasing fireflies : understanding struggling readers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hynes, Myrna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is a wide gap between current understandings of how readers read and how reading is taught in school, particularly to "at-risk" readers. Contemporary reading research and reader-response theories suggest that struggling readers should not be subjected to remedial programs involving "drills and skills," simplified "decodable" reading material, and most of all, low expectations of their teachers. Reading problems are not solved by filling gaps in a child's knowledge or skills. Instead, reluctant readers must be treated as readers, encouraged to develop their personal interests and enthusiasms through reading, and, most importantly, to make their own sense of their reading. By helping my students to read and respond to texts rich in content and appropriate to their interests and ages, I observed significant improvement in their confidence and competence as readers. This teacher-research study describes the growth of four readers in grade-seven with long histories of failure in school. Their stories are told in case studies that contain descriptions of the classroom activities and events that influenced their progress, observations of their interactions with their peers and with me, their teacher, and finally, analyses of their work samples. This work is also about my role in my students' development and, thus, includes my reflections on how I transformed both reading and reader-response theory into practice and on relevant features of my classroom management. In the case study of each student, I have tried to capture their different learning styles and problems and also my thinking processes that arose from the beliefs, questions, observations, reflections, hunches, and flashes of insight that I, like most teachers, used daily and that formed the substance of my reader-based pedagogy. In addition, I discuss in detail the ideas in the research literature, such as reader-response theory and the whole language/phonics debate, that help to explain my students' progress. As a teacher-researcher, I describe my teaching, as well as its effects on my students. Through understanding struggling readers, I came to understand reading. This is an account of my learning that delineates the nature of the interactions between teacher and students which is, in fact, the real curriculum of any classroom. An essential part of teaching is evaluating its effectiveness; this dissertation is a sustained evaluation of my reading program through four of my students' responses to it during one and, in two cases, two school years.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pare, Anthony</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p6399.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p21x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Reading -- Remedial teaching</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613n033c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Of swans, the wind and H.D. : an epistolary portrait of the poetic process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hussey, Charlotte</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation is a qualitative case study of a woman's poetic process. Rather than examine creativity from the outside, I have viewed it from the inside in an attempt to document my direct engagement, as an emergent woman poet, with my own writing. I have conducted personal, poetic research throughout this project in an attempt to construct a self-portrait of my own creativity. To do so, I have not attempted to prove a thesis, or strive for scientific objectivity. As the portrait of a woman's imagination, this text narrates the winding course of a transformative journey brought about by my experimentation with a number of writing strategies, or heuristics. Because the drafting of poems is a highly unpredictable endeavour, I have drawn on various techniques, discarding one if I became blocked in order to experiment with the hoped for success of the next. Chief among the heuristics I have employed was a yearlong fictive correspondence that I entered upon with the Modernist poet, H.D. [Hilda Doolittle]. During our exchanges, I would send her my musing about the writing process along with my poetry which she would critique and send back to me. After completing this epistolary venture, I analysed what our letters revealed about what both blocked and freed my developing voice. I conducted this investigation by laying down a secondary strata of theoretical intertexts addressed to a "Dear Reader" who symbolized my audience made up of my academic committee, in specific, and of writing theorists and scholars in general. I then appended this two-tiered effort with an introduction, multiple conclusions, and a closing-poem. The resulting structure of my dissertation is that of a palimpsest, a genre that H.D. herself often employed to create a more fluid convergence of autobiographical and mythic motifs. Other heuristics such as key word analysis, bodywork, a photograph exercise, dreams, travel, and the retelling of a fairy tale have been called upon, as well, to further inspire this palimpsest of the poetic process.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pare, Anthony</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687k026.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n033c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Poetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Poetry -- Authorship</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acv43nz884"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Nursing</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of the Webster-Stratton Parent Program on the parenting skills of maltreating mothers and the autonomous self-regulation of their preschool/early school age children</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hughes, Jean R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The primary purpose of this randomized controlled trial was to examine the effect of the Webster-Stratton Parents and Children Series, a proven, video-based, modeling, nurse-delivered, group cognitive-behavioural parent program, on the parenting skills and autonomous self-regulated behaviours of children (ages 3-to-8 years) in families on the caseload of child protection. Twenty-eight families on the caseload of one of three child protection agencies were randomly assigned to one of two conditions: the 16-hour weekly intervention group or the 4-month wait-list control group. Twenty-six families completed the study. Results of the statistical analysis showed that mothers in the treatment group had statistically significant improvement in one parenting skill, involvement, and marginally significant improvement in another parenting skill, autonomy-support, during one of two study activities (free-play) compared to the wait-list control group. No significant improvement was found among children in the treatment group when compared to their study counterparts. Further, little but promising support was found for the hypothesized relationship between mothers with a strong parenting profile and children with a strong autonomous self-regulated profile. Given the small sample size, providing only 30% power to detect a 10% change, further exploratory analyses were conducted. Although not statistically significant, performance was found to vary according to group, activity and behaviour. Several characteristics distinguished mothers, and children whose performance showed most change (improvement, deterioration). The fact that 92% of the mothers attended six or more of the eight parent program sessions and the low attrition rate (7%) indicate that the intervention may have been more successful with this population than statistical evidence demonstrates.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gottlieb, Laurie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k432f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nz884</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Nursing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Developmental</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Social</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anp193b61p"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Birth complications and long-term alterations in central dopamine systems : implications for schizophrenia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>El-Khodor, Bassem Fouad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Schizophrenia is a disorder whose pathophysiology is thought to involve increased activity in mesolimbic dopamine (DA) systems. Epidemiological studies have indicated increased pregnancy and birth complications, especially those resulting in fetal anoxia, among those who later develop schizophrenia. Furthermore, stress plays a role in onset and relapse in psychosis. This raised the question whether early life insults, such as birth anoxia, may produce a state of hyperdopaminergia that is exacerbated by stress. This thesis used a rat model of acute global anoxia during Caesarean section (C-section) birth to test the hypothesis that early birth anoxia can produce long-term changes in CNS DA systems. Two control groups of animals were also studied: vaginally born rats and rats born by C-section without added anoxia. As adults, in comparison to vaginally born rats, rats delivered by C-section (without global anoxia) showed: (1) alterations in steady state levels of DA in the CNS (i.e. enhanced DA in nucleus accumbens (NAcc) and striatum and reduced DA in prefrontal cortex); (2) enhanced locomotion and other behavioral responses to a low dose of amphetamine; (3) long-term alterations in DA receptors and in their regulation by stress. Before stress, C-sectioned animals showed increased D1-like receptor binding ([3H]-SCH23390) in limbic areas, compared to vaginally born controls. After stress, these animals showed decreased D3 receptors ([3H]-7-OH-DPAT binding) in NAcc and increased D4-like receptors ([3H]-YM-09151-2 binding + raclopride) in dorsal striatum, NAcc and olfactory tubercles. On the other hand, in comparison to vaginally born rats, adult rats delivered by C-section with an added acute (10 or 15 min) global anoxia showed: (1) enhanced locomotor responses to a stress challenge two weeks after repeated tail pinch stress and (2) heightened behavioral responses to low dose of amphetamine. Although appearing normal on gross observation, rat pups born by C-section showed altered respiratory rates and slightly increased levels of whole brain lactate (an indication of CNS hypoxia) during the first 24h of life, as well as low levels of plasma epinephrine immediately after birth, in comparison to vaginally born controls. After the first 1--5h of life, pups born by C-section + anoxia, remained normal with respect to these parameters, in comparison to vaginal controls. We conclude that early environmental insults, such as birth by C-section, with or without anoxia, can produce long-lasting biochemical and functional alterations in CNS DA systems. These findings support the notion that birth complications might contribute to the pathophysiology of disorders involving central dopaminergic neurons, such as schizophrenia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boksa, Patricia</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429b91c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193b61p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axk81jn19g"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional acetylcholine and serotonin receptors in brain microcirculation : importance of subtype and cellular localization in the determination of function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Elhusseiny, Ahmed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The brain intraparenchymal microcirculation is regulated by various brain neuronal pathways, including the cholinergic and serotonergic systems. In this study, we determined the molecular identity, second messenger coupling, cellular distribution and/or vasomotor functions of the receptors for these two neurovascular systems in human and/or bovine brain microvasculature. Using reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR), we first identified heterogeneous muscarinic acetylcholine receptors (mAChRs) in microvessel and capillary fractions isolated from human cerebral cortex. Using a combination of RT-PCR and second messenger assays on human cerebromicrovascular cell cultures, we then identified functional M2 and M5 mAChRs in endothelial cells, the M1, M3 and possibly M5 in smooth muscle cells, and all five mAChRs in astrocytes. In order to identify the vasomotor function(s) mediated by these receptors, we developed a technique to test the effect of vasoactive neurotransmitters on isolated and pressurized human and/or bovine intracortical penetrating arterioles (diameter ~47mum), known to be innervated by brain neurovascular pathways. ACh dose-dependently dilated human and bovine intracortical arterioles at spontaneous tone or following pre-constriction with serotonin (5-HT). In contrast, nicotine failed to significantly affect the diameters of the arterioles under similar conditions. Application of L-NNA (10-5 M), an inhibitor of nitric oxide synthase (NOS), elicited a gradual constriction (~40%) of the arterioles, indicating the presence of constitutive NO release in these vessels. It also significantly blocked the dilation induced by ACh in both human and bovine arterioles. The mAChR antagonists pirenzepine, 4-DAMP, and AF-DX 384 dose-dependently inhibited the dilation elicited by 10 -5M ACh with the following order of potency: 4-DAMP (pIC 50 = 9.2 +/- 0.1) &gt;&gt; pirenzepine (pIC50 = 6.7 +/- 0.2) &gt; AF-DX 384 (pIC50 = 5.9 +/- 0.1), which best corr</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hamel, Edith</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579t94f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn19g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vm69g"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Living rooms : domestic material culture in fiction by Joan Barfoot, Marion Quednau, and Diane Schoemperlen</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Elmslie, Susan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>My dissertation provides the first full-length study of representations of domestic material culture in contemporary Canadian women's fiction. The first chapter presents two metaphors, the elephant in the living room, and the open secret, and indicates their usefulness in explaining the cultural and critical tendency to overlook the meanings communicated by contemporary domestic material objects and spaces. Drawing on cultural anthropologist Grant McCracken's research into the role of consumption in the preservation of hopes and ideals, the second chapter examines gendered patterns of consumption in Joan Barfoot's first two novels. I suggest that Barfoot's female protagonists reject their suburban homes out of an awareness of the ways these spaces function as repositories of values with which they can no longer live. In the third chapter, I situate my discussion of the Hardoy, or "butterfly chair," in Marion Quednau's novel of the same name, against the backdrop of twentieth-century design debates between modernists and traditionalists. The chair is the object in which the novel's main tensions, which relate to notions of comfort, history, and authority, are embedded. In the fourth chapter I maintain that the central concerns of Diane Schoemperlen's fiction are couched in her representations of domestic material culture. Interpersonal relationships are consistently represented in her fiction as mediated through domestic objects and spaces. Her characters' struggles over issues of control, and the ambivalence characteristically associated with these struggles, often materialize in their manipulations of their domestic environments. Such manipulations make explicit the process of self-fashioning via material culture which every individual engages in on a daily basis, albeit at the level of the tacit.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lecker, Robert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451k283.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vm69g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Material culture in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Quednau, Marion, 1952-</dc:subject><dc:subject>Schoemperlen, Diane</dc:subject><dc:subject>Barfoot, Joan</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vd20n"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anatomy of a failed democratic transition : the case of Nigeria, 1985-1993</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Emelifeonwu, David C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study is about the vicissitudes of democratisation in the context of neo-patrimonialism. It examines the aborted transition to democracy in Nigeria (1985--1993) by critically adopting the arguments proffered in the 'new institutionalism' literature. The key insight of the 'new institutionalism' approaches is that they neither privilege structures nor human agency. Instead they seek to explicate how pre-existing institutions and rules shape the choices of political actors. To this end, the 'new institutionalism' approaches lend themselves to a more comprehensive understanding of the processes of regime change. The annulment of 1993, and the country's continuous failure to establish a viable democratic regime, can be attributed to the underlying political process in Nigeria, which puts an emphasis on capturing power for personal and sectional gains. Given this situation, political competition becomes a struggle of the survival of the fittest between those with power and those without. Thus, this study contends that the constitutive rules of a polity, while not determining the outcome of regime transitions, shapes actors' behavior towards specific goals and interests. The breakdown of the Babangida-initiated transition programme is an interesting example of this dynamic. The challenge to regime transitions therefore is understanding how inherited rules and institutions structure the political actors' choices. To meet this challenge an integrative approach is required for the study of regime transitions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kunz, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21th13p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd20n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Democracy -- Nigeria</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nigeria -- Politics and government -- 1984-1993</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1z40kv595"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Local isotype switching of IgE within allergic nasal mucosa in response to allergen exposure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cameron, Elizabeth Anne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Patients with allergic rhinitis exhibit an exaggerated nasal response to allergen, in large part a consequence of IgE-mediated inflammatory cell activation. IgE within the tissue is considered to derive from IgE-bound inflammatory and/or IgE+ plasma cells. Resting B lymphocytes and cells expressing IL-4 and IL-13, cytokines that induce B cells to undergo epsilon germline transcription and isotype switching to IgE, are present within allergic nasal mucosa. As such, it has been hypothesized here that local isotype switching to IgE may occur at this site. Probes to detect the epsilon germline transcript (Iepsilon RNA), a pre-requisite for isotype switch recombination, the mature epsilon transcript (Cepsilon RNA) and IL-4 and IL-13 mRNA were employed. Since steroids reduce the number of cells expressing these cytokines, the effect of pre-treating patients with fluticasone propionate (FP) was also investigated. Nasal biopsies were obtained from seasonal allergic rhinitis patients before and following in vivo allergen challenge or natural exposure during the pollen season. To confirm local RNA synthesis, nasal tissue was challenged with allergen ex vivo. Immunocytochemistry (ICC) confirmed the presence of B cells within the nasal tissue. In situ hybidization (ISH) demonstrated increases in the number of Cepsilon and IL-4 mRNA and the appearance of Iepsilon RNA+ cells in nasal tissue from placebo-treated patients following in vivo allergen exposure, but not those pre-treated with FP. Ex vivo allergen challenge also resulted in higher numbers of Cepsilon, Iepsilon, IL-4 and IL-13 RNA+ cells in allergen-stimulated compared to unstimulated tissue. With simultaneous ICC/ISH, CD20+/Cepsilon+ (37%) and CD20+/Iepsilon+ (32%) were observed, while the presence of mature epsilon mRNA (Cepsilon+/Iepsilon-) was confirmed using double ISH. Furthermore, IL-4 was associated primarily with T cells (≅70%) and mast cells (≅32%), while these cell types also produced IL-13 (≅44%, ≅18%). It is demonstrated here that the epsilon germline transcript, mature epsilon mRNA and IL-4 and IL-13 mRNA are synthesized locally within allergic nasal mucosa and that steroids inhibit their production. These results indicate that events within the nasal mucosa itself play a primary role in regulating the allergic response at this site and emphasize the importance of focusing on this local regulation when designing future diagnostic and therapeutic strategies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hamid, Qutayba</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j7238.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kv595</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nj856"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Poésie et discours poétique au Canada français (1889-1909)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Campeau, Sylvain, 1960-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1892, in one of his characteristic attacks, Arthur Buies denounced the "deplorable" style of certain young French-Canadian writers of the day. The "jeunes barbares", as he called them, published in small magazines such as Le Recueil litteraire and L'Echo des jeunes, and were strongly influenced by French fin-de-siecle writing (the decadent and Symbolist schools in particular). The creation of the Ecole litteraire de Montreal in 1895 can be seen as a continuation of these varied literary endeavours. Quite aware of the criticisms leveled at young writers by Buies and others, the members of the Ecole viewed their association as both a literary circle and a training ground. The Bulletin du parler francais au Canada , founded in 1902, approached the issue of the poor quality of spoken and written French in French Canada from a more philological angle. It was in the Bulletin... that Camille Roy published his articles on French-Canadian literary history and his famous conference on the nationalisation of French-Canadian literature (in 1904--1905). This text was to have an influence so far-reaching that the Ecole litteraire de Montreal, in its second incarnation, espoused---albeit with some reticence---certain of the "pre-regionalist" values it promoted. The texts published in the Ecole's magazine, Le Terroir (1909), clearly indicate this. This thesis analyses the diverse modernist and pre-regionalist discourses present from 1889 to 1909, taking into particular account the variations in their antagonism (which manifested itself in a number of short-lived quarrels), with a view to providing a more complete and nuanced picture of the period than previous studies have done; it explores, in the process, the less well-known antecedents to the period which was to follow, a period during which the opposition between the regionalists and the "exotiques" came to a head.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Everett, Jane</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn432.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj856</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ecole littéraire de Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>French-Canadian literature -- 19th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>French-Canadian literature -- Québec (Province) -- 20th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>French-Canadian literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>French-Canadian literature -- Québec (Province) -- 19th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dr33b"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nonlinear critical layer development of forced wave packets in geophysical shear flows</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Campbell, Lucy J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We investigate the nonlinear development of a forced wave packet in the presence of a critical layer in a shear flow. Two different geophysical flows are considered: vertically propagating internal gravity wave packets in a stratified shear flow and Rossby wave packets propagating toward the equator in a zonal flow. Most previous analyses of these phenomena have dealt with spatially periodic, monochromatic waves. These studies observed that, in the initial linear stages, the disturbance is absorbed at the critical layer, but subsequently, the linear theory breaks down and nonlinear phenomena such as wave breaking and reflection result. For a more realistic representation of wave activities in the atmosphere, we employ a forcing in the form of a spatially localized wave packet, rather than a monochromatic wave. We solve the nonlinear equations numerically using a pseudo-spectral Fourier approximation and a high order compact finite difference scheme. It is found that the spatial localization delays the onset of the nonlinear breakdown in the critical layer, the absorption of the disturbance continues for large time and there is an outward flux of momentum in the zonal or horizontal direction. For the Rossby wave packet problem, we also derive an approximate analytical solution for the special case of long waves. According to this solution, the total length of the packet increases with time, as seen in the numerical simulations. In the gravity wave packet problem, the horizontal extent of the packet increases with time, but there appears to be a different mechanism for this: the part of the disturbance that spreads out is centered at the zero wave number. The region over which the packet interacts with the mean flow increases in length with time. We observe also that the prolonged absorption of the disturbance stabilizes the solution to the extent that it is always convectively stable; the local Richardson number remains positive well into the nonlinear regime. In this sense, our results differ from those in the case of monochromatic forcing in which significant regions with negative Richardson number appear.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maslowe, Sherwin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x42j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr33b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geophysics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqz20sv485"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The establishment of the American Presbyterian Mission in Egypt, 1854-1940 : an overview</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Burke, Jeffrey Charles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation examines the educational contributions of the American Mission in Egypt using previously untapped archival documents from the Presbyterian Historical Society in Philadelphia. The principal focus of this research is on the establishment of American Mission schools in Egypt. The successes and failures of this missionary movement's work with Copts and Muslims are examined within the context of demographic data and political history. The study also discusses Egyptian anti-missionary sentiments directed against the American Mission in the 1920s and 30s, and constitutes an exploration of Christian-Muslim relations in nineteenth- and early twentieth-century Egypt.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Turgay, Uner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d158b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sv485</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>United Presbyterian Church of North America -- Missions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Missions -- Egypt</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education -- Egypt -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bn45m"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A simple coupled atmosphere-ocean-sea ice-land surface-ice sheet model for climate and paleoclimate studies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Zhaomin, 1963-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We develop a new coupled atmosphere-ocean-sea ice-land surface-ice sheet model for long-term climate change studies. This five-component model incorporates the seasonal cycle, and the three major ocean basins, the Antarctic Circumpolar Current region and the major continents are resolved. The model variables are sectorially averaged across the different ocean basins and continents. The above coupled model (less the ice sheet component) is first used to simulate the major features of the present day climate. In a global warming (cooling) experiment, the thermohaline circulation (THC) in the North Atlantic Ocean is weakened (intensified) due to the increased (reduced) moisture transport to, and warmer (cooler) sea surface temperatures at northern high latitudes. Secondly, the above four-component model is employed to investigate the initiation of glaciation, which is accomplished by reducing the solar radiation and increasing the planetary emissivity only in high northern latitudes. When land ice is growing, the THC in the North Atlantic Ocean is intensified, resulting in a warm subpolar North Atlantic Ocean. The intensified THC maintains a large land-ocean thermal contrast at high latitudes, which leads to enhanced land ice accumulation. We conclude that increased fresh water or massive iceberg discharge from land is responsible for a weak or collapsed THC. Lastly, a dynamic ice sheet model is coupled to the above four-component model. Sensitivity experiments show that a smaller lateral (east-west) ice discharge rate maintains a larger ice volume and extent in our model. Also, a reduced atmospheric CO2 concentration, which is parameterized as an increased planetary emissivity, may lead to the expansion of the ice sheets and hence a larger ice volume and extent. A simple iceberg calving scheme is next introduced to investigate ice sheet-THC interactions on the millennial timescale. We find that the longer the duration of iceberg calving, the longer the time that must elapse before the next calving event can occur. Also, it is shown that the strength of the THC in the North Atlantic Ocean is very sensitive to the discharge rate of the ice sheets. This makes the simulation of the interactions between ice sheets and the THC extremely challenging.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mysak, Lawrence A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pf62d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn45m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical Oceanography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000185h"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A qualitative investigation into adolescents with learning disabilities : their perceptions and uses of social support</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wilkie, Tara V.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This qualitative descriptive inquiry investigates the perceptions and uses of social support of a selected group of adolescents who attended an English school for students with learning disabilities in Montreal, Quebec. I draw on Vygotskian socio-cultural theory as a framework for understanding how the participants access and use people for social support and how these adolescents provide others with social support. I use three Vygotskian concepts, the zone of proximal development, self-regulation and internalization to examine the differences between those who use support well and those who do not. Data collected and analyzed includes audio taped interviews with focus groups, students, parents, teachers and professional staff, school based and classroom based participant observations. A major finding to emerge is that adolescents in this inquiry use or do not use support well based on what they have internalized through previous experiences and social interactions in their home contexts. The students who use support well appear to have had positive demonstrations of social support within their zones of proximal development, thus enabling them to internalize and self regulate how to access and use social support in other contexts. The students who do not use support well do not appear to have experienced positive demonstrations of social support within their zones of proximal development. This latter group experience difficulties in accessing, accepting and using social support both in home and school contexts. However, these adolescents can learn to self regulate, access and use social support when adults, their peers or significant others listen and validate their concerns and move into their zones of proximal development. Implications for teachers include; (a) Creating open and trusting environments in which students feel comfortable in risk-taking and self-disclosure; and (b) Implementing mentoring programs in which a collaborative environment is created and</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lavers, R.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Maguire, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f521s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000185h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>Learning disabled teenagers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75r945c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Trophic position in aquatic food webs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vander Zanden, M. Jake</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines broad-scale patterns in the food web structure of lake ecosystems. The unifying framework for this analysis is the concept of trophic position, which represents the energy-weighted trophic path length leading to a consumer or population. Trophic position was estimated for over 550 populations of fish (16 species) using quantitative dietary data. A method to estimate trophic position of aquatic consumers using stable isotope ratios was developed; this involved correcting for within and among-lake variation in delta15N of primary consumers (organisms used to represent the base of the food web). We report an overall correspondence between dietary and isotopic estimates of trophic position; for each species, trophic position generally ranged the equivalent of one trophic level unit among-populations. The concept of discrete trophic levels provided only a qualitative description of energy flow pathways in aquatic food webs. Among-population variation was much greater than within-population variation in trophic position of lake trout. Long-standing hypotheses about the determinants of food chain length were examined; food chain length was most closely correlated with species richness and lake area. The trophic position approach was used to examine two separate environmental problems relevant to lakes: the bioaccumulation of persistent contaminants in food chains and the impacts of invasive species. Trophic position was the major determinant of PCB levels in lake trout; these relationships were used to characterize biomagnification factors (BMFs) for this and a number of other contaminants. Furthermore, the introduction of smelt into lakes was linked to increased levels of PCB and Hg contamination in lake trout. Stable isotopes were used to quantify the impacts of smallmouth bass and rock bass invasions on food webs leading to lake trout. Lake trout from invaded lakes exhibited reduced consumption on littoral prey fish; a food web shift that is likely to have detrimental impacts on native lake trout populations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rasmussen, Joseph B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gf70w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r945c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fish communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lake ecology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bioaccumulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Food chains (Ecology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Animal introduction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x569b"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aerobic glycolysis in response to visual stimulation studied by positron emission tomography (PET) : preliminary application to mitochondrial disorders</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vafaee, Manouchehr S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Adenosine triphosphate (ATP) is the main source of energy supply for tissue. It is provided either by conversion of glycogen to lactate (anaerobic glycolysis) or by oxidation of glucose (aerobic glycolysis) which is a more efficient way of energy production. The process of aerobic glycolysis, also called oxidative phosphorylation, utilises molecular oxygen (O2) as the oxidant and occurs in mitochondria. Therefore, normal function of mitochondria and normal supply off O2 is vital for cellular work. We have used positron emission tomography (PET) and investigated the issue of oxygen consumption in the visual cortex following stimulation with a colorful visual paradigm. The stimulus was capable of activating visual neurons involved in color processing. We have further investigated the behavior of the oxygen consumption and blood flow in the visual cortex with respect to the rate of stimulation using the same visual stimulus designed in the previous study. We also studied a few available patients who suffered from mitochondrial diseases and compared the results with those obtained from the normals with the aim of shedding some light on the pathophysiology of these disorders.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Evans, A. C.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Giedde, Albert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g448m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x569b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn107087x"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of dystroglycan in muscular dystrophy and synaptogenesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Montanaro, Federica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>alpha- and beta-dystroglycan (DG) were first identified as members of an oligomeric, transmembrane complex expressed in muscle and linking laminin (LN) in the extracellular matrix (ECM) to dystrophin in the submembraneous cytoskeleton. This dystrophin-associated glycoprotein complex (DGC) has been proposed to perform a structural role in skeletal muscle, its loss leading to loss of membrane integrity, muscle fiber degeneration and muscular dystrophy. alpha- and beta-DG appear to form the core of the DGC since alpha-DG is a high affinity LN receptor while beta-DG is a transmembrane protein that anchors alpha-DG to the membrane and interacts with dystrophin intracellularly. In order to determine the involvement of DG in skeletal muscle homeostasis and in LN assembly, we generated mouse muscle cell lines deficient in DG expression. Extensive characterization of these cells revealed that DG is essential for LN assembly on the surface of mature myotubes but that it is not involved in the maintenance of membrane integrity in culture. However, DG-deficient cells show increased apoptotic cell death during and after the period of myoblast differentiation into myotubes, indicating that DG is important for muscle cell survival. The ECM molecule agrin has been implicated in the induction of acetylcholine receptor (AChR) aggregation at the neuromuscular junction (NMJ). The C-terminus of agrin shares significant homology with the region of LN that interacts with alpha-DG; we therefore reasoned that alpha-DG could be an agrin receptor. Ligand overlay assays revealed that alpha-DG binds agrin with high affinity and antibody perturbation experiments indicated that alpha-DG is involved in agrin-induced aggregation of AChRs. The role of alpha-DG in AChR aggregation was further studied using the DG deficient muscle cell lines. We found that alpha-DG is involved in the later stages of agrin-induced AChR aggregation. We further localized DG and two of its intracellular ligands, dystrophin and its autosomal homologue utrophin, to a synaptic layer in the retina suggesting a role for DG in central nervous system synapses. DG, utrophin and LN are also co-expressed around blood vessels indicating a possible function in blood-brain barrier homeostasis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carbonetto, Salvatore</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z069.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107087x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dystrophin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glycoproteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muscular dystrophy -- Genetic aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb397987z"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of cysteine proteinases in IGF-1R turnover, invasion and metastasis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Navab, Roya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Clinical cancer treatment has focused on the use of cytotoxic agents and/or radiation therapy that target both tumor and normal cells. Consequently, current cancer treatments with chemotherapeutic agents are subject to limitations associated with high toxicity and resistance. The cysteine proteinases cathepsin B and L have been linked to the invasive steps during the metastatic process and could therefore provide new targets for drug development. The present work describes our results with a murine Lewis lung carcinoma model which consists of two cell lines, H-59 and M-27, with different patterns of metastasis in vivo. Using this model, we found that the cysteine proteinase inhibitor, E-64, significantly inhibited the invasive/metastatic properties of the liver colonising cell line, H-59 both in vitro and in vivo. Because IGF-1R was identified as a critical mediator of matrix metalloproteinase-2 (MMP-2) synthesis, invasion and metastasis in H-59 cells, the possibility that the cysteine proteinases interfered with receptor for type 1 insulin-like growth factor (IGF-1R) turnover thereby reducing invasion was subsequently investigated. To elucidate more specifically the role of cysteine proteinases in the process of liver metastasis, cathepsin L expression was inhibited in the H-59 cells by transfection with a plasmid vector expressing a 300 by cathepsin L cDNA fragment in the antisense orientation. To further investigate the link between IGF-1R expression levels and invasion in these cells, MMP-2 production and activity were investigated. In cathepsin L antisense transfected H-59 cells reduced MMP-2 levels and activity as compared to controls were observed. Together our results suggest that the cysteine proteinases, cathepsin L in particular may regulate the metastatic potential through a role in IGF-1R turnover. The present results provide evidence that metastatic carcinomas which utilize cysteine proteinases for invasion could potentially be responsive to antimetastatic treatment with cysteine proteinase inhibitors. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brodt, Pnina</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp04q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397987z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mn981"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>spa</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Hispanic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>El pasado entre historias en Terra nostra, de Carlos Fuentes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Montano Rodríguez, Rafael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines Carlos Fuentes' reflection on the interpretation of the past as well as on its fictional representation. For this purpose we study Terra nostra (1975), the Mexican writer's most ambitious novel, because it breaks with the main concepts of historiography and the historical novel. With a circular gallery of text-mirrors structure, the novel is meant to represent the simultaneous aspects of reality, and to present to the reader different interpretations of the past. Fashioned from the concept of intertextuality, the terms "intertemporality" and "interdiscursivity" are used to define the notions of time and the discursive composition of history, integrated in the novel. With the term intertemporality, we examine how Fuentes deconstructs the chronological notion of time, creating instead a simultaneous and dialectical relation between past, present, and future. With the term of interdiscursivity, we see how Fuentes, in his quest to examine Spain's history, integrates in Terra nostra the thought from Giambattista Vico, Erasmus, Americo Castro, and Michel Foucault, as well as important literary figures (James Joyce, Julio Cortazar, Miguel de Cervantes, and Jorge L. Borges). The integration of these thinkers and writers ables the reader to create an interdiscursive notion of history that establishes a dynamic relation between the different discourses on history. From an image used by Borges in "Las ruinas Circulates", an epistemological structure quite different from the one suggested by the three parts of the novel emerges, allowing the reader to read a more open work. Aura (1962) is also studied, because in many ways, it is a prelude to Terra nostra, and because it is an early reflection on the relation between history and fiction. Finally, using the concepts of the double and the other, we also study Una familia lejana, which examines the relation between France and Mexico. We conclude on some paradoxes brought up by those novels, especially Terra</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boruchoff, David A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r354.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mn981</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fuentes, Carlos. Terra nostra</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237ht469"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Acylation stimulating protein (ASP) structure &amp; function studies : in vitro and in vivo in mouse models</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Murray, Ian V. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Acylation stimulating protein (ASP or C3a desArg) is a complement derived product produced by adipocytes and is able to alter their metabolism, stimulating both triglyceride synthesis and glucose transport. This stimulatory activity has been shown to be due to ASP as both plasma derived protein and recombinant protein stimulate glucose transport and triglyceride synthesis. Furthermore, we demonstrated that ASP is functionally distinct from C3a. A two site model for ligand interaction with the receptor is proposed with the carboxy-terminal involved in receptor binding and the disulphide core in stimulating triglyceride synthesis. Functionality of ASP in vivo supported the hypothesis that ASP is involved in plasma triglyceride and glucose clearance postprandially after a fat load. The following data were obtained: (1) Administration of ASP and ASP functional knockouts displayed increased and delayed triglyceride clearance respectively. (2) Administered ASP decreased plasma glucose levels, which was independent from its effects on plasma triglycerides. (3) In ASP functional knockout mice gender differences of greater postprandial lipemia in males and more pronounced reductions of adipose tissue in females were observed. In conclusion the function of ASP was determined as well as structural regions involved. Furthermore, the in vivo physiology of ASP has been determined, with an effect on postprandial metabolism, regulation of adiposity and gender dependent penetrance of the ASP functional knockout phenotype.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sniderman, D. A. D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hb41p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237ht469</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>