<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A44558g00w"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The importance of social support for women on their road to recovery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Duncan, Valerie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The use of alcohol and drugs by women has become a major health issue; though men use and abuse alcohol and drugs at a higher rate than women, this gap is closing and at an alarming rate. In this study, the hypothesis is that women who have positive social support relationships have a higher probability to sustain and maintain their sobriety over time. Information was obtained through qualitative exploration N = (10) as these women recounted their experiences. The objective is to explore the similar factors that assisted these women throughout their recovery process. The findings show that women come to recognize their need for recovery, as their sense of self develops and evolves over time: through positive attachments with others, rediscovery of self and identifying positive feelings. The issue of women and recovery is a relevant factor for social work practitioners as clients and social workers need to function together as partners throughout the problem solving process.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John, Lindsay</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p2129.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558g00w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Recovering addicts -- Social networks -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- Substance use -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Recovering alcoholics -- Social networks -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r495c"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Walter Pichler : the modern Prometheus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nasifoglu, Yelda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The ritualistic aspect of Walter Pichler's work greatly problematizes the traditional view of the art object as the locus of aesthetic contemplation. Yet how are we to approach such art in our secularized world? For it to maintain its meaningfulness, does not ritual require a shared symbolic system? Indirectly guided by Pichler's work, this thesis is an exploration of the contemporary status of the work of art. An investigation into the myth of Prometheus reveals that art and ritual share the same origin. Further inquiries into early Greek sculpture, as well as the concepts of techne and mimesis, expand this origin into the relationship between the art object and the viewer, shifting the customary focus away from the resemblance between the model and the copy. In this space of looking , art no longer presents itself as an aestheticized object---presence and absence, the visible and the invisible, recognition and anamnesis come into play as possible ways of participation in the work of art.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m8500.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r495c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pichler, Walter, 1936-</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sculpture, Austrian -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ritual in art</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rj956"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>History and tradition in modern Japan : translation and commentary upon the texts of Sei'ichi Shirai</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Terakawa, Toru</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the concepts of history and tradition in modern Japan, with an emphasis on the writings of Sei'ichi Shirai (1905--1983). Although Shirai has been considered as one of the most important architects of 20th century Japan, he has also been treated as an obscure figure, no doubt partly because of the enigmatic quality of his writings. A major element that contributed to his obscure status and set him apart from his contemporaries was his understanding of history and tradition. The introductory essay examines the concept of tradition prevalent around Shirai's time: how it was constructed by an a posteriori writing of history and in what ways this is complicated by Shirai's writings. The second portion of the thesis is an annotated translation of two of Shirai's texts demonstrating his attempts to disclose the a priori principles inherent in the unfolding of tradition through history.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4306547.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj956</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Shirai, Seiichi, 1905-</dc:subject><dc:subject>Architecture -- Japan -- 20th century -- Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw0892c67z"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dramatic space : Jerzy Grotowski and the recovery of the ritual function of theatre</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Georges, Pierre Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores temporal forms of architectural meaning through the investigation of the dramatic space of "ritual theatre." In particular, it analyzes the thought and several theatrical productions of the twentieth century Polish theatre director, Jerzy Grotowski: Grotowski is of particular interest because he designed a "total dramatic space" that incorporated both the actors and the spectators (although without necessarily integrating them) for each of his dramatic works. In each case, the spatial relationships created by the theatrical architecture were indissolubly connected to the meaning of the drama itself. In this way, space was used as a kind of third protagonist that, along with the actors and spectators, participates in the theatrical ritual.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397999r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c67z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Teatr Laboratorium (Wrocław, Poland)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grotowski, Jerzy, 1933- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Experimental theater -- Poland</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4t64gq13s"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les veritables enjeux de l'appropriation artistique au regard du droit d'auteur</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Barsalou, Geneviève</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Artistic appropriation constitutes a technique that has been widely used by artists for centuries. It seems to have transcended most artistic movements. Appropriation consists of reproducing a pre-existing work, or of being inspired by it, in order to create a new and distinct work of art. Appropriation poses several problems for copyright law because it challenges the basic principle of copyright which provides that a substantial reproduction of a work without the authorisation of the copyright owner amounts to an infringement. Unlike the United States where it was held that an appropriationist work infringed the copyright of a photographer, the Canadian jurisprudence has not decided the matter. While there has been no formal stand, it seems that artistic appropriation is prohibited by copyright law in Canada. The author argues that this form of censorship is mainly due to the current state of the law which is not adapted to visual arts. Therefore, important changes must occur. Considering their important place in the visual art's world, appropriationist works deserve to be protected by copyright law.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lametti, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032480m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gq13s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw3763880r"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cultural diversity in international standards for criminal sentences</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Braun, Felix, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the debate about cultural relativism of human rights in the concrete context of the prohibition of torture, inhuman and degrading treatment as applied to criminal sentences. A study of the jurisprudence concerning the prohibition reveals that traditional legal methodology is unable to decide this debate unequivocally. It is argued that both an extreme uniformity in its interpretation as well as a complete lack of common standards are indefensible in the contemporary system of international law. Therefore, any modern interpretation of the prohibition has to strike a balance between these two extremes. Yet, this balance can not be established unilaterally once and for all. It has to be the result of an ongoing universal debate within the preexisting legal framework. Thus, the compromise that is found will shift over time to reflect the evolving consensus of the international community.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gaudreault-DesBiens, Jean-Francois</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Provost, Rene</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fz500.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763880r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Multiculturalism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sentences (Criminal procedure)</dc:subject><dc:subject>International law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w661r"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les droits sur les objets de communication et environnements electroniques</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Français , Jean-Arpad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Digital technology has generated a whole new dynamic of convergence of the techniques and the media. In this respect, broadcasting on the Internet is a perfect example. Through the latter rises the question of the ability of the Canadian and French intellectual property systems to embrace the current technological changes. More fundamentally, a comparative analysis of the two legal regimes surrounding broadcasting allows one to assess the cybernetic autonomy of the systems studied. It is argued that any adaptation of the law should be implemented with a general approach and that the belief in the adaptability of the law should be favoured However, when such adaptability shows signs of difficulty, the resolution of problems related to computer networks should be handled less from a technological standpoint with regards to novelty than a structural one with regards to systemic logic.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gendreau, Y.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns739.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w661r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mass Communications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajd472z279"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'impasse de la position canadienne face a la qualification juridique de l'œuvre multimedia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Delisle, Marie-Louise</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The multimedia industry represents a segment of the economy that has recently witnessed a tremendous growth rate. The rapid development of such an industry results in the need to develop adequate legal protection for multimedia works. Although doubt no longer exists as to the copyright protection afforded to multimedia works, their legal qualification remains controversial. The legal qualification of a work will influence the ownership of patrimonial and moral rights in regards to that work. The author surveys the main possible qualifications for multimedia works. Drawing on legislation and jurisprudence from the United States, France and Europe, the author suggests amendments to the Canadian Copyright Act. These amendments would ensure not only the protection of the audiovisual elements generated by their underlying computer programs, but would, by the same token, cover multimedia works.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gendreau, Ysolde</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qn85q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z279</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mass Communications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vd269"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Survey and analysis of intelligent mobile agents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Basha, Nagi Nabil</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The notion of mobile agent, a software component that can move autonomously between the different nodes of a network is gaining wide popularity in business and in academia. The term mobile agent was first introduced in 1994. Since then, lots of research has been carried out in various aspects of the newly introduced paradigm. It might even be surprising to know that a recent census reports the existence of more than 70 mobile agent systems. Therefore, there is a need to gather and analyze what has been done so far in this new area. This survey reviews the field of mobile agents by summarizing the key concepts and giving an overview of the most important implementations. Design and implementation issues of mobile agents are analyzed in general. Some of the most important mobile agent systems are presented and discussed. Java's support for mobile agent development is thoroughly examined. In addition, the role of the Common Object Request Broker Architecture (CORBA) as a broker between mobile agents and their environment is also analyzed. Most importantly, a survey of the major security concerns is provided followed by an analysis of the currently available techniques to address these concerns. Last but not least, a detailed analysis of the Foundation for Intelligent Physical Agents (FIPA) standards for interoperability between heterogeneous agents and their hosts is included. This survey will help in understanding the potentials of mobile agents and why they have not caught on. Once progress is made in the areas of security, programming language support for specific mobile agent requirements, and standards for coordination between heterogeneous agents, it is expected that the mobile agent paradigm will dramatically revolutionize the way the Internet is being used now.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Newborn, Monty</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f119.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd269</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Artificial Intelligence</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544br26r"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Light verbs and the flexible use of words as noun and verb in early language learning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Barner, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present thesis investigated two questions: (1) is there a correspondence between lexico-semantic categories like object and syntactic categories like noun in acquisition, and (2) can the late emergence of action nouns be explained by their use in longer, "complex predicate" constructions (CP), such as Have a hug? Paper 1 examined the use of words that can appear as noun or verb, in the speech of nine English-speaking children (aged 1;3--2;6) and their caregivers. Children showed a strong polarization in their productions, using a majority of object words consistently as nouns and non-object words consistently as verbs. However, children also showed some flexibility, and used fewer non-object words as nouns than object words as verbs. Paper 2 investigated words used by caregivers in CPs to those that were not in the speech of nine English-speaking children (aged 1;3 to 4;6). On average, words used in CPs by caregivers emerged later in child speech that non-CP words. Also, at early stages children had not mastered the use of verbs required for CPs. It was concluded that words used in CPs (i.e. action nouns), may emerge late due to their use in these expressions, and not due to a problem understanding the semantics of action words.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Oshima-Takane, Yuriko</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Crago, Martha</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r496n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544br26r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education, Language and Literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language, Linguistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education, Educational Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j7327"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gonadotrophin-releasing hormone analogue treatment of idiopathic central precocious puberty presenting in girls after age five years : a multi-centre follow-up to final adult height</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Barnes, Robert, 1967-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Idiopathic central precocious puberty may compromise adult height. Gonadotrophin-releasing hormone analogues (GnRHa) suppress puberty and increase final height prediction, but their influence on final height is unclear, especially in girls with pubertal onset just below eight years of age, the traditional limit of normal. At seven children's hospitals, we identified 53 treated and 24 untreated patients (24 and 7 to final height, respectively) whose pubertal onset was between ages 5--8 years. At baseline, bone age advancement and predicted adult height were similar in the two groups. In both groups, the predicted adult height slightly overestimated the final height. What role, if any, GnRHa therapy played in preventing a shorter adult height is uncertain in these borderline cases. The substantial intra- and inter-observer variability in bone age readings compromised the utility of the height prediction method. The methodological challenges inherent to this study are identified and discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Platt, Robert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73px84d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j7327</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Human Development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agm80hx274"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Seed coating with Fusarium oxysporum M12-4A for the biocontrol of Striga hermonthica Del. Benth</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bastiani, Celia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Fusarium oxysporum M12-4A fungus is being evaluated for the biocontrol of Striga hermonthica, a parasitic weed of African cereal crops. The production of M12-4A inoculum was assessed in four Malian villages using local technology and substrates. A delivery system using arabic gum to temporarily glue inoculum powder onto the crop seed was tested. In controlled conditions, coating of sorghum seeds with arabic gum and inoculum powder did not affect seed germination or inoculum viability. However, one week at 40°C significantly decreased the viability of the inoculum by 31%. Fungus growth and chlamydospore germination were also reduced by temperatures of 34 and 36°C. M12-4A was susceptible to the fungicide thiram (ED50 = 38.5mug). Field trials were conducted in Mali to evaluate the large-scale efficacy of the seed coating technology. F. oxysporum M12-4A was detected from some S. hermonthica tissue and soil samples using specific primers and Real Time PCR.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Watson, A. K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx28d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hx274</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Purple witchweed -- Biological control -- Mali</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fusarium oxysporum</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n511s"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Multiple-antenna wireless communications: detection and estimation with smart antennas, and space-time code design considerations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wu, Ren</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The main theme of this thesis is wireless communications using multiple                antennas. The thesis consists of four topics on smart antenna technology, its                applications to direct sequence code division multiple access (DS/CDMA)                communications, and multiple-input multiple-output wireless communications. The first                problem under consideration is the joint estimation of direction-of-arrival (DoA),                propagation delay, and complex channel gain for antenna-array DS/CDMA communications                over frequency selective multipath channels. We propose a subspace based MUSIC-type                estimation algorithm which utilizes the spatial smoothing preprocessing technique.                The proposed algorithm essentially breaks the multipath induced coherency within the                received signals and recovers the full signal subspace spanned by the dominant signal                paths of all users. This allows for the use of MUSIC-type DoA and delay estimators                for individual paths of a particular user. We then describe a new criterion for                detecting the number of signals impinging on a uniform linear array (ULA), which                exploits eigenvector information of the sample array covariance matrix and makes                explicit use of the peak information of the MUSIC spectrum. In the third part we                present an iterative weight matrix approximation (IWMA) algorithm. IWMA computes an                approximation to the optimum weight matrix used by weighted spatial smoothing (WSS)                to completely decorrelate input sources and generate a diagonal source covariance                matrix. A useful observation regarding IWMA is that the generated matrix is suitable                as a basis for subspace-type DoA estimation. In the last part we discuss two                deterministic measures for designing linear processing space-time</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les communications sans fil utilisant des antennes                multiples constituent le thème principal de cette thèse qui traite de quatre sujets                concernant la technologie des antennes intelligentes, son application aux                communications à séquence directe CDMA, et des communications à entrées multiples et                sorties multiples (MIMO). Le premier sujet est celui de l'estimation simultanée des                directions d'arrivée, du retard de propagation et du gain complexe du canal pour des                communications CDMA sur des canaux multi-trajets à fréquences sélectives. Nous                proposons un algorithme d'estimation de type MUSIC à base de sous-espaces, utilisant                un prétraitement par lissage spatial. L'algorithme proposé brise essentiellement la                cohérence induite par les trajets multiples pour recouvrer entièrement le sous-espace                du signal créé par les signaux dominants de tous les utilisateurs. Ceci permet                l'utilisation d'estimateurs MUSIC des directions d'arrivée et du retard pour les                signaux d'un utilisateur donné. Nous décrivons un nouveau critère pour détecter le                nombre de signaux captés sur un réseau d'antennes uniforme et linéaire qui exploite                le vecteur propre de la matrice de covariance des échantillons et qui utilise                l'information des pics de spectre de MUSIC. Troisièmement, nous présentons un                algorithme itératif d'approximation de la matrice des poids (IWMA) qui calcule une                approximation de la matrice des poids optimale utilisée pour le lissage spatial                (WSS), afin de complètement décorréler les sources d'entrées. Avec IWMA la matrice                qui est générée peut être utilisée comme base de l'estimation de type sous-espace des                directions d'arrivée. Nous discutons finalem</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ioannis Psaromiligkos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp91q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n511s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zg321"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamics of thin-walled aerospace structures for fixture design in multi-axis milling</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Meshreki, Mouhab</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le fraisage des structures aérospatiales à parois minces                est un processus critique dû à la flexibilité élevée de la pièce. Les modèles                disponibles pour la prévision de l'effet du système de fixation sur la réponse                dynamique de la pièce sont basés sur des méthodes numériques très lentes et                n'arrivent pas à représenter les cas pratiques du fraisage des structures à parois                minces. Basé sur une analyse des composants structurels typiques produits dans                l'industrie aérospatiale, un élément généralisé de base avec la forme d'une poche                asymétrique, a été identifié pour représenter la réponse dynamique de ces composants.                En conséquence, deux modèles dynamiques efficaces ont été développés pour prévoir la                réponse dynamique des structures aérospatiales types à parois minces. Ces modèles ont                été formulés en utilisant les méthodes de Rayleigh et Rayleigh-Ritz. Dans le premier                modèle, les réponses dynamiques des structures de poches multiples à parois minces                sont représentées par des plaques avec des ressorts de torsion et de translation. Une                méthodologie a été proposée et mise en application pour calibrer la rigidité des                ressorts en utilisant les algorithmes génétiques. Dans le deuxième modèle, la réponse                dynamique d'une poche en 3D est représentée par une plaque équivalente de                multi-travées en 2D. À travers une étude approfondie du fraisage des structures à                parois minces, une nouvelle formulation a été développée pour représenter le                changement continu de l'épaisseur de la pièce durant l'usinage. Deux formulations,                basées sur des contraintes holonomes et des ressorts avec des rigidités finies, ont                été$</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Milling of thin-walled aerospace structures is a critical process due to                the high flexibility of the workpiece. Available models for the prediction of the                effect of the fixture on the dynamic response of the workpiece are computationally                demanding and fail to represent practical cases for milling of thin-walled                structures. Based on the analysis of typical structural components encountered in the                aerospace industry, a generalized unit-element, with the shape of an asymmetric                pocket, was identified to represent the dynamic response of these components.                Accordingly, two computationally efficient dynamic models were developed to predict                the dynamic response of typical thin-walled aerospace structures. These models were                formulated using Rayleigh's energy and the Rayleigh-Ritz methods. In the first model,                the dynamics of multi-pocket thin-walled structures is represented by a plate with                torsional and translational springs. A methodology was proposed and implemented for                an off-line calibration of the stiffness of the springs using Genetic Algorithms. In                the second model, the dynamics of a 3D pocket is represented by an equivalent 2D                multi-span plate. Through a careful examination of the milling of thin-walled                structures, a new formulation was developed to represent the continuous change of                thickness of the workpiece due to the material removal action. Two formulations,                based on holonomic constraints and springs with finite stiffness, were also developed                and implemented to take into account the effect of perfectly rigid and deformable                fixture supports. All the developed models and formulations were validated                numerically and experimentally for different workpiece geometries and</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mahmoud Helmi Attia</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jozsef Kovecses</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j2935.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg321</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5t34sm257"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role and regulation of the Wnt/beta-catenin pathway at the time of embryo implantation in the mouse</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jonnaert, Maud</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the crucial events during mammalian embryogenesis is the process                of implantation. Implantation enables the embryo to invade the uterine endometrium                and to gain access to the maternal circulation. The attachment reaction requires a                highly coordinated dialogue between the implanting blastocyst and the receptive                uterus, known as the embryo-uterine cross-talk. Since the blastocyst expresses                multiple Wnt genes, in this study, we have characterized the role and regulation of                the Wnt/-catenin pathway in embryo-uterine communication. Using a transgenic mouse                that reports Wnt signalling through the canonical pathway, we have demonstrated that                the Wnt/-catenin pathway was transiently activated in the regions of the uterine                luminal epithelium apposed to the blastocyst at the time of implantation. Activation                of this pathway within the endometrium depended on the presence of the blastocyst and                required the oestrogen surge. We further demonstrated that activation of the                Wnt/-catenin pathway was essential for proper implantation to occur. One possible                mechanism that regulates the responsiveness of the luminal epithelium to Wnt is the                regulation of components of the Wnt pathway. We show that there is dynamic pattern of                expression of the components of the Wnt pathway at the time of implantation.                Furthermore, we demonstrate that LIF signalling is required for the expression of a                subset of these Wnt components in luminal epithelial cells at the time of                implantation. Our results demonstrate that the LIF and Wnt signalling pathway form a                network involved in coordinating the process of implantation As Wnt/ß-catenin                signalling is essential for embryo attachment, we proposed</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le processus de l'implantation embryonnaire joue un rôle                crucial lors du développement des mammifères. L'implantation de l'embryon est un                processus extrêmement complexe au cours duquel l'embryon va d'abord s'apposer, puis                adhérer à l'endomètre pour ensuite y pénétrer. Ultérieurement, il a été démontré que                le blastocyste exprime plusieurs gènes de la famille Wnt. C'est pour cette raison que                dans cette thèse, j'ai décidé caractériser le rôle et la régulation de la voie de                signalisation Wnt/-catenine lors du dialogue materno-fœtal. Nous avons utilisé une                souris transgénique qui permet de contrôler la voie de signalisation Wnt/-catenine.                Ainsi, nous avons démontré que la voie de signalisation Wnt/-catenine était activée                de façon transitoire dans les cellules épithéliales du lumen de l'utérus, dans la                région adjacente au blastocyte au moment de l'implantation. L'activation de cette                voie de signalisation dépend de la présence du blastocyste et de la sécrétion                d'oestradiol. Nous avons également démontré que l'activation de la voie de                signalisation Wnt/-catenine était essentielle au processus d'implantation                embryonnaire. Par la suite, nous avons examiné la possible interaction entre la voie                de signalisation Wnt et LIF. En effet, dans les souris mutantes pour le gène LIF, la                voie de signalisation Wnt/-catenine n'est pas activée. Grâce à la technique de                rt-PCR, nous avons caractérisé le profil d'expression des récepteurs Frizzled, des                co-récepteurs LRP, des antagonistes sFRP et DKK et des gènes Wnt dans les souris                mutantes pour le gène LIF et dans les souris de type sauvage. Nous avons démontré que                les composa</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daniel Dufort</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp11c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm257</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Obstetrics and Gynecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d56zz37n"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the Canadian demand for major fresh fruits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zantoko, Lubaki Kumba</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study has been to specify and estimate a complete demand system for fresh fruits in Canada. The Almost Ideal Demand System (AIDS) is used as the functional form to accomplish the purpose of this study. Fresh fruit was assumed to be weakly separable from all other goods at the first stage of the budgeting process and a conditional demand analysis for fresh fruit was carried out at the second stage of the budgeting process, treating total expenditure as an exogenous variable. At the second stage, expenditure on fresh fruit is allocated to five groups: apples, bananas, grapefruit, oranges, and other fresh fruit. The other fresh fruit group includes: apricots, blueberries, cherries, grapes, lemons, pineapples, and strawberries. The second stage allocation was estimated utilising Zellner's iterative SURE procedure with homogeneity and symmetry conditions imposed on the restricted model. Data used in this study were obtained from Statistics Canada and consist of thirty-four observations from 1960--1993. Results of the likelihood ratio test failed to reject the restricted model at 5% significant level. The R-square and Durbin-Watson test statistics indicated that the fit of the model is satisfactory. This study showed that a system of fresh fruit demand is inelastic to total expenditure, own-price, and cross-price effects. All the expenditure elasticity estimates were positive and significant over the study period, and indicate that apples, grapefruit, and oranges were relatively normal goods, while bananas and other fresh fruit category were relative luxury goods. Apples and oranges, grapefruit and other fruit category, oranges and other fruit category, bananas and other fresh fruit category are substitutes; and apples and other fresh fruit category, oranges and the other fruits category are complements.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n047q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz37n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Demand (Economic theory)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fruit -- Canada -- Marketing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085n11d"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dual reference signal post-silicon reconfigurable clock distribution networks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chattopadhyay, Atanu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates the use of averaging techniques in the                development of clock distribution networks and an on-chip clock skew measurement                circuit. Our flexible clock distribution network can be used in both single clock and                multiple clock integrated circuit applications. The design moves away from clock                trees, using a pair of reference clocks traveling in opposite directions to perform                clock synchronization on a daisy-chained (serial) clock distribution line. By                synchronizing each local clock edge to a position directly in between the forward and                reverse reference clock edges, we demonstrate that sub-10 ps variance in clock                arrival times can be achieved between local clocks. The design provides a scalable                and simple-to-layout solution with multi-point skew compensation useful for large                designs. The system provides the benefits of a closed-loop clock de-skewing solution                by compensating for process, temperature and power supply variations, with the power                savings of an open-loop solution at run-time. Our technique allows routing switches                to be included in the clock path, permitting the post-silicon re-sizing and                re-shaping of clock domains. Localized clock switches or a complete chip-wide switch                mesh can be used to re-route clock signals – a capability that is impossible without                our daisy-chained clock network. We investigate a clock network that emphasizes                flexibility and reconfigurability without sacrificing tolerance to clock skew. We                show that this approach is realizable with transistor-level schematic and extracted                circuit structures in TSMC's 180 nm standard process. We also develop a modeling                infrastructure from which we can create a variety of clock netwo</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse étudie une technique de moyennes pour créer un                système de distribution d'horloge et un circuit pour mesurer le désalignement de                phase d'horloge sur circuit intégré. Notre circuit de distribution d'horloge est                polyvalent et peut être employé pour les systèmes avec une horloge simple ou des                horloges multiples. La conception s'éloigne des circuits de distribution par arbres,                utilisant une paire de signaux de référence voyageant en directions opposées pour                corriger le déphasage de chaque horloge répartie linéairement sur la puce. En                synchronisant chaque front ascendant d'horloge locale directement entre ceux des                signaux de référence, on démontre que le déphasage peut-être réduit en dessous de 10                picosecondes. La conception permet une distribution d'horloges qui est simple à                appliquer et extensible. Cette démarche corrige les variations de processus,                d'alimentation et de température, fournissant la correction du désalignement de phase                systématique de chaque tranche de la distribution d'horloge. Notre technique permet                l'introduction des commutateurs de cheminement pour commuter les trajets d'horloge et                changer la grandeur et forme des domaines d'horloge après la fabrication d'un circuit                intégré. Des commutateurs localisés ou un réseau de commutateur en maille qui couvre                le circuit au complet peuvent être utilisés – deux possibilités qui sont impossibles                sans notre réseau connecté en série. Notre recherche souligne la flexibilité et la                reconfiguration dynamique d'un réseau d'horloge sans sacrifier l'alignement de phase                des signaux d'horloges locaux. Nous prouvons que cette approche est réalisable avec                des conceptions niv</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zeljko Zilic</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v9632.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085n11d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn999849g"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of stance width on the organization of feed-forward postural adjustments in standing humans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee-Shanok, William</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Feed-forward (anticipatory) postural adjustments are known to initiate                voluntary movements and displace the CoM within the base of support (BoS). These                changes in muscular activity of the supporting limbs precede the onset of voluntary                movements. In contrast, postural responses to unexpected surface perturbations occur                at short latency after standing balance is disturbed. These compensatory                (feedback-based) postural responses are characterized by directionally tuned muscle                activity, and directionally limited ground forces. When these feedback responses were                faced with a change in initial stance width, the directional tuning remained                consistent and EMG magnitudes decreased as the BoS widened. In addition, with a wide                stance, the force constraint exhibited a more dispersed pattern. This study sought to                better understand the interaction between varying size of base of support and                feed-forward postural control mechanisms. Postural musculature, ground forces under                both limbs and body kinematics were measured as subjects were asked to stand in a                narrow, natural and wide stance and reach towards 13 distinct targets. Results showed                spatially tuned muscle activity as well as similar EMG magnitudes between stances in                almost all muscles, however, lateral force magnitude and maximum lateral center of                mass displacement increased as stance width widened. Force vectors in each limb were                limited to 2 directions, displaying a similar force constraint strategy to postural                feedback responses. These results suggest that both feedback and feed-forward modes                of postural control may share similar underlying organizational strategies in terms                of the neural control.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les ajustements posturaux anticipateurs sont connus pour                initier les mouvements volontaires et pour déplacer le centre de masse (CM) à                l'intérieur de la base de support (BdS). Ces changements dans l'activité musculaire                des membres porteurs precèdent le déclenchement des mouvements volontaires. Par                contre, les réponses posturales à des perturbations inattendues de la surface se                produisent dans un court laps de temps après que l'équilibre ait été perturbé. Ces                ajustements posturaux compensatoires (à base de 'feed-back' ou rétroaction) sont                caractérisés par des muscles actifs directionnels, et des forces dont les directions                sont limitées. Il a été montré que quand ces ajustements ont à répondre à une                changement d'écart de jambes initial, l'organisation directionnelle spécifique des                muscles reste inchangée et la magnitude des électromyographes (EMG) diminue alors que                la base de support s'agrandit. Par ailleurs, plus l'écart de jambes est significatif,                plus les forces exercées au sol se dispersaient. Cette étude cherchait à mieux                comprendre l'intéraction entre les bases de support variées et le mécanisme proactif                des contrôles posturaux. Les musculatures posturales, les forces de réactions au sol                sous les 2 membres et les cinématiques du corps ont été mesurées alors qu'on                demandait aux sujets de se mettre debout avec des écartements étroits, naturels et                écartés des jambes puis ensuite de pointer vers 13 cibles distinctes. Les résultats                ont montré une organisation directionnelle spécifique des muscles, aussi bien que des                magnitudes d'EMG similaires entre les écartements de jambes pour tous les muscles.                Pourtant, la magnitude d</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul Stapley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c71h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999849g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515q21h"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rethinking metal aesthetics: complexity, authenticity, and audience in Meshuggah's «I» and «Catch Thirtythr33»</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smialek, Eric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La complexité inhabituelle de deux enregistrements récents                du groupe métal extrême Meshuggah a entraîné un profond schisme parmi les fans,                offrant ainsi l'opportunité de reconsidérer certaines conceptions courantes                concernant l'esthétique métal ainsi que de raffiner la compréhension du goût et de la                démographie sociale. Durant vingt-et-une et quarante-sept minutes respectivement, I                (2004) et Catch Thirtythr33 (2005) ont surpris les fans par leur durée inhabituelle                (les deux enregistrements étant chacun considérés par le groupe comme chansons                individuelles), leur écriture complexe et, avec Catch Thirtythr33, l'utilisation                programmée de la batterie. En réponse aux questions des intervieweurs concernant                chacun de ces trois facteurs, les membres de Meshuggah ont mis de l'avant des                affirmations qui ont été bien reçues parmi les fans et les journalistes de rock mais                qui semblent cependant aller à l'encontre de leurs pratiques compositionnelles                habituelles, contredisant même, parfois, certaines de leurs affirmations antérieures.                Cette thèse examine ces contradictions et ce que celles-ci impliquent dans la façon                que varient les concepts d'authenticité et des valeurs esthétiques présents dans les                discours sur le métal, utilisant des concepts issus de la théorie critique, de                l'analyse musicale, ainsi que de la sociologie. En mettant en lumière les diverses                valeurs esthétiques existant dans ces discours, je voudrais ici démontrer qu'il                existe une alternative aux modèles traditionnels des fans du métal se basant sur la                classe sociale et qui rendra compte de la diversité des valeurs esthétiques que l'on                retrouve parmi le public du métal de c</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The unusual complexity of two recent recordings by the extreme metal                band Meshuggah has resulted in a strongly divided reception amongst fans, providing                the opportunity to reconsider some common conceptions of metal aesthetics and to                contribute to subtler ways of understanding taste and social demographics. Spanning                twenty-one and forty-seven minutes respectively, I (2004) and Catch Thirtythr33                (2005) surprised fans with their unusual lengths (both recordings considered by the                band to be single songs), complex song writing, and, with Catch Thirtythr33, the                band's use of programmed drums. In response to interviewers' questions about each of                these factors, the members of Meshuggah have made remarks that have been widely                accepted among fans and rock journalists but that also seem to contradict their                compositional practices and sometimes even their own previous statements. In my                thesis, I investigate this discrepancy and its implications for how the concepts of                authenticity and aesthetic values vary in metal discourses using concepts derived                from critical theory, music theoretical analysis, and sociology. By uncovering                several diverse aesthetic values through these discourses, I argue for an alternative                to traditional class-based models of metal fans, one that will acknowledge the wide                variety of aesthetic values found amongst metal audiences in this study.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David Brackett</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qt84n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q21h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atq57ns75v"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs and the risk of Clostridium Difficile-Associated Disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Suissa, Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Clostridium difficile is a bacterium which causes gastro-intestinal                infection. The association between non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) and                Clostridium difficile-associated disease (CDAD) has not been studied. Several case                reports link diclofenac, an NSAID, with CDAD. In this thesis, we conducted a                case-control study, using data from the United Kingdom's General Practice Research                Database (GPRD), to examine the risk of CDAD associated with NSAID use. We identified                1,360 cases and 13,072 matched controls from 1994 through 2005. Using conditional                logistic regression, we found an increased risk of CDAD associated with diclofenac                [adjusted rate ratio 1.35; 95% confidence interval: 1.10-1.67]. We did not observe an                increased risk of CDAD with use of any other NSAID. In addition, no dose response for                diclofenac was found. In conclusion, diclofenac was associated with an increased risk                of CDAD. Several NSAIDs could be prescribed in place of diclofenac, reducing the risk                of CDAD without additional inconveniences.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le Clostridium difficile est une bactérie qui cause des                infections gastro-intestinales. L'association entre les anti-inflammatoires                non-stéroïdiens (AINS) et le C. difficile n'a jamais été étudiée. Plusieurs rapports                de cas lient le diclofenac (AINS) au C. difficile. Dans cette étude cas-témoin, basée                sur des données du United Kingdom's General Practice Research Database, le risque de                C. difficile suite à l'utilisation d'AINS a été évalué. 1360 cas et 13072 contrôles                ont été identifiés entre 1994 et 2005. À l'aide de régression logistique, nous                trouvons une augmentation du risque de C. difficile chez les utilisateurs de                diclofenac [Risque relatif ajusté 1.35; intervalle de confiance 95%: 1.10-1.67].                Aucun autre AINS n'est associé à une augmentation d'infection par le C. difficile. De                plus, le diclofenac n'a pas d'effet de dose. En conclusion, le diclofenac est associé                à un risque accru de C. difficile. Ce risque peut être éliminé en remplaçant le                diclofenac par d'autres AINS.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul Brassard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t35m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57ns75v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ans064761x"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigation into the catalytic mechanism and binding properties of human methenyltetrahydrofolate synthetase</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Copeland, Evelyne Helen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The essential vitamin folic acid upon reduction to its tetrahydro form,                tetrahydrofolate (THF) is a necessary factor in cellular proliferation. THF or its                derivatives are biologically active cofactors, which serve as carriers of one-carbon                units in major cellular processes including nucleotide and amino acid biosynthesis                and in the methylation cycle. The most stable of the THF derivatives, 5-formylTHF                (5-FTHF), is not utilized as a one-carbon donor but is transferred back to the folate                pool by the enzyme, MethenylTHF Synthetase (MTHFS). MTHFS is the only enzyme that                catalyzes the irreversible ATP and Mg2+-dependent conversion of 5-FTHF to                5,10-methenylTHF. Little is known about the catalytic mechanism of this important                enzyme. Structural studies of human MTHFS in solution were undertaken using nuclear                magnetic resonance spectroscopy in order to gain insight into the reaction mechanism                as well as substrate and cofactor binding properties. Nearly complete backbone                assignments were obtained for human MTHFS. The 3D solution structure of hMTHFS was                determined from a total of 1947 NMR-derived distance and torsional restraints. The                atomic rmsd about the mean coordinate position is 0.8 Å for the backbone and 1.5 Å                for all heavy atoms. Human MTHFS consists of a four-stranded b-sheet, a small                two-stranded b-sheet and four main a-helices. The central b-sheet is made up of four                parallel b-strands and is flanked on both sides by a-helices and on one side by an                antiparallel two-stranded b-sheet. Protein-ligand interactions were explored by NMR.                The technique of chemical shift mapping was used to identify potential active site                residues and to guide site-directed mutagenesis experim</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La vitamine essentielle, l'acide folique, réduite à sa                forme tétrahydro, tétra-hydrofolate (THF) est un facteur indispensable à la                prolifération cellulaire. Les dérivés de THF sont des cofacteurs biologiquement                actifs à la base des réactions de transfert d'unités monocarbonées (1C) impliquées                dans des processus majeurs comme la synthèse des nucléotides et des acides aminés                ainsi que dans le cycle des méthylations. Le plus stable des dérivés de THF,                5-formylTHF (5-FTHF), n'est pas utilisé comme "donneur de carbone" mais peut être                introduit au cycle folate par l'enzyme, MéthenylTHF Synthétase (MTHFS). MTHFS est le                seul enzyme à catalyser la transformation du 5-FTHF au 5,10-methenylTHF; une réaction                irréversible et dépendante de l'ATP et du Mg2+. Le mécanisme catalytique de cet                enzyme important est peu connu. Des études structurales de l'enzyme MTHFS humain en                solution par résonance magnétique nucléaire (RMN) ont été effectuées pour déceler le                mécanisme d'action ainsi que pour étudier les liaisons entre l'enzyme et ses                substrats. Une attribution de signaux presque complète a été obtenue pour la chaine                squelettique de l'enzyme. La structure tridimensionnelle en solution de la MTHFS                humaine a été déterminé d'un total de 1947 contraintes de distance et d'angles                dièdres à partir des données expérimentales de RMN. L'écart-type à la valeur moyenne                de la position des atomes (rmsd) est de 0.8 Å pour la squelette et de 1.5 Å pour les                atomes lourds. La MTHFS humaine contient un feuillet b formé de quatre brins, d'un                petit feuillet de deux brins et de 4 hélices a principales. Le feuillet du centre est                formé de quatre brins b pa</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Miroslaw Cygler</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204097d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064761x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A000001961"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Determination of the transmembrane topology of mammalian SLC11A2 by an epitope mapping approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Czachorowski, Maciej</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La famille de transporteurs membranaires d'ions                métalliques divalents couplés aux protons, Slc11a, présente un haut niveau de                conservation parmi les organismes phylogénétiquement distincts et contribue à des                effets pléiotropiques chez l'humain. La topologie des membres de la famille Slc11a de                mammifère n'est pas clairement élucidée. Elle a été investiguée par l'insertion                d'épitopes d'hémagglutinine (HA) dans les segments prédits hydrophiles de l'isoforme                I de la protéine Slc11a2. Des essais de transport de cations ont été effectués afin                de s'assurer du bon fonctionnement de la protéine et de sa localisation à la membrane                plasmique. La technique d'immunofluorescence, effectuée sur des cellules intactes et                perméabilisées LLC-PK1 exprimant de façon stable ces constructions, a indiqué que les                deux extrémités de la protéine ainsi que les segments séparant les domaines                transmembranaires prédits 4/5, 6/7 et 10/11 sont intracellulaires, alors que ceux                séparant les domaines transmembranaires prédits 5/6, 7/8 et 11/12 correspondent à des                régions extracellulaires. Données, qui ont été validées par un essai de marquage de                surface. L'insertion d'épitopes dans l'une ou l'autre des trois premières boucles                hydrophiles prédites de la région N-terminale a résulté en la perte d'activité de                transport de cations de la protéine. Ces résultats sont en accord avec le modèle                topologique existant pour la protéine Slc11a2 qui suggère 12 domaines                transmembranaires et des extrémités intracellulaires.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The Slc11a family of integral, proton-coupled divalent metal                transporters exhibits a high degree of conservation among phylogenetically distinct                organisms and contributes to a variety of pleotropic effects in humans. The topology                of mammalian Slc11a family members remains unclear and was investigated by insertion                of hemagglutinin (HA) epitopes in the predicted hydrophilic segments of Slc11a2                isoform I, followed by cation transport assays to ensure proper protein function and                targeting at the plasma membrane. Immunofluorescence, corroborated by a surface                labeling assay, on stably transfected intact and permeabilized LLC-PK1 cells                indicated that both termini and the intervening segments separating predicted                transmembrane domains 4/5, 6/7, and 10/11 are intracellular, while those linking                predicted TMDs 5/6, 7/8, and 11/12 correspond to extracellular regions. Epitope                insertion in any of the first three predicted hydrophilic loops of the N-terminus                abrogated cation transport activity. These results are consistent with a topological                model for mammalian Slc11a2 having 12 TMDs and intracellular termini.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Philippe Gros</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks29k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000001961</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zg339"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Is urban agriculture associated with food security and nutritional status of preschool-aged children among low- income-peri-urban households of Lima, Peru?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maldonado, Andrea</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans les bidonvilles périurbains de Lima, l'insécurité                alimentaire et la malnutrition de l'enfant sont des problèmes de premiers ordres.                L'agriculture urbaine (AU) est une stratégie d'adaptation qui aide des familles                pauvres dans les zones urbaines à satisfaire leurs besoins alimentaires. Cette étude                a enquêté sur les rapports entre l'AU et la sécurité alimentaire, et l'alimentation                et le statut nutritif des enfants parmi les foyers pauvres périurbains de Lima. Les                personnes principalement responsables des soins des petits enfants des foyers ont été                recrutées des cuisines communautaires. Information sur la socio-démographie, sécurité                alimentaire, et l'activité d'AU du foyer, ainsi que les données anthropométrique et                la santé de l'enfant ont été documentées. Les résultats n'ont pas révélé de                différences au niveau de la sécurité alimentaire entre les foyers qui se livrent à                l'AU et ceux qui ne font pas d'AU, ni pour le statut nutritif ou l'alimentation                d'enfant. Pourtant, la stratification en bas, moyenne et haute intensité d'activité                AU a révélée la plus haute fréquence de consommation d'aliments de source d'animal                parmi les enfants des foyers avec beaucoup d'activité AU, et des z-tas                d'hauteur-pour-âge diminués parmi les enfants des foyers avec un minium d'activité                AU, mais aucune différence dans le statut de sécurité alimentaire. Ces conclusions                suggèrent que l'AU peut contribuer à l'amélioration d'alimentation d'enfants.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In the peri-urban slums of Lima, food insecurity and child malnutrition                are prevalent. Urban agriculture (UA) is a coping strategy to help poor urban                households meet food needs. This study investigated relationships between UA and food                security, and children's diets and nutritional status among poor peri-urban                households of Lima. Caregivers (n=197) of young children (9-71 mo.) were recruited                from 40 community kitchens. Household sociodemographic, food security, UA activity,                child health and anthropometric data were documented. The results revealed no                differences between UA and non-UA households in household food security, children's                nutritional status or diets. However, stratification of UA activity size into small,                medium and large revealed greater frequency of consumption of animal source foods                among children of large scale UA households, and decreased child height-for-age                z-scores in small scale UA households, but no differences in food security. These                findings suggest UA of sufficient volume may contribute to improving children's                diets.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grace Marquis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qt85x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg339</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dr38q"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors affecting the distribution of beech bark disease in two beech-maple forests in south-western Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Motchula, Tania Liane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>RÉSUMÉ La maladie corticale du hêtre (MCH) a été étudiée                dans deux forêts Acer-Fagus à Montréal, Québec. Les symptômes ont été utilisés pour                comparer le niveau de la maladie entre les deux forêts. Les deux, la cochenille du                hêtre (Cryptococcus fagisuga Lind.) et le champignon (Nectria galligena Bres.) ont                été trouvé à l'arboretum Morgan, alors que seulement la cochenille du hêtre a été                trouvée à la réserve de nature Molson. Cela signifie que les deux forêts sont au                niveau du front meutrier et le front d'avancement, respectivement. Une approche                multivariée a aussi été utilisée pour explorer les facteurs qui ont un effect sur la                distribution de la cochenille. La concentration était associée avec la population de                la cochenille, alors que le diamètre de l'arbre et les concentrations des phénols et                du calcium ne l'étaient pas. Une approche de modèle (AIC) a montré que ces modèles                qui contiennent de l'azote, et le diamètre de l'arbre ou les phénols ont été ceux les                plus probables d'expliquer la distribution de la cochenille. Les populations de la                cochenille les plus élevées du côté nord et est, et les plus basses au sud. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>ABSTRACT Beech bark disease (BBD) was studied in two Acer-Fagus forests                in Montreal, Quebec. Symptoms of BBD were used to compare the level of disease                between the forests. Both beech scale (Cryptococcus fagisuga Lind.) and fungus                (Nectria galligena Bres.) were found in the Morgan Arboretum, while only beech scale                was found in the Molson Nature Reserve, signifying that these two forests are at the                killing zone and advancing front, respectively. A multivariate approach was used in                order to explore the factors affecting beech scale distribution. Bark nitrogen                concentration had a positive association with beech scale population, while DBH and                bark phenol and calcium levels had none. A model selection process using AIC showed                that those models containing nitrogen, and DBH or phenols were the most likely to                explain beech scale distribution. Beech scale populations were highest on the                northern and eastern sides of the trees, and lowest on the southern side.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Christopher Buddle</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jz98m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr38q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289k84v"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Recording piano in surround: discovering preferences, investigating auditory imagery, and establishing physical predictors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kim, Sungyoung</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Afin de comprendre les caracteristiques latentes de                l'enregistrement multicanaux de la musique reproduite d'un piano solo, quatre                techniques sophistiquees de captation micro multicanaux ont ete deployees de facon                optimale pour saisir les memes performances simultanement. Les resultats des echells                de preferences chez les auditeurs en relation aux quatres techniques de captation                multicanaux utilisees demontrent que non seulement les techniques de captation, mais                aussi le contenu musical contribuent a faire moduler les preferences des auditeurs.                Afin de predire les preferences obtenues des auditeurs par l'analyse des signaux                binauraux, differentes versions des programmes musicaux furent captures e l'aide dun                Simulateur Tete et Torse (HATS). L'analyse a demontre que la combinaison de deux                mesures electroacoustiques, le Ear Signal Incoherence (ESI) et le Side Base Ratio                (SBR), etait etroitement reliee aux preferences obtenues. Une analyse subsequente a                revele que les principaux attributs de perception ont ete decrits par cinq paires                d'adjectifs bipolaires et la preference des auditeurs etait principalement                representee par ces attributs. Cependant, l'ESI et le SBR n'etaient associes a aucun                des principaux attributs, ce qui conduisit a une nouvelle investigation afin de                trouver les mesures physiques associees a la perception des attributs. De nouvelles                mesures physiques furent alors derivees de l'analyse des captations binaurales                multicanaux de la musique reproduite d'un piano, soit pour la largeur, la precision                des basses et la nettete respectivement. La relation quantitative entre les mesures                physiques, perceptuelles et preferentielles derivees de cette etude pourrait etre$</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In order to develop a better understanding of the differences in the                multichannel reproduction of solo piano music that result from the use of various                popular multichannel microphone techniques, an experimental investigation employing                both physical and perceptual measurements was undertaken. Four sophisticated                multichannel microphone arrays were optimally placed for simultaneous capture of a                series of four piano performances, so that resulting auditory imagery could be                compared between otherwise identical performances. In an initial study, preference                choices of two groups of listeners showed that not only the microphone techniques in                use, but also differences in the musical content, contributed to the modulation of                the listeners' preference. In order to predict the obtained preference of the                listeners through the analysis of the binaural signals, differing versions of the                musical programs were captured through the Head and Torso Simulator (HATS). The                analysis showed that a combination of two electroacoustical measures, Ear Signal                Incoherence (ESI) and Side Bass Ratio (SBR), was closely related to the obtained                preference. The subsequent analysis revealed that the salient perceptual attributes                were described by five bipolar pairs of adjectives, and the listener preference was                mostly accounted by those attributes. However, the ESI and SBR were not associated                with any of the salient attributes, which led another investigation to find the                physical measures associated with the perceptual attributes. New physical measures                were then derived from the analysis of binaurally captured multichannel reproduced                piano music for WIDTH, BASS TIGHTNESS and SHARPNESS, respectively. The qu</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>William Martens</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Wieslaw Woszczyk</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074x07s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289k84v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>