<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak3569515b"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Prevalence and dietary predictors of iron deficiency anemia in women 1-year postpartum living in central Montreal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Murphy, Patricia, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We estimated the prevalence of iron deficiency anemia (IDA) in  women 1-year postpartum in central Montreal. Blood samples were obtained by  venipuncture and questionnaires administered. Iron intake was assessed by a food  frequency questionnaire. Mothers with at least two of the following laboratory  values were considered to have IDA: serum ferritin (SF) &lt; 12 mug/L, mean  corpuscular volume (MCV) &lt; 80 fL and hemoglobin (Hb) &lt; 120 g/L. Blood  samples were analysed for 201 women. The estimates of prevalence of anemia (Hb  &lt; 120 g/L), iron deficiency (SF &lt; 12 mug/L) and IDA were 7.0% (95%  confidence interval [CI] 3.8%-10.9%), 5.5% (95% CI 2.5%-8.9%) and 2.5% (95% CI  0.3%-4.7%) respectively. No significant differences were observed between level of  income and anemia, iron deficiency and IDA rates. Anemia was not related to dietary  iron intake. In conclusion, the prevalence of IDA is low among healthy women 1-year  postpartum in central Montreal.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732d9552.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569515b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Iron deficiency anemia -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iron deficiency anemia -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Puerperium -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r369j"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of a novel endogenous steroid, estradienolone (ED), in human pregnancy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Negi, Ranuka</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Estradienolone (ED, 17beta-hydroxy-[1,5]-estradien-3-one) is a  novel steroid hormone identified in pregnant women. It is an isomer of estradiol  which binds the progesterone receptor and sex hormone binding globulin with high  affinity. Since levels of ED remain high throughout pregnancy and decrease in  association with term or preterm labour, ED may be involved in the maintenance of  pregnancy. The objectives of the present study were to, (i) purify ED from pregnancy  samples in quantities sufficient for chemical analysis to confirm its structural  features, and (ii) identify its binding proteins and receptors. Our results show  that ED binds the novel methyltrienolone (R1881) binding protein of JEG-3 cells with  higher affinity than any other natural steroids tested. Furthermore, ED is able to  inhibit transcriptional activity of the estrogen-receptor-related receptors alpha  and gamma, suggesting that ED may be the natural ligand of these orphan receptors.  ED is also able to activate the xenobiotic receptor SXR. Chemical analysis of the  fine structural features of purified ED is in progress.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698805v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r369j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Obstetrics and Gynecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405s988s"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quality changes in chicken nuggets fried in oils with different degrees of hydrogenation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Yunsheng, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The goal of this research was to investigate the influence of  the degree of hydrogenation of frying oil on quality and textural changes in chicken  nuggets during deep-fat frying. Thermal stabilities of the frying oils were also  studied. The frying oil consisted of blends of hydrogenated and non-hydrogenated  oils mixed at different ratios. Physical and textural attributes of the products, as  well as the moisture and fat contents, were measured at various frying times. Oil  samples were withdrawn at different times and analyzed for colour, free fat acid  (FFA) content, viscosity and dielectric properties. Physical and textural properties  of chicken nuggets were influenced by frying time and the degree of oil  hydrogenation. The experimental data, for changes in the properties of both flying  oil and fried product, was adequately described using first order reaction kinetics.  Increasing frying time decreased product lightness whereas chroma and hardness  values increased. Frying in oils with higher degrees of hydrogenation resulted in  products with lighter and harder (more crispy) texture. Products fried in  non-hydrogenated oil absorbed more oil but also retained more moisture compared to  samples fried in hydrogenated oil. The rate of change in the colour parameters of  oils was observed to increase with increasing frying time and the degree of  hydrogenation. The chroma values of the oils increased when frying time increased  and degree of hydrogenation decreased. The viscosity of oil tended to increase with  increasing degree of hydrogenation. The FFA content and dielectric constant of the  frying oils correlated with frying time and degree of hydrogenation.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236254x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405s988s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Convenience foods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Deep frying</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cookery (Chicken)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mj611"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design of a microcontroller-based, power control system for microwave drying</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Zhenfeng, 1968 Oct. 9-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Microwave drying is an energy-efficient drying method. The  output power of most commercial microwave ovens is controlled in an intermittent  fashion, where the amount of microwave energy is determined by the ratio of "ON  cycles" to "OFF cycles." To provide a more efficient and continuous  power control for the magnetron, a microcontroller-based, feedback power control  system was developed. The system was based on a phase-control principle to achieve  smooth power variations depending on a feedback temperature signal of processed  products. Two temperature sensors, a thermocouple and an infrared sensor, were used  to measure the temperature. A fiber-optic thermometer was used for calibration and  evaluation of the system performance during microwave drying. With the IR sensor,  the mean standard deviation and maximum error in temperature measurement of  controlled water samples were +/-0.34ºC and +/-1.5ºC, respectively.  This result demonstrated the accuracy of the IR sensor in the system control. Under  the IR sensor-controlled system, carrot cubes (Daucus carota L.) lost 85.37% of  their water content and resulted in better color quality than the conventional  microwave-hot air convective drying without a temperature feedback  control.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sw440.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mj611</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture, Food Science and Technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajw827c30n"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The mental health of minors exposed to war and organized violence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Persson, Tonje Jeanette</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Little is known about the effectiveness of non-stigmatizing mental health interventions aimed at reducing or preventing the harmful impact of armed conflict on children, and how war affects the mental health of both non-resettled and resettled minors. This thesis presents, through a literature review, what is known about school-based interventions for minors living in war-exposed countries. Second, it investigates by an empirical study, how exposure to trauma is associated with increased risk for psychological symptoms in recently arrived migrant adolescents to Canada. Existing evidence for school-based programs as a means to reduce distress is promising. In general, recently resettled migrant youth may not be at risk. However, exposure to pre-migratory trauma predicts more emotional problems. Assessing how exposure to adverse events in the pre-migratory phase may be related to psychological adjustment immediately following resettlement may identify the needs of recently arrived migrant children and inform the design of school-based programmes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Peu est connu sur l'efficacité de la non-stigmatisation des interventions de santé mentale visant à réduire ou prévenir les effets néfastes des conflits armés sur les enfants, et comment la guerre affecte la santé mentale des mineurs non-réinstallés et réinstallés. L'objectif de cette thèse est, dans un premier temps, d'établir au travers d'une étude bibliographique, les données existantes concernant les programmes de prévention en milieu scolaire pour les mineurs vivant dans des zones de conflit. Dans un deuxième temps, une étude empirique viendra analyser les répercussions de l'expérience du traumatisme quant à l'apparition de troubles psychologiques sur les adolescents migrants récemment arrivés au Canada. La littérature existante met en exergue le caractère prometteur des programmes de prévention en milieu scolaire, en montrant, que dans bien des cas, ils constituent un élément d'apaisement. De manière générale, les jeunes migrants nouvellement établis ne forment pas une population à risque. Cependant, le fait d'être confronté à un traumatisme prédispose à davantage de problèmes émotionnels. Déterminer la manière dont l'exposition à des événements éprouvants, dans la phase précédant la migration, peut engendrer des ajustements psychologiques immédiatement après l'installation, pourrait permettre d'identifier les besoins des enfants migrants nouvellement arrivés. Cela permettrait également de développer des programmes appropriés au milieu scolaire.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cecile Rousseau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v8491.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827c30n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Developmental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s1616695"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Atypical behaviours in developmental disorders: the association between fatique and autistic symptoms in children with Cri du Chat syndrome</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Claro, Anthony</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The goal of the current study is to examine whether fatigue level of children diagnosed with Cri du Chat syndrome or moderate to severe learning disabilities, is associated with their expression of autistic symptoms. Sixty-nine children with Cri du Chat syndrome and 47 children with moderate to severe learning disabilities were assessed using the ISQ-A for fatigue level and the CARS for autism level rating. In line with our hypothesis, results of hierarchical multiple regression analyses indicated that children who exhibited high levels of fatigue were more likely than children who exhibited low levels of fatigue to express high levels of autistic symptoms. Contrary to our hypothesis, children with moderate to severe learning disabilities who exhibited high levels of fatigue conferred the greatest vulnerability to the expression of autistic symptoms.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'objectif de la présente étude est de déterminer s'il y a un lien entre le niveau de fatigue et l'expression de symptômes associées à l'autisme chez les enfants ayant été diagnostiqués avec le syndrome du Cri du Chat ou des difficultés d'apprentissage modérées ou sévères. Soixante-et-neuf enfants ayant le syndrome Cri du Chat et quarante-sept enfants souffrant de difficultés d'apprentissage modérées ou sévères ont fait l'objet d'examen en utilisant le ISQ-A pour déterminer les niveaux de fatigue et le CARS pour l'évaluation du niveau d'autisme. En accord avec notre hypothèse, les résultats des analyses de régression multiple indiquent que les enfants exhibant des niveaux plus élevés de fatigue étaient plus sujets que les enfants exhibant des niveaux plus bas de fatigue à montrer des niveaux élevés de symptômes d'autisme. Contrairement à notre hypothèse, ce sont les enfants ayant des difficultés d'apprentissage modérées ou sévères et exhibant des niveaux élevés de fatigue qui étaient les plus sujets à l'expression de symptômes d'autisme.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reut Gruber</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jeffrey L. Derevensky</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dd055.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1616695</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Developmental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak06988064"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"Inhibition of mineralization in bones and teeth following ectopic expression of matrix Gla protein"</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaipatur, Neelambar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Matrix Gla Protein (MGP) inhibits mineralization of arteries and  cartilage. To determine its mineral-inhibiting potential in hard tissues, MGP was  ectopically expressed in bones and teeth of mice using an  osteoblast/odontoblast-specific 2.3kb proximal promoter for type 1 collagen.  Mandibles and long bones of Col1a1-Mgp mice and wild-type littermates were analyzed  by Faxitron(TM) radiography, PIXImus(TM) dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DEXA) and  micro-computed tomography (mu-CT). In addition, light microscopy (LM) and  transmission electron microscopy (TEM) were performed. While bone and tooth  extracellular matrices (ECMs) appeared normally established in Col1a1-Mgp mice,  examination of the mineral phase by radiography, DEXA and mu-CT, together with  histological mineral localization by LM after von Kossa staining of undecalcified  tissue sections, and by TEM, revealed massive hypomineralization of bone and tooth  ECMs. In the skeleton of Col1a1-Mgp mice, alveolar bone of the mandible was most  heavily affected (compared to long bones), showing a 50% increase in the  unmineralized osteoid volume compared to wild-type littermates. For teeth,  mineralization was virtually absent in root dentin of both incisors and molars, and  absent in molar cellular cementum, whereas crown dentin showed localized  "breakthrough" areas of mineralization. Acellular cementum formation and  mineralization was absent in the Col1a1-Mgp mice. Immunohistochemical staining of  bone and tooth ECM proteins in Col1a1-Mgp mice showed variations in staining  relative to wild-type tissues, with immunostaining generally restricted to areas of  mineralization. In conclusion, these results confirm in vivo that ECM proteins can  act as inhibitors of bone and tooth mineralization.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n1737.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k06988064</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429969n"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Heart rate telemetry and time-motion analysis of ice hockey referees</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kahn, Bradley</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Referees have a job to ensure a safe and fair playing  environment. The purpose of this study was to quantify on-ice intensities (heart  rate) and on-ice movements (forward or backwards skating or stationary) of referees  during ice hockey games. 15 HC referees had their heart rates monitored and skating  video taped throughout a 60 minute game. A treadmill run test was used to identify  their peak heart rates and VO2. The dominant on-ice activity was forward skating  followed by stationary then backwards skating. On average referees worked at 80% of  their peak heart rate. Significant differences (p&lt;0.05) were found between  period average heart rates and peak heart rates. The results suggest that referees  generally work at an aerobic intensity with numerous anaerobic bursts interspersed  throughout play. Knowledge about the intensity, frequency and amount of skating that  occurs in each direction will help with the development of the athletic ability of  referees.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bv173.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429969n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Heart beat</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hockey referees -- Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn009z330"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Innate resistance to cytomegalovirus infection in wild-derived mice : role of natural killer cell receptors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Girard Adam, Sonia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Human cytomegalovirus (HCMV) infection can cause  life-threatening disease in immunodeficient hosts. Experimental infection in mice  has revealed that natural resistance to murine cytomegalovirus (MCMV) is genetically  determined and mediated by binding of the natural killer (NK) cell activating  receptor Ly49H to the pathogen-encoded glycoprotein m157. The study of genetically  diverse wild-derived strains revealed natural resistance in the PWK/Pas mouse.  However, intracellular staining of NK cells indicated that PWK/Pas mice do not  express Ly49H. Moreover, PWK/Pas were also found to be resistant to mutant virus  lacking m157. Analysis of backcrosses to a susceptible strain demonstrated that  MCMV-resistance is controlled by a major dominant gene effect linked to the Ly49  gene cluster and a modest influence of the major histocompatibility complex (H2).  Ly49 cDNAs encoding four novel activating receptors were identified as candidate  genes for the resistance phenotype. Our results provide genetic evidence for the  existence of alternative NK cell receptors that mediate resistance to viral  infection in mice by mechanisms other than recognition of m157. Functionally  homologous innate resistance genes may be found in human  populations.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k448.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z330</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719m950"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of toll-like receptor 4 in Leishmania-induced chemokine gene expression and inflammatory response</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Godbout, Marianne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Modulation of the innate immune response by Leishmania has been  extensively studied; however, some questions still need to be answered. In the  present study, we demonstrated, in vitro and in vivo, that Leishmania interacts with  TLR4 in order to induce chemokine mRNA expression. That TLR4-dependent macrophage  (Mϕ) activation was shown to be MyD88-independent in vitro, and results in  the activation of the transcription factors NF-kappaB and CREB. Their role in  chemokine mRNA expression was further demonstrated using specific inhibitors toward  these transcription factors. Moreover, using TLR4-deficient mice we confirmed the  role of TLR4 in Leishmania-induced chemokine gene expression and in the subsequent  recruitment of inflammatory cells. Collectively, our results bring new insights for  understanding the interaction of Leishmania with its host cell, the  Mϕ.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c102v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719m950</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bp804"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Preferential maternal LOH in the IGF2R gene in breast cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Demian, Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tumors develop and progress as a result of alterations in  oncogene and tumor suppressor genes. Knudson's two hit model predicts that cancer  arises when both alleles of a tumor suppressor gene are inactivated. The  insulin-like growth factor 2 receptor gene (IGF2R) is known to be a tumor suppressor  for breast cancer, as mutations inactivating both alleles have been found in these  tumors, consistent with its known functions in degrading insulin-like growth factor  2 (IGF2) and activating transforming growth factor beta1 (TGF-beta1), a growth  inhibitor. Tumor suppressors can be inactivated by several means, such as genomic  imprinting (a preferential silencing of a particular parental chromosome), large  deletions resulting in loss of heterozygosity (LOH), and point mutations. In both  humans and mice, IGF2R has gamete-of-origin dependent methylation which results in  exclusive maternal expression in mice, while in humans imprinted expression is seen  only in rare individuals and could be a predisposing factor for cancer. Since it is  known that LOH plays a role in the genesis of breast cancer, we hypothesized that in  some cases the event inactivating the other gene copy is parental imprinting. Our  hypothesis predicted that this LOH is preferentially maternal and, therefore, the  remaining allele is unmethylated. We tested this prediction in 20 breast cancer  samples, thirteen of which (65%) were heterozygous and 9/13 (69%) had LOH. Two of 9  tumors (~22%) showed complete lack of methylation, consistent with LOH of  the maternal allele. However, surprisingly and potentially significantly, normal  tissue from the breast cancer patients was completely methylated in 4 samples and  completely unmethylated in 2. This suggests that IGF2R methylation disruption may be  a pre-existing, cancer-predisposing molecular lesion in the breast of these  patients. More work is needed to exclude technical artifacts in reaching this  conclusion.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139249t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bp804</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343s75s"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of dendritic targeting signals of voltage-gated potassium channel 3</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Deng, Qingwei, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Members of voltage-gated potassium channel subfamily 3 (Kv3)  have been extensively demonstrated to play a significant role in facilitating  function of "fast-firing" neurons in the central nervous system. Kv3.1 and  Kv3.3 channels, members of Kv3 channel subfamily, have different distribution  profiles on the regional level of brain and on the subcellular level of neurons in  mammals and in weakly electric fish, according to mRNA hybridizations in situ and  immunohistochemical analysis. In mammals, Kv3.1 channels are expressed in soma, axon  and proximal dendrites as well as presynaptic membrane of "fast-firing"  neurons. In weakly electric fish (Apteronotus), Kv3.1 channels are distributed in  the soma, in the basilar dendrites and in the proximal apical dendrites of pyramidal  neurons; on the other hand, Kv3.3 channels are expressed in a larger region: soma,  basilar dendrites and entire apical dendrites of these cells. Mechanisms underlying  differential subcellular distribution of Kv3.1 and Kv3.3 channels in the apical  dendritic compartment of pyramidal neurons are unknown. In order to identify peptide  sequences responsible for the differential subcellular localization, I have used  Semliki Forest virus as a modified viral expression system (PDE) in vivo to study  dendritic targeting mechanisms in the pyramidal neurons of electrosensory lateral  line lobe (ELL), where the primary processing for afferent input occurs in the  apteronotid electrosensory system.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pd52z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s75s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Brown ghost knifefish -- Nervous system</dc:subject><dc:subject>Potassium channels</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axs55mc577"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The adenovirus E4orf4 protein induces G2 / M arrest and cell death by inhibiting PP2A phosphatase activity regulated by the B Alpha subunit</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brignole, Claudine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The human adenovirus E4orf4 protein is toxic in human tumor  cells and yeast. In both cases, interaction of E4orf4 with the Balpha/Cdc55  regulatory subunit of protein phosphatase 2A (PP2A) appears to be critical for cell  killing; however, the effect of E4orf4 binding on PP2A is not known. Balpha is one  of several B subunits that form holoenzymes with A and C subunits and regulate PP2A  substrate specificity. In the present studies the effects of E4orf4 on PP2A activity  was examined, as well as the role of PP2A in E4orf4-mediated cell death. Previously  it was shown that binding of E4orf4 had little effect on the dephosphorylation of a  universal peptide substrate by purified PP2A, however this study demonstrates that  E4orf4 reduced PP2A activity to varying degrees against two substrates,  phosphorylase a and histone H1, the latter known to represent a class of substrate  against which Balpha-containing PP2A complexes are highly active. Expression of  E4orf4 was also found to result in the accumulation of hyperphosphorylated forms of  two PP2A substrates, 4EBP-1 and p70S6K (Balpha specific) in vivo, indicating a  significant inhibition of PP2A activity against these substrates. The importance of  such inhibition in cell killing by E4orf4 was supported by the fact that low levels  of okadaic acid (OA) or expression of the heat stable I1 PP2A inhibitor, both of  which inhibit PP2A activity globally, enhanced E4orf4-induced cell death.  Furthermore, E4orf4 killing was reduced by overexpression of a Y307F mutant form of  the PP2A catalytic Calpha subunit, which is insenstitive to downregulation by  tyrosine phosphorylation. E4orf4 was found to induce a significant G2/M arrest, an  effect that was enhanced both by treatment with OA, which alone at high levels has  similar effects, and by expression of simian virus 40 small T antigen (SV40-ST),  which binds to PP2A holoenzymes and preferentially replaces the Balpha subunit.  These results suggest that E4orf4 induce</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vk612.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mc577</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j1548"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Convex functions, majorization properties and the convex conjugate transform</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brennan, Derek</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Let Kw(t) := inf∥P∥ 22≤t 01 |1 - P(theta)|2w(theta) dtheta, where w ≥ 0 is a decreasing function and P ∈ L2([0,1], Leb.). Then we have Kw ≤ Kv ↔01 1wq +l dtheta ≥ 01 1vq+l dtheta ∀ lambda ≥ 0. We present two similar proofs of this result, which are analogous to the well-known majorization theorem: Let v, w ≥ 0 be decreasing functions, and suppose 01 w(theta)dtheta = 01 v(theta)dtheta. Then Fw ≤ Fv ↔01 (w(theta) - x)+ dtheta ≥ 01 (v(theta) - x)+ dtheta ∀ x ≥ 0, where F w(t) = t1 w(theta)dtheta. Since our proofs of this result rely mainly on the convex conjugate transform, or Legendre transform, we include an exposition of convex functions and convex conjugate transforms.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r6184.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j1548</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax346d481g"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Elucidation of nonthermal effects of microwave irradiation on the unfolding pathways of [beta]-lactoglobulin and hemoglobin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al-Jundi, Abdul Nasser</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In recent years there has been considerable interest in the  development of microwave-based food processing technologies. Microwave radiation is  considered to have both thermal and non-thermal effects. The thermal effects are  related to the heat generated by the absorption of microwave energy by water or by  organic molecules, but very little is known about the mechanisms involved in the  putative non-thermal effects. It has been postulated that the latter could involve a  direct energy transfer from the electromagnetic field to the vibrational modes of  macromolecules, altering their conformation. In the present study, the non-thermal  effects induced upon irradiation of protein solutions with microwave energy were  investigated by employing Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy, circular  dichroism, and fluorescence spectroscopy to elucidate the unfolding pathways of  hemoglobin and beta-lactoglobulin (5% in D2O) subjected to either microwave  irradiation (2450 MHz) or conventional heating. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kb33w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d481g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Microwave heating</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hemoglobin -- Denaturation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lactoglobulins -- Denaturation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89d707h"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bioinformatic approaches to the discovery of apoptotic proteins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Acoca, Stephane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The core of this research project revolves around the  development of knowledge and expertise in the field of sequence homology  identification techniques, as applied towards the discovery of Bcl2 family members.  The use of such methods resulted in the uncovering of a Bcl2 Homology 3 (BH3) domain  in a ubiquitin ligase enzyme known as upstream regulatory binding protein 1 (UreB1).  A complete biochemical analysis unequivocally demonstrated binding of the UreB1 BH3  domain to MCL-1, an antiapoptotic member of the Bcl2 protein family. Furthermore,  the discovery of a BH3 domain in UreB1 may provide a link in the established  involvement of the ubiquitin pathway in the degradation of Mcl1 following certain  apoptotic stimuli. In addition, using an independent domain modelling strategy, we  describe the development of BISA, a web-accessible software package for sequence  homology detection.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j38607570.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d707h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289j556"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Slip frequency phase lock loop (PLL) for decoupled P-Q control of doubly-fed induction generator (DFIG)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shen, Baike, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The term "sensor-less" in power electronic drives  refers to measurement of mechanical shaft position and/or speed from the currents  and voltages of the electrical machine. This thesis presents innovative sensor-less  means (a Slip Frequency Phase Lock Loop (PLL) and a gamma-delta Axes Aligner) for  implementing decoupled P-Q control of a doubly-fed induction generator (DFIG) for  wind-turbine application. Proofs of concepts are by digital  simulations. The accuracy of the Slip Frequency Phase Lock Loop in speed  estimation is evaluated; the origin of a shortcoming (small phase lag) located and  compensated for. The Slip Frequency Phase Lock Loop (PLL) and a gamma-delta Axes  Aligner are then evaluated as parts of the decoupled P-Q control of a wind turbine  driven doubly-ed induction generator. The research succeeds in realizing robust  decoupled P-Q control, that is one in which the generator parameters do not have to  be known precisely and can have minor variations such as drifts with temperature.  The system has been successfully tested for optimal wind power  acquisition.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wd29p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289j556</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p091j"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Conjugate gradient methods using MPI for distributed systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sihota, Amit Kaur</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The expanding use of distributed multi-processor supercomputers  has made a significant impact on the speed and complexity of the problems which can  be solved by the finite element (FE) method. Moreover, the use of the standard  Message Passing Interface (MPI) protocol has facilitated the portability of parallel  applications across a wide variety of parallel architectures. The conjugate gradient  method plays an important role in solving discretized partial differential equations  resulting from FE methods. In this thesis, the scalability and performance analysis  of three versions of the conjugate gradient parallel solver are executed on the Sun  symmetric multiprocessor system with 4 processors with problems stemming from finite  element analysis. The implemented solvers demonstrate good scaling behaviour for  matrices with different sparsity patterns stemming from practical finite element  applications.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741s333.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p091j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s5380"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experimental investigation of flamerarefaction interactions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laviolette, Jean-Philippe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the present study, the instability resulting from the  interaction of a spherical flame and a rarefaction is investigated. The goal is to  understand the physical mechanisms governing the evolution of the flame front  subsequent to the interaction. It is shown that the distinct acceleration  characteristics of the rarefaction give rise to both Rayleigh-Taylor and  Richtmyer-Meshkov types of instabilities. Furthermore, following the interaction,  the formation of a funnel of unburned gas into the combustion products is observed,  similarly to the one observed by Markstein in flame/shock interaction experiments.  It is found that the growth rate of the funnel is constant and that it increases  with augmenting pressure gradient at the leading edge of the  rarefaction. It is also demonstrated that the interaction between a flame and  a rarefaction can lead to a greater rate of increase of pressure inside the  combustion vessel. This effect is only observed for a relatively high pressure  gradient at the leading edge of the rarefaction. Furthermore, it is found that  augmenting the flame diameter prior to the interaction results in a higher pressure  increase due to the interaction.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rx23v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s5380</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bp81d"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamic wetting and heat transfer behaviour of aluminium droplets impinging and solidifying on copper substrates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leboeuf, Sébastien</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present work describes an experimental set-up built to  simulate dynamic wetting and heat transfer occurring in many rapid solidification  processes. Tests were performed with molten aluminium droplets falling from a  crucible onto a metallic substrate. A high-speed camera captured the evolution of  the droplet's geometry, while thermocouples, inserted inside the metallic substrate,  allowed a heat transfer analysis to be performed. Aluminium 5754 was found to have a  better initial dynamic wetting and heat transfer compared to pure aluminium. An  increase in the initial temperature of the substrate was associated with better  dynamic wetting and heat transfer. The heat flux was also increased by the use of a  polished substrate compared to a sand-blasted substrate. The use of helium increased  the two aspects studied compared to air and argon atmosphere. Totally non-wetting  conditions were found for droplets in an argon atmosphere with less than 0.02%  O2.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w787t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bp81d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f643s"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Heterjunctions of small molecular weight organic semiconductors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hui, Yu, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Photodiodes made of small molecular weight organic  semiconductors have been fabricated. The organic materials under investigation are  p-type Copper phthalocyanine (CuPc) and n-type 3,4,9,10-perylenetetracarboxylic  bisbenzimidazole (PTCBI). Current-voltage and capacitance-voltage measurements have  been performed to evaluate the electrical properties of the organic photodiodes.  Optical measurements including responsivity and temporal response have also been  carried out. It has been found that device efficiency of the photodiodes is  influenced by the thickness of organic layers as well as the device structures. It  is believed that organic layer thickness is a strong function of materials' exciton  diffusion lengths. The thickness of the organic layer employed in the fabricated  photodiode is 100 A or less. However, the fabricated devices with thin organic layer  showed poor performance in terms of saturation current and breakdown voltage. As a  result, new device structures have been proposed to overcome the problems. Stacking  structure double heterojunction (SDH) and novel comb-like structure single  heterojunction (CSH) device configurations have shown a substantial improvement in  both electrical and optical parameters. There is at least 3 times enhancement in  photocurrent and 10 times increase in external quantum efficiency for photodiodes  employing CSH device structure and 100 A organic layer. Improvements in saturation  current and breakdown voltage have also been observed. In addition, responsivity  measurements in CSH devices have yielded a 7 times improvement. Furthermore, the  carrier lifetime of the photodiode is estimated to be around 1 microsecond from the  temporal response measurements. The combined effect of thin organic layers and new  device structures leads to an overall improvement in device  performance.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gk430.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f643s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As7526c88h"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation of a compact micro-optic and micromirror-based optical power equalizer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hoa, Xuyen D., 1976-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the design and characterisation of a  compact optical power equalizer module for optical fiber telecommunication  applications. The various components of the modules are separately examined in terms  of their impact on the overall dimension, performance and loss of the equalizer  module. Two components are studied in greater details, namely the micro diffractive  optical elements (DOEs), responsible for the multiplexing/demultiplexing of the  wavelength channels, and the micromirrors, responsible for creating the beam  displacements and thus controlling the attenuation. The DOEs allow for the spatial  separation of 64 wavelengths into a two-dimensional array with a compact module.  MUMPs surface-micromachined micromirrors have good optical properties: 0.29 dB  (93.5%) reflectance, low surface sag and negligible curvature. At operating voltages  of less than 15 V, tilts of 16 mrad are obtained, sufficient to provide over 50 dB  attenuation for the equalizer. Simulation results show that the diffractive elements  have low efficiency due to fabrication limitations. The power loss due to beam  clipping is 2.81 dB with overall system efficiency at above 5 dB. Major areas of  improvement in the device packaging, assembly and efficiency have been identified  for future works.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fc15t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526c88h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Optics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q4538"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Real time analysis with development, simulation and validation of discrete element method models for tumbling mill charge motion and liner wear</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Arekar, Chaitanya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tumbling mills, which consume around 6% of world's electric  power, though inefficient (use 1% of the supplied energy) have been used in mineral  processing industry for over a century. Harsh internal mill environments have  prevented the access to in-mill dynamics. This situation has led researchers to  develop models based on the Discrete Element Method (DEM) to predict internal mill  dynamics. But before DEM models can be used in the mineral processing industry,  their rigorous validation is essential. In this thesis, we have carried out real time analysis of the  DEM model to enable online availability of the mill parameters for the mill  operators. We have completed rigorous validation of a DEM model based on nine mill  parameters by comparing the predicted parameters under varying operating conditions  of a 30" pilot mill and some simulated industrial mills. Further, we have also  developed a simulator to predict the wear on the tumbling mill liner  profile. Results show that the charge motion simulator used is faster  than real time. The validation exercise showed that improvements to charge motion  are possible, liner wear prediction is feasible but affects real-time simulator  behaviour. Based on these results, it is recommended to continue the improvement of  the charge motion model as well as the liner wear model.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b660p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q4538</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88ch066"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Application of kinetic energy storage systems to power systems operation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abdul Samad, Alaa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis analyzes some potential applications of kinetic  energy (KE) storage systems in power systems operation. The goal was to take  advantage of the KE stored in the existing rotating machines in a power system such  as synchronous generators and motors by "borrowing" some of the stored KE  when electricity prices are high and "returning" this energy to the  rotating masses when the prices are down. As shown in this thesis, this operation  can be performed from the control center by optimally scheduling the set points of  the generators under automatic generation control (AGC) over a given time horizon.  This coordination of KE was also tested with other types of rotating machines,  namely synchronous and asynchronous flywheels. The specific impact of this optimum coordination of KE storage  has been tested from the perspective of power systems economics and security by  investigating the method's potential to reduce the marginal price of electricity and  to alleviate network congestion. In addition, this thesis examines the potential of  KE storage systems to produce fast (10-30 second) reserve to be used during primary  frequency regulation following the forced outage of a generating  unit.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150j78h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ch066</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25x918d"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Attention-related behaviours in a non-clinical sample of school-aged children : effects of genotype and gender</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Morisano, Dominique</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Recent genetic studies indicate an association between Attention  Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) and the dopamine transporter gene (DAT1) with  possible preferential relation to hyperactivity and impulsivity behaviours. The  present study investigated attention-related behaviours in a non-clinical sample to  determine whether the modulation of these behaviours is associated with genetic  variability of the DAT1 within the normal population. A secondary question explored  whether gender was associated with the measured attention-related behaviours.  Twenty-six children were observed in the classroom during performance of independent  academic work. Motor behaviours during task performance were scored using the  Restricted Academic Situation Scale. Major behavioural problems were scored using  the Conners' Teacher Rating Scale-Revised: Short Form (CTRS-R:S). All participants  were genotyped for the DAT1. The results yielded no significant genotype group  differences, although an association was found between oppositional behaviour  (CTRS-R:S) and gender. These preliminary results are discussed within the current  context of genetics research in ADHD.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579s78v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25x918d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sex differences</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>