<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw95052166"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optical tomography by time-resolved diffuse reflectance measurements</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Long, William F. (William Frank), 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The understanding of the interaction of light with a scattering/absorbing medium provides a foundation needed for developing many applications in diagnostic medicine and industry. The objective of this research was to obtain quantitative depth-resolved information about absorbing constituents in a scattering medium. Initially, the project focussed on quantification in samples where scattering and absorber concentration were variable. Using time resolved reflectance measurements, a series of statistical descriptors of the photon time distributions were calculated. Stepwise multilinear regression was used to formulate linear models from optimal linear combinations of the descriptors. It was found that the scattering coefficient, absorption coefficient and apparent particle diameter could be estimated to within 9, 10 and 7% of their reference values respectively. An array of radial reflectance measurements on layered scattering/absorbing samples was made to obtain information sensitive to sub-surface changes in absorption. As an initial approach to depth-resolved quantification, classical tomographic reconstruction techniques were used. However, due to the ambiguity of the reconstruction, extremely poor estimates of the sub-surface absorption resulted. Chemometric methods were then employed for enhanced quantification. By using stepwise multilinear regression with time-resolved data, the absorption coefficient in the top region of a sample could be estimated to within 2%. However, errors in the absorption coefficient estimations deep within a sample remained high. Further improvements in sample quantification were made by linearizing the reconstruction problem. By using a priori information about sample composition in upper regions, subsequent calibrations for lower regions were directed. Estimations of the absorption coefficient deep within a sample with hierarchical locally weighted calibration were obtainable at greater than 50% accuracy. This represented a 20% improvement at all sample depths over stepwise multilinear regression. Confocal illumination and detection optics was also used for discriminating highly scattered photons from light, which follows a geometric path through a sample. When confocal optics were used together with information from the rising edge of time distribution, little enhancement in quantification was observed in comparison to an integrated signal. This important finding demonstrates that the confocal optical detection should be considered when imaging in scattering/absorbing media.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burns, David H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t23t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95052166</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Analytical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nj813"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intra- and intermolecular interactions governing Pax-3 function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fortin, Anouk S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Pax-3 is a transcription factors important in normal embryonic development, as highlighted by its mutation in independent alleles of the Splotch mouse mutant and human Waardenburg syndrome, both characterized by pigmentary disturbances in the heterozygous state and limb muscle defects in the homozygotes. Pax-3 contains two structurally independent DNA-binding domains, a paired domain and a homeodomain. Through the analysis of a number of naturally occurring mutations, we have shown that both DNA-binding domains are functionally interdependent, as independent mutations in either domain can affect the DNA-binding activity of the other. In support of this finding, modeling the deleterious mutations into the three dimensional structure of the paired domain suggests that a series of consecutive phosphate contacts are essential for DNA-binding by both the paired domain and homeodomain of Pax-3. In addition, the paired domain can regulate the DNA-binding specificity and dimerization potential of the homeodomain and we have exploited the possibility to transfer this effect to a heterologous homeodomain to identify the protein segments involved in this functional interaction. Characterization of a series of chimeric proteins containing stepwise deletions within the paired domain provided two key findings: (i) the C-terminal subdomain of the paired domain does not play a major role in the regulation of the homeodomain DNA-binding and (ii) the N-terminal subdomain and, in particular, the second alpha-helix are essential for the modulation of homeodomain DNA-binding. In addition to intermolecular interactions, the functional association with other transcription factors can also modulate Pax-3 target gene selection and regulation. We found that Pax-3 can recruit PEA3, a member of the ETS family, to form a ternary complex with DNA sequences containing either a paired domain or homeodomain recognition site and a sub-optimal Ets site to which PEA3 normally does not bind. We have</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gros, Philippe</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000179c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj813</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anz806154z"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nuclear transport of heat shock proteins in stressed cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chughtai, Zahoor</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nuclear import of proteins that are too large to passively enter the nucleus requires soluble factors, energy, and a nuclear localization signal (NLS). Nuclear protein transport can be regulated, and different forms of stress affect nucleocytoplasmic trafficking. As such, import of proteins containing a classical NLS is inhibited in starving yeast cells. In contrast, the heat shock protein hsp70 Ssa4p concentrates in nuclei upon starvation. Nuclear concentration of Ssa4p in starving cells is reversible, and transfer of nutrient-depleted cells to fresh medium induces Ssa4p nuclear export. This export reaction represents an active process that is sensitive to oxidative stress. Upon starvation, the N-terminal domain of Ssa4p mediates Ssa4p nuclear accumulation, and a short hydrophobic sequence, termed Star (for starvation), is sufficient to localize the reporter proteins green fluorescent protein or beta-galactosidase to nuclei. To determine whether nuclear accumulation of Star-beta-galactosidase depends on a specific nuclear carrier, I have analyzed its distribution in mutant yeast strains that carry a deletion of a single beta-importin gene. With this assay I have identified Nmd5p as a beta-importin required to concentrate Star-beta-galactosidase in nuclei of stationary phase cells.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stochaj, Ursula</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838221h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806154z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1z40kv552"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Frequency-dependent actions of GABA enhancing anticonvulsant drugs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jackson, Michael F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The contribution of use-dependence to the actions of two novel antiepileptic drugs acting upon the GABA neurotransmitter system was investigated using the rat hippocampal slices preparation. The first study of this thesis demonstrated that tiagabine, a GABA uptake blocker, causes a more pronounced increase of GABAergic responses evoked by high-frequency stimulation (HFS) than of those elicited by a single stimulus. The predominant effect of tiagabine on HFS-evoked responses was to facilitate the generation of GABAA receptor-mediated depolarizations (DRs) which were capable of triggering bursts of action potentials when evoked from the stratum radiatum. Since these results suggested that tiagabine may paradoxically promote rather than inhibit epileptiform discharges, the second study investigated the functional consequences of tiagabine-augmented DRs. Consistent with our observation of enhanced inhibition following HFS, the amplitude of evoked EPSPs superimposed upon tiagabine-augmented DRs were markedly reduced and could no longer trigger action potentials. A similar inhibitory effect on evoked EPSCs was also observed. The large conductance increase associated with the occurrence of DRs suggests that tiagabine can reduce the depolarizing influence of excitatory transmission by increasing the effectiveness of GABA-mediated shunting inhibition. In the third study of this thesis, the effects of gamma-vinyl GABA (GVG, vigabatrin) were investigated in slices prepared from animals pretreated with either an anticonvulsant dose of GVG or saline. GVG pretreatment produced a frequency-dependent strengthening of GABA-mediated transmission such that repetitive stimulation at low-frequencies (2.5--10 Hz) was no longer associated with a depression of inhibition. A reduced sensitivity of evoked IPSCs to the actions of baclofen, a GABAB receptor agonist, suggests that GVG may have produced its frequency-dependent effects by depressing the efficacy of the GABA release regulating negative feedback mechanisms through the presynaptic GABAB autoreceptors. In the final study of this thesis, the acute effects of bath applied GVG on GABAergic inhibition were examined. GVG (100--500 muM) caused a concentration-dependent disinhibitory effect which did not appear to be mediated through an antagonism of postsynaptic GABAA receptors. These results suggest that to acute actions of GVG, distinct from those mediated through is inactivation of GABA-T, do not contribute to the anticonvulsant properties of this drug. In conclusion, to results presented suggest that both tiagabine and GVG produce use-dependent increases in inhibition, an effect which may importantly contribute to their anticonvulsant properties.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Capek, Radan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sf340.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kv552</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am900nw29v"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>New space technology : regulatory challenges for the International Telecommunication Union</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Patterson, Angus, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This work examines the effect of three emerging satellite technologies on the use and regulation of what might be called Earth Orbital Space. The three new technologies, Direct Broadcasting Satellites (DBS), Global Mobile Personal Communication Services (GMPCS), and Global Navigation Satellite Services (GNSS), are being implemented in or planned for different portions of Earth Orbital Space: the geostationary orbit, low earth orbits, and medium earth orbits, respectively. Each technology creates different challenges for the International Telecommunication Union which is the organization charged with their regulation. DBS services were regulated in the 1970s and early 1980s prior to their practical use. That early regulation appears, today, to be overly restrictive in many ways. GMPCS, on the other hand, is now becoming a reality but lacks a solid legal structure to ensure that its potential for global wireless communication can be achieved. GNSS provides yet a different challenge: that of providing for the civil utilization of military navigation systems. The deployment of these new technologies add to the increasing problem of congestion in the orbit-spectrum resource. The final chapter details a number of different proposals aimed at increasing both equity and efficiency in the management of the orbit-spectrum resource.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vlasic, I.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df20g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw29v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kp75b"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Validation of a compartmental model of the kinetic behaviour of radiolabelled L-3,4-dihydroxyphenylalanine (L-dopa) in living brain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Deep, Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research details two experiments that together establish the legitimacy of a compartmental model which describes the cerebral uptake and metabolism of radiolabelled L-dopa in vivo. First, tissue radioactivities calculated with the model were compared with corresponding radioactivities measured previously by chromatographic fractionation of 18F-labelled metabolites in striatal tissue extracts from rats given intravenous injections of L-6-[ 18F]fluorodopa. Second, kinetic constants estimated by model fitting to measured radioactivities from combined metabolite pools in a time-series of static autoradiograms from right cerebral hemispheres of rats administered [3H]dopa, were compared to corresponding previously published estimates based on analyses of measured radioactivities from individual metabolite pools separated by chromatographic fractionation of 3H-labelled metabolites in the left cerebral hemispheres of the same rats. These comparisons confirmed quantitatively the biological accuracy of the model, thus validating the compartmental modelling of autoradiographic data for investigations of the kinetic behaviour of radiolabelled L-dopa in living brain.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cumming, Paul</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p634x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp75b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25xb17b"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cortical regulation of the meso-nucleus accumbens dopamine stress response</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Doherty, Michael, 1964-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is well established that stress will stimulate dopamine (DA) release in the nucleus accumbens (NAcc). That NAcc DA transmission increases in response to stress is of interest given the postulated involvement of this transmitter in the pathophysiology of schizophrenia. It has been speculated that hyperactivity of DA cells that innervate limbic regions, including NAcc, underlie the positive symptoms associated with this disease, including exaggerated responses to stress. Understanding the mechanisms by which stress can stimulate NAcc DA release, mechanisms which are currently unclear, thus has potential clinical implications. One likely source of influence on meso-NAcc DA function is the DA projection to the prefrontal cortex (PFC), acting through descending excitatory amino acid projections to the meso-NAcc DA system. The meso-PFC DA pathway, itself potently activated by stress, has been implicated both in cognitive functions, and the negative symptomatology associated with schizophrenia. The focus of this thesis was to investigate the potential involvement of the meso-PFC DA system in modulating stress-induced DA release in NAcc. The results of these studies have helped to clarify the circuitry by which meso-NAcc DA transmission is influenced. At the cortical level we demonstrated that DA released in PFC during stress can influence the activity of prefrontal cortical output neurons that project to NAcc, or to DA cell bodies in the ventral tegmental area (VTA), either through a direct, inhibitory action, or indirectly by dampening the inhibitory tone provided by GABA interneurons in PFC. Furthermore, PFC GABA may also affect cortical output indirectly, through presynaptic modulation of stress-induced DA release in this region. The present results also indicate that excitatory amino acids (EAAs) acting at NMDA receptors in NAcc exert an inhibitory influence on stress-induced DA release in both NAcc and VTA. These results suggest that EAAs do not exert a direct effect on DA terminals as has been previously suggested, but instead act on NMDA receptors located on NAcc output neurons, likely GABAergic, that project directly or indirectly to the cell bodies of the mesocorticolimbic DA system. This hypothesis is further supported by the results of our final study, in which manipulation of GABA receptors in the VTA was shown to regulate the NAcc DA stress response. The results of these studies provide novel information on how the meso-NAcc DA stress response is regulated, and indicate several possible sources which may contribute to the altered functioning of ascending DA systems that has been suggested to underlie the pathophysiology of several neuro-affective disorders, including schizophrenia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grattor, Alan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741t46c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb17b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z2572"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular characterization of methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase deficiency</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Goyette, Philippe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR) catalyses the conversion of 5, 10-methylenctetrahydrofolate to 5-methyltetrahydrofolate, co-substrate of methionine synthesis. Two types of deficiency have been described for MTHFR. Severe MTHFR deficiency, associated with severe hyperhomocysteinemia and homocystinuria, shows levels of MTHFR activity below 20% of control values. This deficiency has a variable age of onset and shows a wide range of neurological and vascular defects. Mild MTHFR deficiency, with ≈50% enzyme activity and marked enzyme thermolability, has been proposed as a genetic factor in the development of mild hyperhomocysteinemia, a condition associated with neural tube defects and premature vascular disease. The goal of this thesis was to determine the molecular basis for severe MTHFR deficiency. In order to study this, I isolated a 1.2 Kb partial cDNA encoding human MTHFR I determined that its primary amino acid sequence is homologous to the bacterial enzyme, and encodes the N-terminal catalytic domain of MTHFR. The cDNA was used to isolate a full length 2.27 Kb cDNA, to map the locus to chromosome position 1p36.3, and to isolate genomic clones for human and mouse MTHFR. I characterized the mouse cDNA sequence, as well as the gene structure for both human and mouse genes. I observed 90% identity at the amino acid level, almost identical sizes of exons and location of introns, and similar sizes of introns. The exon sizes ranged from 102bp to 432bp, and intron sizes varied from 250bp to 4.2Kb. I identified 13 mutations in severe MTHFR deficiency: 10 missense mutations, 1 nonsense mutation, and 2 splicing defects. I determined that a previously-identified common variant (an Ala →Val mutation) was causative of thermolability in severe MTHFR deficiency. I showed a correlation between genotype, residual activity and phenotype in this disease. I also correlated the presence of another genetic defect, Factor V Leiden mutation, with the possible development of thrombo-embolic events in MTHFR deficiency patients. Finally, I analyzed 8 MTHFR mutations in a bacterial expression system. I determined that 4 of these caused significant reduction of activity (below 20% of control). This thesis contains the first reports of genetic defects in folate metabolism, and a review of available data in severe MTHFR deficiency.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rozen, Rima</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q28p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z2572</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Folic acid deficiency</dc:subject><dc:subject>Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b781n"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Articulating human hands and manipulating objects in virtual environments</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Slavkoff, Evgeny</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis research addresses the problem of human representation in virtual environments (VE). Previous work done on Virtual Reality (ESOPE-RV) lacks an interface to produce dynamic, real-time interactive simulated human representation. The goal of this research was to create the McGill Virtual Operator as a stand alone, independent software application interfacing the Human Operator with various synthetic worlds. For the lower body, including the feet we use pedals to perform the navigation in VE giving a locomotive motion which is simple and acceptable. However, the upper body motion and especially the human hand articulation is much more complex because humans interact with the environment largely with their hands. The approach taken in this thesis is to develop an interactive interface which achieves dynamic real-time hand manipulation while not encumbering the user. The interface is based on two inexpensive data gloves and commercially available six degree of freedom sonar sensor technology and various routines and kinematics algorithms. The result of this work is the creation of a human body interface focused on hand manipulation as a McGill Virtual Operator which can be incorporated for use in any large-scale interactive VE. Ultrasonic sensors are strapped onto each arm of the user, to read their position and orientation. The motion of the fingers is recorded by the data gloves and the information is transmitted to software, which in turn replicates the same motion of the computer human hands in real-time. Experiments were carried out using a collection of fourteen tools designed for the WITS training environment. The performance results of these interactive extensions to the VR environment was evaluated and found to be satisfactory. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Malowany, Alfred</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bz92r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b781n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vm67x"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The longer term effect of early dietary cholesterol on cholesterol metabolism in infants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bayley, Timothy M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La synthese endogene du cholesterol (CH) a ete etudie chez 81 nouveau-nes, ages de 4 mois (BRAS 1) ou de 11 a 12 mois (BRAS2), afin d'evaluer les effets a long terme d'un supplement de CH sur l'homeostasie du CH. BRAS 1 etait compose de 32 nouveau-nes recevant soit du lait humain (HUM) (6M, 7F), une formule a base de lait de vache (VAC) (6M, 3F) contenant 3.5 mg CH/dl, ou une formule a base de lait de vache modifiee (VACM) (6M, 7F) contenant 13.5 mg CH/dl, afin d'evaluer l'effet du supplement sur les taux de synthese du CH. BRAS2 etait compose de 49 autres enfants recevant soit HUM (11M, 6F), VAC (7M, 12F) ou VACM (6M, 7F) jusqu'a l'age de 6 mois dans le but d'evaluer une hypothese d'impression genetique. Ceci a ete realise en utilisant un design "cross-over" et en montant un defi journalier de 250 g de CH a l'age de 11 mois. Le taux d'incorporation de deuterium, provenant des reserves d'eau corporelle, dans la structure du CH a servi comme indice du taux de synthese fractionnel (TSF) de ce dernier sur une periode de 48 heures. Les niveaux de CH total et LDL etaient considerablement eleves dans HUM en comparaison avec VAC et VACM a l'age de 4 mois. La concentration sanguine du CH etait semblable a 11 et 12 mois. Le TSF etait 4 fois plus eleve dans VAC et VACM relatif a HUM, mais il n'y avait pas de difference entre VAC et VACM a 11 et 12 mois. Cependant, les TSF de 4 a 12 mois ont augmente dans HUM et baisse dans VAC et VACM. Nos resultats indiquent qu'independamment du contenu des dietes, le defi journalier de CH n'as pas eu d'effet considerable ni sur les taux de synthese, ni sur les niveaux de CH sanguin. Ces resultats appuient l'idee que le CH alimentaire n'a que des effets minimes sur le metabolisme a long terme du CH.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jones, Peter J. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731560r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vm67x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Infants -- Nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cholesterol -- Metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613n030j"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biochemical and genomic analysis of -galactosidases from Bifidobacterium infantis HL96</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hung, Ming-Ni, 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Among 29 strains of bifidobacteria studied as sources of beta-galactosidase enzyme, Bifidobacterium infantis HL96 showed the highest hydrolytic and transgalactosylic activities. This strain grew well in a MRS medium containing various sugars including lactose, and produced three beta-galactosidases (termed beta-Gal I, II, III). Two genes, beta-galI and beta-galIII, located on 4.6 and 4.4 kb DNA fragments respectively, were cloned into E. coli, and the nucleotide sequences were determined. The 3,069 by-long beta-galI, encoded a polypeptide with a Mr of 113 kDa. A putative ribosome-binding site and a promoter sequence were recognized at the 5' flanking region of beta-galI. A partial sequence of an ORF transcribing divergently from beta-galI resembled a lactose permease gene. The beta-galIII gene, which is 2,076 bp long, encoded a polypeptide with a Mr of 76 kDa. A rho-independent, transcription terminator-like sequence was found 25 bp downstream of the termination codon. The amino acid sequences of beta-GalI and beta-GalIII were homologous to those in the LacZ and LacG families, respectively. The acid-base, nucleophilic, and substrate recognition sites conserved in the LacZ family were found in beta-GalI, and a possible acid-base site proposed for the LacG family was located in beta-GalIII, containing a glutamate at residue 160. beta-GalI and beta-GalIII were over-expressed 35 and 96 times respectively in E. coli by using a pET expression system. Both beta-GalI and beta-GalIII were specific for beta-D -anomeric linked galactosides, but beta-GalI showed more hydrolytic and synthetic activities toward lactose than beta-GalIII. The galacto-oligosaccharides (GaOS) production mediated by beta-GalI at 37°C in 20% (w/v) lactose was 130 mg/ml, which is six times higher than that of beta-GalIII. The yield of GaOS further increased to 190 mg/ml in 30% (w/v) lactose. A major tri-saccharide produced by beta-GalI was characterized as O-beta- D-galactopyranosyl-(1-3)-O-beta-D-galactopyranosyl-(1-4)- D-glucopyranose. beta-GalI was purified by ammonium sulphate precipitation, and anion-exchange (Mono-Q) and gel filtration (Superose 12) chromatographic steps. The enzyme appeared to be a tetramer, with a Mr of 470 kDa as estimated by native PAGE and gel-filtration chromatography. The optimum temperature and pH for ONPG and lactose as substrates were 60°C, pH 7.5, and 50°C, pH 7.5, respectively. The enzyme was stable over the pH range of 5~8.5, and was particularly active at 50°C for more than 80 min. The enzyme was significantly activated by reducing agents, especially glutathione, as well as by Na+ and K+ cations. Maximal activity required both Na+ and K+ at a concentration of 10 mM. The enzyme was strongly inhibited by p-chloromercuribenzoic acid, and by most bivalent metal ions. Hydrolytic activity using 20 mM lactose as substrate was significantly inhibited by 10 mM galactose. The Km and Vmax values for ONPG and lactose were 2.6 mM, 262 U/mg, and 73.8 mM, 1.28 U/mg, respectively. The objectives of this research were to characterize beta-galactosidases of B. infantis HL96 at the molecular and biochemical levels, and to over-express the enzymes in Escherichia coli. Two beta-galactosidase isoenzymes with unique properties were genetically characterized for the first time. beta-GalI properties included a neutral pH optimum, relatively higher temperature stability and a high transgalactosylic activity that makes it very competitive for GaOS synthesis. The results were also important for the advancement of knowledge on the catalytic mechanism and the evolutionary aspect of this enzyme.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lee, Byong H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g447b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n030j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lactose -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Beta-galactosidase -- Analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bifidobacterium infantis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8p58pf58t"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Global and local perception in autism : the role of basic and higher-order attention</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Iarocci, Grace</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study focused on specific conceptual, methodological and developmental issues pertinent to investigating the role of attention in global-local processing among high-functioning children with autism (average verbal mental age (MA) of 89 months and nonverbal MA of 116 months) as compared to their verbal and nonverbal MA matched peers. Two experiments were conducted to assess separately basic processing; focal attention that is drawn by the physical properties of the stimuli and higher-order processing associated with strategically directing attention in accordance with the observer's priorities within a given task. These components of attention are implicated in the typical development of global-local perceptual organization. In Experiment 1, a visual search task was used to explore the role of basic focal attention to perceptually group dots at either a long or short spatial range. In Experiment 2, a visual search and target identification task was used to assess higher-order voluntary control of attention to the global or the local level of a hierarchical geometric pattern. To assess changes in voluntary attending to a specific target level, an implicit manipulation of increased probability of the target appearing at the global or local level or equally at both levels was included. The main finding was that high-functioning children with autism and their verbal and nonverbal MA matched peers showed comparable focused attention to perceptually organize stimuli over a short or long spatial range but different higher-order attentional processing of hierarchical global-local targets. In all groups, search efficiency for long range targets decreased as a function of display size but the search for short range targets was efficient regardless of display size. Long range grouping performance involves goal-driven, focused attention that is constrained by serial inspection whereas the short range grouping performance implicates a sensory-driven, preattentive spatial-indexing mechanism. At higher levels of attentional control, high-functioning children with autism show a preference for using a local attentional strategy whereas their typically developing peers rely on a global attentional strategy to search for hierarchical global-local targets among distractors. The particular style of visual processing used to search for targets was not influenced by implicit changes in the probability of a target appearing at the local or global level. The findings support the interpretation that a perceptual disturbance in global-local processing in persons with autism may be associated with different higher-order strategy-based processing rather than an enhanced ability to integrate features.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burack, Jacob A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pj00h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pf58t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Autism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Autism in children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Perception</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2r36v0222"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structural and nutritional properties of whey proteins as affected by hyperbaric pressure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hosseini Nia, Tahereh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Hyperbaric pressure has been shown to affect the secondary structure of whey proteins such as beta-lactoglobulin (beta-lg). There is limited research, however, regarding the optimal conditions by which pressurization of whey proteins could lead to irreversible changes in secondary structure including the reduction of intramolecular disulfide bonds. Irreversible changes in protein conformation and breakage of disulfide bonds of whey proteins induced by high pressure might result in an increase in their digestibility and a reduction of allergenicity. Hence, the overall objective was to explore the capability of hyperbaric pressure to alter irreversibly the secondary structure of whey proteins and thereby alter their allergenic and nutritional properties. The behaviour of different genetic variants of beta-lg was studied employing variable-pressure Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy to establish the optimum pressures needed for their denaturation. The results showed reversible effects of pressures up to 12.0 kbar on the secondary structure of three main genetic variants of beta-lg. The individual response of the genetic variants to pressure was distinguishable despite their subtle structural differences. Pressure-induced conformational changes were studied separately in bovine serum albumin, Ca++-saturated alpha-lactalbumin and Ca ++-free alpha-lactalbumin by FTIR spectroscopy. The studies revealed that the presence of Ca++ ion and the number of disulfide bonds protects the protein molecules against pressure. As whey proteins appeared to be resistant to denaturation upon single applications of high pressure up to 1200 MPa, we developed a novel pressure processing using a combination of pulse and continuous modes at lower pressures of 400 MPa which led to irreversible denaturation of whey protein structure and disulphide bond breakage. Weanling rats fed with whey protein isolates treated by this novel low pressure processing technique showed enhanced grow</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kubow, Stan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t368f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v0222</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>High pressure (Technology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Globular proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Whey products</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75df221"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structural equation modeling by extended redundancy analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hwang, Heungsun, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new approach to structural equation modeling based on so-called extended redundancy analysis (ERA) is proposed. In ERA, latent variables are obtained as exact linear combinations of observed variables, and model parameters are estimated by consistently minimizing a single criterion. As a result, the method can avoid limitations of covariance structure analysis (e.g., stringent distributional assumptions, improper solutions, and factor score indeterminacy) in addition to those of partial least squares (e.g., the lack of a global optimization procedure). The method is simple yet versatile enough to fit more complex models; e.g., those with higher-order latent variables and direct effects of observed variables. It can also fit a model to more than one sample simultaneously. Other relevant topics are also discussed, including data transformations, missing data, metric matrices, robust estimation, and efficient estimation. Examples are given to illustrate the proposed method.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Takane, Yoshio</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rz35v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df221</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social sciences -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social sciences -- Statistical methods</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xt39b"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate School of Library and Information Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Librarianship as a profession : an investigation of Libyan librarians' attitudes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>El Bennani, Fauzia Khalil</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study is to investigate the attitude of Libyan professional librarians towards their profession. The study also seeks to compare attitudes of Libyan professional librarians from culturally diverse rural and urban communities toward librarianship as a profession. The diversity here refers to the distinctive characteristics of the two communities, which include social life style, values, hierarchies of values and attitude. It is also the purpose of this research to compare the attitudes of Libyan male and female professional librarians towards their profession. Another purpose of this study is to investigate if working in different types of libraries such as academic, public and special will have a different effect on Libyan professional librarians' attitudes towards their profession. The population of this study consisted of all Libyan librarians who at the time were employed in academic and special libraries, and all Libyan librarians who at the time were employed in public libraries that are located in the Tripolitanian area. Thornton's scale to measure librarians' attitudes towards librarianship was selected to be used in this study. In order to determine whether the instrument (scale) items possess the desired qualities of measurement and discriminability when used in different settings (Libyan libraries) and with different subjects, (Libyan librarians) and in order to revise and debug the scale by diagnosing and correcting failings, if any, the following steps were taken: (1) Refinement of the instrument (interviewing subjects). (2) Validation of the instrument, (construct validity). (3) Reliability of the instrument. (Split half). (4) Translating the instrument into Arabic. (5) Pilot study. A computer utilizing (SPSS) Statistical Package for Social Science was used for analyses and comparison. The study's major findings indicated that: (1) Libyan librarians working in libraries located in urban communities have a significantly higher positive attitude towards their profession than those who work in libraries located in rural communities. (2) Libyan rural librarians' gender has no significant effect on librarians' attitude towards their profession. (3) Libyan female librarians working in libraries located in urban communities have a significantly higher positive attitude towards their profession than Libyan male librarians working in libraries located in urban communities. (4) Libyan male librarians working in libraries located in urban communities have a significantly higher positive attitude towards their profession than Libyan male librarians working in libraries located in rural communities. (5) Library location has no significant effect on Libyan female librarians' attitude towards their profession. (6) Library type has no significant effect on Libyan librarians' attitude towards their profession. (7) Libyan librarians have positive attitudes towards their profession.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rees-Potter, Lorna</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m571n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt39b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Librarians -- Libya -- Attitudes</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5x21th10v"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Wounds : theories of violence in theological discourse</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Faber, Alyda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>My dissertation presents a survey of theories of violence in contemporary theological discourse. I consider four positions that represent a range of current trends within theology: Girardian anthropology, the radical orthodoxy movement, liberation theology, and feminist theology. Rene Girard creates a scientific model of violence as a universal scapegoating mechanism at the origin of all human culture, which he posits as knowledge gained through the revelation of Jesus Christ. A key figure in the radical orthodoxy school, John Milbank, recovers Augustine's theology of history as a narrative of the ontological priority of peace in an attempt to discipline human desire away from its fascination with violence. Latin American theologians argue a similar priority of the peace and justice of the kingdom of God in their rhetoric of revolutionary violence as a defense of a poor majority oppressed by the structural violence of the state. Three feminist theologians, Carter Heyward, Rita Nakashima Brock, and Susan Thistlethwaite, construct an essentialist eros untroubled by violence in order to denounce the abuses of patriarchal sexual violence. These contemporary theologians structure their discussions of violence as a speculative problem within categorical distinctions of good and evil. Their ordered theological systems exclude real negativity, not only from God as a totality of good, but also from humans. Within these theodicies, violence becomes unrepresentable in terms of damage to bodies. I analyze the work of Georges Bataille, a philosopher of religion, as a critical counterpoint to these theories of violence. Bataille's practice of a mysticism of violence disturbs theological assumptions of humanness as intrinsically good and extends the notion of the sacred to include abject flesh and its violence. Bataille's work provides resources for a "poetics of reality," a way for Christian theologians to express negativity---undecidability, ambiguity, disorder, pain, violence, bodily disintegration, death---as part of their religious imagination rather than perceiving it as an external threat to ordered theological systems. A poetics of reality is a practice of attention that lives deeply in human instability and human yearning for God.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Skerrett, K. Roberts</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h30c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21th10v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Violence -- Religious aspects -- Christianity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3j3334008"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The psychosocial functioning of families of adults with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eakin, Laurel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The psychosocial functioning of the families of clinic-referred adults with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) was evaluated in two studies. Study 1 examined the psychiatric and psychological difficulties of married adults with ADHD and their spouses, with a focus on the quality of their marital adjustment and family functioning. Study 2 focused on the prevalence of psychiatric disorders, the psychological functioning, and the social functioning of children with ADHD parents. Results revealed that married adults with ADHD had higher rates of comorbid psychiatric disorders and more psychological distress than non-ADHD control adults. The spouses of adults with ADHD did not differ in rates of psychiatric disorders from the control spouses, however, they reported significantly higher levels of current psychological distress. Greater marital and family dysfunction were reported by adults with ADHD than control adults. The spouses of ADHD adults, however, did not report greater marital and family dysfunction than the spouses of controls. The children of ADHD adults were found to be at high risk for ADHD. Forty-three percent of the children met DSM-IV criteria for the disorder. The children with ADHD were found to have higher rates of comorbid disorders, more psychological difficulties, and significantly poorer social functioning than the control children. The non-ADHD children of ADHD adults were not found to differ from control children on these measures. Having a parent without a psychiatric disorder in the home was found to have a protective effect on behavior problems in the non-ADHD children. Together, these studies suggest that evaluating the functioning of family members and the health of the family relationships are important when assessing clinic-referred adults with ADHD. These results suggest that involving family members in the therapeutic process may be beneficial.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Koestner, Richard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx096.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3334008</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Attention-deficit disorder in adults</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychotherapy patients -- Family relationships</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xn34g"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Walter Stace's philosophy of mysticism : a critical analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fanaei Nematsara, Mohammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mysticism can be examined from various viewpoints: historical, theological, sociological, and psychological. This study primarily examines the philosophical status and implications of mysticism, an issue investigated many times, particularly over the last four decades. Walter T. Stace's work in the early sixties is regarded as a hallmark in the field. The topics covered in this thesis are epistemological, metaphysical and religio-ethical and deal with mystical knowledge, its object, and its method. The characteristics of mystical knowledge, its objectivity or subjectivity, its object/s, its logical status, the way/s it is presented in the language, and its method/s of acquisition are investigated. This study is primarily epistemological, since the central issue is the status of mystical awareness in human knowledge. Since this is a philosophical reflection on mystical experience, the primary sources are mystical writings, mainly from Christian classical mystics, and philosophical writings about mysticism, mainly from twentieth-century Western philosophers. Again since it is a 'philosophical reflection' on 'mystical experience,' this study employs two methods: a historical survey of mystics' ideas, and philosophical reflection on mystics' reports or analysis of contents of mystical text. Since the focus of the study is Stace's account of mysticism, his ideas will be examined in detail. Reference to other mystics and philosophers will be primarily for elaboration, comparison and criticism of Stace's analysis. Instead of merely criticizing Stace's arguments and convictions, this study also offers an alternative account and presents a consistent philosophical analysis of mysticism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boutin, Maurice</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hr40g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xn34g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mysticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Philosophy and religion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stace, W. T. (Walter Terence), 1886-</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514nn06x"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the biological functions of protein tyrosine phosphatase PEST in cellular signaling</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Côté, Jean-François, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Identification of physiological substrates of protein tyrosine phosphatases is a key step in understanding the function of these enzymes. We have generated fibroblast cell lines from PTP-PEST -/- embryos (in which the PTP-PEST gene was targeted by homologous recombinaison in ES cells) in order to identify potential substrates with the premise that specific substrates of this enzyme would exist in a hyperphosphorylated state. Analysis of the profile of the phosphotyrosine proteins in the PTP-PEST -/- cells revealed the presence of hyperphosphorylated proteins of 180, 130 and 97 kDa when compared to control cells. The p130 was identified as p130Cas which is constitutively hyperphosphorylated in cells lacking PTP-PEST. In addition, p130Cas was also isolated by a substrate trapping mutant of PTP-PEST in the PTP-PEST -/- cell lysates. Furthermore, the first proline rich sequence of PTP-PEST interacted with the p130Cas family (also including Hef1 and Sin) via their SH3 domain in vitro. In this part of the work, I have combined genetic and biochemical strategies to allow the identification of PTP-PEST substrates. In the second part of this thesis, I have studied the association of PTP-PEST with another focal adhesion protein, paxillin. I demonstrated that a proline rich segment of PTP-PEST (Pro 2) is essential for this interaction. Conversely, LIM3 and LIM4 domains were found both necessary for binding of PTP-PEST both in vitro and in vivo. Finally, using a "substrate trapping" approach, I showed that unlike p130Cas, paxillin is not a substrate for PTP-PEST. Interestingly, the focal adhesion targeting of paxillin is mediated by LIM 3. Thus we propose that PTP-PEST, by a competition with the unidentified ligand of paxillin in the focal adhesion complex, could contribute to the removal of paxillin from the adhesion sites and consequently promote focal adhesion turnover. In the last part of my work, I tested the hypothesis that PTP-PEST could interact with PSTPIP. Our results show that the association between the two proteins is mediated by the CTH domain of PTP-PEST and the coiled-coil domain of PSTPIP. I tested several pathways that could regulate the tyrosine phosphorylation of PSTPIP and found that EGF and PDGF are potent stimulators in murine fibroblasts. Furthermore, I provided evidence that tyrosine 344 of PSTPIP is a docking site for SH2-containing tyrosine kinases. In this respect, I also demonstrated that PTP-PEST can dephosphorylate PSTPIP at tyrosine 344 thereby regulating the association between SH2 domain containing proteins and PSTPIP.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tremblay, Michel L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451k240.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nn06x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77ft039"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of spatial frequency overlap on face and object recognition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Collin, Charles Alain</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There has recently been much interest in how limitations in spatial frequency range affect face and object perception. This work has mainly focussed on determining which bands of frequencies are most useful for visual recognition. However, a fundamental question not yet addressed is how spatial frequency overlap (i.e., the range of spatial frequencies shared by two images) affects complex image recognition. Aside from the basic theoretical interest this question holds, it also bears on research about effects of display format (e.g., line-drawings, Mooney faces, etc.) and studies examining the nature of mnemonic representations of faces and objects. Examining the effects of spatial frequency overlap on face and object recognition is the main goal of this thesis. A second question that is examined concerns the effect of calibration of stimuli on recognition of spatially filtered images. Past studies using non-calibrated presentation methods have inadvertently introduced aberrant frequency content to their stimuli. The effect this has on recognition performance has not been examined, leading to doubts about the comparability of older and newer studies. Examining the impact of calibration on recognition is an ancillary goal of this dissertation. Seven experiments examining the above questions are reported here. Results suggest that spatial frequency overlap had a strong effect on face recognition and a lesser effect on object recognition. Indeed, contrary to much previous research it was found that the band of frequencies occupied by a face image had little effect on recognition, but that small variations in overlap had significant effects. This suggests that the overlap factor is important in understanding various phenomena in visual recognition. Overlap effects likely contribute to the apparent superiority of certain spatial bands for different recognition tasks, and to the inferiority of line drawings in face recognition. Results concerning the mnemonic representation of faces and objects suggest that these are both encoded in a format that retains spatial frequency information, and do not support certain proposed fundamental differences in how these two stimulus classes are stored. Data on calibration generally shows non-calibration having little impact on visual recognition, suggesting moderate confidence in results of older studies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chaudhuri, Avi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55md54m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft039</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Space perception</dc:subject><dc:subject>Face perception</dc:subject><dc:subject>Visual perception</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dr30h"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Root and canopy characteristics of maize types with extreme architectures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Costa, Carlos</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Studies of corn root morphology, canopy description, light and nutrient relationships, have focused on conventional corn hybrids. We are now extending these studies to other corn types with contrasting canopy and root architectures. Field and greenhouse experiments were carried out in order to characterize root morphology, N status in the plant and its relationship with yield and yield components, canopy architecture and light interception of these genotypes. The indoor experiments investigated root morphology and how N affects it. Root fractal geometry and its relationship with standard measured root variables were investigated. The field research, at two sites and over two growing seasons, examined (i) maize canopy architecture with regard to light interception and (ii) nitrogen effects on grain yield of different maize genotypes. Four genotypic types were included: (i) Leafy reduced-stature, Lfy1rd1 (LRS), (ii) non Leafy-reduced stature, lfyrd1 (NLRS), (iii) Leafy normal stature, Lfy1Rd1 (LNS), and (iv) conventional commercial hybrids, lfy1Rd1. Pioneer 3905 served as the check hybrid for late maturity, and Pioneer 3979, the check for early maturity. The work allowed development of following methods: (i) root sampling for measurement of large root systems, (ii) staining to enhance root contrast for measurement with a scanner-based software system, (iii) sample size determination for SPAD meter readings, and (iv) the design and construction of a mobile and multi-strata device for measurement of light interception. Data were collected for mathematical characterization of canopies (i.e. leaf angle, co-ordinates of the maximum height of the leaf, co-ordinates of the leaf tip), plant N status (SPAD meter readings), light interception, yield and grain yield components. Conventional hybrids generally showed greater root length and surface area than their leafy genotypic counterparts at early developmental stages (i.e. up to 15 days from emergence). However, Leafy geno</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt41c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr30h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Corn -- Roots -- Anatomy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fractals</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rw157"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Where have all the Canadians gone? : frame resonance, transformation and institutionalization of the Canadianization movement, 1968-1985</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cormier, Jeffrey, 1967-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Social movements are an understudied aspect of Canadian society. This thesis is an attempt to address this general lacuna by examining the social movement efforts of Canadian cultural nationalists during the 1960s and 1970s, as they struggled to build a strong, vibrant Canadian cultural community. Four social movement based questions guide the analysis. First, why did the Canadianization movement begin when it did? Second, how did the movement transform itself for long-term survival? Third, what kinds of mobilizing structures did the movement make use of, and what influence did these structures have on the movement's activities? And finally, how did the movement maintain itself in times when the political and media climate was unreceptive? This thesis addresses these questions with the combined use of data collected from archival sources as well as twenty-two interviews. The case of Canadianization permits us to empirically document the actions that organizational intellectuals take in pushing for social and cultural change, an aspect of the social movements literature that, until now, has been largely only theorized about.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>van den Berg, Axel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w652s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw157</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Canada -- Intellectual life -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Cultural policy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3t945s56q"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comparing mandibular 2-implant overdentures and conventional dentures : phychosocial and functional outcomes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Awad, Manal A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Using mandibular 2-Implant overdentures is an alternative therapy for edentulous patients. Several studies have been conducted to evaluate the efficacy of this treatment modality compared to conventional dentures. However, most of these studies have emphasized the evaluation of the clinical aspects of the prostheses or did not use standardized specific patient based-outcomes. Therefore, the main objectives of this research was to investigate the effect of using mandibular 2-implant supported prostheses and conventional dentures on oral health related quality of life, using a randomised controlled clinical trial design. The secondary objectives were to assess the factors that explained patients' satisfaction with their prostheses and to evaluate the association between ratings of satisfaction, ability to chew and laboratory tests of masticatory efficiency according to treatment received. In addition, the association between patients' pretreatment preference and general satisfaction with original prostheses was explored, as well as the possible effect of pretreatment preferences on post treatment satisfaction. One hundred and two female and male subjects between the ages of 35--65 years responded to a newspaper advertisement for patients who wished to replace their current prostheses. Forty-eight subjects were randomly assigned to receive conventional denture and 54 to the implant group. Prior to treatment, subjects were asked to indicate which treatment they would prefer if given a choice. Patients' ratings of general satisfaction were evaluated with their original prostheses and two months after receipt of the new treatments using 100mm Visual Analogue Scales (VAS). Similarly, subject's quality of life was assessed using the Oral Health Impact Profile (OHIP), prior to and two months after receipt of the new prostheses. Multivariate regression analysis showed that subjects in the implant group had significantly higher ratings of general satisfaction (p &lt; 0.05) as well as, with their general ability to chew, stability and comfort compared to those who received mandibular conventional dentures. In addition, subjects in the implant group were significantly more satisfied with their ability to chew specific foods with different textures. To the contrary, no significant differences were observed between the two groups using laboratory measures of masticatory efficiency. Furthermore, patients who received implant treatment had significantly lower OHIP scores (p &lt; 0.05) indicating better quality of life compared to subjects in the conventional group. In this trial age, gender, level of education, income and marital status were not significantly associated with either ratings of satisfaction or quality of life. Although patients' preferences were significantly associated with their ratings of satisfaction with original prostheses, preferences did not have a significant effect on post-treatment oral health related quality of life or satisfaction. Overall, the results of this study suggest that, after two months of adaptation, a prosthesis supported by two osseointegrated implants provided significant improvement in oral health related quality of life and satisfaction compared to a conventional denture.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Feine, Jocelyne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225c70g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s56q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149r329"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of women in economic development : case studies of Taiwan, Indonesia and the Philippines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bahramitash, Roksana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The evidence presented in this thesis supports the view that men and women participate in the labour force in qualitatively distinct ways and that, as a result, policies to increase female employment in the formal economy have an impact on economic development that is quite different from those whose aim is simply to increase employment with no regard to its gender composition. While it is well known that women's work is often underreported and undercounted, the thesis contends that women's "work" is also frequently defined incorrectly. From the point of view of development policy it is necessary to define women's work as embracing not only "productive" labour done for monetary gain, but also reproductive and volunteer work which, though not directly remunerated, have important feedbacks on other social, political and economic variables. Those feedbacks in turn may determine the success or failure of a particular "development" strategy. This theory is applied to three "Asian miracle" developing countries, chosen because of their widely varied cultural, political and economic history and structures. The methodology employed is eclectic. Too often social research is bogged down in disputes between those who favour quantitative and those who favour historical-institutional analysis. In reality, especially when dealing with developing countries where there are serious problems of data quality, these two approaches can be mutually complementary. Therefore, in undertaking a comparative study of three cases, the thesis employs quantitative, historical-institutional and anthropological data along with information derived from interviews and field work. The thesis demonstrates ample support for the hypothesis that women's labour has an importance over and above simply more hands at work, that the particular characteristics of female labour, not only produce direct payoffs in terms of development of certain types of manufacturing industries, but many indirect ones in terms of social variables like reduced fertility, increased life expectancy and greater educational attainment. However it also demonstrates that full actualization of these benefits in terms of economic prosperity, improved social welfare, and ultimately political democratization requires a state that is both willing and able (two distinct things) to implement social and economic policies designed explicitly to promote female employment in the formal economy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Smith, Micheal</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zs421.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r329</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women in development -- Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women in development -- Philippines</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women in development -- Taiwan</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655j26p"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anatomy, functional morphology and phylogeny of Aistopoda (Tetrapoda, Lepospondyli)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anderson, Jason S., 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The importance of fossils to phylogenetic reconstruction is well established. However, analyses of fossil data sets are confounded by problems related to the incomplete nature of the specimens. Taxa that are incompletely known are problematic because of the uncertainty of their placement within a tree, leading to a proliferation of most parsimonious solutions because of wild card behavior. Problematic taxa are commonly deleted based on a priori criteria of completeness. Paradoxically, a taxon's problematic behavior is tree dependent, and levels of completeness are not necessarily associated with problematic behavior. Exclusion of taxa based on completeness eliminates real character conflict and, by not allowing incomplete taxa to determine tree topology, the phylogenetic hypothesis is diminished. A method is proposed to allow optimization of taxonomic inclusion and tree stability. It identifies and removes taxa causing multiple most parsimonious solutions, producing a more stable topology, called the phylogenetic trunk. This method is used in an analysis of the Paleozoic Lepospondyli. A single most parsimonious tree, or trunk, was found after removal of one taxon identified as being problematic. The 38 trees found one additional step from this primary trunk are reduced to two by removal of one additional taxon. These trunks are compared to the trees found by excluding taxa with various degrees of completeness. Effects of incomplete taxa are explored by comparison with the stable tree. Correlated characters associated with limblessness are discussed regarding the assumption of character independence. Inclusion of intermediate taxa is found to be the single best method for breaking down long branches.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carroll, Robert L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pp67d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655j26p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Phlegethontiidae</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ophiderpetontidae</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lethiscidae</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aistopoda</dc:subject><dc:subject>Amphibians, Fossil</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>