<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53wx393"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>System level diagnosis and wafer testing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Huang, Kaiyuan, 1954-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis consists of two relate but self-sustaining parts. In Part I a new diagnosability measure, t/ $-$ 1-diagnosability, is proposed for interconnected systems. This new diagnosability assures that all faulty units, except for at most one, can be correctly identified in one step, as long as the total number of faulty units does not exceed t. The class of t/ $-$ 1-diagnosable systems is fully characterized. A polynomial algorithm is presented for determining the degree of t/ $-$ 1-diagnosability for any given system. A polynomial diagnosis algorithm is also given for any t/ $-$ 1-diagnosable systems. It is shown that the degree of t/ $-$ 1-diagnosability could be twice as large as the degree of t-diagnosability for a given system. In Part II a probabilistic diagnosis algorithm is presented for constant degree structures such as grids. It is shown that almost all faulty units can be correctly identified under a binomial failure distribution even when the probability of failure is rather high. The performance is very insensitive to yield variations under a negative binomial failure distribution. The application of this algorithm to the production testing of chips and wafers is explored. A simple test structure is provided for wafer testing, which utilizes the test access port of each die to facilitate comparison testing. The diagnosis algorithm is localized and incorporated into the test structure to determine the status of each die. The scheme is unique in that it is shown to work well when faults are clustered and even when the yield is low.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Agarwal, V. K.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Thalasiraman, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354g89z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx393</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hb348"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Manganese-Bismuth prepared by rapid solidification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guo, Xiaoming</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The low temperature phase (LTP) of MnBi, an interesting material with large magnetic anisotropy, has been obtained for the first time in bulk quantities in almost single-phase form ($&gt;$95$ sp{wt}$%) by melt-spinning, followed by annealing. X-ray, electron microscope and differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) studies indicate that the melt-spun MnBi is amorphous, and may be phase separated. A mechanism is suggested for the glass formation in MnBi. Upon heating, amorphous MnBi first crystallizes around 440 K, then forms LTP around 540 K. DSC and thermomagnetometry studies show that the LTP transforms to high temperature phase around 630 K through two separate processes: a composition transition and a magneto-structural transition. The anisotropy field, $H sb{a}$ of LTP, is measured from 147 to 586 K by a pulsed magnet combined with the singular point detection technique (SPD). $H sb{a}$ increases with temperature, and reaches a maximum value of 9 T at 530 K. The critical field for spin reversal of a ferrimagnetic phase of MnBi is also detected by SPD from 80 to 200 K, reaching a maximum value of 8 T at 120 K. The coercivity of LTP is successfully described by a model of domain wall pinning which predicts, at 300 K, a domain wall energy of 15.7 $erg/cm sp2$ and a wall thickness of 70 A.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Altounian, Zaven</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Strom-Olsen, John O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9675243.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb348</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Analytical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Physical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fq536"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Both sides now : gender relations in credit and agriculture cooperatives in rural Haiti</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Akman, Geraldine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation applies the theoretical perspective of gender relations and develops methods to understand and analyze the movement of women from the center of social systems to its margins when these systems are undergoing rapid socio-economic and political change. This research responded to the pressing need for the application of newer, more appropriate theoretical and methodological perspectives to examine shifting power relations between women and men in areas undergoing transformation. In the case study, I investigate the locus of power in a system of cooperatives in the Departement du Nord, Haiti and discover how and why female members are being relegated to the periphery of this development programme. I find that a system of gender-based social power is causing unequal opportunities and oppressive power relations for female members in the cooperatives. I analyze how and why this system of social power causes conflict when the interests of female and male members differ in the cooperatives and I explore strategies for change. This dissertation also contributes to a greater understanding of the power dynamics which exist when one group holds different preferences and practices to the dominant group whose framework is the one considered acceptable in the society.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hills, T. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn39g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fq536</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women in agriculture -- Haiti</dc:subject><dc:subject>Agricultural cooperative credit associations -- Haiti</dc:subject><dc:subject>Man-woman relationships -- Haiti</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021g843"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bioreactor for the conversion of ammonia into L-valine based on microcapsules each containing multienzyme system with cofactor-dextran recycling</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alsugair, Khaled A. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nylon membrane artificial cells were prepared to produce essential amino acids. The artificial cells contained leucine dehydrogenase, glucose dehydrogenase and Dextran-NAD$ sp+.$ These were packed in a column bioreactor to achieve continuous conversion of ammonia into L-valine with simultaneous regeneration of Dextran-NADH. Kinetic analysis showed that diffusion restriction is negligble when batch and packed-bed column bioreactors were used. The limiting step controlling the rate was the chemical reaction. The effect of backmixing on degree of conversion was insignificant. Ammonia conversion varied linearly with the space time in the range of 0.6-30 minutes. The microencapsulated multienzyme system showed higher efficiency when compared with the same enzymes in free solution. The apparent K$ sb{ rm m}$ values of ammonia, NADH, and $ alpha$-ketoisovalerate were 72, 0.03, 1.2 mM respectively. The study showed that it will be more cost effective to use small volume column bioreactor and high flow rate to achieve a high production rate of L-valine.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chang, T. M. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk22j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g843</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hr31h"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lithogeochemistry and geothermobarometry of mineralized cordierite- orthoamphibole and related rocks at Atik Lake, Manitoba, Némiscau and Montauban, Québec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bernier, Louis, 1961-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cordierite-orthoamphibole rocks associated with contrasting polymetallic mineralization occur in a wide range of metamorphic conditions in the Atik Lake, Manitoba, and Nemiscau and Montauban, Quebec, metamorphic terranes. Lithogeochemistry and geothermobarometry investigations using whole rock major, trace and rare earth elements and mineral chemistries have established the chemical and physical changes that occurred during hydrothermal alteration and subsequent regional metamorphism. The Log(Ratio) method, utilizing ratio profiles of the immobile elements $ rm Al sb2O sb3$, TiO$ sb2$, Zr, Nb, Y V and Cr, was designed to identify the protoliths of the metamorphosed altered rocks. Detailed geothermobarometry and textural evidence indicate that cordierite-orthoamphibole rocks in the three terranes formed at peak P-T conditions of ${ sim}2.5$ kbar and ${ sim}55 sp circ$C at Atik Lake (andalusite zone), ${ sim}4.5$ kbar ${ sim}650 sp circ$C at Nemiscau (sillimanite zone), and ${ sim}6.5$ kbar and ${ sim}620 sp circ$C at Montauban (kyanite-sillimanite zone). Cordierite-orthoamphibole rocks in the terranes exhibit a range of bulk chemical compositions with the most Fe-rich occurring in the Atik Lake belt, and the most Mg-rich in the Montauban mine sequence. Mineral assemblages in these rocks were in equilibrium with contrasting sulfide-oxide $ pm$ arsenide fO$ sb2$-fS$ sb2$ buffers: pyrrhotite-ilmenite $ pm$ arsenopyrite $ pm$ lollingite at Atik Lake, pyrrhotite-pyrite-magnetite at Nemiscau, and pyrrhotite-rutile-sphalerite at Montauban. The partitioning of Fe-Mg between cordierite and anthophyllite was studied for use as a geobarometer. The partitioning coefficient ($ rm K sbsp{D}{Fe-Mg}$) is slightly temperature dependant and strongly pressure dependent. This new geobarometer was empirically calibrated using mineral chemistry from the three terranes and from the literature. High $ rm X sb{H sb2O}$ of the metamorphic fluid is required so that the X$ sb{ rm Fe}$ values of the anthophyllite will be in equilibrium under peak P-T conditions with the appropriate sulfide-oxide $ pm$ arsenide assemblage. Metamorphic dehydration of chlorite-rich hydrothermally altered rocks in the three terranes is compatible with the generation of such water-rich fluids during the crystallization of the cordierite-orthoamphibole rocks.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacLean, W. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng23c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr31h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53wx40v"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The ecology of sediment bacteria and hypolimnetic catabolism in lakes : the relative importance of autochthonous and allochthonous organic matter</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schallenberg, Marc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Microbial metabolic activity in the hypolimnia and sediments of lakes drives the recycling of organic matter both through mineralization and the production of microbial biomass, which may be utilized by grazers. A correction factor was developed based on the water content of sediment samples that corrects sediment bacteria microscopic counts for masking due to sediment particles. Using this correction factor, it was found that sediment bacterial biomass in 22 lakes was positively related to an indicator of the rate of allochthonous organic matter input to lakes. However, the total hypolimnetic carbon mineralization rate of lakes, which integrates both sediment and hypolimnetic water column mineralization, was found to be driven mainly by phytoplankton carbon and to occur mainly in the hypolimnetic water column. Indeed, various hypolimnetic and sediment catabolic processes were found to show a strong positive relationship with indicators of autochthonous organic matter standing stocks and production. In no cases were the processes significantly positively correlated with allochthonous organic matter standing stocks. Results of this research show that autochthonous primary production drives carbon recycling in the hypolimnetic water column, with the ultimate fate of this production being determined principally by the hypolimnetic thickness. The main fate of allochthonous organic matter in lakes is to become a major component of sediment organic matter where it likely drives a much slower catabolism due to its recalcitrance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kalff, Jacob</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483k88f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx40v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lake sediments</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bacteria</dc:subject><dc:subject>Humus</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A707959369"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Isolation and characterization of Dictyostelium discoideum genes encoding a common proline-rich region</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Greenwood, Michael T.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>CABP1 is a cAMP-binding protein found in Dictyostelium discoideum. Anti-CABP1 monoclonal antibody cross-reacts with several polypeptides. The gene encoding CABP1, capA, cross-hybridizes to seven genomic fragments on a genomic DNA Southern blot. Clones representing four different capA-related sequences were obtained by screening both cDNA and genomic libraries with the anti-CABP1 monoclonal antibody and with a capA cDNA. Sequence analysis revealed that the structural similarities between CABP1 and two CABP1-related polypeptides are restricted to a region highly enriched for proline, glycine, glutamine, and tyrosine residues. One of these capA-related sequences encodes the p24 actin-binding protein and the other encodes a homologue of human annexin VII. The levels of the p24 transcript were found to decrease in response to the addition of extracellular cAMP and to increase in the presence of the protein synthesis inhibitor cycloheximide. As a preliminary step towards understanding the function of annexin VII, specific antibodies were generated. Immunoblot analysis revealed the existence of two polypeptides with sizes expected for the two products of the alternatively spliced annexin VII encoding gene.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lasko, P.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Tsang, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161781n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/707959369</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dictyostelium discoideum</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53wx414"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Chiroptical properties of Lyotropic (Acetyl)(Ethyl)cellulose liquid crystals</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guo, Jian Xin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>(Acetyl)(ethyl)cellulose (AEC) polymers with an ethyl degree of substitution (DS) of 2.5 and acetyl DS ranging from 0 to 0.5 form chiral nematic liquid crystals in many organic solvents. The chiroptical properties of these lyotropic AEC mesophases are extremely sensitive to the acetyl DS of AEC and the nature of the solvents although the acetyl group and solvents are achiral and all the polymers share the same chiral cellulose backbone. As the acetyl DS increases from 0 to 0.5, the pitch of AEC mesophases in a given solvent varies from a few nanometer to infinity and a reversal of handedness occurs as a compensated degree of acetylation (DA$ sp*$), where the corresponding mesophase is characterized by an infinite pitch and the absence of macroscopic chirality. The value of DA$ sp*$ and the sign of the temperature dependence of pitch depend on the solvent. Achiral dyes dissolved in these AEC mesophases display liquid crystal induced circular dichroism (LCICD), which results from the helicoidal orientation of the dyes by their chiral matrices. The sign and magnitude of the LCICD are correlated with the handedness and pitch of the AEC mesophases. The mechanism for the handedness inversion for lyotropic AEC mesophases with variation in acetyl DS is discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gray, Derek D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96022422.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx414</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Physical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2227mr52s"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le féminisme de Marcel Prévost; ou, l'art de la mystification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Petcoff, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Even though Marcel Prevost was considered neither an author of world magnitude nor even important within the framework of French literature, he interests us from an historical perspective. The discursive tone he uses in his novels conveys a negative vision of feminism that was common in the last century. Prevost expresses within the romantic structure of his novels the unyielding masculine attitude in the face of women's quest for self-assertion. In his novels one cannot escape the tone of domination and control, and the revival of patriarchal power. Always very aware of his popularity as a writer, Prevost sought to instill his doctrine in the most subtle way possible, and while posing as women's ally, he remained true to his ideal of a domineering male. It is only in the light of contemporary thought that we perceive the idealistic structure he was building. We rediscover the likeness of our ancestors, our great grandmothers, real and idealized by a masculine mind. Over the course of Prevost's novels we observe his image of Woman changing from a chaperoned entity to a quasi autonomous being, while retaining, in his eyes, the same mentality. The stereotyped and fixed role given her since time immemorial have left her without the ability to release her shackles and escape her subservient position. Prevost 's language reveals the resistance of a man who foresees the inevitable day when Man will have to hand over to Woman the control over her own destiny. Throughout his works, mostly forgotten today, he exalts the young virgin, the loving wife and the fulfilled mother. Women who deviate from these norms are relegated to the role of degenerate, hysterical or unsound beings. The interplay between the forces of good and evil serves as a model to incite the reader into making the right choice. Prevost's only goal is to redress women's behaviour and help maintain their traditional role. His work strikes a nostalgic note of the past, recalling "la Belle Epoque" when women were imprisoned as much by conventions as by their corsets, while still letting one guess at their charms. Prevost chooses to continue not to see or understand Woman, only to better reinvent her on the wings of his imagination.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chapdelaine, Annick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m01j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mr52s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Prévost, Marcel, 1862-1941</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c432z"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Songs of wisdom and circles of dance : an anthology of hymns by the Satpanth Ismāʻīlī Saint, Pīr Shams</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kassam, Tazim R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation offers for the first time an extensive scholarly translation of an anthology of 106 ginans (sacred hymns) attributed to the Isma'ili saint-composer, Pir Shams. The Ginan tradition is a sacred corpus of devotional poetry belonging to a sub-sect of the Shiah Muslims known as the Satpanth Isma'ili Khojahs. Composed in various North Indian dialects, ginans are part of a broader rich and complex heritage of Indo-Muslim folk literatures in the Indian subcontinent. For centuries, however, the Satpanth Isma'ilis have carefully guarded this sacred tradition for fear of persecution. By thus presenting a major translation of ginans attributed to a pivotal figure in Satpanth Isma'ilism, this dissertation aspires to advance significantly the academic study and knowledge of this scarcely examined sacred literature. To date, the syncretic nature of Satpanth Isma'ilism has been viewed within a framework of conversion. Thus, generally, the ginan literature has been explained as the creative attempts of Isma'ili pirs (venerated teachers) to effect changes in religious orientation by conveying Nizari Isma'ili teachings through Hindu symbols and themes. However, an examination of the internal evidence in the ginans of Pir Shams--who belonged to the beginnings of Satpanth--in conjunction with events in Sind and the greater Isma'ili world at the time, has brought into focus crucial social and political factors that may also have instigated the formation of Satpanth Isma'ilism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Young, Katherine</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Adams, Charles J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n79t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c432z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ismailites -- Prayers and devotions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Śāmasuddīna Sabzavārī, Pīra, 1165-1276?</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islamic hymns</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sb901"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis and spectral studies of tetrazepinones</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jean-Claude, Bertrand J. (Bertrand Jacques), 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to develop a novel analog of the antitumour agent Mitozolomide 1, the diazotization of a variety of N-(2-aminophenyl)-N$ sp prime$-alkylureas was studied. The diazotization of N-(2-aminophenyl)-N-alkylureas of type 2a gave benzotriazole derivatives 3 (R=CONHalkyl). However, that of N-methyl-N-(2-aminophenyl)-N-alkylureas 2b gave 1,2,3,5-benzotetrazepinones 4 after the neutralization of the reaction mixture. This finding allowed the synthesis of bi- and tricyclic tetrazepinones. Electronic effects on the stability of the tetrazepinone ring system were studied by varying substituents at the benzene moiety. The stability of the tetrazepinones increased with increasing electron withdrawing character of the substituent. Variation of substituents at N5 showed that their stability decreases with increasing steric bulk of the substituents. The decomposition of benzotetrazepinones generally gave N-phenyl-N,N$ sp prime$-dimethylureas, 1-alkylbenzotriazoles and 2-hydroxy-benzimidazoles. The synthesis of stable pyrido-1,2,3,5-tetrazepinones is also described. The tetrazepinones were generally characterized by $ sp1$H and $ sp{13}$C NMR, X-ray diffraction, mass spectroscopy and microanalysis. The existence of the triazene chain was usually confirmed by $ sp{15}$N NMR spectroscopy after specific labelling of the central nitrogen (N2).(DIAGRAM, TABLE OR GRAPHIC OMITTED...PLEASE SEE DAI)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Just, George</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c53k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sb901</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021g85c"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Character and the nature of strategic leadership : artists, craftsmen and technocrats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pitcher, Patricia C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation represents an inquiry into the relationship between character and strategy. From Aesthetics, it borrows the conceptual categories, art, craft, and technique. From Psychoanalysis, it borrows a scientific framework for exploring the inner life. From Psychiatry and Psychology, it borrows methodologies. Strategic Management lent its preoccupations. The study demonstrates the long shadow cast by our inner lives on our actions. It portrays the evolution of the strategic posture of a world class corporation in terms of the character of the men who have led it over the past thirty years. It shows the stages through which the corporation went and how those changes were intimately related to the characters of the key executives.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mintzberg, Henry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579t889.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g85c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Leadership</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akk91fn353"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Transferrin receptor expression in the sheep reticulocyte : biosynthesis and fate during reticulocyte maturation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ahn, Jinhi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The transferrin receptor (TfR) is a membrane protein whose function is to deliver transferrin-bound iron into the cell. Erythroid precursor cells and reticulocytes require huge amounts of iron for hemoglobin synthesis and express large numbers of TfRs. However, as the reticulocyte matures into an erythrocyte, TfRs are lost from the cell, as are a number of other membrane proteins. Nearly a decade ago, it was shown that TfRs are released from the sheep reticulocyte in vesicular form (in exosomes) during culture. Exosome formation may be the mechanism for remodelling of the plasma membrane during reticulocyte maturation. In this thesis, we determine whether the sheep reticulocyte has the capacity to sythesize TfRs and whether TfR biosynthesis or externalization is controlled directly by iron. Although the sheep reticulocyte incorporates ($ sp{35}$S) methionine into the TfR, the labelled TfRs are incompletely glycosylated and are not transported to the cell surface. TfR synthesis is regulated by heme, rather than directly by iron. Newly synthesized TfRs are not externalized; however, pulse-chase experiments showed that they are lost slowly by an iron-dependent mechanism. Externalization of preexisting TfRs is stimulated by hemin but not iron. We propose that hemin catalyzes an oxidative change in the TfR which may facilitate the removal of the TfR from the recycling pathway and allow it to be targeted to multivesicular bodies and ultimately released in exosomes. We suggest that the TfR ectodomain can be cleaved from the released vesicles and propose that exosomal membranes are the source of the soluble truncated TfRs found in the circulation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r720c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn353</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440v168"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Human Communication Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The nature and determinants of sentence comprehension impairments in patients with Alzheimer's disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rochon, Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigated sentence comprehension impairments in patients with dementia of the Alzheimer's-type (DAT). The first three experiments investigated the nature of the impairments using different tasks. Across tasks, patients' performance by syntactic complexity, but was poorer for sentences that had more propositions. Results are discussed in terms of a post-interpretive processing impairment in these patients. Two additional experiments investigated possible determinants of sentence comprehension impairments in DAT. One employed a dual-task paradigm to examine the effect of increasing the processing load associated with sentence comprehension. The other examined processing resource limitations in the patients tested in the first and second experiments by employing a battery of tasks designed to measure all aspects of working memory. In both experiments, evidence for processing resource limitations was seen in impaired performance on a concurrent task in dual-task conditions. Results of the fifth experiment also provided evidence that DAT patients' sentence comprehension impairments are correlated with processing resource limitations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qb48t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v168</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Experimental</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hh105"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of type I collagen gene mutations in osteogenesis imperfecta</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sztrolovics, Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study has optimized techniques for the detection and identification of mutations in the genes encoding type I collagen. Two novel polymorphisms were identified which may serve as useful markers in the linkage analysis of inherited disorders resulting from mutations in these genes. The methods were also used to characterize the gene mutations in four patients with osteogenesis imperfecta, a disease associated with bone fragility of heterogeneous severity. The point mutations demonstrated in these patients resulted in four novel glycine substitutions within the triple helical domains of the type I collagen polypeptide chains, and allowed an evaluation of the relationship between disease severity and the nature of the biochemical defects. The description of these mutations has permitted the identification of three regions in the collagen polypeptide chains in which the disease phenotype exhibits a transition between lethal and non-lethal forms, thereby allowing a more accurate prenatal prognosis of phenotypic severity in osteogenesis imperfecta.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b269w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh105</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78td732"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An interpretive framework for the early Iroquoian village</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Timmins, Peter Andrew, 1958-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A methodology is developed for the interpretation of complex Early Iroquoian villages based upon the analysis of site formation processes. This interpretive method is applied to a study of the Calvert site, a twelfth to thirteenth century Iroquoian village located in southwestern Ontario. Four phases in the occupational history of the village are reconstructed and changes in its economic and socio-political organization are examined through a comparative analysis of data from each construction phase. The systematic rebuilding and long-term use of the village indicate significant planning on the part of the Calvert people and suggest that at least some Early Iroquoian communities had developed higher levels of socio-political organization than have been attributed to them in the past. The Calvert site is placed in its regional context and a model is proposed to explain the economic and socio-political changes observed between the Early and Middle Iroquoian periods in southwestern Ontario.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm618.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td732</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Iroquois Indians -- Antiquities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ontario -- Antiquities</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af4752j390"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The regulation of nicotinic alpha-bungarotoxin receptors in adrenal chromaffin cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Geertsen, Susanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present studies investigate the molecular mechanisms involved in the nicotinic antagonist-induced up-regulation of $ alpha$-bungarotoxin ($ alpha$-BGT) binding sites in bovine adrenal chromaffin cells in culture. To assess the possibility that cellular depolarization and/or the activation of protein kinase C might be involved in the nicotinic antagonist-induced up-regulation, experiments were carried out in which nicotinic antagonists, K$ sp+$ and/or phorbol esters were added to the cells in various combinations. These latter two treatments resulted in increases in the number of toxin binding sites in these cells. The results of the additivity experiments suggested that at least two distinct mechanisms seem to be involved in the up-regulation of $ alpha$-BGT binding sites. One of these appears to be uniquely induced by nicotinic antagonists such as d-tubocurarine while a second may be mediated via the activation of protein kinase C. The effects of K$ sp+$ seem to be primarily mediated via protein kinase C although its action may also be exerted in part in a manner similar to that of d-tubocurarine. The increase in receptors induced by nicotinic antagonists, K$ sp+$ or phorbol esters was attenuated by an activator of adenylate cyclase, as well as an analog of cAMP, suggesting that the cAMP dependent protein kinase may play a role in regulating the number of toxin receptors. The effects of various Ca$ sp{2+}$ channel agonists and antagonists were also determined; however, these agents had no effect on toxin binding under any condition indicating that the regulation of Ca$ sp{2+}$ influx into the cells is not required for receptor up-regulation. Recent studies had demonstrated that a thymic polypeptide, thymopoietin (Tpo), potently and specifically inhibited $ alpha$-BGT binding. Studies in chromaffin cells in culture showed that Tpo resulted in an up-regulation of toxin binding sites in a manner similar to that of d-tubocurarine. The effect of Tpo was specific for $ alpha$-BGT sites as nicotinic acetylcholine receptor mediated events were not altered by Tpo. In conclusion, neuronal nicotinic $ alpha$-BGT receptors in chromaffin cells in culture are regulated by a variety of agents, an observation which suggests that these sites may play a role in this tissue. The results of the studies with Tpo indicate that this polypeptide may represent an endogenous ligand for the nicotinic $ alpha$-BGT receptor.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zs40g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j390</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acz30pv24t"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Forebrain connections of hypothalamic supraoptic neurosecretory neurons in the rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nissen, Ralph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the rat, both the activation of peripheral baroreceptors as well as electrical stimulation in the diagonal band of Broca depress the excitability of vasopressin (VP)-secreting neurons in the hypothalamic supraoptic nucleus via GABA$ sb{ rm A}$ receptors. Baroreceptor activation alters the firing of neurons in the diagonal band consistent with a role as a central relay by which baroreceptor activation arrests the activity of supraoptic VP neurons. Neurons in the adjacent median preoptic nucleus (MnPO) also receive baroreceptor-derived input. Anatomical tracing techniques indicate that MnPO neurons project directly to the supraoptic nucleus whereas diagonal band neurons project to the lateral hypothalamic area adjacent to the supraoptic nucleus where they are proposed to contact GABAergic interneurons. This study evaluates the contribution of the diagonal band and MnPO to the central pathway(s) conveying baroreceptor-derived information to supraoptic VP neurons in the rat, using in vivo extracellular electrophysiology combined with neurotoxic (ibotenic acid) lesions. Stimulation in the MnPO inhibited the majority of supraoptic neurons via GBA$ sb{ rm A}$ receptors. Selective destruction of neuronal somata in MnPO failed to alter baroreceptor-induced inhibition of supraoptic VP neurons. By comparison, lesions in the diagonal band of Broca, or lateral hypothalamus, significantly reduced the number of baroresponsive VP neurons. Moreover, lesions in the lateral hypothalamus attenuated diagonal band of Broca-, but not MnPO-evoked inhibition of supraoptic VP neurons. Thus, neurons in the diagonal band, through their connections to GABAergic interneurons located in the lateral hypothalamus, are considered to relay baroreceptor input to supraoptic VP neurons. While stimulation of MnPO inhibits supraoptic neurons via GABA$ sb{ rm A}$ receptors, this innervation does not appear to convey baroreceptor-derived information to the supraoptic nucleus.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f4627133.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv24t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x558t"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The synthesis of highly oxygenated decalin compounds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guertin, Kevin Richard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Lewis acid catalysed tandem Michael-Claisen (4C + 2C) annelation reaction of 1-trimethylsiloxy-1-methoxy-3-phenylthio-1,3-butadiene and 4,4-dimethyl-2-cyclohexen-1-one has been reexamined. The intermediate E and Z Michael adducts were cyclized under basic conditions to give the $ beta$-diketone 3-phenylthio-5,6,4a,8a-tetrahydro-5,5-dimethyl-(4H,7H)-naphthalen-1,8-dione. Angular methylation of this $ beta$-diketone under basic conditions was examined in detail, providing the cis angularly methylated product stereoselectively. The cis ring junction stereochemistry of the $ beta$-diketone derivative mentioned above has been used advantageously to establish the C$ sb8$ (naphthalene numbering) $ alpha$-hydroxyl stereochemistry required for the forskolin structure. A subsequent enolate oxidation/nucleophilic addition sequence was then used to stereoselectively install the C$ sb1$ and C$ sb2$ (naphthalene numbering) cis $ alpha, alpha$-diol functionality also present in the forskolin structure. Subsequent functional group manipulations then provided 1,2,5,6,7,8,8a-heptahydro-$1 alpha,2 alpha$,4-${ rm trihydroxy}$-8$ alpha$-(tert-butyldimethylsiloxy)-$1 beta(1 sp prime$-${ rm hexynyl}$)-2,5,5,8a$ beta$-tetramethyl-naphthalen-3-one, a highly oxygenated $ alpha$-diketone intermediate for the synthesis of forskolin. A number of the decalin compounds leading to the $ alpha$-diketone intermediate mentioned above, were tested for antifeedant activity against the spruce budworm (Choristoneura fumiferana). Eleven of these compounds were found to be active and structure-activity relationships were examined.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k427k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x558t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128ng25x"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Acetylcholine release in the somatosensory cortex following peripheral nerve injury : a microdialysis and HPLC study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kabani, Noor Jehan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Acetylcholine has been implicated in the reorganization of cortex using lesion studies. These studies suggest that biochemical changes take place in the cortex following peripheral nerve injury. Using microdialysis, we studied the time-dependent change in the release of acetylcholine in control and sciatic-nerve-sectioned cats. Our first finding was that there is intra-animal variability in the release of acetylcholine. Using each cat as its own control we studied the acetylcholine release on days 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11 and 15 after nerve injury. We found that the release of acetylcholine was significantly higher than normal one day after nerve injury. The levels then fluctuated but at day 15 there was a second rise in the levels of acetylcholine release. Based on other studies, we suggest that cortical reorganization is a multi-step process that begins immediately after nerve injury. The change in the release of acetylcholine during the first two weeks suggests that acetylcholine plays a very important role, at least in the initial part of this process.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx06c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng25x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2r36v018g"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Risque infectieux en garderie et essai d'intervention en stimulant l'immunité</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Collet, Jean-Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Part 1. An 8.5 month prospective study was carried out to compare the risk of repeated infections in children attending different type of daycare facilities. Compared to children in family daycare, children in small daycare centres ($ le$20 children) had an increased risk of having $ ge$6 infections (odds ratio (OR) = 2.3; 95% confidence interval (CI) = 2.5-3.6); $ ge$5 upper respiratory tract infections (OR = 2.2; CI = 1.4-3.4); $ ge$2 occurrence of otitis media (OR = 2.6; CI = 1.0-2.6); and $ ge$2 episodes of gastroenteritis (OR = 1.5; CI = 0.9-2.4). Surprisingly this risk was not as high for children attending large daycare centres. Children who had spent at least 3 months in daycare before the beginning of the study were significantly protected compared to new attenders. These infections have important social and economical consequences since 96% of all episodes required a medical consultation. 68% were treated with antibiotics; and approximately 40% of episodes resulted in a parent taking time off work to look after their sick child. Further studies should be performs to assess the long term consequences of repeated infections. Part 2. A randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial was implemented to evaluate the efficacy of an immunostimulator in reducing the occurrence of recurrent respiratory or ear, nose, and throat infections. The parents of 423 children agreed to participate (210 Imocur$ sp circler$ and 213 Placebo). One capsule was administered orally for 10 consecutive days a month for 3 months. Children were followed for a further 4.5 months giving a total of 7.5 months for the study. For the total study period the risk of presenting at least 4 episodes of respiratory or ear, nose, and throat infections was lower in the treated group than in the placebo group (26.7% versus 33.8%), but the difference was not statistically significant (relative risk (RR) = 0.79; confidence interval (CI) = 0.59-1.06). A similar result was observed for the risk of having $ ge$2 episodes of gastroenteritis (RR = 0.77; 95% CI = 0.47-1.25). In contrast, at the end of the three-month treatment period we observed a 48% reduction in risk of presenting $ ge$3 episodes of respiratory or ear nose and throat infections (RR = 0.52; 95% CI = 0.45-0.87) in the treated group. However, this clinically important and statistically significant decrease in risk of recurrent infections did not extend beyond this period. The tolerance of the drug during the trial was excellent. Since these results were obtained from an exploratory analysis, they should be confirmed in further studies.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g187x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v018g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education, Early Childhood</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128ng266"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The sage of Kingston : John Watson and the ambiguity of Hegelianism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Humphrey, Christopher Wainwright</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>John Watson's thought has not been well understood. A question suggested by previous scholarship, namely, how successful was he at his task of re-founding the Christian religion on a philosophical base? is answered first in terms of consistency with the theological tradition. His revision of Christian theology is found to be inadequate by traditional standards; it is then examined as a philosophy of religion which, to his mind, overcame the difficulties of classical theism. It is argued that, despite some advantages, his philosophy of religion is deficient in two respects. First, its method is vitiated by a strained and sometimes mistaken interpretation of the philosophical tradition, indicative of arbitrariness. Second, "Speculative Idealism" as the result of that method reveals conceptual ambiguities corresponding to the ambiguities of classical theism. As the method is not self-evident and is used implicitly by Watson, and the results are philosophically ambiguous, the appropriation of this thought was theologically or philosophically shallow. Though Watson's thought, as far as it was understood, provided an underpinning for the "social gospel" movement in Canada, it is argued that this shallow appropriation explains, at least in part, the brevity of its appeal as philosophy of religion.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r014x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng266</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Philosophy, Canadian -- 19th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Philosophy, Canadian -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Watson, John, 1847-1939</dc:subject><dc:subject>Religion -- Philosophy -- History -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Religion -- Philosophy -- History -- 19th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avt150k78q"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>War by consensus : power, perceptions and British grand strategy 1940-1943</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Farrell, Brian P (Brian Padair), 1960-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>From 1940 through 1943, British grand strategy was shaped by a broad consensus, generally accepted and understood in the central direction of the war. This consensus was based on the assumption of relative weakness, and was expressed by what may be termed the "wear down" approach: "to knock out the props" from under Axis military power by a combination of blockade, bombing, raids, subversion and sabotage, and peripheral campaigns. An ultimate direct assault would only be launched after enemy power had visibly declined. The balance, emphasis, and specific thrust of this outline changed; its essence did not. Even as a powerful Grand Alliance emerged, the British remained convinced that the assumption of relative weakness must continue to guide its grand strategy. This assumption was finally rejected by the coalition as a whole, but it proved well founded for the British themselves. Ultimately, however, this formulation of grand strategy by consensus was, in general, a sober and responsible interpretation of the overall British situation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v853.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150k78q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Great Britain -- History, Military -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Great Britain</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p871w"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>From Notre Dame Collegiate Institute to Marianopolis College : the evolution of an institution (1908-1975); a case study of pivotal decisions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Huntley-Maynard, Jean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Marianopolis College evolved from a small classical college for Roman Catholic women to a CEGEP-level co-educational and multi-confessional institution. This case study analyses the administrative decision-making that guided the college during three pivotal events in its history. Four aspects of decision-making theory are considered: style, constraints, strategies, and kinds. The major question this case study addresses is: What were the decision-making practices that guided the evolution of Marianopolis College from a Roman Catholic classical college for women to a private coeducational and multi-confessional CEGEP-level college? A secondary question is: To what extent can the decision-making practices adopted to cope with change be supported by models of decision-making theory? The major finding of this study is that at the three pivotal points in the college's history the decision-making strategies depended on environmental and organizational constraints, especially the founding purpose of the institution.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f518g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p871w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Marianopolis (College) -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mn892"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structure and properties of lux proteins from bioluminescent bacteria</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Soly, Robert Richard Roland</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The nucleotide sequence from the downstream region of the lux operon from the bioluminescent bacterium Photobacterium phosphoreum was determined. This area contains three genes involved in bioluminescence metabolism: luxF, luxE, and luxG. LuxF is a new lux gene not found in the extensively studied luminescent bacteria of the Vibrio genus. The 26 kDa LuxF protein was found to be homologous to the 35 kDa $ beta$ subunit of bacterial luciferase (LuxB). LuxF is proposed to have arisen from luxB by a gene duplication event followed by deletion of 100 codons near the amino terminal. The LuxF protein was identified as the abundant non-fluorescent flavoprotein of unknown function found in many Photobacterium species. LuxE codes for the 42 kDa fatty acyl-protein synthetase subunit of the fatty acid reductase complex which produces fatty aldehydes for the luciferase-catalyzed light-emitting reaction. This enzyme catalyzes the ATP-dependent activation of free fatty acids and covalently transfers acyl groups to other protein subunits via an intramolecular cysteine residue. Site-directed mutagenesis of five conserved cysteine residues has identified the site of fatty acyl transfer of the synthetase as Cys$ sp{364}.$ LuxG is a new lux gene found in the operons of marine but not terrestrial luminescent bacteria. The 26 kDa LuxG protein was found to be highly homologous to an NAD(P)H:flavin oxidoreductase from Escherichia coli. The primary structure homologies implicate this new lux protein in flavin oxidoreduction biochemistry; a role in the luminescent-specific generation of the FMNH$ sb2$ cosubstrate of luciferase in the light-emitting reaction is likely. Light emission was restored in dark V. harveyi fatty acid reductase mutants by complementation with V. harveyi and P. phosphoreum genes coding for the corresponding inactive enzyme subunit. The variation in fatty aldehyde- and fatty acid-stimulable in vivo luminescence with cell growth (and lux induction) shows that P. phosphoreum subunits interact poorly and in a protein concentration-dependent manner with V. harveyi fatty acid reductase complexes. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m033.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mn892</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>