<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g561c"><ual:graduationDate>1942</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bacteriology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the microorganisms of the genera Staphylococcus and Micrococcus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacLennan, Louise Isabel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The microorganisms of the genera Micrococcus and Staphylococeus belong to the family Micrococcaceae, which is  defined in Bergey's Manuel of Determinative Baeteriology {2) as follows: Family Mierococcaceae Cells in their free condition spherical; during division somewhat elliptical. Division in two or three planes. If the cella remain in contact after division, they are frequently flattened in the plane of division, and occur singly, in pairs, tetrade, packets or irregular masses. Motility rare.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kelly, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns0648967.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g561c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bacteria</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f4357"><ual:graduationDate>1942</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experimental investigations of the effect of steroid compounds on the uterus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Masson, Georges Marie Charles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The close relationship existing between the ovaries and the secondary sex characteristics has been recognized for many centuries. In the early experiments the observations were, however, confined to morphological and physiological changes in the external characteristics after removal of the genital glands. It was not until 1896 that Landau noted uterine atrophy following removal of the ovaries and attempted, though unsuccessfully, to correct this effect in the human through oral administration of desiccated ovarian glands. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Selye, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j29x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f4357</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Uterus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Steroids</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859j64d"><ual:graduationDate>1942</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Marie le Franc : romancière de la Bretagne et du Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McGarry, Ave M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse a pour but de démontrer, par une analyse minutieuse de chacune de ses oeuvres principales, que Marie Le Franc, romancière de la Bretagne et du Canada, bien qu'elle n'appartienne pas au petit groupe de grands artistes immortels,a une place dans l'histoire de la littérature contemporaine. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Furness, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214s288.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859j64d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Le Franc, Marie, 1879-1965 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd376074t"><ual:graduationDate>1942</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mental development as related to institutional and foster home placement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mitchell, Mary Verity</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Until comparatively recently, general intelligence was regarded as innately fixed, unmodifiable and relatively unaffected by environmental factors. However, results of research undertaken during the past two decades suggest that the intelligence of children may undergo modification under certain gross environmental conditions, in accordance with certain general and fairly clear principles. Although much more experimentation and investigation are necessary to supplement existing data, and although the tools of measurement require revision before any sound conclusions can be arrived at, one must be willing to accept the fact, that intelligence is possibly more plastic and modifiable than has hitherto been believed possible. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kellogg, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483n21g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd376074t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Child welfare</dc:subject><dc:subject>PSYCHOLOGY -- MENTAL TESTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Children -- Institutional care</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n6420"><ual:graduationDate>1942</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the arterial and arteriolar architecture in normal and diseased human kidneys by means of neoprene injections</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>More, Robert Hall</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study was undertaken with the hope that the application of a new method to the study of an old problem might remove some of the contradictory ideas that exist concerning the blood supply of the normal and abnormal human kidney. The importance of an accurate knowledge of the blood supply in the normal and diseased human kidney is realized when we consider that for over one hundred years controversy has raged in regard to the relation of renal disease to hypertension. With the recent production (1932-1938) by Goldblatt and others of experimental hypertension by constriction of the main renal artery, the importance of a knowledge of the blood supply of the kidney in hypertension is more fully apparent. The association of chronic renal disease and hypertension as a frequent direct or indirect cause of death is revealed at autopsy and indicates that any work is of value which elucidates in any way the causation of hypertension in human beings. With the knowledge gained from experimental hypertension the problem now is to determine in man the relation to the hypertension to the changes in small arteries and arterioles to the kidney. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Duff, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v866z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n6420</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahq37vr63c"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Learning to engineer life: development of a generally configurable model for the simulation of artificial ecosystems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Parrott, Lael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objective of this project has been to create a generally configurable computational model that can be used to simulate the behaviour of ecosystems. It was undertaken within the "EcoCyborg Project", a research program for which the long term goal is to learn how to engineer living systems, specifically ecocyborgs: ecosystems combined with technological control components. The short term goal of this research program is to improve the practice of ecosystem engineering by creating modelling and simulation tools with which specific design and management questions can be explored. The principal intent in creating the model was to reproduce, in the virtual realm, some of the complex features and dynamics common to all large ecological assemblages. The model is constructed of simple, object-based representations of most of the major biotic and abiotic components that are found in any ecosystem, including a spatially explicit terrain, an atmosphere, and various plants and animals of different species. The behaviour of many of these components is driven by climate-related external forcing functions. Each component is represented by an object, the state of which is described by properties, and the functionality of which is described with rule-based expressions. During simulation, the state of each object is computed at regular time increments, and the system's global-level comportment arises as the aggregation of object-level events. As part of the thesis work, a complete set of configuration programs was written, with which the constitution, initial state, and climate of an ecosystem can be specified for simulation. The model is a novel contribution, due to both the degree of configurability provided by these programs, and the level of detail and breadth of scope with which an ecosystem can be represented. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Ce projet avait pour objectif la creation d'un modèle informatique configurable qui peut être utile à la simulation du comportement d'écosystèmes. Cette entreprise est partie intégrale du "EcoCyborg Project", un programme de recherche dans lequel on étudie l'ingénierie des systèmes vivants, plus spécifiquement d'écocyborgs: écosystèmes combines a des mécanismes de contrôle technologiques. L'objectif a court terme de ce programme de recherche est l'amélioration des pratiques d'ingénierie d'écosystèmes par le développement d'outils de modélisation et de simulation grace auxquels il sera possible d'explorer divers designs et méthodes de gestion spécifiques. Le développement du modèle avait pour objectif principal la reproduction, dans le domaine virtuel, de certains des attributs et comportements complexes communs a tous les assemblages écologiques d'importance. Le modèle est construit a l'aide d'objets configurables simples, représentant la plupart des composants vivants et non-vivants retrouves dans tout écosystème, ainsi qu'une description spatiale explicite du terrain, une atmosphere, des plantes et des animaux d'espèces diverses. Le comportement de la plupart de ces composants est gouverne par des fonctions contraignantes externes de conditions climatiques. Chaque composant est représenté par un objet, dont l'état est décrit par des propriétés, et dont la fonctionnalité est décrite par des expressions a base de règles. Durant la simulation, l'état de chaque objet est évalué à des intervalles de temps réguliers et le comportement global du système emerge de l'agrégation du comportement et de l'interaction de ces objets. Une collection complete de programmes de configuration a aussi été développée, a l'aide desquels la constitution, l'état initial, et le climat propre a un écosystème peuvent être specifies pour fin de simulation. Le modèle présenté est une contribution authentique, autant au niveau du degré de configurabilité possible, qu'au niveau des details et de l'étendue avec lesquels on peut représenter un écosystème. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kok, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60d065s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vr63c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515r505"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization, visualization and quantification of soil macropores and preferential flow using spect and x-ray cat scanning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Perret, Johan S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La presence de macropores entraine une infiltration rapide, dite préférentielle, de composes chimiques, tels les pesticides, a travers la zone vadose du sol. La plupart des études vis ant a caractériser le phénomène d'écoulement préférentiel à travers les macropores considèrent le sol tel une "boite-noire". Ainsi, il n'a pas encore été possible de décrire de façon quantitative l'effet de la géométrie des macropores sur cet important phénomène hydrologique. Quatre colonnes de sol (850 mm x 77 mm de diamètre) ont été prélevées intactes pour visualiser et quantifier la structure des macropores a l'aide d'un CAT scanner. La quantification des macropores a permis de determiner leurs morphologies en deux dimensions (diamètre cylindrique equivalent, rayon hydraulique, rectangularité et circularité), ainsi que plusieurs paramètres tri-dimensionnels et topologiques (longueur, volume, rayon hydraulique en 3-D, tortuosité, densité numérique, coordination, et connectivité). Les pores ayant un diamètre cylindrique equivalent supérieur ou égal à 1.0 mm (c-à-d., les macropores) furent détectés et visualises sans problème. Nos résultats indiquent que la macroporosité moyenne des quatres colonnes de sol fluctue entre 2.1 et 3.8%. Après avoir étudié la distribution des rayons hydrauliques des macropores, il a été conclu qu'environ 20% des gorges des macropores avaient un diamètre de 1.6 mm. De plus, la majorité des reseaux de macropores avait une longueur de 40 mm, un volume de 60 mm3 et une surface de parois de 175 mm2. L'infiltration d'iodure de potassium a été suivie par CAT scanning. Cette approche a permis de caractériser en temps reel les mécanismes d'écoulement préférentiel a travers les macropores. L'infiltration à travers la matrice du sol suggère la presence de petits pores (mesopores) connectes aux réseaux de macropores. Pour modéliser l'écoulement dans la matrice du sol, il est recommande de diviser cette region en deux domaines: les mesopores et les micropores. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The presence of soil macropores provides an opportunity for water and associated chemicals to move preferentially through the vadose zone. Most studies on the characterization of macropore flow consider the soil system to be a "black-box". Thus, efforts to describe macropores in quantitative terms have not yet resulted in a comprehensive theoretical framework that allows for a complete representation of their geometry and their effect on preferential flow. Macropore networks in four large undisturbed soil columns (850 mm x 77 mm diameter), were quantified and visualized, both in 2-D and 3-D, using X-ray Computer Assisted Tomography (CAT). Macropore quantification included two-dimensional parameters (i.e., number of macropores, macropore size, hydraulic radius, rectangularity and circularity), and three-dimensional and topological parameters (i.e., macropore length, volume, 3-D hydraulic radius, tortuosity, numerical density, coordination number, and connectivity). Pores larger or equal to 1.0 mm in equivalent diameter were readily detected, visualized and quantified. It was found that the average macroporosity of four soil columns varied between 2.1 and 3.8 %. From the hydraulic radius distribution, it was inferred that about 20 % of macropore throats have a diameter of 1.6 mm. It was found that the majority of macro pore networks had a length of 40 mm, a volume of 60 mm3 and a wall area of 175 mm2 . Breakthrough of potassium iodide was monitored with X-ray CAT scanning. This approach allowed for real-time examination of flow mechanisms through the macropore and matrix flow domains at various depths along the soil column. Flow in the matrix domain suggested that part of the matrix contains small pores (mesopores) that were connected to macropore networks. It is suggested that the matrix domain should be subdivided into two regions: mesopores and micropores. In addition, the macropore domain should be defined both in terms of macropore geometry and its ability to convey the tracer preferentially. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Prasher, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f6627.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515r505</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soil percolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tomography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil porosity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nh742"><ual:graduationDate>1942</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of growth substances upon some phytopathogenic fungi</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Payette, Albert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>[...] Among the fungi which have been found to give better growth on a synthetic medium with a supply of one or more of the known growth substances, the parasitic ones are largely represented. Thus, some of the physiological problems involved in parasitism may be explained, at least tentatively, on the basis of the need of the parasite for the growth substances which it finds in its host plants. The purpose of these studies was to determine the effect of growth substances upon some phytopathogenic fungi with the view that the results might throw some light upon the physiology of their parasitism. It will appear from the review of literature to follow that vitamin B1, also called aneurine by European workers and thiamine by Americans, is of special interest in this connection and accordingly it has been given the main consideration in the present investigations. The pathogenic fungi under investigation were selected from various groups and represent various types of parasitism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Coulson, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pg93m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nh742</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vf53d"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Water and salt management strategies in a closed drainage basin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ali, Hatem M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le bassin versant Fayoum en Egypte est un bassin fermé n'ayant aucun drainage naturel. Des eaux de drainage salées sont evacuees et entreposées dans le lac Qaroun, où elles deviennent sujet a la concentration par evaporation. Suite a ces contraintes physiques et environnementales, la gestion d'eau et de sel y est généralement difficile. L'accumulation de sels dans le lac peut atteindre des niveaux dangeureux. Afin d'évaluer différentes alternatives de gestion eau / sel, des modèles mathématiques portant sur l'évaporation lacustre, l'acheminement des eaux, et l'équilibre en eau du bassin versant, furent développés et mis a l'épreuve. Les résultats des modèles de simulation ant indique que la division du lac en deux compartiments serait le scenario qui conviendrait le mieux afin de réduire la salinité du lac Qaroun. Le plus petit compartiment, situé à l'extremité est du lac Qaroun, contiendrait une eau relativement douce, avec une salinité de 13.3 dS/m et un niveau de -43.79 m NMS. L'autre compartiment, à l'extremité ouest du lac, contiendrait une eau salée (72.2 dS/m). Des étangs d'évaporation d'une superficie de 6 km^2 seraient necessires pour disposer de la charge en sels de 620,000 t/an. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The Fayoum basin of Egypt is a closed basin with a lack of natural drainage outlets. The saline drainage water disposed of and impounded into Lake Qaroun is subject to evapoconcentration. As a result of these physical and environmental constraints, water and salt management are generally hampered, and salt accumulation in the lake can reach hazardous levels. In order to assess alternative water and salt management scenarios, mathematical models of lake evaporation, as well as lake routing. and basin water balance were developed and tested. Findings from model simulations showed that the most suitable scenario for reducing salinity in Lake Qaroun was to divide the lake into two compartments. The smaller compartment, located at the east end of Lake Qaroun, will have relatively fresh water with a salinity level of 13.3 dS/m, and a water level of -43.79 m MSL. The other compartment, located at the west end of Lake Qaroun, will have saline water (72.2 dS/m). Evaporation ponds of 6 km^2 are required to evacuate the salt load of 620,000 tonnes/year. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madramootoo, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g328.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vf53d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Irrigation -- Egypt -- Qaroun, Lake, Region -- Management</dc:subject><dc:subject>Salt lakes -- Egypt</dc:subject><dc:subject>Water salinization -- Egypt -- Qaroun, Lake</dc:subject><dc:subject>Evaporation (Meteorology) -- Egypt -- Qaroun, Lake -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Salinization -- Control -- Egypt -- Qaroun, Lake</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r617d"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cavity perturbation technique for measurement of dielectric properties of some agri-food materials</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Venkatesh, Meda S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Optimal utilization of microwave energy requires more basic knowledge of the dielectric properties of the material under investigation. The dielectric properties of materials subjected to microwaves are known to depend on moisture content, temperature and density of the material as well as the frequency of the applied microwave field. This thesis deals with the study of cavity perturbation technique and its feasibility to determine the dielectric properties of various agri-food materials. In the study, linear relationships between roots of the dielectric properties and density found in the literature were confirmed to be valid for pulverized grains tested with the cavity perturbation method. The effect of particle size on dielectric properties of chopped grain is also reported as a quadratic relationship. The dielectric properties (epsilon' &amp; epsilon") of materials such as tylose (methyl hydroxy ethyl cellulose); organic solvents such as ethanol, hexane and their mixtures; edible oils such as canola, soya and sunflower oils were determined at various temperatures, frequencies, salt content and other relevant parameters, using cavity perturbation technique.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'utilisation optimale de l'énergie micro-onde requiert une connaissance approfondie des propriétés diélectriques des matériaux traités. Les propriétés diélectriques des matériaux soumis aux micro-ondes dependent du taux d'humidité, de la temperature et de la densité de la matière de même que de la fréquence du champ micro-onde. Cette etude a également examiné la méthode de perturbation de cavités et son utilisation potentielle dans le secteur agro-alimentaire. Dans cette étude, une modélisation linéaire entre la racine des propriétés diélectriques de grains haches et la densité a été validé avec la méthode de perturbation des cavités. L'effet de la grosseur des particules sur les propriétés diélectriques a été identifie comme étant quadratique. Les propriétés diélectriques de matériaux tel le tylose^MC.; de solvants comme l'éthanol et l'hexane ainsi que leur combinaison; d'huiles comestibles comme l'huile de canola, l'huile de soya ou l'huile de tournesol ont aussi été determinées à différents niveaux de temperature, fréquence, pourcentage de sels, etc. en utilisant la méthode de perturbation des cavités.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Raghavan, V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jp74r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r617d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food industry and trade</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dielectric measurements</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cavity resonators</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microwave heating -- Industrial applications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83m2492"><ual:graduationDate>1942</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The use of radio in the school</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Price, Frederick W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Among the plethora of educational aids available to teachers today - films, school libraries, visual and art exhibits, museum showcases, etc. - there has appeared, during the past two decades, the radio.  Fortunately for our schools, indiscriminate acceptance of and enthusiasm for new learning aids has of recent years given way to a properly critical attitude, which the proponents of school broadcasting seem to have found rather more stimulating than discouraging.  This thesis seeks to discover what and where use has been made of the radio in the schools of Canada, United States, and Britain; how it is bing used to best advantage; and what critical evaluations of its use have been made. It attempts to find the answer to the question, Are school radio programs of value as a learning aid? [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Currie, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xp75x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m2492</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Radio in education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698b74p"><ual:graduationDate>1942</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Internal economic control in war-time : Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Reisman, S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The growth of world capitalism has brought with it a spectacular development of state intervention in the functioning of the economic system. The creature of the classical economists, Laissez-Faire, never applied fully, for even in its hey-day, there was a measure of government participation in determining the conditions under which the economy functioned. And as the process of industrialization worked its way and spread, Laissez-Faire increasingly gave way to an ever-expanding measure of restriction from within its own institutions and from the state. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hemmeon, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mq63b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698b74p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>War -- Economic aspects -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Economic conditions -- 1918-1945</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gg95z"><ual:graduationDate>1942</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Haemoglobin : a study of its stability in stored blood</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rochlin, Isidore, author</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study presented in this thesis arose as a side-issue of a main investigation on the preservation of whole blood assigned to the Department of Biochemistry, by the National Research Council, shortly after the outbreak of war in 1939. During the recent Spanish Civil War, the extensive use of stored blood in the treatment of wounded soldiers and civilians had demonstrated the practicability and the usefulness of stored blood in modern warfare. As a result, a widespread interest developed in many countries in the improvement of methods of preservation. The idea of the Blood Bank was introduced in the United States by Dr. B. Fantus in 1937, and within a short time the bank had become an established facility in many of the larger hospitals of North America. When the second World War finally broke out there arose a sudden need, particularly in bombed areas, for large stores of blood. Much blood was collected in anticipation of the "blitzkrieg", but it could be kept only for a week or so and then had to be discarded. Since little research had been done up to the time on the improvement of storage methods, many groups including the one at McGill University, undertook an investigation of this subject. Rapid progress was made, and in the course of two or three years the average time of preservation has been extended to six weeks [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denstedt, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50h025k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg95z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881q11g"><ual:graduationDate>1941</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Geology of chromite</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fortier, Y. O.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation on chromite is not intended to cover all aspects of the mineralogy, geology, and economics of chrome ore. The main purpose is to discuss as adequately as possible the origin of chromite. Chromite is generally considered as a typical mineral of early magmatic origin. But a few authors have expressed some doubt as to the universal early magmatic character of the mineral. Some geologists even suggest that chromite may be hydrothermal. The arguments for late magmatic and hydrothermal chromite come mainly from observations with the microscope, whereas very few advocates have cited arguments based on the geology of chromite deposits and associated igneous masses. One of the objects of this dissertation is to stress the importance of the geology, field relationships, and origin of the rock masses containing the chromite deposits. Taking into account the geological data, observations with the microscope on chromite may be given a better interpretation. This is why certain arguments that a few geologists have found in microscope observations are commented under the light of field geology. It is not maintained that explanations given and conclusions drawn represent the actual happenings. Yet the aim of this work will have been reached if it is shown that argumentation given for late chromite can often be interpreted differently for an early magmatic chromite. [...] </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Osborne, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g563.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881q11g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149s70x"><ual:graduationDate>1942</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Huxley’s novels of ideas : a study in values</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ross, Sally Chipman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In important respects Aldous Huxley is a typical English literary intellectual of the period between the Treaty of Versailles and the present war. His early satire of post-war society is one of the most brilliant expressions of the disillusioned spirit of the nineteen twenties, and his rejection of the attitude of spectator, eight years later, in Eyeless In Gaza, for a positive belief in "the spirit of man" is representative of the trend of the nineteen thirties. The development of his thought must, therefore, be examined in relation to the currents of thought and the events of his time. These relationships will perhaps be clearer to the coming generation, and such a study will be more easily and more accurately done in fifty years' time. There is, however, a value in doing it now. We cannot be, as the Yankee at the Court of King Arthur, all-knowing in another age; we must live in the present century. The main portion of this chapter is, therefore, devoted to a study of the sources of the disillusioned spirit so conspicuous in the literature of the nineteen twenties. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Giles, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nt973.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149s70x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Huxley, Aldous, 1894-1963</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9880vt95h"><ual:graduationDate>1941</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The mental factors in leadership</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cownie, Douglas Heron</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There are probably very few subjects which are of so much interest and importance in the social and economic field and about which so little is known as "leadership". [...] Perhaps the most difficult problems in the study of leadership is that of "prediction". Is it possible to predict, by means of case history, tests or other means, whether a man will be a good leader in such and such a position or not? This problem has been solved in part only, and later on in our discussion we shall try to clarify the issue to some extent, in the case of camp leaders. [...] In brief, the object of our study is "to determine by means of an intensive study of counsellor and camper alike, what factors, individual and social, play a part in the determination of leadership in the camping situation. [...] Among other things, this includes reference to camp activities, the use and interpretation of psychological tests and questionnaires and the general philosophy of camp leadership. The study is primarily concerned with the camp counsellor as such, his personality in toto, his popularity with the campers, his ability to lead groups of campers, his value to the camp as judged by senior staff members, and other factors determined by observation, questionnaires, and tests. In addition, a less comprehensive study was made of certain campers and the results along with those on counsellors were compared and interpreted in the light of the social setting. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tait, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591c24k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vt95h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>CAMPING</dc:subject><dc:subject>Leadership</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dj67r"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Thermal characteristics of screenhouse configurations in a West-African tropical climate</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Desmarais, Gaétan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Biological Control Program (BCP) for Africa operates from Cotonou, Benin, which is part of the International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA). Its present mandate includes the provision of Biological Control Labs to African National Biological Control Programs. Thirty tropical countries are targeted. The challenge presently faced by the BCP is to develop biological control structures adapted to the climatic and economic conditions of those countries. Specifically, structures such as greenhouses, screenhouses and growth chambers must provide, at reasonable expense, protection of experimental material against insects and airborne pathogens, as well as close to ambient temperature and sunlight. A recent innovation, the "screenhouse", is a promising technology with respect to its inherent capacity of providing near-ambient conditions by passive cooling (natural ventilation, radiation absorption and evaporative cooling) alone. However, overheating is still a problem in many conditions. In order to characterize the thermal performance of such structures, and to optimize their cooling performances, various screenhouse architectural configurations, screen types and water cooling options were evaluated during three seasons at the IITA, BCP research station.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le Programme de lutte biologique (PLB) pour l'Afrique de l'Institut international d'agriculture tropicale (IITA), base a Cotonou (Benin), a notamment pour mandat de fournir des laboratoires de recherche sur la lutte biologique aux programmes nationaux de lutte biologique des pays africains. Trente pays tropicaux sont vises. A l'heure actuelle, le PLB est confronte au défi du développement de structures de lutte biologique adaptées aux conditions climatiques et économiques de ces pays. Plus précisément, les structures telles que les serres, les serres grillagées et les chambres de croissance doivent protéger, à des coûts raisonnables, le materiel experimental contre les insectes et les pathogènes véhiculés par l'air, tout en présentant des temperatures proches de la temperature ambiante et tout en laissant passer les rayons du soleil. La nouvelle technologie des "serres grillagées" semble prometteuse en ce qu'elle fournit des conditions proches des conditions ambiantes grace au refroidissement passif (ventilation naturelle, absorption des radiations et évapotranspiration). Cependant, la surchauffe reste un problème dans de nombreuses conditions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Raghavan, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096b096.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dj67r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Greenhouses -- Tropics -- Design and construction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Greenhouses -- Africa, West -- Design and construction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wire screens</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cf00q"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Applications of artificial neural network technology in the design of water-table management systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yang, Chun-Chieh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ce projet de recherche a pour but l'utilisation d'un réseau neuronal artificiel RNA afin de simuler et prédire les variations de la hauteur de nappe libre pour des systèmes de gestion différents, tels le drainage conventionnel de même que l'irrigation souterraine. Les données de bases sont les facteurs météorologiques, tels, precipitation, évapotranspiration et hauteur moyenne de la nappe libre. Les données de precipitation et d'évapotranspiration recueillies ont été utilisées afin d'obtenir les predictions d'un modèle informatique éprouvé connu sous le nom de DRAINMOD. Les résultats ainsi obtenus ont été utilises pour développer un modèle base sur les RNA. Les résultats obtenus grace aux RNA ont été compares aux predictions faites par DRAINMOD afin de valider l'utilisation des RNA dans la gestion de la nappe d'eau et la planification du drainage. De plus, les RNA ont été utilisés dans l'étude des effets du terrain tels la sécheresse, jours de travail, espacement des drains, gestion de l'eau, et le rendement annuel, permettant ainsi la prediction des rendements annuels de culture. Les résultats de cette recherche démontrent que les RNA peuvent produire des predictions semblables a celles de DRAINMOD, et ce de façon significativement plus rapide et nécessitant moins de données de bases. Les RNA peuvent simuler les fluctuations de la hauteur de la nappe phréatique et prédire les rendements de culture sous drainage conventionnel de même que sous irrigation souterraine.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the use of artificial neural networks (ANNs) to model the relationship between input and output variables in two water-table management systems, i.e., a subsurface drainage and a subirrigation systems. The input variables include precipitation, evapotranspiration, and midspan water-table depths. The output variables include the variation in the water-table depths. The measured rainfall and evapotranspiration data were used to derive water-table depth predictions from DRAINMOD: a conventional water-table management model. The measured data and derived predictions were used to develop an ANN model for water-table depths. The results obtained from the ANN were compared with the predictions made by DRAINMOD to determine the applicability of ANNs to land drainage engineering. ANN models were also used to study the relationships among various other design factors, including dry days, work days, SEW-30, drain spacing, water management, and annual crop yields with the help of DRAINMOD. The derived ANN models were used to predict annual crop yields. The predicted results from the ANN models were also compared with the results from DRAINMOD. The results show that an ANN model can make predictions similar to DRAINMOD, and it does so significantly faster and with fewer inputs. With adequate training, an ANN model is capable of simulating the fluctuation of water-table depths and the annual crop yields under conventional subsurface drainage and subirrigation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Prasher, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967670d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cf00q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neural networks (Computer science)</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRAINMOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>Subirrigation -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Subsurface drainage -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Water table -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r4135"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>High pressure water scrubber for controlled atmosphere storage</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vigneault, Clément</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A theoretical model of a high pressure water scrubber (HPWS) was developed in order to evaluate the performance of such an apparatus in reducing the O2 pull-down period in commercial controlled atmosphere storage facilities for fruits and vegetables. A simulation study indicated that the HPWS could be designed to meet most specific requirements. Mass transfer considerations in the design of the HPWS required: 1) a non-intrusive technique to sample bubble. clouds for accurate estimation of bubble physical dimensions generated at the bottom of a water column, this, in order to evaluate available bubble generators; and, 2) of a simple method to determine the solubility of gases in pure and contaminated water since existing methods were deemed time-consuming and expensive. The digital image analysis technique of bubble measurement was refined by: (i) the development of a discriminatory parameter permitting identification of those bubbles within a known focus range such that errors could be held to reasonable magnitudes; and, (ii) the development of a mechanical bubble sampler enabling characterization of high density bubble clouds. A simple and inexpensive pressure apparatus was developed to determine gas solubility in water of various degrees of purity. Results for CO2, O2 and N2 solubilities compared favourably with published data. The HPWS was designed, constructed and its performance in controlling CO2 and O2 was tested under typical CA storage conditions. It was effective for CO2 removal, however, it did not reduce enough the O2 concentration of the CA storage chamber to justify the initial capital investment of this equipment.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Un modèle théorique d'un lessiveur à l'eau à haute pression (LEHP) a été développé pour en évaluer les capacités à réduire la période de mise in regime d'entreposage a atmosphere contrôlée (AC). Une simulation a démontré qu'un LEHP peut être conçu pour répondre à la majorité des conditions d'entreposage AC. Tenant compte du transfert de masse, la conception d'un LEHP requiert: 1) une technique de mesure non intrusive permettant l'estimation des paramètres physiques de nuages de bulles générées au bas d'une colonne d'eau afin de caractériser les générateurs de bulles disponibles; et 2) une méthode simple de mesure de la solubilité d'un gaz dans l'eau distillée ou contaminée, les méthodes existantes étant dispendieuse et laborieuse. Une méthode de mesure de bulles basée sur l'analyse d'images digitalisées a été améliorée par: (i) la mise au point d'un paramètre discriminatoire permettant d'identifier les bulles qui sont a l'intérieur d'une distance focale correspondant a une erreur de mesure acceptable; et (ii) la mise au point d'un échantillonneur mécanique de bulles permettant la caractérisation de haute densité de population de bulles. Un appareil simple et peu dispendieux a été mis au point pour determiner la solubilité d'un gaz dans l'eau de différentes qualités. Les résultats obtenus lors de la mesure de la solubilité du CO2, O2 et N2 dans l'eau distillée sont comparables avec a ceux citées dans la littérature. Un LEHP a été conçu, construit et mis a l'essai sous des concentrations de gaz normalement rencontrées dans l'entreposage AC. L'élimination du CO2 a été réalisée, toutefois le LEHP n'a pas suffisamment réduit la concentration de l'O2 pour justifier l'investissement d'un tel appareil.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Raghavan, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j30p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r4135</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fruit -- Storage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vegetables -- Storage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Protective atmospheres</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A736667788"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of non-woven geotextiles for the sealing of earthen manure storage facilities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Raimondo, Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mechanisms by which manures seal soils indicate the need for an interface of fine porosity between the waste's liquid and the porous medium. The objective of this study was to determine if fine porosity geotextiles offer such a possibility as an interface media. Non-woven geotextiles of 20, 30 and 40 micrometers equivalent pore sizes were subjected to heads of 0.9, 1.8 and 2.7 m of 5% total solids (TS) swine slurry for 1800 hours. Infiltration rates decreased from 5 X 10^-5 m/s to less than 1 X 10^-7 m/s and 2 X 10^-8 m/s within 150 and 1000 hours, respectively and all demonstrated minimum seepage rates of 1.3 to 1.8 X 10^-8 m/s after 1000 to 1400 hours; these rates are slightly greater than the 10^-8 m/s guideline established by the Quebec government. Field sealing of geotextiles liners was confirmed using a 20 micrometers fabric subjected to swine slurries of various total solids (TS) concentrations ranging from 1% to 10%. Infiltration rates indicate that satisfactory sealing requires slurries with a minimum TS content of 4%. As well, higher TS levels favour a longer lasting manure seal at the fabric surface. Sterilized manure of 5% total solids (TS) used to simulate cool field conditions or poor biological sealing mechanisms showed that the sterilized manure retained a constant infiltration rate after 1000 hours. The equivalent natural manure, on the other hand, demonstrated an increase in infiltration rates after 1000 hours, indicating that microbial degradation of the manure solids mat had occurred. Seepage for all experiments conducted showed high degrees of contamination, with the highest Chemical Oxygen Demand (COD) concentrations observed for the 2.7 m heads as well as for the 20 micrometers fabric which also gave significantly higher infiltration rates.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barrington, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn39c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736667788</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geotextiles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Farm manure, Liquid -- Storage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Manure handling</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386n641"><ual:graduationDate>1988</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An integrated treatment system for liquid swine manure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fernandes, Leta F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude examine le potentiel d'un système intégré de traitement du purin de pore, incluant une unite de tamisage et un réacteur séquentiel biologique (RSB). Un nouveau procédé mécanique de separation des fractions liquides et solides du purin a été développé. Ce procédé utilise un convoyeur a courroie fait de materiel filtrant continuellement nettoyé par un jet d'air. Les meilleurs résultats ont été obtenus avec un filtre dont les ouvertures avaient 0.1 mm de largeur et avec une charge hydraulique de 35 litres par minute. Pour des boues dont le contenu en matière sèche variait de 2 a 8%, l'efficacité dans l'élimination des solides était de 47 a 60%. Les fractions solides, séparées par le procédé, contenaient de 14 à 18.5% de matière sèche. Des quantités considerables de carbone organique, azote et ses composes ainsi que phosphore total ont aussi été éliminés du purin par le tamisage. La fraction liquide du purin tamise a été traitée dans le réacteur séquentiel, en laboratoire, avec des cycles d'opération de 24 heures. Ce système s'est avéré très efficace pour des temps de retention hydraulique de 7 a 9 jours ainsi que 20 jours pour la retention des solides biologiques. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The present study investigated the feasibility of an integrated system that includes a microscreening unit followed by a sequential batch reactor (SBR) for the treatment of liquid swine manure. A new mechanical device was developed to separate animal waste slurries into semi-solid and liquid fractions using an endless conveyer belt made of filter material which is continuously cleaned by an air knife. The best results for this unit were obtained with a screen of 0.1 mm mesh opening size and a hydraulic loading of 35 l/min. For influent slurries with 2 to 8% dry matter, the solids removal efficiency was between 47 to 60%, and the separated solids contained 14 to 18.5% of dry matter, respectively. Also considerable amounts of organic carbon and nutrients were removed from the influent waste liquid by the microscreening process. The screened liquid manure was treated in a laboratory scale SBR operating on the basis of a 24 hour cycle. This treatment system proved to be highly efficient, since more than 99% of NH3-N, 96% COD and 97% suspended solids removal were achieved in the reactors operating at 7 and 9 days hydraulic retention time and 20 days biological solids retention time. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mckyes, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n411v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386n641</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Manure handling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Swine -- Manure -- Handling</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fm20v"><ual:graduationDate>1988</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Computerized design of efficient water management systems in humid regions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Darbary, Asghar M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The design of drainage systems is becoming more important as competitive uses of our water resources increase. The design of such systems is time consuming and costly. The drafting aspects of the design are repetitive tasks and subject to human errors. A computer can be used for the drafting purposes so that engineers can concentrate on other aspects of the design. Therefore, a new computer package has been developed. The package uses the drafting ability of the MACDRAIN software and the engineering judgments of the DRAINMOD model. The package is capable of optimizing drainage plans for corn fields with the help of an extensive cost calculation routine. The new computer package is of great value to the drainage designer and contractors in terms of cutting the cost and the time involved in producing the drainage plans. The present computer package runs on an IBM PC with 640 Kb memory, a hard disk, and an 8087 math co-processor. The interactive programs are written in compiled BASIC and are designed to be user-friendly and easy to learn. The Graphical Kernel System (GKS) subroutines are used to display the graphic output. All files associated with any one field are written to one diskette for easy retrieval.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A mesure que la demande pour l'eau s'accroit, il devient important que le design des systèmes de drainage soit fait adéquatement. Le design de ces systèmes coûte cher. L'exécution du plan lui m~me est une tâche repetitive et monotone, sujette aux erreurs humaines. Un ordinateur pourrait s'occuper du dessin alors que les ingénieurs se concentreraient sur d'autres aspects du design. C'est pour quai un logiciel combinant les programmes MACDRAIN, pour le dessin, et DRAINMOD, pour les aspects d'ingénierie, a été développé. Ce logiciel est capable, avec l'aide d'un programme détaillé de calculs des coats, de tracer le plan de drainage optimal pour un champs de mais. Ce nouveau logiciel est un atout majeur pour les ingénieurs en drainage et les contracteurs parce qu'il réduit considérablement les coats et le temps requis pour la realisation d'un plan de drainage. Ce logiciel a été conçu pour fonctionner sur un micro-ordinateur IBM PC avec 64Gk de mémoire, un disque dur et un co-processeur 8087. Les programmes, interactifs, ont été écrits et compiles en BASIC et sont faciles a manipuler. Le système graphique Kernel (GKS) est utilise pour les representations graphiques. Taus les fichiers associes a un même champs sont écrits sur une seule diskette, pour faciliter le travail.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Prasher, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t519x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fm20v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pk320"><ual:graduationDate>1984</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimization of continuous sterilization of fluid foods by means of an interactive computer package</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sidaway, Daphne M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thermal treatment of Newtonian and non-Newtonian fluid food was modelled to permit the optimal continuous sterilization temperature to be found. This model was incorporated into a user-friendly, interactive program package. In the program the food residence time distribution function, based on an appropriate rheological model, is initially calculated. The average residence time to satisfy a minimal lethality requirement and the value of an objective function are then found at each of a number of temperatures. The destruction or development of various components such as nutrients, texture, flavour, and colour can be included in the objective function. The importance of the component is indicated by the value of its corresponding weighting factor which is assigned to it by the process designer. The optimal temperature will then be that at which the objective function is a maximum.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le traitement par la chaleur des aliments fluides newtoniens et non-newtoniens a été modelé afin de determiner la temperature optimale de sterilisation continue. Le modelé a été incorpore dans un progiciel interactif facile a l'emploi. En se basant sur un modelé rheologique approprie, le programme calcul d'abord la fonction de la distribution du temps de residence de la nourriture. Le temps de residence moyen requis pour satisfaire aux besoins d'une lethalite minimale et la valeur d'une fonction objective sont alors determines pour des temperatures specifiques. La fonction objective est basée sur la degradation au le développement de diverses characteristiques et composantes de la nourriture telles que les substances nutritives, la texture, la saveur et la couleur. Dans cette fonction l'importance de chaque constituent est indiquée par la valeur de son facteur adjustant. La temperature optimale est done celle pour laquelle la valeur maximale de la fonction objective est obtenue.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kok, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vb65t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pk320</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food -- Analysis -- Data processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sterilization -- Data processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Food -- Microbiology -- Data processing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bs519"><ual:graduationDate>1984</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A continuous flow particulate medium grain processor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pannu, Kulbir S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Un nouvel appareil utilisant le principe de transfert de chaleur pour le séchage des céréales a été conçu et un prototype a été construit. Le sable est d'abord chauffe et ensuite mesure dans un espace cylindrique ferme avec une quantité prédéterminée de mais à haute teneur d'humidité. Les deux produits granuleux sont melanges pendant une période contrôlée et par la suite séparés. Les grains chauffes sont diriges dans un reservoir d'entreposage et l'intrant approprie (sable) est recirculé pour être chauffé à nouveau. Toutes les operations ont été pensées pour accomplir d'après les phases d'un procédé continu. Les résultats indiquent que les conditions désirées sont facilement atteintes et que l'appareil opère à un coefficient d'efficacité de chaleur de 81%.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A new machine utilizing the principle of particle-particle heat transfer to dry food grains by conduction heating was designed and a prototype constructed. Sand was first heated and then metered into a closed annular space with a predetermined mass of high moisture corn. The two granular media were thoroughly mixed for a controlled time period and were then separated. Heated grain was dispersed into holding tanks and the particulate medium (sand) was recirculated for reheating. The process was mode led to accomplish all the above steps in a continuous flow operation. Results indicate that the steady-state temperature conditions are easily achieved and the machine operates at a heating efficiency of 81%.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Raghavan, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt40s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bs519</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fr91t"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Parable interpretation from Julicher to Ricoeur: a critique and alternative proposal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Siverns, Lloyd E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans la première partie de cette thèse, nous faisons une revue de l'histoire de l'interprétation des parabolas du Nouveau Testament depuis l'époque d'Adolf Julicher jusqu'à maintenant. Nous avons détermine différentes façons d'aborder les parabolas, y compris les démarches historique, existentielle, métaphorique et structurale. Dans chaque cas, nous avons note qu'il y avait une tendance a réduire la parabole a une seule idée ou a un seul sens, souvent a une morale avec perte concomitante de la parabole en tant que parabole, c'est-à-dire en tant qu'histoire courte, dramatique présentant un défi au moyen d'une tension perturbatrice ou libératrice. La deuxième partie de cette thèse réunit quelques-unes des raisons pour lesquelles les parabolas ne donnent pas lieu a des interpretations. Nous sommes d'avis que le récit est plus persuasif que l'interprétation et que la narration de la parabole est plus efficace que sa lecture silencieuse. Nous soulignons ensuite le fait généralement oublie que le narrateur original n'est plus parmi nous et que par consequent les sens suggérés par les inflexions de sa voix échappent a l'auditeur contemporain. Dans la dernière section, nous émettons l'opinion que la parabola ne peut pas être interprétée, mais qu'au plus, elle soulève une imagination répondante qui saisit intuitivement la signification et qui raconte sa propre histoire. Des examples de tentatives de raconter a nouveau les parabolas sont donnes mais aucune n'est aussi efficace que la parabole originale et la plupart essaie de résoudre la tension originelle en faisant de la morale. Nous attendons toujours un genie qui jettera des idées fraîches sur ces oeuvres de genie.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In the first part of this thesis I review the history of the interpretation of the parables of the New Testament from the time of Adolf Julicher to the present. Various approaches to the parables are delineated, including the historical, existential, metaphoric, and structural. In each case, I suggest, there is a marked tendency to reduce the parable to a single meaning or idea, often a moral, with a concomitant loss of the parable as parable--that is, as a short, dramatic, story that challenges through a disturbing or freeing tension. The second part of the thesis gathers together some of the reasons why the parable does not lend itself to interpretation. I argue that story is more persuasive than is interpretation and that the parable spoken is a more effective form of communication than is the silent reading of the parable. I then emphasize the usually forgotten fact that we no longer have the original storyteller with us, and therefore the meanings inferred through inflection and tone elude the contemporary hearer. In the final section, my argument is that the parable cannot be interpreted, but at most it gives rise to an answering imagination that intuitively grasps the meaning and tells its own story. Examples of creative attempts to retell the parables are provided, but none is as effective as the original parable, and most attempt to resolve the original tension through moralizing. We still await a genius to speak afresh these works of Genius.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kirby, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zf21v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fr91t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Storytelling -- Religious aspects -- Christianity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jesus Christ -- Parables</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>