<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655m09f"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Haematological changes in rabbits in experimental atherogenesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Silver, Meredith. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Early in 1961 it was brought to my attention that rabbits on a cholesterol diet were said to become anaemic. It was suggested that I perform haemograms on some cholesterol-fed and some normal animals to determine if the anaemia actually occurred. The results of this pilot experiment, recorded in the appendix, showed a significant degree of anaemia in six cholesterol- and fat-fed rabbits as compared with normal blood values in ten rabbits on a diet of unadulterated commercial chow. The animals on the atherogenic diet also showed leucocytesis and a quite marked reticulocytosis. The findings prompted a review of the literature on blood changes associated with atherogenic diets, and related regimes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McMillan, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xg47m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655m09f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anc580r25f"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Glucose-amino acid metabolism in tumour tissues</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shrivastava, Gyan. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tumour tissues in vitro show an incorporation of glucose carbon into glycine, alanine, glutamate and aspartate. The incorporation into glutamate and aspartate is lower than that observed in normal rat brain cortex slices or chick embryo. This may be due to a lower rate of operation of the citric acid cycle compared with that of glycolysis in tumours. When normal rat brain cortex slices are incubated with tumour tissues in vitro, in a medium containing 5 mM 14 glucose-U-C14, there is a decrease in the amount of glutamine found in the brain cortex slices, with a concomitant increase in the incorporation of glucose carbon into glutamate, aspartate and alanine of the tumour tissues.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Quastel, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365864j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580r25f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An870zv20d"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The growth of Japanese-Canadian trade</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shibata, Hirofumi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Before the Second World War, from 1934 to the outbreak of the War, trade between Japan and Canada consisted almost entirely of Canadian experts. Japan imported 4.7 times as much from Canada as she exported to that country. The average value of Canadian imports from Japan in the 1935 to 1939 period was $4,649,000 (Canadian dollars) annually, which accounted for only 0.67 per cent of the average annual value of Canadian imports from the world at this period, (see Table 1.1). After the War, formal Japanese-Canadian trade relations were resumed and by 1951 Japan had a substantial trade deficit with Canada. In 1953, Japanese imports from Canada were more than eight times as large as her exports to Canada; while Japanese exports to Canada in the same year were $13,629,000 (Canadian dollars), which amounted to less than 0.3 per cent of the total Canadian imports from the world.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Asimakopulos, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9677237.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zv20d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xn173"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quantitative studies of nucleoli in various tissues and cell types of the adult mouse</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shea, John. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the time of its discovery (Fontana, 1781; cited by Montgomery, 1898), the nucleolus has been the subject of numerous investigations. The morphology and chemistry of nucleoli, as well as the origin of nucleolar material, have been ably reviewed by Vincent (1955) and by Stich (1956). Although the literature is very extensive, little quantitative data is available regarding the absolute numbers and sizes of nucleoli. Historically, Lebert (1851; cited by Hoffman, 1953) was the first to attempt an assessment of nuclear and nucleolar diameters in animal cells. His measurements of cancer cell nuclei and nucleoli are, however, of little consequence as quantitative information.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leblond, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mr02t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xn173</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azk51vm57z"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The biology of four species of soil-inhabiting collembola</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sharma, Ganga. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Soil animals, of which micro-arthropods constitute a very high proportion, do not merely play a subsidiary role in the formation of different humus forms, but a most decisive one (Kubiëna, 1955). In order to know more about this role, however, it is necessary to understand something of the biology of these animals. Now, the Collembola are among the most abundant soil arthropods both as regards numbers of species and numbers of individuals, but although some published information on the biology and life-histories of some species exists, it is surprising how little is in fact known.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kevan, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tw12k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vm57z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236586t"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Centrally mediated autonomic cardiovascular responses to drugs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Share, Nathan. N.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Noradrenaline is present in postsynaptic sympathetic neurones, being located both in the adrenergic nerve fibers and in the ganglia from which these fibers originate. More recently noradrenaline was also shown to be present in mammalian brain (Rabb, 1943A, 1943B; von Euler, 1946). That noradrenaline is the chemical transmitter substance liberated by postsynaptic sympathetic neurones is now generally accepted. Whether or not noradrenaline has a functional role at synaptic levels is still unknown.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Melville, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408168h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236586t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354j840"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Andrew Marvell: a study of his miscellaneous poems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shakespear, Nelly. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The critic facing Andrew Marvell's ‘Miscellaneous Poems’ is beset by a number of problems. Although it is but a small collection, its range of subject-matter, of style, and of quality is enormous. It is difficult to see how the lyric perfection of some of the more famous poems can have come from the same pen as the shapeless inanities of ‘A Dialogue between Thyrsis and Dorinda’, or how the delicacy of feeling and sensitivity of expression of ‘On a drop of Dew’ and ‘The Nymph complaining for the death of her Faun’ can have been born out of the mind that was guilty of the callousness and grossness evinced in the satires. Just as noticeable is the disparity between the metaphysical intensity of some of the lyrics and the bantering, cavalier levity of others.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Malloch, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547w06b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354j840</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128f61p"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Energy exchange through an annual sea ice cover</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schwerdtfeger, Peter</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Determination of the energy fluxes resulting from incident solar radiation is fundamental to an understanding of the physical conditions pre- vailing at any point on the earth's surface. Comprehensive work on the balance of thermal energy in temperate regions has been performed and reported, particularly by Thornthwaite and Halstead, (TH54). However, results of similar completeness are lacking for oceanic regions, a fact illustrated by the omission of detail for these areas in Budyko's world atlas of heat balance, (Bu55). The determination of the energy budget is particularly interesting in the Arctic, where an immense latent heat is involved in the freezing and subsequent melting of the oceans.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gold, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bj50p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128f61p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tq56f"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Static and spin-orbit forces from Chew-low theory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schiff, Mortimer</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new calculation is performed of the force between nucleons due to their participation in an exchange of π mesons. The approach is semi field theoretical, but one reduces the essentially relativistic scheme to the situation where one can place a potential function V in the two nucleon Schrödinger equation. In an adiabatic approximation one calculates the change in energy in the system due to the meson exchange activity between the two nucleons a fixed distance apart. When one allows the quasi-static nucleons to move by including Laplacian operators for them in the total Hamiltonian, a spin orbit potential emerges. The calculation is performed up to an exchange of two mesons. Multiple scattering corrections to the potential are accounted for by using the one meson approximation of Chew and Low. An empirical hard core is affixed. In that, also, Chew's values of the cut-off factor and the renormalized coupling constant are used, the calculation fit a within the framework of the Chew-Low theory. The results finally are compared to the empirical ones of Gammel and Thaler, but the agreement is not good.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sharp, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462885j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tq56f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94ht27b"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La correspondance et son utilisation littéraire dan ‘La Comédie Humaine’.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schecter, Estelle. E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>De tous les artifices techniques employés par Balzac pour donner à La Comédie Humaine le mouvement et la variété de la vie, l'utilisation des lettres est l'un des plus remarquables. Balzac en effet se complaît à rédiger des missives de toutes sortes, depuis la lettre d'affaires truffée de chiffres jusqu'au billet-doux le plus galant. Il accompagne fort souvent ces compositions de commentaires qui attestent du plaisir que lui a procuré leur rédaction et montrent amplement que le romancier les a insérées volontairement dans un but précis: peindre un caractère, nouer une situation, renseigner le lecteur, surprendre l'attention, inspirer la crainte, déclencher le drame- bref, que Balzac leur assigne une place de choix dans son arsenal littéraire.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Launay, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q069w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94ht27b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848v087"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Determination of C-C bond dissociation energies in 1-butyne and 1,2-butadiene</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schaffer, Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bonds are broken and formed in all chemical reactions. A knowledge of the dissociation energies of the relevant bonds helps one to predict the ease by which a given reaction may take place. It is obvious, therefore, that such information is useful in deciding which reactions should be included in the overall mechanism of a complex system. The dissociation energy of the bond R1-R2 in the molecule R1R2 is defined as the endothermicity of the reaction in which the bond R1-R2 is ruptured with the formation of two free radicals R1 and R2.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sehon, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128f62z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848v087</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r470s"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Choice of law in contracts of international carriage by air</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sand, Peter. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A Dutch aircraft, on its way from Geneva to London, has an accident in Belgium. One of the victims, a Frenchman domiciled in Denmark, had purchased his ticket in Stockholm. Which law applies to the claims of the passenger's widow against the carrier: Dutch, Swiss, English, Belgian, French, Danish, or Swedish law? Of this kind of hypothetic cases, frequently presented in writings on air law, McNAIR says: "Far-fetched though these examples may appear at first sight, they are by no means beyond the realms of possibility."</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rosevear, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qt51p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r470s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Air and Space Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0v8384137"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular recombination in a supersonic nozzle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Salter, Graham. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The object of the investigation described in this report was to determine the effects of different diluent gases on the recombination of nitrogen dioxide to nitrogen tetroxide in a supersonic nozzle. The diluent gases chosen for the investigation were helium, nitrogen and carbon dioxide because of their widely different molecular weights. A test facility was constructed to supply a measured mixture of heated diluent gas and nitrogen dioxide to a two-dimensional, glass sided, Mach 2 nozzle. The distribution of the concentration of nitrogen dioxide along the centre-line of the nozzle was determined by an optical means, the results being interpreted by use of the Beer-Lambert law.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Swithenbank, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wh167.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v8384137</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zs05f"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of the nonconformist religions on the character of the British Labour Movement, 1875-1895</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saint, Julia. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1875 the Nonconformist churches were numerically the strongest religious group in England and Wales: out of a total population of approximately 20 million, just over 1.5 million were members (as opposed to adherents) of the various Nonconformist denominations. The greater part of their membership came from the middle and upper-labouring classes; the Congregational Church - the largest of the Dissenting groups - had become, on its own admission, an almost exclusively middleclass institution. Of the various sects within the Methodist Church, the Primitive Methodists (150,000 members) and the Welsh Calvinistic Methodists (93,000 members) were most closely in touch with the laboring classes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cx86j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zs05f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gp57z"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Torsion, shear and bending in reinforced concrete beams</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saeed, Mirza. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tests on four concrete beams with transverse-longitudinal steel ratio varying from zero to 1.86 are reported. The strength of the rectangular reinforced concrete beams, all of which fail due to direct shear and torsion, agree favourably with the tensile strength of concrete determined from indirect tension tests. Initial cracks occurred in all the beams at a load corresponding to a combined shear stress of 346 psi in an unreinforced section under combined bending, shear and torsion. Results indicate that the shear reinforcement ceases to be fully effective as the Pt/p+p' ratio approaches and exceeds unity. Moreover the concept of a transition from elastic to plastic states of stress is proved by the results. Expressions have been derived for the stresses and unit angle of rotation for the central section of the beam remaining plane. The results of the limited number of tests appear to agree well with the modified theory.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>De Stein, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881q62z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gp57z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53x041q"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The moisture balance of Barbados and its influence on sugar cane yield</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rouse, Wayne. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Barbados has the distinction of a one crop economy, that crop being sugar cane. This situation has existed for over 500 years, and during the latter part of this period, particularly since 1924, the cane breeding section of the Department of Agriculture has carried on extensive work in developing high yielding varieties of sugar cane especially suited to the island. The nature of investigation has, however, being virtually confined to this one direction, and study of the other important growth factors such as edaphic and especially climatic control has lagged far behind. Fortunately in 1959 a microclimatic station was set up at Waterford under the auspices of the Geography Department of McGill University, and in the last 2 years a considerable knowledge of various climatic parameters has been amassed, and an insight into the moisture balance regime achieved.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hare, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zj030.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x041q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5t34sn93k"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Distortion of the triton core in the hypernucleus H4</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roth, Charles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this investigation is to use an adiabatic approximation in considering two distortions of the triton core in the hypernucleus ^H4. Firstly, the core is allowed a uniform radial expansion and contraction due to the presence of the ^ particle. Secondly, the core can assume an ellipsoidal shape from its original spherically symmetrical form, the volume remaining constant, to first order. The results indicate that both distortions are significant. The maximum reduction of the r. m. s. radius of the core is 24.2%, with a consequent reduction of 12.6% for the mean value of the well depth for the^ - nucleon potential, necessary to bind the hypernucleus.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sharp, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623h152.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sn93k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9306t292m"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comparative study of analog and digital techniques of analysis applied to dynamic closed loop systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roggeveen, Roland. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Over the past decade, the ability of the engineer or scientist to solve problems requiring mathematical analysis has been greatly enhanced by the introduction of electronic calculating machines. The abilities and promise of these machines cover such a wide scope, that probably no other technological development in this decade, if in any decade, holds as much promise for human betterment. Many problems that once had to be left unsolved because of the limited abilities of classical mathematics, can now be answered. More important than the absolute limit of man's capabilities are the numerous problem solutions that these machines have brought within economic feasibility.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>D’Ombrain, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bx922.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t292m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237hw28s"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Preparation of an isolated loop for experimental studies on fat absorption in dogs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rodriguez, Jacinto</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Notwithstanding extensive studies carried out by numerous investigators in this field, the exact mechanism of fat metabolism still remains unknown. However, it would be uncorrect to state that no significant advances have been made in recent years. As a matter of fact, the new methods available have enabled biochemists, pathologists and clinical investigators not only to re-search, (quoting Dr. Skoryna), some of the older findings, but also to throw some light on the intricate processes in fat absorption which were unapproachable by older methods.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Skoryna, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032654d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hw28s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b230z"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spallation of erbium</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rayuda, Garimella. V.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nuclear reactions, in which a highly energetic particle (or photon) bits a nucleus and knocks out one or more nucleons or clusters of nucleons, are called ‘spallation’ reactions. The study of spallation reactions, in particular the study of 'excitation functions’ - variation of production cross section with incident energy - is a simple and often very useful means of investigating the mechanism of nuclear reactions. As discussed later, excitation functions for spallation reactions may be divided roughly into two classes, those for which the threshold is in the region where the Bohr compound nucleus mechanism is said to be applicable ( &lt; 50 Mev), and those with the threshold in the Serber knock-on region ( &gt; 50 Mev).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yaffe, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k600k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b230z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rz16x"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Social mobility in the home-building industry in Montreal, 1951-1961</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rawin, Solomon. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The subject of this study is social mobility as presented in one sector of the Canadian economy - in the home-building industry. The research was centered upon intra-generational change within the lower end of the stratification scale, particularly upon mobility of wage-earning labourers who became self employed workers and small businessmen. A sample of contractors engaged in the home-building industry was investigated and detailed information concerning individual career histories was sought with the view to answering the following questions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Solomon, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386p141.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rz16x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s607s"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stereochemical studies of substituted tetrahydropyrans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Puskas, Imre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Sachse and Mohr (1) were the first theoreticians to recognize that the cyclohexane ring can exist in chair and boat conformations. At room temperature the kinetic energy of the molecule is sufficient to supply the activation energy for ring interconversion, therefore no pure conformation can be isolated although the more stable chair form is the predominant one. Hassel and Ottar (2) pointed out the different nature of the cyclohexane substituents which are now called equatorial and axial. They also realized the greater thermodynamic stability of equatorially substituted cyclohexanes as compared to axially substituted ones.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Edward, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gm03r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s607s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dz871"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The increase in the number of cells and nuclei of skeletal striated muscle during postnatal growth in the rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Puddy, Della. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The growth of the animal body, or any of its constituent organs and tissues is observable to all as a gradual increase in size. It is possible to study growth at several levels. It may be measured at the level of the organism proper; at the level of the tissues or organs; at the level of the cells and now, by chemical methods, even at the level of molecules. However, a growth is analyzed into its constituent parts, the problems of expressing the process have become manifold. Indeed, as Weiss (1949) staged, “It (growth) is not even a scientific term with defined and constant meaning, but a popular label that varies with accidental traditions, predilections, and purposes of the individual or school using it.”</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Enesco, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mn504.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dz871</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p392f"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The distribution of substances with acetylcholine-like activity in subcellular particles from brain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Proulx, Peter</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Acetylcholine (ACh) is widely accepted as a neurotransmitter substance. The marked physiological activity of this substance could have been suspected from the early pharmacologic studies of Hunt and Taveau who demonstrated its intense depressor activity. Later, Ewins isolated it from specimens of ergot which had depressor action on organs supplied by autonomic nerves. Dale then found that this depressor activity was similar to that of muscarine-like substances and that this effect could be abolished by atropine. The same author also showed that ACh could easily be inactivated by an esterase present in tissue.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hosein, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02871063c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p392f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698c23d"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The hexokinase system of the erythrocyte</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Prevost, Charles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The writer has developed an assay for estimation of optimal hexokinase activity in stroma-free hemolyzate, and shown that hexokinase remains stable and active for at least 30 days in human erythrocytes preserved in CD or ACD at 4 °C. Addition of ADP or DPN to the assay medium could increase the enzyme 1s activity; nicotinamide or alloxan depressed it. It is suggested that failure of glycolytic activity during preservation is not therefore due to the formerly supposed lability of hexokinase, but to inhibition of hexokinase attributable to falling pH and ATP, and conditions favouring glucose-6-P accumulation such as decrease of phosphofructokinase, DPN and ADP. Pyruvate produced in cells during the first 15 days of storage tended to be expelled into the external medium. Cyclic adenylate was utilised by the human red cell, as evidenced by conversion of its ribose moiety into lactic acid with concomitant esterification of inorganic phosphate into the stable phosphate fraction.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denstedt, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj1395663.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698c23d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>