<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52j9942"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Laboratory testing of envelope materials for pipe drains</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rehman, Shafiq-ur</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Soils which were known to have caused sedimentation problems in drain pipes were used in the investigations. Different envelope combinations such as soil-fabric, soil-gravel and soil-sand-fabric were evaluated. Nine 100 mm diameter, 250 mm high permeameters were used to determine the functioning of envelope materials and to improve the criteria for testing of envelope materials. To obtain a clear indication of success/failure of an envelope, a wide range of hydraulic gradients and different thicknesses of soils and envelopes were used. The most effective thicknesses were, 5 cm of soil with fabrics and 2.5 cm of soil plus 7.5 cm of gravel for gravel envelopes. All the fabrics were successful in retaining the soil particles. No clogging was observed and higher flow rates were measured in fabrics having 2 to 3 mm thicknesses with openings O$ sb{95}$ finer than 100 $ mu$m. SCS criteria (1988) with the following modifications: $ rm D sb{100}0.3$ mm for gravel; and $ rm D sb{100}&lt;9.5$ mm for crushed rock mixed with sand are suggested. The performance of envelopes meeting these criteria were successful. The laboratory tests show that the use of a fabric with river sand as an envelope has a very good potential for successful field operation. There was no laboratory evidence to reject the functioning of this concept.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Broughton, R. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h383k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j9942</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Drainage pipes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geotextiles -- Testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Subirrigation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848s54x"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthetic studies on a(1,2)-mannans and preparation of a mannosidase inhibitor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rafai Far, Adel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Attempts to design a novel mannosylation were carried, unsuccessfully, on in situ generated 3,4,6-tri-O-benzyl-$ beta$-D-mannose-1,2-sulfite, and on 3,4,6-tri-O-benzyl-$ beta$-D-mannose-1,2-carbonate, with sequential treatments with bromotrimethylsilane and with glycosyl acceptors in the presence of a base. Trials were then conducted on Lewis acid catalysed mannosylations with the two above compounds, and the use of the in situ generated 3,4,6-tri-O-benzyl-$ beta$-D-mannose-1,2-sulfite with a mixture of chlorotrimethylsilane and zinc triflate in glycosylating simple alcohols was successfully demonstrated. However this activation was insufficient to build disaccharides using 1,3,4,6-tetra-O-benzyl-$ alpha$-D-manno-pyranose, methyl-2,3,4-tri-O-benzyl-$ alpha$-D-glucopyranoside and methyl-2,3,6-tri-O-benzyl-$ alpha$-D-glucopyranoside as acceptors. A mannosylating agent, namely 2-O-acetyl-3,4,6-tri-O-benzyl-$ alpha$-D-mannopyranosyl trichloacetimidate, designed for the synthesis of 1,2-mannans was prepared, and used to build a benzylated 1,2-mannan trimer. $ alpha$-D-Mannopyranosylmethylamine-p-nitrophenyl-triazene, a mannosidase inhibitor was prepared by a slight modification of the literature procedure, for future use, in order to alkylate the active site of certain substrate specific $ alpha$-mannosidases.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chan, T. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w4430.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s54x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207tr38g"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ivermectin selection and characterization of the life history traits of Heligmosomoides polygyrus (Nematoda)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Njoroge, Joyce Muthoni</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A stock "parent" (S) strain of the mouse parasite Heligmosomoides polygyrus was exposed to increasing levels of ivermectin at the L4 stage for 15 generations. A Passage line was also developed from the parent strain parallel with the ivermectin selected line to control for the effects of rapid passage of the parasite from host to host during drug selection. A dose titration trial indicated 1.5 fold resistance had developed in the ivermectin selected strain at the 8th generation (IVM-8) both at the L4 and adult stage. A higher dose of drug was required to kill the L4 stage compared to the adults at generation 8. Additional selection pressure for 7 generations (IVM-15) did not change the resistance status of adult worms. The Passage strains (P-8 and P-15) remained susceptible to drug. The life history traits of the parent strain (S), the ivermectin selected (IVM-8 and IVM-15) and the Passage (P-8 and P-15) strains were then compared. Eight generations of selection with ivermectin (IVM-8) resulted in an increase in establishment 8 days post-infection (pi) but decreased egg output and worm burden over 4 months compared with strain S. However these effects were not seen after 15 generations of drug selection. The ivermectin selected strain (IVM-15) had similar establishment, egg production and worm burden as the parent strain (S). Establishment in strain P-8 was intermediate and not different from S or IVM-8 however 15 generations of passage (strain P-15) resulted in higher establishment and more rapid development to adult. This was also reflected in the net egg output and worm burden during the first month of infection. There were no differences in per capita fecundity among the five strains. Environmental pressure exerted by passage of H. polygyrus from host to host rather than ivermectin selection caused shifts in some life history traits of this nematode.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Scott, M. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c260z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tr38g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ivermectin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drug resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heligmosomatidae -- Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c474g"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Economic welfare analysis of coarse grain trade under a trade liberalization policy within the Economic Community of West African States</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nayeyo, Anita Huba</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study analyzed the economic welfare implications of the 1990 intraregional trade liberalization scheme within the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) on member country producers and consumers. Four countries were chosen as a point of focus: Burkina Faso, Cote d'Ivoire, Ghana and Mali, and two commodities: millet and sorghum. The supply and demand functions were estimated using time series data from 1970 to 1990 obtained at the level of administrative regions within each of the four countries. Optimal production, consumption, trade quantities and trade flows were determined using the REACTT model, a spatial price equilibrium solution algorithm. Two trade scenarios were simulated. The first examined trade flows under the 1990 tariff structures and the second examined trade flows under the proposed zero tariff rates. The REACTT model results showed that removal of the tariffs would increase the crossborder trade flows between the four countries by about 12% for millet and 38% for sorghum. The welfare calculations showed that in the case of millet, all four countries would have net positive gains to the tune of $4.6 million in total. For sorghum, Burkina Faso, Ghana and Mali would have net positive gains, C ote d'Ivoire would have a net welfare loss, and the net impact on all four countries would be a positive gain of about $9.3 million. The results of the REACTT model and the welfare calculations suggest that intra-ECOWAS trade liberalization would increase total trade flows and total economic well being of the member countries.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gunjal, Kisan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h63x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c474g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Free trade -- Africa, West</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grain trade -- Africa, West -- Econometric models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economic Community of West African States</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386m48f"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of a nitrogen soil test for fertilizer requirements for corn and wheat production in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Miransari Mahabadi, Mohammad Reza</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One must consider the effects of both soil N and fertilizer N, if rates of N-fertilizer application are to be optimized and NO$ sb3 sp-$ leaching into groundwater be controlled. Objectives were (1) to determine soil $ rm NO sb3 sp-$-N and NH$ sb4 sp+$-N, soil total N, and N fertilizer levels and corn and wheat yields; and, (2) to determine soil sampling times and depths for N analyses that correlated with yields and fertilizer N response. Soil samples taken at seeding and postseeding were analyzed for NH$ sb4 sp+$-N and NO$ sb3 sp-$-N, and for total N in 29 wheat sites and 44 corn sites fertilized with four rates of N. N-Trak (quick test) and laboratory methods were employed to measure soil NO$ sb3 sp-$-N. A significant correlation was found between N-Trak and laboratory methods (R$ sp2$ = 0.61$ sp{**}$ for corn and 0.89$ sp{**}$ for wheat). Compared to the laboratory method, N-Trak overestimated soil NO$ sb3 sp-$-N. Soil NO$ sb3 sp-$-N levels increased upon drying. In some cases soils showed an increase in soil NO$ sb3 sp-$-N from seeding to postseeding. Wheat yields and wheat grain N uptake were better correlated with soil NO$ sb3 sp-$-N at seeding than at postseeding. For corn, yields and grain uptake showed a higher correlation with soil NO$ sb3 sp-$-N at postseeding. Corn regression models predicted 180 to 240 kg ha$ sp{-1}$ of N fertilizer to obtain optimum economic yields and 0 to 40 kg ha$ sp{-1}$ N for wheat. Soil total N was not correlated with corn yields as highly as soil NO$ sb3 sp-$-N. Soil NO$ sb3 sp-$-N can be used as an indicator of fertilizer N requirements for corn and wheat in Quebec.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mackenzie, A. F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm97r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m48f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content -- Measurement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Fertilizers -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nitrogen fertilizers -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wheat -- Fertilizers -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n204123t"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the intracellular sorting of the two myelin-associated glycoprotein isoforms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Minuk, Jeffrey</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Myelin-associated glycoprotein (MAG) is amongst the earliest expressed myelin specific proteins. Its precise function remains unknown, though evidence supports a role for cell-cell adhesion. MAG may also act as a spacer molecule and could be involved in signal transduction. MAG is expressed as two isoforms, designated as L-MAG and S-MAG. Both share identical extracellular and transmembrane domains but differ in their cytoplasmic domains. L-MAG is expressed earlier during myelination than S-MAG. These features, as well as others, suggest that the isoforms have different functions. To confirm this hypothesis, both isoforms were expressed transiently and stably in Madin-Darby canine kidney (MDCK) epithelial cells and the localization of the isoforms was studied. In both transiently and stably transfected cells, L-MAG sorted primarily to the basolateral membrane. In single transfected cells, S-MAG sorted primarily to the apical membrane. When groups of adjacent cells became transiently transfected, S-MAG accumulated at areas of cell-cell contact within the basolateral membrane. In stably transfected cells S-MAG sorted to the basolateral membrane. The data suggest that L-MAG contains an invariable basolateral sorting signal, but that the sorting of S-MAG is dependent upon extrinsic factors, such as the co-expression by adjacent (contacting) cells. As MDCK cells sort the MAG isoforms differently, these data support the hypothesis that the MAG isoforms do perform different functions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Braun, Peter E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515q53s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204123t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dr65m"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of group B streptococcal meningitis on cerebral prostanoid levels and blood flow regulation in the newborn</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mertineit, Carmen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effect of a heat-killed, unencapsulated strain of type III group B streptococcus (GBS), COH 1-13, on cerebral blood flow (CBF) and prostanoid production was investigated in two separate piglet models. In the first model, we examined the temporal profile of changes in CBF and cerebrospinal fluid cytochemistry in response to GBS challenge during a 6 hour study period. Despite marked leukocytosis at 6 hours, GBS did not significantly affect CBF and other cardiovascular parameters, hematology and cerebral prostanoid production. In the second model, we evaluated the early effect of GBS on CBF autoregulatory function and subsequently employed pharmacologic agents to inhibit the effect of GBS. Cerebral perfusion pressure (CPP) was altered by inflating balloon-tipped catheters placed at the aortic root to produce cerebral hypotension and at the descending aorta to produce cerebral hypertension. Piglets inoculated with GBS exhibited a narrow range of CBF autoregulation due to an impairment at the upper limit of CPP, which was prevented by treatment with dexamethasone or ibuprofen. Cerebral prostanoid production did not change significantly with adjustments in CPP between the various treatment groups. We conclude that GBS may impair CBF control without affecting cerebral prostanoid production and may increase the risk of brain damage in neonates with bacterial meningitis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Aranda, J. V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p677q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr65m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w678x"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of HLH transcription factors in POMC gene expression</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McDonald, Scott, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The pro-opiomelanocortin gene encodes protein precursor expressed primarily by the anterior pituitary corticotrophs and intermediate lobe melanotrophs. Pituitary expression of the POMC gene provides a paradigm for studying both tissue-specific and hormonally-regulated gene expression. The POMC promoter is composed of at least 13 different regulatory elements binding many different classes of transcription factors. There are several E-box sequences present in the POMC promoter, including elements DE-2C, CE-1A, and CE-1B. E-box elements bind members of the helix-loop-helix family of transcription factors. These factors exhibit either ubiquitous or cell-restricted expression patterns. The DE-2C element binds cell-specific HLH factors termed CUTE (Corticotroph Upstream Transcription Element) binding factors. This study examines the role of the ubiquitous HLH transcription factors on POMC expression. Northern blot analysis revealed that all of the ubiquitous HLH factors, Pan 1, Pan 2, HEB, and ITF-2 are expressed in POMC-expressing AtT-20 cells, as is the neurally-restricted factor Mash-1. Overexpression of these factors revealed that the ubiquitous factors act on the CE-1B E-box, but not the DE-2C nor CE-1A elements. This finding was confirmed with gel retardation analysis; CE-1B binds overexpressed ITF-2, whereas DE-2C does not. Finally, the activity of the DE-2C element cannot be reconstituted in a non-POMC expressing cell line with the ubiquitous HLH factors alone. Collectively these experiments define a new transcriptional element contributing to POMC gene expression, CE-1B. The ubiquitously expressed members of the HLH family activate POMC transcription through this element; however, these factors alone cannot account for the activity of the CUTE factors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>ovin, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j995b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w678x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb397b27q"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Tillage forces and soil loosening as influenced by tool geometry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maswaure, Justin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A field tillage tool carrier was constructed using a tractor trailer, hydraulic cylinder and steel construction material. Tillage tool blades of varying lengths, widths and angles of attack were fabricated from steel and were used in the study of the effect of tool rake angle, tool width and depth of operation on soil strength properties, draft, draft efficiency, volume of soil manipulated, degree of soil loosening and penetration resistance. The results showed that the draft increased with tool rake angle and width. Operating at a depth of 150 mm and 100 mm depth did not make any significant difference on the draft requirement. Low angles of attack were observed to have a greater potential to loosen the soil, and the loosening increased to a depth of 150 mm then decreased. The draft efficiency was affected by the angle of attack as well as the depth of operation. The cross sectional area of the furrow and hence the volume of soil manipulated was seen to depend on the width of the tool and the operating depth. Slender tools and high rake angles were found to loosen the soil better than wide ones. No distinct trend existed between depth to width aspect ratio and draft requirement. No variation was observed between draft efficiency and d/w ratio. Penetration resistance increased with depth of operation as well as distance from the furrow centre after tillage. Some areas of residual high strength were sometimes left within the sphere of influence of the tools. Some tools dealt with these omissions better than others.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McKyes, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10ws370.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397b27q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tillage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soils -- Density</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tillage -- Equipment and supplies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440v75f"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Assessment of the agricultural value of sugar refinery by-products</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Massicotte, Luc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The sugar refinery process used by Lantic Sugar Ltd generates three by-products having characteristics that give them potential as soil amendments or fertilizers, particularly as a phosphorous and calcium source. Laboratory and a field trials were conducted in order to examine the changes in agronomic properties of soil produced by the application of these residues. During the laboratory experiment, the by-products examined were spend bone char (SBC), filter-press mud (FPM), clarification scum (SCU) and a compost (COM) produced using FPM and SCU, where as in a field experiment, COM, SBC and a mixture (MIX) made of FPM and SCU, were compared to a commercial fertilizer (TSP) and non-treated soils. The orthic humic gleysol of clay texture and low pH soil conditions in which the field experiment was conducted resulted in high P fixation of all the applied residues. Contrasts analysis showed that TSP behaved as the soils unamended P for all nutrient concentrations in tissues over two cropping seasons (1993 and 1994), on two crops, namely wheat (Triticum aestivum, L.) and corn (Zea mays, L.). Treatments (residues at different rates of application) did not significantly increase the Ca levels in COM plots nor did they increase the wet aggregate stability of soil under either crop. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fyles, Jim</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n414.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v75f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Factory and trade waste as fertilizer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Organic wastes as fertilizer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sugar -- Manufacture and refining -- By-products</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bk22f"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of variants within the coding region and 5'-flanking region of the k-casein encoding gene in Holsteins using PCR-RFLP and PCR-SSCP analyses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Masoudi, Mehrnoush</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Single-strand conformation polymorphism analysis (SSCP) and restriction fragment length polymorphism analysis (RFLP) were used to determine the genotype of Holsteins at the $ kappa$-casein ($ kappa$-CN) locus. A 432-bp fragment within exon IV containing nucleotide substitutions diagnostic of the A- and B-variants of $ kappa$-CN was amplified using the polymerase chain reaction (PCR). The sires from the earliest years of the AI industry had a significantly higher (p $&lt;$ 0.01) frequency of allele than sires in modern usage. These data indicate that selection or milk production parameters may discriminate against the B-allele. SSCP analysis was also used for detecting polymorphisms within the regulatory region of $ kappa$-CN gene. A 640-bp fragment within the 5$ sp prime$-flanking region of bovine $ kappa$-CN gene which contained the TATA box, CAAT box, and exon I was amplified using PCR. The SSCP analysis of this fragment revealed no variation, possibly due to the lower detection efficiency of SSCP with large fragment size. Nested primers were, therefore, designed to amplify fragments of 234- and 486-bp. Polymorphism was detected only in the 486-bp fragment and the two variants were designated M$ sb1$ and M$ sb2.$ The allelic frequencies of M$ sb1$ and M$ sb2$ in bulls used by AI industry before 1970 were 0.67 and 0.33, and in bulls used by AI industry after 1980 the frequencies were 0.68 and 0.32, respectively. The frequency of these alleles were not significantly different in Holsteins used by AI industry before 1970 and after 1980. Unlike the apparent change in frequency of the A- and B-variants noted within exon IV, this polymorphism seems to have not responded to selection. However, a higher frequency of M$ sb1$ allele appeared to be associated with B-variant (exon IV) genotypes. The presence of these variants within the regulatory region may possibly be involved in the quantitative expression of $ kappa$-CN gene. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zadworny, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm33p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bk22f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Casein</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genetic polymorphisms</dc:subject><dc:subject>Holstein-Friesian cattle -- Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2227mr974"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of nucleoside analogues on human immunodeficiency virus type-1 infection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harris-Marois, James-Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Human immunodeficiency virus type-1 (HIV-1) reverse transcriptase (RT) is essential for the formation of the viral double-stranded stranded DNA genome from its RNA template. Blockage of this catalytic function by reverse transcriptase inhibitors leads to inhibition of viral replication. Although 3$ sp prime$-azido-3$ sp prime$-deoxythymidine (AZT) is the most successful anti-viral drug to date, its prolonged use results in the emergence of AZT-resistant viral isolates. Several mutations are consistently found within the reverse transcriptase gene of AZT-resistant viral isolates. Although it is generally accepted that these mutations are responsible for the drug-resistance phenotype, the exact mechanism by which this occurs is poorly understood. For example, cloned viruses harboring these mutations show resistance to AZT in tissue culture, yet recombinant HIV RTs that contain these resistance-conferring "mutations" do not show increased inhibition constant (K$ rm sb{i})$ values for AZT as compared to wild type RTs. By in vitro infection, polymerase chain reaction, and reconstituted in vitro reverse transcription assays, we have confirmed previous observations (Arts 1994c) that AZT preferentially terminates HIV-1 nucleic acid elongation after the first template switch. We have also shown that nucleoside analogues are more effective chain terminators in situations in which deoxynucleotide triphosphate pools are limiting. Pre-treatment of cells with AZT prior to infection had a stimulatory effect on generation of viral DNA, but only in the case of AZT-resistant variants and not wild-type strains of HIV-1.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wainberg, Mark</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zd172.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mr974</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A736666668"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A numerical investigation of the February 1993 snowstorm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mac Gillivray, Karl</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite considerable research in the study of explosively deepening oceanic storms, much less attention has been paid to coastal secondary cyclogenesis that is characterized by weak baroclinicity but heavy precipitation. In this thesis, the development of one such storm, the February 1993 cyclone, is investigated using a high-resolution version of the Canadian Regional Finite-element (RFE) model in which more realistic physical representations are incorporated. It is shown that the improved RFE model reproduces extremely well the timing and location of coastal secondary cyclogenesis along the Carolina coast, the evolution of the associated surface pressure perturbations and tropospheric baroclinic waves. The model also performs remarkably well in predicting the distribution and intensity of the storm's precipitation over the New England states, Quebec and the maritime provinces. It is found that the coastal secondary cyclogenesis occurs in response to the low-level inshore advection of warm and moist air from the maritime boundary layer and the approach of the midtropospheric short-wave trough associated with a decaying cyclone to the west. Rapid deepening of the cyclone ensues as intense precipitation falls along the warm and cold frontal zones. Diagnosis of a series of sensitivity simulations reveals that large-scale dry dynamics, latent heat release, air-sea interaction and surface characteristics act in concert to determine the cyclone's intensification and evolution. It is found that the low-level thermal advection contributes more to the cyclogenesis during the incipient stage, whereas the upper-level trough control the cyclone's rapid deepening at later stages. Overall, latent heat release accounts for about 50% of the total deepening. It is also found that ice microphysics (i.e., melting of snow) could indeed induce a thermally indirect circulation superposed onto the mean flow in the vicinity of the rain-snow boundary, but it has a weak negative impact on the cyclogenesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zhang, Da-Lin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v9810.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736666668</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t4086"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Misclassification bias in epidemiologic studies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liyanage, Nilani</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Misclassification of disease and/or exposure is a common and potentially serious problem in epidemiologic studies. The impact of misclassification may be profound and may invalidate results. Despite the fact that there have been a number of articles published on the significance of misclassification bias, many epidemiologic studies are carried out with little attention paid to this issue either in the design or the analysis. The goal of this thesis is to provide clarifications on issues surrounding misclassification of exposure in case-control studies. Specifically, the conditions under which misclassification is likely to occur, the potential impact on effect measures and how misclassification can be prevented through design and corrected for in the analysis are discussed in detail.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wolfson, Christina</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827d68s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t4086</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Biostatistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Statistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289m001"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The bee venom test : a new tonic-pain test</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lariviere, William R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study describes a new test of tonic pain in rats which can be used as an animal model of persistent pain. In the first experiment, the response to subcutaneous injection of various doses of bee venom into the hind paw of the rat was quantified. The second experiment investigated the effect of morphine and aspirin on the response to an intermediate dose of bee venom. Finally, the third experiment examined the response to concurrent injections of bee venom and formalin. Subcutaneous injection of bee venom produced local inflammation, marked edema, and tonic pain responses. Increasing doses of bee venom produced higher mean pain scores and increased durations of responding. Pain responses lasted up to approximately one hour and the inflammation and edema were virtually gone by 8 hours with the lower doses of bee venom tested and by 2 days with the two highest doses tested. Analgesia was produced by morphine and aspirin, indicating that the bee venom test can be used to test analgesic drugs. Concurrent administration of bee venom and formalin produced responses similar to formalin alone, with an increased duration of responding at higher intensities. The data suggest that the bee venom test is a valid animal model of experimental tonic pain.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Melzack, Ronald</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n535c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m001</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Analgesia -- Animal models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pain -- Animal models</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860896w"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Kinetics of bond failure in receptor-mediated cell adhesion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kwong, Dennis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Measurement of the physical strength of bonds linking in biological cells is important in characterizing adhesion processes in circulation. We describe measurements of the hydrodynamic force required to separate doublets of latex spheres cross-linked by receptor-ligand bonds. Previous work with the blood group antigen-antibody system (Tees et al., Biophys. J. 65: 1318-1334, 1993), showed that rupture of receptor-ligand bonds is a stochastic process, both time and force-dependent. The present work extends this study to a protein-protein system, with the receptor, an IgG antibody linked to latex microspheres, either covalently or by physical adsorption, cross-linked via the Fc region by the ligand, Protein G. The normal force at break-up, F$ rm sb{n},$ acting along the doublet major axis in a linear shear field was computed using previously derived equations with the measured shear stress and doublet orientation (Tha and Goldsmith, Biophys. J. 53: 677-687, 1986). The break-up of doublets in Couette flow, tracked individually under the microscope, as well as of populations of doublets was studied at F$ rm sb{n}$ from 20 to 260 pN using a counter-rotating cone and plate Rheoscope. Break-up of doublets bearing covalently bound IgG was both time and force dependent; the fraction breaking up increased markedly with increasing force. In a population of doublets, the fraction broken up increased with duration and magnitude of F$ rm sb{n},$ and decreased with increasing ligand concentration. Doublets of physically adsorbed IgG spheres required significantly lower F$ rm sb{n}$ than doublets of covalently-linked IgG spheres for the same degree of break-up, likely due to surface detachment of IgG molecules rather than rupture of receptor-ligand bonds. Using a stochastic model of break-up (Bell, Science 200: 618, 1978), and a Poisson distribution for the number of bonds, results of the above experiments were simulated and bond parameters determined for this receptor-ligand system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Goldsmith, H. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n9928.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860896w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biophysics, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82k926h"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of sugar maple (Acer saccharum Marsh.) and black walnut (Juglans nigra L.) on soil fertility : preliminary assessment of their agroforestry potential</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kipkech, Francis Chepkonga</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two studies were carried out in the Morgan Arboretum of McGill University to explore the agroforestry potential of some native tree species of Southern Quebec. In the first study, soil chemical characteristics under basswood (Tilia americana L.), white ash (Fraxinus americana L.) and bitternut hickory (Carya cordiformis Wang. K. Koch) in relation to sugar maple (Acer saccharum Marsh.) were assessed in natural stands. Soil pH was highest under white ash and was lowest under bitternut hickory. Soil NO$ sb3 sp-$ was low under basswood compared to white ash. Soil pH and exchangeable soil Ca$ sp{2+}$ and Mn$ sp{2+}$ decreased with an increase in basal area and exchangeable soil K$ sp+$ decreased (p = 0.07) with an increase in the proportion of sugar maple relative to total basal area. In the second study, the effects of black walnut (Juglans nigra L.) on growth and nutrient content of lettuce (Lactuca sativa L.), kale (Brussica oleracea L.), parsley (Petroselinum crispum) and Swiss chard (Beta vulgaris L.) in an alley cropping system were determined. The experiment was carried out in a randomized complete block design with repeated measures. All vegetables survived in the black walnut plantation and in the open field. The order of sensitivity to growth under black walnut was Swiss chard $&gt;$ kale $&gt;$ lettuce $&gt;$ parsley. Low light intensity in the plantation likely decreased plant dry weights and nutrient content. Generally plant N, P and K concentrations were higher in the plantation while Ca, Mg and Mn concentrations were higher in the open field, possibly due to an antagonistic effect of high soil K$ sp+$ content in the plantation and to inhibitory effects of black walnut.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cote, Benoit</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246v03q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k926h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sugar maple -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Eastern black walnut -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil fertility -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hedgerow intercropping -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053j193"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Results and conjectures related to the sharp form of the Littlewood conjecture</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Keliher, Liam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Let $0&lt;n sb1&lt;n sb2&lt; cdots&lt;n sb{N}$ be integers for $N in{ rm I !N},$ and let $ lambda sb1, lambda sb2, ..., lambda sb{N}$ be complex numbers of modulus 1. If $f( theta)= lambda sb1e sp{in sb1 theta}+ lambda sb2 e sp{in sb2 theta}+ cdots+ lambda sb{N}e sp{in sb{N} theta},$ and $g( theta)=e sp{i theta}+e sp{2 theta}+ cdots+e sp{iN theta},$ then a conjecture originally proposed by Hardy and Littlewood states that $ int sbsp{0}{2 pi} vert g( theta) vert sp{p}{d theta over2 pi} leq int sbsp{0}{2 pi} vert f( theta) vert sp{p}{d theta over2 pi}$ for $0&lt;p leq2,$ and that the inequality is reversed for $2&lt;p&lt; infty.$ This paper investigates the current state of this conjecture, presenting cases in which the conjecture has been proven to be true.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Klemes, Ivo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm992.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053j193</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj96022953"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of serotonergic ligands on latent inhibition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jakob, Andrea F. (Andrea Frances)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Latent inhibition (LI) is the attenuation in the acquisition of Pavlovian conditioning to a conditioned stimulus (CS) due to prior extensive exposure to that CS. It is assumed that LI is an animal model of attention in that animals learn to ignore the preexposed CS. The present series of experiments investigated the effects of selective serotonergic (5-HT) ligands known to increase 5-HT neurotransmission on LI using a conditioned emotional response (CER) procedure. In experiment 1, rats preexposed (PE) to 40 presentations of a tone CS acquired CER suppression more slowly than vehicle-treated nonpreexposed (NPE) animals, suggesting LI was obtained. Administration of 10 mg/kg fluoxetine (i.p.) did not influence CER acquisition in PE animals, suggesting that LI was not affected by fluoxetine. However, it was assumed that 40 CS presentations exerted a powerful LI effect, which might mask any effect of fluoxetine. Consequently, we assessed the effects of 5-HT ligands on LI following 10, rather than 40, CS preexposures. Under these conditions, both acute fluoxetine (experiment 2), and chronic (14 day) fluoxetine (experiment 3) administration, were found to augment LI. Experiment 4 suggested that acute administration of the 5-HT2 agonist DOI (2.5 mg/kg) also enhances LI. Experiment 5 revealed that 1 mg/kg 8-OH-DPAT did not influence LI, suggesting that postsynaptic 5-HT1a receptors are not involved in LI. These results suggest that enhancement of 5-HT neurotransmission enhance LI and that this effect is mediated, in part, through the 5-HT2 receptor subtype. The results are discussed within the context of the switching model of LI, which suggests that the effects of 5-HT are mediated through the modulation of the mesolimbic dopamine pathway.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rochford, Joseph</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k012d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j96022953</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Psychobiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Experimental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214r193"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Changes of spontaneous excitatory postsynaptic currents in rat hippocampal pyramidal cells induced by desensitization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ghamari Langroudi, Masoud</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>What determines the amplitude and the time course of spontaneous excitatory unitary events is not well understood. Desensitization of fast AMPA/K channels has been shown to be fast enough to shorten individual quantal responses. However, it is not known whether the desensitization is uniform nor is it known what determines the relation between amplitude and rise or decay times in absence of desensitization. Both the rise and the decay times are essentially amplitude-independent in control conditions, but become markedly amplitude-dependent after desensitization has been suppressed by aniracetam. Strong amplitude-dependence of the rise and decay times suggests that in absence of desensitization the process(es) that determine(s) the time course of unitary events is/are concentration-dependent. Highly nonuniform, and strongly amplitude-dependent desensitization can be explained by its concentration dependence. The scatter of both rise and decay times about the best fitting lines was also amplitude-independent in control conditions. It increased markedly and in an amplitude-dependent manner after addition of aniracetam. The same factors that determine mean values probably determine the scatter as well.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Glavinovic, Mladen I.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg871.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r193</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50tt72m"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigation of methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase in vascular disease and neural tube effects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Frosst, Phyllis D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase catalyzes the reduction of 5,10-methylenetetrahydrofolate to 5-methyltetrahydrofolate, a carbon donor for the remethylation of homocysteine to methionine. Patients with severe MTHFR deficiency have $&lt;$20% residual enzyme activity, moderate hyperhomocysteinemia, vascular lesions and neurological dysfunction. Mildly-deficient individuals with a thermolabile enzyme are at increased risk for developing cardiovascular disease. Two MTHFR sequence changes were identified. The first was a C to T transition at bp 764 altering a proline to a leucine codon; this change was found in one severely-deficient patient. The second was a C to T transition at bp 677, substituting a valine for a highly-conserved alanine codon. The $ rm A to V$ substitution was identified on 35-40% of chromosomes. Expression of the $ rm A to V$ mutation in prokaryotic cells revealed increased thermolability over the wild-type enzyme. Genotyping for the $ rm A to V$ mutation in three vascular disease studies showed that it was associated with mild hyperhomocysteinemia, a risk factor for vascular disease. The preventative effects of folate supplementation on the occurrence and recurrence of neural tube defects (NTDs) have been repeatedly demonstrated. The curly-tail (ct) mouse model for NTDs was used to investigate the involvement of MTHFR in these defects. Ct mice had significantly increased homocysteine levels although differences in MTHFR activity were not demonstrated. The mouse MTHFR gene was mapped to distal chromosome 4, close to the major gene for NTDs in ct. MTHFR is suggested as a candidate locus for the ct defect.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rozen, Rima</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n3225.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt72m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neural tube -- Abnormalities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Blood-vessels -- Diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Folic acid deficiency</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gg062"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Paramètres de blindage photonique d'une salle de radiothérapie</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Frenière, Normand</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Space constraints often present the greatest challenge in determining the lay-out of specific radiotherapy installations. To fulfill these constraints high density concrete is often employed in construction. We have undertaken a study to establish the transmission of primary, leakage and scatter radiation through a particular type of high density concrete. In the course of this study various characteristics of leakage and scatter radiation from a 10 MV linac have also been investigated. The results of these studies are reported in this thesis. To establish the correct chamber configuration required for the characterization of the transmission factors for primary, leakage and scatter radiation and to determine the scatter-to-incidence dose ratio a, we have measured the build-up curves and verified the validity of the inverse square law for these different radiations. The build-up data for the radiation scattered from a humanoid phantom at different angles from the primary axis have shown that even at low scatter angles little to no build-up is required for scatter radiation measurements.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Podgorsak, Ervin B.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Schreiner, L. John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881p08z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg062</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gn00m"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Isolation and characterization of a putative enhancer sequence flanking a polyomavirus transgene</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fahmy, Ramez</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Our laboratory has produced six lines of mice harbouring the polyomavirus Large T-antigen (PVLT) transgene. Mice of all lines express PVLT in testis and three lines develop testicular adenomas. However, mice of a single line, designated MTPVLT-8, express PVLT exclusively in testis and cardiac tissue. These mice develop cardiac hypertrophy and die prematurely. We hypothesize that expression of PVLT in cardiac cells is a consequence of transgene integration near a cardiac specific enhancer element. To support this hypothesis, DNA flanking the transgene was isolated and tested for inclusion or any possible regulatory elements. A restriction map of genomic DNA surrounding the transgene integration site was constructed as a starting point. A lambda clone containing 5-10 Kb of the 5$ sp prime$ flanking DNA was isolated and used for a sequence of experiments. This DNA sequence did not cross-hybridize with DNA isolated from other species and appears to be mouse specific. Northern analysis demonstrate a sequence homology to a single RNA transcript appearing to be expressed in a wide variety of mouse tissues. A gene-bank comparison on a sequenced part of the clone resulted in an 89% sequence homology match with human gualadyn gene sequence. Although a regulatory element was not evident in the preliminary work, we are now in a position to attemp cloning various parts of the clone into expression vectors containing easily assayable reporter genes. Due to lack of appropriate cell lines, in vivo experimentation must be performed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chalifour, L. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c2617.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gn00m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sc32b"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the cognitive modulation of Vestibulo-Oculomotor performance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fadlallah, Hussein</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The object of this study was to investigate the scope of cognitive control over vestibulo-ocular reflex (VOR) performance during rotational vestibular stimulation. Human subjects, with head fixed to the body, were rotated in the dark through 20$ sp circ$ at 40$ sp circ$/s while trying to "look" at an earth-fixed target which was viewed straight ahead just before extinguishing the lights. During this rotation an apparent error of performance was systematically introduced by displacing this target at constant velocity through 12$ sp circ$, either in the same direction as the subject (Diminishing paradigm), or in the opposite direction (Augmenting paradigm). After cessation of rotation the target was re-illuminated and the subject allowed to see the final positional "error" of his/her oculomotor performance. During each trial they were asked either to try and CORRECT or NOT to CORRECT for the extrinsically induced "errors". In a subsequent, series of experiments, 2 hrs of synchronous rotation of the subject and the surrounding visual scene was used to produce adaptive attenuation of the VOR ($ approx$26%). The central component of the second experimental series was performance of the gaze stabilization test described above, conducted on the adapted subjects. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Melvill-Jones, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w4448.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sc32b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Physiological</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gn01w"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Kinetics of phosphorylation and dephosphorylation reactions in the Escherichia coli chemotaxis signal transduction system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Evagelidis, Alexandra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The net result of the Escherichia coli signal transduction pathway is the modulation of the direction of flagellar rotation, which in turn controls the swimming behaviour of the cell. We investigated the effect of different factors on the rates of CheY phosphorylation and dephosphorylation, utilizing purified proteins and working at appropriate time scales. Furthermore, we defined the kinetics for phospho-transfer from CheA to CheY and for CheY dephosphorylation under a standard set of conditions. Having established these assays we were now in a position to determine how other components of the chemotaxis system, such as receptors, CheW, and CheZ influence the rate of CheY phosphorylation and dephosphorylation. In addition, we investigated the rates of CheB phosphorylation and dephosphorylation. CheB, the chemotaxis methylesterase, is phosphorylated by CheA in much the same fashion as CheY and therefore has the potential to compete with CheY for phospho-CheA. By investigating the kinetics of CheY and CheB phosphorylation and dephosphorylation, we hope to acquire a better quantitative understanding of the chemotaxis signal transduction system. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stewart, R. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm981.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gn01w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>