<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ast74cq99m"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A Monte Carlo approach to the validation of a pencil beam algorithm used in treatment planning for conformal beam radiosurgery with static fields</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bélec, Jason</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Stereotactic radiosurgery with several static conformal beams  shaped by a micro multileaf collimator (muMLC) is used for treating small  irregularly shaped brain lesions. Specific requirements for this technique are a  precise localization and positioning of the target (1mm) and a precise (1mm) and  numerically accurate (+/-5%) dose delivery. In this work, a pencil beam algorithm  based treatment planning software BrainScan 5.2 (Brainlab, Germany) is validated  against measurements (diode, radiographic films) and Monte Carlo simulations  (BEAMnrc and XVMC codes). The latter is required because of difficulties in  obtaining precise and accurate dose measurements for small fields. A dedicated muMLC  component module for the BEAMnrc code was developed as part of this project. Results  show that Monte Carlo calculations agree with measured dose distributions to within  2% and/or 1 mm except for field sizes smaller than 1.2 cm where agreement is within  5% due to uncertainties in measured output factors. Comparison with the pencil beam  algorithm calculations were performed for square and irregularly shaped fields at  different incidence angles on rectangular and humanoid homogeneous phantoms. Results  show that the pencil beam algorithm is suitable for radiosurgery although some  differences were found in the comparison of interleaf leakage and beam profile  penumbras.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g566g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cq99m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics, Medical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Radiation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9880vr54v"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Survey of the techniques for developing and using user profiles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bao, Qing, 1980-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The rapid evolution of e-commerce brings more and more interest  in personalized services for each individual user. As a key component of  personalization, user profiles become the center of attention, and have been widely  studied with seriousness. This thesis is a survey on main aspects of the user  profiles, focusing on techniques for developing and using user profiles, including  introduction and discussion on privacy and security considerations, and  international standards. In addition, the thesis considers the future direction of  user profiles.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k3174.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vr54v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848r13g"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Predictors of the decline in physical activity observed in adults from two communities of low-economic status in Montreal, Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Weiss, Deborah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study assessed the predictors of the decline in physical  activity levels observed over the course of a 5 year longitudinal cohort of adults  aged 18--65 living in two low-income, inner-city neighbourhoods in Montreal. The  current study made use of data collected as part of Coeur en Sante St. Henri, an  intervention program designed to decrease cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk factors.  A two-stage cluster telephone survey of a representative sample of residents was  used to collect information on a variety of lifestyle behaviours. Multiple logistic  regression was used to assess the independent predictors of decline in leisure time  physical activity in 626 subjects. Significant predictors of the decrease in  physical activity include age (OR = 1.0 (1.0, 1.1) and BMI (OR = 2.0 (1.1, 3.6), and  a composite index assessing self-efficacy pertaining to physical activity (OR = 2.0  (1.2, 3.2), in males. In females, significant predictors include lack of energy (OR  = 2.4 (1.2, 4.6), perceived lack of athletic ability (OR = 2.4 (1.1, 5.2), not using  a neighbourhood facility for physical activity (OR = 2.8 (1.6, 4.7), BMI (OR = 2.1  (1.2, 3.7), and a composite index assessing self-efficacy pertaining to physical  activity (OR = 2.1 (1.3, 3.5).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paradis, Gilles</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m229b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848r13g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sociology, Public and Social Welfare</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9z903053q"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of a dwelling-referenced geographic information system to characterize urban tuberculosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wanyeki, Ian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Using ArcView 3.2 software, all active TB cases reported in the  former city of Montreal 1996--2000 were precisely geo-coded, that is mapped to the  corresponding residential address. For comparison, using a case-cohort approach  control dwellings were randomly selected from the municipal dwelling GIS, with a  10:1 ratio. We identified 595 case and 5950 control dwellings. Census tract data  from the 1996 Canadian Census as well as dwelling characteristics from the Montreal  housing database were attributed to both case and control dwellings. Multivariate  logistic regression was used with dwelling status (case vs. control) as the  dependant variable, to evaluate the independent influence of crowding and other  socio-demographic factors. A high-precision housing GIS complemented census data in  pinpointing and characterising the occurrence of TB in Montreal. It provided a more  refined assessment of the impact of local crowding, after adjustment for other  important factors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Olson, Sherry</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Schwartzman, Kevin</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415p9945.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903053q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sg918"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analyse des limites juridiques à la liberté de manifester pacifiquement au Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Forget, Patrick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines critically the most important restrictions  placed on the right to peaceful demonstration in Canada. Protected by the Canadian  Charter of Rights and Freedoms as a matter of constitutional law, the right is  limited by a network of civil and penal sanctions in such a way that, in practice,  its exercise is considerably restricted. Firstly, the protection afforded to owners  of land under the law of property excludes all peaceful demonstration on private  property without permission of the owner. Tossed as it is into the street and onto  the sidewalks, the activity may also be seen to disturb other interests protected by  law in the public domain. It is not infrequent that injunctions are brought against  peaceful demonstrations on the grounds that they disrupt public order, that they  harm the economic interests of private parties, or that they are the occasion for  mischief or damage to property. In addition to the limits that originate in the law  of civil liability, peaceful demonstration is restricted by criminal law, in  particular the prohibition against unlawful assemblies, which permits the police to  exercise a control over a demonstration and to intervene in order to prevent  anticipated outbursts. The rules relating to the infraction of unlawful assembly  allow the authorities to disperse the demonstrators at the first sign of tension in  what amounts to a willful confusion, by the legislature, between acts of protest and  acts of violence. Overall, the scope of this network of civil and penal sanctions is  such as to suggest that the right to peaceful demonstration is something of a false  promise.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Macdonnal, Roderick A.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45q954r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sg918</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Demonstrations -- Law and legislation -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88ch10s"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Legal aspects of launching and operating spacecraft</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fiallos Pazmiño, Luis Fernando</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Over the last years, the number of commercial space activities  has increased tremendously. Technological developments have been the main reason in  the emerging of new services that use space infrastructure. In order to provide  these new space services, it is necessary to launch and operate  spacecraft. Complying with the laws and regulations of the launching and  operating activities is one of the most relevant issues that prospective spacecraft  operators may face in this complex industry. This work compiles the legal sources to effectively launch and  operate spacecraft destined for commercial space applications. Its goal is to  identify common constraints that operators may find in the process of licensing and  acquiring orbits or radio frequencies and the national/international legal  principles, which govern spacecraft operations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jakhu, Ram</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k48c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ch10s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Space law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Launch vehicles (Astronautics) -- Law and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429968c"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The hot deformation of A1 containing TRIP steels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Heun-Ho, Hong, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>For TRIP steels to be included as a future structural steel in  automobile industries, the drawbacks associated with high silicon (more than 1%)  must be solved. To this end, TRIP steels, with aluminum as a substitute for the  silicon, have been under investigation by many groups. In this work, the approach is to investigate the effect of hot  deformation on the microstructure and the mechanical properties of the aluminum  containing TRIP steels. The problem with these steels is that the strength is  reduced compared to classical Si TRIP steels. In this work, a number of mechanisms  could contribute to the strengthening, including refining the austenite grain and  work hardening of ferrite. These may also affect the retained austenite  characteristics. Two different C-Mn-Al TRIP aided steels with aluminum contents  of 1.43 wt % and 2.0 wt % were investigated and compared with a typical TRIP steel  containing 1.5 wt % Si. To determine the critical hot working temperatures, the  FactSage software was used to predict the phase diagram and the critical  temperatures were confirmed by heat treatment and metallography of the quenched  specimens. Using these data, hot deformation experiments were performed to  investigate the influence of the deformation temperature and the strain within the  intercritical region by using a Gleeble simulator. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xm40d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429968c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f1706"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Robust bandwidth extension of narrowband speech</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hsu, Wei-shou, 1981-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Telephone speech often sounds muffled and thin due to its  narrowband characteristics. With the increased availability of terminals capable of  receiving wideband signals, extending the bandwidth of narrowband telephone speech  at the receiver has drawn much research interest. Currently, there exist many  methods that can provide good reconstructions of the wideband spectra from  narrowband speech; however, they often lack robustness to different channel  conditions, and their performances degrade when they operate in unknown  environments. This thesis presents a bandwidth extension algorithm that  mitigates the effects of adverse conditions. The proposed system is designed to work  with noisy input speech and unknown channel frequency response. To maximize the  naturalness of the reconstructed speech, the algorithm estimates the channel and  applies equalization to recover the attenuated bands. Artifacts are reduced by  employing an adaptive and a fixed postfilter. Subjective test results suggest that the proposed scheme is not  affected by channel conditions and is able to produce speech with enhanced quality  in adverse environments.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xc399.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f1706</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278t56f"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the characterization of optical waveguides</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Isac, Andrei D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents the realization of a characterization  method for optical waveguides in terms of propagation loss. The method employs a  highly linear video camera aided by a personal computer running image processing and  analysis software. After a brief theoretical overview, the design of the  experimental set-up and its realization are introduced. Several optical waveguides  are examined using the present method and loss values are obtained for various  channel waveguides built on silicon substrates, with the experimental results  detailed for two such wafers. The advantages and limitations of the method are also  briefly discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn9997277.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278t56f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d56zx055"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microcapsules combining alginate, chitosan, poly-l-lysine and polyethyelene glycol for liver cell transplant and cell therapy applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haque, Tasima</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Liver diseases are the eighth leading cause of death in North  America. Currently, liver transplant is the available treatment for patients with  liver failure. However, the shortage of donors and the requirement of  immunosuppressant remain a disadvantage. Microencapsulation of living cells is an  emerging technology which may serve as an alternative therapy for patients requiring  organ transplants. One of the limiting factors in the progress of such therapy is  attaining a biocompatible and mechanically stable polymer. In the following thesis,  a novel microcapsules combining alginate, poly-l-lysine, chitosan and polyethylene  glycol (ACPPA) was designed and evaluated for its use in the treatment of liver  failure. In vitro studies were also conducted to compare the novel membrane, with  other microcapsules, including the widely studied APA microcapsules as well as  alginate coated with chitosan (AC), APA with PEG (APPA) and AC with PEG (ACP).  Results show that the novel membrane can support liver cell proliferation and  function and is capable of providing cell immuno-protection. The study reveals that  chitosan and PEG containing microcapsules can be an alternate material for cell  microencapsulation to be used for live cell delivery and other biomedical  applications. Further in-vivo studies are recommended to evaluate the full  potentials.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sq66t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zx055</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n203z679"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Clock and data recovery circuitry for high speed communication systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ho, Wen Tsern 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The maturing of the telecommunications industry has seen the  development and implementation of devices that work at high frequencies of the  electromagnetic spectrum. With the rapid deployment of optical networks, there is an  increasing demand for low-cost and efficient communications circuitry. In order to  interface with such high frequency signals at lower cost, there has been a recent  push for very high frequency circuits using low-cost fabrication technologies like  digital CMOS. This thesis investigates the usage of legacy architectures and  the implementation of different topologies using digital CMOS technology. Various  Clock and Data Recovery Phase-Locked Loops have been implemented using a 0.18mum  CMOS technology, and the process from modeling to actual implementation will be  presented. The design of the components of the loop, layout issues, and the  performance of the various designs will be discussed. New fully-differential CMOS  designs that are optimized for high-speed operation, yet providing stable lock with  minimal jitter, with a targeted operation range from 1 GHz to 7 GHz, will be  described in detail, as well as their operation and optimization.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b41m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n203z679</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881m51t"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Breadth over depth in evolving game strategies using genetic algorithms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haidar, Ali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Traditional search methods have always suffered from both  spatial and temporal expansion, especially when exploring deeply in search trees. In  this thesis, an optimization technique that reduces the search tree depth and at the  same time maintains the same quality of search is proposed. This research examines  the Genetic Algorithm methodology as a new technique for evolving optimal strategies  by evolving the best weights for the evaluation function. Moreover, this research  demonstrates the hypothesis of breadth over depth by showing how an increase in the  number of features in an optimized evaluation function in a minimax tree can lead to  a reduction in the required search depth. This thesis also investigates the  performance of certain types of parallel processing techniques that can be used to  reduce the processing time of the Genetic Algorithm. The Awari game is used as the testing model in this thesis. This  game has captured the attention of many Artificial Intelligence researchers and  computer scientists, due to the number of strategies and calculations  involved. It was shown that by coming out with an appropriate  representation using the Genetic Algorithm and the added number of features, the  value of a deeper search can be overcome and thereby reduce the overall response  time and the memory usage. The concept of breadth over depth as proposed in this thesis was  found to be successful and would be very useful in areas that require the use of a  search tree.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m7156.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m51t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214p64h"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Manufacturing execution systems integration and intelligence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hadjimichael, Basil</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to survive in today's competitive manufacturing  markets, manufacturing systems need to adapt at an ever-increasing pace to  incorporate new technology which can lower the cost of production, while maintaining  quality and delivery schedules. The task of the manufacturing system becomes even  more challenging in the quest to use a common approach for different manufacturing  plants and ever evolving manufacturing processes for specific plants. This thesis  introduces a reference architecture that enables such changes between plants and  updates within plants. For this, we use the paradigm of Manufacturing Execution  Systems (MES). A developed MES architecture by the National Institute of Standards  and Technology (NIST) is used as the standard reference architecture. Its  flexibility and scalability is applied to a specific steel melt-shop plant case  study. In this case study the standard framework is specified through re-labeling  standard data and modules to specifics tailored for the melt process of a generic  steel plant. Since steel plants are faced with difficult scheduling and disturbance  handling problems, specific intelligent algorithms are developed to deal with these  issues through integrating some of the control into the MES. Conclusions as to the  success of the algorithms along with supporting data and recommendations of further  use for them are also included.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dm90c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214p64h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Industrial</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17ct477"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>FDTD analysis of antennas close to human tissue</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Han, Qingsheng, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Finite-Difference Time-Domain (FDTD) is a numerical method often  used to analyze interaction of electromagnetic radiation with complex  geometries. In this work, we use FDTD method to compute electromagnetic  fields in the near-field of several antennas types. These antennas include bowtie  antenna, "Dark Eyes" antenna, quarter-wave monopole antenna,  monopole-helix antenna and patch antenna. Each one of these structures is modeled  and numerically tested using the FDTD-based software, which allows us to incorporate  detailed models of the human anatomy in the simulation. We test antennas in two application scenarios: cell phone  radiation and breast cancer detection. For cell phone radiation, we study the  maximum average SAR (Specific Absorption Rate) in the human head model exposed to  radiation from antennas used typically in mobile telephones: quarter-wave monopole  antenna, monopole-helix antenna and patch antenna. Breast cancer detection with pulsed microwave radiation requires  broadband antennas. Characteristics of the bowtie antenna and "Dark Eyes"  antenna were studied in the vicinity of a simplified breast tissue model. Special  attention is given to comparison of the trans-receiving antennas' sensitivities to  the backscattered response from a simulated embedded tumor.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/707958249.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct477</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bh80x"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Simulation and control of an underwater hexapod robot</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Georgiades, Christina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>AQUA is an underwater hexapod robot which uses its paddles to  propel itself and to control its orientation. The use of oscillating paddles for  propulsion and control represented a novel and challenging problem, which motivated  the need for a simulation of the motion of the robot based on its paddle  oscillations. The most difficult aspect of this simulation was the characterization  of the forces generated by the paddles oscillating in the water. In this work, a  model predicting the forces produced by an oscillating rigid paddle was developed  and validated experimentally. Also, the forces produced by a flexible fin were  determined experimentally and were compared to those generated by the rigid paddle.  Rigid paddle and flexible fin experiments were performed on an experimental setup,  which was designed and built to measure the forces and torques produced by a paddle  oscillating in a water tank. Finally, a simulation of the AQUA robot was developed,  based on the validated rigid paddle model.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g3296.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bh80x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s3007"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Theory and analysis of a distributed synchronous clocking method</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gross, David, 1976-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>With decreasing transistor sizes and increasing circuit  complexity, managing the clock skew becomes an increasingly important and  challenging task. A novel method of generating and distributing a synchronous clock  to multiple nodes in a distributed system will be presented here. Using phase-locked  and delay-locked loop techniques, the system establishes total synchronization by  adjusting the internal delay between nodes so that all inter-node delays become  equal. Matlab Monte-Carlo simulations of an ideal 8 node system are presented which  validate the theoretical description as well as gauge the performance of any  realistic implementation. A simple yet realistic HSPICE model is used to simulate  random configurations of an 8 node system to help support the theory as well as the  Matlab conclusions.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wj90w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s3007</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak3569513s"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design and development of a cam-driven laboratory ball mill</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Geng, Lei, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In mineral processing industries, grinding processes can be  defined as the particles reduced in size by a combination of impact and abrasion. It  is performed in tumbling mills that describe a class of mills delimited by a  cylindrical chamber filled with balls and/or rock that rotate around its  longitudinal axis. Tumbling mills, whether they are autogenous, semi-autogenous,  ball or rod, are classed according to the nature of the discharge as centre  peripheral discharge mills, end peripheral discharge mills, overflow mills, and  grate discharge mills. These mills are used in at least three industries: mining,  cement and metal powders industries to grind different materials (ore, clinker and  metal powder) to desired quality specifications as principally described by a size  distribution. These tumbling mills range in size from small 0.3 m diameter lab mills  to a 16 m diameter semi-autogenous industrial mill and are driven by chain and  sprocket (lab mills), gear and pinion (pilot and industrial scale mills) and  gearless drives in very large diameter mill (8 to 12 m dia.). All of these mill  drives present advantages and limitations. In this thesis, we focus on the design and development of a  cam-driven laboratory ball mill. An alternative drive system is presented that uses  a newly patented speed-o-cam technology and applies it to a 5 ft diameter lab mill.  We introduce polynomials to modify the cam profile around both the cusp and the  blunt point of the profile to improve pressure angle and shock impact. We build  models of mechanical systems, simulate the full-motion behavior of the models, and  analyze multiple design variations. We integrate the theoretical, virtual and  experimental analyses in order to design an optimal mechanical system. Moreover, the  analysis of static and dynamic forces of cam mechanism is reported in the  thesis.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x86n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569513s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A765371795"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A haptic interface for editing space curves with applications to animation authoring</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Garroway, Diana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Animators working with 3D models and data typically are still  bound to 2D interaction simply because input devices, such as mice, and display  devices, such as graphic screens, are 2D. We present a new multi-modal interface for  editing 3D motion data. We explore the use of a haptic device for intuitive input  and feedback in 3D. Animators are allowed to create 3D animations in a uniform  environment that permits interactive editing of the space curves. In the basic mode,  the haptic device guides the hand of the user along a trajectory that was previously  specified as an animation. Editing can be accomplished by assigning an  elasto-plastic behaviour to the object. This interface provides a simple, intuitive  method for one user or several participants to actually experience movement, other  than visually, for purposes of creation.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bf499.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765371795</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avd66w048s"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Durability design of concrete elememts [sic] against deterioration of bond due to corrosion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bansal, Vipin Kumar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The main objective of this research program is to formulate a  framework for durability design of concrete elements against deterioration of bond  at the steel rebar-concrete interface due to corrosion of reinforcing bars. Mass  loss of the reinforcement is an important parameter in defining the corrosion level.  Therefore, it can be used to develop a correlation between corrosion, cracking and  bond strength at the steel rebar-concrete interface. A preliminary design equation  for prediction of bond strength at different corrosion levels is presented.  Secondly, the existing state of the art of design of concrete elements for  durability against deterioration of bond due to corrosion is  established. The results indicate that initially the bond strength increases  with corrosion, which lead to the formation of a firm layer of corrosion products on  the steel rebar-concrete interface, thereby improving the bond strength  characteristics slightly. However, at higher levels of corrosion, a firm layer of  corrosion products transforms into a flaky layer resulting in the deterioration of  bond. Following this stage, the bond strength decreases almost linearly with the  increase in mass loss. A preliminary design method for durability against  deterioration of bond due to corrosion is proposed, which will help the practicing  engineers with the evaluation and amelioration of the existing infrastructure and  with the design of new concrete infrastructure for durability against corrosion of  reinforcing steel.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719m93f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w048s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nh63z"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Activity and stability of caffeine demethylases found in Pseudomonas putida IF-3</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beltrán Roldán, Juan Guillermo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to establish the viability of using a biological system  to decaffeinate coffee, a bacterium (Pseudomonas putida IF-3) capable of living on  caffeine as its only source of carbon and nitrogen was studied. Resting cell  suspensions and cell-free extracts of P. putida IF-3 were tested to assess their  ability to degrade caffeine, and to determine their capacity to retain activity at  different temperatures. A method to quantify cell lysis was developed; this method  allowed comparison of cell free extract and resting cell caffeine degradation rates.  Caffeine degradation rates for cell free extracts were found to be 55 times faster  than previously reported P. putida data. Resting cells degraded caffeine 12 times  faster than cell free extracts, at 22°C. However, both systems were  equivalently active at 50°C. Finally, resting cells were found to be more  stable than cell free extracts; this was significantly more evident at 50°C  than at 22°C.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cw846.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nh63z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1v53jx55m"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis and secretion of apoC-I and apoE by human SW872 liposarcoma cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wassef, Hanny</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Apolipoprotein C-I (apoC-I) plays an important role in the  metabolism of plasma triglyceride levels and cholesterol metabolism. Little is known  about the regulation of apoC-I production by human adipocytes. Aim. To investigate  the effect of different tissue culture conditions on the synthesis and secretion of  apoC-I and apoE in human SW872 liposarcoma cells and to study the effects of apoC-I  overexpression in these same cells. Methods. SW872 cells were grown in DMEM/F-12  (3:1, v/v). QPCR was used to quantify mRNA synthesis. ELISAs were used to quantify  intracellular and extracellular proteins. Colorimetric reaction kits were used to  analyze intracellular cholesterol and triglyceride concentrations. Results .  Maturation experiments revealed that after 17 days in culture, SW872 cells contained  significantly more cholesterol (100%) and triglyceride (3-fold). Cell maturation was  associated with significantly higher levels of apoE mRNA (+200%) but not apoC-I mRNA  (-50%). The cells secreted more apoC-I (+110%) and apoE (+340%). Cellular apoC-I  increased 620% and apoE increased 1540%. Treatment of cells during maturation with  insulin (0, 10 or 1000 nM) significantly reduced the secretion of apoC-I and apoE  (-14% and -56%, respectively) and intracellular apoC-I and apoE (-10% and -12%,  respectively. Overexpression of apoC-I in SW872 cells resulted in increased cell  number (+70%) and decreased lipids per cell (-32% triglyceride, -36% cholesterol) as  compared to controls. Conclusion. These results suggest that apoC-I and apoE  production is differentially regulated at the transcriptional level in adipocytes  and that apoC-I and apoE play a role in the maturation of human adipocytes and may  have an important role in mediating or regulating cell lipid accumulation. As well,  overexpression of apoC-I in SW872 cells impedes cellular lipid accumulation and  stimulates cellular proliferation.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dq202.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jx55m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Liposarcoma</dc:subject><dc:subject>Adipose tissues</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apolipoprotein C</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apolipoprotein E</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lipids -- Metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9w032360x"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Soil substrate selection for urban trees under deicing salt and compaction conditions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, ShuHong</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effects of high sodium chloride (NaCl) levels on Na and  nutrient retention of three soil substrates and on littleleaf linden growth in  different soil substrates were studied in the laboratory and the greenhouse, within  the framework of a substrate selection program for trees planted in downtown  Montreal. In addition, the effects of the structural soil (SS) compaction were  studied in the first greenhouse experiment. The first greenhouse experiment was  established in a factorial arrangement of four soils x four salt levels in a  completely randomized design with five replicates. The four soil types were (1) L  with a bulk density (BD) of 1.53 g/cm3, (2) LP with a BD of 1.26 g/cm3, (3) SS with  a BD of 1.8 g/cm 3 (SS1.8), and (4) SS with a BD of 2.0 g/cm3 (SS2.0). The second  greenhouse experiment had a split plot design. Two fertilization levels (with  fertilizer and without fertilizer) were randomly arranged as the main plots on ten  benches. Within each main plot, the combinations of three NaCl levels (0, 0.5 and  1.0 g NaCl/kg soil) and three soil substrates (L with a BD of 1.40 g/cm3, LP with a  BD of 1.13 g/cm 3 and SS2.0) were randomized in the sub-plots. Results from the  laboratory leaching experiment indicated that SS had the fastest Na leaching rate  and highest Na loss, while LP retained more Na than SS or L. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm23c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032360x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soils, Salts in -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trees in cities -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Crops -- Effect of salts on</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924c269"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Defining the role of Epstein-Barr virus infection in multiple sclerosis : issues in exposure measurement and misclassification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shoucri, Marie-Rose</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A leading hypothesis for the etiology of multiple sclerosis (MS)  is that a delayed infection by Epstein-Barr Virus (EBV) generates an abnormal immune  response, thereby inducing the disease. EBV is ubiquitous. While asymptomatic in  children, the infection produces the clinical entity infectious mononucleosis (IM)  when it is delayed until adolescence or young adulthood. Typically, case-control  studies have measured exposure to EBV by serology assaying EBV antibodies or by IM  self-report. The findings of these studies are not consistent. Part of the problem in establishing a definite causal  relationship between EBV and MS in case-control studies is related to exposure  measurement and misclassification. Since neither EBV serology or IM self-report  represent a 'gold standard' for exposure, particularly of delayed exposure, it is  difficult to estimate the exposure misclassification that would occur in a  case-control study, and the subsequent bias in the odds ratio (OR). These results support that EBV serology is not a good measure of  delayed EBV infection due to its lack specificity, and that estimates of association  between MS and EBV serology may overestimate or underestimate the OR between MS and  IM. EBV is extremely prevalent, and likely to be differentially misclassified by  serology. We therefore recommend the use of IM self-report for future case-control  studies of MS and EBV.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924c27k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c269</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s161668w"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Generation and purification of recombinant mouse SAA1 and its application in the characterization of SAA receptor on peritoneal macrophage cell line, RAW 267.4</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sheen, Hyuk Ho</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mouse serum amyloid A 1 (SAA1), an apolipoprotein is found in  the serum complexed with high density lipoprotein (HDL). Expression of SAA1 is  increased during acute phase response following infection, inflammation or trauma.  Evidence shows that SAA1 is cleared from the circulation following endocytosis by  macrophages and endothelial cells; incomplete degradation of SAA1 leads to  intracellular AA fibril formation and induction of life-threatening systemic AA  amyloidosis. In this context, at least two important mechanisms remain to be  elucidated: first, identification of putative SAA receptors mediating endocytosis of  SAA by activated monocytoid cells, and second, the conditions that promote  intracellular amyloidogenesis. The data presented in this thesis address the first  query. To characterize the putative SAA receptor protein, mouse  recombinant SAA1 (rSAA1) was generated and purified using gel filtration,  immunoaffinity and GST affinity purification methods. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306sz76f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161668w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860756q"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Determination of the strong coupling constant from dijet production in deep inelastic scattering at HERA</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Plamondon, Mathieu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the present analysis, the constant alphas of Quantum  Chromodynamics (QCD) is determined from dijets production in the regime of neutral  current deep inelastic scattering (NC DIS) with high momentum transfer Q2. This  measurement uses the data collected between the years 1998 to 2000 by the ZEUS  detector located on the HERA ring collider in Hamburg, Germany. Corresponding to an  integrated luminosity of 82.7 pb-1, the data were produced by the interactions  between 27.5 GeV electrons (or positrons) and 920 GeV protons. Defined in a phase  space reducing the theoretical and systematic uncertainties, the dijet production is  observed as well as the total inclusive DIS cross-section. The resulting observable,  the ratio of dijets over the number of DIS events, is then compared to the NLO  predictions provided by the program DISENT. From a QCD fit performed on four bins in  Q2, we obtain a value consistent with the world average: alpha s(MZ) = 0.1157 +/-  0.0017( stat.) +0.0054-0.00 59 (syst.) +0.0075-0.00 65 (th.).</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jv20d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860756q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>