<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537178w"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Towards more effective public health programming for injection drug users : development, evaluation and application of the injection drug user quality of life scale</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brogly, Susan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background. Little attention has been given to the assessment of  quality of life (QOL) in injection drug users (IDUs). Some studies have suggested  that existing measures are inadequate for use in IDUs. Objectives. The objectives were: (1) to develop and evaluate a  QOL measure for IDUs, the Injection Drug User Quality of Life Scale (IDUQOL), (2) to  describe the QOL of cocaine and heroin IDUs and identify its constituents and  correlates, and (3) to describe the relation between the QOL of cocaine and heroin  IDUs and the use of public health programs. Methods. The psychometric properties of the IDUQOL were assessed  in 61 IDUs, 85% of whom were re-interviewed within 4-weeks. The Flanagan Quality of  Life Scale was used to assess the criterion validity of the IDUQOL. The IDUQOL was  subsequently applied in a study of 260 Montreal IDUs to identify their most  important life areas. Associations between QOL and the use of public health programs  and other correlates were assessed using multiple linear regression. Results. The IDUQOL had good psychometric properties: the  test-retest reliability was within accepted standards (intraclass correlation  coefficient = 0.71) and the concurrent criterion validity between the IDUQOL and the  Flanagan was moderate (Pearson coefficient = 0.57). In the study of 260 Montreal  IDUs, housing was the most frequently selected life area of cocaine IDUs. Heroin  IDUs most frequently selected money and feeling good about yourself. Both cocaine  and heroin IDUs were generally dissatisfied with how these life areas fared. QOL was  significantly better for HIV positive IDUs and IDUs who used meal programs, and was  worse for IDUs who attended shelters and emergency departments. No strong relations  were found with needle exchange program use, methadone or other drug  treatment. Conclusion. The IDUQOL appeared to be a conceptually clear and  culturally relevant QOL instrument with good psychometric properties. Programs that  address the life conditions of IDUs might be needed foremost to other initiatives.  Understanding the constituents and correlates of the QOL of IDUs is important to the  development of more effective programs to curb disease transmission, and improve the  well-being of IDUs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Franco, Eduardo</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jf292.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537178w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354f77z"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>DNA methylation machinery as molecular targets for cancer therapeutics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Campbell, Paul Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the elements commonly seen in cancer is the change in  methylation status of the genome. These aberrations in methylation appear to be  critical for the neoplastic phenotype and manifest as changes to gene expression of  oncogenes and tumour suppressors. In addition to epigenetic alterations, the  proteins involved in maintaining the plastic methylation status of the genome, DNA  methyltransferases and demethylases, also show methylation-independent  protein-protein interactions that have effects on cell cycle progression and  proliferation. As changes in gene expression and mitotic regulation are seminal  elements of cancer, and because several methylated DNA binding proteins show  differential expression in a wide variety of cancers, these proteins serve as prime  targets for anticancer therapies. This thesis relates to exploring both current and  forthcoming possibilities and mechanisms of utilizing the DNA methylation machinery  for pharmacological intervention of cancer. Chapter two deals with an antisense  drug, currently in clinical trials, targeted to reduction of DNA methyltransferase  1, the maintenance methylation enzyme in mammalian cells. Our data indicate that the  existence of a common truncation mutation of the adenomatous polyposis coli gene  seen in some forms of sporadic and familial colorectal cancer may lead to downstream  upregulation of DNA methyltransferase 1, as reconstitution of the wildtype protein  reduces DNA methyltransferase 1 mRNA and protein. Reduction of the transcripts of  this methylation enzyme with an antisense oligonucleotide decreases the  tumourigenicity of these colorectal cancer cells, and provides a rationale for use  of this drug in colorectal cancer patients and prophylactic treatment of adenomatous  polyposis coli mutation-bearing individuals. Chapter three describes the rationale,  design, and in vitro and in vivo testing of antisense molecules against the  methylated DNA binding protein MBD2. These drugs red</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Szyf, Moshe</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xf78v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f77z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9306sz74w"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Enhancing biocontrol activity of Colletotrichum coccodes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ahn, Byeongseok</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Resistance responses of Abutilon theophrasti were investigated  to determine defense mechanisms of the weed against Colletotrichum coccodes and to  verify if some chemical suppression of the resistance mechanism could be exploited  to enhance the virulence. Induced resistance in A. theophrasti has been confirmed in  treatments with C. coccodes, benzothiadiazole, bentazon, and acifluorfen. Induction  of peroxidase and phenylalanine ammonia lyase (PAL) activities in the leaves that  did not contact with the inducing agents was observed after the localized stresses  to the first leaf or the root of the plant with those agents. alpha-Amino-oxy acetic  acid (AOA), 2-deoxy-D-glucose (DDG), mannose, oxalic acid, and analogues of oxalic  acid and mannose were tested to enhance C. coccodes virulence. However, the  compounds did not enhance C. coccodes virulence or affect A. theophrasti growth.  Strong antifungal effects, poor inhibitory effects on plant defense mechanisms, or  minor dependence of A. theophrasti on the defense mechanisms that the chemicals  affected could be reasons. The efficacy of C. coccodes increased in the presence of  0.25 kg a.i. ha-1 bentazon more than when C. coccodes was applied alone, while the  effect of glyphosate was minimal. Peroxidase activity was strongly induced by the  treatment of C. coccodes and increased over time. PAL and activation of peroxidase  was inhibited in the presence of bentazon, suggesting the synergy effect by bentazon  is probably due to the suppression on the two defense-related enzymes. In  conclusion, A. theophrasti exploits various biochemical and morphological types of  defense mechanisms against C. coccodes infection. However, the activation of the  defense responses can be suppressed or by-passed in an integrated weed management  system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Watson, Alan K.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655h18s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306sz74w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Phytopathogenic fungi</dc:subject><dc:subject>Colletotrichum coccodes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Weeds -- Biological control</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fx40j"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sephardic influences in the liturgy of Ashkenazic Orthodox Jews of London</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cohn Zentner, Naomi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines Sephardic melodies that were adopted into  the liturgy of the Ashkenazic Jews in London during the early twentieth century. The  work begins by presenting a history of Sephardic and Ashkenazic Jews from the time  they settled in England to the end of the nineteenth century. Through an analysis of  social and religious changes taking place among English Jews of the nineteenth  century, this thesis explicates reforms in the synagogue service that led to the  inclusion of polyphonic music into the synagogue and eventually, to the  incorporation of Sephardic melodies into Ashkenazic synagogue practice. The attempt  to canonize the music of Ashkenazic Jews in England was manifested in the widely  successful Handbook of Synagogue Music (1889, revised 1899). The second edition is  the focus of this thesis. Edited by Francis Lyon Cohen and David M. Davis under the  auspices of the United Synagogue and the Chief Rabbi, this volume included  Ashkenazic pieces by English as well as non-English Jewish composers. Fifteen  melodies of Sephardic origin from the Sephardic compilation The Ancient Melodies,  compiled by David de Sola and Emanuel Aguilar in 1857, as well as from The Music  Used in the service of the West London Synagogue of British Jews, compiled by  Charles Verrinder in 1880 were included in the 1899 edition of the Handbook. This  thesis examines the reasons these Sephardic melodies were chosen for inclusion by  the editors of the Ashkenazic Handbook during a period of reform.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k5489.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fx40j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Judaism -- Ashkenazic rite -- Liturgy -- Texts</dc:subject><dc:subject>Judaism -- Sephardic rite -- Liturgy -- Texts</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jews -- England -- London -- Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adf65v863v"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanism of resistance to Listeria monocytogenes in splenectomized mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pietrangeli, C.E. (Carolynn Eve)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study is an investigation of the basis of the enhanced antilisterial resistance exhibited by splenectomized mice. The response of the mononuclear phagocyte system of these hosts has been extensively investigated as a result of the finding that enhanced antilisterial resistance in these hosts is abolished by treatment with silica. Splenectomized mice demonstrate a quantitatively greater influx of immature macrophage precursors in response to listerial infection and intraperitoneal stimuli. Despite the higher responsiveness of immature macrophage precursors in the splenectomized host, radiation studies have determined that antilisterial resistance in splenectomized mice is provided by the mature mononuclear phagocytes of the liver, the Kupffer cells. However, Kupffer cells of splenectomized mice exhibit the same level of function associated with listericidal activity as non-splenectomized animals. An examination of the cellular composition of the spleen at early time intervals following infection with Listeria has led to the conclusion that enhanced antilisterial resistance in splenectomized mice may be explained on the basis of the loss of a storage function of the spleen. In the absence of the spleen, leucocytes are made available for migration to the liver upon infection of the host. The early destruction of Listeria which presumably results, is responsible for the lower growth of the organism measured at 48 hours post-infection.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306sz99r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v863v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn999725p"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Moving mountains through women's movements : the"feminization" of development discourse and practice in the Indian Himalayas</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chilibeck, Gillian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the varied and contradictory ideas about  rural women and their needs that are produced and circulate within development  discourses and projects. It pays particular attention to the multiple actors  involved in the production of such ideas and the relations of power that determine  which ideas gain authority. Based on ethnographic fieldwork in the Kullu District of  Himachal Pradesh, India, it looks at women's participation in three different  development projects: a women's savings and credit group, a broad-based development  NGO, and the women's village organizations (mahila mandals ). These case studies  demonstrate how development organizations engage with local gender meanings, often  working to reinforce or even exploit inequalities, rather than challenge them. As  women are targeted by such projects, they creatively receive, shape, and negotiate  the ideas and representations that they encounter about themselves. These encounters  limit, and sometimes foster, women's potential for new political identities and  agency.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999726z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999725p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women in rural development -- India -- Himachal Pradesh</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microfinance -- India -- Himachal Pradesh</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rural women -- India -- Himachal Pradesh -- Economic conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sex role -- India -- Himachal Pradesh</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g346v"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The reactions of phosphodiesters with epoxides : model studies to understanding the interaction of PAH epoxides with nucleic acids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Di Raddo, Pasquale</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The reaction of polycyclic hydrocarbon epoxides with the phosphate group of DNA has been suggested as potentially important in the cancer process initiated by this class of compounds. Herein the chemical reactions of model phosphates with various classes of epoxides are investigated. With aliphatic and non-bay-region type expoxides the reaction occurred by stereospecific trans addition of phosphate on the epoxide. Various physical-chemical aspects of this reaction are investigated. With K-region type epoxides the same reaction gave exclusively phenols. The biological implications of this result are discussed. Finally, bay-region type oxides, on reaction with phosphate, gave phosphotriesters whose stabilities depend on the phosphodiester nucleophile used and on the presence and arrangement of the diol grouping next to the epoxide.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386k05f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g346v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Phosphates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Epoxy compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>DNA</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mn03g"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anatomical, electrophysiological and microiontophoretic studies on sympathetic preganglionic neurones in the upper thoracic intermediolateral nucleus of the cat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Backman, Steven B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Properties of sympathetic preganglionic neurones were examined in cat. Following horseradish peroxidase injection into the stellate ganglion, labelled neurones were in spinal segments C(,6)-T(,8) in regions of the intermediolateral nucleus, intermediate grey, central canal and ventral horn. Neurones located in the intermediolateral nucleus had a wide range of physiological properties, and, with the exception of basal activity, the properties studied failed to indicate subgroups. These neurones were also studied according to their sensitivities to substances implicated in synaptic transmission. (gamma)-Aminobutyric acid and glycine had inhibitory effects which were blocked by bicuculline and strychnine, respectively. Glutamate, aspartate and D-L- homocysteic acid exerted excitatory effects. Substance P, thyrotropin-releasing hormone, oxytocin and vasopressin also had excitatory effects; when the physiological properties of responsive vs unresponsive neurones were compared, those excited by oxytocin had shorter latencies of antidromic activation than unresponsive neurones. Thus, subgroups of neurones may be identified on the basis of their responsiveness to some substances and there may be a further breakdown when responsiveness is compared with physiological properties.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f4234.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mn03g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77sq93q"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cortisol, cortisone interconversion in the human fetal lung</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abramovitz, Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since cortisol (F) can influence fetal lung maturation in late gestation, interconversion between cortisol and its inactive analogue cortisone (E), catalyzed by 11(beta)-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase (11-HSD) (E.C.1.1.1.146), may be an important mechanism for controlling the level of F in the fetal lung parenchyma. The objects of this study were to: (1) resolve conflicting data; and (2) to study possible regulating factors of the 11-HSD. Human fetal lungs (HFL) of gestational ages 9-20 weeks were grown as monolayer cultures or as explants with ('3)H-F and ('3)H-E or ('14)C-E (0.01-17 ng/ml), for 6-16 days. Extracts of tissue culture medium were chromatographed to separate the steroids, and the per cent conversion was calculated. From the differences observed between explant and monolayer cultures it was concluded that: (1) the E to F activity observed in midgestational HFL monolayer cultures is an artefact of the culture system and is therefore not physiological, thus resolving the conflicting data; (2) F to E activity predominates in midgestational HFL and resides in undifferentiated epithelial cells; and (3) the 11-HSD in fibroblast-like cells is a different enzyme from the 11-HSD in HFL epithelial cells. These studies suggest that a decrease in the epithelial cell enzyme activity, elevating intracellular F levels at term, may be critically involved in maturation of the HFL.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010q84v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sq93q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arb68xc56z"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Central neural systems regulating adrenal tyrosine hydroxylase</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gagner, Jean-Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This work concerns the role of spinal sympathetic pathways in the transynaptic regulation of adrenal medullary tyrosine hydroxylase activity (ATHA) and catecholamines. Cord transection in adult rats above the origin of the sympatho-adrenal preganglionic neurons (SAPN) causes after 3 days progressive reductions of ATHA, of the Vmax for tyrosine hydroxylation and of adrenal dopamine content. These effects are prevented by prior splanchnicotomy; they may result from a lowering of modulatory impulses of decentralized SAPN. The effect of spinal section on ATHA is accentuated by the repeated injection of serotonergic and muscarinic agonists which could inhibit the SAPN. Following spinal hemisection at various levels, the responses of ATHA and of adrenal epinephrine content to immobilization stress or to administration of apomorphine, insulin or 2-deoxyglucose are mediated by direct and crossed descending projections from supraspinal neurons generating net facilitatory and possibly inhibitory effects. A high performance liquid chromatographic method with amperometric detection was developed to measure simultaneously the three main adrenal catecholamines.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z609p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xc56z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zf287"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The economic effects of public pension plans in Canada : a theoretical and empirical analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Somers, Bertram A. (Bertram Alexander)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thesis examines Canada's public pension system and its economic impact. It discusses the evolution of Canada's public pension plans and by reviewing reports commissioned by the Quebec, Ontario, and federal governments as well as other studies, it indicates the possible direction that the system may take in the future. A two-period model of consumption planning is employed to illustrate the effects of social security programs on saving. A neoclassical growth model is then considered to see what criteria are used to determine the optimal rate of saving. By referring to the Cambridge economists' views on this subject, possible weaknesses in the neoclassical theory are exposed and the implications for economic growth are established. The empirical part of the thesis attempts to resolve two important questions, namely, the extent to which public pension plans have affected personal saving in Canada and the role of public pension benefits in the retirement decision.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343s97t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zf287</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pensions -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social security -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Economic conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pension trusts -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085k951"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Projections of somatic and visceral afferants to sympathetic preganglionic neurons via long intersegmental spinal pathways</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schondorf, Ronnie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In acute C1 spinal cats, electrical stimulaton of myelinated femoral (L5-L6) or pelvic (S1-S3) nerve afferents or natural stimulation of receptors of pelvic nerve bladder afferents increased or decreased the activity of thoracic (T1-T7) sympathetic preganglionic neurons (SPNs) projecting to the cervical sympathetic trunk. A similar proportion of these SPNs responded to electrical stimulaton of myelinated radial (C7-T1) nerve afferents. The responses of SPNs to electrical or natural activation of pelvic nerve afferents in acute spinal animals were compared with those of SPNs in CNS intact or midcollicular decerebrate animals. Myelinated somatic and visceral afferents can activate propriospinal systems which connect with SPNs many segments away from the entry point of these afferents. The proportion of SPNs actively responding to input transmitted via these pathways seems independent of the entry point of the input. These pathways are likely to be operative in the CNS intact or decerebrate preparation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zp17m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085k951</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An870zr50h"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structure of unstable nuclei in the g92 shell</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oxorn, Kenneth Warren</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The level structures of ('94)Ru, ('90)Mo, ('88)Zr, ('89)Mo and ('89)Nb have been studied via the decay of two isomers of ('94)Rh, two of ('90)Tc, two of ('88)Nb, one of ('89)Tc and one of ('89)Mo, respectively. These nuclides were produced via the proton bombardment of isotopically-enriched ('96)Ru and ('92)Mo as well as naturally-occurring Zr. Using gamma and beta spectroscopy techniques, detailed level schemes have been produced. High-spin states in ('89)Nb, ('88)Zr and ('88)Nb have been studied with in-beam gamma-ray spectroscopy techniques. These nuclides were produced with alpha particle-induced reactions on ('89)Y. A neutron-multiplicity experiment was used to identify the nucleus to which several gamma-rays belong. The systematics of the N = 48 and 47 nuclei, along with theoretical descriptions based on the nuclear shell model, are discussed. Contributions to original knowledge are summarized in Chapter V.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm77t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zr50h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nuclear structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gamma ray spectrometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Beta ray spectrometry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cx125"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Space technology : from national development to international cooperation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leister, Valnora</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Present mechanisms to expand global initiatives in the frontier of space have intrinsic limitations. The dominant powers limit access to space technology by other nations on strategic grounds, thus preventing the emergence of international cooperation. If existing patterns of space activities are maintained, the future of East-West and North-South relations in space will be one of growing tension. Four measures to bring about peaceful coexistence and growth in space, however, can be adopted by the international community. These are: (1) creation of an international satellite agency for the monitoring of arms movements and international crises; (2) establishment of measures to prevent deployment of weapons in space; (3) promotion of privatization of space technologies; (4) establishment of regional space agencies among developing countries.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g672.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cx125</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6m311q09w"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Adamic redemption in American literature: 1945 to the present</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>French, John Thatcher</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tg194.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311q09w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>American literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Salvation in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac247ds88v"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An enquiry into the factors that combine to explain managerial achievement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rothwell, Donald S.</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w806t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247ds88v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Management</dc:subject><dc:subject>Executive ability</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap5547s21t"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic control of resistance to intracellular parasites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gros, Philippe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It was originally observed, during kinetic studies of infection, that the intravenous injection of a small inoculum of dispersd Mycobacterium bovis (BCG) cells resulted in one of two distinct patterns of multiplication (growth vs non-growth) in the liver and spleen of mice of several inbred strains. Twenty-four inbred strains of mice which were so examined exhibited marked discontinuous variation in their level of early resistance to BCG infection, as estimated by the number of viable bacilli recovered from the spleen three weks after the intravenous injection of 2.5 x 10('4) BCG. The nature of this genetic variation was then investigated by a Mendelian segregation analysis: resistance of F(,1), F(,2) and backcross progeny bred from representative resistant and susceptible progenitors showed that the trait of resistance was controlled by a single, dominant, autosomal gene, designated Bcg. This gene exists in two allelic forms, Bcg('s) (susceptibility) and Bcg('r) (resistance). The Bcg locus was subsequently mapped to the Chromosome 1 after comparison of the respective strain distribution pattern (SDP) of the previously-mapped Idh-1 and Pep-3 alleles with that of Bcg alleles among mice of BXH and BXD recombinant inbred strains. Strong linkage between the Bcg gene and 2 other host resistance genes, namely Ity and Lsh, was detected by comparison of their respective SDP's. This tight linkage or identity was further confirmed by formal Bcg-Ity-Lsh linkage analysis performed on individual animals of the segregating populations and on inbred mouse strains congenic but for this portion of the first chromosome. The phenotypic expression of the Bcg locus at the cellular level was investigated in vivo: the cell responsible for early resistance was found not to be a T-cell and most probably not a B cell. The genetically-controlled mechanism of defense proved to be resistant to 950 rads of X-irradiation and susceptible to the toxic effect of silica. The reticuloendothelial system of both Bcg('r) and Bcg('s) strains showed an equal ability to clear a bacterial inoculum from their blood and these animals were also comparable in the intensity of the inflammatory response to an intraperitoneal inoculum of BCG. Explanted pleural and peritoneal resident macrophages supported equally well, independently of their genotype, the intracellular growth of various strains of mycobacteria in vitro.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171x96x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547s21t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hg249"><ual:graduationDate>1985</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Enhancement of magnetic susceptibility by leaching and application in mineral separation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hall, Stephen Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Enhancement of the magnetic susceptibility of pyrite particles is observed following a mild oxidative pressure leach. This increase is studied for a range of experimental conditions. The increase in susceptibility is attributed to the formation of a thin layer of ferromagnetic oxides. This layer of leach reaction products has been extensively studied using various analytical techniques. The species identified are (gamma)-Fe(,2)O(,3) and Fe(,3)O(,4), which supports a previously postulated reaction model. This leach treatment significantly increases the magnetic susceptibility of coal-pyrite permitting improved high-gradient magnetic desulfurization of a high pyritic sulfur coal. The leach treatment also enhances the magnetic susceptibility of other iron-containing mineral sulfides. However, application of this leach pretreatment in sulfide/sulfide separations is limited due to galvanic coupling effects which passivate the susceptibility increase reaction. In the presence of oxides, coal and probably other non-sulfides passivation does not occur and the susceptibility of the iron-bearing sulfide increases. The potential exists for the application of the leach as a pretreatment in enhancing fine iron-containing sulfide/non-sulfide magnetic separations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343s983.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hg249</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Leaching</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pyrites</dc:subject><dc:subject>Separation (Technology)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zh59c"><ual:graduationDate>1984</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The productivity of foreign savings in a developing economy : a case study of South Korea, 1961-1980</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yhip, Terrence M. (Terence Michael)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>With South Korea as the case study, this thesis analyzes the role, allocation, and productivity of foreign capital. We evaluate hypotheses based on the Harrod-Domar, Solow-Swan, and dual-gap growth models with foreign savings. An econometric growth-with-foreign debt model (consisting of forty three equations) is estimated to test hypotheses and to quantify theoretical conclusions. The econometrics include tests of (a) the Griffin-Enos substitution hypothesis, and (b) the Please hypothesis or effect. We also include South Korea's internal and external economic adjustments in response to the oil-with-recessionary shocks in 1974-1975, and 1979-1980. The econometric model is tested to ensure that its dynamic and system characteristics are economically and statistically sound to support simulation experiments. As a supplement to the economic analysis, the final chapter includes essential non-economic considerations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g588h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh59c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Capital productivity -- Korea (South)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Econometrics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Korea (South) -- Economic policy -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Investments, Foreign -- Korea (South)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b690d"><ual:graduationDate>1985</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>History and Philosophy of Science Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>From natural history to avian biology : Canadian ornithology, 1860-1950</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ainley, Marianne Gosztonyi, 1937-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is the first full-scale historical treatment of Canadian ornithology from 1860 to 1950. Ornithology is one of the most important branches of modern biology, and ornithologists were pioneer researchers in the areas of evolution, systematics, animal behaviour, zoogeography, migration, population biology and ecology. The institutional development of ornithology in Canada was much retarded by the prevailing utilitarian attitude towards science with its lack of funding for fundamental research. It was not until the second decade of the twentieth century that ornithology became part of the scientific establishment of the Canadian government. Despite this, Canadian ornithologists, in face of considerable difficulties stemming from the lack of encouragement and financial support, pursued pioneering studies in migration, behaviour and population biology of birds. Their research contributions were instrumental in taking ornithology from nineteenth century natural history to twentieth century avian biology.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214p89c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b690d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ornithology -- Canada -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az316q2293"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the person of Christ according to Nestorius</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Choo, Chai Yong</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558f07m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q2293</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nestorius, Patriarch of Constantinople, fl. 428</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jesus Christ -- Person and offices</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8s45q9747"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Neural correlates of long-term changes in predatory behaviour in the cat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Adamec, Robert Edward</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311q08m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45q9747</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cats -- Behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cats -- Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g096p"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Removal of fine particles from water by dispersed air flotation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Reay, David</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r175j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g096p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hydrodynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Water -- Purification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Flotation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Particles</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440t14h"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of linear systems using periodic inputs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carew, Burian</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752h50s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440t14h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Algebras, Linear</dc:subject><dc:subject>System analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kalman filtering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117p648"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Repair of injury to Escherichia coli after freezing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bunch, James Newman</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246s79n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117p648</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bacteria</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>