<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811kj941"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of GPNMB in breast tumor progression</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rose, April</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Breast cancer is the most commonly diagnosed cancer and the second leading cause of cancer related deaths among Canadian women. Development of distant metastases is the leading cause of morbidity and mortality from this disease. Breast cancer is a highly heterogeneous disease that is amenable to intervention with targeted therapeutics; however, therapies that are currently available have limited efficacy in the metastatic setting. To identify novel molecular mediators of breast cancer bone metastasis that might also serve as therapeutic targets, we subjected 4T1 mammary carcinoma cells to in vivo selection in Balb/c mice and isolated sub-populations with an aggressively bone-metastatic phenotype. Gene expression profiling of these cells revealed Glycoprotein NMB (GPNMB), also known as Osteoactivin, as a gene that was highly expressed in bone metastatic breast cancer cells. GPNMB is a type I transmembrane, cell surface expressed protein with an extracellular RGD and PKD domains and a cytoplasmic hemITAM signaling motif that had not previously been implicated in breast cancer. We demonstrate that ectopic GPNMB expression was sufficient to promote migration and invasion of breast cancer cells in vitro and the formation of bone metastases in vivo.Subsequently, we analyzed GPNMB mRNA and protein expression levels in hundreds of breast tumors and found that GPNMB expression positively correlates with increased risk of metastasis and shorter overall survival times. We have also demonstrated that GPNMB is most commonly expressed in breast tumors belonging to the triple negative subtype, for which there are no targeted therapies currently available. We showed for the first time that CDX-011, a GPNMB-targeted monoclonal antibody-drug conjugate, was capable of killing GPNMB-expressing breast cancer cells in vitro and inducing tumor regression in vivo. Finally, we investigated the effects of GPNMB on primary tumor progression and found that it inhibits tumor cell apoptosis while enhancing angiogenesis and tumor growth in vivo. We demonstrate that the extracellular domain (ECD) of GPNMB can be proteolytically cleaved and shed from the surface of breast cancer cells, which is mediated by ADAM10. We postulated that the shed extracellular domain (ECD) of GPNMB might be responsible for some of its pro-angiogenic effects and showed that this ECD was indeed capable of inducing endothelial cell migration in vitro.The body of work described in this thesis is the first to identify GPNMB as a functional mediator of breast cancer growth and metastasis and to validate it as an important clinical target in human breast cancer.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le cancer du sein est le cancer le plus fréquemment diagnostiqué et la seconde cause de mortalité associée au cancer chez les femmes canadiennes. Le développement de métastases est la cause majeure de la morbidité et de la mortalité dûes à cette maladie. Le cancer du sein est une maladie très hétérogène qui peut toutefois être traité par l'utilisation de thérapie ciblée ; toutefois, les thérapies actuellement disponibles ont un effet limité sur la formation des métastases. Dans le but d'identifier de nouveaux médiateurs moléculaires associés à la formation de métastases osseuses dérivées du cancer du sein et qui pourraient être utilisés comme cibles thérapeutiques, nous avons soumis les cellules de carcinome mammaire 4T1 à un processus de sélection in vivo dans des souris Balb/c. Nous avons ainsi isolé des sous-populations de cellules caractérisées par leur agressivité à former des métastases osseuses. L'étude  de l'expression génique de ces cellules a mis en évidence que le gène codant pour la Glycoprotéine NMB (GPNMB), aussi connu sous le nom de Ostéoactivine, est très fortement exprimé dans les lignées de cancer du sein métastatiques pour l'os.GPNMB est une protéine de surface transmembranaire de type I qui possède des domaines RGD et PKD extracellulaires ainsi qu'un motif hemITAM de signalisation cytoplasmique et n'avait encore jamais été rapportée comme impliquée dans le cancer du sein.Nous avons démontré que l'expression ectopique de GPNMB était suffisante pour promouvoir la migration et l'invasion de cellules de cancer du sein in vitro ainsi que la formation de métastases in vivo.Par la suite, nous avons analysé les niveaux d'expression des ARNm et de la protéine GPNMB dans des centaines de tumeur du sein humain et avons observé que l'expression de GPNMB corrèle positivement avec un risque accru de présence de métastases ainsi qu'une réduction du temps moyen de survie. Nous avons également démontré que GPNMB est le plus fréquemment exprimé dans des tumeurs mammaires appartenant au sous-type triple négatif pour lequel il n'y a actuellement aucune thérapie ciblée disponible.Par ailleurs, nous montrons pour la première fois que CDX-011, une drogue conjuguée à un anticorps monoclonal reconnaissant GPNMB, était capable, in vitro, d'éradiquer spécifiquement les cellules de cancer du sein exprimant GPNMB ainsi que d'induire une régression tumorale in vivo.Finalement, nous avons déterminé les effets de GPNMB sur la progression des tumeurs primaires et avons observé que GPNMB inhibait l'apoptose des cellules tumorales tout en augmentant l'angiogenèse et la croissance tumorale in vivo. Nous avons démontré que le domaine extracellulaire de GPNMB (ECD) pouvait être clivé de façon protéolytique par ADAM10 et ainsi être libéré de la surface cellulaire des cellules de cancer du sein. Nous avons postulé que la forme extracellulaire clivée (ECD) de GPNMB pourrait être impliquée dans certains des effets pro-angiogénique et avons montré que cet ECD était capable d'induire la migration de cellules endothéliales in vitro.L'ensemble des travaux décrits dans cette thèse implique pour la premier fois est le premier à identifier GPNMB comme médiateur fonctionnel de la croissance du cancer du sein et de ses métastases. Ce travail identifie GPNMB comme une importante cible thérapeutique pour le traitement des patients atteints du cancer du sein.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peter Siegel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zb38d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kj941</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000029z"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The causes, variability and behaviour in a warming world of the coldest winter-season Canadian temperatures and their associated Arctic air masses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Turner, Jessica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les températures de surface les plus froides au Canada sont associées aux masses d'air arctiques. Ces masses d'air forment pendant l'environnement snow-covered et de bas-lumière du soleil du nord-ouest de haut-latitude en hiver. C'est une région qui avait éprouvé le chauffage localisé intense de température de surface qui n'a pas été bien capturé par des modèles de climat. Le but de cette étude est d'examiner les masses d'air arctiques de la région en détail, le contexte synoptique plus grand des changements de l'intensité de la température à travers le Canada auquel ils sont inclus, leurs propriétés thermo-dynamiques et changements séculaires qu'ils peuvent éprouver.Des tendances dans des anomalies de la température relativement à un moyen de fonctionnement de 30 ans ont été examinées, une mesure de changements de l'intensité séparée des changements du moyen. Des tendances vers la variabilité décroissante ont été trouvées dans le sud-ouest et le nord-est pendant l'hiver et les tendances dans la variabilité croissante les prairies, l'Ontario méridional et au Québec pendant le plein hiver et dans les stations atlantiques dans le tôt-ressort. Cependant, aucune tendance n'a été trouvée dans la variabilité de la signification du nord-ouest que quoique les températures à l'intérieur des masses d'air arctiques augmentent, leur intensité relativement au moyen de fonctionnement de 30 ans avait changé.Quatre-vingt-treize masses d'air arctiques ont été isolées, utilisant les anomalies calculées relativement au moyen de fonctionnement de 30 ans, et examinées. Elles se sont avérées air froid de profond-couche endiguer des événements liés à un anticyclone intense dans la lie des Rocheuses canadiennes. Utilisant un budget thermo-dynamique, nous trouvons le mécanisme primaire de formation pour être diabatic, avec l'advection d'air froid jouant un petit rôle, équilibré par le chauffage d'affaissement. La sublimation se refroidissant des chutes de neige au début de la formation s'est également avérée pour jouer un rôle. Une tendance séculaire vers des événements plus profonds a été trouvée et a diminué le refroidissement radiatif pendant l'événement, probablement dû à l'opacité accrue.Dans une étude de cas d'un événement intense et longévital en février de 1979, l'humidité s'est avérée un composant crucial en maintenant l'air froid. Les cristaux de glace radiatively refroidissent la couche dans laquelle ils sont enfoncés mais arrangent gravitationellement avec le temps ou sont apportés à la terre par l'affaissement ; ils doivent être complétés le niveau par la précipitation si la masse d'air est de continuer de se refroidir. Le transport d'humidité dans la région d'événement est principalement des niveaux supérieurs, des cyclones dans le Golfe de l'Alaska et du nord au-dessus du poteau, où il précipite et tombe dans les niveaux plus bas.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The coldest surface temperatures in Canada are associated with arctic air masses. These air masses form during the snow-covered and low-sunlight environment of the high-latitude northwest in the winter.  This is a region that has been experiencing intense localized surface temperature warming that has not been well captured by climate models. The purpose of this study is to examine the arctic air masses of the region in detail, the larger synoptic context of changes in temperature intensity across Canada in which they are embedded, their thermodynamic properties, and secular changes that they may be experiencing.Trends in temperature anomalies relative to a 30-year running mean were examined, a measure of changes in intensity separated from changes in the mean. Trends towards decreasing variability were found in the southwest and northeast during the winter and trends in increasing variability in the Prairies, southern Ontario and Quebec during mid-winter and in the Atlantic stations in the early-spring. However, no trends were found in the variability of the northwest meaning that even though temperatures inside arctic air masses are increasing, their intensity relative to the 30-year running mean has not been changing.Ninety-three arctic air masses were isolated, using the anomalies calculated relative to the 30-year running mean, and examined. They were found to be deep-layer cold-air damming events associated with an intense anticyclone in the lee of the Canadian Rockies. Using a thermodynamic budget, we find the primary formation mechanism to be diabatic, with cold-air advection playing a small role, counter-balanced by subsidence warming. Sublimation cooling from snowfall at the start of the formation is one of the diabatic processes playing a role. A secular trend toward deeper events was found and decreased radiative cooling during the event, possibly owing to increased cloudiness.In a case study of an intense and long-lived event in February of 1979, moisture was found to be a crucial component in maintaining the cold air. Ice crystals radiatively cool the layer in which they are embedded but settle gravitationally over time or are brought to the ground through subsidence. Moisture must be replenished by precipitation if the air mass is to continue cooling. Moisture transport into the event region is primarily from the upper-levels, 700 hPa, from cyclones in the Gulf of Alaska and from the north over the pole, where it precipitates and falls into the lower-levels.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Richard Gyakum</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tp713.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000029z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s1616520"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Behavioral and electrophysiological correlates of vowel perception in monolingual and simultaneous bilingual users of Canadian English and Canadian French</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Molnar, Monika</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans le cadre de la présente thèse de doctorat, nous avons examiné la perception de la parole chez des individus bilingues simultanés (IBS) exposés au français canadien (FC) et à l'anglais canadien (EC) dès la naissance, afin de caractériser les mécanismes de base de la perception de la parole chez ces individus. C'est bien établi que la perception de la parole chez les locuteurs monolingues est hautement sélective pour les sons de leur langue maternelle, et que cette spécificité linguistique affecte la manière dont ces individus perçoivent les sons de langues secondes. L'organisation de la perception de la parole chez les IBS, lesquels sont des locuteurs natifs de deux langues, est beaucoup moins bien comprise. Afin d'examiner la perception de la parole chez ces individus, nous avons effectué deux études sur la perception des voyelles, à deux niveaux de traitement différents, chez des locuteurs monolingues et bilingues simultanés du français et de l'anglais canadien. La première étude mesure l'impact du contexte linguistique (français, anglais, bilingue) sur la perception de voyelles acoustiquement similaires existant dans les deux langues (plus précisément, la voyelle haute frontale /y/ et la voyelle haute postérieure /u/). Tel qu'attendu, les locuteurs monolingues démontrent un patron perceptif spécifique à leur langue maternelle. Les IBS, au contraire, démontrent un patron différent pour chaque contexte linguistique et sont capables de distinguer des voyelles acoustiquement similaires appartenant à chacune des deux langues--un résultat qu'ils obtiennent grâce à la phénomène de dissimilation. Ces résultats indiquent que les IBS possèdent un espace perceptuel remarquablement détaillé ainsi que la capacité à passer aisément d'un mode perceptif à un autre en fonction du contexte linguistique. La deuxième étude a utilisé les potentiels cérébraux évoqués, plus spécifiquement la négativité de discordance (MMN), pour étudier le rôle des mécanismes pré-attentionnels dans la perception de la parole. Les résultats de cette étude révèlent des patrons de MMN distincts entre les locuteurs monolingues de chacune des deux langues et les IBS, et ceci même lors des stades les plus précoces du traitement de la parole, un résultat qui démontre que le système pré-attentionnel des IBS est sensible au détail phonétique des sons de chaque langue, détail auquel les locuteurs monolingues de chacune de ces langues n'ont pas nécessairement accès. Cet accès automatique au détail phonétique pourrait être une composante essentielle de l'habileté des IBS à passer rapidement et sans effort d'un mode perceptuel à un autre en fonction du contexte linguistique (anglais, français, bilingue).  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In this dissertation, the phonetic perception abilities of simultaneous bilingual (SB) language users exposed to both Canadian English (CE) and French (CF) from birth were tested to examine mechanisms underlying this process. It is well established that monolingual speakers' speech perception abilities are highly tuned to the sounds of their native language, and that this language specificity affects how they distinguish the sounds of a second language. However, it is not well understood how the speech perception skills of simultaneous bilinguals, who are native speakers of two languages, are shaped. In order to investigate speech processing in this population, two studies were designed to assess the vowel perception abilities of monolingual and SB users of CE and CF at two different stages of speech processing. In Study 1, using a behavioral vowel categorization paradigm, we measured how the control of active language mode or language context (English, French, or bilingual) affects the perception of acoustically similar cross-language vowel categories (specifically, front /y/ and back /u/ high vowels). As expected, monolingual speakers demonstrated a language-specific perceptual pattern for the vowels; however, the SB participants displayed different patterns in each active language mode and were able to accommodate acoustically similar vowel categories relevant in the target language, which was achieved by dissimilation (separation) of the categories. These findings indicate that SB listeners rely on a finely detailed perceptual space and are flexible as they adapt their perception to different language environments.In Study 2, using event-related brain potentials, we recorded pre-attentive processing involved in vowel perception as reflected by the mismatch negativity (MMN). The SB listeners exhibited a MMN pattern that was distinct from both monolingual listener groups even during the earliest levels of speech processing, as the SB pre-attentive system is tuned to access sub-phonemic detail with respect to both of their input languages, including detail that is not readily accessed by either set of monolingual peers. This automatic access to fine phonetic detail may be essential in supporting the SBs' ability to make rapid, effortless shifts in perception across different communication contexts (French, English, bilingual).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baum, Shari</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Polka, Linda</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m201n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1616520</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Cognitive</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q428x"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Laser welding of a near-beta titanium alloy Ti-5 Al-5Mo-3Cr</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shariff, Tasneem</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Titanium alloys are widely used in the aerospace industry due to their high specific strength and excellent corrosion resistance. However, for some large scale aircrafts, such as Airbus A380 and Boeing 787, there is a demand for even stronger Ti alloys for structural and load bearing applications. Ti-5Al-5V-5Mo-3Cr (Ti-5553) is a new metastable β titanium alloy that exhibits excellent strength characteristics, even higher than the currently used α-β titanium grades, such as the workhorse Ti-6Al-4V alloy. It is expected that Ti-5553 will gain wider applications in the future and hence its weldability needs to be addressed. The current work is aimed at investigating the laser weldability of Ti-5553. Autogenous welds were produced by varying the defocusing distance and weld speed. The weld quality was investigated in terms of the surface morphology, welding defects, microstructure, hardness, and tensile properties. It was determined that welds with full penetration could be achieved and defects could be maintaned to meet aerospace specification tolerances by carefully manipulating the defocusing distance and weld speed within an optimum processing window. Welding was also conducted with Ti-6Al-4V filler wire and the effect of varying joint gaps was investigated on the metallurgical and tensile properies of Ti-5553 laser welds. It was found that welds with full penetration could be produced upto a gap of 0.5 mm for 3.1 mm thick plates. Increasing the joint gap, and hence the amount of filler wire resulted in the presence of martensite which was due to the incomplete and nonuniform mixing of base material and filler wire. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les alliages de titan sont beaucoup utilises dans l'industrie aérospatiale à cause de leurs caractéristiques de haute dureté et de la résistance à la corrosion. Néanmoins, pour les avions de grande taille, tels que Airbus A380 et Boeing 787, une dureté plus haute est requise dans les applications de support structurel. Ti-5Al-5V-5Mo-3Cr (Ti-5553) est une nouvelle alliage de titan fait de β métastable qui démontre les caractéristiques de dureté qui sont supérieurs à d'autres alliages de α-β de titan qui sont utilisées présentement, en incluant l'alliage de Ti-6Al-4V.   Il est attendu que l'utilisation de l'alliage de Ti-5553 se répandra dans l'avenir, pour cela, la question de soudage de ce matériel doit être adressée. Le travail actuel  recherche l'habilité de soudage à laser de Ti-5553. Les autogènes  soudures ont étés produites en changeant la distance du centre d'intérêt et en variant la vitesse de soudage. La qualité des soudures a été analysée selon l'anatomie de la surface, des défauts de soudage, de la microstructure, de la dureté et des propriétés de traction. Il a été détermine qu'on peut obtenir  les soudures de pleine pénétration et qu'on peut atteindre les spécifications aérospatiales de tolérance des défauts en contrôlant soigneusement  la distance du centre d'intérêt ainsi que la vitesse de soudage dans une fenêtre de processus optimisée.  Le soudage a aussi été conduit avec fil languette de Ti-6Al-4V et l'effet de variation de l'espace entre les jonctions sures les propriétés de traction et sure métallurgie de soudures de Ti-5553 a été investiguée. Il a été constaté qu'on peut obtenir les soudures de pleine pénétration jusqu'une espèce entre les jonctions de 0.5 mm pour les plaques d'épaisseur de 3.1mm. La présence de martensite a été constatée pour une distance entre les jonctions plus grand  ayant plus de quantité de fil languette.  Martensite s'est formée à cause d'un mélange non uniforme et incomplet entre le matériel de base et celui du fil languette.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Richard Chromik</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375w563.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q428x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gg73m"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bone morphogenetic protein 2 (BMP2) regulates follicle- stimulating hormone beta subunit (Fshb) expression in gonadotrope cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ho, Catherine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'hormone folliculo-stimulante (FSH) est nécessaire pour la reproduction chez les mammifères. Le but principal de notre laboratoire et de cette thèse est d'étudier les mécanismes intracellulaires modulant la synthèse de FSH. L'expression du gène de la chaîne béta (β) de FSH (Fshb) est l'étape limitante de la synthèse de cette hormone. Cette dernière est régulée par de nombreuses hormones endocriniennes et de facteurs paracrins comprenant la gonadolibérine, les stéroïdes sexuels et les ligands de la famille de facteur de croissance transformant de type β (TGFβ) tels que les activines. Des études récentes suggèrent que les gènes du développement (BMPs), une sous-famille des ligands de la famille de TGFβ, sont aussi des régulateurs de Fshb. Nous avons observé que BMP2 et BMP4 peuvent stimuler la transcription de Fshb synergistiquement avec les activines. Ici, j'ai utilisé les gonadotropes murines immortalisées, LβT2, pour étudier les mécanismes par lesquels BMP2 régule l'expression du gène de Fshb. J'ai déterminé que BMP2 agit via les récepteurs de BMP, BMPR1A et BMPR2, pour stimuler la transcription de Fshb. Les résultats suggèrent que l'effet de BMP2 sur l'expression de Fshb soit potentialisé lorsque BMP2 agit en coopération avec les activines, et semble dépendre de l'expression de gènes stimulés par les BMP. La puce à ADN a identifié que l'expression des gènes pour les protéines inhibitrices de l'ADN-liante (Ids) est stimulé par BMP2. J'ai démontré que Id2 et Id3 sont requis pour que BMP2 stimule la transcription de Fshb de façon synergistique avec l'activine A. De plus, Id2/3 et SMAD3, un effecteur important de la signalisation d'activine, font liaison  physique pour stimuler coopérativement la transcription de Fshb. En utilisant les cellules gonadotropes, j'ai prouvé que BMP2 communique par les récepteurs BMPRIA, BMPR2 et les protéines intracellulaires SMADs 1 et 5 pour stimuler la transcription d'Id3. J'ai identifié un élément de réponse du BMP2 (BRE) original dans la séquence du promoteur de l'Id3. Additionnellement, ce BRE agit coopérativement avec un autre BRE précédemment identifié pour stimuler l'expression d'Id3 par BMP2. Dans l'ensemble, mon travail définit un mécanisme par lequel BMP2 régule l'expression de Fshb de façon synergistique avec l'activine A. En approfondissant notre compréhension des signaux de transduction multiples qui contrôlent l'expression de Fshb, nous développerons une image plus complète des mécanismes qui régente la physiologie de la reproduction des mammifères. Ces connaissances nous permettront de mieux comprendre les causes de l'infertilité, ce qui peut ultimement mener au développement de nouvelles thérapies plus efficaces.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Proper follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) synthesis, secretion, and action are required for normal reproductive function in mammals. A major goal of our lab and of this thesis is to reveal the intracellular mechanisms controlling FSH synthesis. The expression of the FSHβ subunit gene (Fshb) is rate-limiting in production of the mature dimeric hormone and is regulated by numerous endocrine hormones and paracrine acting factors, including gonadotropin-releasing hormone, sex steroids, and transforming growth factor β (TGFβ) superfamily ligands such as activins. Recent studies suggest that bone morphogenetic proteins (BMPs), a sub-family of TGFβ family ligands, also regulate Fshb transcription. BMP2 and BMP4 were further observed to stimulate Fshb transcription synergistically with activins. Here, I used the immortalized murine gonadotrope cell line, LβT2, to investigate mechanisms by which BMP2 regulates Fshb gene expression. I determined that BMP2 acts through the BMP receptors BMPR1A and BMPR2 to stimulate Fshb transcription. The data suggest that BMP2's effect on Fshb expression is more significant when acting synergistically with activins, and appears to depend on BMP-stimulated gene expression. cDNA microarray analyses identified inhibitor of DNA binding (Id) proteins as BMP2 gene targets. I showed that Id2 and Id3 are required for BMP2 to stimulate Fshb transcription synergistically with activin A. Additionally, Id2 and Id3 physically interact with SMAD3, a major effector of activin signaling, to cooperatively stimulate Fshb transcription. Using gonadotrope cells, I showed that BMP2 signals via BMPRIA, BMPR2 and the intracellular signaling proteins SMADs 1 and 5 to stimulate Id3 transcription. I identified a novel BMP2 response element (BRE) in the proximal murine Id3 promoter that mediates SMAD1/5-dependent Id3 transcription. Furthermore, this BRE acts cooperatively with a previously identified distal BRE to mediate BMP2-stimulated Id3 expression. Overall, my work defines a mechanism whereby BMP2 regulates Fshb expression synergistically with activin A. By understanding multiple pathways mediating Fshb expression, we will develop a more complete picture of fundamental mechanisms governing reproductive physiology in mammals. Such knowledge may provide the necessary foundation for novel insights into causes of some forms of infertility and may therefore lead to the development of newer and more effective treatments.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daniel Bernard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268549k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gg73m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67jr52k"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Contested peace, contested justice: discourse, power, and international justice in northern Uganda</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Armstrong, Kimberley</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine le débat entre la paix et la justice au nord de l'Ouganda qui a fait surface suite à la décision de la Cour pénale internationale (CPI), en janvier 2004, d'enquêter sur le conflit entre le gouvernement de l'Ouganda et l'Armée de résistance du Seigneur. Cette annonce de la CPI s'est butée à la résistance des groupes religieux et politiques locaux, de la société civile et des chefs traditionnels du nord de l'Ouganda, particulièrement ceux de la sous-région d'Acholi. Dans cette région du monde, le débat entre paix et justice est important car il aura des impacts sur le futur de la CPI ainsi que sur les approches de résolution de conflits. En tant que nouvelle institution, la CPI tente de s'imposer comme un acteur important dans les relations internationales, mais son impact sur les situations de conflits actuels reste à démontrer. L'analyse du débat illustre comment les questions centrales concernant l'impact de la recherche de la justice en situation de conflit ont été évitées lorsque les acteurs des deux côtés du débat ont cherché à imposer des concepts légitimes de la paix et de la justice, et ultimement influencer le cours des événements. Cette thèse examine les discours et les représentations mises de l'avant par les acteurs en les remettant dans une perspective historique révélant ainsi les idées préconçues et les significations enchâssées dans certains discours et concepts associés. Examiner la trajectoire historique du débat permet de dévoiler et d'analyser les relations de pouvoir, les significations contestées, et les stratégies des supporteurs et des opposants des interventions de la CPI en relation avec les objectifs de la paix et de la justice. Dans le nord de l'Ouganda, ces objectifs n'ont pas été atteints et, comme le démontre cette thèse, bien des questions demeurent sans réponse concernant les relations entre la paix et la justice. C'est seulement à travers un débat plus engagé et candide ainsi qu'à travers une recherche plus empirique que de telles relations peuvent être mieux comprises, améliorant ainsi notre capacité à aborder le problème de l'extrême violence qui affecte la vie de millions de gens dans le monde. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the debate between peace and justice in northern Uganda that transpired following the announcement of the International Criminal Court's (ICC) decision to investigate the conflict between the government of Uganda and the Lord's Resistance Army in January 2004.  The announcement of the ICC to investigate the conflict was met with resistance by many of the local religious, political, civil society, and traditional leaders in northern Uganda, particularly those from the Acholi sub-region.  The debate between peace and justice in northern Uganda is an important debate that will impact the future of the ICC as well as approaches to conflict resolution.  As a new institution, the ICC is attempting to establish itself as an important actor in international relations, but its impact on situations of ongoing conflict is as yet undetermined.  An analysis of the debate illustrates how important questions about the impact of seeking justice in situations of ongoing conflict were evaded; however, as actors on both sides of the debate worked to impose particular concepts of legitimate peace and justice, and, ultimately, control the outcome of events on the ground.  This thesis examines the discourse and representations mobilized by both sides of the debate, placing the discourse in a historical perspective in order to reveal assumptions and meanings embedded within certain discourses and associated concepts.  By examining the historical trajectory of the debate, the relations of power, contested meanings, and strategies of both opponents and supporters of the ICC's intervention can be revealed and analyzed in relation to the objectives of peace and justice.  In northern Uganda, neither objective has yet been achieved, and, as this thesis demonstrates, many unanswered questions about the relations of peace and justice remain.  It is only through more engaged and candid debate as well as empirical research that such relations can be understood, improving our ability to address the egregious violence that impacts the lives of millions of people in the world today.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Galaty</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fk865.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jr52k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anthropology - Cultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qj045"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigating the limits of temporal clustering analysis for detecting epileptic activity in functional magnetic resonance imaging data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khatamian, Yasha</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une localisation précise de l'activité épileptique est une nécessité pour les patients qui pourraient bénéficier d'une opération résective. L'EEG-IRM fonctionnelle (EEG-IRMf) est une nouvelle technique de localisation qui localise l'activité épileptique dans un enregistrement IRMf en trouvant un signal « blood oxygen level dependent » (BOLD) qui correspond à des événements épileptiques détectés simultanément par un enregistrement EEG. L'analyse temporelle groupée 2D (ATG-2D) est une technique de localisation de l'activité épileptique relativement nouvelle, qui est basée sur des données IRMf. Pour trouver l'activité épileptique, elle décompose l'activité BOLD en différentes composantes selon le moment où elles surviennent sans recourir à un enregistrement EEG simultané. Cette étude évalue la capacité de la technique ATG-2D à détecter une activité épileptique simulée ainsi que sa capacité à détecter une activité épileptique précédemment détectée chez des patients avec EEG-IRMf. Même nous avons montré que la technique ATG-2D pouvait détecter de façon efficace une activité épileptique ayant certaines caractéristiques,  il a aussi été trouvé qu'elle détectait de l'activité non épileptique. Il a été déterminé que la technique ATG-2D pouvait seulement être utilisée pour valider une activité épileptique localisée par d'autres moyens ou pour formuler des hypothèses concernant l'endroit où l'activité pourrait survenir.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Precise localization of epileptic activity is a necessity for those patients who may benefit from resective surgery. One common localization technique, EEG functional MRI (EEG-fMRI), localizes activity in an fMRI recording by finding blood oxygen level dependent (BOLD) signal correlates to epileptic events detected in a simultaneously recorded EEG. 2D temporal clustering analysis (2D-TCA) is a relatively new fMRI-based epileptic activity localization technique that breaks BOLD activity into components based on timing, finding epileptic activity without simultaneously recorded EEG. This study evaluated the ability of 2D-TCA to detect both simulated epileptic activity and activity detected in patients using EEG-fMRI. Although it was found that 2D-TCA could effectively detect epileptic activity with certain characteristics, it also detected activity not associated with epilepsy. As such, it was determined that 2D-TCA can only be used to validate epileptic activity localization by other means or to create hypotheses as to where activity may occur.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jean Gotman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579s548.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qj045</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g310g"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Community assembly of saprophagous arthropods of bird nest boxes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gilbert, Gregor</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les modèles des communautés d'arthropodes saprophages dans les nids des maisons d'oiseaux sont faiblement compris. Les arthropodes saprophages retrouvés dans les nids des maisons habitées par les moineaux (Passer domesticus L.) et les hirondelles bicolores (Tachycineta bicolor (Vieillot)) dans le Sud de la province de Québec ont été collectés à travers deux périodes d'échantillonnage (immédiatement après maturation, et 60 jours après maturation) au cours de l'année 2007. Un total de 5 366 spécimens (10 familles, 15 espèces) ont été collectés durant la première phase d'échantillonnage et 3 794 spécimens (sept familles, 11 espèces) lors de la seconde phase. Pour les deux périodes d'échantillonnage, deux différentes méthodes d'analyses de modèles nul ont révélé des modèles de structure des communautés différents; la première aléatoire et la seconde de co-occurrence positive. Le processus de la colonisation stochastique explique probablement le modèle aléatoire apparent et le processus déterminant comme la colonisation hâtive des espèces pourrait expliquer certains modèles de co-occurrence des espèces. Toutefois, une étude plus étendue dans l'espace et le temps serait nécessaire pour les comprendre entièrement. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The patterns of community assembly of saprophagous arthropods in bird nest boxes are poorly understood.  Saprophagous arthropods from nest boxes of House Sparrows (Passer domesticus L.) and Tree Swallows (Tachycineta bicolor (Vieillot)) in southern Quebec were collected over two sampling periods (immediately post-fledging, and 60 days post-fledging) in 2007.  A total of 5366 specimens (10 families, 15 species) were collected at the first sampling period and 3794 specimens (seven families, 11 species) at the second sampling period.  For both sampling periods, two different methods of null model analyses revealed different patterns of community structure; random in one case, and positive co-occurrence in the other.  Stochastic colonization processes probably explain the apparent random patterns and deterministic processes, such as facilitation by early colonizing species explain some of the patterns of species co-occurrence. However, a larger spatial and temporal scale of study is necessary to understand them more fully.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Terry A. Wheeler</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20ss80h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g310g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924c073"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Environmentally-relevant photochemical reactions of oxidized mercury species with selected organics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Si, Lin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>     Mercury is one of the most toxic environmental pollutants of global concern. Understanding transformation pathways among various mercury species is critical for predicting the fate, transport and potential toxicity of mercury to the ecosystems. The purpose of this research was to advance our knowledge on the photochemical reactions of oxidized mercury species with selected organic molecules by performing kinetic and product studies at near environmental conditions.      The reduction of Hg2+ by small, semi-volatile dicarboxylic acids was the first to be investigated. The highest were observed in systems free of both oxygen and chloride ion with the second-order apparent rate constants of (1.2 ± 0.2) × 104, (4.9 ± 0.4) × 103, and (2.8 ± 0.2) × 103 (L mol-1 s-1) for oxalic, malonic and succinic acids at pH = 3.0 and T = 296 ± 2 K, respectively. The photo-reduction of Hg2+ was mediated by the complexes formed between Hg2+ and dicarboxylic acids, and the identified products were Hg0, hydroxycarboxylic acids and mono-carboxylic acids. Either the presence of chloride ion or dissolved oxygen retarded this photoreduction process.      Next, extensive kinetic data and detailed product information were obtained for the reaction between Hg2+ and alkanethiols. Under our experimental conditions, the apparent first-order rate constants were determined to be (2.0 ± 0.2) × 10-7 s-1, (1.4 ± 0.1) × 10-7 s-1, (8.3 ± 0.5) × 10-8 s-1, for 1-propanethiol, 1-butanethiol, and 1-pentanethiol respectively. The effects of ionic strength, dissolved oxygen or chloride ion on reaction rates were found to be minimal under our experimental conditions. The identified products of the reaction between oxidized mercury species with selected alkanethiols (C3-C5) were Hg0 and disulfides (RS-SR).      Then, kinetic and product studies were performed for the reaction of Hg2+ with thioglycolic acid. This photochemical process was mediated by Hg(OOCCH2S) complex with the apparent first order rate constant determined to be (2.4 ± 0.4)  10-5 s-1 at 296 K, pH 4.  It was found that under our experimental conditions ~90% of the reactants undergo photodecomposition to generate elemental mercury (Hg0) and black metacinnbar (HgS) was formed.     Comparison of the obtained rate constants for the above three photochemical reactions implied the potential significance of weak binding sites (e.g. –COOH) on dissolved organic matter (DOM) in the important yet poorly understood photoreduction of Hg2+ in the aquatic environment.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>     Le mercure est l'un des polluants globaux les plus toxiques présents dans l'environnement. Comprendre les voies de transformation entre les différentes espèces de mercure est essentiel afin de prédire le sort, le transport et la toxicité potentielle du mercure  dans les écosystèmes. Le but de cette recherche était de faire progresser nos connaissances sur les réactions photochimiques du mercure oxydé (Hg2+) avec certaines molécules organiques. Pour ce faire, des études cinétiques ont été réalisées dans des conditions qui sont représentatives du milieu aquatique et les produits de ces réactions ont été identifiés.     La première réaction étudiée est la réduction de Hg2+ par des acides dicarboxyliques semi-volatils de faible masses moléculaires.  Les réactions les plus rapides ont été observées dans les systèmes sans oxygène et sans ion de chlorure et  les constantes de vitesse apparentes du deuxième ordre suivantes ont été obtenues: (1.2 ± 0.2) × 104, (4.9 ± 0.4) × 103, et (2.8 ± 0.2) × 103 (L mol-1 s-1) pour la réaction avec l'acide oxalique, l'acide malonique et l'acide succinique, respectivement, à un pH de 3.0 et à une température de 296 ± 2 K. L'intermédiaire dans la photo-réduction de Hg2+  est  un complexe formé  par Hg2+ avec l'acide dicarboxylique et les produits identifiés sont Hg0 et les acides  hydroxy- et  mono-carboxyliques.   La présence d'ions chlorure ou d'oxygène dissous retarde le processus de photo-réduction.      Ensuite, de nombreuses données ont été obtenues sur la cinétique et sur les produits de la réaction entre Hg2+ et des alcanethiols. Dans nos conditions expérimentales, des constantes de vitesse apparentes du premier ordre ont été déterminées  pour le 1-propanethiol ((2.0 ± 0.2) × 10-7 s-1), le 1-butanethiol ((1.4 ± 0.1) × 10-7 s-1)  et le 1-pentanethiol ((8.3 ± 0.5) × 10-8 s-1).  L'effet de la force ionique, de l'oxygène dissous et de l'ion chlorure sur les taux de réaction se sont avérés minimes dans nos conditions expérimentales. Les produits identifiés sont  Hg0 et des disulfures (RS-SR).Ensuite, la cinétique et les produits de la réaction entre Hg2+ et l'acide thioglycolique ont été étudiés. Ce processus photochimique a comme intermédiaire  le  complexe  Hg(OOCCH2S) et la constante de vitesse apparente du premier ordre a été évaluée à (2.4 ± 0.4)  10-5 s-1 s-1 à 296 K et à un pH de 4. Il a été constaté que dans nos conditions expérimentales, ~90% des réactifs génère du mercure élémentaire (Hg0) et méta-cinabre noir (HgS) a été formé suite à leur photo-décomposition.      Les constantes de vitesse obtenues pour les trois réactions photochimiques décrites ci-haut  indiquent que la présence de sites de liaisons faibles (par exemple, -COOH) dans la matière organique dissoute (DOM) pourrait jouer un rôle significatif dans l'important, si encore peu compris, processus de photo-réduction de Hg2+ dans le milieu aquatique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Parisa A. Ariya</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9353295.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c073</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881m33w"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Guarding problems and geometric split trees</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>King, James</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Beaucoup de problèmes géométriques sont intrinsèquement liés à la question de la division ou classification des points.  Nous étudions deux familles de problèmes dans deux branches distinctes de recherche. Les problèmes de surveillance sont motivés par la question de la surveillance d'une région avec des caméras de sécurité ou d'éclairage avec des feux.  Ces problèmes ont été étudiés depuis des décennies, mais il y a deux problèmes importants dont la complexité n'est pas complètement élucidée.  Tout d'abord, nous étudions le problème de surveiller des polygones simples.  Ce problème est connu pour être NP-complet, mais son approximabilité n'est pas connue.  Deuxièmement, nous étudions la complexité de surveiller des chaînes monotones, aussi connues comme terrains en dimension 1,5.  Comprendre l'interaction des polygones de visibilité et la façon dont ils divisent les ensembles de points est crucial pour l'étude de ces problèmes.  Nous résoudrons un problème important ouvert en prouvant que surveiller les terrains est fortement NP-complet.  Nous présentons également un algorithme d'approximation pour la surveillance des polygones simples avec des gardes sur le périmètre.  Ce nouvel algorithme améliore l'état de l'art.Un arbre de division géométrique est une structure de données pour stocker des ensembles de points qui divise de manière récursive l'espace, et aussi les données, d'une certaine manière aléatoire.  Le compréhension de la répartition de la structure d'un tel arbre est une question de compréhension des répartitions des divisions.  Nous étudions les répartitions associées à plusieurs méthodes de division naturelles.  Nous faisons de nouvelles connexions entre un problème important en géométrie discrète et des distributions de probabilité naturelles.  Dans le but d'analyser les arbres de division géométriques en fonction de leurs divisions, nous introduisons un modèle d'arbre aléatoire qui est général tout en permettant des comparaisons puissants avec les arbres aléatoires dans des modèles plus restreints.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Many geometric problems are intrinsically linked to the issue of splitting or classifying points.  We investigate two such families of problems in two separate branches of research.  Guarding problems are motivated by the issue of guarding a region with security cameras or illuminating it with lights.  Such problems have been studied for decades, but there are two significant guarding problems whose complexity is not completely understood.  First, we investigate the problem of guarding simple polygons; this problem is known to be NP-complete but its approximability is not known.  Second, we investigate the complexity of guarding monotone chains, also known as 1.5-dimensional terrains. Understanding the interaction of 'visibility polygons' and how they separate point sets is crucial for the investigation of such problems.  We resolve a significant open problem by proving strong NP-completeness for terrain guarding.  We also present an approximation algorithm for guarding simple polygons with perimeter guards; this new algorithm improves the state of the art.A geometric split tree is a data structure for storing point sets that recursively splits the space, and in turn the data, in some random way.  Understanding the distribution of such a tree's structure is a matter of understanding the distribution of the splits.  We investigate the distributions associated with several natural splitting methods.  We make new connections between an important problem in discrete geometry and natural probability distributions.  With the goal of analyzing geometric split trees based on their splits, we introduce a random tree model that is general while still allowing powerful comparisons with random trees from more restricted models.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Luc P. Devroye</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f619q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m33w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acr56n148w"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pyramidal finite elements</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Phillips, Joel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les éléments finis pyramidaux peuvent servir comme «colle» pour combiner des éléments avec faces triangulaires (p. ex. tétraèdres) et avec faces quadrilaterales (p. ex. hexaèdres) dans un même maillage. Les éléments finis pyramidaux qui existent présentement sont soit de bas-ordre ou ne sont pas convenables pour les formulations mixtes d'éléments finis. Dans cette thèse, deux familles d'éléments finis pyramidaux sont construites. Les éléments sont équipés de degrés de libertés unisolvents et on démontre qu'ils sont compatibles avec les éléments pré-existantes triangulaires et quadrilaterales d'ordres élevés. On démontre notamment que les éléments produisent des approximations d'ordres élevés et satisfassent une «propriété de diagramme commutatif». Ceci assure que les éléments sont convenables pour des problèmes avec formulation mixte dans les espaces du complexe de Rham. On démontre que tous les éléments pyramidaux doivent utiliser des fonctions de base non-polynômes et que conséquemment la théorie classique des éléments finis ne peut pas déterminer quelles méthodes de quadrature devrait être employées pour assembler des matrices de rigidité lorsque les pyramides sont utilisées. Le problème est résolu en élargissant la théorie classique et une méthode de quadrature appropriée pour les éléments finis pyramidaux est suggérée. Finalement, des simulations numériques avec éléments pyramidaux sont présentées.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Pyramidal finite elements can be used as "glue" to combine elements with triangular faces (e.g. tetrahedra) and quadrilateral faces (e.g. hexahedra) in the same mesh.  Existing pyramidal finite elements are low order or unsuitable for mixed finite element formulations.  In this thesis, two separate families of pyramidal finite elements are constructed.  The elements are equipped with unisolvent degrees of freedom and shown to be compatible with existing high order tetrahedral and hexahedral elements.  Importantly, the elements are shown to deliver high order approximations and to satisfy a "commuting diagram property", which ensures their suitability for problems whose mixed formulation lies in the spaces of the de Rham complex.  It is shown that all pyramidal elements must use non-polynomial basis functions and that this means that the classical theory of finite elements is unable to determine what quadrature methods should be used to assemble stiffness matrices when using pyramids.  This problem is resolved by extending the classical theory and a quadrature scheme appropriate for high order pyramidal elements is recommended.  Finally, some numerical experiments using pyramidal elements are presented.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nilima Nigam</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb160.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n148w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A41687h784"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Defiant bodies: discursive power and resistance in the post-dictatorship novels of Julia Alvarez, Edwidge Danticat and Junot Diaz</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lewsen, Simon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire analyse trois romans d'auteurs caribano-américains – Julia Alvarez, Edwidge Danticat et Junot Diaz – qui traitent de la dictature de Trujillo en République Dominicaine. Même si plusieurs études sur Trujillo examinent déjà les discours culturels qui ont permis au dictateur de solidifier son pouvoir et d'établir une hégémonie, elles ne s'intéressent pas suffisamment à des formes plus subtiles de résistance. Nous montrerons ici comment Alvarez, Danticat et Diaz considèrent différents modèles de discours sur la masculinité, la féminité et l'ethnicité - des discours à travers lesquels le régime de Trujillo a façonné la compréhension qu'ont les individus de leur propre corps et de celui des autres. Nous analyserons aussi comment les auteurs explorent et valorisent des rapports alternatifs au corps, qui permettent aux personnages de formuler de nouvelles conceptions d'une résistance subjective.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This study examines three novels by contemporary Caribbean-American authors – Julia Alvarez, Edwidge Danticat and Junot Díaz – which attend to the history of the Trujillo dictatorship in the Dominican Republic. While recent studies on Trujillo focus on the cultural discourses that enabled the dictator to consolidate power and establish hegemony, they neglect subtle forms of resistance. I argue that the three writers attend to various discursive models of masculinity, femininity, and ethnicity through which Trujillo's regime induced individuals to understand their own bodies and the bodies of others. They also seek out and valorize alternative modes of relating to thebody, which enable the characters to formulate new conceptions of resistant subjectivity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Monica Popescu</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149q25p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687h784</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj9602101m"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The ecology of adaptive radiation in Darwin's finches</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>De León Reyna., Luis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The ecological theory of adaptive radiation postulates that divergent natural selection between populations occupying contrasting environments, or using different resources, can drive adaptive divergence and thereby cause speciation. My thesis investigates this hypothesis in Darwin's finches of the Galápagos Islands. I use field observations, genetic tools, and statistical analyses to study patterns of sympatric coexistence, niche use, adaptive divergence, and gene flow within and among four closely-related species of Ground finches (Geospiza spp.). I also quantify possible impacts of human disturbances on this adaptive radiation. My first major finding is that the coexistence of sympatric, closely related species is facilitated by partial differences in diets (imperfect generalism), promoted by high spatial and temporal environmental heterogeneity. My second major finding represents a demonstration that a single generalist species (Geospiza fortis) might be composed of a number of individual specialists. This individual specialization might be important in promoting the initial stages of adaptive divergence. My third major finding is of strong reproductive isolation between coexisting large versus small beak size morphs with G. fortis. This result suggests the possibility that adaptive divergence drives genetic divergence in the face of initially high gene flow for sympatric populations on a single island. My final major finding is that human activities appear to be negatively impacting adaptive divergence between the small and large beak size morphs of G. fortis. I specifically show how the diet and performance (bite force) differences that characterize the two morphs at an undisturbed site where the morphs remain distinct have degraded at a human-disturbed site where the morphs are no longer distinct. These findings confirm some of the major predictions of the ecological theory of adaptive radiation by revealing how resource (diet) differences that cause adaptive (beak) divergence promote ongoing ecological speciation in Darwin's finches. Overall my thesis illustrates how the study of ecological interactions is central to understanding the factors that promote and maintain the process of adaptive radiation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La théorie écologique des radiations adaptatives propose que la sélection naturelle divergente entre des populations qui occupent des environnements différents, ou utilisent des ressources différentes, peut promouvoir la divergence adaptative et ainsi initier la spéciation. Ma thèse examine cette hypothèse dans le contexte des Pinsons de Darwin des îles Galápagos. J'utilise des observations écologiques, des outils génétiques, et des analyses statistiques pour étudier la coexistence en sympatrie, l'utilisation des niches, la divergence adaptative, et le flux génique entre et au sein de quatre espèces de pinsons étroitement reliées (Geospiza spp.). J'examine également les impacts potentiels de perturbations humaines sur cette radiation évolutive. Ma première conclusion importante est que la coexistence d'espèces étroitement reliées vivant en sympatrie est facilitée par des petites différences dans leur régime alimentaire (le généralisme incomplet), aidé par un niveau élevé d'hétérogénéité spatiale et temporelle.  Ma deuxième conclusion est qu'une seule espèce généraliste (Geospiza fortis) est peut-être composée de plusieurs individus spécialisés. Cette spécialisation au niveau de l'individu pourrait être importante pour faciliter les premières étapes de la divergence adaptative. Ma troisième conclusion est qu'il existe une forte isolation reproductive entre deux formes de G. fortis qui sont divergentes dans la morphologie de leurs becs, mais qui coexistent dans le même milieu. Ce résultat suggère que  la divergence adaptative peut entrainer la divergence génétique même avec un haut niveau initial de flux génique dans des populations vivant en sympatrie sur une même île. Ma dernière conclusion est que les activités humaines sont peut-être en train de restreindre la divergence adaptative entre ces deux formes de G. fortis. Plus précisément, je démontre comment les différences reliées au régime alimentaire et à la performance qui caractérisent les deux formes dans un site non-perturbé, où les deux formes demeurent distinctes, se sont réduites dans un site perturbé par les humains, où les formes ne sont maintenant plus distinctes. Ensembles, ces résultats confirment plusieurs des prédictions les plus importantes de la théorie écologique des radiations adaptatives, en démontrant comment des différences en ressources alimentaires peuvent entrainer la divergence adaptative dans la morphologie des becs, qui promeut ensuite la spéciation écologique continue dans les Pinsons de Darwin. En général, ma thèse illustre comment l'étude des interactions écologiques est essential pour bien comprendre les facteurs qui promeuvent et maintiennent le processus de la radiation adaptative. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eldredge Bermingham</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Andrew Hendry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pq65s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602101m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Ecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207tp72c"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Defining functional domains within GPNMB important for breast cancer cell invasion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacDonald, Patricia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Glycoprotein non-metastatic melanoma protein B (GPNMB)/Osteoactivin (OA) is a transmembrane protein that is commonly expressed in basal/triple-negative breast cancer. Our group discovered that GPNMB/OA is sufficient to enhance the migration and invasion of weakly metastatic murine breast cancer cells in vitro, and promotes the formation of bone and lung metastases in vivo. In this study, we sought to fully characterize the pro-invasive role of GPNMB/OA in human breast cancer cells by defining those motifs/domains within GPNMB/OA that are required to promote breast cancer cell invasion. In addition, we have sought the identity of putative GPNMB/OA interacting proteins that may be involved in promoting GPNMB/OA-mediated effects on breast cancer cell invasion and metastasis. To accomplish this, a panel of GPNMB/OA mutants were generated and expressed in the GPNMB/OA null BT-549 and MDA-MB-453 human breast cancer cells and subjected to in vitro invasion assays characterization. A candidate approach based on previous literature reports was used to facilitate the identification of GPNMB/OA protein binding partners in addition to attempting mass spectrometry analysis. Finally, a transgenic mouse model was created that expresses human GPNMB/OA under the control of the Mouse Mammary Tumor Virus (MMTV) promoter to further explore the role of GPNMB/OA on mammary gland development and tumorigenesis in vivo. Our results indicate that human GPNMB/OA is sufficient to induce enhanced invasion of BT549 breast cancer cells in vitro, which requires both the cytoplasmic tail and RGD recognition motif. Characterization of the MMTV-GPNMB/OA transgenic mice revealed that GPNMB/OA does not negatively affect normal mammary duct development in virgin females and no mammary tumors have developed to date. We conclude that GPNMB/OA is indeed capable of inducing invasion of breast cancer cells in vitro, which may require the participation of integrins and/or the residues/motifs within the cytoplasmic tail responsible for recruiting signalling molecules to this region of GPNMB/OA.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Glycoprotein non-metastatic melanoma protein B (GPNMB), aussi connu sous le nom de Ostéoactivine (OA), est une protéine transmembranaire fréquemment exprimée dans les tumeurs mammaires appartement au sous-type triple négatif. Notre groupe a mis en évidence que l'expression de GPNMB/OA est suffisante pour  accroître, in vitro, les capacités migratoires et invasives associées aux cellules murines de cancer du sein faiblement métastatiques. In vivo, l'expression de GPNMB/OA est caractérisée par une augmentation de la formation des métastases osseuses et pulmonaires. Dans cette étude, nous avons cherché à caractériser le rôle pro-invasif associé à l'expression de GPNMB/OA dans les cellules humaines de cancer du sein en identifiant les domaines ou motifs de GPNMB/OA impliqués dans le phénotype invasif des cellules de cancer du sein. D'une part, nous avons entrepris l'identification de protéines interagissant avec  GPNMB/OA et qui pourraient participer aux phénotypes associés à l'expression de GPNMB/OA. Pour ce faire, nous avons généré une série de mutants pour la protéine GPNMB et nous les avons exprimées dans les lignées cellulaires BT-549 et MDA-MB-453, qui n'exprime normalement pas GPNMB/OA, que nous avons par la suite soumis à des essais d'invasion in vitro. D'autre part, une étude de la littérature scientifique, associée à une analyse par spectrométrie de masse, ont été utilisées pour identifier les protéines partenaires potentielles de GPNMB/OA. Finalement, nous avons généré une lignée de souris transgénique qui exprime la forme humaine de GPNMB/OA sous le contrôle du promoteur Mouse Mammary Tumor Virus (MMTV). Ce modèle murin a été utilisé pour étudier le rôle de GPNMB/OA sur le développement de la glande mammaire et sur la tumorigenèse in vivo. Ainsi, ces travaux ont démontré que la forme humaine de GPNMB/OA est suffisante pour induire une augmentation des propriétés invasives des cellules BT549 et que ce phénotype requiert à la fois la région cytoplasmique et le motif RGD de la protéine GPNMB/OA. La caractérisation, des souris transgéniques MMTV-GPNMB/OA a révélé, pour sa part, que GPNMB/OA n'interfère pas avec le développement normal des glandes mammaires chez les femelles vierges et aucune tumeur n'a été détectée à ce jour. L'ensemble de nos données démontre que GPNMB/OA est capable d'induire les propriétés invasives associées aux cellules de cancer du sein, et que ce phénotype requiert l'interaction du motif RGD de la protéine GPNMB avec les intégrines et/ou des résidus ou motifs présents dans la partie cytoplasmique de GPNMB/OA et qui pourraient induire le recrutement de molécule de signalisation dans cette région de GPNMB/OA.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peter Siegel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hv64v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tp72c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579s55j"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The experience of emotional distress in women with scleroderma: a qualitative study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Newton, Evan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Depression or emotional distress seems to be an issue for many medical patients, but there is debate as to how it should be defined, measured, and treated. The goal of this study was to better understand this issue by conducting in-depth interviews with women with scleroderma, a chronic rheumatic disease. The main objectives were to determine how participants described distress, what they believed caused it, and how they coped with it. Interview transcripts were analyzed using qualitative thematic analysis. Many participants described distress associated with the illness, but the term "depression" was reserved for a very specific, severe experience. Participants preferred more normal mood descriptors, and often described distress in terms of demoralization, or adjustment disorder. Participants listed concrete aspects of the illness that caused distress, and some added that their reaction to stress could exacerbate the progression of the disease. Participants dealt with distress by not dwelling on their circumstances, by for the most part avoiding psychologists and support groups. The support participants preferred came in the form of contact with friends and family.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La dépression et la détresse émotionnelle représentent une difficulté pour plusieurs patients médicaux. Cependant, un débat existe autour de la façon dont celles-ci devraient être définies, mesurés et traités. Le but de ce projet était de d'aborder cette question en conduisant les entrevues avec des femmes atteintes par la sclérodermie, une maladie rhumatologique chronique. Les objectifs principaux était d'établir comment les participantes décrivaient leur détresse, ce qu'elles apercevaient comme étant la cause de celle-ci, et comment elles ont y pu faire face. Les transcrits des entrevues étaient analysés avec l'analyse qualitative thématique. Plusieurs des participantes ont décrit la détresse associée avec la maladie, mais le terme "dépression" était réservé pour une expérience spécifique et sévère. Les participantes ont préféré des descripteurs d'humeur plus banals, et ont fréquemment décrit la détresse comme étant consistant avec la définition de démoralisation. Elles ont listé des aspects concrets de leur maladie qu'elles apercevaient comme étant la cause de leur détresse, et quelques unes parmi elles ont ajouté que leur réaction au stress pourrait exacerber la progression de leur maladie. Les participantes ont gérer leur détresse en évitant de réfléchir sur leurs circonstances, et en évitant les services des psychologues et groupes de soutien pour patients. Le soutien que les participantes ont préférée étaient le contact avec leurs familles et amis. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Danielle Groleau</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Brett David Thombs</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k18n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579s55j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Clinical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17ct23n"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of trainees' skills on client emotional experiencing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Overington, Louise</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Therapist behaviours can impact the success of the therapeutic process for their clients.  This study examined whether two aspects of trainee therapists' behaviour – facilitative interpersonal skills and verbal response modes (VRM) – influenced their clients' process.  Therapist interpersonal skills and VRM were compared across two-minute video segments preceding either deepening levels of client emotional experiencing (N = 30) or unchanging experiencing levels (N = 30).  Interpersonal skills and VRM were unrelated to one another and to differences in client experiencing.  Although trainee skills were unrelated to deepening experiencing, this study provides a descriptive account of the skills that trainees employ with clients during their first year of clinical training.  Challenges of research in this field, limitations of the current study and avenues for future research are discussed. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le comportement d'un thérapeute peut influencer le succès du processus thérapeutique des patients.  Cette étude vise à examiner si deux aspects comportementaux de stagiaires thérapeutes –les compétences interpersonnelles et les modes de réponse verbaux (VRM) –ont influencé les processus de la thérapie.  Les compétences interpersonnelles et les VRM des stagiaires ont été comparés par intervalle de deux minutes précédant soit les niveaux de l'approfondissement  de l'expérience émotionnelle du client (N = 30), soit les niveaux d'expérience émotionnelle invariables (N = 30). Les résultats ne montrent pas de relation entre les compétences interpersonnelles et les VRM, ni selon l'expérience émotionnelle du patient. Bien que les compétences des stagiaires ne sont pas liées à l'approfondissent de l'expérience, cette étude fournit des informations concernant les compétences que les stagiaires emploient avec les patients pendant leur première année d'entraînement clinique.  Les défis de la recherche dans ce domaine, les limitations de l'étude et les perspectives actuelles pour les études futures sont discutées.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marilyn R. Fitzpatrick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nx30h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct23n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aww72bb88m"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Nursing</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Psychological distress after abortion among university students: Developing an intervention</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Curley, Maureen L</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background A gap exists within healthcare between identifying and treating adverse psychological outcomes to abortion.  Meanwhile, 30% of women worldwide experience significant emotional distress after abortion. Specifically, younger women are at the highest risk for developing mental health problems after abortion. No empirical data for interventions to relieve psychological distress after abortion were found.      Goal: This thesis provides a framework to identify and treat psychological distress after legal, induced, voluntary abortion. It proposes a first of a kind evidence-based and patient-centered intervention to relieve psychological distress after abortion among university students. The thesis proposes a theory and conceptual model to understand negative psychological responses to abortion. Population-specific evidence and preference for services support the theory.  Methods The United Kingdom Medical Research Guidelines were used to develop the intervention. Two phases of the five-phase method were used. First, the Pre-Clinical Phase developed: (a) the theoretical and (b) evidential basis for target symptoms of the intervention.  Next, using these results, the Modeling Phase established (c) the design,  (d) patient preferences, and (e) feasibility for delivering the intervention. The thesis is formatted as three manuscripts.        ResultsThe Pre-Clinical Phase applied psychological stress theory to guide the intervention. It also generated evidence from a cross sectional study of N=151 participants who identified target symptoms. Participants who preferred treatment for distress after abortion demonstrated severe psychological stress (Impact of Event Scores of &gt;26) and moderate perinatal grief (Perinatal Grief scores &gt; 60) focused on the pregnancy and abortion.  The Modeling Phase designed the intervention based on patient preferences for a group treatment addressing unanticipated guilt, enhanced coping skills, and education of psychological distress reactions after abortion.  Significance and Conclusions      The thesis is a series of studies that were used to develop a targeted and acceptable intervention for university students who had an abortion, reported distress afterward, and preferred treatment to relieve it if such treatment was available. The thesis provides a mechanism within nursing to understand, identify, and treat psychological distress after abortion that is population-focused, and currently does not exist. The intervention can be tested for efficacy and replicated on larger samples. Effective interventions after abortion have the potential to reduce psychiatric morbidity and mortality after abortion within a university student population.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Découvert Il existe dans le domaine médical une lacune entre la science et la pratique pour comprendre, identifier et traiter les conséquences psychologiques après un avortement.  En effet, 30% des femmes du monde qui ont choisi un avortement subissent des conséquences psychologiques significatives.  C'est surtout évident parmi les jeunes femmes que l'on trouve les risques les plus élevés pour ces problèmes psychologiques.  Les données empiriques pour les interventions qui adressent ce problème n'ont pas été découvertes.  ObjectifCette thèse a comme but de fournir une base de connaissance et pratique pour traiter les problèmes psychologiques, qui existent après un avortement.  L'intervention proposée, unique en son genre,  est basée sur les éléments de preuves recueillis des étudiantes universitaires qui ont éprouvé des effets négatifs après un avortement et qui accepteraient un traitement pour leur désordre. Cette thèse propose une théorie et un modèle pour mieux comprendre les mauvais effets psychologiques après un avortement.  L'évidence accumulée et les préférences des clients, concentres sur la population du groupe de contrôle, soutient la thèse.MéthodesThe United Kingdom Medical Research Guideline a fourni la méthode pour l'élaboration des interventions.   Parmi les cinq phases proposés dans ce guide, les deux premiers ont été utilisés: la phase préclinique et la phase modèle.  La phase préclinique développe  (a) une théorie pour la détresse après un avortement et (b) les symptômes ciblés pour l'intervention. Avec cette évidence comme base, la deuxième phase a été élaborée : (c) plan de l'intervention ;  (d) les préférences du client pour une intervention spécifique et  (e) la faisabilité et l'application du traitement. RésultatsLa phase préclinique, a  déterminé une théorie du désordre psychologique comme base de l'intervention.  En plus, une étude descriptive d'un groupe (N=151) de participants fournit l'évidence des symptômes ciblés.  Les participants qui cherchaient un traitement, avaient démontré une sévère détresse psychologique (Impact de Grands Nombres d'Evénement &gt;26 et deuil périnatal modéré &gt;60), spécifique à la grossesse et l'avortement.  L'évidence ramassée dans la phase préclinique a été utilisé pour déterminer une intervention appropriée.  Parmi ces interventions préférées parmi des clients étaient : le service d'une thérapie en groupe pour la culpabilité non anticipée, le succès des compétences, et l'enseignement sur les effets psychologiques après un avortement. Signification et conclusionLa thèse actuelle représente une série d'études utilisée pour développer une intervention ciblée et acceptée par les étudiants universitaires qui, après avoir subi un avortement, ont éprouvé des conséquences psychologiques négatives et qui cherchaient un  traitement médical.  Cette thèse pourvoit une base de connaissance cohérente dans la profession d'infirmière à comprendre, identifier, et traiter la détresse psychologique après un avortement.  Cette connaissance, concentrée dans la population, n'existe pas encore.  L'intervention développée pourrait être examinée pour l'efficacité et répliquée parmi les groupes plus nombreux.  Les interventions efficaces, qui réduisent la détresse après un avortement pourraient aussi réduire la portée de morbidité psychiatrique et mortalité après l'avortement dans la population du niveau universitaire. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>C. Celeste Johnston</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870w191.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bb88m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Nursing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahh63sw173"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Is a cerebellar deficit the underlying cause of reading disabilities?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Irannejad, Shahrzad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis critically appraised the Cerebellar Deficit Theory (CDT) which claims to provide a parsimonious explanation of the two most prominent existing cognitive deficit theories of dyslexia, namely the phonological and the speed naming deficit theories. Specifically, a mild congenital cerebellar deficit is proposed to give rise to a series of impairments that eventually lead to difficulties in rapid naming, phonological processing and reading. Conceptual problems with the theoretical model behind the CDT were first identified and discussed. The behavioral evidence related to CDT was then evaluated. Following this evaluation, four major questions related to CDT were examined: (1) Was there a relationship between word reading as measured by word identification task and (a) phonological awareness, (b) reading fluency and rapid automatized naming, and (c) purported cerebellar processing tasks?; (2) Did a subgroup of children with dyslexia selected from the sample for this thesis differ in their performance on any of the motor, cerebellar, reading, phonological, and rapid naming measures when compared to a reading-age (RA) and chronological-age (CA) match control subgroup selected from the same sample?; (3) Did any of these group differences remain when the effect of attention was controlled statistically?; and (4) Did a cerebellar deficit provide a good explanatory model at the individual level? Participants were 85 children attending mainstream English schools in Quebec. All participants completed a series of motor and cerebellar-related tasks. Their intellectual functioning, single word reading, word reading efficiency, speed naming, and phonological awareness skills were also assessed. Altogether, results did not seem to support a cerebellar deficit account of dyslexia. Specifically, findings did not reveal a significant relationship between any of the literacy measures and those related to motor and cerebellar tasks. Motor and cerebellar tasks were also not successful in differentiating between 17 participants in the dyslexia subgroup and those in the RA- and CA-match control at either a group or an individual level. This pattern persisted after attention was controlled statistically. A phonological deficit, independent from a cerebellar deficit, seemed to provide the best-supported account of reading difficulties for the dyslexia subgroup in contrast with the typical readers. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse a offert une appréciation critique de la théorie du déficit cérébelleux (TDC) qui prétend fournir une explication parcimonieuse des deux théories du déficit cognitif les plus répandues sur la dyslexie, à savoir la théorie du déficit phonologique et celle du déficit de dénomination rapide. Plus précisément, un déficit cérébelleux congénital léger est réputé causer un ensemble de défaillances qui, à terme, génèrent des troubles de dénomination rapide, de traitement phonologique et de lecture. La thèse a d'abord identifié et commenté les problèmes conceptuels du modèle théorique à la base de la TDC. Les données comportementales liées à la TDC ont ensuite été évaluées. À la suite de cette évaluation, la thèse s'est penchée sur quatre questions d'importance portant sur la TDC : (1) Y a-t-il un lien entre la lecture des mots telle que mesurée par l'identification des mots et (a) la conscience phonologique, (b) la fluence de lecture et la dénomination rapide automatisée, et (c) les soi-disant tâches liées au traitement cérébelleux?; (2) Est-ce qu'un sous-groupe d'enfants dyslexiques choisis parmi l'échantillon utilisé pour cette thèse s'est distingué par ses résultats à l'une ou l'autre des mesures de motricité, d'activité cérébelleuse, de lecture, d'habileté phonologique et de dénomination rapide lorsqu'on l'a comparé à un sous-groupe témoin d'âge correspondant sur le plan de ses capacités de lecture et sur le plan chronologique et choisi parmi le même échantillon?; (3) Est-ce que certaines de ces différences entre les groupes ont subsisté après que l'effet d'attention a été statistiquement géré?; et (4) Le déficit cérébelleux a-t-il offert un bon modèle explicatif au niveau individuel? Les participants furent un groupe de 85 enfants fréquentant l'école anglaise régulière au Québec. Tous ont accompli un ensemble de tâches motrices et cognitives. Leur fonctionnement intellectuel, leur habileté à lire un mot, leur efficacité en lecture, leur aptitude à la dénomination rapide et leur conscience phonologique ont aussi été évalués. Les résultats globaux n'ont pas vraiment renforcé l'idée que la dyslexie s'explique par le déficit cérébelleux. Plus précisément, les conclusions n'ont pas permis d'établir de lien étroit entre l'une ou l'autre des mesures de littératie et celles concernant les tâches motrices ou cognitives. Ces dernières tâches n'ont pas davantage permis de distinguer les 17 participants du sous-groupe de dyslexiques de ceux des groupes témoins, au niveau tant collectif qu'individuel. Cette tendance s'est maintenue après la gestion statistique de l'attention. Un déficit phonologique, indépendant de tout déficit cérébelleux, a semblé fournir l'explication la plus convaincante des difficultés en lecture du sous-groupe de dyslexiques par rapport aux lecteurs typiques.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robert Savage</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870w20s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sw173</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kq79c"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Eigenvalue estimation with the Rayleigh-Ritz and Lanczos methods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Panayotov, Ivo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse, nous étudions deux problèmes différents liés aux bornes d'erreur devaleurs propres. Dans la première partie de notre thèse, nous examinons une conjecturede Knyazev et Argentati [Siam J. Matrix Anal. Appl., 29 (2006), pp. 15 – 32 ]bornant la différence entre les valeurs Ritz d'une matrice hermitienne A correspondantà deux sous-espaces, dont l'un est A-invariant. Nous obtenons une preuve pourune version légèrement plus faible de la conjecture, et discutons la preuve complètepubliée récemment. De plus, nous dérivons certaines implications de la borne, maintenantprouvée, et la comparons à une borne classique dans le même contexte. Dansla deuxième partie de notre thèse, nous dérivons certaines propriétés des matricesHessenberg complexes et examinons les cas appropriés normaux de celles-ci afin deréexaminer les longueurs des vecteurs Ritz dans l'analyse d'erreur du processus deLanczos de tridiagonalization de certaines matrices normales. Cette question a déjàété étudiée pour le cas symétrique réel, mais une partie de l'analyse n'a jamais étépubliée dans une revue scientifique; dans ce cas, nous présentons une nouvelle théorie.Pour le cas plus général de matrices normales, nous développons une théorie applicable,avec de nouvelles bornes serrées.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In this thesis we study two different problems related to eigenvalue error bounds. Inthe first part of our thesis, we examine a conjecture of Knyazev and Argentati [SiamJ. Matrix Anal. Appl., 29 (2006), pp. 15–32 ] bounding the difference between Ritzvalues of a Hermitian matrix A for two subspaces, one of which is A-invariant. Weprovide a proof for a slightly weaker version of the conjecture, and discuss the recentlypublished full proof. Moreover we give implications of the now proven bound andexamine how it compares to a classical bound in the same context. In the second partof our thesis, we derive some properties of complex Hessenberg matrices and considerthe relevant normal matrix cases of these to re-examine the lengths of the Ritz vectorsin the rounding error analysis of the Lanczos process for tridiagonalizing certainnormal matrices. This question has already been studied for the real symmetric case,but part of that answer has never been published in scientific journals, and in that casewe give new theory. For the more general normal matrix cases we develop applicable theory including some new tight bounds.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Christopher Paige</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Xiao-Wen Chang</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p7541.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kq79c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap2676v96f"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Good relations: an alternative paradigm for natural resource governance in Eeyou Istchee</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Troniak, Shauna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les parties de deux accords modernes à Eeyou istchee – les cris d'Eeyou istchee et lesGouvernements du Canada et du Québec – expriment leur relation en tant que «nouvelle relation» fondée sur des principes de reconnaissance mutuelle et réciprocité. La perspective actuelle sur la nouvelle relation à Eeyou istchee est insuffisante pour comprendre les interactions complexes engendrées par les demandes politiques et normatives des parties. Un nouveau paradigme est donc nécessaire pour conceptualiser une nouvelle relation, en mettant l'accent sur les processus politiques et juridiques permettant aux Autochtones et à l'état de se livrer au dialogue réciproque et de négocier des compromis lors de désaccords normatifs de grande profondeur. Des mécanismes formels et informels pour la gouvernance décentralisée des ressources naturelles – y compris les consultations des communautés, et les institutions de co-gestion et de gestion communautaire – peuvent permettre un échange politique et normatif dans le cadre d'un nouveau paradigme.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The parties to two modern agreements in Eeyou Istchee – the Crees of Eeyou Istchee and the Governments of Canada and Quebec – describe their treaty relationship in terms of a "new relationship" based on principles such as mutual recognition and reciprocity.Current perspectives on a new relationship in Eeyou Istchee are inadequate to understand the parties' complex normative interactions and political claims for recognition. An alternative paradigm is needed to conceptualize a new relationship, which emphasizes the political and legal processes that allow Aboriginal peoples and state actors to engage in reciprocal dialogue, and negotiate compromises to deep-seated normative disagreements. Formal and informal mechanisms for decentralized governance of natural resources – including community consultation processes, and institutions for co-management and community-based management – can provide forums for the parties to negotiate their political and normative interactions within an alternative paradigm.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kirsten Anker</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860730k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676v96f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw37637157"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Coordinated multi-level regulation and homeostatic inflammomodulatory functions of the cyclooxygenase-2/ prostaglandin E2 axis in rheumatoid arthritis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mancini, Arturo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>   Rheumatoid arthritis (RA) is a chronic, autoimmune inflammatory disorder that exhibits both articular and systemic manifestations. Prominent among molecular mediators of RA is prostaglandin E2 (PGE2) and the inducible rate-limiting enzyme involved in its biosynthesis, cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2). Long regarded as inflammogenic, the so-called "COX-2/PGE2 axis" is now likened to a homeostatic inflammomodulatory axis poised to regulate the initiation, magnitude, duration and resolution of the inflammatory response. The COX-2/PGE2 pathway's regulatory role in maintaining normal inflammatory homeostasis (i.e., "inflammostasis") is dependent on its tight temporal and inflammation phase-specific regulation; yet, the mechanisms governing the timing and dynamics of this pathway's activity during inflammatory episodes are ill-defined.   The data presented in this thesis demonstrate that the COX-2/PGE2 axis is subject to a series of regulatory "control points" implicating various effector mechanisms and positioned at different levels along the axis to ensure tight temporal regulation of its activity during an inflammatory response. Our data expose a novel control point involving proteolytic cleavage-induced potentiation of human synovial fibroblast (HSF) COX-2 catalytic activity following proinflammatory stimulation. Cleavage is limited, site-specific and quantitatively tightly correlated to PGE2 production (R2 = 0.941). Pharmacological COX-2 inhibitors impede enzyme cleavage, while inhibition of calpain and cathepsin proteases blocks PGE2 biosynthesis in HSFs; in both cases, PGE2 production and COX-2 cleavage remain tightly correlated. Subsequent to this first control point, the COX-2/PGE2 axis falls subject to feedback regulation by PGE2 at the level of COX-2 gene expression. We show that PGE2 induces the phosphorylation of tristetraprolin (TTP), a well-studied mRNA destabilizing protein. Phosphorylation (likely p38 MAPK-mediated) promotes TTP's nuclear export/cytoplasmic sequestration and concomitantly inhibits its mRNA destabilizing capacity, culminating in coupled and coordinated COX-2 promoter transactivation and mRNA stabilization. The consequent increase in COX-2 mRNA/protein levels establishes a self-sustaining cycle of PGE2 production that ensures the expression of downstream PGE2 target genes implicated in terminating inflammation. Among such genes is the p38 MAPK phosphatase DUSP-1, whose expression in HSFs is controlled transcriptionally (partly via the p38 MAPK pathway) and post-transcriptionally (by TTP). Like COX-2, coupling of DUSP-1 gene transcription and mRNA stabilization ensures sustained DUSP-1 levels required for the shutdown of p38 MAPK activity and subsequent inflammatory resolution. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>   La polyarthrite rhumatoïde (PR) est une maladie auto-immune, inflammatoire chronique des articulations avec des manifestations systémiques. Parmi les médiateurs moléculaires de cette maladie se retrouve la prostaglandine E2 (PGE2) et l'enzyme inductible responsable de sa synthèse durant l'inflammation, la cyclooxygénase-2 (COX-2). Longtemps considéré comme inflammogénique, l'axe COX-2/PGE2 est maintenant reconnu pour ses activités homéostatiques et inflammomodulatrices et son rôle régulateur de l'initiation, l'ampleur, la durée et la résolution de la réponse inflammatoire. La conservation de l'homéostasie inflammatoire (i.e., "inflammostasie") par l'axe COX-2/PGE2 nécessite que son activité soit temporellement réguleé par des mécanismes qui sont spécifiquement adaptés à chaque phase de la réponse inflammatoire; cependant, les modes régulateurs de cet axe durant des épisodes inflammatoires restent mal définis.   Mes données de thèse démontrent que l'axe COX-2/PGE2 est régulé à plusieurs niveaux (i.e., "points de contrôle") par des mécanismes effecteurs différents et conçus pour assurer une régulation temporelle de l'axe durant une réponse inflammatoire. Nos données révèlent un point de contrôle antérieurement inconnu impliquant la potentialisation de l'activité enzymatique de la COX-2 par son clivage protéolytique dans les fibroblastes synoviaux humains (HSFs) stimulés avec des agents proinflammatoires. Ce clivage est limité, site spécifique et quantitativement corrélé avec la synthèse de PGE2 (R2 = 0.941). Les inhibiteurs pharmacologiques de la COX-2 bloquent son clivage, alors que l'inhibition des protéases calpaïnes et cathepsines empêche la synthèse de PGE2 dans les HSFs; dans chacun des cas, la production de PGE2 et le clivage de la COX-2 restent fortement corrélés. Suite à ce premier point de contrôle, l'axe COX-2/PGE2 est assujetti au rétrocontrôle par la PGE2 au niveau de l'expression de la COX-2. Nous illustrons que la PGE2 induit la phosphorylation de tristetraprolin (TTP), une protéine déstabilisatrice de l'ARN. Cette phosphorylation (probablement mediée par la voie MAPK p38) cause l'export nucléaire/séquestration cytoplasmique de TTP, conduisant à l'inhibition de ses capacités déstabilisatrices et, ultimement, à l'activation transcriptionnelle et stabilisation de l'ARN couplée et coordonné de la COX-2. Les niveaux élevés conséquents de l'ARN/protéine COX-2 établissent un cycle autoreproducteur pour la synthèse de PGE2 qui assure l'expression des gènes cibles de la PGE2 impliquées dans la résolution de l'inflammation. Parmi ces gènes se retrouve la phosphatase DUSP-1 ("dual-specificity phosphatase"), donc l'expression dans les HSFs est contrôlée au niveau transcriptionnel, en partie par la voie MAPK p38, et post-transcriptionnel par la TTP. Comme pour la COX-2, le couplage de ces deux mécanismes régulateurs assure l'expression soutenue de la DUSP-1 requise pour l'inactivation de la voie p38 et la résolution éventuelle de l'inflammation. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Giovanni Di Battista</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526c681.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w37637157</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225b35p"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of Lgl1 and its role in hyperoxic injury of the newborn lung</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nadeau, Katia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La dysplasie bronchopulmonaire (DBP), une maladie caractérisée par l'arrêt du développement alvéolaire, demeure une des causes principales de morbidité chez les nouveau-nés de faible poids. Plus d'informations sur les mécanismes et les gènes impliqués dans l'alvéolarisation sont nécessaires afin de mieux comprendre la physiopathologie de cette maladie et aider au développement de nouvelles interventions thérapeutiques. LGL1 est une glycoprotéine sécrétée dans le poumon qui est induite par les glucocorticoïdes et est finement régulée lors du développement. Afin d'éclaircir le rôle de Lgl1 dans l'alvéolarisation, j'ai étudié l'expression de Lgl1 dans deux modèles de toxicité d'oxygène chez le rat. Sous hyperoxie, les niveaux de Lgl1 sont réduits puis redeviennent normaux lors de la récupération dans l'air. Le promoteur (région 5') de Lgl1 contient des sites de liaisons pour les récepteurs de glucocorticoïdes (GC), d'acide rétinoïque (AR), de la vitamine D (Vit D), ainsi que pour le facteur de transcription Smad3 (transmet le signal de « transforming growth factor-beta », TGF-β). L'exposition de cellules fibroblastes pulmonaires primaires de rat à ces agents, ensemble ou en combinaison, confirme qu'ils régulent tous l'expression de Lgl1. Fait intéressant, la Vit D ou l'AR seules peuvent inhiber l'expression de Lgl1 induite par GC. Par contre, quand la Vit D et l'AR sont présentes ensemble, aucune inhibition n'est observée sur l'expression de Lgl1 induite par GC. Des analyses de luciférase ont démontrées que ces agents agissent au niveau de la transcription de Lgl1. Une analyse de la localisation des sites de liaisons des récepteurs de GC, AR et Vit D indique que l'emplacement particulier de ces sites sur le promoteur de Lgl1 est aussi trouvé sur 81% des promoteurs de 65 gènes ayant un rôle connu dans le développement des poumons (comparé à seulement 48% d'un groupe de 1000 gènes aléatoires). Ceci suggère que l'encombrement stérique peut influencer l'accessibilité au promoteur quand plus d'un de ces agents est présent à la fois. Afin de déterminer si une déficience de Lgl1 est associée à une arrestation de l'alvéolarisation et contribue à la physiopathologie de la DBP, une souris mutante pour le gène Lgl1 a été générée. Un déficit de Lgl1 a révélé un phénotype complexe, incluant notamment : l'hyperplasie des cellules caliciformes, la production de mucus, l'augmentation de l'expression des interleukines 4 et 13, la perturbation du développement pulmonaire, la fragmentation de l'élastine et la perturbation de la fonction mécanique du poumon. Ce phénotype est aggravé par l'hyperoxie, suggérant que la carence de Lgl1 pourrait contribuer à la DBP dans la période néonatale.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD), a leading cause of morbidity in very low birth weight infants, is characterized by an arrest in alveolar development. An improved insight into the genes and mechanisms that regulate alveolarization is essential to enhance our understanding of the lung pathophysiology of BPD.  LGL1, is a developmentally regulated, glucocorticoid induced, secreted glycoprotein in the lung. In order to establish the role of Lgl1 in alveolarization, I studied Lgl1 expression in two rat models of oxygen toxicity (BPD) that reproduce many of the characteristic features of BPD.  I showed that in hyperoxia, Lgl1 levels are reduced and that these levels normalize during recovery in air. The 5' promoter region of Lgl1 has binding sites for the glucocorticoid (GC), retinoic acid (RA) and vitamin D (Vit D) receptors and for Smad3 (mediates transforming growth factor-beta (TGF-β) signalling), all of which modulate alveolarization and are considered to have a role in neonatal lung injury. Exposure of primary rat lung fibroblasts to GC, RA, Vit D and TGF-β1, alone or in combination, confirmed that all these agents regulate Lgl1 expression. Interestingly, the individual inhibitory effects of Vit D and RA on GC induction of Lgl1 were abrogated when both agents were present. Results of Luciferase assays were consistent with a role for all of these agents in transcriptional regulation.  Interestingly, an analysis of the proximity (&lt;50 base pairs) of binding sites for overlapping Vit D and RA receptors to that of the GC receptor identified 81% of promoters in 65 genes (including Lgl1) important in human lung development compared to 48% in a random set of 1000 genes. This suggests that steric hindrance may influence promoter accessibility when more than one of these agents is present simultaneously.  In order to further explore the functional role of Lgl1, an Lgl1 knockout mouse model was generated. Absence of Lgl1 is embryonic lethal.  Haploinsufficiency for Lgl1 deficiency was associated with a complex phenotype including: goblet cell hyperplasia, mucus production, increased expression of interleukins 4 and 13, elastin fragmentation and disruption of adult lung function. This phenotype was exacerbated by oxygen exposure. The combined results of my studies suggest that Lgl1 deficiency may contribute to neonatal lung injury in BPD.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Feige Kaplan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xr96j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225b35p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd375w58n"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sensory and autonomic function in subclinical depression</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lehoux, Cory Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La dépression est un des troubles psychiatriques les plus communs et est associée avec des incapacités significatives, telles la douleur, un dysfonctionnement physique, et un nombre de conditions médicales sérieuses. Les mécanismes pathophysiologiques sous-jacents cette association ne sont pas bien compris, mais semblent impliquer le système du stress. Cette thèse explore le fonctionnement des systèmes sensoriel et du stress chez de jeunes adultes avec une humeur dépressive sous-clinique – c'est-à-dire sous le seuil de la dépression majeure – et des participants contrôles ayant une humeur normale. La douleur et les problèmes somatiques sont fréquents chez les hommes et les femmes ayant des symptômes dépressifs, malgré le fait que leur seuil de la douleur soit normal. Ceci suggère que leurs maux et douleurs ne sont pas le résultat d'une hypersensibilité généralisée.  La réponse inflammatoire induite par la capsaïcine était réduite de façon significative chez les participants à l'humeur basse, suggérant un fonctionnement détérioré, ou même, une perte de fibres afférentes à petit diamètre dans les couches superficielles de la peau. Le fonctionnement du système nerveux autonome était aussi anormal dans la dépression sous-clinique. La variabilité du rythme cardiaque au repos était plus basse, reflétant un changement dans la balance sympathovagale, caractérisé par une activité vagale réduite et/ou une activité sympathique augmentée. La réponse à un stress mineur était similairement anormale, mais l'augmentation de la réactivité autonome au stress était plus fortement associée aux symptômes anxieux que dépressifs. Le réflexe vasoconstricteur sympathique était intact chez les participants à l'humeur basse, mais une augmentation de la réponse vasoconstrictrice chez les femmes à l'humeur basse, mais pas les hommes, suggère une hyperréactivité sympathique. Les données impliquent que, comme lors d'une dépression majeure, une humeur basse sous-clinique n'est pas une condition bénigne, mais est associée avec une santé détériorée, des plaintes somatiques, de la douleur, et un dysfonctionnement sensoriel chez des adultes en apparence en bonne santé. Le dysfonctionnement du système autonome est similaire à ce qui a été observé dans les populations cliniques, et il fournit une explication plausible aux problèmes sensoriels et somatiques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Depression is among the most common psychiatric disorders and is associated with significant disability, including pain, physical dysfunction, and a number of serious medical conditions. The pathophysiological mechanisms underlying this relationship are unclear, but are thought to involve dysfunction of the stress system. This thesis explores sensory and stress function in young adults with subclinical low mood – i.e. below the threshold for a clinical depressive disorder – and normal mood controls. Pain and somatic problems were frequent in men and women with depressive symptoms, despite the fact that their pain thresholds were normal. This suggests that their aches and pains were not the result of generalized hypersensitivity. The inflammatory response induced by capsaicin was significantly reduced in low mood, indicating impaired function, or even loss, of small-diameter afferent fibres in the superficial layers of the skin. Function of the autonomic system was also abnormal in subclinical depression. Heart rate variability at rest was lower, reflecting a shift in sympathovagal balance characterized by decreased vagal and/or increased sympathetic tone. The response to a mild stressor was similarly abnormal, but increased autonomic reactivity to stress was more strongly associated with anxiety than depression scores. The peripheral sympathetic vasoconstriction reflex was intact in low mood subjects, with an increased vasoconstrictive response in low mood women, but not men, suggesting sympathetic hyperreactivity. The data imply that, like clinical depression, subclinical low mood is not a benign condition, but is associated with impaired health, pain and somatic complaints, and sensory dysfunction in apparently healthy young adults. The autonomic dysfunction is similar to that observed in clinical populations, and it provides a plausible explanation for the sensory and somatic problems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Frances V. Abbott</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93gz86n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375w58n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Physiological</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fx22m"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Journey, a shared virtual space middleware</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Denault, Alexandre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The complexity of developing multiplayer games, along with their popularity, has grown tremendously in the recent years. The most complex of these, Massively Multiplayer Games (MMOGs), require developers to deal with many issues, such as scalability, reliability and cheat prevention. Although individual solutions to these problems exists, very little academic work has been done to address all these issues simultaneously. In addition, experimentation in these areas can require a significant implementation effort.In this work, we present Journey, a unified framework that address all these issues in a simple, modular and efficient architecture leveraging replicated objects. Scalability is addressed through the use of a dynamic cell load-balancing strategy while fault tolerance and cheat prevention are achieved by leveraging existing replicated objects in the system. The proposed framework is implemented using numerous enhancements not found in traditional replication, like obstacle-aware partitioning and remote procedure call systems.The efficiency of this framework is illustrated through the use of Mammoth, a massively multiplayer research framework. Using experimental data from human players, artificial players (NPC) were built and used to stress test and gather performance data. Analysis of this data demonstrated that load balancing provides important scalability benefits while very little overhead is incurred from the fault tolerance and cheat prevention systems.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans les dernières années, la popularité des jeux multi-joueurs a connu une croissance sans égale. Cette croissance a aussi provoqué une augmentation importante dans la complexité de développement, surtout pour les jeux en ligne massivement multi-joueurs (MMOGs). Ces jeux posent des problèmes sérieux, tel que la croissance de capacité, la fiabilité et la prévention de la tricherie. Quoiqu'il existe de nombreuses solutions pour chacun de ces problèmes, très peu de travail académique adresse tous ces problèmes ensembles. De plus, l'expérimentation dans ces domaines nécessite de grands efforts de développement.Ce document présente Journey, un cadre de librairies informatiques unifiées qui adresse tous ces problèmes avec une architecture simple, modulaire et efficace tirant parti de la technologie des objets répliqués. Journey utilise un système d'équilibrage de charge avec cellule dynamique pour pallier aux problèmes de capacité. De plus, les défis de tolérance des failles et la prévention de la tricherie peuvent être adressés à l'aide des objets déjà répliqués dans le système. L'outil proposé utilise plusieurs améliorations qui n'existe pas dans la réplication traditionnelle, tel que la division des espaces prenant compte des obstacles et l'exécution de méthode distantes.La performance de Journey est évaluée à l'aide de Mammoth, un outil de recherche pour les environnements massivement multi-joueurs. À l'aide de données expérimentales de joueurs humains, des joueurs artificiels on été construits pour mesurer la capacité et la performance de l'outil proposé. L'analyse de ses données démontre que l'équilibre des charges démontre une grande augmentation de capacité. De plus, les systèmes de tolérance de fautes et de prévention de la tricherie on très peu d'impact sur la performance du système.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jorg Andreas Kienzle</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n3723.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fx22m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A73666484s"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of the posterior parietal cortex in the manipulation of information in working memory and its dissociation from the prefrontal cortex</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Champod, Anne Sophie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Au cours des dernières décennies, le rôle du cortex pariétal postérieur (CPP) dans les processus de mémoire de travail a été largement débattu. Le fait que cette région soit impliquée en tandem avec le cortex préfrontal (CP) durant la performance de tâches de mémoire de travail a soulevé un questionnement concernant la spécificité de son rôle. La présente thèse porte sur deux régions préfrontale et pariétale, qui sont presque invariablement actives de façon simultanée lors de la performance de tâches de mémoire de travail, soit le cortex du segment horizontal du sillon intrapariétal (SIP) et le cortex préfrontal méso-dorsolatéral (CPMD). Le but principal des présentes études était de déterminer le rôle du SIP dans les processus de mémoire du travail et de dissocier sa contribution de celle du CPMD. Alors que la contribution du CPP aux tâches de mémoire de travail est souvent attribuée aux processus d'encodage et de récupération, la présente thèse teste l'hypothèse stipulant que cette région est directement impliquée dans la manipulation de l'information. De plus, l'hypothèse testée concernant le CPMD stipule que l'implication de cette région dans la manipulation de l'information est secondaire à son rôle dans le contrôle continu (« monitoring ») de cette information. La présente thèse est composée de deux études d'imagerie par résonance magnétique fonctionnelle. Pour ces études, des tâches de manipulation (tâche expérimentale 1), de monitoring (tâche expérimentale 2), et de reconnaissance (tâche contrôle) ont été utilisées afin de dissocier la contribution du CPP de celle du CP dans les processus de mémoire de travail. Des stimuli visuels non-verbaux (étude 1) et verbaux (étude 2) ont été utilisés pour examiner la généralisation du rôle du CPP dans la manipulation de l'information de différents domaines. Pour la première étude, l'utilisation d'un paradigme de soustraction a permis la comparaison du signal relié à la performance des deux tâches expérimentales. Une augmentation de l'activité a été observée au niveau du SIP suite à la soustraction du signal relié à la tâche de monitoring à celui relié à la tâche de manipulation de l'information. Aucune augmentation d'activité significative n'a été observée au niveau du CPMD pour cette comparaison. Pour la comparaison inverse, une augmentation de l'activité a été observée au niveau du CPMD et aucune augmentation significative de l'activité n'a été observée au niveau du SIP. La dissociation fonctionnelle de ces deux régions est en accord avec les rôles suggérés du CPP et du CP dans la manipulation et le monitoring de l'information, respectivement. Pour la deuxième étude, un modèle paramétrique a permis d'examiner la modulation de l'activité au niveau du CPP et du CP avec une augmentation des demandes de manipulation et de monitoring de l'information. Les résultats démontrent une augmentation significative de l'activité au niveau du CPMD et du CPP avec une augmentation du nombre de mots à manipuler. À l'opposé, nos résultats ont montré une augmentation significative de l'activité au niveau du CP, et non au niveau du CPP, avec une augmentation du nombre de mots à contrôler de façon continue. Puisque la manipulation en mémoire de travail requiert le monitoring de l'information, mais que le monitoring ne requiert pas la manipulation de cette information, ces résultats sont en accord avec les rôles respectifs suggérés du CPP et du CP dans les processus de mémoire de travail. Ces études démontrent un rôle du SIP dans la manipulation de l'information en mémoire du travail. Ce rôle est dissociable de la contribution du CPMD dans le monitoring de l'information. Il s'agit donc de la première démonstration du rôle central du CPP dans la manipulation de l'information en mémoire de travail.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Over the past decades, there has been a growing debate about the role of the posterior parietal cortex (PPC) in working memory processes. The frequent increase in activity in this region together with the prefrontal cortex during the performance of working memory tasks has raised the issue of its contribution to working memory function. This thesis focused on two specific prefrontal and posterior parietal regions that are almost invariably co-activated during the performance of working memory tasks, namely the horizontal segment of the intraparietal sulcus (IPS) and the mid-dorsolateral prefrontal cortex (MDLFC). The main aim of the present set of studies was to identify the role of the horizontal segment of the IPS region in working memory processes and to dissociate its contribution from that of the MDLFC. Whereas the contribution of the PPC to working memory has been attributed typically to storage and retrieval processes, the research reported in this thesis tested, for the first time, the hypothesis that this region is centrally involved in the manipulation of information in working memory. Additionally, it was hypothesized that the MDLFC was only secondarily involved in the manipulation of information in working memory due to its specific role in the monitoring of that information. The present thesis is composed of two event-related functional magnetic resonance imaging studies that have used manipulation (experimental task 1), monitoring (experimental task 2), and recognition control tasks to dissociate the contribution of the PPC from that of the prefrontal cortex in the manipulation and monitoring of information in working memory, respectively. Visual non-verbal (Study 1) and verbal stimuli (Study 2) were used to examine the generalization of the role of the PPC in the manipulation of items of information from different domains. In the first study, the use of a subtraction paradigm allowed the direct comparison of the signal related to the performance of the two experimental tasks. In the manipulation minus monitoring comparison, increased activity was observed in the horizontal segment of the IPS but no significant increase in activity was observed in the MDLFC. The reverse pattern of results was obtained in the monitoring minus manipulation comparison, that is, increased activity was observed in the MDLFC and no significant activity was observed in the horizontal segment of the IPS. The dissociable pattern of activity in these two brain regions was consistent with the proposed role of the PPC and prefrontal cortex in the manipulation and monitoring of information in working memory, respectively. The second study used a parametric design to examine the differential modulation of activity in the PPC and prefrontal cortex with increasing manipulation and monitoring demands. The results showed a significant increase in activity in the MDLFC and in the PPC with an increase in the number of words to be manipulated. In contrast, there was a significant increase in activity in the prefrontal cortex, but not in the PPC, with an increase in the number of words to be monitored. Because manipulation in working memory requires monitoring but monitoring does not necessitate manipulation, these findings are in accordance with the suggested role of the PPC and prefrontal cortex in the manipulation and monitoring of information in working memory, respectively. Taken together, the results of the present set of studies demonstrated a central role for the horizontal segment of the IPS in the manipulation of information in working memory dissociable from that of the MDLFC in the monitoring of information. This role in manipulation processes applies to both verbal and non-verbal stimuli. The present thesis therefore demonstrated, for the first time, the primary role of the PPC in the manipulation of information in working memory.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michalakis Petrides</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236238j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666484s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Experimental</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>