<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042v05x"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Energy-balance equations for in-roll stresses for anisotropic materials in wound rolls</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hamad, Wadwood Y.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This Thesis concerns itself with the thorough investigation of the effects of core material parameters on the structural behaviour of wound rolls in core-roll winding systems. The underlying theme in this work is the derivation, based on the theory of elasticity, of an analytic expression for the core material's elasticity modulus as a function of only material parameters and geometry. The approach undertaken herein is purely theoretical and encompasses the rigorous analysis of principally two models; linear isotropic and anisotropic. As for the former, both planar and axisymmetric geometries are investigated; and in the case of the anisotropic model, an axisymmetric plane stress situation is studied. Moreover, finite-element modelling and analysis for the isotropic condition is carried out to confirm the theoretical findings. The objective is then to apply the results; namely, the inclusion of Poisson's ratio and elasticity modulus of the core material, to modify existing energy-balance roll structure formulae. This undertaking is called for if the aim is to have a valid winding model that simulates the actual winding process; i.e., one which incorporates sensing the presence of the core through layers of wound material. Results are further compared with existing winding models and conclusions are given.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pr45h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042v05x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abr86b4444"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Self-cycling fermentation (SCF) of acinetobacter calcoaceticus RAG- 1</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brown, Wayne A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Self-Cycling Fermentation (SCF) technique was applied to a culture of Acinetobacter calcoaceticus RAG-1. Both insoluble and soluble carbon substrates were used as the limiting nutrient. The disappearance of the carbon source was found to correspond with the attainment of a minimum in dissolved oxygen concentration. Cellular occurences, averaged out with asynchronous batch cultures, were magnified by the temporal alignment of metabolic events brought about by the synchronization associated with SCF's. The cell population doubled only once per cycle, thus establishing an equality between cycle time and doubling time. Parameters of primary interest were biomass concentration, total bioemulsifier (emulsan) production, cycle time, and residual carbon concentration. Cycle to cycle variation of these parameters was, in most cases, insignificant. The carbon substrate was completely utilized in all cases in which it was measured, giving this technique an advantage over chemostat-type fermentations. The dissolved oxygen profiles followed throughout a cycle were found to be repeatable. A characteristic shape was associated with each carbon source which can be related to the growth of the organism. Finally, the specific emulsan productivity of SCF's was found to be comparable to those achieved by systems presently implemented.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752h81s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b4444</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4t64gp50q"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of nitrogen in flotation for iron sulphide rejection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sandoval-Caballero, Ignacio</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The rejection of iron sulphides (pyrite and pyrrhotite) using nitrogen was evaluated on three Canadian complex sulphide ores. Laboratory scale work (at McGill and on-site) was conducted and, in addition, continuous minicell testwork was conducted on-site. The promotion of pyrite flotation using nitrogen was confirmed. It was evaluated at Brunswick Mining ahead of zinc flotation (using the minicells), and at Kidd Creek Mines in a laboratory scale investigation of reverse flotation. This latter also showed enhanced chalcopyrite flotation with nitrogen. The explanation of pyrite flotation using nitrogen was based on weakening of galvanic coupling with other sulphides. Nitrogen proved more effective than air in depression of pyrrhotite in processing a pentlandite/chalcopyrite ore. Under some conditions, chalcopyrite was also depressed by nitrogen (apparently when the pulp potential was less than O V vs. S.H.E.). The depressant action of nitrogen on pyrrhotite was interpreted as a reduction in the density of surface OH$ sp-$ sites necessary for electrostatic interaction with xanthate ion in the Hodgson/Agar model of pyrrhotite floatability.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gx30v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gp50q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pb51k"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"They walk through the fire like the blondest German" : African soldiers serving the Kaiser in German East Africa (1888-1914)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Von Herff, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The maintenance of German colonial rule in East Africa depended on a strong military presence. The Kaiserliche Schutztruppe fur Deutsch Ostafrika was established to meet this need, but financial and political constraints dictated that this force be manned by an African rank and file. Initially, most of the African recruits came from outside of the colony, but, as time passed, the Germans began recruiting from a few specific ethnic groups in the colony. The relationship between the African soldiers and their German employers yielded military successes for the new colonial government and, by extension, an enhanced status for the soldiers themselves. Over time, the Africans within the Schutztruppe distanced themselves from other Africans in the colony and began to develop separate communities at the government stations, which in turn fostered the growth of an askari group identity. The interests of these communities became inextricably linked to the German presence in the region. The development of this relationship helps to explain the askaris' support of the German campaign against the British during the First World War.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666561p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pb51k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Germany -- History, Military -- 19th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Germany -- History, Military -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>German East Africa -- History, Military</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z2016"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamics of neural networks and respiratory rhythm generation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lewis, John E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The phase resetting effects of stimulating the superior laryngeal nerve at different phases of the respiratory cycle in cats were measured in terms of the latency of onset of the cycle following stimulation. Fixed-delay stimulation was also used; for certain combinations of delay, stimulus intensity, and cycles between stimuli, it resulted in (1) a variable, rather than consistent, response, and (2) a transient increase in cycle duration during and after stimulation. Phase resetting and fixed-delay stimulation of a simple three-phase model for neural rhythm generation produce responses that are qualitatively similar to those obtained experimentally. We consider the dynamical properties of a class of theoretical models of neural networks that have the same mathematical formulation as the above three-phase model, but consist of a larger number of randomly connected elements. A simple transformation of these models shows correspondence with previous neural network models and enables a theoretical analysis of steady states and cycles. Complex aperiodic dynamics are found in networks consisting of 6 or more elements.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gt844.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z2016</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A41687j658"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cerebral blood flow regulation in the human and in a bovine model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kunicki, Suzanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The role of perivascular nerve fibers, smooth muscle cells and endothelium in the regulation of human and bovine cerebral artery contractility was investigated in vitro and the effect of cold-storage on vessel function was determined. Stimulation of perivascular nerve endings over a range of transmural electric field stimulation produced frequency- and duration-dependent responses in arteries of both species. The pharmacological properties of the cerebral vessels were studied using 17 different vasoactive agents which acted directly on the smooth muscle and/or on the endothelium. Parallel studies on human and bovine vessels indicate that the cow may be a very useful source of tissue for further experimentation. Cold-storage of cerebral arteries did not significantly alter vessel viability or responsiveness to vasoactive compounds, although a reduction in sensitivity to transmural electric field stimulation in human middle and posterior arteries was observed.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795888v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687j658</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jv91c"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Percent depth doses for diagnostic radiology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bissonnette, Jean-Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new model is proposed for the calculation of relative depth doses for diagnostic radiology using a direct photon transport/ray tracing technique which incorporates both primary and first scatter dose. The x-ray spectra are generated from computer algorithms based on the Birch and Marshall semi-empirical model; the spectra are established by matching calculated and measured transmission data. The algorithms for the generation of x-ray spectra and for the calculation of depth doses are described. Relative depth doses are determined for a number of radiographic techniques. The calculations are compared with measured and published depth doses; the agreement is very good for tube voltages below 90 kV$ sb{ rm p}$. It is suggested that relative integral doses obtained from relative depth doses give an accurate representation of risk reductions obtained with different radiological techniques. The integral dose reductions predicted by the model are within 8.5% of those from measured data.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wk37k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jv91c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn1070177"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Renewable Resources</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Moisture transfer behind windbreaks : laboratory simulations and conditional sampling in the field</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaharabata, Samuel K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The spatial distribution of local evaporation from ground-based sources behind solid and porous windbreaks was studied in laboratory models for steady state and intermittent flows. Field observations of wind and turbulence characteristics (turbulence intensity, power spectra and integral length scale L) over surfaces whose zero displacement (d) and roughness length (z$ sb0$) had also been determined, were used to scale the laboratory simulations. Scaling parameters were z/z$ sb0$, $ sigma$/U, L/z$ sb0$ and Uz$ sb{0}$/K, where z, U, $ sigma$ and K are height, wind speed, standard deviation of velocity fluctuations and turbulent diffusivity, respectively. The 50% porosity barrier was found to be the most effective single-barrier set-up for the reduction of moisture loss. Conditional sampling of fluctuations w' and q' of the wind and moisture, respectively, with sonic anemometer and fast-response Krypton hygrometer behind solid and porous windbreaks in the field, revealed frequency of occurrence, duration and intensity of those turbulent structures primarily responsible for moisture transfer.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225c144.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1070177</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Windbreaks, shelterbelts, etc</dc:subject><dc:subject>Evaporation (Meteorology)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8623j0002"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Joint effects of exercise and dietary carbohydrate on pregnancy outcome and early neonatal survival in rats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leccisi-Esrey, Katja</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Exercise and dietary carbohydrate restriction during pregnancy independently reduce maternal weight gain and offspring survival. It was hypothesized that the combined stress of exercise and dietary carbohydrate restriction would decrease offspring survival more than the independent effects. Within the exercise and sedentary groups pregnant rats were randomly assigned to be fed either 60%, 40%, or 20% dietary carbohydrate ad libitum. No statistical interactions were found between exercise and diet. Main effects were found for litter weight, maternal feed intake and weight gain, but not for litter size, pup birthweight, or pup survival in the first two days postpartum. Exercised rats gained less weight and ate more on a per gram body weight basis than sedentary rats. Rats fed carbohydrate restricted diets ate less and gained less weight than the rats fed 60% carbohydrate. These results demonstrate that the neonatal rat is not vulnerable to the effects of moderate maternal exercise and carbohydrate restriction during pregnancy.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sx004.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j0002</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pregnancy -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rats -- Reproduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Exercise</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahq37vp70c"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An analysis of Hannah Arendt's concept of worldlessness</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Graham, Nicholas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores the theme of "worldlessness" in the political thought of Hannah Arendt. The thesis analyzes "worldlessness" by way of Arendt's reflections on the sub-themes of "contemporary crisis," the "Western tradition," the "modern age" and the modern phenomenon of "thoughtlessness." These sub-themes are examined in chapters one, two, four and five respectively. Chapter three examines Arendt's conception of politics and "the world." The analysis proceeds on the basis of Arendt's stated conviction that political thought must take its bearings from "incidents of living experience" if it is to be adequate to its subject matter. More specifically, it investigates the basis and significance of Arendt's contention that the modern condition of "worldlessness" has produced a rupture between thought and experience which has radically altered the character of contemporary understanding. In general terms, the thesis examines the origins of modern worldlessness and the implications of this for contemporary thinking.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zc21f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vp70c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Arendt, Hannah, 1906-1975</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political science -- Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021g419"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of P:S ratio on glycemic control and insulin sensitivity in NIDDM</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Keller, Heather</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The independent effect of a high polyunsaturated:saturated fat (P:S) diet on glycemic control in humans has been poorly studied. We propose that a P:S $&gt;$ 1.0 vs P:S  1.0 vs. P:S  1.0. HDL and IGFl were significantly lower with the P:S $&gt;$ 1.0. Si was unaffected by the P:S difference, however, trends towards decreased Sg and increased insulin secretion were seen with P:S $&gt;$ 1.0. The small sample size limits the making of firm conclusions, however, it suggests that glycemic control may be improved through increased insulin secretion a result of an increase in P:S.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nz221.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g419</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Non-insulin-dependent diabetes -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9306t038d"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reproduction in the cattle egret (Bubulcus ibis ibis) : the function of breeding plumes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Krebs, Elizabeth Ann</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigates the colonization of Barbados, the seasonality of breeding, and the function of breeding plumes in the cattle egret Bubulcus ibis ibis. Colonization occurred around 1956, and the island now has 4 colonies. Numbers of birds at each colony are still increasing. Colonies are evenly spaced around the island. Plumage scores varied seasonally, and males had higher scores than females. Breeding activity peaked in July-August and November-March. Conspecific interference may force poorly plumed birds to breed when environmental conditions are poor. Chick mortality was primarily from starvation during periods of low breeding activity, and primarily from conspecific attack during high breeding activity. Fledging success did not increase with breeding activity. Plumage scores correlated positively in breeding pairs. Well-plumed males fed chicks more often than poorly plumed males and had the higher fledging success. Males contributed more to nest and nestling attendance when their mates were well plumed. Plumes appear to indicate the potential paternal care and the genetic quality of a mate.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c8652.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t038d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Birds -- Behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cattle egret -- Barbados -- Reproduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sexual behavior in animals</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A736665637"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Meteorology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The optimal balance in a low order atmoshperic model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guan, Shucai</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The nature of balance schemes and the concept of the slow manifold are discussed using Lorenz's (1980) model. It has been found that the Bear-Tribbia's (1977) scheme leads to a divergent series in locating the slow manifold of the model. The optimal asymptotic approximation and Pade approximant are use to "sum" the divergent series. The optimal asymptotic approximation gives reasonable approximation to the full solutions of the model and provides the optimal balance relations which are quite accurate when the forcing is small. The accuracy seems to degrade rather quickly as the forcing increases. The "imbalance", which is the difference between the actual flow and the optimal balance state, is found to consist of nearly monochromatic inertial-gravity waves. It is shown that the optimal asymptotic approximation fails to give a reasonable estimate of the level of inertial-gravity wave activity from the Rossby modes. For the case considered in this thesis, the Pade approximant does not seem to work well and hence offers no significant advantage over the optimal asymptotic approximation. The slow manifold, fuzzy slow manifold and effects of the scaling on the balance are also discussed in this thesis.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128b98q.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736665637</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w8472"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Human Communication Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anaphor resolution in written discourse : does phonology provide the missing link?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Orchard, Darla Gayle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A series of experiments was designed to investigate processes involved in written anaphor resolution. The first experiment established that lexical decisions are affected by phonological relationships between primes and targets that are presented visually. Experiment 2 explored the possibility that phonological codes are involved in processing gaps and pronouns, which are examples of surface and deep anaphors, respectively. No evidence was found to support this hypothesis. However, the complete lack of anaphor effects in Experiment 2 suggested that the lexical decision paradigm was not sensitive to anaphor processing. Experiments 3 and 4 compared the priming effects found using a probe recognition task, to those found using a lexical decision task. Results suggested that only probe recognition responses were facilitated by anaphors. Furthermore, the anaphor facilitation effect was found only for sentences containing pronouns. These results were compared to those of previous studies that have used priming methodologies.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g863p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w8472</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Language, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vc61p"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lipoprotein (a) is present in TG-rich fraction in endogenous and exogenous hypertriglyceridemia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Selinger, Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of this study was to examine apo(a)B particles distribution among plasma lipoproteins in two situations in which triglyceride-rich lipoproteins are increased: in normolipidemic subjects after a fat load and in patients with endogenous hypertriglyceridemia. The results obtained demonstrate that, in hypertriglyceridemic patients, the distribution of apo(a)B particles among lipoprotein fractions is different than that observed in normotriglyceridemic subjects. These differences in distribution are a result of the association of apo(a)B particles with TG-rich lipoproteins. Contrary to apo(a)B particles found in the cholesterol-rich fraction apo(a)B particles in the TG-rich fraction are associated with lipoproteins of different sizes. The amount of apo(a)B particles in the TG-rich fraction could represent up to 50% of its total concentration and may contribute to the atherogenic and the thrombogenic potential of VLDL in HTG.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cr50c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vc61p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77sr22z"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of cell-cell and cell-substrate adhesion in lymphatic metastasis : studies in a breast carcinoma model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Djoneidi Djafari, Maziar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to study the role of cellular adhesion in the process of lymphatic metastasis, in vitro models were developed from isolated components of the lymphatic system. Cultures of rat lymphatic endothelial cells and of rat lymph node stromal cells were obtained. The endothelial cells expressed von Willebrand factor (vWF) and angiotensin converting enzyme (ACE), and took up acetylated-low density lipoprotein (Ac-LDL). The stromal cells were composed mainly of Ac-LDL$(-),$ vWF$(-)$ cells which produced in vitro a reticular mesh of fibers, and expressed fibronectin, laminin and type IV collagen. The adhesion of tumor cells derived from two rat breast carcinoma lines of divergent metastatic potentials to the lymphatic cells and to extracellular matrix (ECM) proteins has been tested. The capacity for lymphatic metastasis was found to correlate with tumor cell adhesion to fibronectin, a major component of the lymph node ECM. Inhibition experiments showed that tumor cell adhesion to fibronectin was mediated by a $ beta sb1$ integrin(s). In contrast no correlation was found between tumor cell potential for lymphatic metastasis and tumor cell adhesion to the lymphatic cells. It is postulated that, in the present system, adhesion to fibronectin is one of the factors regulating tumor potential for lymph node metastasis.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sk693.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sr22z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w848b"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modular recognition and binding properties of human heat shock transcription factor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wagner, John, 1966-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A partially purified preparation of in vivo activated human heat shock transcription factor (HSF) has been obtained from HeLa cells and its interaction with the heat shock response element (HSE) in the human Hsp70 gene promoter was investigated. A variety of DNA-protein binding studies including DNAse I protection, hydroxyl radical protection, and diethylpyrocarbonate interference analysis were used to investigate recognition of the HSE by human HSF. Direct contacts to bases within the 5 basepair recognition motif were detected and the overall pattern of binding was compared with the Drosophila results. Analysis of the high resolution protection patterns to extended HSE mutants indicates that HSF binding coincides with the location of the additional element motifs. Moreover, examination of the protection patterns from these constructs indicate that a proposed model for HSF binding is consistent with a model depicting HSF as a trimer.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3333355.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w848b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Heat shock proteins</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82k8269"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spectral multiplicity theory in nonseparable Hilbert spaces : a survey</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Linder, Kevin A. (Kevin Andrew)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Spectral multiplicity theory solves the problem of unitary equivalence of normal operate on a Hilbert space ${ cal H}$ by associating with each normal operator N a multiplicity function, such that two operators are unitarily equivalent if and only if their multiplicity functions are equal. This problem was first solved in the classical case in which ${ cal H}$ is separable by Hellinger in 1907, and in the general case in which ${ cal H}$ is nonseparable by Wecken in 1939. This thesis develops the later versions of multiplicity theory in the nonseparable case given by Halmos and Brown, and gives the simplification of Brown's version to the classical theory. Then the versions of Halmos and Brown are shown directly to be equivalent. Also, the multiplicity function of Brown is expressed in terms of the multiplicity function of Halmos.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fx911.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k8269</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78td27z"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic analysis of the maternal factors controlling the survival of trisomy 16 mouse fetuses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Demczuk, Suzanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The BxH recombinant inbred strains of mice were used to undertake a genetic analysis of the maternal factors controlling the survival of trisomy 16 fetuses. The data presented indicate that the prevalence of trisomic fetuses on day 15 of gestation varies significantly with the genetic background of the mother. The strain difference in the frequency of trisomy appears to be the result of selective elimination of trisomic fetuses. Various statistical methods to elucidate the genetic architecture of the trait from the recombinant inbred strains data indicate that the number of loci involved in the selection process ranges from one to five. Linkage association with two loci have been found; however, with a low probability level (p = 0.292).</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j6738.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td27z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mice -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trisomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301242g"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Entomology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Field and laboratory trials in Mali to determine the effects of neem extracts on three millet pests, Heliocheilus albipunctella De Joannis (Lepidoptera: Noctuidae), Coniesta ignefusalis Hampson (Lepidoptera: Pyralidae) and Kraussaria angulifera Krauss (Orthoptera: Acrididae)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Passerini, Julien</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Formulations of aqueous neem extracts were sprayed in field experiments. Results showed that a 0.5% and 1% concentrations were effective in reducing grasshopper feeding and diminishing damage caused by the millet stemborer, C. ignefusalis. In 1988, neem diminished egg-laying and mine damage by the headminer, H. albipunctella, but no data were available for 1989 because of the low infestation levels of this pest. Neem exhibited some systemic activity. Soil applied neem kernel powder partially protected millet against K. angulifera and C. ignefusalis. Neem treated plots yielded more grain and suffered less damage by insect pests than four different cultural practices. Only the addition of fertilizer was superior to neem in reducing yield losses but it was inferior in limiting pest losses. Experiments to test the residual activity of neem showed that this botanical insecticide can effectively protect millet against K. angulifera for at least seven days, and possibly longer if ultra-violet rays and rainfall are not prevalent. Analysis of plant selection behavior of K. angulifera showed that neem is an antifeedant rather than a repellent. On first to third instar nymphs, growth regulating activity expressed as a difficulty in molting or an absence of sclerotization may occur. Topical applications of neem to the stemborer, C. ignefusalis, also caused growth abnormalities, mostly molting disturbances. Treated larvae that reached the adult stage were malformed. This research indicates that neem based insecticides offer considerable promise for Sahelian farmers for protecting millet crops. It is effective against K. angulifera, but less effective against the stemborer, C. ignefusalis. Although the data obtained for H. albipunctella in 1988 was promising, it was insufficient to reach any conclusions regarding neem's efficacy with respect to this pest.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k828v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301242g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Millets -- Diseases and pests -- Biological control -- Mali</dc:subject><dc:subject>Noctuidae -- Biological control -- Mali</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grasshoppers -- Biological control -- Mali</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pyralidae -- Biological control -- Mali</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neem</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af4752h822"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of retort performance and influence of entrapped air on heat transfer into flexibly packaged simulated foods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Campbell, Stuart N. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The performance of a new horizontal retort (Steriflow Standard 1-Basket Model, Barriquand, Paris, France) was evaluated on the basis of temperature, heat and lethality distribution. Time-temperature data for these studies were obtained from bare thermocouples (type T), and rectangular bricks fabricated from Teflon$ sp{ rm TM}$ and Lexan$ sp{ rm TM}$ with thermocouples positioned at their geometrical centres. The effect of entrapped air on processing parameters for bricks packaged in retort pouches was determined using silicone rubber bricks (10 x 14.5 x 2 cm), containing 5 thermocouples with their junctions positioned from the geometrical centre to near the top surface. The processing media employed were steam/air at two temperatures (121.1$ sp circ$C and 115.6$ sp circ$C) and two levels of superimposed air over-pressure, corresponding to 65% and 75% steam content. With the exception of the highest level of over-pressure (116 kPa), 60 ml of entrapped air caused the heating rate index (f$ sb{ rm h}$) to double. At low levels of air over-pressures, the slowest heating region (often assumed to be the geometrical centre) in the brick was shifted to a height equivalent to 3/4 of the brick thickness from the centre when the entrapped air volume was 60 ml. For similar conditions, the location receiving the least combined lethality during heating and cooling was near the top surface of the brick.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v6594.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752h822</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food -- Preservation -- Testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Retort pouches -- Testing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354g45w"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Tilt-evoked responses in persons with idiopathic Parkinson's disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Peruzzi, Anna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objective of the present thesis was to conduct a comparative study between persons with idiopathic Parkinson's disease and similarly aged normal subjects, by examining their lower limb reflex responses to forward whole head-body tilts under different sensory conditions. Tilts were applied with subjects (10 parkinsonian and 10 control) in standing, via a tilting apparatus through an axis collinear with the ankle joints. Vestibular input was manipulated by changing the acceleration of the tilt, visual input by the use or removal of a blindfold, and somatosensory input by the use of a compliant versus a firm support surface. We found a consistently lower number of respondents in parkinsonian subjects under all the tilting conditions. These patients also demonstrated a higher proportion of absent or abnormal tilt-evoked responses, while exhibiting a significantly greater resting EMG activity in proximal limb muscles. The most significant difference lies in the number of respondents between the two subject groups during the "eyes closed-compliant surface" tilting condition. The basal ganglia play a particular role in the weighing of appropriate versus inappropriate sensory inputs, in order to modify balance responses according to changes in environmental conditions.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c882.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354g45w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225c15d"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Renewable Resources</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of potassium, magnesium, and sulfur fertilization on corn grain and silage yields in a high nutrient soil</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Badra, Abdo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effects of added potassium, K, magnesium, Mg and sulfur, S on corn grain and silage yields were investigated in the field for two years. Due to high nutrient soil, K, Mg and S had no effects on corn grain and silage yields. However, there were trends observed in the treatment effects that were significant. Added K at 240 kg K$ sb2$O/ha increased grain yield over zero kg K$ sb2$O/ha in 1983 and Mg at 60 kg/ha increased grain yield over 30 kg/ha in 1984. In silage, 240 kg K$ sb2$O/ha increased yield over 120 and zero kg K$ sb2$O/ha in 1984. Although there was no K by Mg interaction, there was a need for added Mg to achieve higher yields. The cumulative effect of fertilizer S at 50 kg/ha significantly reduced silage yield in 1984 over zero S treatment indicating that fertilizer S was unnecessary for corn growth by reason of high levels of soil S and sufficient S provided from precipitation and air dry deposition. S had no interaction with K and Mg because there was no need for fertilizer S to increase yields. The antagonistic association between K and Mg was seen at the seedling, tasseling and silking stages. There was an indication of a K by S interaction which was expressed at different stages of growth, but this effect was not evident for dry matter yields.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns208.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225c15d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Corn -- Yields</dc:subject><dc:subject>Magnesium fertilizers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Fertilizers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Silage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Ontario</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sulphur fertilizers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Potassium fertilizers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859g836"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of murine aneuploidy at the blastocyst stage</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jacob, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In humans, the overall birth frequency of trisomy 21 (Downs syndrome) is 1 per 700 livebirths. The incidence at conception is greater, but more than 80% will not reach term (Connor and Ferguson-Smith 1985). Presumably, numerous factors, genetic and environmental are influencing this process. Therefore, an analysis of the factors modulating the survival of murine aneuploid embryos has been initiated. A maternal genetic control modulating the survival of murine trisomic embryos has been observed at day 15 of gestation (Vekemans and Trasler 1987; Epstein and Vekemans 1990). To determine whether this modulation is taking place, before or after implantation, the analysis of aneuploid blastocysts has been started. The frequency of aneuploidy observed at the blastocyst stage has been found not to differ when the maternal genotype varied for both murine chromosomes 19 and 16. Therefore, we can conclude that the maternal genetic control modulating the survival of trisomic embryos at day 15 of gestation is not in effect at the preimplantation stage. Also we observed that genetic factors are modifying the blastocyst development (e.i. the cavitation process).</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cx60t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859g836</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pp06p"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Automated fault diagnosis and empirical validation of fault models in CMOS VLSI circuits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pancholy, Ashish</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The selection of adequate fault models is crucial to generating tests of high quality for complex digital VLSI circuits. This thesis presents a methodology to perform empirical validation of fault models and to get measures of effectiveness of test sets based on the targeted fault models. The methodology is based on the automated fault diagnosis of test circuits, representative of the class of circuits being studied and designed to capture the characteristics of the fabrication process, cell libraries and CAD tools used in their development. The methodology is applied to study the faulty behaviour of random logic environments for an experimental VLSI fabrication process. A test circuit is designed, using CMOS technology, and a statistically significant number of samples fabricated. The samples are tested and, subsequently, diagnosed, using a set of software tools developed for the purpose. Results of the ensuing analysis are presented.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107018h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp06p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>