<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860b41q"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics and Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Bolshevik theory of national self-determination and its practice in Soviet central Asia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Webb, David. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Soviet Union is truly a meeting ground of nationalities; the 1959 census returns list no less than 112 separate races, nationalities and tribes, speaking as many different languages. No other country in the world has such a diversity and mixture of peoples within its borders; consequently, no other country has been faced with such a minority or nationalities problem. The attitude of the Bolsheviks, rulers of the Soviet Union, toward these nationalities, forms the subject matter of this enquiry; in order to understand the factors affecting their attitude, it is first necessary to examine, albeit imperfectly, the Tsarist nationality policy in the Russias, the writings of Marx and Engels upon nationalism, and the view of the Austrian Social-Democrats and Jewish Bundists - for these were the legacies inherited by the Bolsheviks, the first practical, the others theoretical.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brecher, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fs35p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860b41q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics and Political Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A44558h74w"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The spallation of bismuth by 90-MeV. protons</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Washington, Robert. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The reaction cross-section has been measured for Bi209 irradiated with 90+/-2 Mev. protons. Isotopes of Bi, Pb, Tl, and Au were separated chemically, and identified by their half-lives and gamma-ray spectra. The measured cross sections were compared with the theoretical values calculated from Serber's theory, and were found to be in agreement within the experimental error of 30% to 50%. At the proton energy used, it was found that the predominant reaction was Bi209 (p,pxn) where x = 1, 2, 3, etc. up to ca. 8. Emission of more than one proton was less likely by a factor of ca. 10, and yields of Tl and Au isotopes were very small.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yaffe, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kx44z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558h74w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xn19n"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of German</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Robert Musil’s art of characterization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Waseem, Gertrud</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During his lifetime he was not widely recognized as a writer. His work never appealed to the public at large, and in his later years the cultural policy of the Third Reich reduced the circulation of his writings even further. Only years after his death his qualities as a writer were discovered. A brief examination of his life may shed sane light on his present position in the literary world. Musil grew up in a wealthy home and was educated according to a traditional pattern by which difficult children were sent to military academies. Musil, deciding against a military career, studied engineering and later philosophy and psychology, specializing in logic and experimental psychology.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reiss, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f7216.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xn19n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>German</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azw12z879s"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis and secretion of pancreatic enzymes as shown by radioautography using tritiated amino acids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Warshawsky, Hershey</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The philosophical question of constancy and change, as applied to the proteins of the animal body, has been a subject of controversy for over half a century. The experiments of Folin (1905 a) on the effect of the protein level of the diet on the composition of urine marked the beginning of modern concepts of protein metabolism. On the basis of his experiment, Folin (1905 b) assumed that protein catabolism is not all of one kind, but could proceed via two pathways which are essentially independent and different. One pathway of catabolism is variable in quantity of end products, while the other process is constant.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leblond, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z632.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z879s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10wv097"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of steroids produced by the rat adrenal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ward, Pamela. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the major steroids secreted by the rat adrenal has been shown to be the 2018 hemiketal of 18-nydroxy-11-desoxycorticosterone. This compound gives a positive Porter-Silber reaction but does not reduce tetrazolium. Its identification presents the first proof for the existence of a 21-hydroxylated steroid With a 20~18 hemiketal linkage as a natura11y occurring product. The compound appears to possess mineralocorticoid activity comparable to that of 11-desoxycorticosterone but no glucocorticoid activity. Its production by isolated rat adrenals is increased 10-fold by incubation with ACTH. Addition of 11-desoxycorticosterone produces a similar increase in the absence of ACTH.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Birmingham, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r472b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wv097</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z4523"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Timing of DNA duplication in the gut epithelia of the rat by radioautography after thymidine-H3 injection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Warburton, Frederick. E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis reports an attempt to measure the duration of the period during which cells duplicate their nuclear complement of deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) in preparation for mitosis, in the epithelia of the tongue, oesophagus, and intestine of the rat. Information was also sought on the duration of other stages in the cell cycle, and on the renewal time of the entire cell population of these epithelia. The nucleoside thymidine, labelled with tritium (H3), was used as a DNA precursor, and labelled nuclei were detected by radioautography.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leblond, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr62p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z4523</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akk91fq51w"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors in the aetiology of spontaneous abortion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Warburton, Dorothy. P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Spontaneous abortion in man is a subject important to workers in many biological fields -- to the obstetrician who must deal not only with the event itself, but also with its psychological and social aspects; to the demographer who should take account of it in his analyses of population structure and change; to the investigator of reproductive physiology who attempts to find the cause of what is one of the most frequent abnormalities of pregnancy; to the geneticist who tries to assess the role of heredity in the production of such abnormalities; and to the biometrician who is required to find techniques capable of dealing with the statistics of abortion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fraser, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zs06q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fq51w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6q182p75d"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Shakespeare’s use of the Machiavellian stereotype</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wallace, Donald. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The villains of Shakespeare are the most vivid and original in English drama, yet they are not entirely products of his imagination. With this sort of character, as with his plots and other characters, Shakespeare worked within viable dramatic traditions which were strong enough to provide a base and an inspiration for his genius, yet not so rigid as to limit it. One of the strongest of these traditions was that of the Machiavel. The works of Machiavelli were readily available to the Elizabethans. Although the ‘Discourses’ was not published in English translation until 1636 and ‘The Prince’ until 1640, at least four different manuscript translations of the ‘Discourses’ and three of ‘The Prince’ were made in the Elizabethan period.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Walker, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wh17h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182p75d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dt05k"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A synoptic climatology for British Columbia: some effects of mountainous terrain on observed weather</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Walker, Edward. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The problem was to explain effects of mountain terrain, the Canadian Cordillera, on distributions of precipitation and temperature. Techniques from several fields of meteorology were blended with modern data processing in an attempt to overcome the sparseness and non-representativeness of weather observations. Atmospheric characteristics over British Columbia were found to be sharply differentiated by the direction of the flow at the 700 millibar level. Linearized two-dimensional mountain airflow theory was combined with relevant atmospheric characteristics to derive simple models of precipitation distributions over mountain ranges. These models were used to supplement observations to obtain improved charts of precipitation over the southern half of British Columbia. Altitudinal variation, and other characteristics of the distributions of precipitation and temperature not hitherto available were elucidated. The relationships obtained between atmospheric characteristics and observed weather suggest that it may be practicable and economical to observe the climate of sparsely settled mountainous areas using relatively few weather stations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hare, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945v475.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dt05k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Meteorology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77st612"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Economic structure and some probable effects of the European economic community</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vulkovic, Nicola</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Western Europe has made a great step towards integration. The shape is not yet definite, as the presense of two blocs, EEC and EFTA, proves. Less than thirty years ago integration was beyond the horizon. The problem was not of economic order. "… we are so divided politically, burdened with a malicious heredity from our past that the realization of a single market on a continental level, will remain, for a long time to come, an Utopia." 1/ "All far-reaching schemas for a Customs Union to embrace all or most of the European States are quite Utopian and fantastic. They are completely ruled out by the spirit of Nationalism and protection which prevails today." 2/.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wright, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pr44h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77st612</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82kc02b"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pharmacological studies on the experimental assessment of functional changes in the coronary circulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Varma, Daya. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Coronary insufficiency occurs when there is a disproportion between the oxygen needs of the heart and the oxygen supply to the heart. It can therefore be produced either (a) by decreasing the available oxygen supply to the heart, (b) by increasing the work of the heart, or (c) by a combination of both changes. The diagnosis of angina pectoris or coronary insufficiency can often easily be made in the presence of a typical clinical history and characteristic electrocardiographic changes. In many instances, however, the appraisal of substernal and precordial pain may be extremely difficult.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Melville, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n697k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82kc02b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq524js45p"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The economics of forage production and utilization in the province of Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Van de Wetering, Hylke</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>At any time a farm-firm has at its disposal given quantities of various factors of production. This study is concerned with investigating a procedure which will generally lead to that combination of production factors which is both feasible and most renumerative. Any theory of the firm has much the same objectives but sufficient differences in assumptions exist to make a general theory which would include all others an expository tool excelling in completeness rather than lucidity. The subject areas of difference deal with the nature of the objective functional to be maximized, the differentibility of production relationships; the stochastic nature of production relationships and the imperfection of both input and output markets.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Haver, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bn013.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524js45p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pf249"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Carotenoid content of tomato fruits as influenced by season and variety</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Van Loon, John. B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Colour is one of the most important single quality attributes of tomatoes for processing. The character of the red colour affects the appearance and public acceptance of the finished products. The colour of the raw product is related to that of the finished product and processing conditions cannot usually improve on it. The production cost of a high grade juice or paste does not differ significantly from that of a lower grade juice (Filice and Malcolm, 1958). Both the commercial grower and the processor need an insight into the mechanism of the colour formation, the former as an aid in selecting the best suitable varieties for his particular climatic region, and the latter to evaluate the influence of processing on the colour of his final product.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anastassiadis, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462888c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pf249</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Horticulture</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53x0438"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Behaviour of embryonic lung tissue grown in the presence of silica, carbon and carborundum dusts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Van Ermengen, Marina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The closest relative of carbon in the Periodic Table, silicon or silicium is named from one of the common minerals within which it occurs, namely flint, which in Latin was called "silex". After oxygen, silicon is the most abundant element in the earth's crust. Because of its great affinity for oxygen, it occurs exclusively as the oxide, namely silicon dioxide (silica) or quartz and as the hydrated oxide, silicic acid in the form of the salts of various metals. Silica may occur in the free state or mixed with other minerals in siliceous rocks notably in granites. Being one of the hardest components, silica is not as liable to disintegrative action of winds and rains as are the other components of granites.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denstedt, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cp508.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x0438</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613n2121"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The formation of estrogens by liver tissue in vitro</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Usher, David. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The capacity of both the human liver and hepatic tissue from various animal species to synthesize, interconvert and destroy many, if not all, of the large number of estrogens now known to exist, has been amply demonstrated by numerous workers. Techniques have so changed and improved in the past decade that it is now possible to have definitive and quantitative concepts about the different reaction sequences. It is fully realized that these same advances present grave difficulties (such as the determination of radiochemical purity) which will be discussed later in this work.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hobkirk, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dz89k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n2121</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Investigative Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw95054053"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The reaction of oxygen atoms with carbon tetrachloride</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ung, Alban. Y-M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The subject of oxygen atoms has a long history dating back to Becquerel. In 1859, he described a ‘long-lived luminous species’ produced when an electric current was passed through oxygen. In 1891, during an investigation of electrical discharges through various gases at low pressures, Thomson observed a luminous glow in oxygen which persisted ‘some considerable time’ after the electrical discharge had been interrupted. This glow was subsequently called the ‘oxygen afterglow’, but is now generally referred to as ‘air afterglow’. In the years between 1859 and 1900, a large number of investigators round a variety of afterglows from discharged air of unknown purity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Schiff, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hp01n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95054053</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301500k"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Man and the North Shore: a study in environmental response</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tyman, John. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Like Mackinder, “I propose to define geography as the science whose main function is to trace the interaction of man in society and so much of his environment as varies locally.” (13:143) To write a 'human geography' of any area as it exists to-day, is inevitably to attempt an appraisal of its potentialities for human development. This is no less true of studies descriptive of times past. And the student who presents a series of such pictures is, perforce, brought face to face with the fact that estimates of worth do change quite radically with the passage of the centuries. Obviously the environment itself does change in its superficial forms. Also, men choose, mould, develop and modify various aspects of the framework of their surroundings.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lloyd, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq525.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301500k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak930c1866"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Bachelor of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Elastic and strength properties of Elliot Lake quartzites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tun, Hla</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An understanding of the behaviour of rocks subjected to stress is of great importance in engineering practice. Many large engineering projects utilise rock materials either directly, as part of the structure, or indirectly, as the foundation upon which the structure ,or indirectly, as a function upon which the structure will rest. [...] Amongst others the United States Bureau of Mines (2) (3) (4) and Association of Mine Managers in South Africa (5) have published data relating to the physical properties of quartzites. Some of these data are included for comparative purposes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Morrison, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wv100.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c1866</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mining engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9c67wr41x"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Glacial geomorphology in the Kaumajet mountain and Okak Bay areas of North Eastern Labrador</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tomlinson, Roger. F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Arguments concerning the nature and extent of the North American glaciation as a whole, and that of Labrador in particular, have been regularly appearing in print from 1883 until 1959. From the theories and reports presented it is possible to draw together several distinct lines of thought. Early work by Bell (1882-84), Daly (1902), and Coleman (1921) suggested that the higher parts of the eastern edge of north east America had not been covered by continental ice. Coleman goes as far as to say that in the Nachvak area, “the unglaciated condition is known to reach at least 50 miles inland, giving a driftless area of perhaps 3,000 or 4,000 square miles”, though he concedes that valley glaciers must have reached the sea in areas to the south of Nachvak.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021j72q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wr41x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sk879"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The initial stages of annealing of high purity aluminum</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tiivel, Mati</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Metals have been produced, worked and used since prehistoric times. For thousands of years however, most of the knowledge relating to metals was acquired by chance and the experience gained was passed from man to man through the centuries. Thus, many important processes such as forging and annealing, were carried out for centuries without anyone realizing what structural changes were actually taking place. In fact no attempt to explain the changes that occur during annealing was made until 1881. In that year Kalisher observed that heating caused changes in the "molecular structure" of cold worked zinc.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Williams, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt97x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sk879</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Metallurgical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw6634718x"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of the reduction of iron oxides in particulate systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Themelis, Nickolas. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The reduction of iron oxides has been investigated extensively, mainly by virtue of its industrial significance. Nevertheless, despite the large amount of experimental evidence, there has been as yet no agreement as to the mechanism of the reaction, nor has a generalized correlation for the reaction rate been suggested. As a matter of fact, many workers appear to assume that the complexity of the system makes the formulation of such a correlation impossible. One of the main objects of this study has been to attempt an analysis of the mechanism of the reduction, from which a correlation could be derived. To this end, a thorough search of the relevant literature was conducted and the results are presented in the form of a critical review in the first section of this Thesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gauvin, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z453c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634718x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859k25x"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic analysis of some radiation effects in diploid Aspergillus nidulans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tector, Margaret. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The experiments to be described in this thesis were undertaken to obtain stocks of the fungus Aspergillus nidulans containing translocations between various pairs of linkage groups. The translocations were identified genetically, in gamma-irradiated diploid colonies. The chromosomes in this fungus are very small, but some can be identified individually (Elliott, 1960). The stocks characterized here will be used later in an attempt to associate each chromosome with the appropriate linkage group. The method used located not only translocations, but recessive lethals and some point mutants as well.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kafer-Boothroyd, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zm387.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859k25x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fs36z"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Backwardness in reading and brain dysfunction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Taylor, Laughlin. B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In an attempt to establish brain dysfunction as a factor underlying backwardness of reading, an electroencephalogram and several psychological tests were administered to a group of poor readers and normal controls. Although there were no significant differences in the EEG patterns between the two groups, there was a developmental trend suggesting that the poor readers had more posterior slow wave activity at a later age than did the normal controls. For both groups a relationship was also found between IQ ratings and the aide of the brain showing the most posterior slow waves. Two types of poor readers were identified.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rabinovitch, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jf787.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fs36z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s6103"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The importance of the Portuguese East African port of Delagoa Bay in the struggle for supremacy in South Africa 1880-1900</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sylvain, Gerard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Portugal’s interests in the East African coast date from the days of Portuguese ascendancy in the far eastern trade, but for 300 years very little was done to develop these African territories. in the latter half of the 19th century Lisbon gave a 50-year concession to the mozambique company which do not expire until 1941, thus about one-sixth of the whole area, that portion between the Zambesi and latitude 22 south, was governed and administered by this company, the remainder of the territory was administered by the government of Portugal and was known as the Mozambique colony.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>FieldHouse, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c419n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s6103</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q9852"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comparison between the sonic and static elastic moduli of rocks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sutherland, Robert. B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mining is one of the oldest industries, but it is only during the last 50 years that operations have been carried to depths where problems of temperature and ground pressure require special study. Temperature problems can be solved by increasing the now of ventilating air and or conditioning the air by refrigeration. Controls of this nature are limited only by economic factors. Pressure-increases with depth, however, present a far more complicated and difficult problem. The stress distribution can only be postulated since measurement of stresses in rock in situ is at present only in the initial stages of development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Morrison, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk90w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q9852</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mining Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>