<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gj421"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Oral spirochetes : contribution to oral malodor and formation of spherical bodies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>De Ciccio, Angela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Spirochetes are putative periodontal pathogens because they are found in increased numbers in periodontitis. With severity of periodontal disease, there also appears to be an increase in oral malodor. This is due to a greater breakdown of tissues containing sulfurated amino acids such as cysteine, cystine, and methionine. Bacteria in the oral cavity can metabolize these amino acids to produce volatile sulfur compounds such as hydrogen sulfide and methyl mercaptan that contribute to oral malodor. Detection of volatile sulfur compounds is usually performed by gas chromatography or a portable sulfur monitor, but none of these methods provides direct evidence for the production of hydrogen sulfide from oral spirochetes. A successful method has been developed, as described in this thesis, to demonstrate that oral spirochetes are major contributors to oral malodor associated with periodontitis. This has been accomplished by modification of an established method for isolating these bacteria directly from subgingival plaques. A morphological variation of spirochetes, called a spherical body, exists. It has been postulated that this may be a dormant form of spirochetes used as a survival strategy. A number of environmental conditions were tested to determine whether or not they could contribute to spherical body formation in the oral spirochete Treponema denticola ATCC 35405. Cells grown in the absence of rabbit serum, volatile fatty acids, thiamine pyrophosphate, or yeast extract showed a dramatic increase in the numbers of spherical bodies. T. denticola cells grown in the presence of the metabolic end-product lactic acid or at pH 7.42 instead of 6.8 also contained more spherical bodies than the control.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chan, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r973j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gj421</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqz20sv83r"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Watershed master planning for St. Lucia using geographic information systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cox, Christopher, 1967-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A method for estimating long-term average annual soil loss under different land management scenarios from the Marquis and Soufriere watersheds on St. Lucia is presented. The Revised Universal Soil Loss Equation (RUSLE) was used, and a GIS was employed to generate the required input parameters. Model execution and results were also generated within the GIS. Modelling soil loss for the different land management scenarios was based upon a land capability classification and associated conservation treatments. Soil losses under current agricultural land-use patterns were analyzed and compared to potential soil losses under conservation treatments following the criteria specified in the land capability classification. The model predicted substantial declines in soil loss where conservation treatments were assigned, as compared to soil loss under current land-use patterns. It was found that predicted soil losses from the Soufriere watershed were four times that predicted for the Marquis watershed for all the land management scenarios modelled. Of the input parameters in the model, slope steepness was most highly correlated to predicted soil loss. It is anticipated that the findings of this study will be used in the development of a decision support system for agricultural and forestry land planning on St. Lucia.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db957.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sv83r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Universal soil loss equation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geographic information systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>Watershed management -- Saint Lucia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil erosion prediction -- Saint Lucia -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gv60r"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Disruption of a putative calcium channel gene in Saccharomyces cerevisiae</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cho, John Myung-Jae</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A search of the Saccharomyces genome data base revealed an open reading frame of 2039 amino acids with homology to L-type calcium channels. Northern blots probed with a 540 bp PCR product of the ORF showed a transcript of 6.1 kb. Two procedures were used to disrupt the gene: the ORF was truncated by an integrative disruption after the third pore motif, or deleted in the first three pore domains using a one-step disruption construct. In most strains tested, the disruptions gave no apparent phenotype when tested under a variety of conditions. However, conspicuous phenotypes were seen in the strain YEL161-2A, a strain super-sensitive to alpha-mating factor (sst1). In most respects, truncation gave a less severe phenotype than deletion, suggesting that the truncated gene retains partial function. Calcium uptake during normal growth, as well as the increased calcium uptake in response to mating factor, were reduced progressively by the truncation and deletion respectively. Growth rate and cell viability were reduced, cell size heterogeneity increased, and recovery from mating factor arrest was delayed and abnormal. The cells became sensitive to MnCl$ sb2.$ The phenotype resulting from gene truncation was alleviated by a high-calcium medium, and exacerbated by low calcium. Complementation of the deleted strain by a Yep13 plasmid containing BAR1 (SST1) restored normal growth and viability. However, somewhat paradoxically, deletion of the putative calcium channel gene in another sst1 strain (SY1159) showed no phenotype.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Poole, Ronald J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602284k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv60r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Calcium channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Cytology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acr56n3179"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of a renin binding site in the human placenta</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chiu, Sui Mei Linda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Renin is an aspartyl protease that plays a critical role in the production of angiotensin peptides and therefore in the modulation of blood pressure. Renin participates not only in the circulating renin-angiotensin system (RAS) but may also be taken up by tissues to control the activity of the local RAS. In this study, we provide evidence for the existence of a high affinity, saturable binding site for human renin (estimated k$ sb{ rm d}$ of 125 pM) and prorenin, the inactive precursor of renin, in the human placenta. The interesting finding that prorenin could bind to the same site as renin suggests that its role in vivo may be to act as a natural antagonist that would limit the local levels of angiotensin II production. It is of further interest to identify the protein regions important in this uptake; here we show that the degree of glycosylation in prorenin and the active site of renin are not essential in this process. In the near future, experiments will involve in-depth studies of the regions implicated in the binding process and long term goals will be to identify and characterize this novel renin and prorenin binding site.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reudelhuber, Timothy L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd104.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n3179</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av979v4954"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Diffusion channel system for controlled atmosphere storage of spinach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chimphango, Annie F. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Advanced research in Controlled/Modified Atmosphere storage systems has shown that open channels of different lengths and cross sectional areas, connected to an air tight storage chamber, are able to maintain variable stable gas concentrations which could be near optimal concentrations for CA/MA storage of various commodities. This study was geared towards assessing the suitability of the diffusion channels in maintaining a desired gas concentration for CA storage of spinach. Initially, the respiratory behaviour of spinach was studied in gas sealed chambers (replicated four times) stored at four different temperatures, 2$ sp circ$C, 8$ sp circ$C, 15$ sp circ$C and 23$ sp circ$C. The respiration rate of spinach was 20 mgCO$ sb2$/kg.h, 66 mgCO$ sb2$/kg.h, 163 mgCO$ sb2$/kg.h and 271 mgCO$ sb2$/kg.h for 2$ sp circ$C, 8$ sp circ$C, 15$ sp circ$C and 23$ sp circ$C, respectively. A model was developed based on principles of enzymatic kinetics which could reliably predict the respiration rate of spinach at any given storage temperature. Two other sets of experiments were carried in a cold room set at 2$ sp circ$C. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roghavan, G. S. V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k0050.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v4954</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Spinach -- Postharvest technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spinach -- Storage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Protective atmospheres</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811km625"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Feasibiliy studies for laser spectroscopy of thorium ions in a Paul trap</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cheng, Hongmei</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis evaluates the suitability of Thorium(Th) ions for optical spectroscopic measurements in a Paul trap. A $ sp{232}Th$ sample, placed near the ring electrode, is evaporated with a Nd:YAG laser pulse and then selectively ionized by a synchronized dye laser pulse. Ions created inside the trap follow stable orbits and are cooled by hydrogen buffer gas. The stability and trapping efficiency for the ions are examined at various trap operating conditions. The motion of the ions in the trap is studied with particular attention to volume occupied by the ions in the phase space. With the trap operating at optimum conditions for stability and spectral resolution, laser-induced fluorescence measurements at selected rf phase angles are applied to five optical transitions of Th ions. Results indicate that two transitions are most suitable for spectroscopic studies and 60-80 ions are required to produce a spectrum with signal-to-background ratio of 1:1.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lee, Jonathan K. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9675749.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km625</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Nuclear</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811km63f"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Neutrophil-endothelium interactions in patients with systemic inflammatory response syndrome</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Xu-wu, 1955-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Multiple Organ Dysfunction Syndrome (MODS) is associated with high mortality in patients admitted to the surgical intensive care unit (SICU). MODS begins with a systemic response described as Systemic Inflammatory Response Syndrome (SIRS). Studies on SIRS patients may provide an insight into the mechanisms by which SIRS progresses to MODS. In this thesis, the interactions between circulating polymorphonuclear neutrophils (PMNs) from patients with SIRS and endothelial cells (ECs) from human umbilical veins were measured in order to elucidate the mechanism for PMN adhesion and subsequent cytotoxicity of the ECs. PMNs from patients with SIRS were compared to PMNs from pre-operative surgical patients without SIRS and with healthy control subjects, in vitro. The results showed that PMNs adherence to ECs increased progressively from healthy controls to patients with SIRS. PMN-HUVE cytotoxicity, however, did not show this trend. PMNs from SIRS patients treated with lipopolysaccharide, unlike PMNs from patients without SIRS or healthy controls, showed no increase in PMN-EC adhesion. The results also showed that EC activation with TNF-$ alpha$ and Il-1$ beta$ led to high levels of PMN-EC adhesion and cytotoxicity, whereas PMN treatment with lipopolysaccharide played a lesser role. Autologous plasma provided significant protection from PMN mediated EC damage. From this data I conclude that activation of the EC by cytokines associated with SIRS is far more important in promoting PMN-EC adhesion and subsequent cytotoxicity than PMN stimulation with lipopolysaccharide and that there are host factors in plasma that modulate this response.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Christou, N. V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm28t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km63f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207tr308"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Metabolic and oceanographic consequences of iron deficiency in heterotrophic marine protozoa</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chase, Zanna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Iron is recognized as a key element regulating primary production in large regions of the ocean, but nothing is known of its direct effect on higher trophic levels. Growth and metabolism of two species of heterotrophic protozoans fed iron-rich and iron-poor prey were thus examined. Maximum growth rates of Paraphysomonas imperforata and P. butcheri were observed only when Fe quotas of bacterial prey were greater than 70 $ mu$mol Fe:mol C. At lower Fe:C ratios, but at constant prey biomass (C/ml), both species grew significantly slower. Minimum Fe quotas of the flagellates at these slow growth rates ($ sim$10 $ mu$mol Fe:mol C) were similar to those of iron-limited phytoplankton and bacteria. Growth rate reduction was the result of direct elemental limitation by Fe, judging from the protozoans' positive response to Fe additions and from their biochemical characteristics. Filtration and carbon ingestion rates increased under Fe-limitation, but carbon gross growth efficiency (CGGE) decreased when Paraphysomonas imperforata consumed iron-poor bacteria. Ammonium regeneration efficiency was also reduced. The decrease in CGGE was a consequence of reduced activity of the iron-dependent electron transport system, greater DOC excretion, and greater CO$ sb2$ evolution by Fe-limited flagellates. Paraphysomonas imperforata excreted Fe, even when limited by this element, and retained less of the ingested ration and thus had a higher Fe regeneration efficiency than when consuming Fe-rich bacteria. According to recent measurements of biogenic Fe:C in the subarctic Pacific, our results suggest that heterotrophic bacterivorous flagellates may experience iron-limitation in remote oceanic regions. Such limitation could profoundly affect C, N and Fe cycling in the sea.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Price, Neil</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f94j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tr308</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Marine protozoa -- Growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iron -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Marine protozoa -- Effect of metals on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carbon cycle (Biogeochemistry)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Marine protozoa -- Metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692t8318"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of lesions to learning and memory systems on the morphine conditioned cue preference</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chai, Sin-Chee, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present thesis investigates the effects of lesions to several hypothesized learning and memory systems on the morphine conditioned cue preference on the radial maze. Lesions of the structures thought to be centered to learning systems: the lateral nucleus of amygdala, fornix/fimbria, anterior dorsal striatum and posterior dorsal striatum, were made, In Experiment One, each structure was lesioned separately. Only lesions of the lateral nucleus of amygdala blocked morphine CCP learning. In Experiment Two, rats with combined lesions of fornix/fimbria and dorsal striatum, the lateral nucleus of amygdala and fornix/fimbria, as well as the lateral nucleus of amygdala and dorsal striatum were all impaired on morphine CCP. All of the rats with combined lesions were impaired in this CCP learning. These findings suggest that the lateral nucleus of amygdala is necessary for the morphine CCP. Participation of dorsal striatum or fornix/fimbria is also required. Some hypotheses about the interactions among the structures are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>White, Norman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd79k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t8318</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Brain -- Localization of functions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Memory -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Conditioned response</dc:subject><dc:subject>Learning -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rats -- Behavior</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3r074x21m"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interactions between the retinoid signaling pathway and the signaling pathways of protein kinases A and C in the differentiation of embryonal carcinoma cell lines P19 and RAC65</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cetateanu, Nicolae Dragos</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Several studies have shown that the retinoic acid (RA)-activated signaling pathway can interact with both the PKA and the PKC signaling pathways. The aim of this project was to investigate the mechanism of such an interaction in the differentiation of P19 and RAC65 murine embryonal carcinoma cells. Two activators and two inhibitors of both PKA and PKC were used in differentiation experiments. Of these eight modulators, only the PKA activator dibutyryl cyclic adenosine monophosphate (dbcAMP) and the PKC inhibitor sphingosine were found to significantly potentiate the effect of RA in the neuronal cell differentiation of these cells. However, neither of these two modulators showed a significant modulatory effect on RA-mediated transactivation. Moreover, neither dbcAMP nor sphingosine modulated the RA-induced expression of a retinoid-responsive gene (RAR$ beta$). In conclusion, the signaling pathways of PKA and PKC appear to modulate RA-induced P19 and RAC65 neuronal differentiation. We postulate that this interaction involves the products of genes expressed in response to these signaling pathways.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leyland-Jones, Brian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dv12x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074x21m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hh60c"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intercropping of corn with soybean, lupin and forages for weed control and improved silage yield and quality in eastern Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carruthers, Kerry</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The intercropping of corn with legumes is an alternative cropping strategy to corn monocropping which may help reduce inputs into the production of silage for livestock feed. The reduction of inputs will decrease costs to producers and potential damage to the environment. Two experiments were carried out at each of two sites in 1993 and 1994. The first experiment investigated the effects on silage yield and weed control of seeding soybean or lupin alone or in combination with one of three forages (annual ryegrass, Lolium multiflorum Lam.; perennial ryegrass, Lolium perenne L.; and red clover, Trifolium pratense L.). The second experiment examined the effects on silage yield and weed control of seeding date (simultaneous with corn or three weeks later) and number of rows of large-seeded legumes (one or two) seeded between the corn rows. For both experiments intercropped plots received 90 kg ha$ sp{-1}$ less nitrogen fertilizer than monocropped plots (which received 180 kg ha$ sp{-1})$. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Smith, D. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f95t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh60c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Companion planting -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Weed control -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Weeds -- Biological control -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Yields -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n5254"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genomic organization and chromosomal mappling of the murine a1,2-mannosidase IB gene involved in N-glycan maturation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Campbell Dyke, Nathalie V.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>$ alpha$1,2-Mannosidases are a family of enzymes with similar amino acid sequences that are required for the formation of complex and hybrid asparagine-linked oligosaccharides in mammalian cells. We have determined the genomic structure of one member of this enzyme family, the murine $ alpha$1,2-mannosidase IB gene. Two BALB/c cosmid genomic clones (Cos.31.1 and Cos.25.1) and three overlapping 129/sv P1 genomic clones were isolated. Analysis of Cos.31.1 and the P1 clones showed that the $ alpha$1,2-mannosidase IB gene spans 180kb of the genome, and consists of 13 exons representing the complete open reading frame of the enzyme. Comparison of the intron/exon boundaries with those found in the partially characterized D. melanogaster mas-1 gene indicates that there is some conservation of $ alpha$1,2-mannosidase genomic structure between species. Fluorescence in situ hybridization with $ alpha$1,2-mannosidase UB genomic DNA (Cos.31.1) localized the gene to mouse chromosome 3F2. Sequence analysis of the Cos.25.1 cosmid clone provided evidence for the existence of another related gene or pseudogene. Fluorescence in situ hybridization with Cos.25.1 localized this sequence to mouse chromosome 4A13.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Herscovics, Annette</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g7012.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n5254</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429c27j"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamic load balancing on the earth-SP system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cai, Haïying</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The rapid progress of computer systems based on fine-grain multithreaded program execution models introduce both unique opportunities and challenges in the design and application of dynamic load balancing algorithms. This thesis presents a study of dynamic load balancing under the EARTH muitithreaded model. In this study, we have implemented a number of load balancing algorithms on the EARTH-SP testbed--a realization of EARTH model on the IBM-SP2 system. Our study has been carried out on both benchmark programs and a set of stress tests. The major results of this thesis include: (A) Demonstration that a load balancing algorithm is likely to be robust if it has the following features: (1) initiating load balancing requests by both the satiated and the hungry nodes; (2) making use of certain history information to guide balancing decisions. (B) Several specific observations and conclusions: (1) The performances of the load balancers vary under different computation models. This difference between load balancers becomes substantial under certain class of computation such as SPMD model. (2) When the parallelism grain size is small, the performance difference between load balancing algorithms becomes significant. This indicates the importance of searching good load balancers for efficient exploitation of fine-grain parallelism. (3) Some architecture parameters such as polling interval have a considerable impact on the effect of dynamic load balancing. (4) A load balancer with shorter communication path is likely to be scalable. (C) Suggestions for a number of aspects which should be considered in the exploitation of the design space for load balancing algorithms and their evaluations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gao, Guang R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gz09t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c27j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dx40x"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of biases on economic decision making : an experimental approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Buck, Elizabeth L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Neoclassical economics assumes that consumers have stable, well-defined preferences. However, only 16% of subjects selected a chocolate bar when given a choice between it and a coffee cup, while 43% kept a chocolate bar previously given to them when offered a trade for a coffee cup. Instructional wording had no effect. These results support the hypothesis that people value losses more than gains. Subjects were asked their willingness-to-pay (WTP) for twelve goods classified as either public or private, or as environmental or nonenvironmental. WTP tended to be lower for public goods when subjects previously ranked the personal importance or benefit they placed on the good. Importance was a weaker bias than benefit. Benefit appeared to induce free rider behaviour for public goods. The only environmental good affected by reading about sustainable development was one specifically mentioned in the article. Biases affecting WTP did not generally affect attributes correlated to WTP.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thomassin, Paul</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945s791.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx40x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Value</dc:subject><dc:subject>Consumer behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Public goods -- Valuation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economics -- Decision making</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asj1393997"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthetic studies on a(3,6)-mannans and a novel approach to the stereoselective construction of b-mannosides</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bubenik, Monica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Attempts were made to synthesize cleanly and efficiently a 3,6-branchpoint mannose monomer via three synthetic routes. This monomer was then to be used in a solution-phase synthesis of a high mannose-type nonasaccharide using a PEG soluble polymer support developed in our laboratory. The monomer was to meet the requirements of (1) stable protecting groups on positions 2 and 4; (2) easily cleavable groups on positions 3 and 6; (3) a group which is stable and a good donor on position 1. The key step in the synthesis of the first monomer, containing allyl groups on positions 3 and 6, involved using Ogawa's stannylation methodology. The key step in the second route involved benzylating a monomer containing two ester groups on positions 3 and 6 using Bundel's methodology. The third route, based on well established literature procedures, gave the desired compound in acceptable yield but with more purification effort. Using a similar approach to that taken independently by Stork and Hindsgaul, attempts were made to construct $ beta$-glycosides using antimony as a temporary connector. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chan, T.-H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408017t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1393997</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515q428"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nitrogen mineralization in boreal forest stands of northwestern Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brown, Susann Melissa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effect of species, parent material, and stand age on nitrogen mineralization were examined during aerobic lab and field incubations. The experimental design consisted of 3 tree species (birch (Betula papyrifera Marsh.); poplar (Populus tremuloides Michx.); and conifers (Abies balsamea (L.) Mill. and Picea glauca (Moench) Voss.)); two parent materials (lacustrine clay and glacial till); and three stand ages (50, 75, and 124 years of age). The strongest determinant of nitrogen mineralization potential was species. The effects of parent material and stand age were variable. Total nitrogen, pH, and soil moisture also affected N mineralization. Nitrogen mineralization dynamics may be largely affected by annual changes in quality of organic matter or climate. Available nitrogen inherent in forest stands must be taken into consideration when replacing hardwood stands with softwoods, because eliminating stages of boreal mixedwood succession could have detrimental effects on available nitrogen and forest productivity in the long-term.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fyles, James</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r0423.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q428</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Forest soils -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trees -- Effect of minerals on -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Taigas -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pj31h"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quantification of human tumor cell locomotory behavior in a three- dimensional collagen gel matrix</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boulos, Yola</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Conventional two-dimensional glass and plastic in vitro cell culture systems potentially lack an accurate representation of the in vivo reality of three-dimensional cell locomotory processes; an important loss of valuable information or even misinformation in understanding and interpreting underlying cell behavioral mechanisms could result. This thesis uses a dynamic quantification approach of human tumor cell locomotory behavior in a three-dimensional collagen gel matrix in conjunction with time-lapse videomicroscopy and computer digitization. This approach better approximates physiological in vivo cell behavior by allowing cell trajectory analysis and expression of phenotypic characteristics previously not observed in two-dimensional culture systems or end point measurements. The main objective of this thesis is to determine whether there are quantifiable differences between benign, malignant, and normal cell locomotory behavior that can be measured in a significant and useful manner. The second objective of this thesis is to determine whether quantifying cell locomotory behavior can potentially reveal the existence of functional subpopulations within a heterogeneous tumor population. Further study of such a three-dimensional system can expand our insight into the metastatic and invasive processes of cancer and potentially contribute in assessing neoplasm aggressiveness and even patient morbidity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Noble, P. B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s210h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj31h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50tt592"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The partitioning of mercury among the solid components of sediments of the Saguenay Fjord, Québec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bono, Andrew B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An estimated 60 tonnes of mercury, released from a chlor-alkali plant between 1947 and 1976, are buried in the sediments of the Saguenay Fjord. Despite rapid sedimentation rates, concentrations of Hg in surficial sediments remain well above preindustrial levels. The partitioning of Hg among sedimentary solids was investigated to elucidate the fate of buried mercury and determine the source of contamination in surficial sediments. Box cores from two stations along the axis of the Saguenay Fjord (SAG-6B, SAG-30B) and one from the Laurentian Trough (CL-1B) were collected in June, 1992. A sequential extraction protocol modified from existing techniques was tailored to evaluate the distribution of mercury among four operationally defined chemical fractions in Saguenay Fjord sediments: organic matter (C$ sb{ rm org}$), iron and manganese (hydr)oxides, acid-volatile-sulphides (AVS), and pyrite. This study provides new insight into the chemical pathways and fate of mercury within the Saguenay system, and contributes to a greater understanding of the geochemical behaviour of inorganic mercury in natural systems. Additionally, modifications made to the sequential extraction protocol may be applied and facilitate future studies of mercury partitioning in other systems. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mucci, Alfonso</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw58j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt592</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Environmental Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603r043c"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Potential chemical remediation of mercury in recently impounded reservoirs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boiridy, Mia Ingrid</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Several mitigation procedures have been proposed to limit the transfer of Hg and MeHg to aquatic organisms but most cannot be applied to large reservoirs such as those of northern Quebec for practical, economical, and environmental reasons. A better understanding of the diagenetic behaviour of Hg and methylmercury in aquatic environments has lead us to consider methods of enhancing natural processes which would either limit the mobility of Hg in flooded soils or its methylation. Different concentrations of iron oxide, iron shavings and ferrous ammonium sulphate were added to soil slurries in the presence or absence of calcite and gypsum. Mercury released to the supenatent solutions and methylmercury adsorbed to the slurry solids were monitored with time to determine the trapping efficiency of the different chemical additives under both reducing and oxygenated conditions. Whereas all three reagents limited the release of Hg(2+) to the supernatent solution when reducing conditions were allowed to develop in the slurries, ferrous ammonium sulphate appeared to be the most effective at limiting Hg methylation. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mucci, Alfonso</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0969197.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r043c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Environmental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514nn36n"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experimental study of Cd-citrate co-adsorption on corundum</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boily, Jean-François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An experimental investigation of metal-organic co-adsorption was conducted using cadmium and citrate in the presence of corundum. The experiments were performed in the pH range 3.0 to 10.0 in a 0.01M NaCl matrix with citrate:Cd ratios of 0.00 and 10.00. The presence of citrate enhances cadmium adsorption between pH 3.5 and 7.2, and reduces it above pH 7.2. The results from the experiments provide constraints on the thermodynamic properties of the surface complexes. The adsorption of Cd is quantified by the competition between aqueous CdCit$ sp{-1}$ and the surface species $&gt;$AlCitCd$ sp0$, $&gt;$AlOCd$ sp+$, and $&gt;$AlOCdCl$ sp0$. The experimentally determined equilibrium constants provide a means to predict Cd mobilities in groundwater systems by describing the relative stabilities of surface and aqueous metal-organic complexes as a function of metal-to-ligand and solute-to-sorbent ratios.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fein, Jeremy B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p51n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nn36n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4x51hm20f"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The development of a steadiness tester for the upper extremity in children of school age</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Birnbaum, Rena</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Currently there is no standardized assessment for the evaluation of upper extremity steadiness in children. The objective of this study was to obtain preliminary psychometric properties of a clinical tool to assess steadiness in the upper extremity in children aged six to ten years. One hundred twenty-two healthy children were recruited from regular schools. Children were instructed to hold a stylus in a steady position in a small circular opening for fifteen seconds, in supported and unsupported positions, using the dominant and non dominant hand. The number of times the stylus touched the metal grid was automatically recorded. Normative data were established and confounders such as age, gender and handedness were considered. Results of inter rater and test retest reliability analyses varied from fair to good. Thirteen children with postural tremor were similarly tested and scores of healthy subjects and children with tremor were compared. Scores effectively discriminated between the healthy and tremor groups. The steadiness tester may be a useful diagnostic tool for children with movement difficulties affecting fine motor control.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Majnemer, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731594k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hm20f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cc85m"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of some novel anticonvulsant drugs on the synchronous activity recorded in the presence of 4-aminopyridine in the rat hippocampus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Billinghurst, Lori L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite advances in understanding the pathogenesis of epilepsy, it remains a significant therapeutic challenge. Studies of the novel antiepileptic drugs (AEDs) gabapentin, lamotrigine and topiramate suggest that they will aid in managing seizures refractory to more established agents. However, a consensus has not been reached on their respective cellular and molecular mechanisms of action. Moreover, only a limited number of studies have examined the effects of these drugs in infants and children, a patient population with a particular propensity for seizure generation. Therefore, the objective of this investigation was to assess the effects of these new AEDs on the synchronous epileptiform activity evoked by the convulsant 4-aminopyridine (4AP) in the immature brain. The experiments described in this thesis indicate that at clinically relevant concentrations, gabapentin, lamotrigine and topiramate effectively reduce epileptiform events induced by 4AP in the hippocampal slice in vitro. These findings support previous work, and will be relevant for designing future antiepileptic compounds.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Avoli, Massimo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257g94k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc85m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axk81jn46c"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of an algorithmic method for the recognition of biological objects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bernier, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An algorithmic method for the recognition of fungal spore cells in microscopic images, as well as its development and its origin, are described and demonstrated. The process is designed for a machine vision project which automatically identifies fungal spores within field samples for epidemiological simulation models. The method consists of a three-pass system that successfully recognizes spores in any position and which is tolerant of occlusion. The algorithm, as implemented, demonstrated an accuracy of $ pm$5.3% on low quality images which is less than the assumed error of humans performing the same task. The processing speed also compared favorably with the performance of humans. The method developed presents a framework of description that, through the first two passes, highlights certain distinctive aspects within an image. Those highlighted aspects are then recognized by the third pass. The system is loosely based on biological vision, is extremely versatile and could be adapted for the recognition of virtually any object in a digitized image.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Landry, J. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp72h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn46c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer vision -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fungi -- Spores -- Identification -- Data processing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqb98mh47j"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dietary habits in Crohn's disease families in Quebec : a case-control study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bernard, Edmond-Jean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background. Worldwide, the incidence of Crohn's Disease (CD) has been rising in the last thirty years. It has no known causal factor, and remains incurable today. Using a hospital registry of French Canadian CD patients, a case-control study was undertaken in 1989 to assess potential risk factors for CD. Methods. 49 CD cases and 48 controls (healthy family members) answered a food frequency questionnaire that referred to dietary exposure at the time of CD diagnosis. Results. CD patients were younger than family controls: 35 years vs. 41 years (p = 0.001). They also had more years of schooling (8.0 years vs. 5.0 years; p = 0.017) and held higher skilled work (OR = 0.23; 95% CI: 0.08-0.69). Univariate analyses showed that CD patients consumed more carbohydrate-rich and less fiber-rich foods than controls: OR cornflakes = 3.43 (95% CI: 1.40-7.91); OR white bread = 8.75 (95% CI: 3.01-25.42); OR high fiber bread = 0.09 (95% CI: 0.03-0.23); OR fruit and vegetable intake = 0.24 (95% CI: 0.09-0.60). Multivariate conditional logistic regression modeling confirmed that cornflakes, white bread and to a lesser extent, fiber, were associated with CD: OR cornflakes = 5.23 (95% 1.02-26.91); OR white bread = 7.91 (95% CI: 1.16- 54.11); OR fiber = 0.36 (95% CI: 0.01-1.30). Conclusions. Although this original study confirms previous results, the possibility that biases, namely reverse-causality and recall, may have influenced associations between dietary factors and CD, warrants further research. A nested case-control study may offer an interesting design.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Collet, Jean-Paul</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q6140.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mh47j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f7961"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the interaction of extratropical cyclones with topography</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bensimon, Dov Richard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To better understand the role of mountains in lee cyclogenesis, two such cases which occurred during BASE (Beaufort and Arctic Storms Experiment) are simulated using the Mesoscale Compressible Community model (MC2). Both cases are shown to satisfy criteria for lee cyclogenesis, despite some ambiguity in its definition. The successful simulations reveal that lee cyclogenesis involves several processes: (1) formation of an upper-level short wave, (2) column stretching, (3) enhanced convergence and increased relative vorticity resulting from adiabatic warming, (4) latent heat release and, in one case, increased baroclinicity due to low-level blocking by topography. The results of sensitivity experiments indicate that removal of topography (latent heat) produces a stronger (weaker) lee cyclone. Topography significantly influences the distribution of precipitation with climatological consequences for areas in the lee. It is found that cyclogenesis can still occur in the absence of mountains in the two cases studied, although mountains modify the cyclogenetic processes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yau, M. K.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Zhang, D. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579v24z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f7961</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physical Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>