<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010t32q"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spatio temporal evaluation of entropy-based source localization in magnetoencephalography</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hedrich, Tanguy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Pour 30% des patients touchés par une épilepsie focale, une intervention chirurgicale peut être envisagée en vue de réséquer la zone du cerveau provoquant les crises d'épilepsie. Les pointes intérictales sont des évennements épileptiques transitoires, se produisant entre les crises d'épilepsie. Pendant la prise en charge préchirurgicale de ces patients, la localisation de source en magnétoencéphalographie (MEG) est utilisée pour détecter la région du cerveau où les pointes intérictales se produisent. L'estimation de la taille des décharges épileptiques peut être une information utile pour l'estimation de la zone à réséquer. De plus, une pointe épileptique peut se propager le long de la surface corticale. Il est crucial pendant l'exploration préchirurgicale de localiser un tel circuit de propagation  pour s'assurer d'identifier la zone initiale des décharges épileptiques. Le maximum d'entropie sur la moyenne (MEM) est une technique de localisation de source qui permet d'introduire une distribution de référence contenant des informations a priori sur les données MEG. Cette distribution de référence est basée sur l'hypothèse que le cerveau est divisé en parcelles de générateurs qui peuvent être considérées comme actives ou non. Il a déjà été prouvé que cette méthode était sensible à l'extention spatiale de la source. Le MEM cohérent (coherent MEM - cMEM) est une version du MEM qui ajoute une contrainte de lissage spatial à l'intérieur des parcelles. Pour ce mémoire, MEM et cMEM ont été comparés à une technique de localisation de source standard: l'estimation de norme minimale (minimum norm estimate - MNE). Le premier objectif de ce mémoire est de tester la performance de l'estimation du décours temporel d'une pointe. Nous avons généré des simulations de pointes interictales se propageant le long de la surface corticale, entachées par du bruit de fond réaliste. Nous avons montré que MEM et cMEM obtenaient d'excellents scores de détection spatiale, ainsi qu'une précision temporelle similaire au MNE. Ensuite, nous avons évalué la précision spatiale des méthodes de localisation de source en utilisant la matrice de résolution, qui peut être vue comme l'ensemble de toutes les fonctions d'étalement de point des méthodes de localisation de sources. Les matrices de résolution du MEM et du cMEM ont été estimées en utilisant des simulations de Monte Carlo. Les résultats ont montré que MEM et cMEM avaient une meilleure résolution spatiale théorique que MNE. Finalement, nous avons proposé une méthode visant à obtenir une carte d'activation se basant sur une analyse statistique non paramétrique. La réalisation de la carte statistique s'est faite avec une méthode utilisant le rééchantillonnage bootstrap dans le domaine temps-échelle. Nous avons trouvé que les résultats variaient avec l'extention spatiale de la source estimée. Cependant, la variance de l'estimation de la distribution de l'hypothèse nulle semblait être sous-estimée, étant donné que la carte statistique manquait de spécificité.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>For 30% of patients affected by focal epilepsy, a surgical intervention is considered to remove the zone of the brain triggering the seizures. Interictal spikes are transient epileptic discharges, occurring between seizures. During presurgical investigation of patients affected by focal epilepsy, magnetoencephalography (MEG) source localization is used to detect the brain region where interictal spikes occur. The estimation of the size of the brain region generating the epileptic discharge may be a useful piece of information for the estimation of the resection area. Moreover, the interictal spike may propagate along the cortical surface. It is crucial during presurgical investigation to detect propagation pattern to identify the onset of the epileptic discharges. Maximum entropy on the mean (MEM) is a source localization method which allows one to introduce a reference distribution containing prior information about MEG data. This reference distribution is based on the assumption that the brain is divided into parcels of generators that can be considered as active or not. It has already been demonstrated that this method is sensitive to the spatial extent of the source. Coherent MEM (cMEM) is a version of MEM adding a spatial smoothness constraint within the parcels. In this thesis, MEM and cMEM were compared to a standard source localization technique: the minimum norm estimate (MNE). The first objective of the thesis was to test the performance to estimate the time course of a simulated epileptic spike. We simulated interictal spikes propagating along the cortical surface. Real MEG background data were used to corrupt noise-free simulations, thus providing realistic simulated data. We demonstrated that MEM and cMEM provided excellent spatial detection scores and a similar temporal accuracy to MNE. We then evaluated the spatial accuracy of the source localization methods using the resolution matrix, which can be seen as the set of all the point spread functions of the source localization methods. MEM and cMEM resolution matrices were estimated using Monte Carlo simulations. The results showed that MEM and cMEM have higher theoretical spatial resolution than MNE. Finally, a method was proposed to obtain a map of activation based on a non parametric statistical analysis. The map was performed using a bootstrap-based analysis in the time-frequency domain. We found that the results varied with the spatial extent of the source. However, the variance of the estimate of the null distribution seemed to be underestimated as the statistical map lacked specificity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Christophe Grova</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pt890.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010t32q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82kb601"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Individual and competitive adsorption of phosphate and arsenate onto manganese oxide in seawater</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Strugstad, Maryon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'adsorption et la désorption individuelle et compétitive des ions arséniate et phosphate sur un oxyde de manganèse amorphe hydraté(OMH) en suspension dans une solution d'eau de mer ont été étudiées pendant 48 heures à 23 ± 3°C. L'aire de surface spécifique de l'OMH était 270 m2/g tandis que le rapport solide:solution était constant à 0.15 g/L dans toutes les expériences. Les concentrations en oxoanions étaient comprises entre 2 et 46 μM pour le phosphate, et de 0.6 à 6 μM pour l'arséniate. Dans les expériences d'adsorption compétitive, les oxoanions furent ajoutés aux suspensions simultanément ou séquentiellement à [As(V)]:[SRP](rapport molaire)= 1:2.5, 1:10, 1:100. Les résultats expérimentaux d'adsorption individuelle ont été projetés sur des isothermes d'adsorption de Langmuir et Freundlich pour déterminer la capacité d'adsorption (Γmax) et ses constantes (Kads etKf). L'arsénate possède une plus forte affinité (70-79 % adsorbé) que le phosphate (21-44 % adsorbé) pour l'OMH dans les expériences d'adsorption individuelle. Les cinétiques d'adsorption sont similaires pour les deux oxoanions, soit une rapide adsorption initiale, suivie d'une période plus lente et s'accordent bien avec lesmodèles de pseudo-premier ordre et pseudo-second ordre. Les expériences de désorption individuelle révèlent que les OMH chargés en phosphates et arsénates libèrent rapidement les deux oxoanions à la solution quand ils sont exposés à de l'eau de mer naturelle contenant ̃ 2.1 μM de phosphate et 14 nM d'arséniate. Elles démontrent également que l'adsorption d'arséniate à la surface de l'OMH dans l'eau de mer est réversible, tandis qu'une partie du phosphate est irréversiblement liée aux OMH. Quand les deux oxoanions sont ajoutés simultanément à la suspension, une véritable compétition est seulement observée à [As(V)]:[SRP] =1:100 ce qui provoque une réduction de l'adsorption des deux oxoanions. Cependant, un effet synergique (augmentation d'adsorption d'arséniate et de phosphate de ̃4 % et 6-10 %, respectivement) est noté à [As(V)]:[SRP] = 1:2.5 et 1:10. Lorsque le phosphate est ajouté en premier, l'addition subséquente d'arséniate a peu d'effet sur l'adsorption du phosphate. En revanche, quand l'arséniate est ajouté en premier, l'addition subséquente de phosphate provoque une désorption de 5 % d'arséniate lorsque [As(V)]:[SRP] = 1:10 pour les deux experiences séquentelles.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The individual and competitive adsorption and desorption of arsenate and phosphate on amorphous hydrous manganese oxide (HMO) from seawater suspensions were investigated over 48 hours at 23 ± 3°C. The specific surface area of the HMO was 270 m2/g and the solid:solution ratio was 0.15 g/L in all experiments. The oxyanion concentrations ranged from 2-46 μM (phosphate) and 0.6-6 μM (arsenate). In competitive adsorption experiments, the oxyanions were added simultaneously or sequentially to the suspensions [As(V)]:[SRP] (molar ratio)= 1:2.5, 1:10, 1:100. The adsorption data from individual experiments were fitted to Langmuir and Freundlich adsorption isotherms and the adsorption capacity(Γmax) and the adsorption constants (Kads and Kf) were determined. Arsenate displayed a stronger affinity (70-79 % adsorbed) than phosphate (21-44 % adsorbed) for HMO in individual adsorption experiments. The adsorption kinetics were similar for both oxyanions with rapid initial adsorption followed by a slower adsorption, and the kinetics fit well to pseudo-first- and pseudo-second-order models. The individual desorption experiments revealed that both phosphate- and arsenate-laden HMO rapidly release phosphate and arsenate back into solution when exposed to natural seawater containing ̃ 2.1 μM SRP and 14 nM As(V). They also demonstrate that arsenate adsorption onto HMO in seawater is reversible, whereas a fraction of the phosphate is irreversibly bound to the HMO. When the two oxyanions were added simultaneously, effective competition was only observed at [As(V)]:[SRP] = 1:100, resulting in reduced adsorption of both oxyanions, whereas a synergistic effect (increased adsorption of ̃4 % [As(V)] and 6-10 %[SRP]) was noted at [As(V)]:[SRP] = 1:2.5 and 1:10. When phosphate was added first, subsequent addition of arsenate had little effect on phosphate adsorption, but when arsenate was added first, subsequent phosphate addition caused a 5 % desorption of arsenate when [As(V)]:[SRP] = 1:10 in both sequential experiments.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bjorn Sundby</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Alfonso Mucci</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440x101.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82kb601</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Geochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322h944"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Physiochemical, morphological, pasting and softening kinetic properties of selected rice varieties from West-Africa</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nwankpa, Chijioke</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The physicochemical, morphological, pasting and softening kinetics of rice varieties selected from West-African countries were investigated. The studies conducted were aimed at  enhancing the adoption and use of these local varieties in improving food security in Africa through the development of acceptable new rice-based products .The varietal, morphological and physiochemical impacts on appearance, pasting, textural properties and softening kinetics were also analyzed. To unravel structural properties of the respective isolated rice starch from the selected rice varieties, scanning electron microscopic analysis was also carried out.           The varieties studied were Faro 61, Faro 60, Faro 44, Tox 3145 and Nerica 3.  Microscopic studies carried out on the isolated starch indicated that the starch granules were 4.43 -5.62 µm. The structural variations observed did not clearly provide an explanation for the pasting and textural properties of the studied rice varieties. Morphological studies also revealed that the rice granules were polyhedral, irregular in shape and tightly packed.  Proximate studies indicated that the rice varieties were composed of 0.35 - 0.52% fat, 0.32 - 0.57% ash , 8.97 - 10.35% protein, 88.63 - 90.08% carbohydrate and 22.4 - 28.50% amylose. The proximate results indicates that these varieties are high protein containing waxy rice varieties.        Color parameters (L*and b*)  studies of uncooked rice flour samples indicated high values of L* and low values of b* for all the rice varieties. The order of increasing whiteness was found to be Faro 61 &gt; Faro 44 &gt; Faro 60 &gt; Nerica 3 &gt; Tox 3145 while the b* values ranged from 5.09 - 7.26. The high degree of whiteness and low values of yellowness of these rice varieties indicate that their flours would be highly acceptable by most consumers.      Results of the pasting properties studies indicated significant differences in the peak viscosity , trough viscosity, final viscosity and set back viscosity of the rice flours. Faro 44 showed a higher peak viscosity value (3984.5 cP) while Nerica 3  indicated the lowest peak viscosity value (2850.5 cP). Faro 44 and Tox 3145 had the highest and lowest trough viscosities, respectively.  Break down viscosities were within the 546.5 and 1164 cP range for the rice varieties. Faro 44 had significantly higher breakdown viscosities than other varieties. The result indicated that Faro 44 flour is suitable for the production of value added products such as noodles, due to the ability of its paste to swell sufficiently while remaining intact and stable during sheering.  Setback viscosity varied from 865.5 to 2138.5 cP. Faro 44 showed the highest setback viscosity (2138.5 cP) while Faro 61 showed the least (865.5 cP). The pasting temperature of Faro 44 was higher than the other rice varieties and found to be 85.50C.     Textural studies indicated hardness decreased with increase in cooking time.  When cooked from 5 minutes to 25 minutes, there was gross disintegration of the rice granular structure . These structural changes provide an explanation for the corresponding changes in the tissue strength and elasticity of the studied rice varieties. In addition, the rate of textural changes related with the cooking temperature utilized in this study was found to confirm with two pseudo first-order kinetic mechanisms. The kinetic model utilized indicated  that the apparent rate constants K1 a  varied from 0.03776 to 0.4468 min-1 while K1 b  varied  from 0.008475 to 0.013665 min-1 .     Over all, variations were observed in the morphological, physicochemical, pasting and softening kinetic properties of all the studied rice varieties. These studies are vital in ensuring an improving quality of rice by thermal processing.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les variétés de riz étudie étaient Faro 61, 60 Faro, Faro 44, Tox 3145 et Nerica 3. Les observations microscopiques réalisées sur l'amidon isolé ont indique que les granules d'amidon variaient eutre 4.43 et 5.62 µm. Ces variations structurelles n'expliquait pas clairement les propriétés texturales et collantes des variétés de riz étudie. Des études morphologiques ont aussi révélé que les granules d'amidon de riz étaient polyédriques, serre et de forme irrégulière. L'analyse immédiate des macronutriments  a révélé que les variétés de riz sont composées de 0.35 à 0.52% de matières grasses, de 0.32 à 0.57% de cendres, 8.97 à 10.35% de protéines, de 88.63 à 90.08% de glucides et, enfin, 22.4 à 28.50% d'amylose. Ces résultats indiquent que ces variétés sont les variétés de riz sont riches en protéines.L'étude sur les paramètres de couleur (L* et b*) des échantillons de farine de riz non cuite indique de valeurs élevées de L* et de faibles valeurs de b* pour toutes les variétés de riz.  L'ordre croissant de blancheur a été jugée être Faro 61&gt; Faro 44&gt; Faro 60&gt; Nerica 3&gt; Tox 3145, tandis que les valeurs de b* variaient entre 5,09 et 7,26. Un haut degré de blancheur combine a un faible de jaunissement de ces variétés de riz indiquent que ces farines seraient bien acceptées par la plupart des consommateurs.      Les résultats des études des propriétés collantes ont dénoté des différences significatives pour la viscosité maximale, minimale, finale et la viscosité de rechute des farines de riz. Faro 44 a montré une valeur de viscosité maximale élevée (3984,5 cP), tandis que le Nerica 3 indique la valeur du sommet de la viscosité moins grande (2850,5 cP). Faro 44 et Tox 3145 avaient respectivement les plus hautes et les plus basses viscosités minimales. Les viscosités de dégradation se rangeaient entre 546,5 et 1164 cps pour toutes les variétés de riz. Faro 44 avait une viscosité de dégradation nettement plus élevés que les autres variétés. Ce résultat indique que la farine de riz Faro 44 est appropriée pour la production des produits à valeur enrichie, tels que les nouilles, en raison de la capacité de la pâte de gonfler suffisamment tout en restant intacte et stable pendant le cisaillage. La viscosité de rechute varie de 865,5 à 2138,5 cP. Faro 44 a montré la viscosité de rechute la plus élevé (2138,5 cP), alors que Faro 61 a montré la moindre (865,5 cP). La température de gélatinisation de Faro 44 était plus élevée que les autres variétés de riz et établie à 85.5°C.    Le etudes texturales ont indiqué que la dureté diminue avec la hausse du temps de cuisson. À la fin du cuisson de 5 minutes à 25 minutes, il y a eu une désintégration brute de la structure granulaire de riz. Ces changements structurels fournissent une explication pour les changements correspondants dans la solidité du tissu et l'élasticité des variétés de riz étudiées. En outre, le taux de changements de texture en rapport avec la température de cuisson utilisée dans cette étude correspond à deux mécanismes cinétiques de pseudo premier ordre. Le modèle cinétique utilisé a indiqué que les constantes de vitesse apparentes K1 a ont varie de 0,03776 à 0,4468 min-1, tandis que K1 b se rangeaient entre 0,008475 et 0,013665 min-1. Ces études sont essentielles afin d'assurer et améliorer la qualité du riz par traitement thermique.    Dans l'ensemble, les variations des variétés du riz étudiées ont été observées en tant que leur caractéristiques morphologiques, physico-chimiques, les propriétés de gélatinisation, ramollissement ainsi que les propriétés cinétiques.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Benjamin K. Simpson</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Michael O. Ngadi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602430p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322h944</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Food Science and Technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149s89n"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ecosystemic worldview in Russian fairy tales</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kadyrbekova, Zaure</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les analyses des animaux dans la littérature se concentrent pour la plupart sur la signification de l'animal métaphorique ou symbolique et negligent par là même l'animal réel qui disparaît souvent derrière sa représentation métaphorique ou mythologique. Ces interprétations traditionnelles révèlent l'anthropocentrisme qui domine dans les sciences humaines en général, et les études littéraires en particulier. Pourtant, les animaux dans la littérature retiennent encore des caractéristiques spécifiques à leur espèce. En analysant certains contes de fées russes du point de vue des études animales, je vais montrer que les animaux gardent leur capacité d'être agent, qu'ils conservent leur spécificité animale et qu'ils sont impliqués dans des relations complexes comme compagnons des humains. Cette représentation des animaux dans les contes de fées russes montre que la vision traditionnelle du monde russe est écosystémique – c'est-à-dire que les humains sont sur un même plan d'égalité que les autres êtres vivants. Compte tenu du nombre insuffisant d'analyses sur les contes de fées russes, et du manque d'analyses sur les animaux dans les contes de fées en général, la présente étude représente une étape importante pour combler cette lacune.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The majority of interpretations of literary animals focus on the animals' metaphoric or symbolic significance, overlooking the actual animal, which often completely disappears behind its metaphoric or mythological representation. Such traditional interpretations of animals expose the dominant anthropocentric focus of the humanities in general, and literary studies in particular. Yet, even as textual representations a lot of literary animals still exhibit some basic species-specific characteristics. By analyzing selected Russian fairytales through the animal studies perspective I will show that in a lot of Russian fairytales animals exercise their agency, retain their animal specificity and are involved in complex companionate relationships with humans. Such portrayal of animals in Russian fairytales warrants identifying traditional Russian worldview as ecosystemic – in which humans are positioned on an equal plane with other living beings. Given the insufficient number of interpretive works on Russian fairytales, and the lack of work on fairytale animals, the present application of animal studies to Russian folktales can be one of the first steps to filling this niche. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anna Berman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gr58b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149s89n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Slavic and East European</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r642r"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The regulation of estrogen-related receptor alpha by the O-linked N-acetylglucosamine post-translational modification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tsang, Wing Kin David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les récepteurs nucléaires sont des facteurs de transcription qui, suite à différents stimuli physiologiques, contrôlent des processus moléculaires variés en modulant l'expression de leurs gènes cibles. Le récepteur ERRα (Estrogen-related receptor) est considéré comme un récepteur orphelin, car jusqu'à présent aucun ligand pour ce récepteur n'a été identifié. Par conséquent, les différents stress affectant la voie d'ERRα modifie son activité via des modifications post-traductionnelles ou en changeant l'activité de ses corégulateurs. La modification O-GlcNac est unique à la voie biosynthétique hexosamines glucose-dépendante et plusieurs auteurs suggèrent qu'elle sert de « senseur nutritionnel » de la cellule. Dans le présent mémoire, nous démontrons que la modulation des niveaux cellulaires d'O-GlcNac affecte le profil d'interactions géniques d'ERRα en plus d'altérer l'activité transcriptionnelle de ce récepteur nucléaire. Plusieurs patrons de réponse suivant la modification de cette voie ont été observés, ce qui suggèrent que la modification du programme transcriptionnel d'ERRα par la voie O-GlcNac est complexe. Bien que nous n'ayons pu démontrer qu'ERRα était une cible directe de la modification O-GlcNac, certains de ses corégulateurs ont déjà été démontrés comme subissant cette modification, ce qui pourrait expliquer certains des résultats obtenus. La capacité de la voie O-GlcNac de modifier l'activité d'ERRα supporte le rôle clé d'ERRα comme régulateur majeur des gènes métaboliques et implique qu'il est un acteur clé dans la réponse cellulaire suite à des changements physiologiques de disponibilité des nutriments.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Nuclear receptors regulate various cellular processes by modulating gene expression in response to chemical signals produced by physiological stimuli. The absence of an identified ligand for the orphan nuclear receptor ERRα stresses the importance of post-translational modifications (PTMs) and coregulators in determining its activity. The O-GlcNAc modification is unique to the glucose-dependent hexosamine biosynthetic pathway, and has been suggested that it acts as a "nutrient sensor" of the cell. We demonstrate that changing cellular levels of the O-GlcNAc PTM affects the genomic binding profile and transcriptional activity of ERRα. The differential responses of known ERRα gene targets suggests that an ERRα transcriptional program regulated by O-GlcNAc levels is complex, and does not indiscriminately increase the activity of ERRα on all of its target genes. We were unable to show that ERRα is directly O-GlcNAcylated, but its partners have been. Which could account for some of the observations presented. The ability for the glucose-dependent O-GlcNAc modification to alter ERRα activity supports the known role of ERRα as a key regulator of metabolic genes and implies that it is important in the cellular response to changes in physiological nutrient availability. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vincent Giguere</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sk615.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r642r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848t83k"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of context on the recognition of objects in healthy controls and schizophrenia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maguire, Melissa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'objectif de cette thèse consiste en l'étude des activités cérébrales reflétant l'influence qu'exerce la présence de contexte sur la reconnaissance d'objets ambigus et non-ambigus. L'activité électrophysiologique et les potentiels évoqués en réponse à des objets cibles présentés dans les scènes congruentes et neutres ont été enregistrés et analysés. Cette thèse comprend deux manuscrits décrivant chacune une étude. La première étude examine l'influence du contexte de la scène sur la reconnaissance d'objets ambigus et non-ambigus chez des sujets sains. Les résultats de cette étude indiquent un plus grand effet de contexte avec les objets ambigus, tel que démontré par de plus grands effets de contexte sur les potentiels évoqués et une plus forte augmentation du taux de reconnaissance des objets lorsque présentés dans des contextes congruents. L'effet de contexte se manifeste de manière à rendre les activités de reconnaissance d'objets ambigus semblables aux activités de reconnaissance d'objets non-ambigus. De plus, l'effet de contexte se manifeste très tôt, dès les premières étapes de l'analyse perceptive de l'objet.La deuxieme étude porte sur l'influence du contexte de la scène sur la reconnaissance des objets ambigus et non-ambigus chez les sujets atteints de schizophrénie et chez des sujets contrôles. Les résultats de cette étude montrent, une fois de plus, que l'influence du contexte est plus forte avec les objets ambigus et que le contexte exerce son influence au cours des premières étapes de l'analyse perceptive. Ces effets de contexte se sont toutefois avérés de plus petite magnitude chez les sujets atteints de schizophrénie. De plus, l'effet de contexte sur les potentiels évoqués corrélaient avec les symptômes positifs de la schizophrénie, en particulier avec le niveau de délires des patients. Les personnes avec le plus de symptômes positifs ont montré un plus grand effet de contexte. Globalement, cette étude démontre que les personnes atteintes de schizophrénie utilisent le contexte de façon anormale.ie, en particulier dans les délires. Les personnes ayant plus de symptômes positifs ont montré un plus grand effet de contexte. Globalement, cette étude fournit des preuves que les personnes atteintes de schizophrénie utilisent le contexte de façon irregulier, par rapport aux sujets sains.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The scope of this thesis is to investigate the underlying brain activity of the influence of scene context of the recognition of ambiguous and unambiguous objects. Electrophysiology studies were used, and event-related potentials (ERPs) were  analyzed in response to target objects presented in consistent and neutral scenes. This thesis is manuscript-based, with two primary studies. The first study focuses on the influence of scene context on the recognition of ambiguous and unambiguous objects in healthy subjects.  The findings from this study indicate that context has a greater influence over ambiguous objects, evidenced by increased ERP amplitudes and a greater increase in recognition from neutral to consistent scenes for ambiguous objects compared to unambiguous objects. In addition, context appears to exert its influence by causing ambiguous objects to be treated as unambiguous objects.  Finally, the influence of context began early, during stages of object perceptual analysis.The second study focuses on the influence of scene context on the recognition of ambiguous and unambiguous objects in subjects with schizophrenia, compared to a matched control group.  The findings for this study indicate, once again, that the influence of context is stronger for ambiguous objects and that it exerts its influence during early stages of perceptual analysis.  Subjects with schizophrenia were revealed to have a deficit in processing scene context, as the ERP amplitudes of the effect of context were smaller in the schizophrenia group. In addition, the effect of context correlated with the positive symptoms of the illness, specifically delusions, in that individuals with more positive symptoms showed a greater effect of context.  Overall this study provides evidence that individuals with schizophrenia use context to in an abnormal way, compared to healthy controls. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mathieu Bernard-Brodeur</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qt14j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848t83k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Cognitive</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cx484"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Formes et figures du grotesque dans «La grande tribu : c’est la faute à Papineau!» de Victor-Lévy Beaulieu</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vien, Myriam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the role of the grotesque in Victor-Lévy Beaulieu's La  Grande Tribu : c'est la faute à Papineau. It aims to show how the writer's primary aesthetics offers a new conception of Quebec's national past and society that subverts the initial project of the text and its original model, the epic. The hypothesis underlying this study is that the grotesque – through improbable mixings, hybridization, and metamorphosis – enables Lévy-Beaulieu to reflect on the ways the world has changed and to put the future of a community into words. The first chapter gives an overview of the main theories on the grotesque in order to turn its defining characteristics into concrete analysis tools. In this respect, the works of Mikhail Bakhtine, Wolfgang Kayser and Rémi Astruc are closely analyzed to provide the theoretical framework of this study. The second chapter deals with the various occurrences of the grotesque in La Grande Tribu in order to see how they participate – with an emphasis on the representation of the ways the body and language mutate – in shifting the plot into another reality altogether. Finally, the last chapter focuses on the specific relationship between time and historical continuity in the text. Under the influence of the "grotesque time", which minimizes the distance between past and present, La Grand Tribu drifts into an entropic temporality in which memory rules the characters' fate and complicates the plot by harking back to and repeating the past.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire examine la présence grotesque à l'œuvre dans La Grande Tribu : c'est la faute à Papineau ! de Victor-Lévy Beaulieu, dans le but de montrer comment l'esthétique privilégiée par l'écrivain installe une nouvelle vision du passé national et de la société québécoise, détournant le projet initial de l'œuvre et son modèle de départ, l'épopée. L'hypothèse qui sous-tend cette étude est que le grotesque, en déployant les figures du mélange improbable, de l'hybridation et de la métamorphose, permet de penser la transformation du monde et d'articuler le devenir d'une communauté. Le premier chapitre propose un survol des grandes propositions formulées sur la question grotesque afin de convertir les principaux traits définitoires du phénomène en outils d'analyse concrets. À cette fin, les travaux de Mikhaïl Bakhtine, Wolfgang Kayser et Rémi Astruc, sont décortiqués pour établir le cadre théorique de cette recherche. Le deuxième chapitre aborde les manifestations du grotesque dans La Grande Tribu dans le but de voir comment celles-ci participent, par la représentation de la mutation du corps et du langage notamment, au basculement du récit dans une toute autre réalité.  Enfin, un dernier chapitre interroge le rapport particulier au temps et à la continuité historique qui prend place dans l'œuvre. Sous l'effet du « temps grotesque », qui aplatit les distances entre le passé et le présent, La Grande Tribu verse dans une temporalité entropique où la mémoire s'approprie le destin des personnages et entraîne le récit dans le ressassement et le redoublement.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michel Biron</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wr08w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cx484</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Canadian (French)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amc87pt90r"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La poétique bilingue de Patrice Desbiens</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Simard, Mathieu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bilingualism is a recurring feature in Franco-Ontarian writer Patrice Desbiens' work. However, Desbiens' critics generally consider his bilingualism from an angle that is more social than formal. In this thesis, we study the literary forms of Desbiens' bilingual writing. We situate this bilingualism in the broader context of Bakhtinian heteroglossia, and reflect on the relationship between bilingualism and the plurality of voices (heterophony) and of points of view (heterology) within the literary text. In the first chapter, we distinguish four forms of bilingualism, three of which are employed by Desbiens. The next three chapters are thus devoted to the study of these forms. We first look at the "heterophonic-heterological" form, in which a diversity of voices, languages and points of view are intermingled. We then analyze the "monophonic-heterological" form, which integrates two languages and two points of view within a single voice. Finally, in the fourth chapter, we observe the "monophonic-monological" form, which unites languages around a single voice and a single point of view.In our conclusion, we show that Desbiens' bilingual writing participates in both a "particularist" and a "universalist" aesthetics, and that through the combination of these aesthetics, the writer tries to find a "third way" (Lucie Hotte). In L'homme invisible/The Invisible Man, Desbiens uses the many facets of plurilingualism to problematize the notions of "knowledge" and "truth". However, this "third way," which makes particularist and universalist issues overlap, is abandoned after L'homme invisible/The Invisible Man in favour of another way. Our reading of Desbiens' collections of poems shows an increasing homogenization of plurilingualism: in the period between 1980 and 1995, heterogeneous forms dominate, but they are progressively replaced in the 2000s by a much more homogeneous form, the monophonic-monological one. While successively expressing particularistic and universalistic considerations, this form restricts the heterogeneous potential of plurilingualism: it retains from the latter only the diversity of languages, eliminating the plurality of voices and of points of view.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Plusieurs textes de l'écrivain franco-ontarien Patrice Desbiens sont bilingues. Or, les recherches sur Desbiens ont principalement insisté sur l'aspect social de ce bilinguisme, au détriment de sa dimension formelle. Notre mémoire, lui, se penche sur les formes littéraires de l'écriture bilingue. Nous situons le bilinguisme dans le cadre plus large du plurilinguisme bakhtinien : quels sont les rapports entre le bilinguisme et la multiplicité de voix (hétérophonie) et de points de vue (hétérologie) présente dans le texte littéraire ? À partir du modèle bakhtinien, le premier chapitre de ce mémoire décrit quatre formes générales de bilinguisme, dont trois sont présentes chez Desbiens. Les chapitres suivants sont consacrés à l'étude de ces trois formes. Nous nous penchons d'abord sur la forme hétérophonique-hétérologique, qui fait s'entrechoquer une diversité de voix, de langues et de points de vues. Ensuite, nous analysons la forme monophonique-hétérologique, qui agence deux langues et deux points de vue avec une seule voix. Enfin, dans le quatrième chapitre, nous observons la forme monophonique-monologique, qui fédère les langues autour d'une seule voix et d'un seul point de vue. En conclusion, nous montrons que l'écriture bilingue de Desbiens participe aux esthétiques « particulariste » et « universaliste » et qu'à travers leur entrelacement, l'écrivain tente de trouver une « troisième voie » (Lucie Hotte). Dans L'homme invisible/The Invisible Man, Desbiens recourt aux multiples facettes du plurilinguisme pour problématiser les notions de « connaissance » et de « vérité ». Faisant se superposer les enjeux du particulier et de l'universel, la voie tracée dans ce récit est cependant abandonnée dans le reste de l'œuvre. Notre lecture des recueils de Desbiens dévoile effectivement une homogénéisation croissante du plurilinguisme, à partir de la période 1980-1995 – où la forme hétérophonique-hétérologique domine – jusqu'aux années 2000, où une forme plus homogène – la monophonique-monologique – est à l'avant- plan. Or, tout en exprimant successivement des considérations particularistes puis universalistes, cette forme restreint le potentiel hétérogène du plurilinguisme : elle ne conserve de ce dernier que la diversité des langues, éliminant celle des voix et des points de vue.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Catherine Leclerc</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q475m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pt90r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Canadian (French)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67jv50n"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comparison of cardiorespiratory behaviour in premature infants under different post-extubation ventilatory support modalities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kanbar, Lara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background: Preterm infants with gestational age (GA) &lt;= 32 weeks require endotracheal tube mechanical ventilation (ETT-MV) during their first few days of life. These infants are quickly weaned from ETT-MV and extubated to some type of noninvasive ventilatory support; usually Nasal Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) or non-synchronized Nasal Intermittent Positive Pressure Ventilation (NIPPV). Currently, there is no evidence to select one mode over another. The aim of this thesis was to compare cardiorespiratory behavior of infants undergoing nasal CPAP and NIPPV by evaluating the immediate post-extubation period, using novel automated evaluation techniques. Patients &amp; Methods: Recruited patients were preterm infants with GA &lt;= 32 weeks and birth weight (BW) &lt;= 1250g, under ETT-MV undergoing their first extubation attempt. Data were collected during each of 3 time-periods post-extubation. For each period, the 3 types of non-invasive support were applied in a random order for 45 minutes each: CPAP, NIPPV at a rate of 20 (NIPPV20) and 40 (NIPPV40) breaths/minute. Heart rate, oxygen saturation, and respiratory movements of the ribcage and abdomen were measured. Data were analyzed with an Automated Unsupervised Respiratory Event Analysis system (AUREA) and features characterizing cardiorespiratory behavior were extracted for each modality. Classifiers were used to distinguish between the modalities. Results &amp; Conclusions: There were no consistently significant differences in any of the features defined by the metrics or in the state features between CPAP and NIPPV20, NIPPV40. Furthermore, classification attempts using logistic regression and AdaBoost were only a little better than chance. Thus, any differences in the modalities are unlikely to translate to clinically significant differences.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Contexte: Les nouveau-nés prématurés avec un âge gestationnel (AG) &lt;= 32 semaines requièrent ventilation par tube endotrachéale (VTET) au cours de leurs premiers jours de vie. Ces enfants sont rapidement sevrés avec la VTET et extubés à un certain type d'assistance ventilatoire non-invasive; habituellement pression positive continue (PPC) ou non synchronisé ventilation par pression positive non-invasive (VPPNI). À l'heure actuelle, il n'existe aucune preuve pour la sélection d'une méthode plutôt qu'une autre. Le but de cette étude était de comparer le comportement cardiorespiratoire des nouveau-nés subissant le PPC et le VPPNI en évaluant la période post-extubation immédiate, en utilisant de nouvelles techniques d'évaluation automatisées. Patients et Méthodes: Les patients recrutés étaient des nouveau-nés prématurés avec un AG &lt;= 32 semaines et avec un poids de naissance (BW) &lt;= 1250g, sous VTET et subissant leur première tentative d'extubation. Les données ont été recueillies au cours de chacune des 3 périodes de temps post-extubation. Pour chaque période, les 3 modes de soutien non-invasive ont été appliquées dans un ordre aléatoire pendant 45 minutes chacun: PPC, VPPNI à un taux de 20 (VPPNI20) et 40 (VPPNI40) respirations / minute.La fréquence cardiaque, la saturation d'oxygène, et les mouvements respiratoires de la cage thoracique et de l'abdomen ont été mesurés. Les données ont été analysées avec un système automatisé sans surveillance respiratoire de l'analyse de l'événement (AUREA) et les caractéristiques qui caractérisent le comportement respiratoire ont été extraites pour chaque modalité. Des classifications ont été utilisés pour tenter de faire la distinction entre les modalités. Résultats et Conclusions: Il y avait aucune différence significative consistante entre les caractéristiques définies par les mesures ou entre les fonctions de l'etat entre PPC et VPPNI20, VPPNI40. De plus, les tentatives de classification en utilisant la régression logistique et AdaBoost étaient seulement un peu mieux que le hasard. Donc, les différences dans les modalités sont peu susceptibles de se traduire par des différence cliniquement significative</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kearney, Robert E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dd30t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jv50n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418r57v"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Extratropical cyclone climatology for eastern Canadian cities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Plante, Mathieu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this study, a Lagrangian tracking algorithm is applied to the 850-hPa relative vorticity field to characterize extratropical cyclone tracks across eastern Canada. Seasonal cycles are examined in terms of overall cyclone frequency, intensity, regions of development and decay. We found that cyclones tend to develop over the Rockies, the Great Lakes or the Western Atlantic. They are most intense over Newfoundland and North Atlantic, and decay over Greenland. Cyclones tracking across Toronto, Montreal, Halifax and St-John's are further analyzed, with typical cyclone tracks, origin, frequency, mean local growth rate, and mean intensity. Among others, we found that cyclone activities at east coast cities (Halifax, St-John's) are dominated by Atlantic cyclones, more frequent in winter, while Montreal's and Toronto's cyclones travel primarily from the Great Lakes, frequent and intense in spring and autumn. Cyclones from the Gulf of Mexico are not frequent, but extreme. The relationship between winter cyclone tracks and modes of atmospheric variability are also examined with an emphasis on the El Niño - Southern Oscillation (ENSO), North Atlantic Oscillation (NAO) and Pacific North American pattern (PNA). An ENSO and PNA-related oscillation between continental and coastal cyclones is confirmed. The inter-annual variability of winter cyclones cross eastern Canadian cities are quantified. Cyclone activities in Toronto and Montreal shown to be modulated by ENSO and PNA, while NAO dominates the cyclone variability in Halifax and St-John's. The local cyclone variability is found to be small in terms of overall cyclone statistics, but important in terms of changes in the origins of the local cyclones.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Un algorithme est appliqué sur le tourbillon relatif à 850-hPa afin de calculer la trajectoire des cyclones affectant l'Est du Canada. Les variations saisonnières de ces trajectoires sont approfondies par l'étude de plusieurs paramètres, tels que la fréquence, l'intensité, l'origine, le taux de développement et le taux de dissipation des cyclones. L'étude démontre que les cyclones se développent principalement au dessus des Rocheuse, des Grands Lacs et de la côte Est des États-Unis, et se dissipent près des côtes Est et Ouest du Groendland. Les plus intenses se trouvent à Terre Neuve et au Nord de l'Atlantique. Ces statistiques de cyclones sont ensuite évaluées plus spécifiquement pour les cyclones atteignant Toronto, Montréal, Halifax et St-John's. Entre autre, il est démontré que les villes côtières sont pricipalement affectées par les cyclones en provenance de la côte Est Américaine, fréquents en hiver, tandis que Toronto et Montréal sont principalement affectés par les cyclones en provenance des Grands Lacs, plutôt fréquents au printemps et à l'automne. Les cyclones en provenance du Golf du Mexique sont moins fréquents, mais constituent une grande partie des extrêmes. La variation inter-annuelle de l'activité cyclonique est ensuite évaluée selon différents régimes de variabilité climatiques, tels qu'ENSO (El Nino-Southern Oscillation), le NAO (North Atlantic Oscillation) et le PNA (Pacific-North America). Les résultats consolident la présence d'une oscillation entre cyclones continentaux et cyclones côtiers pendant ENSO. L'étude démontre que la variabilité cyclonique inter-annuelle à Toronto et Montréal est dominée par ENSO et le PNA, tandis que le NAO a un plus grand impact à Halifax et à St-John's.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Richard Gyakum</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Seok-Woo Son</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430789j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r57v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q950z"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>EFL learner and teacher perspectives on corrective feedback and their effect on second language learning motivation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Miranda-Calderón, Natalia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une démarche de méthodes mixtes a été utilisée dans cette étude qui porte sur les croyances de 247 élèves du secondaire, ainsi que leurs 12 professeurs d'anglais, langue étrangère, par rapport à la rétroaction corrective en ce qui a trait aux types, à la fréquence et aux attitudes positives et négatives que les participants pourraient avoir envers celle-ci.  Les données furent recueillies à l'aide d'un questionnaire administré à tous les participants, ainsi que par l'intermédiaire d'entrevues approfondies avec un sous-échantillon composé de 15 élèves et des 12 professeurs participant à l'étude.  Ces entrevues ont eu lieu à deux différents sites d'échantillonnage à Santiago au Chile : une école bilingue privée et une institution semi-privée.  Les points de vue des enseignants et apprenants par rapport à la rétroaction corrective ont été comparés intra- et inter-écoles quantitativement en analysant avec le test U de Mann-Whitney les données obtenues du questionnaire, et qualitativement en faisant une analyse de contenu des entrevues, dans le but d'identifier les différences qui pourraient affecter la motivation en L2 des étudiants.  Les tests révèlent qu'il y a dans les deux contextes de recherche des disparités évidentes entre les croyances des enseignants et des apprenants en ce qui a trait à la rétroaction corrective.  Alors que les élèves expriment des points de vue positifs envers la rétroaction corrective et son efficacité, ainsi qu'une préférence pour les types explicites de correction, les professeurs doutaient de son efficacité et s'inquiétaient de ses effets sur la confiance en soi des élèves.  De ce fait, les professeurs proféraient une préférence pour les types plus implicites de rétroaction.  Ces résultats font l'objet d'une discussion portant autant sur les effets potentiellement néfastes qu'ils pourraient avoir sur la motivation en L2 des élèves que sur leurs implications pédagogiques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The present mixed-methods research study examines the beliefs of 247 high school students and their 12 EFL teachers about corrective feedback in terms of its types, frequency, and their positive and negative attitudes towards it. The data were gathered by means of a questionnaire administered to all participants and in-depth interviews conducted with a subsample of 15 students and all 12 of the participating EFL teachers at two distinct research sites in Santiago, Chile: a private bilingual school and a semi-private institution. Teacher and learner perspectives on error correction were compared within and across schools in order to identify differences that might affect students' L2 motivation by quantitatively analyzing the questionnaire data by means of the Mann-Whitney U Test and by qualitatively examining the interviews through content analysis. The results revealed that in both research settings there were evident disparities between teacher and learner perspectives on corrective feedback. Whereas students expressed positive views of corrective feedback and its effectiveness as well as preferences for explicit types of correction, teachers were skeptical of its effectiveness and concerned about its effect on learners' self-confidence. Accordingly, teachers reported preferences for more implicit types of feedback. These results are discussed in terms of the potentially detrimental effects they may have on students' L2 motivation and in terms of their pedagogical implications. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roy Lyster</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p361f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q950z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Language and Literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zh73g"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fonction auteur et auteur-fiction chez André Gide</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Malka, Ruth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since its publication, André Gide's works mainly generated biographical analyses. As Gide's texts are first-person narratives and as the stories written recall the author's life experience, especially as far as homosexuality is concerned, it is tempting to think that each book he wrote is somehow autobiographical. The point of this thesis is to question those analyses which seem to forget an essential dimension: fiction. Instead of thinking that each text is a mirror reflecting Gide's image, we are going to see how the author set himself in his fiction. Gide takes a posture: through his literary work, he doesn't show himself as he is, neither as he thinks he is, but rather as he would likely to be seen. The author-function established correspond to the author's invention of his own character: the author is created through fiction. The role Gide would like to endorse consists in defending pederasty. He is the one who creates gidian immoralism, a new ethics both hedonist and antimoralist. As Gide writes against social conventions and protestant moral, he establishes himself the prophet of a new religion. The posture Gide takes frees him from the guilt he inherited from his protestant upbringing for being a homosexual, trying to persuade not only his readership but also himself that he is right of doing so. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Depuis sa parution, l'œuvre d'André Gide a principalement suscité des analyses biographiques. Comme les textes gidiens sont écrits à la première personne et que les diégèses présentent des similitudes avec la vie de l'auteur, notamment en ce qui concerne l'homosexualité, il est tentant de penser que chaque ouvrage relève d'une forme d'autobiographie. L'objectif de ce mémoire est de montrer les limites de ces théories en s'appuyant sur une dimension qu'elles oublient, à savoir la fiction. Au lieu de voir dans chaque texte une projection de soi, il s'agit d'y déceler une mise en fiction de soi. Gide prend une posture : grâce à son écriture, il se donne à lire à son lectorat non pas tel qu'il est ni tel qu'il pense être, mais tel qu'il aimerait être perçu. La fonction auteur mise en place par Gide correspond à l'invention de son propre personnage : l'auteur est créé par la fiction. Le rôle que Gide cherche à endosser est celui du défenseur de la pédérastie. Il est celui qui établit l'immoralisme gidien, une nouvelle éthique hédoniste et antimoraliste. Se dressant contre les conventions sociales et la morale protestante, s'établissant prophète d'une nouvelle religion, la posture que prend Gide lui permet de se débarrasser de toute la culpabilité que lui a laissée son éducation puritaine en regard de l'homosexualité, à la fois aux yeux du lecteur et à ses propres yeux. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Arnaud Bernadet</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g86t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zh73g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azp38wg98h"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of time and rate of nitrogen, sulfur and boron application on canola growth in southwestern Québec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ruan, Qianying</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Canola (Brassica napusL.) seeds have a high oil content (&gt; 40 %), the lowest saturated fat concentration (6.8%) among the vegetable oils, plus low erucic acid and glucosinolate levels, making this crop highly valuable in the oilseed industry.  Québec, a province where little canola is currently produced, has considerable potential to expand canola cultivation and, in doing so, strengthen the provincial agricultural sector.  However, at this time there are no well-founded fertility recommendations for canola production in southwestern Québec; there is a lack of sufficient data on canola responses to nitrogen (N), sulfur (S) and boron (B).  Therefore, field studies were conducted in 2011 and 2012 to determine the optimum rate and timing of N fertilizer additions, and also the best rates of S and B application under southwestern Québec conditions.  In 2011, factorial combinations of four levels of N [0, 50, 100 (or 50 + 50) and 150 (or 50 + 100) kg ha-1], two levels of S (0 and 20 kg ha-1), and three levels of B (0, 0.5 foliar spray at 20% flowering stage, and 2 kg ha-1 soil applied before sowing) were tested. Single doses of N fertilization (50, 100, 150 kg ha-1) were all applied before sowing. Split N fertilization was also evaluated at two levels: 100 kg ha-1 (50 + 50 kg ha-1) and 150 kg ha-1 (50 + 100 kg ha-1), where the first dose of 50 kg N ha-1 was applied before sowing, and the remainder was side-dressed at the 3-4 leaf stage.  In 2012, two additional treatments were added, one applied as 20 kg S ha-1, 0.5 kg B ha-1 and 200 kg N ha-1, and the other as 20 kg S ha-1, 0.5 kg B ha-1 and 50 + 150 kg N ha-1.  In 2011, N fertilization had positive effects on dry biomass, leaf area, plant height, seeds silique-1, harvest index, yield, and seed protein content, but a negative effect on seed oil content. The optimum N rate was 150 kg N ha-1, resulting in the highest seed yield and good seed quality.  In 2012, canola did not respond as strongly to fertilizer additions as in 2011, apparently because of lower established plant densities. Application of fertilizer N affected fewer variables in 2012: 1000-seed weight, and harvest index, seed oil content and seed protein content. Of the four blocks in the 2012 experiment, only block four had a reasonably high average plant population density.  For block four, the yield data was curvilinearly and positively correlated with N rate (R² = 0.5702, P &lt; 0.0001), with peak yield occurring at 150 kg N ha-1.  Canola growth was often not affected by the time of N application.  In 2011, there was a S x B interaction for 1000-seed weight, in that the effect was positive with foliar application of 0.5 B kg ha -1 and negative when 2 kg B ha-1 was soil-applied).  Boron alone increased 1000-seed weight in 2012.  Our results indicated that S and B levels in the soils used were probably sufficient for canola production.  Plant height was decreased (2.9 %) by S application at 20 kg ha-1 in 2011.  In conclusion, our data suggest that the best N application regime for canola production in southwestern Québec may be a single application at 150 kg N ha-1; this produced the highest seed yield without sacrifice of seed quality.  Sulfur and B additions may not be required for canola production in southwestern Québec. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les semences du canola (Brassica napusL.) ont des teneurs élevés en huile(&gt; 40%), la plus basse concentration en graisses saturées (6,8%) parmi les huiles végétales et une faible teneur en acide érucique et en glucosinolates, ce qui les rend très précieux dans le secteur de la production des huiles végétales. La province de Québec, avec une faible production de l'huile de canola, a la capacité d'augmenter sa production et, effectivement, de renforcer l'agriculture provinciale. Cependant, les recommandations pour la fertilisation des plantes de canola pour la culture au Québec ne sont pas bien définies; il y a un manque d'information concernant la réponse de canola à l'azote (N), le soufre(S) et le bore (B). Les études menées en 2011 et 2012 ont déterminé le taux et la saison idéals pour les additions de l'engrais enrichi avec de l'azote et, en plus, le taux optimal pour le soufre et le bore au Québec. En 2011, les combinaisons factorielles de quatre niveaux deN [0, 50, 100 (ou 50 + 50) et 150 (ou 50 + 100) kgha-1], deux niveaux de S (0 à 20 kg ha-1), et trois niveaux de B (0, 0,5 pulvérisation foliaire au stade de la floraison de 20% et de 2kg ha-1 appliqué au sol avant les semailles) ont été testées. Des doses uniques de la fertilisation d'azote (50, 100, 150 kg ha) ont tous été appliqués avant les semailles. En même temps, la fertilisation d'azote a également été évaluée à deux niveaux: 100 kg ha-1 (50 + 50 kg ha-1) et 150 kg ha-1 (50 + 100 kg ha), où la première dose de 50kg N ha-1 a été appliqué avant les semailles, et le reste a été appliqué au stade de 3-4 feuilles. En 2012, deux traitements supplémentaires ont été ajoutés : le premier a été 20 kg S ha, 0,5 kg B kg ha-1 et 200 N ha-1, et l'autre a été 20 kg S ha-1, 0,5 kg de B ha-1 et 50+ 150 kg N ha-1. En 2011, la fertilisation d'azote a montré des effets positifs sur la biomasse sèche, la surface foliaire, la hauteur des plantes, des graines par silique, l'indice de récolte, le rendement et la teneur en protéines des graines, mais a eu un effet négatif sur la teneur en huile des graines. Le taux optimum de  Na été 150kg N ha-1, entraînant le rendement grainier élevé et une bonne qualité des semences. En 2012, le canola n'a pas bien répondu aux ajouts d'engrais comme cela a été en 2011, apparemment, en raison de la baisse des densités de plantation. L'application des engrais azotés a augmenté seulement les poids de 1000 graines, l'indice de récolte, la teneur en huile des graines et la teneur en protéines des graines. Parmi les quatre blocs dans l'expérience de 2012, le bloc # 4 a eu seulement une densité de population de plantes relativement élevée par rapport de la moyenne. Pour le bloc #4 les données de rendement était curviligne et corrélées positivement avec le taux de N (R ² =0,5702, p &lt;0,0001), avec un rendement maximal se produisant à 150kg N ha-1. La croissance du canola n'a pas été souvent affectée par le temps d'application N. En 2011, il y avait une interaction de S x B pour un poids de 1000 graines en ce que l'effet a été positif avec une application foliaire de 0,5 B kg ha-1 et négative lorsque 2 kg B ha-1a été appliqué sur le sol. Seul le bore a augmenté le poids de 1000 graines en 2012. Nos résultats indiquent que les niveaux S et B dans les sols utilisés étaient probablement suffisants pour la production de canola. La hauteur de la plante a été diminuée (2,9%) après l'application de S à 20k g ha-1 en 2011. En conclusion, nos données suggèrent que le meilleur régime d'application de N pour la production de canola au Québec est une seule application à 150 kg N ha-1, ce qui a produit le rendement grainier élevé sans sacrifice de la qualité des semences. Possiblement, les additions du soufre et du bore ne sont pas requises pour la production de canola au Québec.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Donald L. Smith</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558h45f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wg98h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04ds80x"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The power spectrum of cosmic microwave background polarization from cosmic string wakes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Salton, Grant</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We compute the integrated Sachs--Wolfe type contribution to the CMB polarization power spectrum from cosmic string wakes. An introduction to topological defects, cosmic strings, CMB polarization, and spin-s fields is given. We then use these tools to compute the angular power spectrum of E- and B-mode polarization due to cosmic string wakes, in the flat sky limit. We find that cross-correlation terms (i.e.,  EB, ET, BT) vanish, while the EE and BB power spectra are equal in shape and magnitude. This result is in stark contrast with B-mode polarization from Gaussian fluctuations, which vanishes identically.  However, we find that the shape of the power spectrum from cosmic string wakes is very similar to the predicted B-mode power spectrum from gravitational lensing, but with a small overall amplitude.  As such, the cosmic string wake signal is too small to be picked out from lensing, and background subtraction techniques would be very difficult.  We find that the peak amplitude in the dimensionless power spectrum (sqrt(l(l+1)C_l/2pi)) is about 10^(-4) at a peak value of l~400.We briefly study the asymptotic version of the power spectrum and find that C_l is approximately constant until a turn around point set by the angular size of the dominant wakes.  We then determine which cosmic string wakes give rise to the dominant contribution to the full, integrated power spectrum and find that the dominant wakes are those which were formed at the time of equal matter and radiation, and which intersect our past light cone at recombination. We conclude that the Fourier space signal (power spectrum) is too weak to detect cosmic string wakes in existing data, and future searches should focus on distinct position space features.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Nous calculons la contribution intégrée au spectre de puissance de la polarisation du fond diffus cosmique (CMB) grâce aux sillages des cordes cosmiques. Une introduction aux défauts topologique, cordes cosmiques, de polarisation du CMB, et aux champs spin–s est donnée. Nous utilisons ensuite ces outils pour calculer le spectre de puissance angulaire de la polarisation des modes E et B grâce aux des sillages des cordes cosmiques, dans la limite du ciel plat. Nous trouvons que les termes de corrélation croisée (EB, ET, BT) sont zero,  tandis que les spectres de puissance pour EE et BB ont la même forme et grandeur. Ce résultat contraste le polarisation du mode B causée par les fluctuations Gaussiennes, qui disparaîssent. Cependant, nous trouvons que la forme du spectre de puissance causée par les sillages de cordes cosmiques est très similaire au spectre en mode B prédite par lentille gravitationnelle, mais avec une amplitude globale trés faible. Donc, le signal du sillage de corde cosmique est trop faible pour être measuré au-dessus l'indicatif du lentille. Aussi, les méthodes de soustraction du fond serait très difficile. Nous trouvons que l'amplitude maximum dans le spectre de puissance sqrt(l(l+1)C_l/2pi) est d'environ 10^(-4) pour l~400.Nous étudions brièvement le forme asymptotique du spectre de puissance, et nous trouvons que Cl est quasi–constant en l jusqu'à un tournant correspondant à la taille angulaire du sillage le plus important. Nous déterminons alors quel sillage donne la contribution dominante au spectre de puissance complet. Nous trouvons que les sillages dominants sont ceux qui ont été formés à l'epoque de l'égalité de matière et de rayonnement, et qui croisent notre cône de lumière passé à l'époque de recombinaison. Nous concluons que l'indicatif dans l'espace Fourier est trop faible pour être détecté. Donc, les recherches futures devraient se concentrer sur les caractéristiques l'espace spatial.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Patrick Hayden</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Robert Brandenberger</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418r584.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04ds80x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rh639"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Medical Physics Unit</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigation of Cherenkov emission with applications in dosimetry, image guidance and intensity modulation in radiation therapy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zlateva, Yana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les objectifs de cette étude sont de valider la potentielle application de l'émission Cherenkov (EC) pour la dosimétrie en radiothérapie, pour l'imagerie en temps réel et pour la modulation des faisceaux par l'analyse de sa corrélation avec la dose de rayonnement et par un décalage spectral vers la fenêtre infrarouge proche (FIP) des tissus biologiques afin de maximiser sa détection. Ce travail apporte une contribution originale aux travaux antérieurs en corrélant efficacement, d'une part, la dose de rayonnement et l'EC en 2 dimensions à l'aide d'une fibre optique et d'un spectromètre à réseau, et ce, sans l'aide d'un facteur de conversion variant spatialement et généré par ordinateur ou d'un colorant fluorescent, et d'autre part, en effectuant avec succès le déplacement de l'EC à la FIP dans un fantôme simulant les tissus biologiques grâce à l'utilisation de points quantiques (PQs).La dose de rayonnement a été corrélée avec l'EC à la fois par simulation informatique et par mesures expérimentales. Un simulateur Monte Carlo (MC) de l'EC a été conçu en utilisant la plateforme de simulation Geant4. Les fantômes utilisés dans les expériences consistaient d'un réservoir d'eau et d'un fantôme simulant les tissus biologiques composés d'eau, d'Intralipid® et de sang de boeuf. Le système de détection optique est composé d'un câble de fibre optique multi-mode à saut d'indice, placé hors du faisceau d'électron et relié à un spectromètre à réseau de diffraction à canal unique comprenant un dispositif à couplage de charge éclairé par l'avant ou l'arrière. Des points quantiques CdSe/ZnS, émettant à (650 ± 10) nm, ont été utilisés afin de réaliser un décalage de l'EC vers la FIP.Une analyse préliminaire a indiqué une forte corrélation entre la dose de rayonnement et de l'EC avec un coefficient de corrélation de Pearson supérieur à 0.99. La corrélation de la dose en fonction de l'EC a été étudiée via des scans de la chambre d'ionisation dans le fantôme d'eau le long de l'axe central du faisceau ainsi que par des scans de fibre optique avec la pointe de la fibre positionnée sur le bord du champ du faisceau. Après normalisation, le point effectif de mesure du système optique des faisceaux d'électrons cliniques de 18, 12 et 6 MeV, s'est révélé être situé à des profondeurs respectives de 1.7 cm, 0.8 cm et 0.1 cm, et ce, en aval de l'axe de la fibre, avec un coefficient de corrélation Pearson pour toutes les données de plus de 0.99. La fenêtre d'EC d'un faisceau d'électrons de 18 MeV a été décalée avec succès vers 650 nm dans le réservoir d'eau, confirmant sa capacité à stimuler la photoluminescence de CdSe/ZnS, et dans le fantôme simulant les tissus biologiques. La diminution de la taille des champs ainsi que l'augmentation de la profondeur des PQs ont eu pour effet de diminuer le signal, quoiqu'un décalage du signal était encore apparent à 1 cm de profondeur. L'analyse statistique des données nous a confirmé que le bruit n'a pas d'impact significatif sur le signal, mais que le rayonnement peut avoir un impact sur les composantes électroniques du spectromètre.Les résultats de ce travail confirment le potentiel d'application de l'EC pour la dosimétrie en radiothérapie, pour l'imagerie en temps réel et pour la modulation d'intensité des faisceaux en fonction des informations relatives au microenvironnement des tumeurs, comme l'oxygénation. En effet, l'EC est intrinsèque au faisceau d'électrons, est non-ionisante et peut être détectée en dehors du faisceau. De plus, les PQs utilisés dans nos expériences sont photostables et peuvent être modifiés afin d'intégrer des molécules pouvant nous informer sur la microbiologie des tumeurs. Il est prévu que la technique proposée sera applicable à la cartographie de dose en 3D au moyen de la tomographie optique diffuse, à l'imagerie par EC en temps réel et la localisation spatiale durant la radiothérapie, ainsi qu'à la modulation du faisceau en fonction du microenvironnement de la tumeur.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The aims of this work are to validate the potential application of Cherenkov emission (CE) in radiotherapy dosimetry, online imaging and beam modulation by analysis of its correlation with radiation dose and by a spectral shift to the near-infrared (NIR) window of biological tissue in order to maximize its detection. This work makes an original contribution to scientific knowledge by effectively correlating radiation dose and CE in two dimensions, using an optical fiber and grating spectrometer, without need for a computer-generated spatially variant conversion factor or a fluorescent dye, and by successfully shifting CE to the NIR in a tissue-simulating phantom with the use of quantum dots (QDs).Radiation dose was correlated with CE via both computer simulation and experimental measurements using clinical 6-18 MeV electron beams. A Monte Carlo (MC) CE simulator was designed using the Geant4 simulation toolkit. In order to maximize the signal, beam incidence angle was optimized through simulation and experiment and the feasibility of two-fiber detection was assessed. Phantoms used in the experiments were a water tank and a tissue-simulating phantom composed of water, Intralipid® and beef blood. The optical detection system consisted of a multi-mode step-index fiber optic cable (numerical aperture = 0.22 for dose versus Cherenkov studies), positioned out of the beam and connected to a single-channel diffraction grating spectrometer incorporating a front- or back-illuminated charge-coupled device (CCD). A cylindrical ionization chamber was used for dose measurements. CdSe/ZnS core-shell QDs, emitting at (650 ± 10) nm, were used to achieve a NIR shift of the CE signal.A preliminary software analysis indicated a strong correlation between radiation dose and CE with a Pearson correlation coefficient larger than 0.99. A beam incidence angle of 50° relative to the surface normal produced a CE maximum along the horizontal fiber. An angle of 47° (corresponding to more than 80% of the maximum signal) was adopted in order to maximize the scan depth by avoiding beam perturbation due to setup components and fiber protrusion into the field. Dose versus CE correlation was investigated via water phantom ion chamber scans along the beam central axis and optical fiber scans with the fiber tip positioned at the field edge. With all data sets normalized to 1, the effective point of measurement of the optical system for 18, 12 and 6 MeV clinical electron beams was found to be at depths of approximately 1.7, 0.8, and 0.1 cm, respectively, downstream from the fiber axis, with a Pearson correlation coefficient for all (simulated and experimental) data larger than 0.99. CE by an 18 MeV electron beam was successfully shifted towards 650 nm in water and in a tissue-simulating phantom. Smaller field sizes and larger QD depths resulted in a lower signal, though a shift was still apparent for a 1 cm depth of the QDs. Statistical data analysis indicated no noise bias and that radiation might have impacted the spectrometer electronics.The results of this work validate the potential for application of CE in radiotherapy dosimetry, online imaging and intensity modulation based on tumor microenvironment information, such as oxygenation, since CE is intrinsic to the beam, non-ionizing and can be detected outside the beam, and the QDs used for the experiments are photostable, tunable, and can be modified to incorporate molecular reporters. Future work involves the use of a multi-channel spectrometer for simultaneous collection of main, reference and background signals, incorporation of a lens or a single-mode fiber to reduce the sensitive volume, as well as development of better spectral data extraction techniques. It is expected that the proposed technique will be applicable to 3D dose mapping by means of diffuse optical tomography, online CE imaging and localization during radiotherapy, and beam modulation based on tumor microenvironment information.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Issam El Naqa</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021j35k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rh639</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Radiation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr172146h"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electrical transport, filtering and NMR of GaAs/AlGaAs quantum wires</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Evert, Abraham</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'étude des électrons dans de faibles dimensions est un domaine qui a donné un aperçu incroyable dans les dernières décennies du Effet Hall quantique fractionnaire de Wigner cristallisation . Au cours des dernières années, l'intérêt s'est développé à partir de l'étude de la physique fondamentale des deux conducteurs dimensions à l'ingénierie expérimentale nouveaux Etats à l'aide de techniques de la nanotechnologie . Nous avons maintenant la possibilité de créer de haute qualité et un zéro dispositifs dimensions , c'est- fils quantiques et boîtes quantiques . A des températures très basses , la physique quantique domine le comportement de ces dispositifs provoquant de nouvelles propriétés émergent , en raison des interactions entre électrons améliorées , les interactions spin-orbite et de nombreux autres effets. Ces nouvelles propriétés sont le résultat de l'interaction des ensembles de particules quantiques et ne peuvent être compris par intuition classique. Non seulement la nouvelle physique y passionnants à découvrir à basse dimensions , mais il ya des applications prometteuses à l'horizon.Les électrons contraints à une dimension sont prévus pour entrer dans un état connu comme le liquide de Luttinger . Bien qu'il existe des preuves solides pour l'observation du liquide de Luttinger déjà , il est encore un domaine d'étude très active. En outre, il a été prévu que les interactions entre les spins nucléaires hélice commandés en GaAs et un état liquide de Luttinger pourraient se traduit par un effet de rétroaction des spins nucléaires qui se traduiraient par des observations expérimentales distinctes. Non seulement cet état de fournir des preuves claires de comportement de type liquide de Luttinger , mais il a le potentiel pour soutenir convoités fermions de Majorana qui ont des applications dans le traitement de l'information quantique. Ce projet consistait en la fabrication de GaAs / AlGaAs quantum fils échantillons en collaboration avec Sandia National Laboratories avec des paramètres tels que la longueur et le bien- profondeur variable. Nous avons ensuite effectué des mesures détaillées de transport électronique à basse température pour identifier les échantillons de fils quantiques prometteurs. Bonne échantillons ont été refroidis à la suite de 300   mK   où on a observé une certaine quantification de la conductance . Il a été déterminé que, pour atteindre des températures inférieures électroniques , le filtrage est nécessaire. À cette fin , à basse température filtrées porte-échantillons ont été conçus, construits et caractérisé. Les porte-échantillons filtrés ont donné lieu à des observations supérieures aux échantillons non filtrés , ce qui reflète probablement une température d'électrons inférieure. Grâce à notre meilleur échantillon de filtres , puis nous avons effectué des expériences de résonance magnétique nucléaire résistivement - détectés , sonder l'interaction entre les électrons et les spins nucléaires dans les fils quantiques. Alors que l'état prédit n'a pas été observée , les bases d' une telle expérience est complète et sa s'attend à ce qu'un échantillon suffisamment haute qualité affichera le comportement de signature avec la méthodologie actuelle .</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The study of electrons in low dimensions is a field which has yielded incredible insights in the past decades from the Fractional Quantum Hall Effect to Wigner Crystallization. In recent years, interest has grown from studying the fundamental physics of two dimensional conductors to engineering experimental new states using nanotechnology techniques. We now have the capability to create high quality one and zero dimensional devices, that is, quantum wires and quantum dots. At very low temperatures, quantum physics dominates the behavior of these devices causing new properties to emerge, due to enhanced electron-electron interactions, spin-orbit interactions and many other effects. These new properties are the result of the interaction of ensembles of quantum particles and cannot be understood by classical intuition. Not only are there exciting new physics to be discovered at low dimensions, but there are promising applications on the horizon.Electrons constrained to one dimension are predicted to enter a state known as the Luttinger liquid. While there exists strong evidence for the observation of the Luttinger liquid already, it is still an area of highly active study. Furthermore, it has been predicted that interactions between helically ordered nuclear spins in GaAs and a Luttinger liquid state could results in a nuclear spin feedback effect which would result in distinct experimental observations. Not only would this state provide clear evidence of Luttinger liquid behavior, but it has potential to support sought-after Majorana fermions which have applications in quantum information processing.This project consisted of the fabrication of GaAs/AlGaAs quantum wires samples in collaboration with Sandia National Laboratories with varying parameters such as length and well-depth. We then performed detailed electronic transport measurements at low temperature to identify promising quantum wire samples. Good samples were cooled further to 300  mK  where some quantization of conductance was observed. It was determined that to reach lower electronic temperatures, filtering was required. To this end, low temperature filtered samples holders were designed, constructed and characterized. The filtered sample holders resulted in superior observations to unfiltered samples, likely reflecting a lower electron temperature. Using our best sample with filters, we then performed resistively-detected nuclear magnetic resonance experiments, probing the interaction between the electrons and the nuclear spins in quantum wires. While the predicted state was not observed, the groundwork for such an experiment is complete and its expected that a sufficiently high quality sample will display the signature behavior with current methodology. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Guillaume Gervais</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wr095.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172146h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Solid State</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd3760949"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"Merely going round": engaging with poetic thought through play in Wallace Steven's poetry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Belzil, Diane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La thèse suivante examine l'importance du jeu dans la poésie de Wallace Stevens et comment il révèle une isométrie structurelle entre sa poétique et l'éthique philosophique d'Immanuel Kant, Hans-Georg Gadamer, et Emmanuel Levinas. Cette comparaison démontre que Stevens n'est pas concernée par les concepts philosophique «le bien» ou «la vérité», mais essai plutôt de déterminer la condition ontologique de la pensée poétique, ce qu'il fait en écrivant de la poésie qui tend vers la fiction dominante de son âge; la Fiction Suprême. Cette thèse est divisée en trois étapes, chacune visant à démontrer l'importance du changement, l'abstraction et le plaisir (les trois termes dans la poème de Stevens Notes Toward a Supreme Fiction) pour déterminer comment les jeux de Stevens fonctionnent. Le premier chapitre identifie un topos observé tout au long de la carrière de Stevens dans lequel les poèmes sont abstrait de la réalité extrapoetic, les situant dans un espace séparé de la pensée, un espae de jeu. Le deuxième chapitre examine de plus près à cet espace de jeu et les métaphores de l'habitation, des saisons et du climat que Stevens utilise pour le décrire. Tout comme les théories de Kant et de Lévinas nécessitent une mise en forme métaphysique, la poésie de Stevens sec localise dans un domaine séparé, la pensée poétique. Le troisième chapitre fait une étude diachronique des considérations de la pensée poétique comme un domaine distinct de Stevens, faisant un usage particulier de la critique de l'éthique de Jacques Rancière pour démontrer que la poésie de Stevens est en mesure d'éviter le tournant éthique à travers son propre tournant poétique.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The following thesis examines the importance of play in Wallace Stevens's poetry and how it reveals a structural isometry between Stevens's poetics and the philosophical ethics of Immanuel Kant, Hans-Georg Gadamer, and Emmanuel Levinas. This comparison demonstrates that Stevens is not concerned with writing toward the philosophical concepts of 'good' or 'truth,' but rather with determining the ontological condition of poetic thought, which he does by writing poetry that reaches toward the guiding fiction of his age, the Supreme Fiction. This study is conducted in three stages, each aiming to demonstrate the importance of change, abstraction, and pleasure (the three key terms in Stevens's Notes Toward a Supreme Fiction) in determining how Stevensian play operates. The first chapter identifies a turning topos operating throughout Stevens's career in which poems are abstracted from extrapoetic reality by locating them in a separate space of thought, a play space. The second chapter looks more closely at this play space and the metaphors of dwelling, seasons, and climate that Stevens uses to describe it, arguing that the seasons' relationship to climate and climate's relationship to the Supreme Fiction finds a structural correlative in the ethical theories of Kant and Levinas. Much as Kant and Levinas's theories require a metaphysical grounding, Stevens's poetry is grounded by locating itself in a separate realm, poetic thought. The third chapter makes a diachronic study of Stevens's considerations of poetic thought as a separate realm, making particular use of Jacques Rancière's critique of ethics to demonstrate that Stevens's poetry is able to avoid the ethical turn through its own poetic turn. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Miranda Brun Hickman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150n27n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd3760949</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - American</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698b96q"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Efficient imitation learning and inverse reinforcement learning with application to navigation in human environments</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kim, Beomjoon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une compétence essentielle au bon fonctionnement des robots mobiles est la capacité à naviguer efficacement dans leur environnement. Ainsi, pour les robots sociaux ou d'assistance, il est essentiel de pouvoir naviguer parmi des foules humaines. Les critres de performance typiques, tels qu'atteindre un endroit ciblé par le chemin le plus court, ne sont pas appropriés dans de tels environnements, où il est plutôt important de se déplacer d'une manire socialement adaptée en respectant, par exemple, les zones de confort des piétons. Cette thèse examine un système d'apprentissage par démonstration ayant pour but de résoudre le problème de planification de trajectoire adaptée à un environment humain. L'apprentissage par démonstration est un cadre pratique permettant l'acquisition de controlleurs complexes en utilisant des trajectoires de démonstration provenant d'un expert. Nous proposons deux approches basées sur l'apprentissage par démonstration. La première approche est basée sur l'apprentissage par renforcement inverse, dans lequel nous représentons de façon compacte les comportements de planification de trajectoire socialement adaptative en fonction des cots appris. La deuxième approche est fondée sur l'apprentissage par imitation, où nous utilisons l'apprentissage supervisé pour aquérir ces comportements, et fournissons subséquemment des garanties théoriques sur sa performance. Nous évaluons notre approche en la déployant sur un véritable fauteuil roulant robotisé dans différents scénarios et la comparons à des trajectoires humaines.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A key skill for mobile robots is the ability to navigate efficiently through their environment. In the case of social or assistive robots, this involves navigating through human crowds. Typical performance criteria, such as reaching the goal using the shortest path, are not appropriate in such environments, where it is more important for the robot to move in a socially adaptive manner such as respecting comfort zones of the pedestrians. This thesis investigates the Learning from Demonstration framework to address the socially adaptive path planning problem. Learning from Demonstration is a practical framework for learning complex policies using demonstration trajectories produced by an expert. We propose two approaches based on Learning from Demonstrations. First approach is based on Inverse Reinforcement Learning, in which we compactly represent the socially adaptive path planning behaviours as a cost function that we learn. The second approach is based on imitation learning, in which we use supervised learning to learn such behaviours, and then provide theoretical guarantees on its performance. We evaluate our approach by deploying it on a real robotic wheelchair platform in various scenarios, and comparing the robot trajectories to human trajectories.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Joelle Pineau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rc22g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698b96q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rx854"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La divergence des politiques nationales Scandinaves en matière de migration irréguliére: comparisons et facteurs explicatifs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Naud-Arcand, Constance</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ten years after the entry into force of the Maastricht Treaty, why the governments of countries sharing many similarities, particularly in regard to geography, history, culture, economic and political development, why such governments continue to formulate and implement diverging policies on irregular migration? This is the question under scrutiny in this thesis. Through the comparison of the three Scandinavian countries over the last thirty years, we argue that variations in public opinion towards migration as well as variations in the influence of Scandinavian domestic interest groups working on migration issues led to variations in the political influence of right-wing Scandinavian national parties, which, in turn, contributed to the divergence of Scandinavian national policies on irregular migration. By targeting three understudied cases whose migration situation has recently evolved significantly, we attempt to fill a gap in the current literature. In addition to raising questions about the viability of an ever growing European Union, our results identify paths for reflection for those who wish to influence the policymaking process.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dix ans après l'entrée en vigueur du traité de Maastricht, pourquoi les gouvernements de pays partageant plusieurs similitudes, notamment en ce qui a trait à la géographie, à l'histoire, à la culture, au développement économique et même au système politique, pourquoi, donc, de tels gouvernements continuent-ils à mettre en œuvre des politiques divergentes en matière de migration irrégulière? Voilà la problématique étudiée dans le cadre de ce mémoire. En comparant les États scandinaves au cours des quelque trente dernières années, nous arguons que des variations tant de l'opinion publique en matière de migration que de l'influence des groupes d'intérêt nationaux scandinaves dont le champ d'action est lié aux migrants ont mené à des variations du poids politique des partis nationaux scandinaves d'extrême-droite, variations qui expliquent, quant à elles, la divergence observée au niveau des politiques nationales scandinaves en matière de migration irrégulière. En ciblant les trois États scandinaves, qui ont fait l'objet de très peu de comparaisons systématiques en matière de migration, et ce, même si leur situation migratoire a grandement évolué, nous tentons de combler une lacune dans la littérature à cet égard. En plus de soulever des interrogations quant à la viabilité d'une Union européenne sans cesse élargie, les résultats offrent des pistes de réflexion aux personnes souhaitant influencer les prises de décision politiques.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rex J. Brynen</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Antonia Maioni</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g585z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rx854</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0v838382f"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le sujet du poème dans «Cap au pire» de Samuel Beckett: suivi du récit Tombeau</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lorrain, Félix-Antoine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This Master's thesis consists of three sections. First, it examines the question of the subject in Samuel Beckett's work through a close reading of Cap au pire, the French translation of Worstward Ho, showing that beyond its endeavour towards a mere nothing or a transcendent being, the poem as artwork creates its own reality in engaging a subjectivity through its enunciation. A second short section presents the creative writing section and addresses its relations with the critique section on the postulate that the artwork is conditioned by its enunciation thus its subject. The last section of the thesis proposes a mourning account in which a speaker trying to relieve himself from his sorrow through the process of writing reconstructs in his discourse the fragmented memory of the disease, agony and death of his sister and his own evolution towards it.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire est composé de trois parties. Il propose dans un premier temps une critique du sujet chez Samuel Beckett à partir d'une lecture rapprochée de Cap au pire, montrant qu'au-delà d'une tentative d'atteindre un rien immanent ou un être transcendant, le poème fabrique sa réalité propre en engageant à même son énonciation un processus de subjectivation. Une deuxième courte section présente la partie création en abordant quelques-unes de ses relations avec la partie critique à partir du postulat que l'énonciation, donc le sujet, conditionne l'œuvre. La dernière partie du mémoire est composée d'un récit de deuil dans lequel un sujet cherchant à se délester de ses « maux » par l'écriture reconstitue dans son discours la mémoire fragmentée de la maladie, de l'agonie et de la mort de sa sœur et de sa propre évolution vis-à-vis de celle-ci.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alain Farah</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913t12z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838382f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Modern</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atm70mz825"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Online time-dependent clustering with applications to distributed social networks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Renard, Benjamin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cluster analysis can be defined as the study of algorithms and methods that aim at organizing data into meaningful groups in an unsupervised fashion. These algorithms are essential to understand specific sets of data and the relations between items inside these sets, and are used in many scientific fields (e.g., computer vision, biology, economics). If the data evolves over time, we need specific algorithms to represent the evolution of the clustering of the dataset over time. An additional complication arises when we do not have the entire dataset at once but instead receive elements one by one, e.g., in the case of data streams, but always want to obtain an up-to-date clustering of the data. This thesis aims at providing an analysis of online time-dependent clustering algorithms that fulfill the requirements aforementioned.We present here an algorithm that combines both the online and time-dependent requirement, while also solving the challenges brought by data streams. One of the main challenges of a data stream setting is to keep the computational resources bounded as the number of processed items increases. Our algorithm combines a Dirichlet process-based generative model with a Sequential Monte Carlo (SMC) sampler for posterior inference. We also provide an enhancement, called targeted resampling, that improves the performance of existing SMC samplers. We test our algorithm on synthetic and real-world datasets with two different applications in mind. The first one is the real-time clustering of search engine queries, which we use to improve search in distributed social networks. The second one focuses on clustering titles of scientific or news articles, which can be used to provide real-time news aggregation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'analyse des regroupements statistiques peut être définie comme l'étude des algorithmes et des méthodes qui visent à organiser, de façon non supervisée, des ensembles d'objets en groupes significatifs. Ces algorithmes sont essentiels à la compréhension de certains ensembles de données et des relations qui existent entre leurs différents éléments. C'est pour cela qu'ils sont utilisés dans de nombreux domaines scientifiques (e.g., vision, biologie, économie). Si les données évoluent au cours du temps, nous voulons être en mesure de pouvoir représenter l'évolution des regroupements au cours du temps. Des complications supplémentaires apparaissent lorsque nous n'avons pas accès à la totalité des données mais que nous recevons les éléments un par un tout en souhaitant obtenir un regroupement à jour à chaque instant. Cette thèse cherche à créer un algorithme de regroupement en temps réel qui dépends des données temporelles des différents éléments.Nous présentons ici un algorithme qui combine ces deux spécifications, tout en résolvant les difficultés apportées par la configuration où les données arrivent en flux continu. La principale difficultée apportée par cette configuration est de devoir borner l'utilisation des ressources (mémoire et temps de calcul) quand le nombre d'éléments à traiter augmente. Notre algorithme combine un modèle génératif basé sur les processus de Dirichlet avec un échantillonneur de Monte Carlo Séquentiel (MCS) pour l'inférence des probabilités postérieures. Nous introduisons aussi une amélioration, nommée Echantillonnage Ciblé, qui améliore la performance des actuels échantillonneurs MCS. Nous testons notre algorithme sur des bases de données réelles et simulées pour deux types d'applications. La première consiste à regrouper en temps réel des requêtes faites à un moteur de recherche, ce que nous appliquons à l'amélioration de la recherche dans les réseaux sociaux distribués. La seconde application consiste à regrouper des titres d'articles de journaux ou de revues scientifique, ce qui peut servir à fournir un aggrégateur d'informations en temps réel.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mark Coates</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>George Kesidis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892f28p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mz825</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aff3658442"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A flexible tool for the visualization and manipulation of musical mapping networks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Krajeski, Aaron</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La plupart des instruments de musique numériques (IMN) assemble les données gestuelles des musiciens par des capteurs électroniques et transforme ces données en son à travers de programmes de synthèse séparés. Le mappage d'entrées de commandes aux paramètres de synthèse est arbitraire, à multiples facettes et extrêmement important pour l'efficacité des IMN. Les outils logiciels existent pour aider ce processus et tentent de rendre la tâche du mappage musical plus transparente, rapide et configurable. Cette thése présente MapperGUI, un outil graphique multiplateforme pour la manipulation des réseaux de mappage musicaux.La bibliothèque logiciel libmapper, développée au Input Devices and Music Interaction Laboratory, crée un cadre standard pour que les IMN communiquent les données sur un réseau réparti et map leurs signaux en collaboration en temps réel. MapperGUI présente une interface utilisateur pour les réseaux libmapper, ce qui permet aux utilisateurs non-experts de manipuler ce système textuel. L'interface a pour but d'être flexible, en sorte qu'elle puisse accommoder la vaste gamme de réseaux et de tâches musicales qui doivent être complétées en mappant. À cette fin, elle offre plusieurs visualisations et modes d'interactions indépendantes à l'intérieur d'un seul cadre.    Ce document porte sur quelques un des enjeux qui affrontent le domaine du mappage musical et décrit les motivations qui sous-tendent le projet MapperGUI dans ce contexte. De la recherche pertinente dans les domaines de la visualisation des données et la conception d'interface sont résumées et appliquées à la tâche de créer une interface d'utilisateur graphique pour les réseaux de libmapper. Des interfaces graphiques précédentes pour libmapper sont examinées pour leurs caractéristiques réussies qui peuvent être incorporées à MapperGUI. Des difficultés de mise en oeuvre précises et des caractéristiques du programme final sont décrites. Les connaissances tirées d'entrevues avec des utilisateurs de MapperGUI sont présentées, ainsi que des travaux futurs et des extensions possibles pour l'interface.MapperGUI est disponible pour téléchargement gratuit en tant qu'application autonome à www.libmapper.org/downloads. Tout le code est code source libre et peut être accédé à https://github.com/mysteryDate/webmapper.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Most digital musical instruments (DMIs) gather gestural input from musicians by way of electronic sensors and transform these data into sound through separate synthesis engines. The mapping of control inputs to synthesis parameters is arbitrary, multi-faceted and extremely important for the effectiveness of DMIs. Software tools exist to aid in this process and attempt to render the task of musical mapping more transparent, swift and configurable. This thesis presents MapperGUI, a cross-platform graphical tool for the manipulation of musical mapping networks. The libmapper software library, developed at the Input Devices and Music Interaction Laboratory, creates a standard framework for DMIs to communicate data on a distributed network and map their signals collaboratively in real-time. MapperGUI presents a graphical user interface for libmapper networks, allowing non-expert users to manipulate the text-based system. The interface aims to be flexible, such that it can accommodate the vast array of musical networks and tasks that must be performed when mapping. To this end, it provides multiple independent visualizations and interaction modes within a single framework. This document explores some of the issues challenging the field of musical mapping and describes the motivations behind the MapperGUI project in this context. Relevant research in the fields of data visualization and interface design is summarized and applied to the task of creating a graphical user interface for libmapper networks. Prior graphical interfaces for libmapper are examined for successful features that can be incorporated into MapperGUI. Specific implementation challenges and features of the final program are described. Insight gained from interviews with users of MapperGUI is presented, along with future work and possible extensions for the interface.MapperGUI is available for free download as a standalone application at www.libmapper.org/downloads. All code is open-source and can be accessed at https://github.com/mysteryDate/webmapper.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marcelo Wanderley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gx00q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff3658442</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237hv881"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Parent and peer attachment relationships and non-suicidal self-injury in young adolescents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Joly, Melanie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'automutilation non-suicidaire est définie comme étant une altération consciente, intentionnelle, et directe des tissus de l'organisme sans intention suicidaire et exclut tous comportements socialement acceptés ou à des fins esthétiques, tels que les tatouages et les perçages (Favazza, 1998). La fréquence élevée d'automutilation non-suicidaire chez les adolescents et jeunes adultes a incité les chercheurs à explorer les raisons occasionnant ce comportement. Alors qu'un important corpus de recherche a documenté le rôle de la régularisation des émotions dans les comportements d'automutilation, les fonctions sociales n'ont pas été autant étudiées et requièrent une attention supplémentaire (Muehlenkamp, Brausch, Quigley, &amp; Whitlock, 2013). Des chercheurs ont fourni des preuves constantes que les problèmes familiaux sont associés aux comportements d'automutilation. Ceci dit, la plupart ont utilisé un indice combiné pour mesurer la qualité de la relation d'attachement parentale (p.ex., Gratz, Conrad, &amp; Roemer, 2002; Hilt, Nock, Lloyd-Richardson, &amp; Prinstein, 2008a). Tel que proposé par Parkes et Stevenson-Hinde (1982), l'attachement est un concept complexe constitué de dimensions comportementales et cognitives/affectives. Ainsi, il s'avère nécessaire d'étudier les dimensions (p.ex., confiance, communication, aliénation) contribuant le plus aux comportements d'automutilation. Une seule étude à ce jour a examiné l'influence de plusieurs dimensions d'attachement sur l'automutilation des jeunes adultes (Bureau et coll., 2010), mais ceci n'a jamais été étudié chez les jeunes adolescents. En tenant compte du fait que l'automutilation fait généralement son apparition en début d'adolescence (Nock, 2009) et que les jeunes sont de plus en plus influencés par leurs paires suite à la transition au secondaire (Allen &amp; Land, 1999), des recherches additionnelles doivent être menées afin d'examiner le lien entre les dimensions d'attachement (parents et paires) et les comportements d'automutilation chez les jeunes adolescents. Afin de combler cette lacune, les objectifs de cette recherche étaient a) d'examiner les dimensions d'attachement (parents et paires) en fonction du groupe (NSSI versus Comparaison) et du sexe des participants; b) d'explorer une interaction entre l'automutilation et le genre; et c) d'investiguer la contribution relative de l'attachement parentale et de l'attachement avec les paires aux comportements d'automutilation. Les participants étaient 65 jeunes adolescents (M âge = 12.37, SD = .52; 57% de filles) qui reportent s'être automutilés et un groupe de comparaison sélectionné selon le sexe et l'école secondaire fréquenté. Les participants ont remplis les questionnaires How I Deal with Stress (HIDS; Heath &amp; Ross, 2007) afin d'identifier la présence d'automutilation non-suicidaire et The Inventory of Parent and Peer Attachment (IPPA; Armsden &amp; Greenberg, 1987) pour examiner trois dimensions d'attachement (confiance, communication, aliénation). Ces questionnaires d'autoévaluation étaient remplis en groupe de 20 étudiants pendant les cours et dans leur classe respective. Les résultats indiquent que les jeunes adolescents qui s'automutilent perçoivent plus négativement leurs relations avec leurs parents et leurs paires au niveau de toutes les dimensions d'attachement comparativement à ceux qui ne s'automutilent pas. De plus, l'attachement parental semble être un meilleur indicateur du statut d'automutilation que l'attachement avec les paires. En somme, cette étude est une contribution à la littérature sur l'automutilation non-suicidaire puisque les résultats raffinent notre savoir sur la relation entre les dimensions d'attachement et l'automutilation en début d'adolescence, et suggèrent que les filles et les garçons qui s'automutilent sont autant affectés par la qualité de la communication, la confiance et le sentiment d'aliénation avec leurs parents et leurs paires. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Non-suicidal self-injury (NSSI) is defined as the deliberate destruction of one's own body tissue without suicidal intent and for purposes not socially sanctioned, thus excluding tattooing and piercing (Favazza, 1998). The high prevalence rate in both clinical and community studies have prompted researchers to explore correlates associated with this behaviour. While a large body of research has documented the role of emotion regulation in NSSI, the social functions have not been as extensively studied and warrant further attention (Muehlenkamp, Brausch, Quigley, &amp; Whitlock, 2013). Scholars have provided consistent evidence that family relationship problems are associated with reports of NSSI. However, most used a composite score to measure the overall quality of attachment (e.g., Gratz, Conrad, &amp; Roemer, 2002; Hilt, Nock, Lloyd-Richardson, &amp; Prinstein, 2008a). As proposed by Parkes and Stevenson-Hinde (1982), attachment is a multifaceted concept comprised of behavioural and cognitive/affective domains. Accordingly, there is a need to further investigate which attachment dimensions (e.g., trust, communication, and alienation) are more predictive of NSSI status. Only one study to date has examined the contribution of several parent attachment dimensions to NSSI among college students (Bureau et al., 2010), but this has not been investigated among young adolescents. In the light of the fact that NSSI has its onset typically during the early teen years (Nock, 2009) and that peers are increasingly influential following the transition to high school (Allen &amp; Land, 1999), additional research examining the association between parent and peer attachment dimensions, and NSSI in early adolescence is needed. In order to address this research gap, the main objectives of the current study were a) to examine group (NSSI/ Non-NSSI) and gender differences in parent and peer attachment dimensions (i.e., trust, communication, and alienation); b) to explore a potential interaction between NSSI status and gender; and c) to investigate the relative contribution of parent attachment versus peer attachment to NSSI status. Participants were 65 adolescents (M age = 12.37, SD = .52; 57% female) who reported engaging in NSSI and a comparison group of adolescents matched on gender and school. Participants completed the How I Deal With Stress questionnaire (HIDS; Heath &amp; Ross, 2007) in order to screen for NSSI. They also completed the Inventory of Parent and Peer Attachment (IPPA; Armsden &amp; Greenberg, 1987) to examine three attachment dimensions (i.e., trust, communication, and alienation). These self-reported questionnaires were completed during class time in their school classrooms in small groups of 20. Results from a two-way MANOVA indicated that young adolescents who reported engaging in NSSI perceived their relationships with parents and peers more negatively on all attachment dimensions relative to their non-self-injuring counterparts. Furthermore, a logistic regression revealed that parent attachment was more predictive of NSSI status than peer attachment. Overall, this study represents a contribution to the NSSI literature as it extends our knowledge about the relationship between attachment dimensions and NSSI in early adolescence, and suggests that males and females who engage in NSSI are equally affected by quality of communication, the degree of trust, and alienation issues with parents and peers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nancy Lee Heath</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g5867.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hv881</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afb494c61g"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comparison of methodologies for induction motor design</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kibby, Devon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the last few decades, the world of electric machine design, specifically induction machine design, has been reinvigorated by the introduction of power electronics.  Where designers were once limited to a single alternating current waveform with constant voltage and frequency, power electronics have thrown all those assumptions out the window.  The change has necessitated new design methods that go beyond the typical induction motor electrical equivalent circuit seen in every textbook for the last century and have sent designers back to first principles. With that sentiment, early induction motor invention and improvements are explored. It is shown that even though the development and commercialization of the induction motor was quite rapid, the theory and understanding of the underlying physics kept pace.  Basic design methodologies and tools, including the Hopkinson magnetic circuit and the Steinmetz equivalent circuit, from the so-called "'Golden Age' of induction motor development" are traced forward through textbook examples to support the claim. Newer electric machine analyses are presented in the form of the modern treatment of the magnetic equivalent circuit, MEC, and the finite element method, FEM.  A derivation of the MEC element from the magnetic scalar potential is completed utilizing the theory of tubes and slices to give a more tangible justification to the field assumptions made.  The knowledge from these assumptions is then applied to the FEM to show how to construct an MEC element using the FEM.  Tellegen's theorem is applied to the MEC and a brief example given showing how one might compute the first-order sensitivity of a small change in stator windings in an induction motor to a small change in torque. A brief overview of the engineering design process is described with a focus on augmentation with computer aided design tools, CAD.  The equivalence shown between the MEC and FEM is used to support the idea that a FEM-based electric machine CAD package could be modified to utilize MEC assumptions or knowledge in order to reduce computation time when coarser models are favored, such as in the early design stages.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Depuis les dernières quelques décennies, l'industrie de la conception de la machine électrique, spécifiquement la conception de moteur à induction, a été revigoré par l'introduction des électroniques de puissance. Là ou les concepteurs étaient jadis limités à un courant alternatif avec fréquence et voltage constant, l'électronique de puissance est venue compliquer les lignes directrices de la conception. Ces changements ont nécessité des nouvelle méthodes qui vont au-delà du circuit équivalent typique mentionné dans tous les livres de référence depuis le dernier siècle et ont reporté les concepteurs aux principes de base. C'est à partir de cette complication que l'évolution du moteur à induction depuis son invention est revisitée. Il a été démontré que, malgré son développement et sa commercialisation notablement rapides, la théorie du moteur à induction et notre compréhension des principes physiques ont suivi le rythme. Les méthodologies de base et outils de conception provenant du soi-disant âge d'or du moteur à induction, notamment le circuit magnétique Hopkins et le circuit équivalent Steinmetz, sont retracés dans les exemples à travers les livres de référence pour supporter la thèse. L'analyse des machines électriques actuelles est présentée sous la forme du circuit magnétique équivalent (MEC) moderne et par le calcul par éléments finis (FEM). Une dérivation du MEC à partir du potentiel magnétique vectoriel est réalisée en utilisant la théorie des tubes et tranches pour justifier les hypothèses concernant les champs électromagnétiques. Par la suite, ces hypothèses sont appliquées au calcul FEM pour démontrer la création d'un MEC à partir du calcul FEM. Le théorème de Tellegen est appliqué au MEC et un exemple concret est élaboré pour démontrer comment calculer la sensibilité de premier ordre entre un petit changement dans le bobinage électrique du stator et un petit changement dans le couple.Un bref aperçu du procédé de conception est apporté avec un focus sur la contribution des logiciels de conception assistée par ordinateur (CAD). L'équivalence démontrée entre la méthode du MEC et celle par le calcul FEM est utilisée pour soutenir l'idée que les logiciels CAD basés sur le calcul FEM pourraient être modifiés pour inclure les hypothèses apportées par le MEC dans le but d'économiser le temps de calcul lorsque, durant les étapes préliminaires de la conception, un modèle simple suffirait.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David Alister Lowther</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010t330.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494c61g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010t348"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An exploration of complex matrix factorization as a tool for single-channel musical source separation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bronson, James</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Depuis l'introduction de la factorisation en matrices non-négatives (NMF) en tant qu'outil pour la séparation de sources musicales monophoniques (SC-MSS) au début du 21e siècle, son utilité et sa popularité ont augmenté de façon régulière et elle continue d'être un grand domaine d'intérêt au sein de la communauté de traitement du signal. Cependant, il est reconnu dans la littérature sur le sujet que l'hypothèse fondamentale du modèle de mélange pour la représentation spectrale de la source acoustique, à laquelle la NMF est appliquée, enfreint la véritable nature de la superposition des signaux acoustiques en ignorant la combinaison de phase entre sources superposées. Il est aussi reconnu que les procédures de type NMF pour la séparation de sources nécessitent des procédures de post-traitement additionnelles pour réintégrer l'information de phase à la représentation spectrale des sources une fois la factorisation complétée. Cette thèse explore la factorisation de matrices complexes (CMF), une variante de la NMF récemment proposée qui intègre l'information de phase des sources acoustiques dans le cadre de la factorisation de matrices. Ceci permet le développement de procédures de séparation de sources fondées sur un modèle de mixage ancré dans le domaine des spectres complexes (dans lequel le mélange de sources qui se superposent est préservée). La CMF apporte aussi l'avantage d'intégrer l'estimation de la phase des sources constituantes directement à l'algorithme de factorisation, ce qui élimine le besoin d'estimation de phase a posteriori. Trois expériences ont été réalisées afin d'étudier le comportement de la CMF comparé à la NMF lorsqu'appliqué à des mélanges simples fait à partir d'instruments acoustiques qui se superposent. La principale contribution de cette thèse est la formalisation d'une contrainte de phase, fondée sur des propriétés physiques, qui impose des liens entre ses estimations au court du temps. Nous montrons que l'algorithme de la CMF, armée de cette nouvelle contrainte de phase, donne des résultats prometteurs lorsqu'il est utilisé sur des signaux acoustiques simples dans le cadre de la SC-MSS.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Since the introduction of non-negative matrix factorization (NMF) as a tool for single-channel musical source separation (SC-MSS) in the early part of the 21st century, it has steadily increased both in practicality and popularity, and continues to be a major area of focus within the signal processing community. It is acknowledged in the literature, however, that the fundamental assumption of the mixture model for the spectral representation of the acoustic sources, to which NMF is applied, violates the true nature of the superposition of acoustic signals by disregarding the phase relationship between overlapping sources. It is also recognized that NMF-based source separation procedures require additional post-processing, in order to reincorporate the phase information back into the spectral representation of the sources, once the factorization is complete. This thesis explores Complex Matrix Factorization (CMF), a recently proposed variant of NMF, which incorporates the phase information of the acoustic sources into the matrix factorization framework, allowing for the development of source separation procedures founded on a mixture model rooted in the complex-spectrum domain (in which the superposition of overlapping sources is preserved). CMF has the additional benefit of integrating the estimation of the phase of the constituent sources directly into the factorization algorithm, eliminating the need for post-factorization phase estimation. Three experiments were conducted, investigating the behaviour of CMF, as it compares to NMF, when applied to simple test mixtures constructed from overlapping acoustic instruments. The main contribution of this thesis is the development of a physically motivated phase-based constraint, which restricts the relation between the phase parameter estimates over time. The CMF-based separation procedure, armed with this novel phase constraint, is demonstrated to offer promising results when employed as a tool for SC-MSS on the simple acoustic test case considered.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Philippe Depalle</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827f93b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010t348</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>