<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237ht31p"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>History, law and government control of civil aviation in India</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Menon, P. K.</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd02q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237ht31p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- India</dc:subject><dc:subject>History, Asia, Australia and Oceania</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, Public Administration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation -- India</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj67315433"><ual:graduationDate>1966</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The prime spectrum of a ring</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Greenspan, Harry</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z234r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67315433</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rings (Algebra)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qn49v"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Human Communication Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of auditory sequences by hearing-impaired and normal-hearing children</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ling, Agnes H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'habilite de suivre un ordre auditif fut étudiee chez des enfants d'audition normale de cinq et neuf ans et chez des sujets atteints de surdite, ages de 6 à 14 ans, 18 pour chaque groupe. Les sujets choisis pouvaient repeter des syllabes enregistrees, identifier des images correspondant à des sons d'entourage de 200 msec. de duree.  Des ordres de 2, 3 et 4 de ces stimuli furent enregistrés au rythme de 1, 2 et 4 stimuli par seconde. Les enfants d'audition normale et, d'une façon moins eVidente, les enfants atteints de surdité avaient une plus grande facilite à se rappeler des ordres verbaux plutôt que non-verbaux. Pour tous les groupes, la vitesse la plus rapide fut optimale pour les consonnes, et la vitesse la plus lente, pour les sons non-verbaux. Les sujets d'audition normale furent superieurs à ceux atteints de surdité, pour les ordres verbaux mais ces derniers, furent supérieur aux sujets ages de cinq ans et non pas de neuf ans, pour les ordres non-verbaux. Des implications pour l'entraînement auditif sont discutes. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Auditory sequencing ability was studied in 18 five and 18 nine year old normal-hearing children, and in 18 hearing-impaired children aged 6 to 14 years. Subjects selected were able to repeat syllables differing in initial consonant or final vowel and identify pictures corresponding to 200-msec. environmental sounds. Sequences of 2, 3 and 4 such items were recorded at 1, 2 and 4 items per second.  Significant interactions between type of stimuli, sequence length and rate were obtained. Normal-hearing children and, to a lesser extent, hearing-impaired children had greater facility in recalling verbal than nonverbal sequences. For aIl groups, the fastest rate was optimal for consonants, and the slowest rate for nonverbal sounds.  Normal children were superior to hearing-impaired subjects on verbal sequences. On nonverbal sequences, hearing-impaired were more accurate than normal five year olds, but less accurate than nine year olds. Implications for auditory training are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Donald G. Doehring</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq48b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn49v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hearing Impaired Persons</dc:subject><dc:subject>Auditory Perception</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Audiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Memory, Short-Term</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mental Recall</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5h73px567"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ethics of metaphysics and ethics of value : a study in the thought of Bernard Lonergan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thompson, Donald F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Within the thought of Bernard Lonergan, is described a universal dynamic structure immanent within intellectual, moral, and religious consciousness. In Insight: A Study of Human Understanding, his analysis of the invariant pattern of that structure grounds a cognitional theory, an epistemology, and a metaphysics which then enables him to propose an ethic based on the structure of the good as immanent within every act of rational self-consciousness. In later works, principally Method in Theology, his orientation shifts to incorporate a new notion of value, which is distinct in that it is apprehended through feeling. The result is an ethic oriented to the transcendental objective of value and developed from the patterns of cognition which apprehend that value. This thesis studies that shift, and focuses on Lonergan's admitted sources to it: Max Scheler, Dietrich von Hildebrand, Jean Piaget, Susanne Langer, Abraham Maslow, and existential thought generally. In reconstructing it, the thesis finds grounds to differentiate the cognitional theory based upon analysis of intellectual as opposed to affective operations, their invariant norms for authentic operation, and their contents in facts and values respectively.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj12j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73px567</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Values</dc:subject><dc:subject>Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lonergan, Bernard J. F</dc:subject><dc:subject>Metaphysics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q785n"><ual:graduationDate>1970</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some aspects of downwards two-phase slug flow in pipes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sourour, Sami</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the present work, investigations are carried out for the ultimate use of the "Bis table Fluid Amplifier" as an alternator to produce intermittent vertical water slugs. The effect of some geometrical and flow variables on the amplifier characteristics used in a vertical position, is studied experimentally. The minimum control flow required to switch the main power jet from one wall to the other is obtained as a function of the main jet flow rate, the splitter angle and its distance from the main nozzle. The efficiency of the amplifier functioning as a pressure recovery device is determined in relation to the output load. Theoretical and experimental results are compared.  Some aspects of downwards air water flow in long vertical tubes are investigated. The formation of a spherical-cap air slug in an overflow pipe, and the behaviour and stability of the air-water interface in the tube are studied with the aid of motion picture films.  Finally, a theory is appended concerning the transient polytropic compression of a gas in a vertical tube by a high velocity falling liquid slug from a constant flow supply.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>N. E. Cooke</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gp863.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q785n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fluid amplifiers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jet pumps</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fluid dynamics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8623j034w"><ual:graduationDate>1988</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spatial fading characteristics of VHF broadcast signals in an urban environment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Banik, Tuhin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is concerned with the measurement and characterization of radio signal spatial fading in urban micro-environments. Automated field strength measurements at ten FM broadcast frequencies were conducted in a small region of a built up urban center (the McGill University campus, Montreal, Canada). The measurements show that the received signal comprises two independent fading components: long term fading (average power variations over large spatial intervals), and short term fading (rapid power fluctuations over small spatial intervals). A number of statistical and time series analysis methods (probability density, quantile-quantile plots, autocovariance, crosscovariance, spectral density) were exploited to characterize the fading behaviour (long term and short term) for different urban surroundings. Since specific behavioural differences were observed, it is concluded that the methods used (experimental and statistical) provide a basis for characterizing spatial fading phenomena of mobile radio signals in urban areas.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cz03d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j034w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rm83k"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A self-driven test methodology for built-in self-test of sequential circuits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Muradali, Fidel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Test cost comprises a substantial portion of producing an integrated circuit. As a result, structural modifications of the circuit via design for test (DFT) techniques are commonly used as an aid to reduce test cost to the lowest possible level. One important class of DFT is Built-In Self-Test (BIST). In BIST, test generation and response analysis logic is integrated into the original circuit and are transparent during normal operation. In this manner, in-circuit tests can be performed with minimal need of external test equipment, if any. Test strategies based on pseudorandom test stimuli are attractive since the simplicity of the pattern generation logic facilitates on-chip test application. Unfortunately, until now, these methods have been more appropriate for testing combinational rather than sequential circuits. This is largely because, unlike combinational testing, detection of sequential faults can require specific orderings of circuit operations which are prohibitively difficult to produce using a pseudorandom source. This thesis introduces a new DFT technique which permits at-speed on-chip sequential testing using parallel pseudorandom test patterns applied only to the primary inputs of the circuit under test. Test network design focuses on adjusting fault free circuit activity and aiding error propagation. This is done via the strategic insertion of a small number of low area test points. The resulting system is unique in that aside from a test mode flag, all I/O signals needed for test system operation are tapped from within the circuit itself. This feature virtually eliminates the control signal generation logic typically needed in other test point strategies. Also, as opposed to the conventional approach of restricting circuit alterations to the state elements, the proposed flexibility in choosing modification sites is beneficial when considering speed constrained designs. Experiments demonstrate that high single stuck-at fault coverage is achieved for a number of benchmark circuits.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rajski, Janusz</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w389d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rm83k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj6731544c"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation of the cadherins expressed in mouse thymocytes and testis, utilizing the polymerase chain reaction : identification of two novel cadherins, T1-cadherin and T2-cadherin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Munro, Sandra Bronwen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The cadherins are calcium-dependent cell adhesion molecules. I have used a polymerase chain reaction (PCR) strategy to identify the cadherins expressed in mouse CD4$ sp+$ CD8$ sp+$ thymocytes and testis. Two novel cadherins (designated T1-cadherin and T2-cadherin) were discovered utilizing this approach. cDNAs containing partial coding regions for T1-cadherin and T2-cadherin were used as molecular probes in Northern blot and in situ hybridization protocols to determine the tissue- and cell-specific expression patterns of T1- and T2-cadherin. A T1-cadherin mRNA transcript of 3 kb was detected in adult mouse testes extracts. An mRNA transcript of 3.5 kb was detected for T2-cadherin in mouse brain and testes extracts. In situ hybridization analysis suggested that T2-cadherin is expressed by the Sertoli cells in the seminiferous epithelium. In addition to T1-cadherin and T2-cadherin, five other cadherins (E-cadherin, N-cadherin, P-cadherin, K-cadherin, and OB-cadherin) were found to be expressed at various stages during testicular development. The relative levels of each testicular cadherin mRNA transcript were determined in fetal, newborn, 7-day-old, 21-day-old, and adult mouse testes by semi-quantitative PCR. N-cadherin mRNA was expressed at all stages of testicular development, with maximal levels being present in the testes of 21-day-old mice. E-cadherin, P-cadherin, K-cadherin, OB-cadherin, and T2-cadherin mRNA transcripts were expressed in the fetal gonad. The testicular levels of these cadherin mRNA transcripts decreased dramatically after birth. Conversely, T1-cadherin mRNA was not detected in the fetal, newborn, and 7-day-old testes, but was present in 21-day-old and adult testes. T1-cadherin levels were 10-fold higher in the testes of adult mice, compared to the levels found in the testes of 21-day-old mice. As well, the N-cadherin, T1-cadherin, and T2-cadherin mRNA levels were examined in the estrogen receptor knockout (ERKO) mouse. T1-cadherin mRNA levels</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Blaschuk, O. W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zj22x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731544c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tn54g"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A novel receiver structure for data detection in the presence of rapidly changing nuisance parameters</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nassar, Carl R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis introduces a novel receiver structure for the detection of data in the presence of rapidly changing nuisance parameters. Underlying equations characterizing the novel receiver are presented first. This is followed by a presentation and explanation of the receiver implementation; the implementation uses a parallel structure to facilitate a real time processing. A theoretical analysis of this receiver is provided. Here, we introduce an existence condition; this condition suggests the broad applicability of our receiver. Next, we present two algorithms, one based on rate distortion theory, and the other on the Generalized Lloyd Algorithm (GLA). These two algorithms facilitate the creation of the novel receiver's variables for many practical applications. We apply our receiver to four communication environments of practical interest. These environments can be described briefly as follows: (1) an MPSK signal is sent across a channel introducing noise and a phase offset; here, the phase offset is constant over only N symbols, where N is small but greater than two (e.g., N = 3); (2) as in (1), an MPSK signal is sent across a channel introducing noise and a phase offset; this time, the phase offset is constant over only N = 2 symbols; (3) a coded MPSK signal is sent across a channel adding noise and rapidly changing phase; and, finally, (4) independent data symbols are sent across a channel introducing timing offset and noise; here, the timing offset changes in every received burst of data. We show that, in these environments, our receiver is able to offer gains when compared to the receivers in the current literature; our receiver gains in terms of performance, complexity, or both. There exists a great potential for future research. The novel receiver introduced in this thesis can be applied to many other communication environments of practical interest.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Soleymani, M. Reza</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Blostein, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq026.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tn54g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w630r"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An analysis of utilization of health services by the elderly in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Newman, Edward, 1957-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Population aging in Canada is expected to result in a sharp increase in the use of health services by the aged. The purpose of this thesis, is to enhance the knowledge of the utilization of the health system by the elderly. For this, an analysis of the utilization of three health services was pursued, using data from two health surveys, and two general social surveys in a statistical examination; to describe age-use; identify the major determinants of utilization; and to discover the sources of change in use. The results show that the aged were the highest users of health services among all age groups. Use increased for some services, and decreased for others. Changes in how people were managed by the health system, and to a lesser extent a rise in disease prevalence, were the primary sources of variations in utilization. There was no conclusive evidence of the presence of supplier induced demand. Population aging was not a significant determinant of changes in health service use, but rather factors associated with the management of the elderly by the health system; this includes technological changes in medicine, and changes in treatment patterns.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Soderstrom, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r000k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w630r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Medical care -- Utilization -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Older people -- Medical care -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78td618"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interpretive ground and moral perspective : economics, literary theory, early modern texts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>LiBrizzi, Marcus</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation provides a critical, systematic survey of economics in literary theory and practice. Since Aristotle, economic categories have been used as interpretive grounds on which to conceptualize the literary text and distinguish it as a moral or normative sphere. Because economic categories presuppose different norms of individual and social action, the use of a specific category as an interpretive ground generates a particular outlook or moral perspective. In the first part of the discussion, we critique theories in which the literary text is conceptualized as an economy. After distinguishing three distinct models of the "textual economy," we evaluate them in terms of their logical consistency and normative presuppositions. Selecting the model that is the most logically consistent and normatively valuable, we study two early modern works to see if this model operates as an intentional device implicated in a work's form and content. The works chosen are William Shakespeare's Sonnets and William Bradford's history "Of Plimoth Plantation," both of which display a facination with economic discourse. The second part of the discussion takes up the question of economics in the theory and practice of putting texts in context. We distinguish four different models of contextualization that depend on economic categories. Explicitly or implicitly, contemporary research agendas and critical positions depend on these categories to situate a literary text in a specific setting. An economic category like exchange, for example, is frequently privileged as a common ground, a shared quality or characteristic used to integrate a text with a context. After critiquing models of contextualization, we synthesize the best they have to offer into a new framework. We then use this framework to situate the texts by Shakespeare and Bradford into the historical settings of their production and reception. The result is a picture of the text in context that is vital, a moving picture, quite unlike the customary still life of artifact and background.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bristol, Michael D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d1369.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td618</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bradford, William, 1590-1657 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af4752j30h"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>In vitro regulation of fetal bovine erythropoiesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Qinggang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Fetal bovine serum (FBS) is one of the most important supplements for cell culture, and is a rich source of both defined and unknown factors required for proper cell growth. A serum-free bioassay system was developed to facilitate the purification and characterization of the heparin-binding growth factors in FBS. Three factors with different effects on erythropoiesis were isolated and identified with the combination of several chromatographic techniques. An 8 kd heparin-binding peptide which stimulated thymidine incorporation into fetal erythroid cells had an N-terminal sequence identical to insulin-like growth factor (IGF II). The growth promoting effect of this peptide was potentiated by heparin in culture. It was also found that the relative affinity of IGFs was in the order of IGF II $&gt;$ IGF I $&gt;$ insulin. The second heparin-binding erythroid regulating factor isolated was a 46 kd protein. The N-terminal sequence of this protein was identical to that of apolipoprotein H (Apo H). It inhibited thymidine incorporation into fetal erythroid cells with an ED$ sb{50}$ of 36 nM. A 100% inhibition of thymidine incorporation and a 40% decrease in cell numbers in culture were observed at 840 nM. The third factor identified was an 11 kd peptide with an N-terminal sequence similar to C4a, a fragment of complement C4. This peptide was a potent cytotoxic agent and was not species-specific, lysing not only bovine fetal erythroid cells, but also human adult red blood cells at very low concentrations. A clonal assay system for bovine fetal liver cells was developed to further characterize the erythropoietic effects of IGF II, the most important of the isolated factors. It was found that bovine fetal erythroid colonies could not be developed at low concentrations of FBS, unless they were grown over stromal cells. Bovine fetal liver stromal cell lines could support erythroid growth through secreting soluble factor(s) and by direct contact to erythroid cells. It was clear that IGFs stimulated erythropoiesis in this system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Congote, L. F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gh89q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j30h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881n490"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vasa function in Drosophila pole plasm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liang, Lu.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Pole plasm in Drosophila melanogaster, through the posteriorly localized determinant nanos, controls the formation of the abdominal segments and, through an unknown mechanism, controls the formation of the germline. oskor, vasa, and tudor are three critical genes in the pole plasm assembly pathway and their gene products, oskar RNA, Vasa protein and Tudor protein are localized in the pole plasm in a precise order. The localization of oskar and nanos mRNAs is closely related to their translational activation. We provide evidence here by in vitro biochemical assays that Vasa protein is an ATP-dependent RNA helicase, an ATPase and an RNA-binding protein, as was predicted from its sequence similarity to mammalian translation initiation factor eIF-4A. The enzymatic activities of Vasa protein are important for its function, but the initial localization of Vasa protein to the pole plasm is independent of its RNA helicase and RNA-binding activities. Further, we cloned Bruno, a Xenopus etr-1 homologue with three ribonucleoprotein-recognition-motifs (RRM), by far-western screening using Vasa protein as bait. Bruno is the product of the gene arrest, which was cloned independently by Webster and Macdonald at Stanford University. The localization of Bruno protein in S1-10 oocytes is similar to that of oskar and gurken RNAs. This is significant as both oskar and gurken RNAs contain Bruno-response-elements at their 3$ sp prime$UTRs. Bruno is mislocalized in vasa mutant ovaries, suggesting that the localization of Bruno protein requires Vasa function. As a translational activator of oskar and nanos RNAs and a regulator of Bruno protein. the participation and the importance of Vasa protein in pole plasm assembly and function is obvious. Whether Vasa acts directly or indirectly to activate translation of specific mRNAs will require further examination.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lasko, P. F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988m54q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881n490</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Drosophila melanogaster -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oogenesis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr171z743"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stochastic approximation algorithms for statistical estimation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Shaolin, 1963-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents some broadly applicable algorithms for computing maximum likelihood estimates (MLE) from the incomplete data based on the stochastic approximation (SA) proposed by Robbins and Monro (1951). The usual approach for such problems is the EM algorithm. In many interesting examples, however, it is impossible to carry out either the E-step or the M-step of the EM algorithm. Although some remedial EM algorithms were developed, these algorithms could be very expensive numerically, especially when both the E-step and the M-step become intractable. The SA algorithms proposed are appealing because they avoid computing expectation within iterations and are easy to implement. These advantages are reinforced by a discussion of some examples illustrating how these SA algorithms can succeed while the EM algorithm is intractable. Theory showing convergence of these algorithms along with the rate of their optimal convergence is developed. Moreover, the thesis also explores some theoretical issues about the robustness, consistency and asymptotic theory of the SA estimation of MLE with incomplete data in the double array sense.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gu, Minggao</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zs32s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171z743</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Statistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053h59v"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anergy and the human skin immune system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hassan-Zahraee, Mina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An initial study comparing cytokine gene expression in the skin of control vs. anergic patients lacking delayed type hypersensitivity reactivity revealed no difference; but disclosed an apparent absence of detectable CD3+ T cells in the skin of anergic individuals. To assess its significance for anergy, an investigation of the role of skin T cells in DTH-reactive healthy individuals was undertaken. To do so, the phenotypic and functional characteristics of T cells isolated from skin and blood were compared. Analysis by flow cytometry has shown that 74% of skin T cells expressed cell surface HLADR, 66% were positive for the IL-2 receptor CD25, and less than 43% have displayed the VLA integrin $ alpha$4 chain as compared to 28%, 7%, 79% for peripheral blood mononuclear cells respectively. The expression of a cutaneous lymphocyte antigen (CLA) was 61% in the former and 14% in the latter. Functionally, skin T cells failed to proliferate in response to all ligands including IL-2, anti-CD3, lectins and phorbol esters with ionomycin, as well as showed a reduced Ca++ flux to phytohemagglutinin. Skin tissue co-cultured with autochtonous PBL could inhibit its proliferative reaction. Despite their ability to proliferate, lymphocytes from skin were shown to be able to produce IFN$ gamma$ in response to PHA+IL-12 as well as anti-CD3+IL-2. Inhibition by anti-cytokine mAbs revealed that in both instances IL-12 was obligatory for this production. In an additional study it was established that a hitherto uncharacterized subset of T cells in blood which could secrete IFN$ gamma$ consisted of CLA+ cells. This observation established a functional link between these CLA+ skin-seeking T cells and the CLA+ T cells in skin. A major difference between IFN$ gamma$-producing cells from blood and skin was found to be the tempo of synthesis: whereas, PBMC was first detected to contain IFN$ gamma$ 42 hours following activation, lasting for days, skin cells were positive after 2.5 hrs of activation, (or 16x faster) for a duration of only 90 minutes. These kinetics were confirmed using intact skin in culture. Experiments designed to reveal the mechanism of this fast action have shown that mRNA for IFN$ gamma$ is present in unstimulated isolated skin T cells as well as in intact skin, but not in PBMC, and its presence may be attributed to ongoing constitutive transcription. Activation of skin T cells, which has been shown to elicit prompt translation in IFN$ gamma$ synthesis has also been shown, at the same time, to terminate IFN$ gamma$ gene transcription in an apparently selective manner. Accordingly, it can be seen that the amount of IFN$ gamma$ synthesized in skin and the duration of its synthesis is preprogrammed. This mode of regulation may be unique to the skin, and unique for IFN$ gamma.$ The results presented are interpreted to indicate that r cells present in human skin may play an essential role in the DTH response, and provide evidence for "peripheral sensitization", or lymphocyte activation outside organized lymphoid tissue. Because of its speed, it may represent the antigen-specific component of a first line cutaneous host defence system. The absence of such T cells in the skin of anergic patients may indeed be responsible for a lack of DTH reactivity, and its clinical consequences.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gordon, Julius</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b476d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h59v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cc387"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Virtuality and reality of a near-optimal time-delayed teleoperator control system based on teleprogramming paradigm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haule, Damian Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The teleprogramming control paradigm is suggested as a means to efficiently perform teleoperation tasks in situations where the remote and local manipulator systems are connected via a low bandwidth delayed communications link. The effects of communication delays in the order of seconds can be reduced by building a virtual reality simulated model of the remote site with which the operator can interact to receive immediate quality feedback using a Human-Machine Interface (HMI) for telepresence applications. This concept overcomes the delay by transmitting not Cartesian or joint level informations in the form of signals, but rather symbolic, error tolerant, command program segments to the remote site. Symbolic instructions are send to the remote station every time the contact state changes or every second if no change of contact state has occurred. Remote robotic systems are often very complex and difficult to operate, especially as multiple robots are integrated to accomplish difficult tasks in an unstructured or hazardous environments. In addition, training the operators is time-consuming and costly. A simulated virtual reality based system will provide a means by which operators can be trained to operate in an intuitive, and cost-effective way. Operator interaction with the remote system is at a high, task-oriented, level. Real-time state monitoring can prevent illegal robot actions and provides interactive feedback. A teleprogramming based simulator is essential for cost-effective Teleoperator Interface &amp; Training (TIT) using supervisory control approach. An intelligent virtual interface is required which provides a rich means of presenting diagnostic and visual state information to the operator with reduced fatigue in real-time. The Mobile Servicing System (MSS) Operations and Training Simulator (MOTS) will be used as a leading edge implementation of the teleprogramming concepts. MOTS provides high-fidelity, functional kinematic and dynamic software simulation of the MSS Space Segment in on-orbit configuration. MOTS is a real-time simulation environment of varying degrees of fidelity, along with an aggregate of software tools intended for the support of MSS space operations and training of crew and ground personnel. Primary interface to MOTS simulation models is through a Common Data Base (CDB) where telecommands are stored in a common shared memory. Hence, all telecommand data elements that are used to control the simulation modules are exported through the CDB by the Human Computer Interface (HCI) pages, hand controllers (H/C) and Display &amp; Control (D&amp;C) panel. Communication between simulation modules is achieved through the CDB in real-time.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Malowany, Alfred S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tw67w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc387</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zg011"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Physicochemical controls of greisen formation and cassiterite deposition at the East Kemptville tin deposit, Nova Scotia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Halter, Werner E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Prior to complete crystallization of leucogranitic magma at East Kemptville, tectonic fracturing induced a pressure drop, allowing a NaCl-HCl-HF-rich fluid phase to separate. This fluid caused pervasive sericitization and extracted the ore metals from the melt. It was then channeled into the fractures and caused greisenization in the apical part of the intrusion. During greisenization, the leucogranite was converted into quartz-sericite greisen through sequential replacement of K-feldspar and albite. Muscovite was replaced by topaz to form quartz-topaz greisen, host to sulphide and cassiterite mineralization. In this greisen, the OH$ sp-$ of muscovite is replaced by H$ sb2$O and O$ sp{2-},$ which leads to its dehydration during microprobe analyses. Close to veins, suphides and cassiterite were re-dissolved in quartz greisen. The altering fluid had a pH of 3.0 and contained 4.8m Cl, 3.7m Na, 0.53m Fe and minor F, K, S and Sn as determined from fluid inclusions and mineral equilibria. The temperature of greisenization was determined to be $480 pm 15 sp circ rm C$ using a F-OH exchange geothermometer between topaz and muscovite and oxygen isotopic data on cassiterite and quartz; the pressure was estimated to be 4.1 $ pm$ 1.0 kbars using fluid inclusion isochores. Alteration occurred though a process of compensated infiltration in which small aliquots of fluid were exchanged between the rock and the vein, while the bulk flow was parallel to the vein. This created a distribution of the components controlled by chemical potential gradients; Fe, Sn, S and F were transported away from the vein and Na towards it. Changes in physicochemical parameters of the fluid were quantified using computer simulation, which, in conjunction with fluid inclusion data, indicates that cassiterite precipitated in response to a pH increase. Changes in a$ sb{ rm Cl-}$ and $f rm O sb2$ were insufficient to account for cassiterite precipitation or acted against it. Modeling further showed that</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Williams-Jones, Anthony E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hb27v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg011</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xn22p"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>In quest of emotional gratification and cognitive consonance : organized labour and Québec separatist nationalism, 1960-1980</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guentzel, Ralph Peter</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the reaction of organized labour to Quebec separatist nationalism for the period between 1960, the year of the creation of the Rassemblement pour l'independance nationale and the beginning of the Quiet Revolution in Quebec, and 1980, the year of the first referendum on Quebec's constitutional status. The thesis investigates four labour organizations: the Canadian Labour Congress (CLC), the Federation des travailleurs et travailleuses du Quebec (FTQ), the Confederation des syndicats nationaux (CSN), and the Centrale de l'enseignement du Quebec (CEQ). It shows in which ways the positions of the four centrals have been informed by their members' national identifications and the emotional and cognitive mechanisms that resulted from these identifications.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Levesque, Andree</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c41s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xn22p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Québec (Province) -- History -- Autonomy and independence movements</dc:subject><dc:subject>Labor unions -- Québec (Province) -- Political activity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88cj13t"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Study of the role of macrophage activation and macrophage derived cytoxic factors in early embryo loss</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haddad, Elias K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Using murine models of spontaneous and induced embryo resorption, we have investigated the role of macrophages in the mechanism of early embryo loss. The results showed that macrophage derived nitric oxide was associated with embryo resorption, and that decidual macrophages could be triggered by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) to produce nitric oxide, indicating that the decidual mononuclear cells were primed in situ. Using double immunostaining, we have shown that macrophages were the cellular source of the inducible nitric oxide production. We further showed that embryo abortion can be significantly decreased by inhibiting the production of nitric oxide in vivo. The results presented strongly suggested a role for nitric oxide as an effector molecule in mediating early embryo loss and showed that the in situ activation of decidual macrophages was an early event preceding spontaneous abortion. It is known that interferon-$ gamma$ (IFN-$ gamma$) is the major cytokine responsible for the priming of macrophages and that LPS can trigger primed macrophages to produce nitric oxide. Therefore, the observation that exogenous LPS induced embryo abortion in most strains of pregnant mice suggested that the decidual macrophages have been previously primed in situ. To investigate the role of IFN-$ gamma$ as a potential priming signal for decidual macrophage activation, we studied the effect of the depletion of IFN-$ gamma$ on LPS induced pregnancy loss. The results showed that IFN-$ gamma$ deficient mice were more resistant to LPS induced abortion than control mice. This suggested that IFN-$ gamma$ was essential for the priming of decidual macrophages and that decidual macrophages from IFN-$ gamma$ deficient mice could not be activated when exposed to LPS both in vivo and in vitro. Our results also showed increased IFN-$ gamma$ mRNA expression simultaneously in the same embryos that also expressed elevated iNOS mRNA, a macrophage activation marker. This suggested that macrophage activation, subsequent nitric oxide production, and spontaneous embryo loss could be a consequence of local IFN-$ gamma$ over production. While LPS serves as an exogenous triggering factor, endogenous TNF-$ alpha$ is known to trigger NO production by primed macrophages. Therefore, we investigated the role of TNF-$ alpha$, as a second signal, in mediating embryo loss. Our studies showed that the frequency of embryos with significantly increased TNF-$ alpha$ mRNA expression corresponded to the incidence of murine embryo abortion. In addition, the results showed that increased TNF-$ alpha$ mRNA was simultaneously expressed with iNOS mRNA suggesting a potential role for TNF-$ alpha$ in the triggering of decidual macrophages. In summary, we demonstrated the presence of activated decidual macrophages in murine placentas, and that inducible nitric oxide produced by these macrophages was responsible for embryo death. We further showed that IFN-$ gamma$ was responsible for the priming of decidual macrophages, and that the expression of TNF-$ alpha$, a potential secondary signal was associated with decidual macrophage activation, NO production, and subsequent embryo loss.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baines, M. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gp87c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj13t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Obstetrics and Gynecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tw685"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Immunochemotherapy in experimental leishmaniasis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eslami, Zohreh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The proliferation dynamics in vitro of the obligate intracellular protozoan parasite Leishmania donovani was studied for 14 days in resting monolayers of peritoneal macrophages of C57BL/6 $(Lsh sp{ rm s})$ mice inoculated with 5, 50, or 500 promastigotes/cell. Irrespective of the inoculum, only 50 to 65% of the cells became infected initially; only 3 to 6 amastigotes were present in each macrophage initially, suggesting a limited number of parasite ligands on the host cell. The amastigotes did not divide in the first 3 or 4 days after infection and then they actively proliferated from day 5 to day 8; the number of parasites was then reduced. Infection with L. donovani down-regulates immunity and parasite clearance by macrophages, but IL-2-stimulated splenocytes activate leishmanicidal action in vitro in infected peritoneal macrophages and in vivo in C57BL/6 (Lsh$ sp{ rm s})$ mice. IL-2-stimulated splenocytes were most effective when used in the non-proliferating phase of the infection, whereas the anti-leishmanial drug Pentostam was most effective when used during the proliferative phase. Immunochemotherapy was more effective than either treatment alone. Infection with L. donovani abolishes the ability of macrophages to produce the superoxide and INO microbicidal responses; curative treatment with IL-2-stimulated splenocytes restores the ability of infected macrophages to secrete inorganic nitrogen oxides, but not to produce a superoxide response. Pentostam had no effect to stimulate either microbicidal mechanism in infected cells; the drug is, therefore, probably directly toxic to the parasite. These studies have indicated, among other things, that IL-2-stimulated splenocytes rescue infected cells and infected animal from the immunological deficit which L. donovani induces, allowing the re-establishment of those mechanisms that make the macrophage an essential component of the host's protective immune system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tanner, Charles E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vj26j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tw685</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Leishmaniasis -- Immunotherapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Leishmaniasis -- Chemotherapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3j333382j"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Principles of energy and momentum conservation to analyze and model air flow for perforated ventilation ducts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>El Moueddeb, Khaled</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A theoretical model was developed to predict the air distribution pattern and thus to design perforated ventilation ducts equipped with a fan. The analysis of the air distribution pattern of such systems requires accurate measurement procedures. Several experimental methods were tested and compared. Accordingly, the piezometric flush taps and thermo-anemometer were selected to measure respectively the duct air pressure and the outlet air flow. Based on the equations of energy and momentum conservation, a model was formulated to predict the air flow performance of perforated ventilation ducts and to evaluate the outlet discharge angle and the duct regain coefficients without evaluating frictional losses. The basic assumptions of the model were validated by experimentally proving the equivalence of the friction losses expressed in the 2 cited equations. When compared to experimental results measured from four wooden perforated ventilation ducts with aperture ratios of 0.5, 1.0, 1.5, and 2.0, the model predicted the outlet air flow along the full length of perforated duct operated under turbulent flow conditions with a maximum error of 9%. The regain coefficient and the energy correction factor were equal to one, and the value of the discharge coefficient remained constant at 0.65, along the full length of the perforated duct. The outlet air jet discharge angle varied along the entire duct length, and was not influenced by friction losses for turbulent flow. Assuming a common effective outlet area, the model was extended to match the performance of the fan and the perforated duct and to determine their balance operating point.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barrington, Suzelle F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wr756.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333382j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Air ducts -- Design and construction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Air flow -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arj430629w"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>City at war : the effects of the Second World War on Verdun, Québec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Durflinger, Serge Marc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This work examines the effects of the Second World War on Verdun, Quebec, an urban, working-class community with a 1941 population of 67,000. Verdun was the third-largest city in Quebec and the thirteenth-largest in Canada. This study assesses the military, civilian and industrial contribution of this community to the national war effort. No comprehensive study of Canada's 'home front' war has ever been approached from the perspective of a community study. Verdun's population was 58% English speaking and 42% French speaking. Nearly one-third of Verdun's English-speakers were born in the British Isles. Verdun's exceptional British character and its linguistic mix remain sub-themes throughout this work, which concludes that French-Canadian participation in the war effort at the local level was significantly greater than the historiography has suggested. Verdunites of both language groups exhibited an exceptionally strong sense of community identification and civic pride and the city's wartime responses were influenced by this shared feeling of local identity. Some of the characteristics of wartime life in Verdun followed national trends; a detailed examination of these themes provides new insight into the wider Canadian home front experience. This study intends to provide an innovative addition to the literature of Canada's participation in the Second World War and to enhance existing knowledge of Canadian and Quebec social and cultural dynamics existing at that time.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Miller, Carman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr418.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430629w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Verdun (Québec) -- History -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Québec (Province) -- Verdun</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603r0024"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design, operation and applications of a visible-light confocal scanning Fourier transform Raman microscope for volumetric Raman spectrochemical imaging</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brenan, Colin John Herbert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new type of confocal Raman microscope called a Fourier transform confocal Raman microscope (FT-CRM) was designed, built and characterized with respect to its spatio-spectral imaging properties. Several different applications of the FT-CRM are presented that take advantage of its unique spectral and spatial imaging characteristics. The instrument combines focused illumination with spatially-filtered detection in a confocal optical configuration to collect photons scattered from a diffraction-limited volume in the sample (typically ${&lt;}5 times10 sp{-18} m sp3)$ and reject photons from outside that region. The molecular vibrational information encoded in the inelastic, or Raman, spectral component of light scattered from the confocal volume is measured with a visible light Fourier transform Raman spectrometer. By scanning the sample relative to the confocal volume, a volumetric Raman spectrochemical image of the sample can be constructed. Raman scattering is an inherently inefficient process; hence an optimal radius pinhole must be found that balances the FT-CRM optical throughput against the microscope spatial resolution and image contrast. Detailed experimental measurements mapped out the FT-CRM spatial response (axial and lateral), optical throughput and image signal-to-background and signal-to-noise ratios as a function of pinhole radius. Excellent agreement was found between these measurements and the predictions of a theoretical microscope model also developed as part of this thesis. Several applications of the FT-CRM included volumetric compositional imaging of three-dimensional chemically inhomogeneous materials such as cellulose and polyester fibers in water or two immiscible optically-similar liquids, water and trichloroehthylene, in a porous quartz sandstone matrix. The potential of the FT-CRM for non-invasive spectrochemical detection and imaging through a turbid tissue-like medium was demonstrated and a new spectral estimator, Fast Orthogonal Search, was evaluated to replace the discrete Fourier transform to improve the microscope performance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hunter, Ian W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w6311.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r0024</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Analytical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Optics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042v47f"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of the Wilms' tumor suppressor gene wt1 and its role in disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bruening, Wendy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Wilms' tumor suppressor gene 1 (wt1) encodes a transcription factor belonging to the Early Growth Response (EGR) family of proteins. The gene produces an mRNA that is alternatively spliced to yield four different species. In this thesis, it is shown that the wt1 gene has two sites of translational initiation, an AUG codon and a CUG codon that is upstream of and in frame with the AUG codon. The combination of alternative initiation sites and alternatively spliced exons allows the gene to encode eight different isoforms. It was previously shown that heterozygous mutations of wt1, predicted to result in a reduction in dosage of WT1, are associated with a predisposition to Wilms' tumor and mild abnormalities of the genitourinary system. However, other mutations of wt1, primarily missense mutations predicted to disrupt the ability of WT1 to bind to DNA, are associated with the severe disease of Denys-Drash syndrome (DDS). To explain the different disease states associated with mutations of wt1, it has been suggested that the mutations in DDS individuals must be acting other than as null alleles, i.e. in a dominant or dominant-negative fashion. In this thesis, an individual with DDS is reported to have a splicing mutation of wt1, predicted to drastically alter the ratio of WT1 isoforms. Because no altered forms of WT1 are produced in this individual, we were able to eliminate the possibility that DDS is caused by a gain of function of mutated WT1. In this thesis it is also shown that WT1 can form dimers through a domain encoded by its first two exons, and that mutated WT1 proteins are able to antagonize the function of wild-type WT1 by binding to and inactivating the wild-type proteins. This dominant-negative activity is hypothesized to reduce the dosage of functional WT1 to very low levels and to thus cause the severe disease of DDS. The work reported in this thesis also shows that WT1 is imported into the nucleus by a signal contained within its first zinc finger</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pelletier, Jerry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526d865.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042v47f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn1070622"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A kinetic study of gallium arsenide etching in H2O2-NH4OH-H2O solutions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bryce, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gallium arsenide, a compound semiconductor commonly used in optoelectronic devices, is often subjected to wet etching techniques during microelectronic device manufacture. In this work, the wet chemical etching of gallium arsenide in $ rm H sb2O sb2$-$ rm NH sb4OH$-H$ sb2$O solutions was studied using a batch stirred-tank reactor. A kinetic control regime was established and the influence of each component's concentration on the intrinsic etch rate was determined. The reaction rate was found, in the presence of excess NH$ sb4$OH, to fit a rate equation, r = k (H$ rm sb2O sb2 rbrack sp{0.75}$ at 15, 25, and 40$ sp circ$C with an activation energy of 33.7 kJ/mol. Using NaOH instead of NH$ sb4$OH resulted in greatly reduced reaction rates, and it was concluded that the presence of the ammonium ion increases the rate by forming soluble compounds with oxidized species of Ga and As. When mass transfer resistances are introduced, using a flow reactor to simulate an industrial etching apparatus, the reaction rates are considerably reduced and the rate's dependence on $ rm H sb2O sb2$ concentration is shifted closer to linear. Convective mass transfer expressions for flow past a flat plate were successfully used to predict the etch rate. The two reactors were used to etch samples masked by a circuit pattern, and the crystallography of GaAs dictated the shape of the etch profiles rather than the mass transfer limitations of the system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Berk, Dimitrios</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km21x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1070622</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Inorganic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>