<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613n2210"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bacteriology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of Aminosugars in Glycoside Synthesis and in Cell-Metabolism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Srinivasan, S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In recent years, several investigations have revealed the widespread distribution of 2-aminosugars. They are common constituents of a broadly classified group of substances which are known as mucopolysaccharides, having diverse biological functions. With the exception of chitin, all the mucopolysaccharides so far isolated and analysed, have been found to possess, besides aminosugars and other sugars, such substances as glucuronic acid, sulphates, acetates and phosphates. A broad classification of mucopolysaccharides is given in Table I (Meyer, 1943).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Quastel, J. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z709140c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n2210</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Bacteriology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53x053h"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bacteriology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biological Studies on Treponemata</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Speers, Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This investigation was originally undertaken because it offered a challenge to attempt the solution of a biological connundrum which has existed for more than half a century. As will be seen later, in the review of the literature, T. pallidum has yet to be grown in vitro (with retention of its pathogenicity for experimental animals) and this fact alone would be enough to stimulate an investigation of the fundamental biological properties of this organism. At the same time, the successful in vitro cultivation of T. pallidum would undoubtedly lead to the development of a stable specific antigen and have far reaching effects in syphilis research. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z69q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x053h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Bacteriology and Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956k67p"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>the Reactions of Active Nitrogen with Chloromethanes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sobering, Simon Edgar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Active nitrogen, as it is now commonly known, was first discovered by Lewis (1) in 1900. He used relatively pure nitrogen, through which a condensed discharge was passed. He noted that the discharge tube was filled with a "beautiful chamois-yellow mist," which persisted for several seconds after the current was interrupted. The spectrum of this afterglow was banded and could be identified with part of the nitrogen spectrum. The use of sodium to remove the last traces of oxygen and water eliminated the afterglow. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd376136m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956k67p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Physical Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1n79h814w"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Poultry Husbandry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A Study of the Mechanism of Antibiotic Action in Eggshell Calcification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith, Robert E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The demand for poultry meats and eggs as a human food is the great stabilizing factor for the permanency and profit of the poultry industry. To maintain this demand, poultry products must exhibit excellent food value and appealing appearance. In dealing with the fresh egg industry the maintenance of superior quality depends to a large extent upon the quality of the shell encasing the egg. Any malformation of the eggshell, while it may not be serious enough to lead to a more rapid deterioration of the contents, detracts from consumer appeal, a necessity in modern sales programs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nikolaiczuk, N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s6171.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h814w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Poultry Husbandry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085p82k"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>the Relationship Between Abilities and Interests: a Factorial Study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith, David D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The psychologist engaged in educational and vocational counselling usually makes quite extensive use of two types of psychological tests. These are measures of ability and measures of interest. Instruments of these types usually provide the core of psychometric data about the client upon which the counselling is based. Their use rests on the assumption that the pattern of interests characteristic of an individual and the pattern of abilities found for the same individual are not necessarily related, pattern to pattern, in any particular way.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f971k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085p82k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2r36v2259"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bacteriology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors Affecting the Rate of Acetic Acid Production by Species of Acetobacter</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smart, Celina E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A review was made of the literature on acetic acid bacteria. Publications were found about stock-culture media, classification and the nutritional requirements for the growth of Acetobacter species. Research had not appeared to be done, however, on either the physical conditions or the nutrients relative to an efficient production of acetic acid from ethyl alcohol. The work reported in this thesis is an attempt to provide information that heretofore has been lacking about the Acetobacter group of bacteria. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wallace, R. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n4787.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v2259</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Bacteriology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab5644w38v"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Base Metal Deposits in the 'Labrador Trough' Between Lake Harveng and Lac Aulneau, New Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Slipp, R. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Twenty-three base metal deposits in Late Precambrian layered rocks of the "Labrador Trough'', 250 miles north of Knob Lake, New Quebec, are described. The metals of the deposits are copper, nickel, zinc, lead, gold and silver; not all occur in one deposit.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692tb00p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644w38v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab27740260"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some aspects of the deglaciation of the Indian House Lake area with particular reference to the former proglacial lakes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Barnett, David Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The peninsule of Labrador-Ungava* (Map 1) is a population desert, having harsh, cold winters and brief, warrn, fly-cursed summers, but offering the glacial geomorphologist ample scope for working on virgin territory, with abundant landforrns often of textbook simplicity. However, it is only in recent years thot extensive aerial photography has been undertaken, and this, together wlth certain military and economie developments within the peninsule, has led to an increasing awareness of the significance of the glacial history of the a rea. These developments led ultimately to the establishment in 1954, of the McGi Il Sub-Arctic Research La bora tory, through which it was proposed to develop a scientific research programme related to this little known a rea. With the establishment of the Laboratory, a Field Director was appointed by McGill University to supervise the studies of the younger workers on the staff. A natural outcome of the system was for an emphasis to develop along the lin es of the research interests of the senior man. Under the direction of Dr. J. D. Ives the system developed into what Matthew (196la) has termed the 1 McGill Programme in relation to the deglaciation of the peninsula. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, J. B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nc573.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b27740260</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geomorphology -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Indian House Lake Region, Labrador</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glacial epoch -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Indian House Lake Region, Labrador</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bj62g"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The abandoned glacial lake shorelines of southwest Labrador</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harrison, David Alan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this thesis is to describe in detail the fonn, lithology, elevation, tflt and distribution of abandoned glacial lake shoreline features and associated fluvioglacial and glacial deposits of Southwest Labrador Qnap 1). These characteristics are the result of distinct geomorphic and geophysical processes operating in late glacial and post glacial times and therefore a study of these characteristics reveals certain facts about the glacierization of Labrador-Ungava* and the deglaci erization of Southwest Labrador. The tilt of the glacial lake shoreline features is a result of glacial isostatic recovery and therefore the tilt of the shorelines reflects the differentiai thickness of the laurentide lee Sheet over Southwest Labrador during a certain stage in the Wisconsin period. If tilts of shorelines in other areas are used in conjunction with the tilts from Southwest Labrador it is possible to locate a point which represents a centre of ice dispersal of the Laurentide lee Sheet during a certain stage in the Wisconsin period.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, J. B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bz03c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bj62g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Glacial landforms -- Labrador, Southwest</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physical geography -- Labrador, Southwest</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab27740278"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology and Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Acculturation among the Seven Islands Montagnais</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Richardson, R. Alan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The impact of Euro-canadian civilization on the Algonkian speaking aborigines of the Province of Quebec poses many problems. sane of these problems, espeaially those involving changes in social organization and culture patterns are of interest to anthropologiste and other social scientiste. others are of more immediate or practical concern to government administrators and I:ndian welfare agencies. The present thesis has thus a two-fold objective: a general and a specifie purpose. The general purpose is to contribute to the body of anthropological knowledge wbich concerna itself with the understanding of the processes of culture change and culture growth. Such knowledge is essential to the planning and effective implementation of governmental policies among these people. The specifie purpose will be to descr!be and analyze some aspects of the process of culture change, or acculturation, among the Montagnais Indiana of the seven Islands band of the Quebec-Labrador region of canada. Three phases are abstracted in the acculturation process. The Haliotenam Reserve, one of the segments of the band is chosen as a typological representative of a community in Phase III of the postulated developmental sequences to be examined.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fried, Jacob</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qw46n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b27740278</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Montagnais Indians</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acculturation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cx947"><ual:graduationDate>1961</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The glacial geomorphology and deglacierization of the George River Basin and adjacent areas in Northern Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Matthew, Edward Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The importance of Labrador-Ungava as one of the main gathering grounds and centres of dispersal of the Laurentide ice sheet, and as the location of the final disappearance of the ice was recognized as early as 1896 with the publication of the reports of the government geologist, A.P. Low. Despite this knowledge the peninsula has received very little attention until recently, due undoubtedly to its inaccessibility, and to the practical difficulties of field research in the subarctic environment. Until about 1945 the studies of glacial geomorphology that had been completed ( with the exception of the early work of Low) were almost entirely confined to the coastal regions, in particular to the Atlantic coast of Labrador. The most significant scientific contribution was that of Tanner, who visited the coast of Labrador in 1937 and 1939. The investigations of Tanner and his colleagues, and Tanner (1944) synthesis of the reports of earlier geologists were published in a summary of the glaciations of the entire peninsula, which remains the standard regional reference to this day. Inevitably, with the meagre, and o:tten not entirely accurate information of the interior parts of Labrador Ungava there is a marked contrast in the degree to which detailed evidence is available to the glacial geomorphologist, attempting to decipher the details of glaciation over the whole peninsula.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wr52f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cx947</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Glacial epoch -- Québec (Province) -- George River Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geomorphology -- Québec (Province) -- George River Region</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajw827g554"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of Endocrine Effects on Experimental Metastatic Bone Tumors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Singh, T.B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Until recently the tumor process has been regarded as a one-step cause and effect event. The investigations during the past ten years have shown to an increasing extent the developmental character of the tumors, as well as the significance of various factors affecting the process of malignancy. Although the division of tumor process into three phases, (Induction, Critical and Progression), was suggested by Kline and Rush in 1941, it was not until 1951 that the concepts of Greene and Furth have, so to say, switched the consensus by dividing the tumors into autonomous and dependent, therefore denying the generally held view that cancer always represents an autonomous self-perpetuating entity. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Skoryna, S. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rm94b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827g554</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p403r"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>the Hausdorff and Hamburger One-Dimensional Moment Problems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shtern, Israel H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis we consider the Hausdorff and Hamburger one-dimensional moment problems. The Hamburger moment problem may be stated as follows. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765374709.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p403r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject><dc:subject/></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nm89q"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Behaviour of Modulated Electron Beams Subjected to Various Potential Distributions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shkarofsky, Issie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The electronic equation was checked for modulated beams, subjected to various potential distributions. A demountable system with two cavities was used. In a drift tube, the d.c. current or voltage or distance was varied. The maxima and minima points in the patterns were investigated for phase and power. The power at the second maximum was less than theory predicted. Results on a sealed off tube were similar. The discrepancy was probably due to secondary electrons.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Woonton, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289n627.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nm89q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject><dc:subject/></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z462b"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genesis of the Montreal Council of Social Agencies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shepherd, William F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This is a study of the origins of the Montreal Council of Social Agencies, a highly-developed welfare planning body of Montreal. An analysis is made here of its position and its functions in relation to the historical background of the Province of Quebec and to the cultural forces which impinge on the Council's growth and development. The work deals also with the formation of Financial Federation because of the symbiotic relationship which exists between it and the Council.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Moore, J. O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m7666.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z462b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qn43g"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Study of a Case of Adrenal Tumor with Regard to Steroid Metabolism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Serrano, Pedro A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present investigation was carried out in a patient with the adrenogenital syndrome who was found to have an adrenal tumor. The urinary corticosteroids and 17-ketosteroids were studied during three different periods: before any treatment, on cortisone administration, and after surgical removal of the tumor.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Venning, E. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m93v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qn43g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject><dc:subject/></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042x73g"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>the Antidiuretic, Pressor and Oxytocic Properties of Corticotropin-Releasing Factor (CRF)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Segal, Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since adrenocorticotrophic hormone (ACTH) and cortisone have become of importance for therapeutic use, the factors which regulate the secretion of ACTH have been extensively studied (1). Three views have been put forward concerning this regulation; a) that ACTH secretion is controlled by the systemic blood level of adrenaline; b) that its secretion is controlled and regulated by the systemic blood level of adrenal cortical hormones and; c) it may be controlled by the hypothalamus via the hypophysial portal vessels (1). [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Saffran, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr761.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042x73g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Psychiatry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s400p"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Individual Differences in Patterning and Level of Physiological Activity. A Study of Arousal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schnore, Morris M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The contribution of physiology to psychology has been mainly twofold: First, it has provided constructs and a frame of reference for the attempts to explain behavior; second, it has provided techniques for experimental studies. Among the psychological studies that have employed physiological techniques one can distinguish two rather different approaches: one aims at discovering the physiological mechanisms underlying behavior, while the other has borrowed the methods of physiology to obtain additional variables for observation. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Malmo, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838421x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s400p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acz30px48t"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>In vitro studies on the control of the release of ACTH</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schally, Andrew. V.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is now good evidence that the Central Nervous System is largely responsible for the direct or indirect regulation of the endocrine glands (1). In the case of the neurohypophysis and the adrenal medulla this control is probably direct, as both these glands are richly innervated. On the other hand the control exerted by the central nervous system over the adenohypophysis and thereby the gonads, thyroid and adrenal cortex is incompletely understood (1), but the evidence points to a neurohumoral type of control (1). From the work of Harris and ethers it appears, that both the hypothalamus and the neurohypophysis are involved in the integration of the activity of the adenohypophysis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Saffran, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s6189.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30px48t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mr14m"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors in Scotland affecting the Scottish migrations to Canada between 1840 and 1896</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ross, Valerie. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Scots' emigration to Great Britain's American colonies didnot become a recognizable phenomenon until after the Union of1?0?, for it was not until that date that Scots were vestedwith the right to migrate freely to England's colonies in America.At first the movement was a relatively small one, evincing nostartling developments. Around 1?68, however, it began to swellconsiderably and from that time until the outbreak of the AmericanRevolution, it grew in scale. Both Lowlands and Highlands wereaffected by this "rage for emigration", but it was the latter whofelt the greater impact.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207ts81z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mr14m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Scotland -- Economic conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Scotland -- Emigration and immigration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Emigration and immigration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Scotland -- Social conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Scots -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dk29j"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The life cycle and cytology of the myxogastres</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ross, Ian. K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In recent years considerable attention has been directed towards the organisms collectively known as "slime moulds". Recent work on these organisms has revealed that they are particularly favourable organisms for studying the physiology and morphology of differentiation. The term "slime mould” commonly refers to the members of four different groups of organisms; the Labyrinthulales, the Acrasiales, the Myxogastrales or Myxomycetes, and the Plasmodiophorales. With the exception of the Plasmodiophorales, the members of these groups are non-parasitic in higher plants.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wilson, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gh56g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dk29j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Botany</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q7944"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Sacred Theology</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Religion</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The realm of miracle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rogers, Allison. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>What can we believe about miracles? It is a question to which very divergent answers have been made by a great variety of people. Not infrequently untutored individuals have held views at wide variance with men of vast learning; of men of erudition themselves it would seem true to say that there has never been unanimity of belief; and, if of bygone centuries it be true that no common point of view regarding miracles received assent, it is equally true to affirm that in our own time there is a like disparity of opinion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thomson, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vx697.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q7944</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Divinity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nj47c"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The legal status of military air transport</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rippon, Clive. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1782, the Montgolfier Brothers, professionally engaged in the manufacture of paper bags , produced the first machine to accomplish flight per se. Their first practice was to fill paper bags with hot air, which ascended by the thermodynamic force produced. Following their original discovery, they made larger and larger bags until they eventually evolved a great balloon which was capable of carrying a man into the air. Development was so rapid that within ten years from the first successful man-carrying ascent, balloons were successfully employed in warfare by the French, against the Austrians in 1794 at Maubeuge, in the battle of Fleures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pépin, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wr53q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj47c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>International Air Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak930c196f"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The geology of the Cumberland Sound region Baffin Island</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Riley, George. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The existence of Baffin Island has been known for many years, but, since the time of the last world conflict, when its strategic importance became evident, increasing interest has been shown in its history and development. In this, no easy pattern can be followed, because of the many factors influencing the settlement of the Island. Its geographical location made it a resting place for explorers, and provided harbours for whaling fleets of earlier years. Trading posts were placed by the Hudson' s Bay Company at accessible points along the coast, and the Royal Canadian Mounted Police has, in recent years, established stations at four localities.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kranck, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q795d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c196f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anz806383t"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The fiscal system of Jordan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rezek, Gabriel. E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Before the First World War, the territory that comprised Transjordan was part of the Ottoman Empire. For administrative purposes, Transjordan was included in the province (vilayet) of Syria which itself was divided into 4 districts (sanjaks). After the defeat of the Turks in 1918, the Ottoman Empire disintigrated and Emir Faisal, son of Sherif Hussein ruler of the Hejaz, was proclaimed King on March 8th 1920. This, however, conflicted with the policy of the Allies as revealed by the Sykes-Picot secret Agreement concluded in the spring of 1916 and which contemplated the division of that area into spheres of influence.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Armstrong, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913t536.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806383t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>