<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pc64v"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expression of stem-loop binding protein during murine oogenesis and pre-implantation development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Champigny, Marc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The goal of the work presented here was to investigate the hypothesis that cytoplasmic SLBP is required for translation of somatic H1 mRNA, and their translational repression is due to a lack of SLBP in the cytoplasm of oocytes, and early cleavage-stage embryos. To this end, the expression of SLBP in murine oocytes and pre-implantation embryos was characterized by RT-PCR, Western blotting, and immunocytochemical. techniques. mRNA encoding SLBP was detected throughout oogenesis and pre-implantation development, from small growing oocytes to the late blastocyst stage. SLBP protein was found in the nucleus and cytoplasm of growing and fully-gown prophase I-arrested oocytes. SLBP accumulated to extremely high levels during meiotic maturation in a process requiring translation. The protein remained abundant both in the nucleus and cytoplasm throughout the 1- and 2-cell stages. SLBP was depleted in 4-cell embryos in a process independent of DNA replication, and was not detected again until the late 8-cell stage. From the late 8-cell stage to the early blastocyst stage, SLBP was detected exclusively in the cytoplasm. Interestingly, in late blastocysts, SLBP was translocated to the nucleus. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clarke, Hugh</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd992.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc64v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mice -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chromatin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oogenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genetic regulation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q845w"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expression of human prolidase in E. coli : kinetic and metal binding properties</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carriles, Claudia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Expression of human prolidase in E. coli: Kinetic and metal binding properties. Massive iminodipeptiduria, severe skin ulcers, and mild mental retardation mark Prolidase Deficiency, a rare autosomal recessive disorder. In vitro, Prolidase requires incubation with Mn 2+ for maximal activity, however, the in vivo role of metal in prolidase catalysis has not been clarified. Human Prolidase cDNA was cloned into the bacterial expression vector pRSET C. The plasmid expresses a chimeric protein consisting of a hexahistidine tag and enterokinase site at the N-terminus of prolidase. This protein was purified to homogeneity. Several properties of the purified prolidase were examined. Prolidase preferentially bound Mn in vivo. In vitro incubation and atomic absorption studies revealed a positive correlation between activity and Mn2+ content, and a negative correlation between Zn content and activity. Prolidase has two distinct metal binding sites each binding two metals with different metal binding affinities towards Mn2+ and Zn2+. Prolidase thermostability was directly proportional to percent Mn2+ content. In addition, chelators inhibited prolidase activity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hechtman, Peter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bk32p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q845w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Prolidase</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zd28k"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cultivation of wild palms in the rainforest of Darién, Panamá</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cansari, Rogelio</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Great importance is currently being given to any type of ecosystem; the tropical forest is one of them and it is our case. Also, in the same way, importance is given to ecosystems inhabitants, which in one or another manner depend of the ecosystems and for many years have demonstrated a harmonious relation with their environment. In consequence, this thesis in its first chapter describes relevant issues of human communities that have lived for many years in the tropical forest located in the Darien province in the Republic of Panama. These communities are of the Embera and Wounaan indigenous groups. In particular, I present their point of view and the negative experiences that these groups have found with the scientific research which, in fact, has been conducted within their territories and that they have also been the object of for many years. Due to these conditions, the Embera and Wounaan state the wed to establish new policies to initiate a method of mutual understanding with an individuals and organized groups interested in conducting work in their territory. One of the proposals is to acknowledge participation and the right to understand and explain what is planned to be conducted as a research and to return obtained results by means of a well structured document.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Potvin, Catherine</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b5475.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd28k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Palms -- Panama -- Darien Province -- Seeds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Germination</dc:subject><dc:subject>Embera Indians -- Panama -- Darien Province</dc:subject><dc:subject>Waunana Indians -- Panama -- Darien Province</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rain forests -- Research -- Panama -- Darien Province</dc:subject><dc:subject>Palms -- Planting -- Panama -- Darien Province</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x598s"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evidence for a receptor binding 24R, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 in developing bone</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Byrd, Alyson</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Although 24R,25(OH)2D3 has been implicated in bone development, its biological role and mechanism of action remain controversial. In search for evidence of a receptor, nuclear and cytosol extracts were isolated from mandibles and calvaria of E17.5 mice. Competition and saturation analysis identified a saturable, specific and high affinity (Kd=1.1nM) 24R,25(OH) 2D3 binding-protein. The results of these and sucrose sedimentation studies indicate that this protein is not vitamin D receptor (VDR) or vitamin D binding protein (DBP). Tissue specificity experiments suggest that this putative receptor is also present in liver but not brain. pBDGal4-hRXRalpha bait was used to screen neonate and embryonal mandible/calvaria cDNA libraries using the yeast two-hybrid system. PCR screening was also performed using primers from the zinc-finger region of the VDR. To date no positive clones have been identified. Isolation of this putative receptor will provide valuable insight into the mechanism of this metabolite's role in bone development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>St-Arnaud, Rene</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10ws477.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x598s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Human Development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719p481"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structure and evolution of supernumerary chromosomes in the Pacific giant salamander Dicamptodon tenebrosus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brinkman, Jacquelyn N.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Pacific Giant salamander, Dicamptodon tenebrosus, from the Pacific Northwest of North America has variable numbers of supernumerary chromosomes, from 0 to 10, per individual. B chromosome frequency among populations varies geographically such that salamanders from the most southern and northern regions have lower average numbers of B chromosomes than salamanders in the middle of the range. This variation in B frequency may be correlated with both historical and climatic factors. To assess how the supernumerary chromosomes originated in D. tenebrosus, B chromosome DNA was isolated by microdissection and amplified by degenerate oligonucleotideprimed PCR. The B DNA hybridized similarly to genomic DNA from individuals of D. tenebrosus and the related species D. copei and D. ensatus demonstrating that the supernumerary chromosomes were derived from the normal chromosome complement. Unique hybridization bands in both D. copei and D. tenebrosus suggest that the shared sequences have evolved independently.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Green, David M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55md964.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719p481</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dicamptodon -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chromosomes</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cz733"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The optical properties of paper and polyethylene mulches and their effect on growth and development of head lettuce (Lactuca sativa L.), on microclimate modification and weed control in organic soil</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brault, Dominique, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lettuce plants (Lactuca sativa L. var. Ithaca) were transplanted on different beige and black paper mulches and on a coextruded white/black polyethylene mulch in organic soil in 1997 and 1998. Non-weeded and weeded control plots were also used. Plant mortality in 1997 for plants grown on bare soil was 10 to 15% greater than that of mulched plants. Head weight was found to be 3.6 times (1997) and 12 times (1998) greater for lettuce grown on mulch compared with a weeded control. The transmission, reflection and absorption of light of the white/black polyethylene mulch and black paper mulch remained stable over the course of the experiment while those of the other papers changed over time. Paper mulch decomposition occurred during the experiment. Although, black paper mulch was the only mulch that gave complete control of weed growth, weed populations present under the beige papers were too small in terms of the size and number of weeds to cause lettuce yield reduction.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stewart, Katrine</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jenni, Sylvie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579v44f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz733</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mulching</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lettuce -- Growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lettuce -- Weed control</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plastics in agriculture</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290c682"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Diet and reproductive success of herring gulls nesting on the middle north shore of the Gulf of St. Lawrence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boyne, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Breeding biology and diet of Herring Gulls Larus argentatus were studied on Ile Nue, in the Mingan Archipelago National Park Reserve, in the Gulf of St. Lawrence. Nesting parameters were measured 1994--1996, and fledging success and diet were followed in 1996. Clutch size was low in all three years of the study, and hatching success was low in 1995. Low clutch size and hatching success could not be explained by researcher disturbance, predation, or competition for nest sites, leaving food-stress as the most likely explanation. To reduce the biases associated with determining diet, we used four methods to estimate diet. The 1996 breeding season was divided into three periods using changes in the number of gulf pellets collected from roost sites as an indirect measure of dietary changes; these periods corresponded to the pre-spawning, spawning, and post-spawning periods of capelin Mallotus villosus. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Titman, Rodger D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq26m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c682</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Herring gull -- Québec (Province) -- Mingan Islands -- Reproduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Herring gull -- Food -- Québec (Province) -- Mingan Islands</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rk22w"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Diversity and zoogeography of Brachycera (Diptera) in disjunct grasslands of the southern Yukon</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boucher, Stéphanie, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The diversity and zoogeography of Diptera (Brachycera) of disjunct xeric grasslands in the southern Yukon were studied. Over 20,000 flies were collected representing 32 families and 213 species. In terms of abundance, the predacious guild dominated (54% of total specimens) due mostly to the family Chamaemyiidae which represented 45% of all specimens. In terms of diversity, the phytophagous and parasitoid guilds were dominant (25.5% of total species each). The most diverse families were Agromyzidae (32 species), Chloropidae (31 species), Tachinidae (23 species) and Pipunculidae (20 species). Thirty-four undescribed species were collected and 58 species were recorded for the first time in the Yukon. Zoogeographic analysis indicates that the Diptera fauna of these grasslands is dominated by widespread Nearctic or Holarctic species, but the fauna also includes southern grassland species with disjunct distributions, and species endemic to Beringia. The presence of endemic and disjunct species suggests that these grasslands were present in Beringia during the Wisconsinan and acted as a refugium for grassland Diptera.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wheeler, T. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn59z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rk22w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Grasslands -- Yukon</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diptera -- Yukon</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860902t"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Germination ecology of Carex (Cyperaceae) : effects of light, stratification, and soil moisture</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bond, Alison Marguerite</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Congeneric species occupying different habitats might be expected to have different seed dormancy strategies and germination requirements while those growing in the same habitats may be more similar. I tested this hypothesis with a broad survey of the germination of 51 Carex species from mesic deciduous forests, wet deciduous forests, and wetland or seasonally flooded areas in response to different controlled environmental conditions. A canonical discriminant analysis based on the responses of 29 species to various treatments showed clear differences among seeds from each habitat with respect to germination behaviour. Germination of seeds from mesic deciduous forest species was generally faster after moist stratification than after either submersion or dry storage. In seeds from most wet areas of deciduous forest, wetland, or seasonally flooded habitats, germination was similar or greater after submerged as compared to moist stratification. Total germination was significantly increased by light in all species except Carex pedunculata , an ant-dispersed species. Germination was not significantly different on a poorly drained peat soil than on a well-drained sandy loam. Seeds of most species were at least physiologically dormant at maturity and germination of fresh seeds was generally low. Spring germination was similar among species from all habitats and generally began in late May or early June, at fairly high temperatures (min 7°C, max 17°C), which is unusual for forest species but consistent among Carex species.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w192j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860902t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Germination</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carex</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085n482"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of combined inhaled bronchodilator therapy in the treatment of COPD</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Benayoun, Serge</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The introduction of a single inhaler comprising a beta2-agonist and ipratropiurn (CombiventRTM) in the treatment of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) should enhance compliance, improve patient outcomes and result in lower medication costs. Using the Saskatchewan Health databases, a cohort of subjects initiating treatment with CombiventRTM was identified and followed up to one year. A reference cohort was formed from all subjects who were dispensed, for the first time, two canisters, one of ipratropium and one of inhaled beta 2-agonist, on the same day. CombiventRTM users presented lower costs associated with inhaled bronchodilators (RR = 0.83; 95% Cl: 0.76 -- 0.92), despite a slight increase in overall use of these medications (RR = 1.16; 95% Cl: 1.07 -- 1.26). Moreover, the use of other respiratory drugs and antibiotics was unchanged (RR = 1.03; 95% Cl: 0.93 -- 1.16). The availability of a simpler dosing regimen did not alter significantly the treatment of COPD and resulted in appreciable cost savings.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Suissa, Samy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515q61g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085n482</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s454r"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The equivariant Grothendieck group of certain contractible threefolds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bell, Jason Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis consists of two parts. In the first part, projective modules are considered. The main objective is to give criteria, which when satisfied allow us to decide whether or not a projective module is stably free and whether or not it is free. We do this by analysis of the Grothendieck group of a ring and by studying cancellation theorems. The second part is similar, except that in this section equivariant projective modules are considered. The focus is on deciding whether or not an equivariant projective module is in fact equivariantly stably free. We do this by studying the equivariant Grothendieck group. Finally, we compute the structure of the equivariant Grothendieck group for well-known examples of contractible affine varieties.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Russell, Peter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c69b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s454r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89d870g"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic identification of the Lactobacillus species using PCR-based pepN sequences</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bélanger, Elisabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To improve the existing methods based on phenotype and/or genotype a new genotyping method was investigated to identify Lactobacillus species. The method used the polymerase chain reaction (PCR) to amplify specific sequences of aminopeptidase (pepN) genes. The primers for the PCR reactions derived from a pepN sequence of Lactobacillus rhamnosus S93. PepN amplification products of 387 bp were obtained from forty three Lactobacillus strains and from some strains of Lactococcus (3), Streptococcus (2) and Bifidobactertium (5). Restriction fragment length polymorphisms (RFLPs) and single-strand conformation polymorphisms (SSCP) methods were used to detect polymorphisms among amplified aminopeptidase DNA fragments from the different Lactobacillus strains. The results of RFLPs after digestions with Sau3A I, Rsa I and Tru9 I confirmed that the PCR products were specific. According to the fingerprints generated, Lactobacillus species tested could be grouped in four. SSCP allowed a good discrimination between different pepN PCR products of the same size. Some Lactobacillus strains, Lb. plantarum and Lb. rhamnosus showed the different ssDNA patterns. Though for many strains of Lactobacillus the SSCP patterns were similar, no general comparison can be made because all the samples were not loaded on the same SSCP polyacrylamide gel. The SSCP, PCR-based method can be easily modified to increase the rate of polymorphism detection. This new genetic identification method is different from others because it uses specific pepN DNA sequences for each strain tested and it uses SSCP to detect the presence of polymorphisms. The method is also applicable to other genera of lactic acid bacteria.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lee, B. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d6362.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d870g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lactobacillus -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lactobacillus -- Identification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aminopeptidases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polymerase chain reaction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881p19g"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Postnatal maturation of the electroretinogram of the guinea pig (Cavia porcellus)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Behn, Darren</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Unlike most rodents, the guinea pig (Cavia porcellus) is born with its eyes open. It has been claimed that most of the functional and structural maturation of the retina takes place in utero. In fact, to our knowledge, no study has specifically examined if there was a postnatal maturation of the retina in guinea pigs. The aim of this study was to determine whether the retinal development of the guinea pig continued after birth. The results showed that both photopic (cone) and scotopic (rod) function continue to develop after birth, the former taking more tune to reach maturity than the later.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lachapelle, Pierre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vw14f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881p19g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fz853"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biocatalysis of tyrosinase in organic solvent media using phenolic substrate models</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bao, Haihong</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The biocatalysis of tyrosinase was investigated in selected organic solvent media, using catechin as substrate. The results showed that the optimal enzymatic activity was obtained at pH 6.2, 6.6, 6.0 and 6.2 in heptane, toluene, dichloromethane and dichloroethane media, respectively. The kinetic studies indicated that the Km values were 5.38, 1.03, 2.52 and 4.03 mM, for the enzymatic reaction in heptane, toluene, dichloromethane and dichloroethane media, respectively, whereas the Vmax values were 12.2 x 10--4, 3.3 x 10--4, 14.7 x 10--4 and 12.0 x 10--4 deltaA mug protein--1 sec--1 , respectively. The results showed that the change in acetone concentration, used as co-solvent for the tyrosinase biocatalysis, from 5 to 30% (v/v) in the heptane medium resulted in a decrease of 4.3 to 96.7% in enzymatic activity. However, the presence of 12.5, 22.0 and 22.0% of acetone in the media of dichloromethane, dichloroethane and toluene resulted in a maximal increase in enzymatic activity of 42.6, 71.8 and 92.1%, respectively. Moreover, the biocatalysis of tyrosinase in dichloromethane and heptane reaction media, using model phenolic substrates was also investigated. The Km values for the tyrosinase biocatalysis in dichloromethane medium, using 4-methyl catechol, catechol and catechin as substrates, were 2.21, 2.36 and 2.52 mM, respectively, whereas the Vmax values were 5.1 x 10--4 , 6.0 x 10--4 and 14.7 x 10 --4 deltaA mug protein--1 sec --1, respectively. In addition, the Km values for tyrosinase biocatalysis in the heptane medium, using p-cresol, catechol and catechin as substrates, were 1.07, 4.32 and 5.38 mM, respectively, whereas the Vmax values were 0.8 x 10--4, 1.0 x 10 --4 and 12.2 x 10--3 deltaA mug protein--1 sec--1, respectively. The characterization of the end products resulting from the tyrosinase biocatalysis, using selected substrates, was carried out by spectrophotometeric scanning, differential scanning calorimetry and pyrolysis/gas chromatography coupled to</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kermasha, Selim</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cw21h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz853</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Phenol oxidase</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polyphenol oxidase</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq524jq989"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vis musculi : the use of muscle as a power source for implantable cardiac assist device design</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Badhwar, Vinay</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Transformed fatigue resistant skeletal muscle has been proposed as a potential power source for totally implantable ventricular assist systems (VAS). The goal of this study was to determine the optimal latissimus dorsi muscle (LDM) configuration capable of obtaining maximum power output. A device was designed to measure the power output and performance characteristics at varying levels of preload from each of four in situ configurations in Watts/kg of muscle(W/kg). Eight LDMs were acutely measured and revealed peak power output as follows: Sub-Dorsi (compliance chamber between LDM and chest wall): 8.3 +/- 1.6 W/kg; Circular (chamber in skeletal muscle ventricle): 16.4 +/- 6.2 W/kg; Linear-Origin (measurements from LDM thoracolumbar origin): 47.1 +/- 4.4 W/kg; Linear-Insertion (measurements from LDM humeral insertion): 59.9 +/- 12.1 W/kg, (ANOVA, p &lt; 0.0001). A linear oriented LDM is capable of generating maximal power output comparable to current VAS requirements. Confirmation of these findings in mansformed, conformed, fatigue-resistant muscle will provide information essential for the optimal design of muscle powered ventricular assist systems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chiu, Ray C-J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vj89t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq989</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c481w"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quantitative analysis of metabolic breast images from Positron Emission Mammography (PEM)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aznar, Marianne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>X-ray mammography cannot always distinguish between benign and malignant breast lesions. This leads to unnecessary biopsies, costs, and stress for the patient. Positron Emission Mammography (PEM) provides images of increased glucose metabolism in malignant tumours compared with healthy tissue. After injection of a radioactively-labelled glucose analog, cancerous tumours appear as bright spots on the breast image. Quantitative analysis of PEM images consists in comparing the amount of activity absorbed in both breasts of a patient. Based on ROC analysis of 15 subjects, an asymmetry of 10% in the number of counts detected from each breast was taken as a sign of cancer. The application of the count asymmetry method seems to results in a 22% improvement of PEM accuracy (from 64% to 86%). It is particularly useful for the detection of big or diffuse tumours. Quantitative data will also provide tools for future applications of PEM technology, such as follow-up of patients after cancer therapy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thompson, C. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nk30t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c481w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics, Medical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913r959"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Relationships between microbial physiological status and nitrogen availability in forest soils</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Au, William R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Although the physiological nitrogen demand of the soil microbial biomass is a major determinant of N mineralization in forest soils, the exact nature of the relationship is unclear. This study investigated the relationships between a respiration-based indicator of microbial physiological N demand (NIR) and N availability in forest soils. NIR was found to correlate significantly with net mineralized N in the field and annual foliar litterfall N fluxes. In a laboratory incubation, NIR was shown to be sensitive to changes in soil available C and N pools. These results demonstrated that microbial physiological N demand is determined by relative availabilities of labile C and N, and that it is significantly related to N cycling in forest soils. Results from a seasonal study of a forested watershed suggest that nutrient availability determined tree production and soil C availability, which in turn determined microbial physiological N demand and nitrogen dynamics in the forest.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fyles, J. W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236420h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r959</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nitrogen cycle</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Forest soils -- Fertilization</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adf65v9853"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modelling the interannual variability of the Arctic sea ice cover</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Arfeuille, Gilles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A thermodynamic-dynamic sea ice model based on the granular material rheology of Tremblay and Mysak is used to study the interannual variability of the Arctic sea ice cover during the 41-year period 1958--1998. The sea ice model is coupled to both a mixed layer ocean model and a one-layer thermodynamic atmospheric model. The model is first run with monthly climatology for most of the thermodynamic and dynamic forcing components to obtain a stable periodic seasonal cycle. For the 41-year run, the monthly wind stress forcing is derived from analyzed sea level pressures from the National Centers for Environmental Prediction (NCEP Reanalysis) data. The atmospheric thermodynamic forcings are based on monthly climatology. In this thesis we explore the high-latitude sea ice circulation and thickness changes due to year-to-year variations in the wind field. We focus our study on the interannual variability of the sea ice. volume in the Arctic Basin, and the subsequent changes in the export of sea ice from the Arctic Basin into the northern North Atlantic via Fram Strait. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mysak, Lawrence A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k7244.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v9853</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical Geography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physical Oceanography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azp38wf96r"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Phenotypic analyses of PTP-PEST null cells and gene targeting of its substrate, p130cas</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Angers-Loustau, Alexandre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To understand the physiological role of the protein tyrosine phosphatase (PTP) PEST, the phenotypes of PTP-PEST (--/--) mouse fibroblasts have been studied PTP-PEST was shown to translocate to the membrane periphery following stimulation by the extracellular matrix protein fibronectin, and to play a role in cell migration, spreading, and cytokinesis. For this action, PTP-PEST was shown to regulate the phosphorylation levels of p130cas, paxillin, FAK and PSTPIP, and their association with SH2 domain-containing proteins like Src and Crk. From these proteins, p130cas is known to be a direct substrate. Experiments for the obtention of p130cas (--/--) embryos and cell lines have also been initiated, up to the generation of adult chimeric animals. In the process, a genomic fragment of p130cas containing a C-terminal exon has been cloned and analysed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tremblay, Michel L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sj385.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wf96r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f568p"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Field testing of a biological system for reducing nitrate pollution</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Andrade, Marc-David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The overall goal of this study was to investigate the possibility of reducing NO3-- concentration in the lower soil horizon by promoting denitrification. The study looked at an inexpensive remediation practice for subsurface-drained fields in order to degrade N0j' and consequently diminish NO3-- pollution. The experiments were conducted on a corn field at the Macdonald Campus Farm. The field was composed of sandy loam soil underlined by a clay layer. In this study, sucrose was injected at a concentration of 20 mg L --1 within the subirrigation water. Furthermore, the water table was maintained at approximately 70 cm from the soil surface in order to create an anaerobic environment that allows for denitrification. The purpose was to furnish dissolved organic carbon (DOC) to the resident microorganisms in order to carryout a higher amount of denitrification. The NO3-- levels in ground water were monitored weekly. Gas samples were taken from the field to observe whether N2O emissions increased as a result of the treatment This was considered to be important since N2O is a greenhouse gas. It was found that the addition of sucrose significantly resulted in a faster rate of denitrification. The higher biological activity severely damped the NO3-- peaks in the subsoil, which arose following major rainfall events. The addition of sucrose at 20 mg L--1 was found to be significant in lowering the amounts of released N2O. Therefore, adding DOC in the subirrigation water not only helped remediate water contamination but also served as a remedy to atmospheric pollution. In addition, the hydraulic conductivity of the soil was monitored to ensure that no bioclogging arose from an anticipated rise in the bacterial population due to the addition of sucrose. It was found that the addition of sucrose at 20 mg L--1 did not contribute in anyway to reduce the soil's hydraulic conductivity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Prasher, Saiv O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77ss01d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f568p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Subirrigation -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Denitrification -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soils -- Nitrate content -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil remediation -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad217qr71r"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structure and function of the adult rat vas deferens</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Andonian, Sero Barkev</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Four aspects of the function of the vas deferens were examined by light microscope immunocytochemistry of Bouin-fixed, paraffin-embedded material. First, the expression of aquaporin-1 by endothelial cells of the vascular channels in the lamina propria of the distal region, suggested water transport from the lumen of the vas deferens via the dilated intercellular spaces to underlying vascular channels, the function of which may be to concentrate sperm. Second, the expression of 3beta-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase by principal cells was indicative of steroid synthesis. Third, the ability of the vas deferens to create a special environment for protecting spermatozoa in the lumen was investigated using anti-glutathione S-transferase (GST) antibodies. Both principal and basal cells showed varying degrees of GST expression in the different regions of the cauda and vas deferens, suggesting a complex, changing environment of substrates to which epithelial cells and sperm are subjected. Fourth, the epithelial cells lining the cauda epididymidis and vas deferens were investigated for their secretory and endocytic functions. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hermo, Louis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn80x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr71r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abg257h05w"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Maternal dietary glucose intake affects neonatal gastrointestinal development in rats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anderson, Susan A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To test the hypothesis that maternal glucose restriction (GR) would compromise small intestine (SI) growth and development, we used a diet induced model of IUGR. Pregnant rats and offspring were fed isoenergetic diets {0% (deficient), 12, 24% (restricted), 60% (adequate) glucose) from gestation day (gd) 0 through adolescence. SI tissue was collected at gd20, birth, 12--24h, postnatal day (pd) 7, 15, 21, 28, 35, 49 and in controls. GR affected pup weight at early timepoints, resulting in IUGR; beyond effects due to differences in body wt, GR compromised SI length at 12--24h and promoted SI growth during peak lactation (pd15; total and distal wts). Dietary glucose regulated in utero (gd20) expression of sodium-dependent glucose co-transporter (SGLT1) protein. Diet-induced precocious maturation of lactase and sucrase was observed in glucose deficient animals. In summary, there were periodic but no permanent effects of dietary glucose intake on gut growth and development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Koski, K. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc401.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257h05w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pregnancy -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glucose -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gastrointestinal system -- Growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rats -- Development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Low-carbohydrate diet</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gg13g"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Response of plant roots and pastureland soils to increasing CO2 concentration</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al-Traboulsi, Manal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In an attempt to investigate the cause of change in the competitive ability between monocots and dicots in a pastureland in Farnham, Quebec under CO2 enrichment, I chose to study the response of Plantago major (dicot) and Poa pratensis (monocot) grown in ambient and elevated CO2 chambers, hypothesizing that a large increase in root biomass of dicots would be observed under elevated CO 2. A transient stimulation of root biomass of Plantago major was found during the first month of CO2 exposure but disappeared later. The second objective of this study was to examine the effect of 5 years of CO2 enrichment both on root biomass and on total C and N content of roots and soil in the pasture. The largest belowground growth was recorded for Taraxacum officinale. Plantago major responded by achieving the highest aboveground growth. N content of CO2 enriched roots was reduced. This change in the elemental composition of root tissues might negatively affect the process of decomposition and therefore, the nutrient availability to soil microbes and plants. The observed reduction of NO3 in CO2 enriched soil maybe due to greater N immobilization caused by the expected increase in microbial populations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Potvin, Catherine</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw667.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg13g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soils -- Carbon content</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pastures -- Effect of atmospheric carbon dioxide on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kentucky bluegrass -- Roots</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plantago major -- Roots</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0r9675838"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanisms of drug resistance in malaria</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abrahem, Abrahem F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Plasmodium falciparum is a protozoan parasite that causes malaria, a disease that is widely spread in the tropical world. Chloroquine has been very effective against malaria since it was introduced into the field until the emergence of chloroquine resistant malaria. Chloroquine resistant malaria has become widely spread in the endemic area. In addition, cross resistance to other antimalarial drugs that are different in structure and function has been reported, even though some of these drugs had not been previously used in that particular region. The objective of this study was to determine the molecular mechanism of this resistance. Actinomycin D resistant Plasmodium falciparum was selected in vitro from the drug sensitive parental clone, 3D7. Interestingly, we found that the selected strain is resistant to chloroquine, mefloquine, antimalarial drugs, and Rhodamine 123. Comparison between 3D7 parental and 3D7R/act-D2 resistant P. falciparum did not show a difference in the level of expression of pfmdr1 previously implicated in the drug resistance. In addition we found that the level of accumulation of two drugs actinomycin D is reduced in the resistant parasite as compared with the sensitive one. Further studies indicated that the reduction in the drug accumulation was due to the increase in drug efflux. Furthermore, to identify if other P-glycoprotein homologues are involved in the resistance, oligonucleotide primers to conserved sequences in ABC domains have been used. An ABC protein homologous to subunit 4 of the 26S proteasome complex has been cloned. In vitro transcription, translation and immunoprecipitation analysis were done using reticulocytes lysate and polyclonal antibodies generated against peptide sequence in the P. falciparum S4 subunit. Surprisingly a decrease in the expression of this gene was found in the resistant clone, 3D7R/act-D2, compared to its parental cell line as determined by Northern blot analysis. Studies are in progress to determine</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Georges, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks57r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r9675838</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Malaria</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drug resistance in microorganisms</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plasmodium falciparum</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w683s"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of purified extracellular lipase fractions from Pseudomonas fragi CRDA 037</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abdul Wahab, Aliaa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The partially purified extracellular lipase from Pseudomonas fragi CRDA 037, obtained by ammonium sulfate precipitation, was subjected to further purification by successive ion-exchange and size-exclusion chromatographies using the Fast Protein Liquid Chromatography system. The purification of the partially purified lipase resulted in two enzymatic fractions, FIVa ' and FIVb', with a purification-fold of 169 and 195, respectively. Native electrophoretic analyses revealed the presence of three bands for fraction FIVa', with estimated molecular weights (MW) of 16.2, 25.8 and 38.5 kDa and two bands for FIVb' , with estimated MW of 15.2 and 25.8 kDa. The two purified fractions, FIVa' and FIVb', showed an optimum pH of 9.5 and 10.0, respectively, and an optimum temperature of 80°C. The Km values for FIVa' and FIVb' were 3.85 and 5.49 mM and the V max values were 2.78 and 2.09 U/mg, respectively, using triacetin as a substrate. The purified lipase fractions retained more than 90% of their activity when stored at room temperature for 36 h. The lipase activity of the purified lipase fractions was completely inhibited by 10 mM of FeCl 2, FeCl3 and Ellman's reagent. However, 10 mM of CaCl2 and EDTA activated the two purified lipase fractions by 20 to 50%. Both fractions exhibited high specificity towards short- and long-chain fatty acid esters of triacylglycerols. Fraction FIVa' showed higher specificity towards triacetin, tristearin and tripalmitin, whereas fraction FIVb' exhibited higher activity with triacetin, trimyristin and triolein. In addition, the two purified lipase fractions were able to catalyze, to almost the same extent, the hydrolysis of butter and olive, canola and fish oils. The gas-liquid chromatography analysis of free fatty acids, obtained by the hydrolysis of the four edible oils, revealed that fraction FIVa' was more specific for the hydrolysis of fatty acid esters chain lengths of C12 to C18 whereas fraction FIVb' showed a non-specific hydrolyzin</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kermasha, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f811x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w683s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pseudomonas fragi</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lipase -- Separation</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>