<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abr86b650p"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Théorie et critique littéraires dans la revue Présence africaine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tetreault-Simard, Diane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Founded in 1947, the review Présence Africaine has been at the cross-roads of the social, political, and cultural revolution of the Black world; it was instrumental in the coming of a literature. In this thesis, we have attempted to show the main avenues followed by literary criticism in Présence Africaine. In keeping with the unity of the review, we have placed the different problems, in the chronological order, as they were posed by the Africans. From its beginnings up to the sixties, Présence Africaine has been particularly active in defining literature in relation to the colonial situation of Africa. A brief presentation of the review, its origins, its goals, its evolution, lead us to describe the major currents of Black-African literature. The review has caused the black intellectuals to become conscious of the specificity of Black Men; this movement developed within the concept of "négritude", which we will study from a historical and literary point of view. Présence Africaine has also studied the problem of national literatures, which was the normal- outcome of the search for African roots. Furthermore, conscious of this situation, the Black intellectual commits himself in the fight against colonialism, first by his writings, but also through a concerted effort and influence with his brothers. Présence Africaine has thus been a witness to the birth of Black-African literature and a platform for the opinions of its writers and artists. We have studied the different currents of criticism in Présence Africaine. It has allowed us, we hope, to define Black-African literature and to perceive its present trends.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vigneault, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r175v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b650p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r4178"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Meteorology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rain attenuation statistics across Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ro, Chul-Un</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A method to generate rain attenuation statistics has been confirmed experimentally: actual attenuation statistics were obtained from a 5-mile microwave link operating at 11.2 GHz and compared with the results of computations from raingauge records observed alongside the link. The storm velocity required in this method was estimated from radar and from 700-mb-level wind speed. These were compared. The resulting statistics suggest that the storm velocity can be estimated from radiosonde observations where the radar facilities are not available. Using the method, 10-year attenuation statistics were computed in the regions of Halifax, Montreal, Toronto, Thunder Bay, Winnipeg and Edmonton. The statistics of attenuation for various hop lengths and various frequencies have been compiled. They are 10-year mean probabilities, year-to-year variation of the probabilities, individual duration of fade and joint and conditional probability as well as rainfall rate statistics in the regions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>ufuca, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n645t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r4178</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Meteorology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kt455"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Measurement of cardiac output using radioactive xenon</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Richard, Philippe F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cardiac output can be determined by infusing radioactive xenon at a constant rate and measuring the Xe concentration in the pulmonary artery and a peripheral artery. To validate this technique, a roller pump was inserted in series with the superior and inferior vena cavae. Venous return was thus equal to pump flow. In 6 mongrel dogs, a total of 19 flow measurements were obtained using xenon and compared to the pump flow. The correlation was excellent ("r" = 0.953). Cardiac output can also be determined by inserting a known mass of Xe-133 within the lumen of the gastrointestinal tract. Using 4 anaesthetized dogs, 10 pairs of measurements were obtained by both the constant infusion and intestinal injection techniques with a correlation "r" = 0.986. The constant infusion technique was applied in 10 critically ill patients. The 30 results obtained in these patients are compatible with associated clinical state and are compared with results obtained, in similar state, by others authors using standard methods.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacLean, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kk36v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kt455</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3f462845k"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Slow rhythms of neural activity associated with mayer waves</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Preiss, George</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Sustained oscillations of blood pressure (BP) unrelated to respiratory rate, and termed Mayer waves were investigated in Nembutal anaesthetized cats. The waves had mean repetition rates and mean amplitudes of 2.5 cycles/min and 26.6 mm Hg respectively. Spontaneous respiratory chest movements revealed a waxing and waning rhythm similar to Cheyne-Stokes breathing during Mayer waves. Sympathetic single and multiunit discharges (in thoracic cord and cervical nerve respectively) and phrenic activity in paralysed artificially ventilated animals showed a rhythmic variation in rate and amplitude respectively, with the same period as that of the Mayer waves. Peak discharges in both nerves preceded the BP peak by 7 sec. Since Mayer waves and Cheyne-Stokes type of breathing were present after bilateral carotid and aortic denervation and both efferent neural rhythms were sustained when sources of feedback were eliminated by stabilizing BP, a common central origin for both rhythms was postulated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Polosa, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343w13d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462845k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad217qs95j"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Uptake of cyanocobalamin-co57 and other macromolecules by Ehrlich ascites tumor cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Peirce, Karen L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Three membrane transport systems were examined in vitro in Ehrlich ascites cells. Fluid uptake was measured by sucrose-H3 uptake; endocytosis was measured by radioactive I131 serum albumin (RISA) uptake; the uptake of carrier macromolecules was measured by cyanocobalamin-Co57 (B12) uptake. Biphasic uptake was observed for B12 and RISA uptake, the secondary uptake being dependent on temperature. Sucrose uptake was only partially temperature dependent. Iodacetate inhibited B12, sucrose and protamine sulphate-stimulated-RISA uptakes. A reversible inhibition of B12 primary and secondary uptakes occurred with 0.0015M EGTA, whereas RISA uptake was unaffected. Secondary B12 uptake was inhibited by the vinca alkaloids and colchicine; only primary albumin uptake was decreased by vinblastine. Cytochalasin B had little effect on all three systems. It was concluded that all uptake systems could have been by endocytosis, each varying in specificity and in metabolic and structural requirements.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cooper, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf88n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qs95j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r8577"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Glial cells in semithin sections: identification of cell types and the radioautographic demonstration that glial cells originate from cells of the subependymal layer in rat brain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paterson, Jean A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The staining of half-micron Epon sections with toluidine blue permits reliable identification of neuroglia in rat cerebrum: astrocytes, microglia, and three subgroups of oligodendrocyte. Other characteristic cells are found in the subependymal layer; similar cells near this layer are called free subependymal cells. Tritiated thymidine injected into the lateral ventricle of 100g rats allows strong labeling of the subependymal region, as demonstrated by dioautography. Examination of animals at various times after injection reveals that some of the labeled cells arising in the subependyma emigrate as free subependymal cells to corpus callosum. There, successive changes in labeling indicate that free subependymal cells become light oligodendrocytes, which then become medium shade, which in turn yield dark oligodendrocytes. Different labeling patterns, however, are observed for astrocytes and microglia. In conclusion, in 100g rats, free subependymal cells migrate to corpus callosum, where they transform into oligodendrocytes, probably into astrocytes, and possibly into microglia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leblond, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tg18d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r8577</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s336v"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hormone receptors in bone: an evaluation of the uptake of estrogen and cortisol into bone cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nutik, Gordon P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The uptakes of the radioactive hormones, 3H-estradiol-17β and 3H-cortisol, in bone cells were evaluated. Nuclear and cytoplasmic fractions were prepared from pulverized bone. Incubations were done in 3H-estradiol-17β, 3H-estradiol-17β plus tenfold amount of unlabelled estradiol, 3H-cortisol, and 3H-cortisol plus tenfold unlabelled cortisol. There was no difference in the uptake of 3H-estradiol-17β alone or the 3H-estradiol-17β plus unlabeled estradiol, leading to the conclusion that there is no specific binding of estrogens in bone cells. Cortisol uptake studies initially showed competitive uptake, but this uptake was later proven to be due to Transcortin, a plasma corticosteroid binding globulin. After dexamethasone uptake studies, a specific cellular binding glucocorticoid, no uptake was seen - signifying the absence of a cytoplasmic binding site for cortisol in bone. The lack of specific binding suggests absence of estrogen and cortisol receptor molecules in bone cells.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cruess, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74ct75n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s336v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25xc72m"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A search for non-aldosterone salt-retaining humoral factors in the plasma, urine, and liver of chronic canal dogs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mittelman, Joseph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dogs with chronic partial constriction of the thoracic inferior vena cava (chronic caval dogs) develop sodium retention, ascites and edema. Experimental studies have shown in the past that a reduction in glomerular filtration rate and hyperaldosteronism separately or in combination are not the sole determinants of progressive sodium retention in the chronic caval doge It has been suggested by at least two groups of investigators that either subtle alterations of intrarenal hemodynamics or elaboration of non-aldosterone salt retaining humoral factors, or both, may be involved in promoting tubular sodium retention in this experimental preparation. While evidence has been presented for the former proposal, the latter has not previously been systematically explored. To study the possible existence of a non-aldosterone salt-retaining humoral substance, ascitic fluid and plasmas from various drainage areas of 34 chronic caval dogs were infused into the left renal artery of small dogs pretreated with ADH and DOCA, and undergoing a modest natriuresis. On the average, no decrease in sodium excretion was observed. To further investigate this problem, ultrafiltrates of fractionated ascitic fluid, plasmas, urine, and liver homogenates in the molecular range of 500 to 50,000 were lyophilized and concentrated up to 200 times before reinfusion. In 30 assays, no evidence for a nonaldosterone salt-retaining substance was observed in the molecular range studied. Therefore, within the limits of the preparative and assay methods employed, a non-aldosterone humoral factor could not be demonstrated as an important cause for sodium retention in chronic caval dogs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Levy, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f9157.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xc72m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aff365828p"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimisation of mine capacity and cut-off grade under conditions of uncertainty</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mascall, Graham F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>After a mineral deposit has been discovered and explored a decision must be made on how to best develop it to production. This thesis deals with the problem of optimisation of the mine development decision and in particular shows how and why uncertainty must be included in the evaluation as well as profitability. In reality the mine development decision is based on limited information regarding mineral markets and mining conditions which cannot realistically be assumed to be certain. The thesis compares both uncertain and certain approaches to optimisation and shows the effects of considering uncertainty with respect to optimisation of mine capacity and cut-off grade.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacKenzie, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vt98b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365828p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mining Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af4752k96t"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Communication Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intonation in normal-hearing and hearing-impaired infants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Manolson, Hilda A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Intonation contours in the demand utterances of ten hearing impaired infants aged 12 to 24 months and ten matched normal hearing infants were measured and compared. Developmental changes within the normal-hearing infants were reflected in the time required to make fundamental frequency changes, duration of stable fundamental frequency following a change, vocalization time and number of utterances. Subgroups within the hearing impaired infants were differentiated by the frequency ranges used and by the number of amplitude changes. Number and size of fundamental frequency changes, number of amplitude changes and the frequency ranges used differentiated between normal-hearing and hearing-impaired infants. Results of this study indicate that measures of fundamental frequency and amplitude in the demand utterances of infants one to two years of age are affected by maturation and audition, thus suggesting that the role of intonation in language acquisition could be meaningfully investigated with intensive sampling of intonation contours both developmentally and in relation to marked physiological and environmental differences.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Doehring, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vx13c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752k96t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human Communications Disorders</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw3763b007"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of intracellular application of Ca2+ on the membrane properties of the spinal motoneuron</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lisiewicz, Adam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Calcium ions were injected iontophoretically into spinal motoneurons of cats under Dial anaesthesia. The calcium was released by passing a current between barrels of a compound micropipette containing calcium chloride and potassium chloride. There was a marked fall in membrane resistance and excitability; in 50% of these neurons some hyperpolarization was also observed. The mean reversal potential for the action of calcium did not differ from the reversal potential for the post-spike hyperpolarization, it was nearly 10 mV More negative than the resting membrane potential, and about 20 mV more negative than the reversal potential for IPSP, (the latter was relatively positive, owing to the leakage of chloride from the microelectrode). It was concluded that the main physiological action of the increase in free calcium in the neuroplasm caused by iontophoretic injection is to increase the membrane conductance to potassium.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Krnjevic, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tc43d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763b007</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pq962"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of thyrotropin and the long-acting thyroid stimulator on adipose tissue</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hart, Ian R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Thyrotropin (TSH) and the long-acting thyroid stimulator (LATS) have similar actions on glucose metabolism in adipose tissue in vitro. Both thyroid stimulators cause enhancement of lipolysis when added to adipose tissue slices or free fat cells from guinea pig, rat and human but LATS has no effect on that from mice. LATS is not as rapidly bound by adipose tissue and has a delayed onset of action compared to TSH. Both mediate lipolysis via adenyl cyclase. The lipolytic effect is a more sensitive assay for the detection of LATS than the mouse bioassay and using this technique LATS is detectable in the serum of 91% of Graves' disease patients.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McKenzie, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p343h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pq962</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd3760817"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Metabolism of cortisol in the human newborn</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Daniilescu-Goldinberg, D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>14C-cortisol was administered to two newborn infants and one adult, and the pattern of urinary metabolites analyzed and compared. Seventy to 86% of the radioactivity extracted in the unconjugated fraction and 86 to 100% of that extracted in the glucuronide fraction were accounted for in terms of known steroids. In the case of the infants, 6β-hydroxycortisol represented 64% of the radioactivity extracted in the unconjugated fraction, while tetrahydrocortisone (67 and 73%), cortolone (10 and 13%) and 6β-hydroxycortisol (16 and 13%) were the sole significant components of the glucuronide fraction. A small amount of radioactivity was extracted in the steroid sulfate fraction, but there was no detectable incorporation of 14C into cortisol sulfate.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Giroud, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j36b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd3760817</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988p04x"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vascular sensitivity of sympathomimetic amines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Pi-Chuan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Six sympathomimetic amines were used to investigate the postulation that the neuronal uptake process determines the sensitivity of the isolated perfused rabbit central ear artery to extra- and intraluminally applied noradrenaline and related amines. The artery was found to be more sensitive to intra- than to extraluminal noradrenaline, but the reverse was true for metaraminol, methoxamine, metanephrine, and isoproterenol. No difference was noted between the sensitivity of the artery to intra- and extraluminal phenylephrine. Drugs and procedures which impair the neuronal uptake process appeared to diminish the difference between the sensitivity of the artery to extra- and intraluminal noradrenaline, but had little or no effect on the responses of the artery to other amines. These results suggest that the neuronal uptake process is not the sole mechanism determining the sensitivity of the artery to intra- and extraluminal sympathomimetic amines.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yong, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042x174.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988p04x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amc87pt733"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Communication Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of phonatory transitions on stuttering</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blomfield, Christina J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The influence of phonatory transitions on stuttering was examined in a group of 14 young adult stutterers. Subjects performed five oral readings of two passages, one containing all-voiced sounds, and the other both voiced and voiceless sounds. Results showed, in contrast to a previous study by Adams and Reis (1971), that more stuttering was associated with the all-voiced passage and that rate of adaptation was similar for both passages. Adams and Reis's method of comparing passages appeared to be misleading, since a strong context effect was found in the present study or frequency of stuttering on voiced to voiced transitions, which was lower than expected in the combined passage. Higher than expected frequencies of stuttering were found to be associated with both voiced to voiceless and voiceless to voiced transitions in the combined passage, not only for the latter transitions as suggested by Adams and Reis. Theoretical implications and recommendations for further research were discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Doehring, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m33d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pt733</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human Communications Disorders</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q926w"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The binding of ligands to synaptosome membranes. A nuclear magnetic resonance study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yung, James W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nuclear magnetic resonance has been used to study the association of atropine and eserine with acetylchol inesterase extracted from squid head ganglia and synaptosome membranes from rat brain cortex. Line width changes of the N-methyl and phenyl groups of atropine and the N-methyl and C-methyl groups of eserine resulting from association with the enzyme and the synaptosome membranes have been used to study the interactions. The results show that whereas eserine binds at the active site of the enzyme, atropine binds at a site distinct from the active center. Further proof that the binding sites of the two ligands are distinct from each other was obtained by showing that the antichol inesterase, tetraethyl pyrophosphate (TEPP) diminished the binding of eserine but not of atropine. The effect of pH, ionic strength and TEPP on the binding of synaptosome membranes was similar to the results obtained with soluble acetylchol inesterase. This indicates that both ligands bind to the synaptosome membrane bound acetylcholinesterase. The significance of the non-catalytic site on acetylchol inesterase in relation to the acetylcholine receptor is discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kato, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053k377.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q926w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75rc020"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of oxygen breathing on the distribution of pulmonary perfusion in patients with chronic bronchitis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wilson, James</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 9 patients with chronic bronchitis and obstructive ventilator defects: 1) Perfusion was decreased in poorly ventilated regions, though to a lesser extent than the reduction in ventilation. 2) Four patients (group I) had no significant change in distribution of perfusion while breathing 40% oxygen and possible explanations are discussed. These patients all had severe chronic obstructive ventilatory defects with carbon dioxide retention and 3 had a history of cor pulmonale. 3) Five patients (group II) had a significant tendency to improve perfusion in poorly ventilated regions while breathing 40% oxygen. These patients had significantly less severe obstructive ventilatory defects than group l patients and none had a history of cor pulmonale.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anthonisen, N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mm97t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rc020</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hc892"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cardiorespiratory changes following cardiopulmonary bypass in patients with normal and abnormal preoperative cardiorespiratory function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stevenson, Charles S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We studied cardiorespiratory function following cardiopulmonary bypass for aorto-coronary bypass (six patients) and for mitral valve replacement (five patients). Our investigations were carried out within six hours of bypass. We used inspired oxygen concentrations of 21%, 40% and 100%. We measured mean pulmonary artery (PPA) and wedge (PPW) pressures, cardiac output and arterial blood gas tensions. The first group of patients had normal preoperative hemodynamic studies. Following bypass (mean duration 62 minutes) PPA and pulmonary vascular resistance remained normal despite the presence of hypoxemia (mean PaO2 61 mmHg) secondary to pulmonary shunting (mean 22%). The second group of patients had abnormal preoperative and postoperative hemodynamic studies. Following mitral valve replacement hyperoxemia (mean PaO2 330 mmHg) was associated with an abnormally elevated PPW (mean 20 mmHg) while hypoxemia (mean PaO2 59 mmHg) was associated with an almost normal PPW (mean 13 mmHg). Cardiac output decreased and systemic vascular resistance increased with hyperoxemia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hampson, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806318h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hc892</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr172125r"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Communication Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vibro-tactile cues in speech discrimination by deaf children</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sofin, Beverly A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two experiments were carried out to determine whether a vibrotactile indicator of fricative sounds would help profoundly deaf children in speech discrimination. In the first experiment ten profoundly deaf boys were tested under two conditions 1) audition supplemented with lip reading and 2) audition and lip reading supplemented by the vibrotactile cue. Results showed that the subjects performed significantly better when they were aided by the vibrotactile cue. These results remained consistent even when lip reading cues were omitted in a second experiment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ling, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085p313.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172125r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human Communications Disorders</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zk76f"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The survival of dog renal allografts following pretreatment with lymphoid cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rivard, Jean-Yves</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Following Billingham's first attempt to enhance skin grafts in the mouse in 1956, several authors reported prolongation of skin grafts following antigenic pretreatment, including in most cases passive conditioning or immunization. Non viable antigenic material was generally chosen and given intravenously or intraperitoneally. In spite of various injection schedules and doses or material, results were extremely modest, consisting in a gain of a few days in survival but often quite consistently. We include a selected list in Table I.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Guttmann, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hz661.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zk76f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb397c36w"><ual:graduationDate>1970</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rapid diagnosis of parainfluenza 1 virus by immunofluorescence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Portnoy, Joseph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The direct immunofluorescent antibody method was used for the rapid diagnosis of parainfluenza 1 virus. 60 nasopharyngeal secretion specimens known to contain a respiratory virus, as determined by previous conventional isolation procedures, were inoculated onto HeLa cell monolayers on Leighton tube coverslips and onto Rhesus monkey kidney monolayers. 24 hours later, the former were checked for fluorescence and hemadsorption, the latter only for hemadsorption. Of the inoculated specimens, 35 contained parainfluenza 1 virus. In the Rhesus monkey kidney cells hemadsorption was detected in 60%; in the HeLa cells, hemadsorption and fluorescence were obtained in 31%. Using a high multiplicity of infection, parainfluenza 1 antigen was detected 10 hours after inoculation of the HeLa cells. These results suggest that immunofluorescence is promising in the rapid diagnosis of parainfluenza 1 virus. Further fluorescent studies should include direct smears of nasopharyngeal secretions and the use of Rhesus monkey kidney instead of HeLa cells.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Spence, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z055.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397c36w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Microbiology and Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asj139511h"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Silver methenamine staining of argentaffin and related cells in the mouse duodenum as seen in the light and electron microscopes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nichols, David B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gomori 's silver methenamine stain was adapted for use in the electron microscope and applied to the mouse duodenum to investigate the endocrine cells claimed by other researchers to be argentaffin and argyrophile. After paraformaldehyde fixation it was observed that both biconcave and spherical granule endocrine cell types were argentaffin. By employing densitometry on the granules within these cell types and also by determining their percentages of spherical granules, it was discovered that the distinction between the cell types was poorly defined. It was concluded that the duodenum possessed one family of argentaffin cells with variation in number, shape and staining of granules. These findings contradicted the claim made by other investigators that only biconcave granule cells were argentaffin. It was observed that iron hematoxylin stained the same cells that silver methenamine stained and therefore concluded that iron hematoxylin could be used as a routine stain for argentaffin cells.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leblond, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f437s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139511h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515r530"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electron microscopy of in vitro irradiated human peripheral lymphocytes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moinuddin, M. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Human peripheral lymphocytes irradiated in vitro are radiosensitive. Morphologic changes are similar to those seen in the lymphoid tissue after in vivo irradiation. These changes however are non-specific. Cytoplasmic changes precede those in the nucleus. Of the cytoplasmic organelles, mithochondria are the most radiosensitive. The macrophages are radioresistant; they play a role in removing the cell debris in tissue culture. Quantitative analysis shows a relationship between the radiation dose, post-radiation interval and the extent of cell damage.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bain, B.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Albarracin, N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xc73w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515r530</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042x18d"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors influencing left ventricular function and oxygen usage in the normal and ischaemic perfused rat heart</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mierzwinski, Louise M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Current disagreements regarding the choice of substrates for optimum recovery of mechanical performance in the oxygen deprived myocardium partly results from the failure to adequately distinguish between oxygen deprivation in a region of myocardium (ischaemia) and total oxygen deprivation (hypoxia). Attempting to solve this problem, the perfused isolated rat heart, contracting auxotonically, was used to examine the effects of glucose, lactate and acetate on mechanical recoverability and oxygen usage following hypoxia or ischaemia. With glucose administration to ischaemic preparations, mechanical parameters and oxygen usage had almost recovered to their initial resting values. Similar recoverability, but to a lesser extent, occurred with lactate or acetate. However in hypoxic preparations, initial recovery was shown only with glucose, while introduction of lactate or acetate resulted in continued deterioration. This study suggests that aerobic and anaerobic metabolized substrates may serve equally well in hearts suffering ischaemic injury whereas the mechanical performance of the hypoxic heart can be only maintained through energy derived anaerobically.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fallen, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333547c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042x18d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62fc35j"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Attempted synthesis of 25-hydroxydihydrotachysterol 3</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacDonald, Bonita C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Preliminary studies concerning a general synthesis of 25-hydroxydihydrotachysterol3 from stigmasterol were carried out. In order to differentiate between the two double bonds in stigmasterol, the olefin at C - 5 was protected by means of the i-steroid formation. The side-chain was then cleaved by ozone, allowing introduction of various other side-chains by a Wittig condensation. Preparation of the "cholesterol-like" side-chain incorporating a 25-hydroxyl function was achieved by a methyl lithium reaction with 3-halo propionyl chloride. Complete details of the Wittig reaction have not yet been successfully worked out. Acid catalysis restores the double bond at C-9. Introduction of an olefin at C-9 produces the necessary diene in ring B of the steroid which undergoes ultraviolet irradiation to the triene system of tachysterol. Details of the U. V. irradiation of the diene were investigated fully on the model compound, ergosterol. Attempts to isolate tachysterol from the photolysis products proved futile. The crude irradiation products were reduced directly to their more stable diene form to yield dihydrotachysterol.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Just, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nv01g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fc35j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>