<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2227mr796"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dyadic matrix converter theory : development, and application to voltage-source-converter type matrix converter</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kazerani, Mehrdad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>For the past twenty years, the theoretical advance of the matrix converters has been impeded by the complexity arising from the time-varying trigonometric functions in their transformation matrix. In addition, the switching difficulties associated with the bidirectional switches have complicated the practical implementation of this class of converters. In this thesis, the dyadic matrix structure and the a-b-c to d-q-0 transformation have been melded together to develop the dyadic matrix converter theory which is a generalized theory for the three-phase to three-phase matrix converters. The thesis addresses the zero-sequence interaction in the matrix converters and the role of the zero-sequence elements in the Displacement Power Factor (DPF) correction on the utility-side, based on the Static VAR Controller (SVC) principle. Also, it is proved that using all the control degrees of freedom available, the dual condition of Unity Displacement Power Factor (UDPF) on side-1 and Field Vector Control (FVC) on side-2 can be established. In this thesis, a new matrix converter topology, based on the three-phase voltage-source converters, has been proposed in which the switching difficulties reported in the conventional nine-bidirectional-switch topology have been bypassed. The theoretical expectations have been verified by the simulation as well as experimental tests on a laboratory prototype of the new matrix converter topology composed of three units of voltage-source converters each rated at 1 kVA.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ooi, Boon-Teck</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d8497.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mr796</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qn95z"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Upper ocean modelling in Baie des Chaleurs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gan, Jianping, 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An eddy-resolving upper ocean model is developed to study the dynamics and thermo-dynamics of Baie des Chaleurs (BdC, 47.5-48.5N, 65.5-66.5W), Gulf of St. Lawrence (GSL), Canada. The model has primitive equation dynamics with two active layers embedded with a Kraus-Niiler type mixed layer model at the top. Forced by observed wind, atmospheric heat fluxes, river runoff and appropriate remote forcing (in particular, the Gaspe Current, GC), the model demonstrates that the mean cyclonic general circulation pattern in the bay is a consequence of the intrusion of the GC. In the mixed layer, atmospheric heat fluxes and horizontal thermal advection play a key role in the thermal balance at the eastern part of the bay. The local mixed layer fluctuations are controlled by wind and GC induced divergence. The entrainment (and its corresponding heat flux) is important at the western part of the bay and changes the mean mixed layer depth on a time scale of more than a week. Varying GC intensified the flow variations induced by the wind in the bay and improved simulation results as compared with observations. Sensitivity runs are conducted to study the effects of external forcing, important physical processes and the internal physical parameterisation on the model results and to compare these with the main model run. Experiments show that nonlinearity is very important in determining the circulation pattern in the bay. Changing external thermal forcing also modifies dynamical processes in the BdC. The fluctuations in the near surface temperature are mainly due to latent and sensible heat changes. The parameter study indicates that, the model is not overly sensitive to changes in most of the parameters, but suggests that sensitivity of the mixed layer physical parameters depends on the dynamical and thermodynamic system applied. Hydrographic and current meter data are used first to study the variability of both the dynamics and thermodynamics in the BdC and its relation to the separation/intrusion of the unsteady GC. A numerical model is then applied to gain insight into the problem. The time scales of interest range from tidal to seasonal. The results show that the kinetic energy in the BdC is dominated by the semi-diurnal tide (M$ sb2$) and periods of 5-10 days for high and low frequency bands, respectively. Most of the energy in the low frequency band is found to be induced by wind-related forcing. Both observations and model results indicate that seasonal variations in the BdC are strongly related to the characteristics of separation/intrusion of the GC, which is mainly controlled by its transport magnitude as well as phase, duration and strength of its acceleration (or deceleration). The separation occurs when (adverse) vorticity having an opposite sign from that existing upstream is generated near the separation area. Although the separation can be generated in a decelerating GC, it can also occur in an accelerating GC when the GC is strong enough to advect upstream vorticity necessary to form a recirculation and the related adverse vorticity downstream. Nonlinearity is critical to the separation. Nevertheless, separation can be generated in a linear current with strong deceleration. The GC intrudes either along the coastline (attachment) into the bay by a non-separated GC or following the separation of the GC (reattachment). Effects of various physical processes on the separation/intrusion and variability of eddies in the BdC are examined.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ingram, R. Grant</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jq70m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn95z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical Oceanography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adr26z0322"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The epidemiology and control of gastrointestinal nematodes of small ruminants in a semi-arid area of Kenya with emphasis on hypobiosis of Haemonchus contortus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gatongi, Peter Maina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A study on the epidemiological dynamics of gastrointestinal nematodes of small ruminants was conducted in a semi-arid area of Kenya over a period of two years. Three major trichostrongylid species were identified; Haemonchus, Trichostrongylus and Oesophagostomum. Trichuris and Strongyloides species were occasionally encountered. Of the major trichostrongylids, Haemonchus spp. was the most prevalent (90%) and accounted for about 80% of the total worm burden. This species was found to undergo hypobiosis at levels that varied with seasons: nil levels of hypobiosis were recorded during the wet months and as much as 80% was recorded during the dry months. Hypobiosis was not investigated in the other nematode species. Evaluation of the relationship between the faecal egg count and the worm burden showed that the two parameters were more highly correlated during the wet months than during the dry months. This was a desirable situation because it is during the wet season that livestock owners in this area need to closely monitor the worm burdens in their animals. Treatment with ivermectin before the onset of the rains not only delayed the onset of egg shedding but also controlled clinical helminthiasis. In addition, a temporal change in the pattern of the appearance of infective larvae on pasture was observed; the appearance was delayed for about a month after the onset of the rains. The effect of treatment administered during the rains was a temporary and a short-lived relief of infection as evidenced by a brief decline in egg output: it had no detectable impact on pasture infectivity. These results suggested that removal of hypobiotic larvae before they resumed development had the combined benefit of reducing both the severity of clinical helminthiasis and the level of pasture contamination. This impact was expressed in improved flock performance and particularly in the improvement of birth weights that subsequently enhanced kid and lamb survival rates. Probably due to</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Scott, M. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq468.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z0322</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ruminants -- Parasites -- Kenya</dc:subject><dc:subject>Haemonchus contortus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nematoda -- Control</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579v18t"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Disability assessment in dementia of the Alzheimer's type</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gélinas, Isabelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Functional disability assessments are recognized as being important for the diagnosis of Dementia of the Alzheimer's type (DAT) as well as for monitoring the impact of intervention and determining the need for home assistance or institutionalization. Existing instruments designed for the assessment of functional disability with this population are generally unsatisfactory with regards to their content or psychometric properties. The objective of this research project was to develop a more appropriate French and English assessment of functional disability for use with proxy-respondents of community-dwelling individuals who have DAT. The Disability Assessment for Dementia (DAD) was developed in several stages using three panels composed of health care professionals and caregivers of individuals with DAT. Forward-backward translation procedures were performed at each stage to ensure that the French and English versions of the scale were comparable. Content validity was verified by a fourth panel of experts. The DAD was then administered to 59 community-dwelling DAT subjects and their caregivers to determine internal consistency and the need to eliminate items. The instrument developed, which consisted of 46 items, was reduced to 40 items, 17 related to basic self-care and 23 to instrumental activities of daily living, as a result of this process. The content validity of the final version was established by a majority of members from the panel of experts. It also demonstrated a high degree of internal consistency (Cronbach's alpha = 0.96) and excellent interrater (N = 31) and test-retest (N = 45) reliability (Intraclass correlation coefficients of 0.95 and 0.96 respectively). In addition, it was found not to have gender bias. Estimates of its validity were determined in another study. The DAD represents a valid and reliable instrument which is short and easy to administer. This instrument should have a positive impact on geriatric rehabilitation, and on clinical and</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wood-Dauphinee, Sharon</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Gauthier, Louise</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z361.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v18t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Health Care Management</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042v90q"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Female-friendly chemistry : an experiment to change the attitudes of female cégep students towards applied chemistry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gillbert, Catherine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This experiment demonstrated that it is possible to use classroom intervention to change the attitudes of female college students towards theoretical and applied chemistry. A pilot study was used to test the experimental design, develop measuring instruments and obtain some preliminary information on the attitudes of college science students. The experiment was of the pretest, post-test, experimental, control group design with a total sample size of 204 students. The treatment experienced by the experimental group consisted of a modified curriculum that included information about topics found by the researcher to be of interest to women, information about how chemistry benefits human health and the environment, a laboratory manual containing profiles of prominent Canadian women chemists and visits by women chemical engineers. Regression analysis of the data showed a significant positive change in the attitudes of the female students in the experimental group (p $&lt;$.05) and there was some indication that more of them were contemplating a career in the theoretical or applied physical sciences. The experiment indicated the importance of sensitizing college instructors to the needs of female students. A series of recommendations for college instructors and the Ministry of Education resulted from this work.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gillett, Margaret</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193b89c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042v90q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- Education -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dx33h"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expression of the human neurofilament heavy gene (NF-H) in transgenic mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Côté, Francine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mammalian neurofilaments (NFs), the intermediate filaments (IFs) of nerve cells, are composed of three different polypeptides, commonly referred to as the low (NF-L), middle (NF-M) and heavy (NF-H) subunits. As members of the IF family and major components of large myelinated fibers, NFs have been assigned a putative role in maintaining the structural integrity of the neurons and in determining axonal caliber. To study the expression and function of the human NF-H gene, a genomic clone encompassing the human NF-H gene was isolated (Cos4NF-H) from a chromosome 22 enriched library and transgenic mice were generated. Four transgenic lines with multiple copies of the intact human NF-H gene were obtained. Northern blot analysis revealed that the human transgene was expressed specifically in neurons at level of approximately two-fold the endogenous mouse level. In addition, the human NF-H gene was expressed at the correct stage during the mouse nervous system development. Furthermore, expression of the human NF-H gene appeared to be proportional to gene copy-number and independent of the position of integration into the mouse genome. This is the first example of such a pattern of transgene expression in nerve cells. These results suggest that the regulatory signals necessary to direct the correct expression of the human NF-H gene lie within the injected clone and are recognized between the two mammalians species. Once identified, the control elements may constitute a valuable tool to direct the expression of foreign genes specifically to neurons. The human NF-H transgenic mice appear normal at birth but progressively develop tremors and pathological features reminiscent of the ones observed in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). For instance, one sees selective enlargements of motor neuron perikarya, dorsal root ganglion (DRG) neurons and proximal axons in addition to distal axonal atrophy and muscle atrophy. Electron microscopy studies showed that the swellings consisted of intracytoplasmic accumulation of NFs. Axonal transport experiments were undertaken to determine if cytoskeletal elements were abnormally transported as has been suggested for a number of neurodegenerative diseases such as ALS. The proteins synthesized in motor/sensory neuron cell bodies were labeled and their subsequent transport to distal axonal segments was analyzed by SDS gels and fluorography. The results showed an impairment of axonal transport of NF proteins, actin and tubulin. There was also retention of some rapidly transported organelles. A possible mechanism to explain these results is that overexpression of the human NF-H gene led to neurofilamentous swelling formation that disrupted axonal flow and eventually resulted in motor neuron degeneration. The human NF-H transgenic mice are therefore a valuable model of human motor neuron disorders and can be used to test therapeutic strategies aimed at reducing the neurofilamentous swellings.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Julien, Jean-Pierre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v910.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx33h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3t945s766"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>3D model-based segmentation of individual brain structures from magnetic resonance imaging data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Collins, Louis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis addresses a specific problem of model-based segmentation; namely, the automatic identification and delineation of gross anatomical structures of the human brain based on their appearance in magnetic resonance images (MRI). The approach developed in this thesis depends on a general, iterative, hierarchical registration procedure and a 3-D digital model of human brain anatomy that contains both volumetric intensity-based data and geometric atlas data that co-exist in a brain-based stereotaxic coordinate system. The model contains features derived from an MRI atlas of gross neuroanatomy, that is the result of an intensity average of 305 brains created with an automatic stereotaxic registration procedure developed here. The objective of this thesis is achieved by inverting the traditional segmentation strategy. Instead of matching geometric contours from an idealized atlas directly to the MRI data, segmentation is achieved by identifying the spatial transformation that, under certain constraints, best maps corresponding features between the model and a particular volumetric data set. After automatic recovery of the linear registration transform, the 3-D non-linear transformation is recovered by estimating the local deformation fields, recursively selected by stepping through the entire target volume in a 3D grid pattern, using cross-correlation of invariant intensity features derived from image data. This registration process is performed hierarchically, with each step in decreasing scale refining the fit of the previous step and providing input to the next. When completed, atlas contours defined in the model are mapped through the recovered transformation to segment structures in the original data set and identify them by name. Experiments for registration and segmentation are presented using simple phantoms, a realistic digital brain phantom as well as human MRI data. The algorithm is used to estimate neuro-anatomical variability, to automatically segment cerebral structures and to create probabilistic representations of the same structures. Validation with manual methods shows that the procedure performs well, is objective and its implementation robust.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peters, T. M.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Evans, A. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp68x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s766</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591b30h"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Early doctrine of the Shiåh, according to the Shī̊ī sources</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Clarke, Lynda, 1956-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Well before the Occultation of the Twelfth imam in 330/942 and before the time of the great Shi 'i theologians such as al-Shaykh al-Mufi d (d. 413/1022), the Shi 'ah had constructed their own integral and elaborate system of thought. This thought is expressed in the sayings of the Shi 'i imams, recorded in hadi th collections gathered in the traditionist centres of Kufah and Qum. It is apparent when these narratives are pieced together that the Shi 'i system as presented by the Shi 'ah themselves bears little resemblance to the descriptions of the heresiographers. At the centre of the Shi 'i worldview is the relation between the imams and the community. The imams' constitution is altogether supernatural, and they succeed to the whole of the prophetic knowledge, while the Shi 'ah, who were created of the same substance as the imams, are the bearers and beneficiaries of that knowledge. The imams continue to receive intelligence from God so that they know every thing and are able to address themselves to every circumstance, while the Shi 'ah must resort to no one else to guide them. God is known only through the imams and they conduct their followers to Paradise while others are left for the Fire. There is, however, evidence of revision of belief already in the time of the first traditionists. The definition of faith is emended so as to allow the non-Shi 'ah a place in Paradise and enable the Shi 'ah to integrate into the larger community. The confinement of the imams by the Abbasids and the lesser Occultation lead to reconsideration of the question of authority: human reason is given a greater role as the Shi 'ah set about thinking how to evaluate the words of the imams already recorded. Kalam, a field of enquiry formerly forbidden to the faithful Shi 'ah due to the necessity of absolute submission to the statements of the imams, is sanctioned so that dicta concerning theology are issued under their names. Tradition now moves away from predestinarianism, and other</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Landolt, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c79r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b30h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Shīʻah -- Doctrines</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A37720f849"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of emotional ads : the role of involvement, ad type, and type of purchase motives</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Coderre, François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present dissertation examines the impact of advertising message involvement (AMI) and the type of ad (ADTYPE) on the nature (cognitive versus affective) and level of abstraction of the information that is encoded during ad exposure. In addition, it examines the impact of brand response involvement (BRI) and the type of purchase motives (TPM) on the nature and level of abstraction of the information that is used for making a judgment or choice. An experiment using 372 subjects was conducted. A 2x2x2x2 between subjects design manipulated AMI (low versus high), ADTYPE (rational versus emotional), BRI (low versus high), and TPM (cognitive versus affective). Results indicated that ADTYPE determines the nature of the information that is encoded during ad exposure, whereas AMI determines the level of abstraction of cognitive (but not affective) information encoded. Results regarding the impact of BRI and TPM were not conclusive.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chattopadhyay, Amitava</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z78q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720f849</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Consumer behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Advertising</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g211s"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The stability of shallow stopes of hard rock mines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bétournay, M. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Canadian hard rock mine extraction practices have commonly created shallow stopes, 12% of which have caved to surface, from instabilities originating from stope hangingwalls, crowns or footwalls. To date, however, mine operators have applied few of the available data gathering and design tools to strike a balance between maximum economic excavation dimension and stope viability. The preference has been to use personal mining experience. Several common rock mass environments are surveyed as well as the various ways in which shallow stopes have failed. It has been found that these rock masses develop gravity-induced movement in the form of plug failures, ravelling of rock blocks, strata failures, chimneying disintegration, and rock mass block caving. New failure-specific analytical equations are developed here for these common failure mechanisms. They address the mechanics of the failure process and incorporate the capability to arrive at the ultimate failure outline, for comparison to the location of the bedrock surface. This research has shown that: plug failures occur along steep, uninterrupted discontinuities bounding large blocks. Plug failure potential reduces substantially with confining compressive stress, discontinuity inclination, the absence of low friction surfaces and shearing of intact rock interrupting the discontinuity. Ravelling requires little peripheral confining stress for stabilization and prevention of block falls or slides. However, inherent conditions such as shallow dipping or vertically dipping joints can cause block falls to develop to surface. Low confining stresses, resulting from multiple stope extraction in orthogonal horizontal directions, would offer conditions suitable for plug and ravelling failures. Strata failures are caused by excessive stope spans, but the limited loading received from above strata is such, that the failure cavity created is of limited vertical extent, some 25% of the stope width. Chimneying disintegration occurs in weak rock masses with low cohesion, over narrow openings that can be as deep as 275 m. The onset of chimneying disintegration can be created by compressive stresses, but develops as a result of mobilization of the rock mass by gravity in active shear. Block caving requires large spans to develop, and stabilizing could be overcome from arching stresses overcoming bulk arching strength. Controlling instability elements are tabulated for these failure mechanisms. A limit equilibrium correlation between span and cohesion for chimneying disintegration is presented, and the controlling limits between the occurrence of chimneying disintegration and block caving is discussed. Ravelling and chimneying disintegration are the most expected failure mechanisms for shallow stopes of hard rock mines. Although failure of the shallow stope may start around its periphery, stope failure to surface would likely occur in or close to the surface crown pillar. Although the analytical equations developed require input of in situ stresses defined by numerical modelling in order to yield a precise answer, conventional numerical modelling or empirical methods are shown to be unable to predict stope failures as the analytical equations have. A step-by-step stability analysis procedure is presented, incorporating rockmass environment, expected failure mechanism(s), and applicable data gathering and anlytical methods. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mitri, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r039s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g211s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj6731590g"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Occupational Health</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Suicide and other causes of death in electrical utility workers : their association with exposure to electric and magnetic fields</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baris, A. N. Dalsu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertaion comprises three related papers. The first paper reports a historical cohort mortality study which was carried out among 21,744 electrical utility workers in the province of Quebec. A total of 1582 deaths were observed at the end of follow-up (1970-1988). A job exposure matrix (JEM) was used to estimate the exposure to 60 Hz electric, magnetic, and pulsed electromagnetic fields (PEMF) from the code of the last job held by each worker. The results showed no evidence of excess of cause specific or general mortality relative to provincial death rates in the cohort overall. The ratios of Standardized Mortality Ratios (SMRs) as estimates of rate ratio (RR) in the exposed relative to the background group were also calculated. Statistically significant RRs were found for pancreatic cancer for electric fields (RR = 2.8, 95% Confidence intervals (CI) 1.13-7.01) and for lung cancer for PEMF (RR = 1.56, 95% CI 1.05-2.25). Deaths caused by accidents and violence showed significant RRs for electric fields (RR = 2.16, 95% CI 1.59-2.92), magnetic fields (RR = 1.76, 95% 1.29-2.39) and for PEMF (RR = 1.96, 95% CI, 1.40-2.71). Occupational accidents related to power lines explain for some of the excess of deaths from accidents and violence. There was a small non-significant association with magnetic fields for leukaemia (RR = 1.52, 95% CI 0.45-4.47) and brain cancer (RR = 1.59, 95% CI 0.57-4.31), but the results for these two sites were based on small numbers. The second paper reports a case-cohort study to investigate a previously suggested association between exposure to electric and magnetic fields and suicide. Forty-nine deaths from suicide between 1970 and 1988 were identified in the above-mentioned cohort and a sub-cohort comprising a one percent random sample was selected from it. Cumulative and current exposures to electric fields, magnetic fields and PEMF were estimated for the sub-cohort and cases through the JEM. For cumulative exposure, rate ratios (RR) for all three fields showed mostly small non-significant increases in the medium and high exposure groups. The most elevated risk was found in the medium exposure group for electric field-geometric mean (RR = 2.76, 95% CI 1.15-6.62). The results did not differ after adjusting for socioeconomic status (SES), alcohol use, marital status and mental disorders. There was little evidence for an association of risk with exposure immediately prior to the suicide. Small sample size (deaths from suicide) and inability to control for all potential confounding factors were the main limitations of this study. The third paper reports a study of validity attributing magnetic field exposure by using a worker's last job. This was done by comparing, in a sample of the cohort, estimates obtained using last job with those obtained using full work histories. The correlation between indices based on last job and those based on all jobs varied between 0.75 and 0.78. The study showed that the last job was particularly good in identifying the highest exposed individual. The results are most likely to be generalizable to other industries in which highest exposed jobs are also skilled jobs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Armstrong, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks40k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731590g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b080r"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A numerical study of midlatitude squall lines with the Canadian regional finite-element model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bélair, Stéphane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A research version of the Canadian regional finite-element (RFE) model is used to evaluate the capability of the operational model in reproducing the meso-$ beta$-scale structure and evolution of three different types of midlatitude squall-line systems, and to advance our understanding on the development of these features. In this thesis, we use the well-documented 10-11 June 1985 squall line as a test bed to examine the appropriate incorporation of various physical representations and their coupling with RFE's model components. It is demonstrated through a series of sensitivity studies that the operational prediction of squall lines can be improved if more realistic model physics, reasonable initial conditions, and high resolution are used. It is shown that subgrid-scale moist convection and grid-scale moist physics must be adequately treated in order to reproduce the internal structures of the squall line. Then, the improved version of the RFE model is used to study the role of gravity waves in the development of a prefrontal squall line associated with the 14 July 1987 Montreal flood. It is found that the gravity waves and convection propagate in a "phase-locked" manner and that the wave-CISK mechanism accounts for the maintenance and intensification of the system. It is also found that frontogenetical processes and release of conditional symmetric instability are responsible for the development of a trailing stratiform rainband associated with the July 1987 Montreal flood. Numerous sensitivity experiments are conducted, and they show that the meso-$ beta$-scale structures and the wave-convection system are very sensitive to the interaction of the parameterized convection with grid-scale physical processes. In the last part of the thesis, the along-line variability 26-27 June 1985 squall line during PRE-STORM is examined. It is found that the three-dimensional structures of the squall's circulations are determined by both a large-scale trough and convectively generated disturbances. In particular, it is shown that rear inflows in the stratiform region tend to be more intense to the south of the mesolow and neat the base of the large-scale trough.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zhang, Da-Lin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x639.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b080r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj6731589q"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The collaborative process as seen through children's disagreements while learning science</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Barfurth, Marion A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The emphasis in mathematics and science education on children actively constructing their own knowledge, collaborating with each other and in contexts that are technologically rich is resulting in new classroom dynamics. Often portrayed as a series of polite exchanges, this study aims to advance our understanding of the collaborative learning process. It does this by looking at a less frequently reported event, children's disagreements while learning science. Following a proposal for conceptually advancing the field the research questions addressed include: (a) Looking at the importance and nature of children's disagreements during a design and construction task using LEGO/Logo and (b) Using the proposed analytic framework to see what it tells us about the collaborative process during children's disagreements. The findings suggest that looking at a disagreement from a social and cognitive move perspective provides an effective framework for looking at the collaborative process. It revealed that disagreements can be a legitimate form of collaboration and elementary school children's disagreements, while on task, can be both extensive and constructive.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shore, Bruce</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Groen, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tr244.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731589q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Science -- Study and teaching (Elementary)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354h24b"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Adenosine and acetylcholine synthesis in a sympathetic ganglion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tandon, Anurag</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The role of adenosine in modulating synaptic transmission in the cat superior cervical ganglion was investigated in this thesis. The first study showed that perfusion of ganglia with exogenous adenosine increased their acetylcholine (ACh) content. The effect was reduced by blockade of nucleoside transport, as if adenosine's action was mediated at an intracellular site. Isotopic labelling of the extra ACh with radiolabelled choline showed that the additional transmitter was due to increased ACh synthesis, and associated with increased choline transport. After its formation, preganglionic stimulation could release the extra ACh, but not if vesamicol, a vesicular ACh transport inhibitor, was present. Thus, the extra ACh appears to require mobilization from a reserve pool of transmitter. Activity-dependent modulation of synaptic transmission is known to occur in sympathetic ganglia. One such form of adaptive behavior is the increase in ACh content ('rebound ACh') after high frequency preganglionic stimulation. The possibility that adenosine might play a role in the rebound phenomenon was examined in the second study. The accumulation of rebound ACh was sensitive to nucleoside transport inhibitors; dipyridamole reduced rebound ACh if it wzs present only after the stimulation, but not if it was present only during stimulation. After its synthesis, rebound ACh was released by preganglionic stimulation, but not if vesamicol was present, as if the extra transmitter had to be mobilized from a reserve pool. Because the dipyridamole-sensitive step occurred after the conditioning period, it seemed possible that a retrograde messenger triggered the post-stimulation change in ACh synthesis. Thus, the final series of experiments tested whether a postsynaptic signal could alter presynaptic ACh synthesis. Antidromic stimulation increased ganglionic ACh synthesis, and, consequently, ACh content. Subsequent evoked ACh release was potentiated, as if the additional transmitter was releasable. The antidromic stimulation-induced increase in AZh content was blocked by dipyridamole suggesting that adenosine might be involved. Overall, the results presented in this thesis are consistent with the notion that adenosine acts as a retrograde messenger after high frequency orthodromic stimulation to induce an increase in presynaptic ACh synthesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Collier, Brian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt74x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354h24b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bh06x"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Specification driven architectural modelling environment for telecommunication systems synthesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tanir, Oryal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Design automation has steadily contributed to improvements witnessed in the system design process. Initial applications were to address low level design concerns such as transistor layout and simulation; however the focus of tools has slowly been progressing up the design abstraction scale. The current state-of-the-art provides modelling capabilities at different levels of abstraction, but solutions for synthesis issues at the register-transfer and lower levels are the norm. The proliferation of design description languages at different abstraction levels has prompted the need for standardization (VHDL and Open-Verilog) to promote design migration and re-use. While design automation has helped in reducing design time-lines and design churn, a major source of design difficulties is just recently being addressed and promise to be the next wave in design automation applicability. The problems arise within the architectural (or system) level of abstraction very early in the design cycle. The recent research in this field attempts to bridge the design process gap between specification and design, and provides a platform for experimenting with hardware and software trade-offs. This dissertation studies the requirements for an environment for architectural design. In particular, an environment specific to the telecommunications domain is proposed in order to limit the potentially large design exploration space. An intermediate design language is also introduced to accommodate both high level modelling and synthesis driven by the user and environment. Finally a Design Analysis and Synthesis Environment (DASE) is described to facilitate the architectural level activities. The environment, a proof of concept, provides generic modal library, simulation, synthesis and Petri-net analysis support. Realistic design examples are explored, to illustrate architectural design activities with the environment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Agarwal, V. K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558g18b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bh06x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, System Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dx34s"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mother's problem solving in relation to child nutrition in the Philippines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ticao, Cynthia J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examined Filipino mothers' problem solving on issues related to child feeding, using a dyadic, peer-help approach. The participants were mothers of children under 6 years of age from the town of Camaligan, in the southern Philippines, where malnutrition among children is prevalent. Two studies were conducted: one using a controlled experimental session and the second using a multi-session nutrition education format. In the first study, mothers were paired with a mutual or unilateral friend to discuss a feeding problem to which they initially gave similar solutions and one to which they gave different solutions. Their post-discussion solutions were better in quality and number than the pre-discussion solutions; also mothers paired with a mutual friend gave more and better finaL solutions to the initially-agreed problem than other mothers. Mothers' final solutions were more likely to come from their own than their partner's discussed solutions, suggesting that the partner's role was to facilitate the mother's own problem-solving process. In the second study, mothers paired with a mutual or unilateral friend were compared with an unpaired control group, after pacing themselves through four problem-based nutrition education sessions. For all three groups, mothers' nutrition knowledge and target child's weight-for-age and height-for-age improved from before to after the sessions. In conclusion, mothers show improvements in the number and quality of solutions they generate and the nutrition knowledge they acquire as a result of a problem-solving approach to nutrition education.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Aboud, Frances</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v66g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx34s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nutrition -- Study and teaching -- Philippines</dc:subject><dc:subject>Children -- Nutrition -- Philippines</dc:subject><dc:subject>Group problem solving</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343t989"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fundamental order and the number of countable models</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tanović, Predrag</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Let T be a complete, first order theory in a countable language. We investigate certain nonisolation properties of types in small superstable theories. Also, we prove that T has 2$ sp aleph$o nonisomorphic countable models in the following cases. (A) T is strictly stable and the order type of rationals cannot be embedded into O(T) and there is no strictly stable group interpretable in T$ rm sp{ sp.q}.$ (B) T is superstable, the generic of every simple group definable in T$ rm sp{ sp.eq}$ is orthogonal to all NENI types and  rm sup {U(p) vert p{ in}S(T) } geq omega sp omega .</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Loveys, James</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c49v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343t989</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386m32j"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigation of the structure of coal using ultrasonic energy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Razi, Javeed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of the research was to find out more about the structure of bituminous coal by studying the rate of mass transfer in coal particles. Previous investigations had shown that small molecules could be trapped in the coal matrix in two different ways. A procedure was developed to keep the various extracts separate from one another. Each of the extracts were analyzed in the following ways: (a) Ultimate analysis; (b) Molecular weight determination; (c) FT-IR spectra; (d) Differential scanning calorimetry; and (e) Thermogravimetric analysis. In the extraction process the first extraction was simple Soxhlet extraction. The residue from this was irradiated with ultrasonic energy and then re-extracted. The residue of the second extraction was ground to a small size and re-extracted without using ultrasonics. The fourth extraction was on the residue of the third extract, using ultrasonics. In general the molecular weight of each successive extract increased while the amount of extract decreased. From the chemical analysis and the molecular weights it appears that the successive extracts are, by and large, members of a family of addition polymers. This finding, coupled with the fact that over 60% of the total coal could be extracted by the procedures used, shows that the bulk of this coal does not consist of a cross-linked polymer. As was shown in previous research the rate of extraction using ultrasonic energy did not rupture and chemical bonds and the extraction rate curve approximated that predicted by Fick's Law, being slightly lower initially and slightly higher later. This work confirmed this. It can be concluded that the only effect of the ultrasonic irradiation was to speed up the relaxation of the glassy coal matrix and release the small molecules so that they could diffuse. The diffusivities of the molecules being extracted was determined for different sized particles. The apparent diffusivity became smaller as the particle size became smaller. This is the opposite of what would be expected if the molecules were diffusing out of small pores. To explain this anomalous effect it has been hypothesized that many of the coal molecules are trapped inside a molecular cage or clathrate, which has been formed from fossilized lignin of the original plants. Some auxiliary experiments were carried out to ascertain the practicability of shattering the coal by soaking the coal particles in a liquid at high pressure and temperature and then suddenly releasing the pressure to let the liquid flash to vapor. The process worked well to produce small coal particles, but there were difficulties in recovering all the coal particles when pyridine was used as the liquid.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cooke, N. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj40g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m32j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591b322"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamic and evanescent wave light scattering of poly(ethylene oxide) - latex systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Polverari, Marco</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The principal aims of the thesis were to carry out a systematic analytical study to determine the solution properties of narrow-distribution and broad-distribution linear poly(ethylene oxide) (PEO) polymer samples in aqueous and organic solution and to study the adsorption properties of these polymer samples onto glass interfaces and spherical latex particles. The deposition characteristics of various types of bare and PEO coated latex particles onto collector surfaces were also studied. These studies allowed to ascertain the presence of PEO clusters in aqueous solution. The cluster size was found to be time dependent and to vary between 0.45 $ mu$m and 0.90 $ mu$m. The clusters were found to be in a thermodynamic equilibrium with the free polymer in solution and were found to reform spontaneously after a 30 minute period following filtration. Adsorption studies indicated that the adsorption of PEO onto latex particles is kinetically controlled and that increased surface roughness and polarity of the latex particles decreases PEO adsorption. PEO clusters in solution were found to increase the value of the effective diffusion constant, D$ rm sb{eff}$ and thus decrease the calculated hydrodynamic layer thickness. Evanescent wave light scattering was used in conjunction with a hydrodynamic impinging jet method for the study of depositing and non-depositing colloidal systems near interfaces. For non-depositing systems a comparison of the measured particle concentration profiles to the theoretically expected particle concentration profiles, calculated from DLVO theory, was made. The agreement was found to be very good. The deposition of bare and PEO-coated latex particles onto glass interfaces was also investigated. From the data it was found that bare and smooth latex particles adsorb much more strongly onto collector surfaces than "hairy" latex particles which have long copolymer chains, such as itachonic acid, grafted onto their surfaces. The results indicated that the thicker the adsorbed polymer layer, the stronger the steric force preventing deposition of the polymer coated colloidal particles onto the collector surface. When the combined ellipsometric layer thickness of the particles and the collector surface exceeded a critical value, found to be about 15 nm, no particle deposition onto the collector surface was possible.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>M., Van de Ven T. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp260.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b322</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Physical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r5133"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship between sex steroid levels and memory functions in women</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Phillips, Susana M. (Susana Maria)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Memory function was examined in association with sex hormone levels in women. The results of the first study suggest that self-reports of memory problems were especially prevalent among women attending a menopause clinic compared to a nonpatient sample. In the following investigation, women given placebo after undergoing a bilateral oophorectomy showed decreases in memory performance, specifically on a paired-associate learning task, coincident with declines in estrogen levels. Significant improvements were found in estrogen-treated women pre- to postoperatively in the immediate recall of paragraphs, in association with supraphysiological estrogen levels. A final study on naturally-cycling women found a decline in visual memory performance during the menstrual compared to the luteal phase of the cycle. Visual memory scores were positively correlated with progesterone levels whereas paired-associate recall scores were positively associated with estradiol levels during the luteal phase. These results suggest that certain aspects of memory covary with changes in sex steroid levels in some women.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sherwin, Barbara</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd72n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r5133</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Menstrual cycle -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Menopause -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Menopause -- Hormone therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Estrogen -- Therapeutic use</dc:subject><dc:subject>Memory -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kc62j"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Contact events in T help for B cell activation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poudrier, Johanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The generation of an Ab response is modulated by contact and cytokine mediated T help for B cells. Here we show that murine splenic small resting B cells do not express mRNA for, or bear IL-2R. Accordingly, these cells do not respond to IL-2. T- contact events induce IL-2R expression on B cells and this is inhibited by blocking of CD40, MHC II or CD54. Although CD40 ligation on its own induces B cell proliferation, it does not confer IL-2 responsiveness. In contrast, signalling through MHC II and CD54 synergizes with IL-5 to induce functional IL-2R on B cells. Moreover, physiological, gp39$ rm sp{low},$ T help for B cell IL-2 responsiveness is equivalently dependent on ligation of CD40, CD54 and MHC II, and requires prior sIg signalling. IL-5 synergizes with either LPS or Th to render B cell responses to IL-2 autonomous of further stimulus. Thus, expression of a functional IL-2R is a marker of B cell activation which appears to be tightly regulated through sIg signals and T-contact events and can be modulated by cytokines.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Owens, Trevor</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc41j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc62j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m375n"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structure-morphology-mechanical property relationships in various random ionomers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kim, Joon-Seop</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of this study was to explore the effects of a range of variables on the properties of ionomers, and also to investigate the structure-morphology-property relationships in these materials in order to advance our understanding in the light of the EHM model. In the first part of the work, the influence of variables such as sample preparation conditions, molecular weight and degree of neutralization on the dynamic mechanical properties of ionomers were studied. In the second part, the effects of surfactant addition and chemical structure of ionomers were investigated. Sodium sulfonated polystyrene ionomers were mixed with the surfactant sodium p-dodecylbenzene sulfonate. This surfactant molecule has a head group identical to the ionic group of the polymer chain. Therefore, the head group resides in the multiplets, and tail group in the restricted mobility region surrounding the multiples. This results in a dramatic decrease in the cluster $T sb{ rm g}$ as a function of the amount of added surfactant. In the next project, the contact surface area of the chain and its effect on multiplet size was studied. An inverse relationship between contact surface area and size of multiplet was found; if the size of multiplet is decreased, the cluster $T sb{ rm g}$ increases and the ionic plateau is also higher and longer. Furthermore, when the pendant group of the polymer is replaced by a bulkier group, the chain becomes stiffer. As a result, the two $T sb{ rm g}$s shift to higher temperatures. In still another part of the study, the dynamic mechanical properties of poly(styrene-co-sodium methacrylate) ionomers were re-investigated in detail. Discontinuities in the plots of various parameters obtained from the tan $ delta$ vs temperature and modulus vs temperature curves as a function of the ion contents were found. These discontinuities suggest that there are two morphological changes in the system as a function of the ion contents, one at ca. 4-6 and the other at ca. 12-14 mol % of ions. In addition, the data were interpreted using filler and percolation concepts. The Guth equation for modulus vs filler content is applicable up to 30 volume % of the clusters. The Halpin-Tsai equation for the regular system is also applicable at low ion contents. For the percolation approach, the percolation threshold was found at 5.4 mol % of ions. The critical exponent and critical volume fraction of clusters were found to be 1.31 and 0.64, respectively. The
critical exponent is in the range cf universal values, while the volume fraction is
higher b'1.an those for other systems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eisenberg, Adi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng622.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m375n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acv43p013f"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Centre for Medical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Acupuncturists' clinical problem-solving strategies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lam, Siu-Yuk Rebecca</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigates the clinical problem-solving among Western-trained and traditionally trained acupuncturists. Fifty-six subjects with varying clinical experience were divided into four groups: physicians without acupuncture training (control), physician-acupuncturists, non-licensed physician-acupuncturists, and traditionally trained acupuncturists. Three clinical cases (two routine and one non-routine), were given to the subjects to provide diagnostic and treatment plans. The data were quantitatively and qualitatively analyzed. Subjects' diagnostic and treatment plans were evaluated against reference models for Western medicine and traditional Chinese medicine (TCM). The results indicate that acupuncturists were influenced by their initial medical training. Physician-acupuncturists and non-licensed physician-acupuncturists' practices were greatly influenced by the training in Western medicine, regardless of their exposure to traditional Chinese medicine. The traditionally trained practitioners outperformed the other groups of subjects in the non-routine case. Accuracy in diagnoses and treatments for the non-routine case was also positively related to the length of clinical experience. The findings support theories of expertise that experts use forward reasoning when coping with familiar cases, and backward reasoning when encountering difficult cases.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Patel, Vimla</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Eisemon, Tom</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z286h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p013f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Diagnosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acupuncturists</dc:subject><dc:subject>Medical education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acupuncture</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adn39x331j"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Oxygen transport to the liver and the brain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kassissia, Ibrahim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The multiple indicator dilution technique was employed to examine the in vivo kinetics of oxygen transport in the liver, known for its very permeable capillary bed, and the brain, known for its very tight capillary bed. $ rm sp{18}O sb2$-saturated $ sp{51}$Cr-labeled erythrocytes, labelled albumin, sucrose and water (the tracers for the study substance, vascular, interstitial, and cellular references respectively) were simultaneously injected into the target organs. Timed anaerobic samples were collected at the outflow and analyzed by mass spectrometry for relative $ rm sp{18}O sb2$ enrichment, and for $ gamma$ and $ beta$-radioactivity. Distributed-in-space models of capillary transport were used to analyze the data. In the liver, oxygen transport and distribution were influenced by the temperature and hematocrit of the perfusate, and shown to be compatible with a flow-limited process. In the brain, flow varied significantly between animals, in concert with parallel changes in oxygen consumption. Analysis indicated that transfer of both $ rm sp{18}O sb2$ and $ sp3$H-water indicators from blood to brain is barrier limited, and it is concluded that low tissue oxygen concentration in the brain is due to limited endothelial permeability to oxygen.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rose, Colin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q61q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x331j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jw535"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the development of a batch type inclusion sensor in liquid steel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Hyoung Chul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An inclusion sensor system for liquid metals first developed at McGill and dubbed with the acronym, LIMCA, is now in daily use for monitoring metal quality in ALCAN's casting centers. This method can simultaneously provide the number density, and size distribution, of inclusion particles in molten metals. Attempts have been made to extend the LIMCA technique to analyses of steel cleanliness. In order to commercialise the LIMCA system, a batch type probe, similar to an oxygen sensor, was developed and tested in low carbon steel melts. For industrial applications, a series of experiments was carried out in a 60 ton tundish at DOFASCO. The data derived from these LIMCA measurements were compared to those obtained by DOFASCO personnel using the 'slime' technique for inclusion detection.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Guthrie, R. I. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m33t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jw535</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>