<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514np54s"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of two work postures on musculoskeletal disorder risk associated with computer work</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fedorowich, Larissa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L’objectif de ce projet de recherche était de quantifier les effets de changer la posture de travail sur les patrons de la région cou/épaules durant un travail prolongé sur ordinateur chez des jeunes adultes en santé. De cela, en découleraient des données objectives à propos d’interventions devenant communes en milieu de travail à l’ordinateur : marcher-et-travailler. L’activité musculaire du haut du corps (EMG), le débit sanguin (LDF), la perception de l’inconfort ainsi que la performance à l’ordinateur ont été enregistrés toutes les 9 minutes pendant une période de 90 min alors que les sujets reproduisaient un texte à l’ordinateur, ceci pendant deux sessions, une étant assis et l’autre en marchant sur un tapis roulant. Les résultats de cette étude confirment l’état d’inconfort au niveau du cou et des épaules étant plus élevé à la position assise comparativement à la marche. D’autres résultats de cette étude nous montrent un modèle d’activité musculaire durant la marche, qui reflète potentiellement une adaptation bénéfique à un travail informatique de longue durée. Les différents mécanismes observés lors des deux postures pourraient soutenir l’idée de travailler sur un ordinateur avec une posture autre que celle assise, avec pour but de prévenir les troubles musculaires dans la région des épaules et du cou.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The aim of this Master’s study was to quantify the effects of modifying computer work posture on neck/shoulder patterns in healthy young adults during a prolonged computer task. In turn, this would serve to provide objective data on a popular computer work intervention: walk-and-work. Upper body muscle activity (EMG) and blood flow (LDF) as well as discomfort and typing performance data were recorded every 9 minutes during a 90-min computer typing task during two sessions of sitting and walking on a treadmill. Results of this study show that discomfort in the neck/shoulder area was higher during sitting and this discomfort increased over time compared to walking. Muscle activity and blood flow patterns were indicative of a lower neck/shoulder load during working while walking, which potentially reflects healthier adaptations to prolonged computer work. This may support that performing computer work in a posture other than sitting may be beneficial in preventing neck/shoulder disorders.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Julie Cote</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c145z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np54s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Occupational Health and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qq28h"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microfluidic based methylation sensing on single DNA molecule</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cao, Yi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le profile de la méthylation à l’échelle génomique est crucial pour la compréhension des maladies causées par des mécanismes cellulaires. Ici, nous avons développé une nouvelle méthode de mappage optique directe de la distribution de méthylation sur la molécule d'ADN étirée par microfluide. L’étirage extensif d’une molécule d‘ADN dans une cellule à l’échelle nanométriqe a été réalisé, ce qui rend le mappage de position possible. En utilisant le marqueur methyl-binding domain (MBD), conjugué au fluorophore green fluorescent protein (GFP), nous avons démontré la faisabilité du profile de méthylation de molécule individuelle sur l'ADN du bacteriophage lambda artificiellent méthylé. Nous avons également effectué la classification et la lyse d’une cellule individuelle sur chip en récupérant les informations génétiques et épigénétiques sur l’ADN extrait par l'étiquetage de multiplex. Notre approche surmonte les limitations de débit, de coût et d'amplification d’erreur. Cette méthode a le potentiel ultime de détecter des altérations génétiques et épigénétiques entre les cellules individuelles, elle facilitera aussi la découverte de nouveaux objectifs associés avec la maladie.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Genome-scale methylation profiling is crucial for the discovery of cellular mechanisms underlying diseases. Here we developed a new method for direct optical mapping methylation distribution on microfluidic-stretched single DNA molecule. Extensive stretching of single DNA molecule was achieved in nano-scale confinement, making it applicable for positional mapping. By using fluorophore-ligated marker, GFP-conjugated methyl-binding domain (MBD), we demonstrated the feasibility of generating a single molecule methyl-map on artificially methylated lambda DNA. We also performed direct retrieval of genetic and epigenetic information from the DNA extracted from single cell by multi-color labeling. Our approach overcomes conventional limitations in regards of throughput, cost and amplification bias. This method has the ultimate potential to detect coarse-grained genetic and epigenetic alterations between individual cells, which will facilitate the discovery of novel disease-specific targets.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Walter Reisner</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Moshe Szyf</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rr965.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qq28h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483n29p"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genomic characterization of wild barley germplasm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nandha, Prabhjot</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Barley (Hordeum vulgare subsp. vulgare) is an important cereal crop grown worldwide for producing malt and is used as animal feed. Wild barley (Hordeum vulgare subsp. spontaneum), the progenitor species of cultivated barley, is a rich source of genetic variation, which can be utilized for the improvement of cultivars. Various molecular markers are available to study genetic variability and diversity in plants. We used two different types of SSR or microsatellite markers- genomic SSRs (gSSR) and expressed sequence tag SSR (EST-SSR)  markers, to assess and compare the genetic diversity between the wild and cultivated barley germplasm obtained from PGRC genebank, Saskatoon.  A total of 48 genomic (gSSR) and 16 EST-SSRs were applied on 27 wild and 20 cultivated barley accessions. Based on the results, genomic (SSRs) were more informative than EST-SSRs and wild barley possessed more genetic diversity as compared to cultivated barley. Various  species specific alleles were found to be higher in number in wild barley. Also, both endogenous and exogenous transposons were explored, so as to develop novel gene capturing tools in wild barley genome. In this, Mu like (MULEs) transposons were found to be endogenously present in certain important domesticated traits and Ac/Ds transposons system was introduced through conventional hybridization procedure into the wild barley germplasm, so as to utilize these mobile elements as functional genomics tools. In addition, transposons based markers were also employed to assess genetic diversity between wild and cultivated barley. All these efforts of molecular characterization of wild barley's genome will aid in the improvement of modern cultivated barley species by ultimately introgressing useful genes from wild barley species into cultivated barley.       </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L’orge (Hordeum vulgare subsp. vulgare) est une céréale importante cultivée dans le monde entier et est utilisée pour la production de malt ainsi que pour l'alimentation animale . L’orge sauvage (Hordeum vulgare subsp. spontaneum), l’espèce progénitrice de l'orge cultivé, est une source riche de variation génétique, qui peut être utilisé pour l'amélioration des cultivars . Divers marqueurs génétiques moléculaires sont disponibles pour étudier la variabilité et la diversité génétique des plantes . Nous avons utilisé deux types de marqueurs différents - microsatellites SSR génomiques (gSSR) et  les marqueurs de séquence exprimée SSR (EST- SSR) - afin d'évaluer et de comparer la diversité génétique entre le matériel génétique de l'orge sauvage et cultivé obtenus de la banque de matériels phytogénétique de RPC, Saskatoon. Un total de 48 génomique (gSSR) et 16 EST-SSR  ont été appliquées sur 27 accessions sauvage et 20 accessions d'orges cultivés. Basé sur les résultats, les SSR génomiques (gSSR) ont été plus informatifs que les EST - SSR. De plus, l'orge sauvage possédaient une plus grande diversité génétique que celle de l'orge cultivée. Diverses allèles spécifiques à l’espèce ont été trouvées en plus grand nombre dans d'orge sauvage. Aussi, afin de développer de nouveaux outils génomique pour la capture des gènes dans l'orge sauvage, les transposons endogènes et exogènes ont été exploré dans celui-ci. Les transposons de types Mu (mules) ont été trouvés présent endogèniquement dans certains traits domestiques importants et le système de transposons Ac/Ds a été introduit par la procédure d'hybridation conventionnelle dans l'orge sauvage, de manière à utiliser ces éléments mobiles comme outils de génomique fonctionnelle. De plus, les marqueurs de base transposons ont également été utilisés pour évaluer la diversité génétique entre l'orge sauvage et cultivé. Tous ces efforts de caractérisation moléculaire du génome de l'orge sauvage aideront à améliorer les espèces modernes de l'orge cultivés par l’introgression de gènes utiles d'espèces d'orge sauvages  dans l'orge cultivée.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jaswinder Singh</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tz20d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n29p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q737h"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On Mazur-Tate type conjectures for quadratic imaginary fields and elliptic curves</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gomez, Clément</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, we formulate and partially prove conjectures à la Mazur-Tate for two cases of L-functions. Suppose given a L-function L(M,K,s) attached to an arithmetic object M  over a number field K (a "motive") so that L can be twisted by characters of the Galois group G of an extension of K. To this pair (L,G), one may hope to associate a theta element Theta(L,G) in A[G], where A is a well defined ring, that interpolates the special values L(M,K,chi,1) of L twisted by characters chi of G. The notion of interpolation means that the evaluation of Theta(L,G) at chi gives the value L(M,K,chi,1) or at least a simple and explicit transformation of the value L(M,K,chi,1). Following the ideas of Mazur and Tate, the theta element should capture the arithmetic properties of L or more precisely the arithmetic properties of the geometric objects M and K from which L is constructed.The first chapter is devoted to the case of Artin L-functions associated to a quadratic imaginary field K and twisted by characters of the Galois groups of ray class field extensions K(m) of K. The theta element captures information about the class number formulas of the fields $K(m). For the second chapter, the underlying geometric object is a pair (K,E) of a quadratic imaginary field K and an elliptic curve E defined over Q. The theta element should capture there information about the rank of the Mordell-Weil groups E(K).The key ingredient in the study of the theta elements in both cases is the existence of a set of cohomology classes in  appropriate cohomology groups that satisfy local and global compatibilities. These systems, sometimes called Euler system or Kolyvagin system even if the literature is not unified on this appellation, arise from purely geometric considerations. In chapter 1, these classes, called in that case elliptic units are constructed by considering units in the ray class fields of K, whereas in chapter 2, they arise by considering the Heegner points over K in a Shimura curves associated to E and K.Each chapter has the form of an article and can be read independently from the other one.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse, nous formulons et prouvons partiellement des conjectures à la Mazur-Tate pour deux cas précis de fonctions L. Supposons donnée une fonction L(M,K,s) attachée à un objet arithmétique M défini sur un corps de nombre K et supposons que cette fonction L puisse être tordue par les caractères associés au groupe de Galois G d'une extension de K. Dans une telle situation, il est naturel d'espérer associer à cette paire (L,G) un élément theta Theta(L,G) dans un anneau de groupe A[G] qui interpole les valeurs spéciales L(M,K,chi,1) de L tordue par les caractères chi de G.  Par interpolation, nous entendons ici que l'évaluation de Theta(L,G) en chi donne la valeur L(M,K,chi,1) ou au moins une transformation explicite de cette valeur. Selon les idées de Mazur et Tate, l'élément Theta(L,G) est alors censé capturé les propriétés arithmétiques et géométriques des objets M et K associés à L.Le premier chapitre est consacré au cas des fonctions L d'Artin associées à un corps quadratique imaginaire K et tordues par les caractères des groupes de Galois des extensions des corps de classe de rayon K(m). Dans ce cas, l'élément theta capture des informations sur les formules du nombre de classe des corps K(m). Dans le second chapitre, l’objet géometrique sous-jacent est une paire (E,K) constituée d'une courbe elliptique E définie sur Q et d'un corps quadratique imaginaire K. L'élément theta capture ici des informations sur le rang du groupes de Mordell-Weil E(K).L'ingrédient principal dans l'étude des élément theta dans les deux cas est l'existence d'un ensemble de classes cohomologiques dans des groupes de cohomologie galoisienne précis satisfaisant des compatibilités locales et globales. Ces ensembles parfois dénommés systèmes d'Euler ou systèmes de Kolyvagin (même si la littérature n'est pas encore unifiée sur le sujet) proviennent de considérations purement géometriques. Dans le premier chapitre, ces classes dénommées unités elliptiques sont construites à partir d'unités globales dans les extensions de corps de classe de rayon de K alors que dans le second chapitre, ces classes proviennent des points de Heegner sur des courbes de Shimura associées à E et K.Chaque chapitre a la forme d'un article indépendant.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Henri Darmon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rc038.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q737h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9z903299r"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Community development crowdmapped and texted</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brandusescu, Ana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans ce mémoire, l’utilisation des technologies mobiles couplée avec une plateforme en ligne pour la cartographie de crise dans un contexte de développement communautaire est étudiée. La cartographie de crise a été utilisée dans le mouvement des technologies de l'information et de la communication (TICs) au service du développement comme méthode pour connecter et renforcer les capacités des citoyens dans des situations d’urgence. Cette étude a utilisé Crowdmap, la plateforme cartographique « dans un nuage »de Ushahidi est utilisée pour analyser si les citoyens allaient envoyer des textos et envoyer des messages en ligne comme les courriels, les tweets et les soumissions provenant des applications de téléphones intelligents pour le développement communautaire (ex. : les lieux locaux, les atouts de la communauté, les éléments à améliorer). De plus, l’étude interroge l’utilité des plateformes pour les crises dans des conditions de problèmes graves (de crise) et de problèmes chroniques (qui persistent, long terme) dans les communautés. Les problèmes du développeur et de l’utilisation du participant (ex. : l’organisation communautaire) dans le contexte de communautés locales ont été également abordé. Le contexte de l’utilisation de la plateforme de cartographie de crise a été changé afin de développer cinq applications pour des initiatives de développement communautaire dans quatre communautés (études de cas) au Canada: l’Université McGill (une application) et Lachine (deux applications) à Montréal, ainsi que Acadia Park (une application) et Grandview-Woodland (une application) à Vancouver. La méthodologie comprend cinq étapes. Premièrement, cinq applications sur une plateforme de cartographie de crise ont été créées. Deuxièmement, le matériel de télécommunications pour recevoir les messages textes envoyés par les participants a été mis sur pied. Troisièmement, un logiciel de télécommunications afin de cartographier les messages textes dans l’application cartographique a été installé. Quatrièmement, les communautés ont été visitées  et des panneaux narratifs ont été utilisés  pour communiquer et proposer les applications aux audiences dans un langage non technique et multilingue. Le chercheur a également  participé aux diverses réunions locales, créé des manuels, ainsi que co-élaboré et distribué des affiches et pamphlets. Cinquièmement, les applications ont été administrées  en géolocalisant, téléchargeant et analysant les messages entrants .Les données ont été collectées  en recevant les messages, en les approuvant et en utilisant la méthode de crowdmapping. Les résultats se présentent sous forme de quatre tendances: (1) les défis techniques de la plateforme, (2) l’utilisation des technologies de l’information et de la communication (TICs) par les organisations communautaires, (3) l’utilisation des TICs par les participants, et (4) les problèmes de temporalité, d’écosystème technologique et de petites données (à l’opposé de données massives ou Big data). Les quatre résultats ont contribué à une utilisation et une adoption inconsistantes des applications, produisant une étendue inégale des 254 messages totaux reçus parmi les quatre communautés. La conclusion discute des implications et des perspectives plus vastes pour la cartographie mobile et sur le web dans le cadre du développement communautaire. Les TICs de plateformes de cartographie créent des possibilités innovantes pour les pratiques de développement communautaire et d’auto-organisation. Les études subséquentes devraient inclurent le développement de technologies davantage participatives en fonction des cadres existants de développement communautaire. Ceci permettra d’assurer la participation communautaire et l’utilisation à long terme, afin de pouvoir alimenter un dialogue significatif et continu à propos des lieux importants dans les quartiers.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The thesis investigates the use of mobile technology and an online crisis mapping platform for community development practices. Mobile technology has been widely used to facilitate communication and build social structures for communities. Online mapping platforms allow non-experts to create, organize, and visualize a dialogue about events like earthquakes, fires, or floods. In particular, crisis mapping has been used in the information and communications technology for development (ICT4D) movement as a method of connecting and empowering citizens during emergency events. Ushahidi is the best-known example of a mapping platform used for crises, which integrates mobile technologies by allowing for texting/SMS (a.k.a. Short Message Service) to collect citizen reports. Crowdmap, Ushahidi’s cloud-based mapping platform is used to investigate whether citizens would text/SMS and send online messages such as email, web-based, tweets and smartphone application submissions for community development (e.g., local places, community assets, improvements). Moreover, the thesis interrogates the utility of crisis mapping platforms for acute (crisis) and chronic (persistent, long-term) issues in communities and examines developer issues and participant (i.e., community organization) use. A crisis mapping platform is repurposed to deploy five applications for community development initiatives in four communities (case studies) in Canada: McGill University (one application) and Lachine (two applications) in Montreal; Acadia Park (one application) and Grandview-Woodland (one application) in Vancouver. The methodology consisted of five steps. First, five applications on the crisis mapping platform were created. Second, telecommunications hardware were set up to receive SMSs submitted by participants. Third, telecommunications software were set up to map SMSs to the mapping applications. Fourth, meetings were scheduled with the communities. Here, storyboards were used to communicate and propose the applications to non-technical, multilingual audiences. In addition, attending local meetings, creating manuals, co-designing and distributing multilingual posters and flyers were critical for community outreach. Fifth, the applications were administered by geo-locating, uploading and parsing incoming messages. The data was collected by receiving, approving and crowdmapping messages. There are four trends in the findings: (1) the technical challenges of the platform, (2) the use of information communication technologies (ICTs) by community organizations, (3) the use of ICTs by participants, and (4) the issues of temporality, technology ecosystems and small data. The four findings contributed to an inconsistent adoption and use of the applications, producing an uneven spread of the 254 total messages among the four communities. The thesis concludes by discussing broader implications and prospects of mobile and web-enabled mapping for community development. ICT mapping platforms create innovative possibilities for community development practices and self-organization. Future work includes developing more participatory technologies according to existing community development frameworks. This will ensure community participation and long-term use before we spark meaningful and lasting community dialogues about local places.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Renee Sieber</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qv897.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903299r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8p58pg998"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The divergence of the TE/ICM lineages correlates to the polarity character before setting-up the outer/inner positioning in the pre-implantation mouse embryo</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anani, Shihadeh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans l'embryon de la souris, les divisions asymétriques au stade 8 génèrent deux types de cellules; des cellules polaires et apolaires. Ces cellules sont attribuées à des positions extérieure et intérieure, respectivement. Cette configuration interne/externe est le premier signal de la formation des deux premières lignes de cellules; « trophectoderme » (TE) et de la « inner cell mass » (ICM), respectivement. Les cellules polaires extérieures deviennent « TE » et donnent lieu au placenta. Par contre, les cellules intérieures apolaires deviennent « ICM » et donnent lieu à l’embryon et le sac « vitellin ». Ici, nous avons analysé la fréquence des divisions asymétriques au cours de la transition des 8-16 cellules, et on a aussi évalué les relations entre la polarité de la cellule, la cellule et la position nucléaire, et la « Hippo » activation de signalisation de la voie qui initie l'expression de le gène spécifique lignée avec les 16-cellules d'embryons. On a trouvé que la fréquence des divisions asymétriques variait d'un embryon à l'autre. Donc, nous avons constaté que dans la plupart des embryons; plus de 75% des 8 blastomères de cellules (6/8 cellules) divise de façon asymétrique. De nombreuses cellules apolaires ont été placées dans des positions extérieures dans les 16-cellules embryons, peu après la division, tandis que seulement une ou deux cellules apolaires ont été placés dans des positions intérieures. Analyse du « live imaging » a montré que les cellules apolaires extérieurs ont été internalisés par les cellules polaires par le processus de « envelopment ». En utilisant des blastomères isolés des 8 cellules, nous avons analysé le processus d'internalisation des cellules apolaires. On a trouvé des indications de tension corticales supérieures dans les cellules apolaires, par rapport à les cellules polaires. Enfin, nous avons constaté que les cellules apolaires activer « Hippo signalisation » avant de prendre des positions intérieures. Nous montrons également que le traitement « Y27632 » perturbe la polarité et la « Hippo signalisation ». En outre, utilisant le système d'isolat, nous montrons que le processus d'internalisation est également perturbé. Nos résultats suggèrent que les cellules polaires et apolaires ont des différences intrinsèques qui établit la configuration interne/externe et qui règle différemment la « Hippo signalisation » pour activer les programmes d'expression génique spécifique. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In the mouse embryo, asymmetric divisions at the 8-cell stage generate two cell types, polar and apolar cells, which are allocated to outer and inner positions, respectively. This outer/inner configuration is the first sign of the formation of the first two cell lineages, trophectoderm (TE) and inner cell mass (ICM), respectively. Outer polar cells become TE and give rise to the placenta, while inner apolar cells become ICM and give rise to the embryo proper and yolk sac. Here, we analyzed the frequency of asymmetric divisions during the 8-16 cell transition and assessed the relationships between cell polarity, cell and nuclear position, and Hippo signaling activation, the pathway that initiates lineage-specific gene expression in 16-cell embryos. While the frequency of asymmetric divisions varied from one embryo to another, we found that in most embryos 75% of 8-cell blastomeres (6/8 cells) divided asymmetrically. Interestingly, many apolar cells in 16-cell embryos were located at outer positions soon after division while only one or two apolar cells were located at inner positions. Live imaging analysis showed that outer apolar cells were eventually internalized by surrounding polar cells. Using isolated 8-cell blastomeres, we carefully analyzed the internalization process of apolar cells and found indications of higher cortical tension in apolar cells than in polar cells. Lastly, we found that apolar cells activate Hippo signaling prior to taking inner positions. We also show that ROCK inhibitor Y27632 treatment disrupts polarity and Hippo signaling and using the isolate system we show that the internalization process is also disrupted. Our results suggest that polar and apolar cells have intrinsic differences that establish the outer/inner configuration and differentially regulate Hippo signaling to activate lineage-specific gene expression programs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yojiro Yamanaka</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q021q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pg998</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abv73c368c"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Myopic conflict: documentary ecologies of violence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pringle, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis seeks to explicate three films that trouble the well-examined distinction between fact and fiction in contemporary depictions of violence. Standard Operating Procedure (Errol Morris, 2008), The Act of Killing (Joshua Oppenheimer, 2012), and Redacted (Brian De Palma, 2007) complement each other, as all three films are examples of contemporary hybrids of documentary and fiction that agitate prevailing attitudes held toward non-fiction representations of violence. By adopting a critical methodology termed ‘media ecology,’ this project attempts to think about media environments that affect ‘patterns, dangers, and potentials’ while considering the agency exerted by contemporary images of warfare and the ethics of spectatorship.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse considère trois films qui brouillant la distinction entre fiction et réalité dans les représentations contemporaines de la violence. Standard Operating Procedure (Errol Morris, 2008),The Act of Killing (Joshua Oppenheimer, 2012), et Redacted (Brian de Palma, 2007) complètent les uns et les autres, comme trois exemples d'hybrides contemporains du documentaire et de la fiction qui remanient les perspectives habituels a propos des représentations des histoires vraies de la violence. En adoptant la méthodologie d’une  ‘écologie médiatique,’ ce projet tente de penser des environnements médiatiques qui transforment ‘les modèles, les dangers et les potentiels,’ tout en tenant compte de l’efficacité des images contemporaines de la guerre et l'éthique des spectateurs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alanna Michael Thain</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55zb895.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c368c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042x21q"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exploring the experiences of students in alternate programs: an interpretative phenomenological analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pereira, Liane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The policies governing education have given schools the responsibility of meeting the needs of a diverse student population, including those with emotional and behavioural difficulties (EBD).  To balance their need for individualized educational programs with their right to inclusion in schools, students with EBD may be placed in alternate programs within a mainstream school setting.  However, little is known about student experiences that lead to this placement or their experiences in these programs.  This phenomenological study explored how eight grade students in alternate programs make sense of their schooling.  Six students participated in a mapping activity and an individual audio-recorded interview during which they described their school journey and educational experiences.  This yielded visual- and text-based data that was analyzed using interpretative phenomenological analysis.  Results revealed four salient themes that included (a) struggling to develop and defend their sense of self, (b) schooling as an increasingly complex social process, (c) schooling as tumultuous, and (d) exploring ways to cope with stress.  Using a developmental perspective to frame these students’ experiences, this study presents a multi-level understanding of schooling for students with emotional and behavioural difficulties.  Implications for educators, administrators, researchers, and policy-makers are discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les politiques qui régissent l’éducation exigent de la part des écoles d’accommoder les besoins divers de la population étudiante, dont ceux des étudiants ayant des difficultés émotionnelles ou de comportement.  Afin d’assurer un accès équilibré à ces étudiants qui ont besoin à la fois d’un plan d’éducation individualisé et d’être inclus dans les écoles conventionnelles, ces derniers sont parfois placés dans des programmes alternatifs au sein des écoles traditionnelles.  Cependant, on dispose de peu d’information sur l’expérience des étudiants menant à un tel placement, ni sur leurs parcours dans le cadre de ces programmes.  Cette étude phénoménologique explore comment des étudiants de 8ième année ayant été placés dans des programmes alternatifs expliquent leurs trajectoires scolaires.  À travers des entrevues enregistrées, six étudiants ont décrit leur parcours et leurs expériences éducatives.  Ce processus a permis de recueillir des données visuelles et textuelles qui ont été soumises à une analyse phénoménologique interprétative.  Les résultats suggèrent quatre thèmes principaux : (a) des difficultés quant au développement et à la défense du soi, (b) l’enseignement  comme processus social de plus en plus complexe, (c) les perturbations liées à la fréquentation scolaire, (d) l’exploration de la gestion du stress.  Cette étude présente une analyse multi-niveaux de l’enseignement destiné aux étudiants en proie à des difficultés émotionnelles ou de comportement.  Elle met en évidence les implications pour les éducateurs, les administrateurs, les chercheurs et les législateurs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tara Flanagan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z8289.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042x21q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q930g"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"These aren't the drones you're looking for" secrecy and the weapon legitimation process, 2009-2013</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anderson, Sean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire examine les variations dans les formulations précises utilisées par l’administration Obama et le New York Times lors du processus de légitimation publique des véhicules aériens sans pilote (UAV) armés. Il utilise un cadre théorique qui analyse l’action socialement dense créée par l’interaction entre les pratiques, les connaissances préalables et l’état de la relation symbiotique entre les deux communautés. Cette analyse a été achevée à l’aide du logiciel Atlas.ti afin de faciliter le codage interprétatif et l’analyse des articles du New York Times et les communiqués officiels de l’administration Obama publiés et émis entre janvier 2009 et mai 2013. En examinant ces sources, ce mémoire met en lumière le processus par lequel des constellations particulières d’action socialement dense ont rendu possibles les formulations précises de chaque communauté dans un contexte donné. Cela illustre également comment la définition sociale de la technologie des drones a été élaborée et comment l’administration Obama a pu se limiter à une réaction restreinte devant l’attention portée aux attaques de drones par la presse.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis examines variations in specific framing used by the Obama administration and New York Times journalists during the public legitimation process of armed unmanned aerial vehicles. It employs a theoretical framework that examines the socially thick agency created through the interaction of practices, background knowledge and the state of the symbiotic relationship between the two communities. This research was completed by using Atlas.ti software to assist in interpretive coding and analysis of New York Times articles and official Obama administration statements from January 2009-May 2013. By examining these sources, this thesis illuminates the process by which particular constellations of socially thick agency made each community’s specific framing possible in a given context. This also illustrates how the social definition of drone technology was constructed and how the Obama administration’s limited response to journalistic attention was possible.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vincent Pouliot</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731710z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q930g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science - International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4x51hn43z"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of East Asian Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"Topomorphic revolution", power, and identity: a study of the implications of landscape transformations in modern Eastern inner Mongolia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pratte, Anne-Sophie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mon mémoire est une étude des transformations du territoire dans la région de Tongliao en Mongolie Intérieure des temps modernes. En premier lieu, j’examine les mécanismes grâce auxquels l’Empire des Qing a exercé son pouvoir sur la terre et a circonscrit la notion d’une «identité Mongole» de par la cartographie du territoire, la restriction des mouvements et l’imposition d’un code de loi particulier. Puis, je me penche sur la transition d’empire à état-nation dans la première moitié du vingtième siècle et montre que les transformations des institutions politiques ont eu un impact limité sur le pastoralisme. Finalement, je documente les transformations dramatiques du territoire qui ont eu lieu à l’ère post-Mao—que j’appelle «Révolution Topomorphique». Cette étude soutient qu’en sculptant l’espace, les empires et états-nations ont fixé les conditions de l’identité mongole et ont transformé les normes sociales et les relations de pouvoir au sein de la société dans la région de Tongliao en Mongolie Intérieure. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>My thesis is the study of landscape transformations in the Tongliao region of Inner Mongolia, their driving forces and their implications in terms of social organization and identity. I first examine the mechanisms through which the Qing Empire exercised power over the land and circumscribed the notion of a “Mongol Identity” through the mapping of the territory, the restriction of migration and the imposition of a particular legal code. Then, I look into the transition from empire to nation-state in the first part of the twentieth century, and show that the transformation of political institutions had a limited disruptive impact on pastoralism. Finally, I document the dramatic transformations of the landscape that took place in the post-Mao era from the early 1980s to the 2000s—which I call “topomorphic revolution.” I find that, by shaping the space and setting boundaries in the territories, empires and nation-states successively set the terms for the Mongol ethnic identity, and transformed the social norms and power relations prevailing in the society of the Tongliao area in Inner Mongolia. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robin Yates</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qq29s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hn43z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Asian</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pq98m"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Earthquakes at stressed ramps emplace injectites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sherry, Timothy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis I examine the infuence of fault geometry on local static stress change fields and the development of fault rock structures. In the foreland of orogenic belts, the development of deformation structures such as faults, folds, and fractures is coupled with fluid flow. Fluids derived from underthrusting sediments enter actively deforming basins, and thefeedback between deformation and fluid pressure controls the structures that form. In turn, major and minor structures determine permeability pathways for fluid migration. Thrust ramps are areas where low angle thrust faults locally increase in dip. Assuming elastic wallrock, the hanging wall must deform across the ramp to move past the asperity. This deformation influences the distribution of static stress along the fault and subsequent development of fault rock and damage structures. The Naukluft Thrust, a Cambrian basal decollement in central Namibia, hosts a granular carbonate fault rock called \Gritty Dolomite" which was a slurry of grains and supercritical CO2. In proximity to a thrust ramp, gritty dolomite intruded upsection from the fault plane into the hanging wall, forming large (70 m) slurry-filled dikes called "injectites." The thrust ramp on the Naukluft Thrust is a eld analog for active fault-related deformation where we can apply static stress change models to relate fault slip to wall rock strain. The relationship between the thrust ramp and injectite structures was investigated by GPS mapping 20 km tortuous fault trace in the region of the thrust ramp and fitting a topographic model of the fault surface. Cross sections of the surface model, parallel to the southeast hanging wall transport direction, were input into the USGS Coulomb 3 software to model static stress changes caused by fault geometry. Model stress saturation was set equivalent to a dolomite wallrock tensile strength of 7 MPa to identify areas of potential tensile fracturing. An area of modeled fault dilation, corresponds to observed dilation of the fault zone. Injectites tend to correlate with areas where high stress gradients in the wall rock develop between areas of compressional and tensile stress. The injectites are not well correlated with maximum static tensile stress in the wallrock. Static tensile stress change facilitated the emplacement of injectites, however it is likely that dynamic stresses during coseismic slipincreased the fluid pressure of the gritty dolomite slurry and drove intrusion into fractured wallrock. I propose that at locations of increased compressional stress normal to the fault surface, injectite formation is favored along extreme wallrock stress gradients. Thus the combination of favorable wall rock conditions, and pressurization on the fault surface, best explains injectite formation. I applied a novel approach to estimating paleoearthquake energy from injectite aperture,based on previous work which indicated that coseismically-produced CO2 gas was the pressurizing fluid which drove slurry injection. The volume of gas available to ll injectites is related to the thickness and area of the earthquake slip patch which was frictionally heated to liberate CO2. Injectite dimensions were used in a simplied volume calculation to modelthe earthquake slip patch required to generate the volume of material in the injectite. A simplified fluid of CO2 - H2O was used to elucidate the influence of water compressibility on the earthquake energy. Estimates of earthquake moment magnitude, Mw, were about 4.2. The compressibility of water's influence in the supercritical CO2 slurry was negligible.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans la présente thèse, j’examine l’influence de la géométrie des failles sur les champs locaux de variations des contraintes statiques et le développement des structures dans les roches de faille. Dans l’avant-pays de ceintures orogéniques, la formation de structures de déformation telles que des failles, plis et fractures est jumelée à l’écoulement des fluides. Des fluides dérivés de sédiments chevauchés entrent dans des bassins en déformation active, et la rétroaction entre la déformation et la pression des fluides contrôle les structures qui s’y forment, les structures majeures et mineures déterminant en retour les voies de perméabilité pour la migration des fluides. Les rampes de chevauchement sont des zones où le pendage généralement faible de failles de chevauchement augmente localement. Si les roches bordant la faille sont élastiques, le toit doit se déformer le long d’une rampe pour permettre le franchissement de cette aspérité. Cette déformation influence la répartition des contraintes statiques le long de la faille et le développement subséquent des roches de faille et des structures d’endommagement. Le chevauchement de Naukluft, un décollement basal d’âge cambrien dans le centre de la Namibie, est l’hôte d’une roche de faille carbonatée granuleuse appelée « Gritty Dolomite » ou dolomie granuleuse, formée à partir d’une boue de grains et de CO2 supercritique. À proximité d’une rampe de chevauchement, cette dolomie granuleuse a pénétré dans le toit à partir du plan de faille, formant de grands dykes (70 m) appelés « injectites » remplis par ces boues. La rampe de chevauchement sur la faille de Naukluft est un analogue de terrain d’une déformation active associée à une faille auquel des modèles de variations des contraintes statiques peuvent être appliqués pour relier le glissement le long de la faille à la déformation dans les épontes. La relation entre la rampe de chevauchement et les structures d’injectite a été examinée en cartographiant par GPS sur environ 20 km la trace tortueuse de la faille dans la région de la rampe de chevauchement et en calant sur ces observations un modèle topographique de la surface de la faille. Des coupes du modèle de la surface parallèles à la direction sud-est de transport du toit ont été versées dans le logiciel Coulomb3 de l’USGS pour modéliser les variations de contraintes statiques causées par la géométrie de la faille. La saturation des contraintes fixée dans le modèle équivalait à une résistance en tension de l’éponte dolomitique de 7 MPa, ceci afin de cerner les zones de possible fracturation en tension. Une zone de dilatation le long de la faille produite par le modèle correspond à la dilatation observée de la zone de faille. Les injectites ont tendance à être corrélées avec des zones où se forment de forts gradients de contraintes dans l’éponte, entre des zones de contraintes de compression et de tension. Les injectites ne sont pas bien corrélées avec des contraintes de tension statiques maximums dans l’éponte. Si des variations des contraintes de tension tatiques ont facilité la mise en place d’injectites, il est probable que des contraintes dynamiques durant le glissement cosismique ont accru la pression des fluides dans la boue de dolomie granuleuse, en forçant l’intrusion dans les roches fracturées bordant la faille. Je propose que, dans les sites de contraintes de compression accrues perpendiculaires à la surface de la faille, la formation d’injectites est favorisée le long de gradients extrêmes de contraintes dans l’éponte. Ainsi, une combinaison de conditions favorables dans l’éponte et de la pressurisation sur la surface de la faille est la meilleure explication de la formation d’injectites. J’ai appliqué une approche novatrice à l’estimation de l’énergie des paléoséismes à partir des dimensions de l’ouverture d’injectites, reposant sur des travaux antérieurs qui indiquent que du CO2 gazeux d’origine cosismique est le fluide pressurisant qui provoque l’inject </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Christen Danielle Rowe</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494c46c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pq98m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Geology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axs55mf97m"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fair and unfair weak oblivious transfers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Yongzhi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le transfert inconscient est une des principales primitives cryptographiques. Dans l’article [4], les auteurs ont présenté et étudié une variante faible du transfert inconscient que l’on qualifie d’injuste. Ils ont aussi démontré une simulation qui établie la limite théorique des primitives de type faible transfert inconscient injuste auxquelles on peut réduire le transfert inconscient. Notre  ́etude de cette simulation nous porte à croire qu’elle correspond en fait à une primitive juste plutôt qu’une primitive injuste. Dans ce mémoire, nous revisons quelques articles récent portant sur les faibles transferts inconscients injustes et étudions les propriétés de la nouvelle famille de primitives justes en relation au transfert inconscient.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Oblivious transfer is one of the most important cryptographic primitive. An un- fair weak version of OT with leakage is introduced and studied in [4]. The theoretical bound, which determines whether an unfair weak oblivious transfer can be used to implement OT, comes from a simulation analysis in [4]. The study on the simulation shows that it indeedcorresponds to another kind of very similar weak oblivious transfer, which we name as fair weak oblivious transfer (FWOT). In this thesis, we review recent papers on unfair weak oblivious transfer and study the properties of newly proposed primitive FWOT and its relation to OT.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Claude Crepeau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tq08s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mf97m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78tg21q"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A peer-to-peer matching system for grocery home delivery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sazavar, Amin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis introduces a new delivery method for electronic grocery shopping. This method involves a peer-to-peer matching system in which customers (carriers) who shop at a grocery store are assigned other customers (clients) who have ordered groceries to be delivered to their home.  Carriers deliver groceries to the clients’ homes, in return for an incentive.  The matching system matches carriers to clients to minimize the total travel time on the network.In order to examine how this new method of delivery performs, we compare it with the current methods of grocery delivery: regular grocery shopping, where every customer visits the grocery store, and truck delivery service, where groceries are delivered to customers who have ordered them. Four different scenarios are designed and simulated. A set of performance measures is then developed in order to evaluate the different scenarios. The matching system is simulated by employing a mixed-integer optimization method and solved by the IBM-CPLEX add-on in Matlab. The truck delivery service is presumed to be a multi-depot split-delivery truck delivery service and is simulated by using a partial inference of a multi-depot split-delivery vehicle routing problem heuristic. The scenarios are simulated and examined on a hypothetical network –The Sioux Falls traffic network.The most important finding from the results is that the new delivery system – the matching system – performs well in terms of total travel time in the network and has the potential to be implemented alongside the two other current methods of grocery shopping. The matching system reduces the travel time in the network compared to regular grocery shopping, but does not outperform truck home delivery service. The performance of the matching system is found to be the greatest when the number of carriers is equal to the number of clients.The matching system produced acceptable results in the study presented in this thesis; however, the need for a more detailed investigation is obvious to be able to judge its privileges to the regular truck delivery service.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse propose une nouvelle méthode de livraison pour l'épicerie en ligne. Cette méthode implique un système d'appariement de pairs dans laquelle les consommateurs (livreurs) qui achètent à l'épicerie sont liés à d'autres consommateurs (clients) qui ont commandé en ligne une épicerie à être livrée à leur domicile. Les livreurs livrent l'épicerie au domicile des clients, en échange d'une rétribution. Le système de recherche assigne les livreurs aux clients dans le but de minimiser le temps total du voyage sur le réseau.Afin d'évaluer comment cette nouvelle méthode de livraison performe, on le compare avec les méthodes actuelles de livraison d'épicerie: achats réguliers en épicerie, où chaque client se rend à l'épicerie et où la livraison est effectuée par camion et où l'épicerie est livrée à des clients qui les ont commandé. Quatre scénarios différents sont conçus et simulés. Un ensemble de mesures de la performance est ensuite développé afin d'évaluer les différents scénarios.Le système d'appariement est simulé en utilisant un procédé d'optimisation en nombres entiers et résolu par l' IBM - CPLEX module dans Matlab. Le service de livraison par camion est présumé être une fraction de la prestation de services de livraison de camion multi - dépôt et est simulé en utilisant une déduction partielle d'un multi- dépôt véhicule split- livraison problème de routage heuristique. Les scénarios sont simulés et examinés sur un réseau hypothétique - Le réseau de circulation Sioux Falls.Le point le plus important dans l'ensemble de ces résultats est que le nouveau système de livraison - le système de correspondance - se comporte bien en termes de temps total de voyage dans le réseau et a le potentiel pour être mis en œuvre aux côtés des deux autres méthodes actuelles de l'épicerie. Le système d'appariement réduit le temps de voyage dans le réseau par rapport à l'épicerie régulière, mais ne surpasse pas un service de livraison par camion. La performance du système d'appariement se trouve être la plus efficace lorsque le nombre de livreurs est égal au nombre de clients.Le système d'appariement a produit des résultats acceptables dans l'étude présentée dans cette thèse, mais la nécessité d'une enquête plus approfondie est évident pour être en mesure de juger de ses privilèges pour le service régulier de livraison par camion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marianne Hatzopoulou</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Matthew Roorda</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s5646.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tg21q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62fc38c"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Enhancing livelihood resilience in Makueni county, Kenya: the role of informal credit in smallholder farming</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>James, Carlyn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>En raison de la dégradation des terres, les pressions démographiques croissantes, et de fréquentes sécheresses, les petits exploitants agricoles dans les zones arides d'insécurité alimentaire du Kenya ont du mal à atteindre les objectifs de production tout en maintenant un ensemble diversifié de cultures pour soutenir la santé / nutrition. Dans la région semi-aride de la province orientale de Ukambani plus spécifiquement, ces facteurs sont aggravés par l'érosion des sols et la variabilité climatique, rendant n'importe quel niveau de l'agriculture commerciale, une entreprise précaire. Gardant cela à l'esprit, la plupart des établissements de crédit dans ce domaine considèrent les petits exploitants de financement pour être un jeu à très haut risque. En outre, le développement de sources de crédit qui sont en harmonie avec les besoins dépendante des saisons des petits exploitants n'est pas toujours très rentable pour les établissements de crédit. De la même manière, le point de vue de l'agriculteur nous dit que les coûts de transaction et des frais supplémentaires associés aux déplacements vers un établissement de crédit, de soumettre une demande de prêt, et en attendant qu'il soit traité sont tout simplement pas en harmonie avec l'énorme contraintes de temps et d'argent qui sont au centre de toute vie agraire. Pourtant, l'insécurité alimentaire chronique est une caractéristique particulière du système des moyens de subsistance des petits exploitants dans Ukambani qui couches urgence sur le dessus d'un ensemble déjà appuyant sur des besoins de crédit. Cette recherche est une des réponses à la question de savoir où ces agriculteurs se tournent de crédit en cas de besoin, et comment le crédit offre des petits exploitants une certaine prévisibilité au milieu d'un environnement très imprévisible et difficile. Dans cet article, je soutiens que le crédit améliore la résilience du système de subsistance des petits exploitants en aidant les agriculteurs absorber les chocs. Je décris le paysage financier de mon fieldsite du comté de Makueni, Ukambani, typologizing les sources formelles et informelles de crédit qui sont théoriquement disponibles pour les agriculteurs. Plus précisément, je passe en revue les raisons pour lesquelles les petits agriculteurs sont statistiquement moins susceptibles de se tourner vers les institutions formelles de crédit et de se concentrer sur les points forts de la structure de prêt du groupe informel (chama en kiswahili ou mwethiya dans kikamba), dont la preuve ethnographique montre est incroyablement fiable, adaptatif, et une source populaire de crédit. Ce faisant, je démontre les moyens de ces groupes permettent aux agriculteurs d'effectuer des transactions Kamba en utilisant une variété de médias (par exemple, le capital social, les biens matériels, des connaissances / compétences, trésorerie) qui portent tous une valeur similaire. Employant (2004) le concept de Jane Guyer de convertibilité, je soutiens que cette interprétation plus large de la valeur et de crédit permet à ces groupes de résister à être vulnérable aux fluctuations des flux de trésorerie ou des pénuries dans les aliments, par exemple. Parce que le crédit et l'endettement sont intrinsèquement liées concepts, je me concentre aussi sur l'état métaphysique de l'endettement et les diverses obligations interpersonnelles qui définissent la vie sociale de l'homme. J'utilise les données ethnographiques pour montrer que s'endetter à une autre personne (plutôt qu'une institution) renforce sa capacité à répondre aux risques et l'imprévisibilité. J'utilise (2003) le concept de Parker Shipton de mandatement et (2003) l'idée de Janet Roitman de la dette comme «richesse non autorisée» à développer l'idée que la dette est en fait une fonction productive de la vie financière des petits exploitants et peut donc être conçue comme un indicateur économique positif dans le plus grand système de petites exploitations de subsistance dans Ukambani.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Due to land degradation, growing population pressures, and frequent drought, smallholder farmers in Kenya’s food insecure drylands are struggling to meet production objectives while maintaining a diverse set of crops to support health/nutrition.  In the Eastern Province’s semi-arid region of Ukambani more specifically, these factors are compounded with soil erosion and climatic variability, making any level of commercial farming a precarious venture. Bearing this in mind, most lending institutions in this area consider financing smallholders to be a very high-risk game. Moreover, developing sources of credit that are consonant with smallholders’ seasonally-dependent needs is also not always very profitable for the lending institutions. In the same way, the farmer’s perspective tells us that the transaction costs and added fees associated with traveling to a lending institution, submitting a loan application, and waiting for it to be processed are simply not congruent with the enormous time and money constraints that are central to any agrarian lifestyle. Still, chronic food insecurity is a particular feature of the smallholder livelihood system in Ukambani which layers urgency on top of an already pressing set of credit needs. Smallholder credit needs are unique in that they generally require smaller amounts of money (by most standards, “microloans”) more frequently albeit erratically, and lending institutions often do not or cannot meet these needs in a cost-effective way. With this in mind, this research is one response to the question of where these farmers turn for credit in a time of need, and how credit offers the smallholder some predictability amidst a very unpredictable and challenging environment. In this paper, I argue that credit enhances the resilience of the smallholder livelihood system by helping farmers absorb shocks. I describe the financial landscape of my fieldsite of Makueni County, Ukambani, typologizing the formal and informal sources of credit that are theoretically available to farmers. More specifically, I review the reasons that smallholder farmers are statistically less likely to turn to formal lending institutions and focus on the strengths of the informal group lending structure (chama in Kiswahili or mwethiya in Kikamba), which ethnographic evidence shows is an incredibly reliable, adaptive, and popular source of credit. In doing so, I demonstrate the ways in these groups allow Kamba farmers to transact using a variety of media (e.g. social capital, material goods, knowledge/skills, cash) that all bear similar value. Employing Jane Guyer’s (2004) concept of convertability, I argue that this broader interpretation of value and credit allows these groups to resist being vulnerable to fluctuations in cash flow or shortages in food, for instance. Because credit and debt are inherently linked concepts, I also focus on the metaphysical state of indebtedness and the various interpersonal obligations that define human social life. I use ethnographic evidence to show that incurring debt to another person (rather than an institution) strengthens one’s capacity to respond to risk and unpredictability. There is nothing binding a person to an institution apart from coercion, while interpersonal debt is grounded in other forms of obligation that bind people together. I use Parker Shipton’s (2003) concept of entrustment and Janet Roitman’s (2003) idea of debt as “unsanctioned wealth” to develop the idea that debt is actually a productive feature of smallholders’ financial lives and can therefore be framed as a positive economic indicator within the larger system of smallholder livelihood in Ukambani. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Galaty</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf94s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fc38c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anthropology - Cultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236539f"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Alternative Inka imperial strategies in Northern Ecuador: a comparative study of Tawantinsuyu’s subjugation of the Caranqui confederation and the Yumbos</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hechler, Ryan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines how the Inkas’ preconceptions of two neighboring Ecuadorian societies, the Caranqui Confederation and the Yumbos, affected imperial methods of subjugation.  Drawing upon a mixture of primary historical sources as well as previous archaeological and ethnohistoric research, I suggest that regional Inka-proclaimed imperial accomplishments were not necessarily as successful as they conveyed.  My analysis provides evidence to further support recently developed notions of Inka-propagated discrimination against societies of different environmental contexts; however, I also find that many of these biases were slowly being reassessed in northern Ecuador.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine la façon dont les idées préconçues des Inkas à propos deux sociétés équatoriennes voisins, la Confédération Caranqui et la Yumbos, ont affectées les méthodes d’assujettissement impériales employés. En faisant usage de sources historiques primaires et de recherches archéologiques et ethnohistoriques précédentes, je suggère que les réalisations régionales proclamées par l’empire Inka n’étaient pas nécessairement autant de succès qu’ils prétendaient. Mon analyse fournit des preuves pour soutenir des notions récemment développées  que les Inkas propageaient de la discrimination à l'égard des sociétés de différents contextes environnementaux. Par contre, je trouve aussi que beaucoup de ces préjugés étaient en train d’être réévalués par l’empire dans le nord de l'Équateur.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nicole Couture</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920g0935.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236539f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anthropology - Anthropology Archaeology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35tc44p"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aspect-oriented modelling with instantiation cardinalities illustrated using software design patterns</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bhalotia, Sunit</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The power of aspect-oriented modelling is that a model designer can encapsulate the structural and behavioural properties of a specific concern within an aspect model. Theoretically, if the functionality provided by such a modularized concern is needed repeatedly within a system, a model user can instantiate the aspect model multiple times within the same target model. Practically, though, it is often not clear which model elements from the aspect model the model user is allowed to instantiate multiple times, and how the model weaver is supposed to compose the structural and behavioural elements of the aspect model instances with the target model. Motivated by past research that points out the pending issues related to multiple aspect model instantiations, this master thesis proposes to extend the customization interface of aspect models with instantiation cardinalities , a novel concept that allows the model designer to unambiguously declare which model elements of an aspect model can be multi-mapped. As a result, customization ambiguities are completely avoided for the model user. Furthermore, instantiation cardinalities give the model designer fine-grained control about how many instances of each structural and behavioural element contained in an aspect model are to be created in the target model. This thesis describes the syntax and semantics of instantiation cardinalities in detail, and shows how they integrate with object-oriented concepts such as inheritance and polymorphism. The elegance of the approach is illustrated by presenting aspect-oriented design models of six well-known and widely used behavioural, structural and creational design patterns.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La puissance de la modélisation orientée aspect est que le concepteur d'un modèle peut regrouper toutes les propriétés structurelles et comportementales d'une préoccupation particulière. En théorie, si la fonctionnalité que fournit un modèle aspect est utilisée à plusieurs endroits dans un même système, l'utilisateur de ce modèle aspect peut instancier le modèle plusieurs fois dans le même modèle cible. Cependant, en pratique, il s'avère que ce n'est souvent pas évident pour l'utilisateur de savoir quels éléments du modèle il a le droit d'instancier plusieurs fois et comment le tisseur de modèle doit les combiner avec le modèle cible dans ce cas là. En partant des problèmes connus de multi-instanciations des modèles aspects, cette thèse de maîtrise propose d'inclure des cardinalités d'instanciation dans l'interface de personnalisation d'un modèle aspect. Ce nouveau concept permet au concepteur d'un modèle de préciser exactement quels éléments peuvent être instanciés plusieurs fois, ce qui évite à l'utilisateur de faire des erreurs de personnalisation. De plus, en spécifiant des cardinalités d'instanciation, le concepteur du modèle peut contrôler le nombre d'instances de chaque élément du modèle aspect qui seront créées dans le modèle cible. Cette thèse www.gmail.comrrrrdécrit la syntaxe et la sémantique des cardinalités d'instanciation et montre comment les intégrer avec les concepts orientés objet tels que l'héritage et le polymorphisme. L'élégance de l'approche est démontrée en présentant les modèles aspects de six "design patterns" structurels et comportementaux bien connus.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jorg Andreas Kienzle</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d969x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tc44p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A794081146"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A codebook-based modeling approach for Bayesian STSA speech enhancement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ghodoosipour, Golnaz</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le rehaussement num´erique de la parole est une composante fondamentale des syst`emes detraitement audio et trouve actuellement des applications dans une vaste gamme de produits de consommation pour l’entreposage, la transmission et la reproduction de la voix, y compris : les t´el´ephones cellulaires, cam´eras vid´eo, enregistreurs vocaux PDA (assistants num´eriques), syst`emes de t´el´econf´erence et t´el´ephones mains-libres d´automobile. Au cours des derni`eres d´ecennies, le probl`eme du rehaussement de la parole a ´et´e consid´erablement ´etudi´e dans la litt´erature technique en raison de la demande croissante pour la r´eduction lu niveau de bruits de fond `a partir du signal vocal d´esir´e dans ces applications.Diff´erentes approches ont ´et´e propos´ees pour le rehaussement de parole contamin´ee par diff´erents types de bruit. L’objectif commun est de supprimer autant de bruit que possible sans introduire de distorsion au signal parole. Parmi les diff´erentes cat´egories de m´ethodes propos´ees pour l’am´elioration de la parole, les approches dans le domaine fr´equentiel sont g´en´eralement favoris´ees en raison de leur complexit´e inf´erieure, la facilit´e de mise en oeuvre sur un processeur num´erique en temps r´eel et la ressemblance avec le traitement naturel ayant lieu au sein du syst`eme auditif humain. Dans la famille des approches fr´equencielles, les estimateurs bay´esiens de l’amplitude spectrale `a courte dur´ee (STSA) offrent la meilleure performance globale en termes de la r´eduction du bruit et la distorsion de la parole. Alors que les m´ethodes STSA ont r´eussi dans les conditions de bruit stationnaire, le probl´eme de l’am´elioration de la parole dans un environnement de bruit non-stationnaire est encore une question d’int´erˆet courant pour la recherche.Le principal objectif de cette th`ese est de d´evelopper une estimation bay´esien am´elior´ee des param`etres STSA dans le but de rehausser la qualit´e d’un signal parole (canal unique) en pr´esence de niveaux mod´er´es de bruits non-stationnaires. `A cet ´egard, nous utilisons une formulation bayesienne bas´e sur la minimisation de l’erreur quadratique moyennede des param`etres `a pr´edictifs `a court terme de la parole et du bruit, partir de l’observation de la parole bruit´ee. Cette approche est fond´ee sur un travail r´ecent par Srinivasam et al. dans lequel des livres de codes sont utilis´es pour la repr´esentation des coecients de pr´ediction lin´e (LP) et gains d’excitition de la parole et du bruit. Ces livres de codes sont `a leur tour utilis´es afin de r´ealiser l’estimation MMSE des spectres de puissance qui sont requis lors de l’application de la m´ethode de rehaussement STSA. Dans cette th`ese, les spectres de puissance estim´es par l’approache MMSE sont utilis´es au sein de la m´ethode W-SA, o`u ils servent `a calculer le gain de rehaussement qui sera appliqu´e au signal btuit´e dans le domaine de fr´equence. En comparaison avec une m´ethod exis tante, la nouvelle m´ethode de rehaussement de la parole propos´ee dans cette th`ese donne lieu `a des am´eliorations importantes de la qualit´e du signal.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Speech enhancement algorithms are a fundamental component of digital speech and audio processing systems and currently find applications in a wide variety of consumer products for storage, transmission and playback of voice, including: cell phones, video cameras, PDAs voice recorders, teleconference speaker phones and hands-free car phones. Over the last few decades, the problem of speech enhancement has been vastly studied in the technical literature because of the increasing demand for removing a certain amount of background noise from the desiredspeech signal.Didifferent approaches have been proposed for the enhancement of speech contaminated by various types of noise. The common goal is to remove as much noise as possible without introducing distortion to the processed speech. Among the different categories of speech enhancement methods, frequency-domain approaches are usually favored in applications due to their lower complexity, ease of implementation on a real-time digital signal processor and resemblance to thenatural processing taking place in the human auditory system. Within the family of frequency domain approaches, Bayesian estimators of the short-time spectral amplitude (STSA) oer the best overall performance in terms of noise reduction and speech distortion. While the STSA methods have been successful under stationary noise conditions, the problem of speech enhancement in a nonstationary noise environment is still an open issue for research.The main goal of this thesis is to develop a Bayesian STSA estimator with the purpose of single-channel speech enhancement in the presence of moderate levels of nonstationary noise. In this regard, we use a Bayesian minimum mean squared error (MMSE) approach for the joint estimation of the short-term predictor parameters of speech and noise, from the noisy speech observation. This approach is based on a recent work by Srinivasan et al. where trained codebooks of speech and noise linear predictive (LP) coefficients are used to model the a priori information required by the Bayesian MMSE estimation. Afterwards, the estimated power spectra are passed to the W-SA Bayesian STSA speech enhancement method, where they are used to calculate the enhancement gain in the frequency domain. Finally, these gains are applied to the noisy speech short-term Fourier transforms. which are then converted back to the time-domain to obtain the desired estimate of the clean speech. When compared to an existing benchmark approach fromthe literature, the proposed speech enhancement approach developed in this thesis gives rise to a notable improvement in the quality of the processed noisy speech.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Benoit Champagne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qs973.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/794081146</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60d069w"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Beneath Trees - for string quartet and electronics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beebe, Preston</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis connects the principles of the rhizome as outlined by Gilles Deleuze and FelixGuattari and their application to the musical composition Beneath Trees. Concepts such asheterogeneity, multiplicity, rupture, and cartography are examined throughout the compositionalprocess of this work. I explain how each of these principles can be used in the context of amusical composition. This thesis will also touch briefly on creating and developing material froma single melodic line by means of computer-assisted composition. Through the use of rhizomaticprinciples, I will demonstrate ways in which canons and arithmetic sequences can formconnections between musical materials. Beneath Trees examines both how these principles caninfluence the compositional process, and also how they can be applied metaphorically to governmusical material in various ways.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse relie les principes du rhizome tel indiqué par Gilles Deleuze et Félix Guattariet leur application à la composition Beneath Trees. Des concepts tels que l'hétérogénéité, lamultiplicité, la rupture et la cartographie seront examinées dans l’ensemble du processus decomposition de ce travail. Je vais expliquer comment chacun de ces principes peuvent êtreutilisés dans le cadre d'une composition musicale. Cette thèse touchera aussi brièvement lacréation et le développement de matériel à partir d'une seule ligne mélodique au moyen decomposition assistée par ordinateur. Grâce à l'utilisation de principes rhizomatiques, je vaisdémontrer plusieurs facettes par lesquelles les canons et les suites arithmétiques peuvent formerdes connexions entre le matériel musical. Beneath Trees examine à la fois la façon dont cesprincipes peuvent influencer le processus de composition, et aussi les appliquermétaphoriquement à gouverner le matériel musical de diverses façons.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Philippe Leroux</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jr977.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d069w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avt150n09q"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fatigue behaviour of flax/glass/epoxy hybrid composites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Asgarinia, Soroush</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An experimental investigation of the fatigue behaviour of woven flax fibre hybridized with woven glass fibre, in an epoxy matrix, is presented. Three different hybrid compositions of flax fibre with glass fibre were manufactured using vacuum assisted resin transfer moulding. The hybrid composites are all five layer symmetric laminates [0w]5. All the laminates were tested under tension-tension fatigue loading conditions. The specific stress-number of cycles to failure (S-N curves) of all hybrid configurations were generated. The results were compared in terms of fatigue life, fatigue sensitivity, modulus decay and fracture mode of each hybrid laminate at different load levels. The results showed that introducing a small amount of glass fibre in a flax fibre laminate, improves the fatigue strength and fatigue life of the laminate. For the hybrids with partial replacement of glass fibre with flax fibre, the reduction in fatigue strength is evident compared to the plain glass fibre laminate. However, looking at the normalized S-N curve, good improvement on the fatigue life at low load levels and reduction in fatigue sensitivity is apparent.  In summary, this work shows the potential for increased use of natural fiber materials in low-load bearing structures.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse présente une étude expérimentale du comportement en fatigue de composites hybride lin/E-glass/époxy. Trois différentes compositions hybrides fibres de lin/fibre de verre ont été fabriquées en utilisant un procédé d’infusion de type VARTM. Les composites sont tous symétriques à cinq couches [0w]5. Ils sont ensuite testés en fatigue avec un chargement de type tension-tension. Le nombre de cycles à rupture (S-N) de toutes les configurations hybrides ont été obtenues. Différentes propriétés des composites hybrides sont comparés pour plusieurs chargements, notamment la résistance en fatigue, la sensibilité à la fatigue, la diminution du module ainsi que le mode de rupture. Les résultats montrent que l'introduction d’une petite quantité de fibre de verre dans un laminé de fibres de lin améliore la résistance à la fatigue et le nombre de cycle maximum avant rupture. Pour les hybrides avec remplacement partiel des fibres de verre avec de la fibre de lin, la réduction de la résistance à la fatigue est évidente par rapport au stratifié uniquement à base de fibres de verre. Cependant, en regardant la courbe S-N normalisée, on remarque clairement une amélioration significative de la durée de vie en fatigue à faible charge et une réduction de la sensibilité à la fatigue. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Larry Lessard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j413n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150n09q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acr56n4167"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of international norms on civil society's ability to control corruption: the case of Guatemala</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Castellanos Mottola, Mariana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine la relation entre les normes internationales et la capacité de la société civile de contrôler la corruption gouvernementale. Plus particulièrement, elle se concentre sur la capacité des organisations de la société civile guatémaltèque (OSC) dans l’utilisation des normes internationales contre la corruption, comme celles de la Convention Interaméricaine contre la Corruption (IACC en Anglais), pour le control effectif de ce problème. Sur la base de la théorie de la reddition de comptes sociale, cette recherche qualitative analyse les nuances du rôle potentiel à jouer par les OSC dans l’effort de faire le gouvernement responsable des actes de corruption. L’analyse de littérature pertinente et d’informations statistiques, ainsi que des interviews avec des informateurs clés, montrent que même quand ces indices reflètent des faiblesses et réclament un certain perfectionnement, l’infrastructure initiale en termes des politiques anti-corruption et des institutions est déjà sur place. Tous ces éléments ont leur origine dans la IACC et son mécanisme de révision MESICIC, et sont normalement utilisés par les OSC du Guatemala pour le potentiel control de la corruption dans le long terme.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the relationship between international norms and the ability of civil society to control government corruption. Specifically, it focuses on the ability of civil society organizations in Guatemala to utilize international norms against corruption, such as the Inter-American Convention against Corruption (IACC), to control this problem effectively. Based on a theory of social accountability, this qualitative research is aimed at analyzing the nuances of the potential role CSOs may have in holding the government accountable for corrupt actions. Through the assessment of relevant literature, statistics and key informant interviews, key findings reveal that although these indicators may show weaknesses and still demand refinement, the necessary initial infrastructure in terms of anticorruption policies and institutions is already locked in place. These intangibles all stem from the IACC and its peer review mechanism MESICIC, which in turn are effectively used by CSOs in Guatemala to potentially control corruption in the long-term.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Philip Oxhorn</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bf82k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n4167</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anz806321t"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Check ça-icite</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hyatt, Nicolas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Check ça-icite is a musical composition for solo amplified voice, chamber ensemble and tape modelled on and featuring the French dialect spoken in Windsor-Essex County, Ontario. The source material of the work consists entirely of recorded speech samples from this region, whose linguistic and acoustic properties are analysed and transcribed both intuitively and with the assistance of the computer to generate pitch, harmony, rhythm, timbre, and other musical material. The instrumental ensemble metaphorically represents a collection of voices communicating the shared experiences of these Francophones. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Check ça-icite est une composition musicale pour voix amplifiée solo, ensemble instrumental et bande qui s’inspire du dialecte francophone parlé dans le comté Windsor-Essex en Ontario. Le matériau de l’œuvre provient entièrement d’échantillons de la langue parlée dans cette région; ces échantillons ont été analysés et transcrits intuitivement, ainsi qu’à l’aide de l’informatique musicale, pour gérer les hauteurs, le rythme, le timbre et d’autres paramètres musicaux au sein de l’œuvre. L’ensemble instrumental représente, d’une manière métaphorique, un regroupement de voix qui communiquent les expériences et le vécu des membres de cette communauté francophone.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Philippe Leroux</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kn75f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806321t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591c28p"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Capturing heterogenity in functional regression relationships: A fuzzy cluster-wise linear regression approach to functional linear models and functional extended redundancy analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tan, Tianyu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Données fonctionnelles sont des mesures qui sont censées être généré à partir d'une fonction lisse sous-jacent varie sur un continuum tels que le temps ou l'espace. Modèles linéaires fonctionnels ( FLM ) et fonctionnelle prolongée analyse de redondance (FERA ) sont des méthodes d'analyse de régression qui étudient les relations entre prédicteur fonctionnelle et variables dépendantes. En réalité, les données fonctionnelles pourraient provenir de population hétérogène et en ignorant cette hétérogénéité au niveau de la grappe se traduirait par des inférences statistiques biaisées. Pour capturer l'hétérogénéité de niveau des grappes dans les données fonctionnelles, diverses approches de clustering ont été développés par l'extension des techniques de clustering des données multivariée à l'analyse des données fonctionnelles. Néanmoins, il ya eu peu d'efforts pour développer des algorithmes de clustering pour capturer l'hétérogénéité de niveau des grappes dans les relations de régression fonctionnels. Cette thèse vise à combler l'écart en étendant floue régression de cluster - sage ( FCR ), qui est une méthode populaire pour capturer une telle hétérogénéité dans la régression linéaire multivariée, les paramètres de régression fonctionnels. Les méthodes proposées , appelées fonctionnelle cluster sage floue régression ( FFCR ) et fonctionnelle floue longue analyse de redondance ( FFERA ), combinent FCR avec FLM et la FERA, respectivement, d'une manière unifiée. Ils permettent de classer les sujets en différents groupes et l'estimation des coefficients de régression cluster sage simultanément. La thèse commence par examiner les méthodes de classification existantes compte de l'hétérogénéité de niveau des grappes dans les données fonctionnelles ou des relations de régression multiple. Puis, il discute FLM, FERA et FCR, qui sont les trois piliers des méthodes proposées dans le mémoire. La thèse fournit ensuite des détails techniques de FFCR et FFERA, y compris les critères et les algorithmes pour l'estimation des paramètres. L'utilité de FFCR et FFERA est démontrée par l'analyse des ensembles de données réelles et simulées. La thèse se termine par un résumé des implications et des extensions possibles des méthodes proposées.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Functional data are measurements that are assumed to be generated from an underlying smooth function varying over a continuum such as time or space. Functional linear models (FLM) and functional extended redundancy analysis (FERA) are regression analysis methods that investigate the relationships between functional predictor and dependent variables. In reality, functional data could come from heterogeneous populations and ignoring such cluster-level heterogeneity would result in biased statistical inferences. To capture cluster-level heterogeneity in functional data, various clustering approaches have been developed by extending clustering techniques for multivariate data to the analysis of functional data. Nonetheless, there has been little attempt to develop clustering algorithms to capture cluster-level heterogeneity in functional regression relationships. This dissertation aims to fill the gap by extending fuzzy cluster-wise regression (FCR), which is a popular method for capturing such heterogeneity in multivariate linear regression, to functional regression settings. The proposed methods, called functional fuzzy cluster-wise regression (FFCR) and functional fuzzy extended redundancy analysis (FFERA), combine FCR with FLM and FERA, respectively, in a unified manner. They allow classifying subjects into different clusters and estimating cluster-wise regression coefficients simultaneously. The dissertation begins by reviewing existing clustering methods in accounting for cluster-level heterogeneity in functional data or multiple regression relationships. Then, it discusses FLM, FERA and FCR, which are the three building blocks of the methods proposed in the dissertation. The dissertation subsequently provides technical details of FFCR and FFERA, including their criteria and algorithms for parameter estimation. The usefulness of FFCR and FFERA are demonstrated by the analysis of simulated and real data sets. The dissertation concludes with a summary of the implications and possible extensions of the proposed methods.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Heungsun Hwang</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0326160.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c28p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Experimental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s339p"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Summer camp youth leadership development: an investigation of adolescents’ perceptions of leadership and program value</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martin, Katlyn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude qualitative vise à explorer les perceptions des adolescents au leadership et au Waycross Camp, en particulier à son programme Leaders-en-Formation  (c-à-d.: Leaders-in-Training (L.I.T.)). Les données ont été recueillies au moyen d'entretiens auprès des anciens participants du programme L.I.T. et des notes de réflexion. Les objectifs de recherche ont évolué avec la progression de l’étude en posant une question de recherche et trois sous-questions. La question directrice de la recherche était la suivante: « De quelles façons le programme L.I.T. de Waycross Camp a-t-il informé les notions de leadership aux participants? » Les sous-questions restantes posées: a) « Quels facteurs externes (c-à-d : l'endroit, les pairs, ou le personnel) ont-ils contribué aux expériences des participants au programme L.I.T. de Waycross Camp?, »  b) « Quelles sont les choses que les participants ont appréciées du programme L.I.T. de Waycross Camp? », et c) « De quelles façons le programme L.I.T. de Waycross Camp a-t-il influencé les participants depuis la fin du programme? »Une revue de la littérature a conduit au cadre conceptuel de cette étude, qui comprenait trois domaines qui se chevauchaient : 1) « Le développement de la jeunesse », 2) « Le leadership des jeunes », et 3) « Le camp d'été. » En utilisant le motif de la théorie à base empirique et le constructivisme, une analyse constante et comparative des données a révélé quatre thèmes émergents de participants, y compris respectivement: 1) « Combler l'écart », 2) « Donner la permission d'être humain », 3) « Retrousser ses manches », et 4) « Servir le bien de tous ». Chacun de ces quatre thèmes a donné un résultat, y compris respectivement : 1) « La communauté », 2) « La largeur d’esprit », 3) « Les pleins pouvoirs », et 4) « Le caractère ». Quatre résultats de camp représentés dans les recherches pertinentes ont été synthétisés avec les quatre thèmes émergents et leurs quatre résultats, y compris respectivement : 1) « L’interaction sociale », 2) « L’identité et le concept de soi », 3) « L’intention et l'engagement », et 4) « La spiritualité, l’éthique, et la moralité ». En tout, les thèmes, les résultats, et les résultats du camp ont produit un modèle holistique de leadership de la jeunesse.En fin de compte, ces quatre thèmes, leurs résultats, et les résultats du camp ont révélé un chevauchement entre les notions valorisées des participants du leadership et les aspects valorisés de Waycross Camp et son programme L.I.T. En élaborant le leadership comme une expérience relationnelle, les participants ont démontré une compréhension du leadership en harmonie avec les théories contemporaines de leadership. Bien que les participants aient indiqué que certains facteurs externes (c-à-d : l'endroit et les pairs) contribuaient à leurs expériences L.I.T., les réponses des participants concernant l'impact perçu du personnel du programme furent mitigées. Même si les participants ont parfois lutté pour identifier les compétences spécifiques acquises au programme L.I.T. qu'ils étaient en mesure d'appliquer dans des situations particulières, les participants ont déclaré qu’ils étaient mieux équipés et mieux assurés en utilisant le leadership une fois le programme L.I.T. terminé. En outre, de nombreux participants ont attribué des gains importants dans leur savoir-faire quotidien (par exemple, leur compassion, leur compréhension, etc.) suite aux expériences de Waycross Camp.Mots clés: le développement de la jeunesse, le leadership, le camp</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This qualitative study aims to explore adolescents’ perceptions of leadership and Waycross Camp, specifically its Leaders-in-Training (i.e., L.I.T.) program. Data was collected through interviews with former L.I.T. program participants and reflective memos. Research aims evolved as the study progressed, ultimately posing one research question and three sub-questions. The guiding research question asked: How has Waycross Camp’s L.I.T. program informed participants’ notions of leadership? The remaining sub-questions asked: a) How do external factors (i.e., location, peers, or staff) contribute to Waycross Camp’s L.I.T. program participants’ camp experience?, b) What do participants value about Waycross Camp’s L.I.T. program?, and c) How has Waycross Camp’s L.I.T. program influenced participants since the program’s completion? A review of the literature led to this study’s conceptual framework, which included three overlapping domains: 1) “Youth development,” 2) “Youth leadership,” and 3) “Summer camp.” Using grounded theory and constructivism, a constant comparison data analysis revealed four emergent participant themes, including 1) “Bridging the gap,” 2) “Giving permission to be human,” 3) “Rolling up your sleeves,” and 4) “Serving the greater good.” Each of these four themes yielded an outcome, including 1) “Community,” 2) “Openness,” 3) “Empowerment,” and 4) “Character,” respectively. Four camp outcomes depicted in relevant research were synthesized with the four emergent themes and their outcomes, including 1) “Social relationships,” 2) “Identity and self concept,” 3) “Agency and engagement,” and 4) “Spirituality, ethicality, and morality,” respectively. Together, the themes, outcomes, and camp outcomes produced a holistic model of youth leadership.Ultimately, these four themes, outcomes, and camp outcomes revealed an overlap between participants’ valued notions of leadership and valued aspects of Waycross Camp and its L.I.T. program. In framing leadership as a relational experience, participants demonstrated an understanding of leadership congruent with contemporary leadership theories. While participants reported that some external factors (i.e., location and peers) contributed to their L.I.T. experiences, responses were mixed as to the perceived impact of L.I.T. program staff. Although participants struggled at times to identify specific skills acquired during L.I.T. that they were able to apply to specific circumstances, participants reported feeling better equipped and assured in exercising leadership after the program’s completion. Furthermore, many participants attributed significant gains in life skills (e.g., compassion, understanding, etc.) to Waycross Camp experiences. Key words: youth development, youth leadership, camp</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lynn Butler Kisber</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Anila Asghar</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf96b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s339p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93h270j"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Higher ectoparasite richness and abundance in introduced red lionfish («Pterois volitans») at low latitudes: implications for biotic resistance and enemy release</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sellers Lara, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Several hypotheses have been proposed to explain the role of parasites and pathogens in biological invasions, however two fundamentally related hypotheses are most prevalent in the literature: the Enemy Release Hypothesis (ERH) and the Biotic Resistance Hypothesis (BRH). The ERH predicts that introduced species escape the negative effects of parasites present in their native range. This release is postulated to benefit invaders when interacting with native species in their introduced range. On the other hand, parasites in the introduced range can colonize and accumulate in the introduced host if they are able to shift from closely related native host species; this accumulation of parasites in the introduced range can potentially offset the benefits of enemy release. Thus, in contrast to the ERH, the BRH predicts that biotic interactions, such as parasitism, can limit the success of introduced species in their new range. This resistance by enemies in the introduced range is thought to be stronger at low tropical latitudes compared to higher latitudes. For the first component of my thesis I used the rapid and widespread invasion by the Indo-Pacific lionfish as a natural experiment to determine whether introduced lionfish accumulate more parasites and experience a greater effect of parasites at low latitudes. I compared the diversity, abundance, and impact of parasites infecting this invader across latitudes from Florida to Panama. I predicted that while overall lionfish would be infected by few parasites, their abundance and species richness would increase at low tropical latitudes. The second part of this thesis considers the accumulation of parasites from native hosts onto the invasive lionfish and begins to examine one prediction of the enemy release hypothesis. For this I compared parasite richness and abundance between lionfish and three ecologically similar native fishes. I expected that some parasites from native hosts would colonize lionfish, but predicted that natives will be more heavily parasitized and experience a stronger effect of parasites overall.My results are consistent with previous studies of latitudinal patterns of parasitism in native fish; ectoparasite diversity and abundance increased at low latitudes, but endoparasites did not follow a latitudinal pattern. Although ectoparasite species richness and abundance increased at low latitudes I did not find a significant effect of parasite abundance on the condition of lionfish. In comparing parasitism across host species, both native hosts were infected by a greater species richness and abundance of parasites compared to introduced lionfish. Furthermore, parasite abundance had a significant effect on the condition of the native grouper Cephalopholis cruentata, but I did not detect such an effect on the lionfish. Combined, my results show that introduced lionfish accumulate more parasites at lower latitudes, however parasitism in the invader may be too low to generate biotic resistance. Relative to lionfish, native hosts were more heavily parasitized, and parasites had a significant negative effect on the condition of at least one native host. Low rates of parasitism could benefit lionfish when competing with more heavily parasitized native fishes, however more research is needed to evaluate this and examine potential indirect effects of parasites on the invasion. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Plusieurs hypothèses ont été proposées pour expliquer le rôle des parasites et pathogènes dans les invasions biologiques; cependant, deux hypothèses reliées prévalent dans la littérature: l’hypothèse de la libération des ennemis (ERH) et l’hypothèse de la résistance biotique (BRH). La ERH prédit que les espèces envahissantes s’échappent des effets négatifs des parasites présents dans leur aire de répartition indigène. Cette libération est postulée de bénéficier les envahisseurs dans leurs interactions avec les espèces indigènes dans les lieux où ils ont été introduits. D’autre part, les parasites dans la zone introduite peuvent coloniser et s’accumuler dans l’hôte introduit s’ils sont capables de passer d’espèces d’hôtes indigènes reliés. Cette accumulation de parasites dans la nouvelle aire de répartition peut potentiellement neutraliser les bénéfices de la libération des ennemis. Contrairement à la ERH, la BRH prédit que les interactions biotiques, comme le parasitisme, peuvent limiter le succès des espèces envahissantes dans leur nouvelle aire de répartition. Cette résistance effectuée par les ennemis dans la zone introduite est supposée être plus forte aux latitudes plus basses tropicales qu’aux latitudes plus élevées. Dans la première partie de ma thèse, j’ai utilisé l’invasion rapide et répandue de la rascasse Indo-Pacifique comme une expérience naturelle pour déterminer si les rascasses introduites accumulent plus de parasites et subissent des effets plus prononcés de parasites aux latitudes basses. J’ai comparé la diversité, l’abondance et l’impacte des parasites qui infectent cet envahisseur à travers de latitudes de Florida à Panama. J’ai prédit que, bien que les rascasses soient infectées avec peu de parasites, l’abondance et richesse de ces-derniers augmenteraient aux latitudes basses tropicales.La deuxième partie de ma thèse considère l’accumulation de parasites d’hôtes indigènes sur la rascasse envahissante, et examine une prédiction de l’hypothèse de la libération des ennemis. Ici j’ai comparé la richesse et abondance de parasites entre la rascasse et trois poissons indigènes qui étaient pareils écologiquement. J’attendais que quelques parasites d’hôtes indigènes colonisent la rascasse, mais qu’en général, les espèces indigènes seraient plus infectées et subiraient un effet plus fort des parasites.Mes résultats coïncident avec des études antérieures de modèles latitudinaux de parasitisme dans des poissons indigènes: la diversité et abondance d’ectoparasites augmentaient aux latitudes basses, mais les endoparasites ne suivaient pas un modèle latitudinal. Bien que la richesse et l’abondance des ectoparasites augmentent aux latitudes basses, je n’ai pas trouvé un effet significatif de l’abondance des parasites sur la condition des rascasses. En comparant le parasitisme entre hôtes, j’ai trouvé que les hôtes indigènes ont été infectés par une diversité et abondance élevés de parasites par rapport à la rascasse introduite. Par ailleurs, l’abondance des parasites avait un effet significatif sur la condition du mérou indigène Cephalopholis cruentata, mais je n’ai pas détecté un effet pareil sur la rascasse.Ensembles, mes résultats indiquent que la rascasse introduite accumule plus de parasites aux latitudes basses; cependant, ce taux de parasitisme est peut-être trop bas pour générer une résistence biotique. Par rapport à la rascasse, les hôtes indigènes étaient plus fortement infectés, et les parasites avaient un effet négatif significatif sur la condition d’au moins un hôte indigène. Des bas taux de parasitisme pourraient bénéficier à la rascasse quand elle est en compétition avec des poissons indigènes fortement infectés; cependant, plus de recherche est nécessaire pour évaluer cela et examiner des effets indirects potentiels des parasites sur cette espèce. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brian Leung</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mark Torchin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t243p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h270j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Ecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awh246w05g"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Robotic Anesthesia: a Novel Pharmacological Robot for General Anesthesia and Robot-assisted Intubation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wehbe, Mohamad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L’anesthésie robotique s’occupe de la gestion pharmacologique des patients ainsi que des tâches manuelles habituellement effectuées par les anesthésistes. &#x2028;L’anesthésie générale comprend trois éléments : l’hypnose, l’analgésie et la relaxation musculaire. Différents médicaments sont utilisés pour contrôler chacun de ces composants. Habituellement, ces médicaments sont administrés manuellement par les anesthésistes. Afin de réduire la charge de travail de l’anesthésiste en salle d’opération, nous avons considéré l’administration automatique de l’anesthésie générale. À cet égard, nous avons développé un système en boucle fermée pour effectuer la livraison automatique des médicaments d’anesthésie générale. Ce système administre le propofol pour le contrôle de l’hypnose, le remifentanil pour le contrôle de l’analgésie, et le rocuronium pour la relaxation musculaire. Ce système comprend un ordinateur pour exécuter l’algorithme à boucle fermée, un moniteur d’anesthésie, et trois pompes à perfusion. Le système contrôle le débit de perfusion de façon à ce que les valeurs des signes vitaux se rapprochent le plus possible de leurs valeurs cibles. Cette dissertation présente une revue des développements robotiques en anesthésie. De plus, elle présente le développement technologique du système en boucle fermée, les algorithmes, l’interface utilisateur et son utilisation clinique.Cette dissertation traite également de l’intubation assistée par robot. Nous avons comparé les performances du système d’intubation sur un mannequin de voies respiratoires standard et un mannequin de voies respiratoires à difficulté ajustable. Nous avons utilisé deux mannequins de voies respiratoires, un mannequin de voies respiratoires standard, et un mannequin de voies respiratoires à difficulté réglable sur deux réglages : standard et difficile. Pour chaque configuration, vingt essais d’intubation ont été faits. Les résultats montrent que les intubations assistées par robot permettent une acquisition de compétence plus rapide que les intubations manuelles.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Robotic anesthesia has to deal with pharmacological patient management as well as manual gestures usually performed by anesthesiologists. General anesthesia is composed of three components: hypnosis, analgesia, and neuromuscular blockade. Different drugs are used to control each of these components. Usually, administration of these drugs is under the manual control of anesthesiologists. In order to reduce the anesthesiologist’s workload in the operating room, we propose automated delivery of general anesthesia.We have developed a closed-loop system for automated delivery of all drugs used for general anesthesia. This system delivers propofol for hypnosis control, remifentanil for control of analgesia, and rocuronium for neuromuscular blockade. The system is composed of a computer connecting the closed-loop algorithms, vital signs monitoring parameters, and three infusion pumps. The infusion rates and doses of the drugs are determined based on the feedback from the monitoring parameters.This thesis presents a review of robotic developments in anesthesia. It presents the technological development of the closed loop system, the algorithms, the user interface and its clinical use.The thesis also presents a system, which allows robot-assisted intubation. The technical features of this system are described as well as its testing in simulation on a standard airway mannequin and difficult airway mannequin. We hypothesized that robot assistance results in a faster skill acquisition than manual procedures for endotracheal intubations. We used two airway mannequins, a standard airway mannequin, and an adjustable airway mannequin on two settings: standard and difficult. For every setup, 20 intubation trials were performed; intubation times were measured for each trial. Results show that robot-assisted intubations allow faster skill acquisition over manual intubation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thomas Hemmerling</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qv900.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246w05g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>