<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A44558g31w"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Majlisul Islamil Ala Indonesia (MIAI) : its socio-religious and political activities (1937-1943)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Syaroni, Mizan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates the activities of the Majlisul Islamil A`la Indonesia (MIAI), an Islamic federative organization of pre-independent Indonesia, elaborating in particular on the federation's socio-religious and political stance. Operating for only six years (1937--1943), the MIAI represented Muslim groups, as a counterpart to the "secularists," within the nationalist movement during both the final years of Dutch rule and the early stages of the Japanese occupation. The MIAI was established for the specific purpose of unifying the Islamic organizations---political and non-political, traditionalist and modernist alike---while at the same time reviving Muslim political and socio-religious strength after the decline of the Sarekat Islam, which had for almost fifteen years dominated the nationalist scene. The mission of the MIAI was seen by Muslims as a response to the threat posed by external forces. It reacted in particular against Dutch policies considered discriminatory by Muslims concerning matters involving Islamic belief and practice, such as marriage and education. The federation also took a strong stand regarding Christian polemic aimed at Islam and took part in Indonesian Muslim response. That the establishment of the MIAI was favored by most Islamic organizations attested to the strong sentiment among Indonesian Muslims for a common front, regardless of their differences on socio-religious and political issues. Together with the GAPI (Gabungan Partai Politik Indonesia or the Federation of Indonesian Political Parties) and the PVPN (Persatuan Vakbonden Pegawai Negeri, or the Association of Government Employees), the MIAI took part in demanding political reform on behalf of Muslim groups. Indeed, notwithstanding its short life span, the MIAI was a pioneer for national unity in general and Indonesian Muslim unity in particular.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Turgay, A. Uner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9675863.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558g31w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Indonesia -- Politics and government</dc:subject><dc:subject>Madjlis Islam Alaa Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islam and politics -- Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nationalism -- Indonesia -- History -- 20th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nk32c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The mystery of the Mystery sonatas : a musical rosary picture book</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Strieck, Katia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Heinrich Ignaz Franz von Biber's (1644--1704) Mystery Sonatas of 1676 are a set of fifteen sonatas for violin and continuo plus one unaccompanied passacaglia for solo violin. They are unusual in their use of scordatura and in the presence of an image associated with the Rosary devotion before each sonata. This association between image and music in the sonatas, and the correspondence to the fifteen mysteries of the Rosary closely resembles the structure of seventeenth-century Rosary picture books. In this thesis the context, background, and meaning of the sonatas is explored. The first chapter examines the function of the sonatas and places them in context by outlining musical life in Salzburg, the sonata tradition, the Rosary devotion, Emblem books, and Rosary picture books. The second chapter focuses more on the collection as a whole and on elements such as key, dance affect, and scordatura. The third chapter consists of an examination of three sonatas---each one unique in placing the listener in a different relation to the mystery.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cumming, Julie E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xx021.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nk32c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biber, Heinrich Ignaz Franz, 1644-1704. Sonatas, violin, continuo (Bayerische Staatsbibliothek: Mus. Ms. 4123)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s697c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Predicting democratic peace (DP) breakdown : a new game-theoretic model of democratic crisis behavior</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stocco, Aaron B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Research into the democratic peace (DP) proposition has shown that democracies rarely, if ever, fight wars against each other. At the same time, rational choice models predict that there will sometimes be circumstances in which war is a rational option for rational states. If democratic states are rational, then war between them should, theoretically, be an option that is exercised. This thesis examines the possibility of Democratic Peace (DP) Breakdown, whereby the causal factors responsible for democratic peace fail to operate properly and war between democracies becomes either likely or inevitable. Applying a game theoretic model of asymmetric deterrence and the concepts of communication and commitment problems in crisis bargaining, the author shows that there is a strong deductive argument for DP Breakdown. This thesis will attempt to show that a strong deductive argument can be made for deterrence failure between democracies embroiled in an international crisis. While most research into the democratic peace is concerned with identifying and explaining how and why democratic peace succeeds, this thesis will develop a counter-intuitive theoretical approach for understanding how and why democratic peace fails. By doing so it is expected that a greater understanding of the behavioral dynamics of democratic peace will be developed. The argument developed here will draw on the theoretical works of Fearon and Kilgour &amp; Zagare and attempt to bridge the gap between democratic peace studies, formal deterrence modeling, and rationalist theories of war. It is hoped that the synthesis of these three bodies of literature will produce a model of democratic crisis behavior that is capable of generating new and interesting hypotheses about democracies and international crisis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Meadwell, Hudson</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wj175.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s697c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Peace -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Deterrence (Strategy) -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>War -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50gz281"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"Living right and being free" : country music and modern American conservatism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stein, Eric, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The rising popularity of country music in the United States since WWII is a cultural phenomenon intimately related to the ascendance of conservative values, leaders, and movements over the same period. By routinely celebrating themes like heterosexual love, the patriarchal nuclear family, hard work, individualism, freedom, patriotism, religion, and small-town life, country music provided the soundtrack for the insurgent conservatism of politicians like George Wallace, Richard Nixon, and Ronald Reagan. In the sixties and seventies, while other forms of popular music (rock, folk, soul) articulated the values of liberals, socialists, hippies, war protestors, feminists, and civil rights activists, country music alone stood for the "traditional" values cherished by the so-called "silent majority" that powered the rise of the Right. The spread of both country music and conservatism is also a reflection of the "southernization" of America---the diffusion across the nation of cultural and political traits long associated with the South.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Moore, Leonard J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pq19z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gz281</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Conservatism -- United States -- History -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Country music -- History and criticism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zg61g"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Lady and the unicorn : the iconography of love in a series of fifteenth-century tapestries</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sowley, Katherine Ilsley</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The corpus of literature on the Lady and The Unicorn tapestries has most often focussed on technical/stylistic aspects or attempted to explain the iconography of this work with little definitive consensus in either domain. An informative element in the history of this problematic work is the patron, who played a primordial role in the artistic process of the late Middle Ages. Although the patron of our subject has been identified as Jean LeViste and his personal and family history is relatively well-documented, few attempts have been made to place this work in the context of his reality. An investigation of the figure and his milieu will certainly benefit our understanding of the themes of heraldic display and courtly love that are most often proposed to interpret our work. The patron's situation will bring us to a new level of interpretation in this work---the glorification of women---which, like the other themes represented throughout this series, served the interests of the patron and reflected his reality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boker, Hans J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765373215.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg61g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Love in art</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tapestry, Medieval -- France</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qp23x"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Early American Pentecostalism and the issues of race, gender, war, and poverty : a history of the belief system and social witness of early twentieth century Pentecostalism and its nineteenth century holiness roots</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smalridge, Scott</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Early American Pentecostalism had an ambiguous social witness, which contained both radical and conservative elements. The millennarian-restorationist core of the Pentecostal belief system was prophetic and counter-cultural in that it inspired adherents to denounce the injustices of the status quo and announce the justice of the soon-coming Kingdom of God. Consequently, in the earliest years of the American movement, many Pentecostals, professed and practiced (1) racial equality, (2) gender equality, (3) pacifism, and (4) anti-capitalism. However, this prophetic social witness co-existed, from the very beginning, with a strong conservative ethos, which defended the norms, beliefs, and values of nineteenth-century 'Evangelical America' against the apparent religious and cultural 'anarchy' of modern society. As Pentecostal groups (especially white Pentecostal groups such as the Assemblies of God) organised, institutionalised, and rose in socioeconomic status, the prophetic voices of early Pentecostalism were increasingly ignored, and the conservative ethos grew to dominate Pentecostal social concerns.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Klempa, William J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg62r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qp23x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Race relations -- Religious aspects -- Pentecostal churches -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pentecostalism -- History of doctrines</dc:subject><dc:subject>Church and social problems -- Pentecostal churches -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pentecostalism -- United States -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s698n"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>As her world turns : women and soap opera</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schachter, Tammy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mass produced narratives that have been designed and targeted for predominantly female audiences have been marginalized by dominant culture. Throughout the history of art and English literature, women have been both objectified and misrepresented. All that has been deemed domestic, emotional and of the personal sphere has been declared valueless by patriarchy. The soap opera genre reverses this negative valorization. It is one that perpetuates the feminine tradition of creating communities through words---talk, gossip, testimony. In this work, the American soap opera is discussed as a venue for the exploration of issues that concern women's lives, as a site for the generation of female pleasure, and as the mother of subcultural networks that inform a female community. While the narratives address women's concerns, the soap opera fan magazines and fan clubs celebrate a form that highlights orality, emotion and empathy in a culture that often depreciates them.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kaite, Berkeley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2687308.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s698n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soap operas -- United States -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Television and women -- United States</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A736666803"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Compassion in The Tibetan Book of the Dead and the Tractate Mourning : a comparative study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sasson, Vanessa Rebecca</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Tibetan Book of the Dead and the Jewish Tractate Mourning are important texts about death in their respective traditions. The Tibetan Book of the Dead is a manual read by the living to the deceased as the deceased journeys through the many realms of the after-life. It is an abstract, philosophical text. The Tractate Mourning on the other hand, is a highly empirical and pragmatic text that guides the living through their loss. It is concerned only with the living left behind and offers no guidance to the deceased. Despite this profound difference however, this thesis has as its objective to show that both traditions, as evidenced through these texts, share an underlying emotion: compassion. Through the concern shown to the deceased as he or she stumbles through the often terrifying realms of the after-life in the Tibetan tradition, and through the precise and detailed instructions given to the living in the Jewish tradition as the mourners are guided through their grief, both texts exhibit profound compassion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Levy, Barry</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hayes, Richard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k06989604.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736666803</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Death -- Religious aspects -- Judaism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Karma-gli-pa, 14th cent. Bar do thos grol</dc:subject><dc:subject>Death -- Religious aspects -- Buddhism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8s45qb94x"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Learning and retention adaptations of myoelectric activity during a novel multi-joint task</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sarantinos, George D. V.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The learning and retention adaptations of muscle activity were studied during a novel multi-joint task. Electromyographic (EMG) signals were recorded from the posterior deltoid, long and lateral heads of the triceps, pectoralis major, biceps and brachioradialis muscles. These data were assayed in a pattern recognition analysis (SVD) to ascertain the minimum number of 'common features' or waveforms (W's) required to describe the set of input EMG patterns (IP). Fifteen participants performed targeted arm movements, which incorporated the shoulder and elbow articulations, as fast and as accurately as possible in the horizontal plane. Both experimental (E) and control (C) groups were employed. The E group was trained (Day 1 to Day 4) and tested both pre- and post-learning. They were further re-tested during a retention period (RET) consisting of 1, 2, 4, 6 and 8 week post-learning sessions. The C group was tested before and after learning and at the end of the RET period. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Turcotte, Rene</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz8062014.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qb94x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electromyography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Motor learning</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arm -- Movements</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m4012"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Picturing Ireland in England during the Great Famine era : the depiction of Ireland by artists and illustrators, 1842-1854</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saparoff, Linda W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the pictorial record of the Great Famine Era circa 1842--1854: the engravings, sketches, and paintings found in the English public domain. As part of the historical record, these contemporary visual images document attitudes of prejudice and indifference held about Ireland and the Irish during the calamitous years of the Great Irish Famine. The study probes the broad contextual background, narrative structure, and didactic intent of these works in an effort to assess the prejudicial impact of the visual record as a whole.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elbourne, Elizabeth</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hr79p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m4012</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ireland -- In art</dc:subject><dc:subject>Famines -- Ireland -- History -- 19th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000222f"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Muslim responses to Christianity in modern Indonesia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ropi, Ismatu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As Indonesian Muslim depictions of Christianity have varied over time, this study is an attempt to provide a brief survey of the Muslim attitudes towards Christianity in modern Indonesia. It will set the stage by first investigating the Muslim depiction of Christianity as found in the seventeenth century works of Nuruddin al-Raniri. It will go on to survey some aspects of Dutch colonial policy concerning Indonesian Islam and will cover Muslim responses to and perceptions of Christian doctrine in the Old Order and New Order periods. Some polemical writings from the two communities produced by such writers as Hendrik Kraemer, F. L. Bakker, A. Hassan, A. Haanie and Hasbullah Bakry will be examined in detail. This thesis will inquire into the connection between Indonesian Muslims' treatment of Christians, ranging from polemic and suspicion to dialogue and accommodation, and political events which occurred and religio-political policies adopted particularly in the New Order under Soeharto. Furthermore, this thesis will also discuss the works of Mukti Ali and Nurcholish Madjid who in recent years have called for the more objective and positive dialogue leading to practical cooperation between Muslims and Christians in Indonesia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Federspiel, Howard M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gn093.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000222f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religion and politics -- Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Christianity and other religions -- Islam</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islam -- Indonesia -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islam -- Relations -- Christianity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n5432"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'inévitable, et, Ecrire l'inceste</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roger, Jean-Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The inevitable (creativity). Between the ages of seven and fifteen years, Paul had sexual intercourses with his father. He was introduced to this state of matter by pornographic photos. Described as being representations of love, and thinking as such, he accepts to imitate the depicted characters, at the request of his father. From the Laurentians to Montreal, Paul and his father "will make love" everywhere: Onboard the car, at home, in the washroom of a school... They "will make love" despite questions from a mother who seeks to know the truth and whom Paul considers too weak to help him put an end to a relationship that becomes more and more heavier. Finally, Paul is able to say "no" to his father at adolescence. Writing incest (critic). Studying incest literature in Les Enfants du sabbat by Anne Hebert. Taboo that needs to be shut of. But can not be because of the enchanting attraction of transgression; incest is shown and is said, it uncovers itself like a souvenir which repeats, here again, itself, hides behind lust, mysticism, whereas the voluptuous relationship is disembodied. This art of expression of disappearance which is found at each level in the text (tense used in the narration, characters, space) loans also to incest its defence mechanism and censorship as the symbolical exclusion, identification to the aggressor, and the will to succeed which is initialized by the confession of the victim denounciating the crime against human nature.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rivard, Yvon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h778.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n5432</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hébert, Anne. Enfants du sabbat</dc:subject><dc:subject>Incest in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r768j"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pontus de Tyard et les voies musicales, suivi de, Fugue à trois voix silencieuses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rocheville, Sarah Dominique</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This Master's thesis is comprised of two sections. The first one, entitled "Pontus de Tyard et les voies musicales", analyses the representation of music in two of sixteenth century French writer's " Dialogues philosophiques". Indeed, in his work, music is personified by a woman, Pasithee. Through an examination of three different aspects of the relationship between music and writing, we will attempt to grasp the mysterious link between the "Solitaire" and his muse, incarnation of music and of poetic inspiration. The second section, "Fugue a trois voix silencieuses ", a tale in which three female characters express their "voices", as defined by the rules of harmony established by Johann Sebastian Bach, is a literary transposition of the fugue form. The fugue is a musical form in which the contrapuntal structure includes several voices that blend with and reply to each other. Similarly to a canon, the parts seem to chase within a repeated motif. The literary transposition of the fugue form was fascinating to us. Our story follows the literary tradition which draws its strength from the encounter of music and writing.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rivard, Yvon</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Desrosiers-Bonin, Diane</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw74x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r768j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tyard, Pontus de, 1521-1605 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848s63w"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La figure du chansonnier : résurgence du sujet, et, Marie-la-putain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Robitaille, Hélène</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The stage is a place where symbolic space and real space, symbolic time and real time are superimposed. The critical part of our thought process entitled La figure du chansonnier: resurgence du sujet, tries to examine the way singers (Gilles Vigneault as it happens) create a symbolic place where the risk of fusion between reality and symbolism is much lesser than in other art forms: therefore it is possible not to dissociate the singer as shown to the public and the I that both mark out and cover his work. We think this is a very soft way to work the stage, that values the union between the subject and his message. On the other hand, theater through all its conventions more clearly defines the fusion between reality and symbolism and the risk involved with such an enterprise. Maybe the actor who is both symbolically and literally under the lights is in much greater danger than the singer of being irreconcilably and without an end exposed to that fusion of reality and symbolism. We think that art, which probably consists of creating a symbolic distancing, gets its greatest strength when its second will is in motion: achieving symbolism and then coming back to reality transformed (for the better). What interested us all through Marie-la-putain, the play which constitutes the creation part of our thesis is to investigate the grey zone where through the spotlight there is no going back to reality: we don't go back to reality, or if we do, it is with great difficulty. All through the play the heroine will on stage try to sacrifice a part of her she would not normally have. The creation part, through Marie, is in fact the opposite of the critical part: it examines the stage as a place that allows disappropriation and dissolution.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lane-Mercier, Gillian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hm327.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s63w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Vigneault, Gilles, 1928- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A44558g325"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modernist visual aesthetics and The double hook</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rempel, Geoff S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the significant role of expressionist and minimalist visual aesthetics in the construction (imagery, structuring, language) and subsequent interpretation of Sheila Watson's The Double Hook. While Sherrill Grace's Regression &amp; Apocalypse the groundwork for a literary expressionist reading of Watson's novel, this study elaborates the crucial links between literary and painterly expressionism in the novel and suggests Watson's critique of the expressionist aesthetic. A reading of the minimalist aesthetic, as both an extension of and an alternative to the expressionist reading of the text, emphasizes the relevance of noniconic painterly strategies to the novel and, by implication, of alternate forms of spectatorship that are demanded by the text. This study ultimately shows how Watson creatively synthesizes these extremes of modernist visual aesthetics and asks for the reader's imaginative and critical engagement with the modernist arts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Trehearne, Brian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365738q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558g325</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aesthetics in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Watson, Sheila, 1909- Double hook</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25xb70v"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Yoruba migrants : a study of rural-urban linkages and community development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Redd, David Allen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In looking at rural-urban linkages, this thesis addresses the extent to which social research may be generalized within development policy. Studies of Yoruba migrants in south-western Nigeria demonstrate that the ties between migrants and their hometowns can have a positive impact on local community development, an outcome which some researchers would suggest reflects a larger trend throughout the Third World. However, using information on the historical and cultural background of the Yoruba as well as a brief examination of Yoruba immigrants to North America, this study proposes that the utility of these ties in hometown development relates more to the past circumstances of Yoruba migration than the existence of 'structural regularities' in the migrant linkages of developing countries as a whole. These conclusions are then used to argue that one cannot generalize the results of migrant-hometown studies in policy formation without an understanding of the historic evolution of those ties.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bossen, Laurel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq27w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb70v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rural-urban migration -- Nigeria</dc:subject><dc:subject>Migration, Internal -- Nigeria</dc:subject><dc:subject>Yoruba (African people) -- Social life and customs</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x5992"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Homo Faber : Edmund White by Edmund White by Mark Pupo</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pupo, Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Although he has played a significant role in contemporary queer letters, the American novelist, essayist and biographer Edmund White has received little critical attention. This thesis examines White's autobiographical-fictive series of novels, focusing in particular on the account of a 1970s and early 1980s articulation of queer community in The Farewell Symphony. White's novels engage a post-structural critique of identity formation, literary affect and queer intimacies. The implications of this critique are addressed in this thesis both in an elaboration of a foucauldian genealogy of White and in an adaptation of the concerns of Roland Barthes's exploratory autobiography, Roland Barthes by Roland Barthes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cope, Karin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw68j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x5992</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>White, Edmund, 1940- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s1618336"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of exercise frequency on the stereotypic behaviours of individuals with developmental disabilities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Prupas, Andrea Robin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effects of exercise frequency on the stereotypic behaviours of four children with developmental disabilities were examined. Two exercise treatments were implemented, differentiated by frequency. The single frequency exercise treatment consisted of one daily 10 minute walk/jog session, while the multiple frequency treatment involved three 10 minute walk/jog sessions per day. Stereotypic behaviours were observed prior to the exercise sessions, as well as immediately following exercise. The results indicated similar reductions in stereotypic behaviours with the use of both treatments. In the single frequency condition, subjects demonstrated a mean reduction of 51.6%. These data confirm the results of past research, in which a decrease in stereotypic behaviours was observed following a single bout of exercise. However, the positive results are usually short-lived. The mean reduction of 58.9% following the multiple frequency condition can be viewed as more effective than the single frequency condition because the reduction was maintained throughout different periods of the day. Inter-rater reliability of stereotypic behaviours was 86%. The use of a multiple frequency exercise treatment informally revealed the interaction between exercise, environment, and stereotypic behaviours. Observation in the classroom suggested that as the structure of the classroom increased, stereotypic behaviours decreased. Thus, exercise combined with a structured classroom is likely to yield an optimal decrease in stereotypic behaviours.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, Greg</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dv28t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1618336</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Exercise for children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Developmentally disabled children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qk94j"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Claudel et le Japon : une autre écriture, suivi de, Minuscules</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pronovost, Annie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Japan and oriental art were great influences on some of Claudel's texts. A brief review of the origins of the Japanese short story and of the first encounters between Claudel and Japanese art precedes, in this essay, an analysis of Claudel's writing in this regard. Then, based on the poet's texts about Japan and/or reflecting his experience of Japan, we attempt to isolate major features of oriental writing: attention paid to emptiness and silence, different view on mimesis, purity and simplicity of style, settling of the subject, and eternity given by the creative act to fleeting moments. In conclusion, it seems that Japanese literature presents an atmosphere of self-restraint that sometimes appears as insensibility. The second part of this master's thesis is a collection of short stories which show, at various extents, the same characteristics of oriental writing as observed within Claudel's literary works.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rivard, Yvon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx56k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk94j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Claudel, Paul, 1868-1955 -- Sources</dc:subject><dc:subject>Claudel, Paul, 1868-1955 -- Knowledge -- Japan</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35tb57j"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gender, design and education : the politics of voice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poldma, Tiiu Vaikla</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study is to investigate a series of issues around the primary theme of value constructions and the ways that these influence the construction of interior spaces and impact on its occupants. The ways in which knowledge is disseminated currently in our society and the noticeable absence of the female voice in that knowledge construction is perpetuated in social relations. Spatial designs create an envelope that formalizes these relations and create symbols of' status, hierarchy and power at the expense of voices of collaboration and experience. Secondary issues about the absence of female voice in the underlying values that shape space are also studied, as they have evolved historically and as these exist in today's social and economic climate. Theoretical themes are woven around examples of situations in pedagogy and the practice of interior design and architecture.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wood, Elizabeth</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zd29v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb57j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sex differences (Psychology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Knowledge, Theory of</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interior decoration -- Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw3763914c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>spa</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Hispanic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pedro Calderón de la Barca : personajes sin madre</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pelenur, Diana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the image of the absent mother, and its implications, in a limited selection of plays by Pedro Calderon de la Barca. The characters studied are Segismundo and Rosaura from La vida es sueno , Semiramis from La hija del aire and Focas, Eraclio y Leonido from En la vida todo es verdad y todo mentira. The study was done from a psychoanalytic perspective, using as reference the theories of Erik Erikson, Jacques Lacan and John Bowlby. Erikson's ideas are based on Freud but with some changes, since he represents the ego's functions as well as a greater elaboration of classic psychoanalytical concepts. His main argument is that the ego's nature is determined not only by inner forces but by social and cultural influences. His theory encompasses a series of psychological development stages that occur throughout an individual's life cycle. Jacques Lacan obtained international fame through his personal interpretation of---and rupture with---Freud. The main emphasis of his work is in the importance of language as the mirror of the unconscious mind. John Bowlby is considered one of the most important psychiatrists of the twentieth century. His attachment theory is one of the principle theoretical developments in psychoanalysis in the latter part of this century. The purpose of this investigation was to give an explanation of the selected characters and their psychological development based on the proposed theories. The consequences of maternal deprivation and isolation manifest themselves in the development of the personality of the characters, mainly impeding the normal formation of the ego and super ego.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Perez-Magallon, Jesus</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579v460.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763914c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Abandoned children in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Calderón de la Barca, Pedro, 1600-1681 -- Characters -- Abandoned children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Absentee mothers in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj9602307p"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quelle corrélation affective peut-on obtenir entre l'émotion musicale et l'expression picturale (couleurs, traits, spatialisation) chez les jeunes enfants de quatre ou cinq ans?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Papageorges, Elisabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this research is to investigate the emotions of pre-school children. The research task was to elicit children's affective responses to music through the act of drawing. Three pre-school children with no formal musical training or formal schooling participated in the study. During three sessions of "play" they played musical instruments, listened to music selected for sharp contrasts in mood, and drew pictures. The children expressed their feelings about the musical selections by drawing on large sheets of paper with coloured pencils. Afterwards they discussed how they felt about the music and they described how their drawings related to the music. These discussions were tape recorded. The children produced twelve coloured drawings which, together with their explanations, were a source of insight into their emotional responses. The analysis of these data showed that the children perceived the emotional content of the music and were able to express it through the use of colour, form and space. The study concluded that this type of research is relevant to the education of pre-school children because children need to externalize their feelings; the method used here is a path to do so.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Russell, Joan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v060g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602307p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Musical perception</dc:subject><dc:subject>Child psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Emotions in children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429c43x"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An alternative possibility of identity development : a discussion of Rudolf Steiner and Waldorf education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Okumoto, Yoko</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis addresses the question of identity from the perspective of Rudolf Steiner and Waldorf Education attempting to make a connection between Steiner's theory of self development in relation to the spiritual world, and the postmodern concept of identity. Fundamentally, what matters in education for Steiner is how knowledge is introduced in such a way as to become organic, developing with the growth of the students, so that they can learn to think creatively and imaginatively. The holistic and artistic approach which Waldorf Education takes seems to succeed in developing students' identity in a way that the students can connect strongly and meaningfully with the community, society, and the universe. The thesis explores the philosophy and strategies adopted in Waldorf Education in its goal of developing the self and identity. In addition, the study examines the benefits which Waldorf Education can provide to contemporary public education and identifies the challenges it faces in the postmodern context.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wood, Elizabeth</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v503m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c43x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Steiner, Rudolf, 1861-1925</dc:subject><dc:subject>Waldorf method of education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amp48sf76h"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of al-Ghazālī's concept of the knowledge of God in his three later works : Iḥyā, al-Munqidh, and Iljām al-Awāmm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nurbaethy, Andi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis studies al-Ghazali's theory of knowledge, particularly his concept of knowledge of God in his three later works: "The book of Knowledge" of the Ih&amp;dotbelow;ya', al-Munqidh, and Iljam al-`Awamm. From his conception of knowledge of God the first book of the Ih&amp;dotbelow;ya ', to his criticism of various approaches to attaining the knowledge of God in the Munqidh, to his assertion of the best method for attaining the knowledge of God in the Iljam, the aim of the current study is to find out which faculty of man's perception, according to al-Ghazali, is the most appropriate for accessing Divinity. Since al-Ghazali's three works studied here---were composed in different periods, and since the Iljam was completed only a few days before his death, the objective of this study is then to see if there is any change, or development, in al-Ghazali's position regarding the issue of knowledge of God during the later period of his life.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ormsby, Eric L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd86w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sf76h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ghazzālī, 1058-1111 -- Contributions in theory of knowledge</dc:subject><dc:subject>God (Islam) -- Knowableness -- History of doctrines</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956j06r"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Muḥyī al-Dīn Ibn al-Arabī and Sharīah</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nurasiah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the views held by Muh&amp;dotbelow;yi al-Din Ibn al-`Arabi on shari`ah, based for the most part on his magnum opus, al-Futuh&amp;dotbelow;at al-Makkiyyah. It explores his attitude towards the shari`ah as practical religious law and his teachings concerning its sources and interpretation. Despite being misunderstood on account of his s&amp;dotbelow;ufi background and his well-known criticism of the fuqaha' Ibn al-`Arabi's teaching, in fact, advocated a strict and consistent orientation to the shari`ah. This thesis shows how, on the one hand, his criticism of the jurists was due to their inability to achieve the high standards that he set for interpreting the law, and how, on the other, his s&amp;dotbelow;ufi beliefs complemented, rather than weakened, the foundations of the shari`ah. It is clear that the principle underlying his approach to the shari`ah's application was his belief in its being a manifestation of God's mercy. He demonstrates this by pointing to the direct sources of God's law, accepting differences in legal opinion and seeking as much as possible the deeper spiritual and universal meaning of God's intentions in the law.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hallag, Wael B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx96q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956j06r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Islamic law -- Interpretation and construction -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ibn al-ʻArabī, 1165-1240</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>