<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m640v"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Developing drug and gene therapies for peroxisome biogenesis disorders of the Zellweger Spectrum</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Argyriou, Catherine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Zellweger spectrum disorder (ZSD) usually results from biallelic mutations in PEX genes required for peroxisome biogenesis. PEX1-G843D is a common hypomorphic allele associated with milder disease. We previously showed that fibroblasts from patients with a PEX1-G843D allele recovered peroxisome functions when cultured with the nonspecific chaperone betaine and flavonoid acacetin diacetate. To identify more effective flavonoids for preclinical trials, we compared 54 flavonoids using our cell-based peroxisomal assays. Diosmetin showed the most promising combination of potency and efficacy; co-treatments of diosmetin and betaine showed the most robust additive effects. This was confirmed by 5 independent assays in primary PEX1-G843D patient cells. Neither agent was active in PEX1 null cells. I propose that diosmetin acts as a pharmacological chaperone to improve stability, conformation, and function of PEX1/PEX6 exportomer complexes. All individuals with a PEX1-G843D allele develop a retinopathy that progresses to blindness. To investigate pathophysiology and identify endpoints for experimental trials, I used the knock-in mouse model for the equivalent human mutation, PEX1-G844D. I characterized the progression of retinopathy and found reduced cone cell function and number early in life with more gradual deterioration of rod cell function. Electron microscopy at later stage retinopathy showed disorganization of photoreceptor inner segments and enlarged mitochondria. As retino-cortical function was relatively well-preserved, I propose that the vision defect in the PEX1-G844D mouse is primarily at the retinal level. In contrast to the human PEX1-G843D which behaves as a misfolded, degraded protein in fibroblasts, I found equivalent amounts of murine PEX1-G844D and wild-type PEX1 proteins in retina and other tissues. I propose that murine PEX1-G844D is stable but subfunctional. To determine if we could slow visual loss in PEX1-mediated ZSD, I performed a proof-of-concept trial for PEX1 retinal gene augmentation therapy using the PEX1-G844D mouse. Subretinal injections of AAV-PEX1 at both early and later disease stages resulted in a non-statistically significant trend of improved visual acuity after 2 months, and a twofold improvement in both rod- and cone-mediated retinal electrophysiological response after 5-6 months. Neither injection, viral capsid exposure nor the transgenic protein negatively altered retinal histology or visual response. These results support the potential of retinal gene augmentation to improve vision in patients with ZSD at both earlier and later stages of disease.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le Trouble de la biogénèse des peroxysomes du spectre de Zellweger (ZSD) est généralement causé par des mutations bialléliques dans les gènes PEX, qui sont requis pour la biogénèse des peroxysomes. L'allèle hypomorphe PEX1-G843D est le plus fréquent et est associé à une présentation plus légère de la maladie. Nous avons démontré précédemment que les fibroblastes provenant de patients avec un allèle PEX1-G843D récupèrent leurs fonctions peroxysomales lorsque le chaperon non-spécifique bétaïne et le flavonoïde diacétate d'acacétine sont ajoutés à la culture. Dans le but d'identifier les flavoinoïdes les plus efficaces pour des essais pré-cliniques, nous avons comparé 54 flavonoïdes en utilisant des tests cellulaires de la fonction peroxysomale. La combinaison de puissance et d'efficacité la plus prometteuse a été attribuée à la diosmétine; le co-traitement avec la diosmétine et le bétaïne a eu l'effet additif le plus robuste. Cela a été confirmé par 5 tests indépendants dans les cellules primaires PEX1-G843D provenant de patients. Aucun de ces agents n'a été actif dans les cellules nulles pour PEX1. Je propose que la diosmétine agisse comme un chaperon pharmacologique pour améliorer la stabilité, la conformation et la fonction des complexes d'exportation PEX1/PEX6.Toutes les personnes atteintes de ZSD qui ont un allèle PEX1-G843D développent une rétinopathie qui progresse jusqu'à la cécité. J'ai utilisé un modèle de souris knock-in avec la mutation PEX1-G844D, équivalente à la mutation chez les humains, dans le but d'investiguer sur la physiopathologie et d'identifier des paramètres cliniques à mesurer pour les essais expérimentaux. J'ai caractérisé la progression de la rétinopathie et démontré une diminution de la fonction et du nombre de cônes tôt dans la vie des souris, avec une détérioration plus graduelle de la fonction des bâtonnets. L'imagerie à microscope électronique à un stade plus avancé de la rétinopathie a démontré une désorganisation des segments intérieurs des photorécepteurs et des mitochondries élargies.  Puisque la fonction rétino-corticale était relativement bien préservée, je propose que la défectuosité de la vision chez les souris PEX1-G844D se situe d'abord au niveau de la rétine. Alors que la protéine PEX1-G843D humaine se comporte comme une protéine mal repliée qui est dégradée dans les fibroblastes, j'ai découvert qu'il y a des quantités similaires de protéines Pex1-G844D et de Pex1de type sauvage dans la rétine et d'autres tissus chez la souris. Je propose donc que le PEX1-G844D chez la souris est stable, mais moins fonctionnelle. Pour déterminer si on peut ralentir la perte de vision chez les personnes atteintes de ZSD dû à un défaut du gène PEX1, j'ai réalisé un essai de preuve de concept pour une thérapie d'augmentation du gène PEX1 dans la rétine des souris PEX1-G844D. Des injections sous-rétiniennes de l'AAV-PEX1 aux stades précoces et avancés de la maladie ont entraîné tendance vers une amélioration de l'acuité visuelle, sans être statistiquement significatives. De plus, cela a permis de doubler les réponses électrophysiologiques de la rétine après 5-6 mois. Ni l'injection, ni l'exposition à la capside virale ou la protéine transgénique n'a négativement altéré l'histologie de la rétine ou la réponse visuelle. Ces résultats démontrent le potentiel d'une augmentation génique rétinienne pour améliorer la vision chez les patients atteints de ZSD, aux stades précoce et avancé de la maladie. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nancy Braverman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xh13f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m640v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860924v"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Obtaining the biomechanical behavior of ascending aortic aneurysm by using novel speckle tracking echocardiography</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alreshidan, Mohammed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction: Ex vivo measurement of ascending aortic biomechanical properties may help in the process of estimating the risk for rupture or dissection of dilated ascending aortas.  A validated in vivo method that can predict aortic biomechanics does not exist. Speckle tracking transesophageal echocardiography (TEE) has been used to measure ventricular stiffness; we sought to determine if speckle-tracking echocardiography could be adopted to estimate aortic stiffness in vivo and compare these findings to those obtained by ex vivo tissue measurements.Methods: 17 patients undergoing ascending aortic resection were recruited to be part of the study with the mean aortic diameter of 56.16 ± 15 mm. Intra-operative speckle tracking echocardiographic analysis was used to calculate aortic stiffness index using the following equation:β2=   ln⁡〖(SBP⁄(DBP))〗⁄AoS (β2 stiffness index; SBP: Systolic BP; DBP: Diastolic BP,    AoS: circumferential strain). Ex vivo stiffness was obtained by mechanical tissue testing according to previously described methods. The aortic ring at the pulmonary trunk was divided into four equal quadrantsResults: the mean aortic diameter was. The in vivo stiffness index for the inner curvature, anterior wall, outer curvature and posterior wall were 0.0544 ± 0.0490, 0.0295± 0.0199, 0.0411± 0.0328 and 0.0502± 0.0320 respectively. The mean ex vivo 25% apparent stiffness for inner curvature, anterior wall, outer curvature and posterior wall were 0.0616 ±0.0758 MPa, 0.0352± 0.00992 MPa, 0.0405± 0.0199 MPa and 0.0327± 0.0106 MPa respectively. The patient matched ex vivo 25% apparent stiffness and in vivo stiffness index were not significantly different (p=0.8617, two way ANOVA with repeated measures). Conclusion: The use of speckle tracking TEE appears to be a promising technique to estimate ex vivo mechanical properties of the ascending aortic tissue.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introduction: Déterminer les propriétés biomécaniques ex vivo de l'aorte ascendante pourrait aider à obtenir de meilleures estimations de risques de ruptures et dissections du tissu dans le cas de dilatations. Aucune méthode permettant la prédiction du comportement mécanique du tissu aortique in vivo n'a encore été validée.L'échographie transoesophagienne de suivi des marqueurs acoustique est utilisée pour mesurer la rigidité du ventricule ; dans le cadre de cette étude, nous avons cherché à déterminer si une telle technique pouvait également être utilisée dans l'estimation de la rigidité de l'aorte in vivo en comparant les résultats mesurés à des données obtenues au préalable en ex vivo.Méthodes: 17 patients ayant subi une ablation de l'aorte ascendante avec un diamètre moyen de  56.16 ± 15 mm ont fait parti de l'étude. L'analyse de l'échographie transoesophagienne preopératoire de suivi des marqueurs acoustique a permis le calcul de la rigidité aortique en utilisant l'équation suivante β2=   ln⁡〖(SBP⁄(DBP))〗⁄AoS, (β2 rigidité; SBP: Pression systolique; DBP: Pression diastolique,    AoS: Déformations circonférentielles). La rigidité du tissu a été obtenue ex vivo par des tests mécaniques en suivant des méthodes décrites dans de précédentes études.  Enfin, l'anneau aortique au tronc pulmonaire fut divisé en quatre quadrants de tailles égales.Résultats: Les rigidités in vivo de la courbure intérieure, paroi antérieure, courbure extérieure et paroi postérieure étaient de 0.0544 ± 0.0490, 0.0295± 0.0199, 0.0411± 0.0328 et 0.0502± 0.0320. Tandis que les moyennes ex vivo de la rigidité mesurée à 25% pour la courbure intérieure, paroi antérieure, courbure extérieure et paroi postérieure étaient de 0.0616 ±0.0758 MPa, 0.0352± 0.00992 MPa, 0.0405± 0.0199 MPa et 0.0327± 0.0106 MPa. Des résultats similaires ont été trouvés chez les patients entre les rigidités ex vivo (mesurées à 25%) et in vivo avec une différence non significative (p=0.8617, analyse ANOVA double avec des mesures répétées).Conclusion: L'utilisation de l'échographie transoesophagienne de suivi des marqueurs acoustique semble donc être une technique prometteuse permettant l'estimation de propriétés mécaniques du tissu de l'aorte ascendante in vivo.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kevin J. Lachapelle</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Richard L. Leask</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pg25g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860924v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429c68s"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Liquid-phase epitaxy growth of SiGe graded buffers on Si (001)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Jun</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse porte sur la qualité des couches tampons graduelles de SiGe ou des couches déposées sur Si (001) au moyen d'un système d'épitaxie en phase liquide conçu sur mesure. Premièrement, des couches tampons graduelles de SiGe à faible composition en Ge ont été déposées sur Si (001) à l'aide d'une solution de même composition initiale (~2% en Ge). La croissance débute à 950 °C et se termine à différentes températures finales: 940 °C, 850 °C, 750 °C, 650 °C, 550 °C ou 450 °C. La croissance bidimensionnelle de la couche est maintenue jusqu'à une température minimale de 650 °C. Une diminution supplémentaire de la température engendre une croissance de morphologie plus tridimensionnelle. Une analyse détaillée des états de contraintes de la couche tampon graduelle révèle que la couche initiale à l'interface couche tampon/substrat est à l'origine totalement contrainte et qu'elle se relaxe complètement quand la croissance se prolonge. Tout au long de la croissance et de la diminution continuelle de la température, les dernières portions de la couche comportent à la fois plus de Ge et de contraintes. Il s'agit de la première description de la morphologie de croissance et de l'évolution des états de contraintes dans les couches tampons graduelles de SiGe durant une croissance LPE. En plus de l'étude des croissances longues de SiGe à partir d'une solution à 2% de Ge, les propriétés de couches issues de croissances courtes (950-940 °C) pour des solutions de compositions différentes (2%, 4% ou 5% de Ge) sont présentées. La croissance initiale présente une transition du motif caractéristique en hachures croisées à une morphologie plus tridimensionnelle provoquée par la proportion croissante de Ge dans la solution. Nous avons établi que la quantité maximale de Ge qui permet une croissance bidimensionnelle est de 3.1%. La couche initiale est d'abord totalement contrainte puis présente un état de relaxation partielle de 30% et devient de nouveau totalement contrainte quand la composition augmente de 1.4% à 3.1% en Ge. C'est la première description de l'évolution de la qualité de couches LPE initiales de composition croissante en Ge.Les propriétés des couches tampons graduelles de SiGe déposés à l'aide de solution de différentes composition (2%, 4% or 5% de Ge) à 950-750 °C sont également étudiées. Le film initial de chaque couche tampon graduelle, proche de l'interface couche tampon/substrat, est complètement relaxé à haute température mais présente une contrainte en tension après refroidissement à température ambiante. Plus loin de l'interface, la couche tampon graduelle présente des contraintes de compression et se retrouve de plus en plus contrainte. De plus, un procédé de gravure chimique des dislocations a été développé afin d'évaluer la densité de dislocations traversantes des couches de SiGe et des couches tampons graduelles obtenues par LPE. La TDD des couches tampons graduelles (i.e. des couches épaisses) issues de solutions à 4% et 5% de Ge, est de ~106 cm-2, soit un ordre de grandeur inférieur à leur propre couche initiale (la couche déposée pendant le premier intervalle de ~10 °C). La TDD des couches tampons graduelles déposés à l'aide d'une solution de Ge à 2% est similaire à la TDD de leur couche initiale qui est de ~106 cm-2. C'est la première démonstration d'une réduction de la TDD au moyen d'une couche tampon graduelle de SiGe obtenue par LPE.Enfin, des couches de SiGe ont été déposées, à partir de solutions de différentes compositions, sur des substrats de Si0.88Ge0.12/Si (001) obtenus par dépôt chimique en phase vapeur à des températures de 950-940 °C. Les dislocations traversantes présentes sur ces substrats CVD provoque la nucléation de dislocations de désaccord de mailles plus efficacement qu'une gaufre de Si, ce qui engendre une relaxation de la couche initiale plus importante ( 86%) que dans la couche déposée sur une gaufre de Si (complètement contrainte ou relaxée à ~30%).</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis discusses the quality of SiGe graded buffers or films grown on Si (001) by a custom-designed, liquid-phase epitaxy (LPE) system. First, Low-Ge-content SiGe graded buffers were grown on Si (001) with the same initial solution composition (~2%Ge). The growth started at 950 C but ended at different final temperatures 940 C, 850 C, 750 C, 650 C, 550 C, and 450 C. The growth maintains two-dimensional film until the temperature drops to 650 C. Further temperature decreasing results in film morphologies with more three-dimensional growth. A detailed analysis of the strain states of the graded buffer reveal that the initial film at the buffer/substrate interface is fully strained initially and during a longer growth process becomes fully relaxed. As the growth continues with further temperature reductions, the latter parts of the film have both more Ge content as well as strain. This is the first report about the growth morphology and strain states evolution of SiGe graded buffers during the LPE growth process.In addition to investigating long growths of SiGe from a 2%Ge solution, the properties of films from short growths (950-940 C) with different solution compositions (2%Ge, 4%Ge, 5Ge%) are presented. The initial growth transitions from the characteristic crosshatch morphology into a more three-dimensional morphology with increasing Ge content in the solution. We found that the highest Ge film that maintains two-dimensional film growth is 3.1%Ge. The initial film changes from fully strained to 30% partially relaxed and back to fully strained as the composition increases from 1.4%Ge to 3.1%Ge. This is the first report about tracking the quality evolution of initial LPE films with increasing Ge content.The properties of SiGe graded buffers grown with different solution compositions (2%Ge, 4%Ge, 5%Ge) from 950-750 C are studied as well. The initial film of each graded buffer close to the buffer/substrate is fully relaxed at high temperature but experiences tensile strain after cooled to room temperature. The film of the graded buffer further from the interface experiences compressive strain and becomes more strained. Also, an etch pit density process was developed to study the threading dislocation density (TDD) of LPE SiGe films and graded buffers. The TDD of graded buffers (i.e. thicker films) grown with 4%Ge- and 5%Ge-content-solution is ~106 cm-2, one order of magnitude lower than their own initial films (the film grown in the first ~10 C growth interval) while the TDD of the graded buffers grown with 2%Ge-content-solution is similar to its low initial film TDD, ~106 cm-2. This is for the first time to present the TDD reductions by LPE SiGe graded buffers.Finally, SiGe films were grown on CVD-grown Si0.88Ge0.12/Si (001) substrates with different composition solutions from 950-940 C. The existing threading dislocations on CVD substrates make the misfit dislocation nucleation easier than on bare Si, which helps the initial film relax more (86%) than those on bare Si (fully strained or ~30% relaxed).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nathaniel Quitoriano</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rz81z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c68s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mining and Materials</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r5418"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Emergent tensions in video-data editing to support teacher reflection: a reflective look at a research-practice partnership</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baradaran Rahmani, Niloufar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To cut or not to cut? This dilemma points to an important aspect of collaborative research (Coburn &amp; Penuel, 2016) that relies upon video captures from classroom activities to provide the impetus for teacher reflection on practice. Our research team partnered with consultants and teachers in youth sector mathematics to form a community of practice (CoP) (Wenger, 1998).  This self-study reflects on one of many instrument producing activities.  Specifically, the process of turning raw footage into edited clips.  It describes the tensions that arise between researchers and teachers by adopting the framework of cultural-historical activity theory (Engeström, 1987).  The data sources consist of videos from classrooms and meetings, transcripts, and field notes.  Outcomes shed light on the tripartite of the three communities, projecting their object on different aspects of the video, "best practices" or "improvable practices".  This reflective paper contributes to opening up a methodological discussion about video research in educational settings.  Keywords: Video research, video-based collective reflection, video pedagogy</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Couper ou ne pas couper?  Ce dilemme soulève une question pertinente pour la recherche collaborative (Coburn et Penuel, 2016) utilisant la captation vidéo d'activités en classe comme appui à la réflexion sur les pratiques.  Notre équipe effectue une recherche en partenariat avec des praticiens anglophones de mathématique du primaire et du secondaire formant une communauté d'apprentissage professionnelle (Wenger, 1998).  Pour cette auto-étude ("self-study"), je pose un regard précis sur la captation vidéo, en particulier en ce qui concerne le choix des données à extraire.  J'adopte la théorie de l'activité (Engeström, 1987) comme cadre pour analyser les tensions qui émergent entre chercheurs et praticiens dans le travail de sélection et de découpage des vidéos.  J'effectue une analyse réflexive sur notre pratique de chercheurs afin de documenter le processus par lequel les captations vidéo sont découpées en extraits à diverses fins.  La majorité des sources de données sont des transcriptions d'enregistrements vidéo ainsi que des notes de terrain.  Les résultats soulignent la tripartite des communautés de la recherche, conseiller pédagogique, et les enseignants, qui tendent à mettre l'accent sur différents aspects des vidéos, entre pratiques «exemplaires» et pratiques «perfectibles».  Ce regard réflexif ouvre la porte sur une discussion méthodologique sur la vidéo en recherche collaborative en milieu scolaire.Mots clés: Recherche avec vidéo, réflexion par l'entremise vidéo</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alain Breuleux</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451k90k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r5418</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab5644t89x"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Family Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pharmacology management of major neurocognitive disorders in the United Kingdom: a population-based drug utilization study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Andersen, Kathleen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background: Major neurocognitive disorders (MNCD) affect 1 in 11 persons over age 65. Cholinesterase inhibitors (ChEIs, i.e. donepezil, galantamine, and rivastigmine) and memantine are the only approved drugs for the management of MNCD in both the United Kingdom (UK) and Canada. The objective of this thesis was to describe the sex, age, and clinical characteristics associated with MNCD drug utilization, and to examine how prescription patterns vary with these characteristics.Methods: I assembled a retrospective, population-based inception cohort of all patients aged 65+ years with a new diagnosis of MNCD between 1997 and 2017 in the Clinical Practice Research Datalink, a primary care database with 15 million patient records from over 700 primary care practices in the UK. Patients were followed from MNCD diagnosis until the date of departure from the general practitioner practice, death, or March 2017. MNCD drug utilization patterns included time from date of diagnosis to medication initiation, switches, adherence and persistence, which were described overall, by sex, age group (65-74, 75-84, 85-94, 95+) and MNCD subtype (Alzheimer's, vascular, mixed, other [dementia with Lewy bodies, frontotemporal and Parkinson's] and non-specific). Associations between patient characteristics and drug initiation, switches, discontinuation and non-adherence were compared using Cox proportional hazards regression models, presented as hazard ratios (HR) with 95% confidence intervals (CI), adjusted for relevant demographic and clinical covariates.Results: A total of 91,025 patients with MNCD were identified, among whom 25,071 (28%) received at least 1 MNCD drug prescription during follow-up and 13% of initiators switched to a second MNCD drug. Persistence was low (82% after the first trial, 56% after 6 months, 19% after 2 years), and adherence was modest among those who were persistent (53% at 2 years). Compared to male patients, female patients were more likely to initiate treatment with donepezil (adjusted HR=1.10, 95% CI 1.07-1.14), less likely to discontinue treatment with donepezil (adjusted HR=0.96, 95% CI 0.93-0.99) and less likely to become non-adherent (adjusted HR=0.91, 95% CI 0.87-0.96) to donepezil treatment. As compared to patients diagnosed at age 65-74, those diagnosed over age 95 were more frequently prescribed memantine (28%, versus 9%), less likely to switch medications (adjusted HR=0.25, 95% CI 0.23-0.28), were less persistent and had a higher rate of non-adherence. There were observed differences among the 5 dementia subtypes with respect to MNCD treatment initiation, switches and persistence but not adherence.  Conclusion: In this population-based inception cohort, the largest MNCD primary care drug utilization study conducted to date, MNCD drug utilization varied by sex, age and MNCD subtype. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Contexte : Chez les personnes de 65 ans et plus, les troubles neurocognitifs majeurs (TNM) touchent 1 sujet sur 11. Les inhibiteurs de la cholinestérase (c.-à-d. donépézil, galantamine et rivastigmine) et la mémantine sont les seuls médicaments approuvés pour la prise en charge des TNM au Royaume-Uni (R.-U.) et au Canada. Cette thèse vise à décrire le genre, l'âge et les caractéristiques cliniques associés à l'emploi des médicaments pour les TNM, ainsi qu'à examiner comment les schémas de prescription varient en fonction de ces caractéristiques.Méthodes : À partir de la Clinical Practice Research Datalink, une base de données sur les soins primaires qui comporte 15 millions de dossiers de patients provenant de plus de 700 pratiques de soins primaires du R.-U., j'ai réuni une cohorte rétrospective populationnelle formée de tous les patients âgés de 65 ans et plus, ayant reçu un nouveau diagnostic de TNM entre 1997 et 2017 et qui étaient suivis depuis le diagnostic de leur maladie. Les patients ont été suivis entre le moment de leur diagnostic de TNM et l'arrêt du suivi par leur omnipraticien, leur décès ou le mois de mars 2017. Les schémas d'utilisation des médicaments pour les TNM incluaient : délai entre la date du diagnostic et l'instauration du traitement médicamenteux, passages à d'autres médicaments, observance et persistance. Ces schémas ont été décrits pour l'ensemble de la population et selon le genre, le groupe d'âge (65 à 74 ans, 75 à 84 ans, 85 à 94 ans, 95 ans et +) et le sous-type de TNM (maladie d'Alzheimer, vasculaire, mixte, autre [démence à corps de Lewy, frontotemporal et maladie de Parkinson] et non spécifique). Les associations entre les caractéristiques des patients et l'instauration du traitement médicamenteux, les passages à d'autres médicaments, l'arrêt du traitement et la non-observance ont été comparées au moyen de modèles de régression des risques proportionnels de Cox et présentées sous forme de rapport des risques instantanés (RRI) avec intervalles de confiance (IC) à 95 %, ajustées en fonction des covariables démographiques et cliniques pertinentes.Résultats : Au total, 91 025 patients atteints de TMN ont été repérés; 25 071 (28 %) d'entre eux avaient reçu au moins 1 ordonnance de médicament pour les TNM pendant le suivi, et 13 % étaient passés à un second médicament pour les TNM. La persistance était faible (82 % après le premier essai, 56 % après 6 mois et 19 % après 2 ans), et l'observance était élevée chez les patients affichant une persistance élevée (77 % à 2 ans). Comparativement aux hommes, les femmes étaient davantage susceptibles de recevoir un traitement avec le donépézil (RRI ajusté : 1,11; IC à 95 % : 1,07 à 1,14), moins susceptibles d'arrêter le traitement avec le donépézil (RRI ajusté : 0,96; IC à 95 % : 0,93 à 0,99) et moins susceptibles d'être non observantes (RRI ajusté : 0.91, IC à 95 % : 0,87 à 0,96) au traitement avec le donépézil. Comparativement aux patients diagnostiqués entre 65 et 74 ans, les patients diagnostiqués après 95 ans avaient reçu plus fréquemment de la mémantine (28 % p/r à 9 %), étaient moins susceptibles de passer à un autre médicament (RRI ajusté : 0,25; IC à 95 % : 0,23 à 0,28), affichaient moins de persistance et présentaient un taux plus élevé de non-observance. Des différences ont été observées entre les 5 sous-types de démence quant à la prescription de médicaments pour les TNM, aux passages à d'autres médicaments et à la persistance, mais pas en ce qui a trait à l'observance.  Conclusion : Dans cette cohorte populationnelle de patients suivis depuis le début de leur maladie, qui constitue la plus vaste étude sur l'usage de médicaments pour les TNM en soins primaires menée à ce jour, l'utilisation de ces médicaments variait en fonction du genre et de l'âge des patients, et du sous-type de TNM.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kristian Filion</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Machelle Wilchesky</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10ws72k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t89x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Family Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqb98mh824"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sacrificial goals: The antecedents and consequences of sacrificing basic psychological needs in the pursuit of career goals</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>St-Jacques, André</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Pursuing long-term career goals often leads people to make sacrifices that can have enduring affective and self-regulatory costs. We investigated whether sacrificing basic psychological needs to reach a career goal was detrimental beyond the sacrifice of physical needs (e.g., sleep) or core activities (e.g., time with friends) using a year-long, 6-wave, prospective study of 310 young adults actively pursuing a career goal. Career goal motivation, aspirations and career demandingness were assessed at the start of a school year, while three forms of sacrifice were assessed at midyear. Psychological distress and self-regulation were assessed at both the beginning and end of the school year. Results showed that psychological need sacrifice was associated with increased psychological distress and decreased career- and personal goal progress over the year. Moreover, results suggested that psychological need sacrifice stemmed from career demandingness, introjected motivation and extrinsic aspirations. Implications of these findings for basic psychological needs theory (BPNT) and long-term goal pursuit are discussed.Keywords: Basic psychological needs, self-determination theory, sacrifices, goal progress, distress</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La poursuite d'objectifs de carrière à long terme conduit souvent les gens à faire des sacrifices qui peuvent avoir des coûts affectifs et d'autorégulation persistants. Nous avons examiné si le fait de sacrifier les besoins psychologiques de base pour atteindre un objectif de carrière était nuisible au-delà du sacrifice des besoins physiques (par ex. le sommeil) ou le sacrifice d'activités de base (par ex. temps avec ses amis). 310 jeunes adultes poursuivant un objectif de carrière ont participé à cette étude. En début d'année, ces participants ont complété six questionnaires à la longueur d'une année scolaire et ont été évalués sur leur motivation pour cet objectif de carrière, leurs aspirations de vie et sur le niveau d'exigence de la carrière choisie. Les trois formes de sacrifice ont été évaluées en milieu d'année, tandis que la détresse psychologique et l'autorégulation ont été évaluées au début et à la fin de l'année scolaire. Les résultats démontrent que le sacrifice de besoins psychologiques était associé à une détresse psychologique accrue et à une diminution de progrès sur les objectifs de carrière et personnels au cours de l'année. De plus, les résultats suggèrent que le sacrifice des besoins psychologiques découle du niveau d'exigence de carrière, de la motivation introjectée et des aspirations extrinsèques. Les implications de ces résultats pour la théorie des besoins psychologiques de base et pour la poursuite des objectifs à long terme seront discutées.Mots clés: Besoins psychologiques de base, théorie de l'autodétermination, sacrifices, progression vers un objectif, détresse</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Richard Koestner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k040k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mh824</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bk593"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of beta blockers on survival in head and neck cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Letian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>RÉSUMÉLes bêta-bloquants sont une classe de médicaments principalement utilisés pour la prise en charge des maladies cardiovasculaires et de l'hypertension. En 2008, il a été découvert que ces médicaments sont efficaces contre l'hémangiome infantile, une forme de tumeur vasculaire, et ils sont depuis devenus la première ligne de traitement de cette maladie. En conséquence, les chercheurs ont commencé à examiner le lien potentiel entre l'utilisation des bêta-bloquants et l'amélioration du risque et du pronostic de cancer. Cependant, aucune étude n'a examiné l'association entre l'utilisation de bêta-bloquants et la survie pour le cancer de la tête et du cou (CTC).Objectif : estimer dans quelle mesure l'utilisation à long terme des bêta-bloquants est associée à une meilleure survie globale (SG) dans un échantillon de patients canadiens atteints de CTC.Méthodes : Un total de 303 patients atteints de CTC, une sous-cohorte du site canadien de l'étude HeNCe Life, ont été recrutés à l'Hôpital Notre-Dame de Montréal, QC, Canada. Nous avons recueilli des informations de référence et de suivi sur un éventail d'expositions (par exemple, utilisation de bêta-bloquants, comorbidités) à partir des dossiers médicaux en utilisant la base de données OACIS, qui a ensuite été fusionnée avec la base de données HeNCe Life. L'information sur la survie a été extraite du Registre de l'état civil du gouvernement du Québec. L'analyse des données comprenait des statistiques descriptives, la régression proportionnelle de Cox et l'analyse de survie de Kaplan-Meier.Résultats : Le profil de survie des utilisateurs de bêta-bloquants (temps de survie moyen : 74,2 mois, IC 95%: 60,3-88,3) ne semblait pas significativement différent de celui des non-utilisateurs (temps de survie moyen : 89,9 mois, IC 95 %: 84,5-95,1) dans l'analyse de survie de Kaplan-Meier. Nous n'avons pas observé d'association significative entre l'utilisation de bêta-bloquants à long terme et des améliorations de la SG pour le CTC tant dans le modèle brut (HR: 1,46, IC 95%: 0,75-2,85) que dans le modèle ajusté de risques proportionnels de Cox (HR: 0,82, IC 95 %: 0,38-1,77).Conclusion : L'utilisation de bêta-bloquants à long terme ne semble pas être associée à une amélioration de la survie pour le CTC. D'autres études sont nécessaires pour examiner le rôle potentiel de la sélectivité des bêta-bloquants dans le pronostic du CTC.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>ABSTRACTBeta-blockers are a class of drugs mainly used for the management of cardiovascular disease (CVD) and hypertension. In 2008, these drugs were discovered to be effective against infantile hemangioma, a form of vascular tumour, and have since become the first line therapy for this condition. As a result, researchers began to examine the potential link between beta-blocker use and improved cancer risk and prognosis. However, no study has examined the association between beta-blocker use and survival in head and neck cancer (HNC).  Objective: to estimate the extent to which the long-term use of beta-blockers is associated with better overall survival (OS) in a sample of Canadian HNC patients.Methods: A total of 303 HNC patients, a sub-cohort of the HeNCe Life study Canadian site, were recruited from Hôpital Notre-Dame in Montreal, QC, Canada. We retrieved baseline and follow-up information on an array of exposures (e.g., beta-blocker use, comorbidities) from medical records using the OACIS database, which was subsequently merged with the HeNCe Life database. Survival information was retrieved from the Register of Civil Status of the Government of Quebec. Data analysis included descriptive statistics, cox proportional regression and Kaplan-Meier survival analysis.  Results: The survival profile of the beta-blocker users (mean survival time: 74.2 months, 95% CI: 60.3-88.3) did not appear to be significantly different from that of the non-users (mean survival time: 89.9 months, 95% CI: 84.5-95.1) in Kaplan-Meier survival analysis. We did not observe any significant association between long-term beta-blocker use and improvements in HNC OS in both the crude (HR: 1.46, 95% CI: 0.75-2.85) and the adjusted Cox proportional hazards model (HR: 0.82, 95% CI: 0.38-1.77). Conclusion: Long term beta-blocker use did not appear to be associated with improved survival in HNC. More studies are required to examine the potential role of beta-blocker selectivity in affecting HNC prognosis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Faleh Tamimi Marino</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Belinda Farias Nicolau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r3350.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bk593</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ast74cs84d"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The solubility, speciation, and transport of the high field strength elements (HFSE) niobium, tantalum, and uranium</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Timofeev, Alexander</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les éléments à champ électrostatique élevé (HFSE, high field strength elements) sont considérés comme étant immobiles dans de nombreux environnements géochimiques, dans lesquels les fluides hydrothermaux de température élevée jouent un rôle important dans leur transport. Parmi les métaux considérés dans cette thèse, le niobium est souvent utilisé comme élément de référence, par rapport auquel la mobilité des autres éléments est comparée; le tantale est également considéré comme étant difficile à transporter; et l'uranium, connu pour être particulièrement mobile dans les environnements oxydants, est considéré comme étant immobile dans les systèmes réduits. À l'aide d'observations de terrain et d'études expérimentales, cette thèse évalue la mobilité réelle de ces métaux et détermine leur solubilité et leur spéciation. Le comportement du niobium et du tantale dans un environnement hydrothermal a été décrit pour la première fois dans le gisement de métaux rares de Nechalacho, situé dans les Territoires du Nord-Ouest du Canada. L'analyse géochimique des roches, la pétrographie et les analyses à la microsonde électronique ont été utilisées pour distinguer les comportements magmatiques et hydrothermaux de ces métaux. Le niobium et le tantale sont portés notamment par le zircon, la colombite-(Fe), la fergusonite-(Y), l'uranopyrochlore et la samarskite-(Y). Un modèle génétique impliquant la cristallisation magmatique de ces minéraux, suivie d'un épisode hydrothermal, a été proposé pour expliquer leur présence. La remobilisation locale de ces deux métaux a été observée, mais est limitée à une échelle inférieure au mètre. D'autres travaux ont été effectués de façon expérimentale afin de déterminer la solubilité et la spéciation du niobium dans des solutions contenant du fluor, à 150, 200 et 250 °C. Ces expériences, réalisées dans des autoclaves en titane, ont permis d'identifier la présence des espèces Nb(OH)4+ et NbF2(OH)3°. La présence de cette dernière espèce d'hydroxyl-fluorure augmente de plusieurs ordres de grandeur la solubilité du niobium dans les solutions acides et riches en fluorure. Des expériences similaires ont été réalisées pour le tantale, à des températures de 100-250°C. À faible concentration en HF, Ta(OH)5° prédomine, alors qu'à une forte concentration en HF, TaF5 prédomine à des températures moindres que 150 °C, tandis que de façon plus générale, c'est l'espèce TaF3(OH)3- qui domine. Ces deux dernières espèces entraînent une augmentation rapide de la solubilité du tantale. Cependant, dans le même fluide, le tantale est presque toujours moins soluble que le niobium. La modélisation géochimique de l'altération hydrothermale impliquant des saumures acides a démontré que les rapports Nb/Ta peuvent diminuer dans les cristaux altérés hydrothermalement et que l'élimination du HF du fluide ou l'augmentation du pH, entraînent la déposition du niobium et du tantale. Ces données expérimentales ainsi que les observations propres au gisement de Nechalacho démontrent que la mobilisation hydrothermale du niobium et du tantale est en effet possible. Alors que le niobium et le tantale se trouvent principalement dans l'état de valence 5+, les conditions redox jouent un rôle majeur dans le comportement géochimique de l'uranium. La solubilité et la spéciation de l'uranium ont été évaluées dans des conditions oxydantes et réductrices, entre 200-350 °C. Les données expérimentales ont révélé que l'espèce UO2Cl2° domine dans les conditions oxydantes et l'UCl4° dans les conditions réductrices. Les deux espèces augmentent rapidement en abondance avec une activité de chlorure croissante, mais l'UCl4° le fait plus rapidement que l'UO2Cl2°. La modélisation géochimique d'un système d'oxyde de fer-cuivre-or (IOCG) a démontré que la formation de gisements d'uranium pouvait provenir de la circulation de fluides réducteurs, et la croyance de longue date que l'uranium est immobile dans des conditions réductrices est en fait injustifiée. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The high field strength elements (HFSE) are considered to be immobile in many geochemical environments, within which hydrothermal fluids at elevated temperature play a key role in their transport. Of the metals considered in this thesis, niobium is often used as a reference element, against which the mobility of other elements is compared, tantalum, the geochemical "twin" of niobium, is assumed to be equally difficult to transport, and uranium, known to be highly mobile in oxidizing environments, is deemed to be immobile in reducing systems. Through the use of field-based and experimental studies, this thesis evaluates the actual mobility of these metals and, through qualitative and quantitative means, determines their solubility and speciation. The behaviour of niobium and tantalum in a hydrothermally altered setting was first described in the Nechalacho rare metal deposit, situated in the Northwest Territories of Canada. Whole rock geochemical data, petrography, and electron microprobe analyses were used to separate the magmatic and hydrothermal components of the behavior of these metals in a deposit that underwent pervasive hydrothermal alteration. Niobium and tantalum were found to be hosted in zircon, columbite-(Fe), fergusonite-(Y), uranopyrochlore and samarskite-(Y) and a genetic model incorporating the magmatic crystallization of these minerals followed by a hydrothermal overprint was proposed to explain their occurrence. Local remobilization of the two metals was observed, but was limited to a sub-meter scale. Further work was carried out experimentally, in order to determine the solubility and speciation of niobium in solutions containing the ligand most likely to form complexes with this metal, fluoride, at 150, 200, and 250 °C. These experiments, carried out in titanium autoclaves, identified the presence of the species Nb(OH)4+ at low HF concentration and NbF2(OH)3° at high HF concentration. The presence of the latter hydroxyl-fluoride species increases the solubility of niobium in acidic fluoride-rich solutions, by orders of magnitude. Destabilization of this complex is most easily accomplished through a reduction in the HF concentration of the fluid, for example, by fluid-rock interaction involving carbonate rich formations. Similar autoclave experiments were carried out with tantalum at 100-250 °C. At low HF concentration Ta(OH)50 predominates, whereas at high HF concentration TaF5, at  ≤150 °C, and, more commonly, TaF3(OH)3-, result in rapid increases in tantalum solubility. However, in the same fluid, tantalum is almost invariably less soluble than niobium. Geochemical modeling of hydrothermal alteration involving acidic brines demonstrated that Nb/Ta ratios may decrease in hydrothermally altered crystals and that removing HF from the fluid, or increasing its pH, result in niobium and tantalum mineral deposition. These experimental data, together with the above observations from the Nechalacho deposit, demonstrate that hydrothermal mobilization of niobium and tantalum is indeed possible, particularly in fluoride-rich acidic systems. Whereas niobium and tantalum are found predominantly in the 5+ valence state, redox conditions play a major role in the geochemical behavior of uranium. The solubility and speciation of uranium was evaluated at oxidizing and reducing conditions, at 200-350 °C, using autoclave experiments containing redox buffers employed to control oxygen fugacity. The experimental data revealed that the species UO2Cl2° dominates at oxidizing conditions and UCl4° at reducing conditions. Both species increase rapidly in abundance with increasing chloride activity, but UCl4° does so more rapidly than UO2Cl2°. Geochemical modelling of an iron-oxide copper gold (IOCG) system, demonstrated that the formation of uranium ore deposits could arise from an influx of reducing fluids, and the long-held belief that uranium is immobile under reducing conditions is unwarranted. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anthony E. Williams-Jones</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q862j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs84d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qm153"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamic remodeling of membranes and their lipids for cholesterol transport during steroid biosynthesis in Leydig cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Venugopal, Sathvika</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cholesterol is the only precursor for all steroids produced in mammals. During hormone induced acute steroidogenesis, large quantities of cholesterol is trafficked from its intracellular stores to the cholesterol-poor organelles, mitochondria, to be converted to pregnenolone, the first of all steroids. Although steroidogenesis is extensively studied, the actual source organelle that stores and then mobilizes cholesterol for utilization in steroid production and the pathway that assists this hydrophobic molecule to be trafficked to mitochondria are yet to be determined. Utilizing the domain 4 (D4) of the Perfringolysin O protein produced by Clostridium perfringens, which binds to high concentrations of cholesterol in membranes without cytotoxicity, we first determined the source organelle. Live cell imagining analysis in a Leydig tumor cell line and primary rat Leydig cells utilizing mCherry tagged D4 revealed release of a pool of cholesterol from the plasma membrane within 30 minutes of hormonal stimulation. Thus leading us to conclude that the bulk of steroidogenic cholesterol destined for mitochondria originates from the plasma membrane during acute steroidogenesis. Further we identified a pregnenolone mediated feedback mechanism that stops excessive cholesterol movement from the plasma membrane and thus protects mitochondria from cholesterol-induced toxicity.  We also investigated possible trafficking pathways. A hydrophobic cholesterol molecule from the plasma membrane needs to traverse the aqueous milieu to reach the mitochondria for steroid production. Many pathways have been proposed to assist cholesterol in this endeavor, but a precise mechanism that facilitates rapid movement of large quantities of cholesterol to the mitochondria had yet to be determined.  Previous studies showing an increased interaction between the endoplasmic reticulum and mitochondria during acute steroidogenesis, led us to hypothesize that cholesterol from the plasma membrane enters the endoplasmic reticulum via a membrane association and thus reaches mitochondria by plasma membrane – endoplasmic reticulum – mitochondria associations called as PAMs. These membrane associations and cellular signals are facilitated by a variety of lipid classes. Hence, we addressed this hypothesis by subcellular fractionation of hormonally induced and also hormonally induced but steroidogenesis-inhibited MA-10 cells subjected to lipidomics analysis utilizing mass spectrometry. The results obtained from this study further supported the notion that PAMs are the route for cholesterol movement from plasma membrane to the mitochondria. Further, we also noted a dynamic reorganization of multiple lipid classes that facilitate the membrane associations and cellular signals. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le cholestérol est le seul précurseur pour tous les stéroïdes produits chez les mammifères. Au cours de la stéroïdogenèse aiguë, induite par des hormones, de grandes quantités de cholestérol sont relocalisées des réservoirs intracellulaires vers les organites cellulaires pauvres en cholestérol, les mitochondries. Le cholestérol y sera converti d'abord en prégnénolone, le premier de tous les stéroïdes à être synthétisé. Bien que la stéroïdogenèse soit largement étudiée, l'organite cellulaire source qui emmagasine et mobilise le cholestérol pour la production de stéroïdes ainsi que la voie de transport qui permet au cholestérol, cette molécule hydrophobe, d'être transporté jusqu'aux mitochondries n'ont pas encore été déterminés.Nous avons pu déterminé l'organite cellulaire source, en utilisant le domaine 4 (D4) de la protéine Perfringolysine O, produite par Clostridium perfringens. Le D4 se lie à des concentrations élevées de cholestérol dans les membranes, sans causer de cytotoxicité.  L'analyse d'imagerie de cellules vivantes dans une lignée cellulaire tumorale de Leydig et des cellules primaires de Leydig de rat, en utilisant le D4 marqué au mCherry, a révélé la libération d'un pool de cholestérol à partir de la membrane plasmique dans les 30 minutes suivant la stimulation hormonale. Ceci nous mène à conclure que la majeure partie du cholestérol stéroïdien, destinée aux mitochondries, provient de la membrane plasmique pendant la stéroïdogenèse aiguë. En outre, nous avons identifié un mécanisme de rétroaction à la prégnénolone qui arrête le transport excessif du cholestérol à partir de la membrane plasmique et protège ainsi les mitochondries de la toxicité induite par le cholestérol.Nous avons également étudié les voies possibles du transport du cholestérol. Une molécule hydrophobe de cholestérol, située dans la membrane plasmique, doit traverser le milieu aqueux pour atteindre les mitochondries pour la production de stéroïdes. De nombreuses voies ont été proposées pour aider le cholestérol dans cette entreprise, mais un mécanisme précis qui facilite le mouvement rapide de grandes quantités de cholestérol vers les mitochondries n'a pas encore été déterminé. Des études antérieures montrant une interaction accrue entre le réticulum endoplasmique et les mitochondries, pendant la stéroïdogenèse aiguë, nous ont amené à émettre l'hypothèse suivante; le cholestérol de la membrane plasmique entre dans le réticulum endoplasmique via une association membranaire et atteint ainsi les mitochondries par la membrane plasmique - réticulum endoplasmique - les associations de mitochondries appelées PAM. Ces associations de membranes et signaux cellulaires sont facilités par une variété de classes de lipides. Par conséquent, nous avons vérifié cette hypothèse par l'analyse lipidomique utilisant la spectrométrie de masse. Plus précisément, nous avons comparé les différents lipides retrouvés dans les  fractions sous-cellulaires de cellules MA-10 induites hormonalement vs ceux retrouvés dans les fractions sous-cellulaires de MA-10 induites hormonalement mais dont la stéroïdogenèse avait été inhibée. Les résultats obtenus à partir de cette étude ont également soutenu l'idée que les PAM sont la voie du transport du cholestérol de la membrane plasmatique vers les mitochondries. En outre, nous avons également noté une réorganisation dynamique de multiples classes de lipides qui facilitent les associations de membranes et les signaux cellulaires.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vassilios Papadopoulos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zd457.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qm153</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anc580p95q"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biomechanics of ascending aortic aneurysms: An investigation into 2D strain echocardiography and tensile mechanics to identify at-risk patients</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Emmott, Alexander</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'aorte est la plus grosse artère du corps et sert de conduit pour le flux sanguin systémique du cœur. Elle est caractérisée principalement par son comportement élastique passif, au cours de la systole, qui permet de convertir l'énergie des fluides en un potentiel élastique. Lors de la diastole, ce potentiel emmagasiné est utilisé afin de maintenir la circulation systémique. En condition pathologique, la paroi vasculaire subit un remodelage qui peut entraîner une altération de sa fonction élastique telle qu'observée dans les cas d'anévrismes aortiques. Sans traitement, les anévrismes aortiques comportent un risque important de rupture pouvant mener à une invalidité grave ou à la mort. Les lignes directrices cliniques pour l'intervention chirurgicale sont basées sur des seuils de diamètre aortique. Malheureusement, ces critères d'intervention sont de faibles prédicteurs d'incidents puisque environ 40% des cas de dissection et de rupture se produisent à des diamètres inférieurs aux lignes directrices chirurgicales. Le diamètre de l'aorte est un critère insuffisant pour établir la détérioration élastique et le remodelage pathologique du vaisseau contribuant à la dissection et la rupture. Dans le cadre de la présente thèse, nous avons testé l'hypothèse que les propriétés élastiques ou mécaniques de la paroi aortique peuvent être utilisées comme un marqueur de la dysfonction aortique ascendante et contribuer à titre de valeur ajoutée au critère de diamètre afin d'identifier les patients à risque.Dans le cadre de la présente thèse, nous avons utilisé l'échocardiographie trans-œsophagienne, une technique qui nous permet d'évaluer les propriétés mécaniques de l'aorte ascendante via l'imagerie ultrasonore du cœur et des grands vaisseaux. Nous avons ensuite validé cette méthodologie avec un essai de traction ex vivo sur tissu réséqué. Plus précisément, nous avons développé de nouvelles mesures de rigidité in vivo appelées le «Cardiac Cycle Pressure Modulus» (CCPM) et le «Cardiac Cycle Stress Modulus» (CCSM). Ces nouvelles mesures ont été comparées avec différentes techniques bien établies dans la littérature telles que l'histologie, les paramètres de rigidité et les paramètres de perte d'énergie ex vivo de la paroi aortique. Cette approche a été appliquée de façon globale (c'est-à-dire, la moyenne de la circonférence) et de façon régionale, soit à quatre foyers distincts de la circonférence aortique. Le CCPM global et le CCSM global ont été significativement prédictifs des indices mécaniques ex vivo et de l'histopathologie. Ces mesures pourraient être utilisées pour identifier les patients ayant un remodelage aortique défavorable et qui ne répondraient pas aux critères chirurgicaux standard de ≥5,5 cm de diamètre. L'analyse régionale a démontré que l'hétérogénéité dans le CCPM et le CCSM augmente avec la dégénérescence médiale créant une distribution inégale du stress physiologique dans la paroi aortique. De plus, des profils de déformation à la traction et à la compression ont été observés de façon simultanée dans des régions avoisinantes de l'aorte de certains patients, ce qui suggère un environnement physio-mécanique plus complexe que ce qui a été précédemment signalé. Finalement, la présente thèse propose une nouvelle technique d'évaluation des patients ayant un anévrisme de l'aorte ascendante. Cette technique peut fournir une dimension supplémentaire et cruciale à la gestion chirurgicale des patients.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The aorta is the largest artery in the body and serves as the conduit for systemic blood flow from the heart. Its central property is its passive elastic behaviour that converts fluid energy to elastic potential during systole and subsequently returns that stored potential to maintain systemic circulation during diastole. With disease the pathological remodelling of the wall can result in an impairment of its elastic function, particularly in the case of an aortic aneurysm.  If left unrepaired, aortic aneurysms carry significant risk of tearing and often result in death or serious disability. Clinical guidelines for surgical intervention are based on aortic diameter thresholds, but unfortunately these criteria are insufficient and an estimated 40% of dissection and rupture cases occur at diameters below the surgical guidelines. Aortic diameter criteria do not fully relay the risk that elastic impairment and pathological remodelling contribute to dissection or rupture. Herein, this thesis tested the hypothesis that the elastic or mechanical properties of the aortic wall can be used as a marker of ascending aortic dysfunction and contribute added information beyond size to identify at-risk patients. In this work we used transesophageal echocardiography, an application of ultrasound imaging to the heart and great vessels, to assess the mechanical properties of the ascending aorta and subsequently validated this methodology with ex vivo tensile analysis on resected tissue. Specifically, we developed novel in vivo stiffness metrics termed the Cardiac Cycle Pressure Modulus (CCPM) and the Cardiac Cycle Stress Modulus (CCSM) that were compared with aortic wall histology and ex vivo stiffness and energy loss parameters that have been widely reported, previously. This approach was applied globally (i.e., circumference averaged) and regionally at four distinct foci around the aortic circumference. Global CCPM and CCSM were significantly predictive of ex vivo mechanical indices and histopathology and could be used to identify patients with adverse aortic remodelling who did not meet standard surgical criteria of ≥5.5 cm diameter. Regional analysis demonstrated that heterogeneity in CCPM and CCSM increased with medial degeneration creating uneven distribution of physiological stress in the aortic wall. Furthermore, both tensile and compressive strain patterns were observed simultaneously in neighbouring regions of some patients suggesting a more complex physio-mechanical environment than had previously been appreciated. Ultimately, this work proposes a novel assessment technique to follow patients with ascending aortic aneurysms that may provide a crucial added dimension to surgical management of patients.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Richard L. Leask</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f589f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p95q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hs03j"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluating the security of ARINC-825 and controller area networks, the impact of bus security in aerospace</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dubois, Dirk</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les voitures récentes contiennent des réseaux interconnectés pour assuré que les consommateurs ont accès à la technologie et les caractéristiques de sécurité modernes dans leurs voitures. Les voitures peuvent maintenant être une cible pour les pirates et les agents malveillants, parce qu'ils contiennent des blocs de commande électroniques connecté par laréseau CAN. De plus, l'industrie aérospatiale étend son soutien au rèseau CAN grâce à la spécification de ARINC-825. Notre recherche examine l'état de la sécurité du réseau CAN et propose un nouveau matériel pour atténuer les attaques. Nous démontrons une attaque d'usurpation, appelée «DeceptiCAN», qui effectue une attaque par déni de service ciblée suivie d'une usurpation du nœud attaqué. Nous proposons ensuite le module serveur mandataire pour le réseau CAN, une solution matérielle qui permet de protéger les noeuds critiques d'un réseau CAN. Nousprésentons une démonstration de faisabilité de la conception de base des modules serveur mandataire et démontrons qu'elle protège efficacement le réseau. Nous étendons ensuite notre travail au domaine aérospatial en examinant le protocole ARINC-825-4. Nous présentons notre simulation du protocole et démontrons comment nous pouvons l'utiliser pour évaluer la sécurité d'ARINC-825-4. Nous présentons ensuite notre outil de reniflage pour ARINC-825-4, qui peut exfiltrer les données de la simulation et analyser les contenu des données. Finalement, nous attaquons le protocole de ARINC-825-4 enétendant notre outil de renifleur et nous discutons de la sécurité du système.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>To provide customers with the latest technology and safety features, cars now contain complex interconnected networks. Containing multiple Electronic Control Units (ECUs), connected using the Controller Area Network (CAN) bus, cars can now be a target for hackers and malicious agents. Furthermore, the aerospace industry is expanding support for CANthrough the Aeronautical Radio, Incorporated (ARINC)-825 specification. Our research examines the state of CAN security and proposes new hardware to mitigate attacks. We demonstrate the DeceptiCAN spoofing attack, which performs a targeted denial of service attack followed by spoofing of the node under attack. We then propose the CANProxy module, a hardware solution to help protect mission critical nodes in any network implementing CAN. We present a proof of concept experiment of the Proxy Modules core design and demonstrate that it effectively protects the network. We then extend our work to the aerospace field, examining the ARINC-825-4 protocol. We present our simulation of the protocol and demonstrate how we can leverage it to evaluate the security of ARINC-825-4. We then present our ARINC-825-4 sniffing tool that can exfiltrate data from the simulation and performs an analysis of the data's contents. Finally, we attack the ARINC-825-4 protocol by extending our sniffer tool and discuss the security of the system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brett Meyer</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g7390.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hs03j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qm16c"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of methods to study the interactions of twin arcs in an electric arc furnace</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Burkat, Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Electric Arc Furnace (EAF) was applied to industrial processes over a century ago. In recent years there has been an increased interest in the direct current twin cathode EAF. It proved to be a successful technology in industry and now there is interest to learn more about what is happening inside the furnace especially relating to the interactions of the two electric arcs. These interactions have an impact on arc structures since they can cause the two arcs to merge. The observed structures are separated into two groups based on the number of attachment points on the anode: (1) merged arcs, and (2) separate arcs, containing one and two attachment points, respectively. In this thesis, the interactions between two atmospheric pressure argon arcs were recorded using high-speed imaging. Two image analysis methods were developed for the processing of the large amount of image data.The first method attempted to reconstruct the arc path between the cathodes and the common anode from the images. To do so, a two-step process was developed. In the first step the cathode and anode attachment spots were located on the image. In the second step the Dijkstra's path finding algorithm was used to find a path between the endpoints that went as much as possible through the center of the arc column. It was shown that imaging from one axis was insufficient to get a good understanding of the true shape of the electric arc since an image is a two-dimensional projection of a three-dimensional world.The second method aimed to quantify the time the arcs spent separate or merged. An image analysis program was developed to classify each frame into one of two structures. The effect on the observed arc structure of suddenly doubling the current through one arc from its nominal value of 50 A was investigated for increasingly large cathode-anode distances. For low cathode-anode distance (lower than 25 mm as studied in this thesis), the sudden current increase lead to an increased time the arcs spent in a merged structure, in accordance with the increased Lorentz force-induced interactions.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Depuis plus d'un siècle, le four à arc électrique (FAE) est utilisé dans les procédés industriels. Dernièrement, il y a un intérêt croissant pour le FAE à double cathode à courant continu. Cette technologie s'est avéré être un succès industriel, déclenchant ainsi un intérêt pour son étude fondamentale, notamment en ce qui concerne les interactions des deux arcs électriques. Ces interactions ont été séparés en deux modes selon le nombre de points d'attachement sur l'anode : (1) le mode d'arcs fusionnés (2) le mode d'arcs séparés. Les arcs fusionnés ont un point d'attachement sur l'anode et les arcs séparés ont 2 point d'attachement sur l'anode. Dans cette thèse, les interactions entre deux arcs d'argon à pression atmosphérique ont été visualisées en utilisant l'imagerie à haute vitesse. Pour ce faire, deux méthodes d'analyse d'imagerie à haute vitesse ont été développés pour le traitement de grandes quantités de données.Avec la première méthode, nous avons essayé de reconstruire la trajectoire tracée par l'arc entre les cathodes et l'anode à partir des images. Pour y parvenir, un processus en deux étapes fut développé. Dans la première étape, les points d'attachement de la cathode et de l'anode ont été positionnés sur l'image. Dans la deuxième étape, l'algorithme de Dijsktra fut utilisé pour déterminer le chemin le plus court entre les points d'attachement qui passe le plus possible à travers le centre de la colonne d'arc. Il a été démontré que l'utilisation de l'imagerie d'un seul axe est insuffisant pour avoir une bonne compréhension de la vraie forme de l'arc électrique. En effet, une image est une projection bidimensionnelle d'un monde tridimensionnel.La deuxième méthode avait pour but de quantifier les durées de temps des arcs en mode séparé et fusionné. Un programme d'analyse d'image fut développé afin de permettre le classement de chaque image dans l'un des deux modes d'attachement. Ce programme fut utilisé pour étudier l'effet d'une augmentation soudaine du courant (2x) à travers un arc (valeur nominale de 50 A) pour des distances cathode-anode croissantes. Pour une distance cathode-anode inférieure à 25 mm, l'augmentation soudaine du courant cause une augmentation de la durée d'arc en mode fusionné. Ceci est en accord avec l'augmentation des interactions induites par la force de Lorentz.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sylvain Coulombe</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2687529.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qm16c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p266m"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History and Classical Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Statecraft and institution building between two revolutions: Taha Hussein and Egypt's road to independence (1919 -1952)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ahmed, Hussam Eldin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse est une biographie sociale de l'intellectuel égyptien Taha Hussein (1889-1973). Alors que les études existantes sur Hussein ont exploré sa remarquable carrière littéraire, cette étude, le fruit de recherches menées auprès des archives nationales égyptiennes et françaises, des archives de l'université du Caire, ainsi que des archives personnelles de Hussein, porte sur sa carrière publique en tant qu'homme d'état et fonctionnaire publique. Ni l'historiographie égyptienne ni les projets littéraires fondés sur des études postcoloniales, ayant focalisé exclusivement sur l'œuvre publiée par Hussein, ne rendent justice au contexte institutionnel et politique dans lequel il écrivait et prenait ses décisions. En conséquence, il reste un excellent exemple d'un intellectuel piégé dans des binaires simplistes, tels que «culturellement authentique» ou «occidentalisé» qui ne tiennent pas compte de la complexité de ses perspectives intellectuelles. La thèse se tourne plutôt vers ce qu'il a fait en tant qu'homme politique de premier plan et montre que, loin de son image d'homme de lettres désintéressé par la politique, promouvoir la culture était sa stratégie politique pour construire une démocratie forte et garantir une vie meilleure pour les Égyptiens.A travers la vie de Hussein, cette thèse raconte un moment de modernité alternative qui s'arrête dans les années 1950 devant la montée de la colère publique contre l'intervention des puissances coloniales dans les affaires égyptiennes et arabes. L'étude montre comment ce moment s'est déroulé, et ce par l'analyse des efforts de Hussein visant à avancer la Nahda en construisant de solides institutions éducatives et culturelles modernes, telles que l'université laïque et l'académie de la langue arabe, qui, selon lui, étaient indispensables à la création d'un humanisme nationaliste égyptien capable de s'approprier l'essentiel de la culture européenne et d'aborder la tradition arabo-islamique de façon critique. En explorant l'histoire peu étudiée des établissements d'enseignement, cette thèse se détourne de la lutte triangulaire de pouvoir entre les Britanniques, la monarchie égyptienne et les partis politiques qui dominent l'historiographie de la période parlementaire (1922-1952). Cela montre que, malgré un contexte politique difficile, Hussein et d'autres sont arrivés à adopter la gratuité de l'éducation, à élargir l'influence culturelle de l'Égypte dans la région et à habiliter des institutions importantes de culture et d'éducation qui ont continué sous Nasser.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis is a social biography of the Egyptian intellectual Taha Hussein (1889-1973). While studies of Hussein have explored his remarkable literary career, this study uses Egyptian and French state and university archives, as well as Hussein's private papers, to shift the focus to his public career as a statesman and a civil servant. With their exclusive reliance on Hussein's published work, neither Egyptian historiography nor literary projects grounded in postcolonial studies do justice to the institutional and political context in which he was writing and making decisions. As a result, he remains a prime example of an intellectual who is trapped in simplistic binaries, such as "culturally authentic" or "westernized" that fail to account for the complexity of his intellectual outlook. The thesis turns instead to what he did as a leading politician, and shows that far from his image as a "man of letters" disinterested in politics, his promotion of culture was a political strategy to build a strong democracy and guarantee a better life for Egyptians.Using Hussein's life, this thesis narrates a moment of alternative modernity that gets shut down in the 1950s by increasing public anger against the intervention of colonial powers in Egyptian and Arab affairs. The study shows how this moment was worked out at the ground level through the examination of Hussein's efforts to take the Nahda forward by building strong modern educational and cultural institutions, such as the secular university and the language academy, which he believed were essential to create an Egyptian nationalist humanism that showed a critical appropriation of European culture and fostered an active engagement with the Arab-Islamic tradition. By exploring the understudied history of educational institutions, this thesis turns away from the triangular struggle of power between the British, the palace and the political parties dominating the historiography of the parliamentary period (1922-1952). It shows that, despite a challenging political context, Hussein and others were able to introduce free education, expand Egypt's cultural influence in the region, and empower important institutions of culture and education that continued under Nasser.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Laila Parsons</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139440r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p266m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History and Classical Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515q83h"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic risk score and its utility in diabetic nephropathy management</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Simon, Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction: Diabetic nephropathy is the leading cause of chronic kidney disease and end stage renal disease in most industrialized countries and increasingly so in countries with transition economies. While major successes in the treatment of diabetic nephropathy have been obtained, a proportion of type 2 diabetic patients continues to progress along the path of renal disease despite receiving evidence-based recommended medications for the management of their diabetic nephropathy. This phenomenon is characteristic of renal non-response and is associated with unmet renal needs. We hypothesize that patients presenting evidence of renal non-response can be genetically distinguished from patients presenting evidence of renal response and that these genetic traits may differ between European Caucasian patients of different ethnic backgrounds. Design and method: the ADVANCE study is a 2x2 factorial randomized trial assessing the effect of blood pressure and glycemic control in 11,140 patients with type 2 diabetes (T2D) over a period of five years. 4,098 Caucasian participants from ADVANCE were genotyped in addition to having their urine: albumin creatine ratio (UACR) and estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) measured at regular intervals during the study. We began by reviewing the best practices in the study of gene-environment interactions to propose an appropriate process to identify such interactions. The geo-ethnic origin of Caucasian genotyped patients of ADVANCE was then determined by principal component analysis on a set of 139,186 independent single nucleotide polymorphisms. Phenotypic comparisons were conducted between patients of different geo-ethnic backgrounds living in different geographic regions to assess the impact of genes and environment on renal and diabetic traits. We designed a classification algorithm based on longitudinal measures of UACR and eGFR to identify patients presenting evidence of renal non-response or renal response for UACR and eGFR separately. Genome wide associations studies were conducted between these patient groups to identify genetic determinants associated with UACR and eGFR non-response. Genetic risk scores were created using genetic determinants of renal non-response and their capacity to stratify patients according to their risk of developing unmet renal needs was evaluated. Following these analyses, the presence of geo-ethnic based genetic heterogeneity within the genetic determinants of renal non-response was assessed. Results: The first principal component separated ADVANCE Caucasian participants in groups of Slavic and Celtic ethnic origins. Age of onset of T2D and albuminuria appear to have an important genetic component as the values of these traits were also different between Slavic and Celtic individuals living in the same countries. Our classification algorithm identified distinct groups of patients with and without renal non-response. GWAS analyses revealed distinct genetic determinants associated to UACR and eGFR non-response. Genetic risk scores based on renal non-response genetic determinants could stratify patients according to their risk of developing unmet renal needs, identify patients who benefit the most from blood pressure and glycemic control treatments at a renal level, as well as stratify patients according to their risk of experiencing DN onset for those without DN at study entry. Distinct genetic architectures between Slavic and Celtic patient groups of the Caucasian ADVANCE population were identified. These distinct architectures were also observed for the genetic determinants renal non-response. Conclusion: Our results indicate that genetic tools could distinguish patients likely to experience DN onset from those remaining free of DN, and could identify patients who will benefit the most from blood pressure and glycemic control beyond the capacity of common clinical risk factors.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introduction : La néphropathie diabétique est la cause principale d'insuffisance rénale chronique dans la plupart des pays occidentaux et de manière croissante dans les pays en voie de développement. Malgré le fait que plusieurs succès furent rapportés dans le traitement de la néphropathie diabétique, une proportion de patients diabétique de type 2, continue de progresser sur le chemin de l'insuffisance rénale et cela malgré leur traitement avec des médicaments recommandés. Ce phénomène est caractéristique de la non-réponse rénale et est associé aux besoins rénaux non satisfaits. Nous faisons l'hypothèse que les patients présentant des évidences de non-réponse rénale peuvent être génétiquement distingués des patients présentant des évidences de réponse rénale et que ces traits génétiques peuvent être différent chez les patients Caucasien avec des origines géo-ethniques différentes. Design et méthodologie : l'étude ADVANCE est un essai clinique factoriel 2x2 randomisé évaluant l'effet d'un control de la pression sanguine et de la glycémie chez 11,140 patients diabétique de type 2 sur une période de cinq ans. 4,098 patients caucasiens d'ADVANCE furent génotypés en plus d'avoir leur ratio d'albumine et de créatinine urinaire (UACR), et leur taux de filtration glomérulaire estimé (eGFR) mesurés à des intervalles de temps réguliers pendant l'étude. Nous avons créé un algorithme de classification basé sur des valeurs longitudinales d'UACR et d'eGFR afin d'identifier les patients présentant des évidences de non-réponse rénale ou de réponse rénale pour UACR et eGFR séparément. Des études d'association pangénomiques furent complétées entre ces groupes de patients afin d'identifier des déterminants génétiques associés à la non-réponse UACR et eGFR. Des scores de risque génétique furent créés à partir de ces déterminants génétiques et leurs capacités à stratifier les patients par rapport à leur risque de développer des besoins rénaux non satisfaits furent évaluées. Suite à ces analyses, la présence d'une hétérogénéité au sein des déterminants génétique de la non-réponse rénale fut évalué. Résultats : Le premier component principal sépara les patients Caucasien d'ADVANCE en groupe d'origine Slavic et Celtic. L'âge de début de diabète et l'albuminurie semble avoir un component génétique important car les valeurs de ces traits étaient différentes chez les patients Slavic et Celtic habitant dans le même pays. Notre algorithme de classification a identifié deux groupes distincts de patients avec et sans non-réponse rénale. Les études d'association pangénomiques ont révélées l'existence de déterminants génétiques distincts pour la non-réponse UACR et eGFR. Des scores de risque génétique créés à partir de ces déterminants génétiques, furent capable de stratifier des patients par rapport à leur risque de développer des besoins rénaux non satisfaits, d'identifier les patients qui bénéficient le plus à un niveau rénal des traitements de control de la pression sanguine et de la glycémie, ainsi que d'identifier au sein des patients sans néphropathie diabétique les patients les plus à risque de développer cette complication du diabète. Des architectures génétiques distinctes furent identifiées entre les patients slavic et celtique au sein des patients caucasiens d'AVANCE. Ces distinctions furent également observées au niveau des déterminants génétique de la non-réponse rénale. Conclusion : Nos résultats indiquent qu'un outil génétique peut distinguer les patients susceptibles de développer la néphropathie diabétique de ceux susceptible de demeurer sans néphropathie diabétique, et qu'il peut identifier les patients qui bénéficient le plus à un niveau rénal de leurs traitements contre l'hypertension et l'hyperglycémie, et ceci au-delà des capacités des indicateurs cliniques conventionnels.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pavel Hamet</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333468x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q83h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axw42nb12j"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Association of Leukotriene receptor antagonists (LTRAs) use and the risk of aortic stenosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhu, Nanqing</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Contexte: La sténose aortique (SA) est la troisième maladie cardiovasculaire en importance dans le monde occidental. Il affecte 4% des personnes âgées de 65 ans ou plus aux États-Unis et le nombre passe à 7% à l'âge de 80 ans. Actuellement, seules les chirurgies invasives ou coûteuses de remplacement de la valve aortique percutanée sont disponibles pour les patients symptomatiques. Ainsi, la découverte de traitements médicaux qui ralentissent la progression de la maladie de la valve aortique constituerait un progrès médical important. Des études in vitro ont montré l'implication des leucotriènes dans la pathogenèse de la SA par l'intermédiaire des récepteurs des leucotriènes. Par conséquent, les antagonistes des récepteurs des leucotriènes (ARLT), un traitement de l'asthme non stéroïdien établi, est une cible thérapeutique potentielle de la SA.Objectifs: Le but de cette étude était de déterminer si l'utilisation des ARLT est associée de façon indépendante à une incidence plus faible de sténose aortique à l'aide de données administratives provenant du Québec.Méthodes: À partir des bases de données administratives sur la santé du Québec, au Canada, une cohorte d'étude de personnes âgées de plus de 66 ans, principalement avec une coronaropathie soupçonnée, a été créée entre le 1er avril 2001 et le 30 mars 2011. Les personnes ayant un diagnostic antérieur de SA, de sténose mitrale, de SA congénitale ont été exclues de la population. Le résultat a été un nouveau diagnostic d'AS non rhumatismale ou de remplacement d'une valve chirurgicale. L'exposition a été définie comme les individus ayant au moins 90 jours cumulatifs d'exposition à l'ARLT après l'entrée de la cohorte. Une analyse cas-témoins imbriquée a été utilisée avec des témoins appariés selon l'âge et la durée du suivi. Les odds ratios de AS ont été estimés avec un modèle de régression logistique conditionnelle avec ajustement pour les facteurs de confusion. Plusieurs analyses de sensibilité, traitant principalement d'éventuels biais de classification erronée, ont été effectuées pour explorer la robustesse des résultats.Résultats: La cohorte comprenait 20466 cas et 204660 témoins appariés. Le temps moyen de suivi pour les cas et les contrôles était de 382 et 369 jours, respectivement. Comparativement aux individus non exposés aux ARLT, les utilisateurs des ARLT avaient un risque légèrement accru de SA (ORadj = 1,45, IC à 95%: 1,16-1,82). Cependant, cette association n'a pas été observée de façon uniforme dans toutes les analyses de sensibilité. Dans une analyse de sensibilité où l'exposition n'incluait que les utilisateurs actuels de LTRA, l'utilisation de LTRA n'était pas associée à un risque accru de SA (ORadj = 1,24, IC 95%: 0,98-1,56), lorsque les décès dus à la SPA étaient inclus dans le résultat. Des associations significatives pourraient être confirmées soit. En outre, l'analyse des risques concurrents a également montré une association nulle entre l'exposition au LTRA et le développement de la SA.Conclusions: L'utilisation d'ARLT n'a pas été associée à un risque plus faible de sténose aortique dans cette étude de population basée sur des personnes âgées soupçonnées d'une maladie cardiaque au Québec. Des études supplémentaires avec une puissance améliorée sont nécessaires pour estimer plus précisément l'effet de l'utilisation des ARLT sur la sténose aortique.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Background: Aortic stenosis (AS) is one of the most common heart valve diseases in the Western world. It affects about 2% people aged 65 or above and the number rises to 7% by the age of 80. Presently, only invasive surgical or expensive percutaneous aortic valve replacement are available as treatment for symptomatic patients. Thus, discovery of medical treatments that slow down the progression of aortic valve disease would be a significant therapeutic advance. In vitro studies have shown the involvement of leukotriene in the pathogenesis of AS via leukotriene receptors. Therefore, leukotriene receptor antagonists (LTRAs), an established non-steroid asthma treatment, are a potential therapeutic target of AS. Objectives: The goal of this study was to determine whether use of LTRAs is independently associated with a lower incidence of aortic stenosis using population data from Quebec.Methods: Using the Quebec, Canada health administrative databases, a study cohort of individuals over 66, principally with suspected coronary artery disease, from April 1,2001 and March 30, 2011 was created. Individuals with previous diagnosis of AS, mitral stenosis, congenital AS were excluded from the population. The outcome was a new diagnosis of non-rheumatic AS or surgical valve replacement. A nested case-control analysis was used with controls (10:1)  matched by age and follow-up duration. Exposure was defined as individuals with at least 90 cumulative days of LTRAs exposure after cohort entry.  Odds ratios of AS were estimated with conditional logistic regression model with adjustment for confounders. Several sensitivity analyses, principally addressing possible misclassification bias, were performed to explore the robustness of the results.Results: The cohort consisted of 20466 cases and 204660 matched controls. Mean follow up time for cases and controls was 382 and 369 days, respectively. Compared to individuals not exposed to LTRAs, users of LTRAs had an increased adjusted odds ratio (ORadj= 1.45, 95% CI:1.16-1.82) for the diagnosis of AS. However, this association was not consistently observed across all sensitivity analyses. In one sensitivity analysis where exposure only included current LTRAs users, an associated with AS was not present (ORadj=1.24, 95% CI: 0.98-1.56). Similarly, when death due to AS was included in a composite outcome, no statistically significant associations could be confirmed either. Furthermore, analysis from competing risk model also showed a null association between LTRA exposure and AS development. Conclusions: The use of LTRAs was not associated with lower risk of aortic stenosis in this population based study of Quebec seniors with suspected heart disease. It appears unlikely that LTRAs are associated with any meaningful reduction in the diagnosis of AS but additional studies with improved power and longer follow-up are required to if more precise estimates are desired.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>George Thanassoulis</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>James Brophy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150m33k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nb12j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajd472z69t"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Contribution of known and novel DNA repair genes to pancreatic cancer susceptibility</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith, Alyssa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Pancreatic adenocarcinoma (PAC) is a deadly malignancy that most commonly presents at a late stage and is ultimately refractory to systemic therapies. Even more devastating is the familial clustering of PAC (and other cancers) that is observed in 10-15% of cases. These kindreds, however, represent an opportune subset of patients for studies aimed at early detection and precision oncology strategies. While a fraction of the observed familial clustering of PAC is attributable to inherited (i.e., germline) genetic mutations in known PAC susceptibility genes (e.g., BRCA1 and BRCA2), the genetic causes for the overwhelming majority of familial PAC (~85%) remain undefined. The rapid lethality of PAC has hindered the collection of DNA, tumour specimens, and high-quality clinical and epidemiologic data that are critical for genetic studies of PAC. Herein, we demonstrate that a rapid ascertainment methodology, as used by the Quebec Pancreas Cancer Study (QPCS), a prospective clinic-based PAC research registry that was established in our lab in 2012, leads to high participation rates and allows for the collection of rare "high-risk" kindreds for studies of PAC heredity. Motivated by recent studies by our group and others suggesting that PAC associated with germline mutations in homology-directed DNA repair (HDR) genes have increased sensitivities to DNA damaging agents (e.g., platinums) and poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase inhibitors, we combined the resources of the QPCS and the Ontario Pancreas Cancer Study to define the prevalence of germline mutations in 4 known HDR-implicated PAC susceptibility genes (BRCA1, BRCA2, PALB2 and ATM) among 150 consecutive PAC cases with French-Canadian ancestry – a population known to harbour founder (i.e., recurrent) mutations in these genes – and 236 cases unselected for ancestry. Using clinical data collected by these registries, we provide supporting evidence for the role of precision therapy in this PAC subtype, and make recommendations for reflex genetic testing that can be easily applied in the routine management of PAC. To elucidate the unexplained majority of familial PAC, we used next-generation sequencing to interrogate the germline exomes of 109 PAC cases from 93 "high-risk" kindreds and used a filter-based approach to identify several candidate PAC susceptibility genes involved in DNA repair. Most notable are FAN1, NEK1 and RHNO1, which each harboured pathogenic mutations in 3 kindreds (3.2%) and demonstrated segregation with PAC in 2 kindreds. The identification of several low prevalence candidate genes, rather than a single major gene in our large case series highlights the likely heterogeneity of PAC heredity. Adverse survival was observed in early stage PAC cases with germline mutations in DNA repair genes, pointing to a hypothesis that these cases may represent a distinct clinical subtype with selective drug sensitivities. Overall, this thesis aims to characterize the contribution of both known and novel germline genetic causes of PAC and supports the notion that distinct genetic subtypes of PAC may benefit from targeted therapies, highlighting the limitations of the current "one-size-fits-all" approach to PAC treatment.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'adénocarcinome pancréatique (ACP) est un cancer mortel qui se présente le plus souvent à un stade avancé et finit par être réfractaire aux thérapies systémiques. Encore plus dévastatrice est l'agrégation familiale de l'ACP (et d'autres cancers) qui est observée chez 10-15% des cas. Cependant, ces apparentés représentent un sous-ensemble opportun de patients pour des études visant la détection précoce et les stratégies d'oncologie de précision. Alors qu'une fraction de l'agrégation familiale observée de l'ACP est attribuable aux mutations génétiques héréditaires (c.-à-d., germinales) dans les gènes de susceptibilité à l'ACP connus (ex., BRCA1 et BRCA2), les causes génétiques de la majorité de l'ACP familial (~85%) restent indéfinies. La mortalité rapide de l'ACP a entravé la collecte d'ADN, de spécimens de tumeurs et de données cliniques et épidémiologiques de haute qualité qui sont essentielles pour les études génétiques de l'ACP. Nous démontrons ici qu'une méthodologie d'inspection rapide, telle qu'utilisée par l'Étude Québécoise sur le cancer du pancréas (QPCS), un registre prospectif de recherche sur les ACPs établi dans notre laboratoire en 2012, conduit à des taux de participation élevés et permet de rassembler de rares cas d'apparentés «à haut risque» pour des études sur l'hérédité de l'ACP. Suivant des études récentes de notre groupe et d'autres groupes suggérant que l'ACP associé aux mutations germinales dans les gènes de réparation homologue directe de l'ADN (RHD) ont une sensibilité accrue aux agents endommageant l'ADN (ex. platines) et inhibiteurs de poly(ADP-ribose) polymérase, nous avons combiné les ressources du QPCS et de l'Étude Ontarienne sur le cancer du pancréas pour définir la prévalence des mutations germinales dans 4 gènes connus de susceptibilité à l'ACP impliqués dans la RHD (BRCA1, BRCA2, PALB2 et ATM) parmi 150 cas d'ACPs d'ascendance canadienne-française – une population connue comme ayant des mutations fondatrices (c.-à-d. récurrentes) dans ces gènes – et 236 cas non sélectionnés pour l'ascendance. En utilisant les données cliniques recueillies par ces registres, nous apportons des preuves du rôle de la thérapie de précision dans ce sous-type d'ACP et faisons des recommandations pour des tests génétiques en reflexe pouvant être facilement appliqués dans la prise en charge de routine de l'ACP. Pour élucider la majorité inexpliquée de cas d'ACP familial, nous avons utilisé le séquençage de nouvelle génération pour investiguer les exomes germinaux de 109 cas d'ACPs provenant de 93 apparentés «à haut risque» et utilisé une approche par filtre pour identifier plusieurs gènes candidats de susceptibilité au ACP qui sont impliqués dans la réparation de l'ADN. Les plus remarquables sont FAN1, NEK1 et RHNO1, dans chacun desquels se trouvaient des mutations pathogènes chez 3 apparentés (3,2%) et démontraient une ségrégation avec l'ACP dans 2 apparentés. L'identification de plusieurs gènes candidats à faible prévalence, plutôt que d'un seul gène majeur dans notre grande série de cas, met en évidence l'hétérogénéité probable de l'hérédité de l'ACP. Une survie défavorable a été observée dans les cas d'ACP au stade précoce avec des mutations germinales dans les gènes de réparation de l'ADN, convergeant vers l'hypothèse que ces cas pourraient représenter un sous-type clinique distinct avec des sensibilités sélectives aux traitements médicamenteux. Dans l'ensemble, cette thèse vise à caractériser la contribution des causes génétiques germinales connues et nouvelles de l'ACP et soutient la notion que des sous-types génétiques distincts d'ACP peuvent bénéficier de thérapies ciblées, soulignant les limites de l'approche généralisée du traitement de l'ACP qui est présentement appliquée.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>George Zogopoulos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c9683.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z69t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq524jr136"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Positive change following a first episode of psychosis: a mixed methods study using a convergent design</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jordan, Gerald</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Un premier épisode psychotique (PEP) est souvent une maladie mentale grave et pénible. Cependant, un PEP peut également constituer une opportunité de changement positif. Bien que des changements positifs aient été rapportés à la suite de diverses maladies physiques (tel le VIH) ou d'événements traumatiques (telle la guerre), très peu d'études ont porté sur les changements positifs pouvant suivre un PEP. Pour combler cette lacune, cette thèse aborde deux questions: 1) Quels sont les changements positifs qu'éprouvent les personnes après un PEP et 2) Quels facteurs ou processus peuvent faciliter de tels changements? Ces questions de recherche ont été abordées en synthétisant les connaissances scientifiques existantes, basées sur deux revues de la littérature (un examen de la portée et une revue systématique) et en menant une étude empirique à méthodes mixtes, divisée en deux chapitres. L'examen de la portée de la littérature a été effectué en six étapes: l'identification de la question de recherche et des études pertinentes, la sélection d'études, la présentation des données, le codage et la synthèse des résultats, et une consultation avec des parties prenantes. Toutes les données ont été décrites et soumises à une analyse thématique. La revue systématique d'études mixtes, employant une synthèse qualitative convergente, a été réalisée en cinq étapes: la formulation d'une question de revue, la définition des critères d'éligibilité, l'identification des sources d'information, l'identification et la sélection des études et l'évaluation de la qualité des études. Les données ont été analysées en utilisant une synthèse thématique. L'étude empirique des méthodes mixtes a utilisé un design convergent de méthodes mixtes, incluant une composante quantitative (n=94) et une composante qualitative (n=12). Dans la composante quantitative, les participants ont rempli des questionnaires validés évaluant les changements positifs (l'échelle Posttraumatic Growth Inventory) et les prédicteurs de changement positif (les échelles Subjective Experiences of Psychosis Scale, le Brief COPE, le Recovery Assessment Scale, le Child and Youth/Adult Resilience Measure, et le Multidimensional Scale for Perceived Social Support). Dans la composante qualitative, les individus ont participé à des entrevues semi-structurés évaluant les raisons pour lesquelles ces participants estimaient avoir reçu des services d'intervention précoce; comment ils pensent avoir changé après leur PEP; et les facteurs qu'ils perçoivent comment ayant facilité de tels changements. Les données quantitatives ont été analysées à l'aide de statistiques descriptives et de régression multiple, tandis que les données qualitatives ont été analysées à l'aide d'une analyse thématique. Les résultats des études ont révélé que les participants (y compris ceux ayant une expérience vécue de PEP eux-mêmes, ainsi que leurs familles et amis) ont vécu des changements positifs au niveau individuel (le développement d'un sentiment d'identité plus robuste, l'amélioration de la santé mentale, etc.), du niveau interpersonnel (l'amélioration des relations avec autrui) et au niveau spirituel/religieux (une spiritualité renforcée). Ces changements étaient facilités par des facteurs et des processus personnels (l'adaptation, le rétablissement, la spiritualité, etc.), par des facteurs relationnels ou sociaux (le soutien social, etc.), par des facteurs contextuels (avoir reçu des services de santé mentale;  avoir des cadres culturels sur lesquels s'appuyer, etc.), ainsi que par des processus non liés au PEP (expériences de développement normatives). Un PEP peut mener à des perceptions de changement positif parmi les personnes elles-mêmes, leurs familles et leurs amis. Ces découvertes valident les expériences des personnes qui ont connu des changements positifs grâce à leur expérience de PEP et peuvent alimenter la prestation de services porteurs d'espoir, et axés sur les forces pour les personnes vivant un PEP.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introduction: A first episode of psychosis (FEP) is often a severe and highly traumatic mental illness. However, FEP may also present an opportunity for positive change. While positive changes have been reported following various physical illnesses (e.g., HIV) or traumatic events (e.g., war), little research has investigated positive changes following FEP. To address this knowledge gap, this dissertation addressed two research questions: 1) What are the positive changes persons experience following FEP, and 2) What factors or processes facilitate such changes? Methods: These research questions were addressed through synthesizing the extant scientific knowledge in two systematic reviews (i.e., a scoping and systematic mixed studies review), and through conducting one empirical mixed methods study that was separated into two chapters. The scoping review was carried out in six steps: identifying the research question and relevant studies, selecting studies, charting the data, coding and summarizing results, and consulting with stakeholders. All data were charted and subject to thematic analysis. The systematic mixed studies review employed a convergent qualitative synthesis design, and was conducted in five steps: formulating a review question, defining eligibility criteria, identifying sources of information, identifying and selecting studies, and appraising the quality of studies. Data were analyzed using thematic synthesis. The empirical mixed methods study employed a mixed methods convergent design, whereby participants completed a quantitative (n = 94) and qualitative component (n = 12). In the quantitative component, participants completed validated questionnaires assessing positive change (i.e., the Posttraumatic Growth Inventory) and predictors of positive change (i.e., the Subjective Experiences of Psychosis Scale, Brief COPE, Recovery Assessment Scale, Child and Youth/Adult Resilience Measure, and Multidimensional Scale for Perceived Social Support). In the qualitative component, participants partook in semi-structured interviews assessing why participants felt they came to receive services at an early intervention service; how they feel they changed following their FEP; and what they perceive facilitated such change. Quantitative data were analyzed using descriptive statistics and multiple regression, while qualitative data were analyzed using thematic analysis. Results: Findings across studies revealed that following FEP, participants (including persons with lived experience of FEP themselves as well as their families and friends) experienced positive change at the individual level (e.g., developing a stronger sense of self, improved mental health, etc.), interpersonal level (e.g., improving relationships with others) and spiritual/religious level (e.g., experiencing greater spirituality). These changes were facilitated by factors and processes at the personal level (e.g., coping, experiencing personal recovery, engaging in spirituality, etc.), relational or social level (e.g., social support, etc.), contextual level (e.g., through receiving mental health services, etc.), as well as by processes unrelated to FEP (e.g., normative developmental experiences). Conclusions: A FEP may lead to perceptions of positive change among persons themselves, their families and friends. These findings validate the experiences of persons who have experienced positive change as a result of their experience of FEP, and can inform the delivery of positive, hopeful, strengths-based services to persons experiencing FEP. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ashok Malla</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Srividya Iyer</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw82m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jr136</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychiatry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0r9676053"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Impact of folate and homocysteine metabolism disturbances on brain biochemistry and cognitive function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bahous, Renata</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le folate est crucial pour le fonctionnement du cerveau et le métabolisme de l'homocystéine et de la méthionine (incluant les réactions de méthylation). Les perturbations du métabolisme du folate peuvent être d'origine génétique ou nutritionnelle. En Amérique du Nord et en Europe, une grande proportion d'individus porte des déficiences génétiques affectant le métabolisme de l'acide folique tel que dans le locus MTHFR (677C&gt;T), qui code pour la méthylènetétrahydrofolate réductase. Ce polymorphisme induit une déficience modérée en MTHFR ainsi que de l'hyperhomocystéinémie (HHcy). Une autre variante fréquente dans la population se trouve dans le locus de la méthionine synthase réductase ou  MTRR (MTRR 66A&gt;G). Notre laboratoire a créé et caractérisé des souris avec une mutation de Mthfr ou Mtrr, respectivement, qui constituent de bons modèles pour les variants humains, avec l'HHcy et les symptômes cliniques qui y sont associés. En utilisant ces modèles, nous avons démontré que les perturbations dans le métabolisme du folate peuvent induire des perturbations dans le métabolisme de la choline, étant donné que ces deux voies métaboliques ont en commun la reméthylation de l'homocystéine en méthionine.  Nous avons préalablement démontré que des souris âgées de 3 mois avec des mutations de Mtrr (Mtrrgt/gt) ont un trouble de mémoire. Comme premier objectif de cette thèse, nous avons examiné les conséquences d'une carence en Mtrr dans le cortex et l'hippocampe de jeunes souriceaux mâles et avons observé des perturbations du métabolisme de l'acétylcholine. D'autre part, en Amérique du Nord, les céréales sont fortifiées en acide folique depuis deux décennies. Par surcroît, la consommation de suppléments vitaminés s'est considérablement accrue. C'est particulièrement fréquent pour les femmes planifiant une grossesse, qui en consomment dix fois plus que la dose recommandée. Ceci justifie les préoccupations au sujet d'une consommation excessive d'acide folique. Pour le second objectif, nous avons donc examiné l'effet de la consommation d'une diète riche en acide folique durant la grossesse, pour des souris femelles du type sauvage, sur le développement du cerveau et la mémoire de leur progéniture. Nous avons montré, chez ces souris, qu'une diète trop riche en acide folique induit une pseudo-carence en MTHFR chez les mères et souriceaux ainsi que des perturbations dans le métabolisme de la choline et des groupes méthyl. De plus, cette diète provoque des troubles de mémoire pour la progéniture, un retard de croissance chez les embryons et perturbe le développement du cerveau. Dans la population vieillissante, des  niveaux insuffisants de folate ainsi que des niveaux élevés d'homocystéine sont communs et sont considérés comme des facteurs de risque pour la neurodégénérescence et des détériorations cognitives, dont particulièrement la maladie d'Alzheimer (AD). Dans un troisième objectif, nous avons utilisé des souris âgées et déficientes en Mthfr (hétérozygotes), nourries d'une diète appauvrie en acide folique afin de comprendre comment les perturbations du métabolisme du folate peuvent contribuer à la neurodégénérescence et aux troubles de mémoires. Nous avons évalué la mémoire de ces souris à l'âge de 8 mois et 10 mois.  Nous avons démontré qu'à 10 mois, ces souris ont un trouble de mémoire à court terme, des perturbations du métabolisme de la choline dans le cortex ainsi que des dérèglements des gènes impliqués dans la transmission synaptique ainsi que des modifications epigénétiques. Les données de cette thèse suggèrent que des dérangements du métabolisme du folate, qu'elles soient d'origine génétiques et/ou nutritionnelles, peuvent avoir des conséquences défavorables sur la biochimie du cerveau et la cognition à tous les stades de vie  (développement, jeunesse ou vieillissement) et qu'une dose optimale de folate permet un fonctionnement adéquat du cerveau.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Folate is a B vitamin that plays an essential role in normal brain/cognitive function and homocysteine/methionine (methyl) metabolism. Disturbances in folate metabolism can be either genetic or dietary. In North America and Europe, there is a high proportion of individuals that have genetic deficiencies in enzymes involved in the metabolism of folate, such as methylene-tetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR 677C&gt;T) that results in mild MTHFR deficiency and hyperhomocysteinemia (HHcy), and methionine synthase reductase (MTRR 66A&gt;G). The Rozen laboratory developed and characterized MTHFR-deficient and MTRR-deficient mice, respectively, that are good models of human HHcy and associated disorders. Using these mouse models, we have shown that disturbances in folate metabolism can result in disturbances in choline metabolites, since choline and folate metabolism intersect at the remethylation of homocysteine to methionine. It was previously shown that at 3 months of age, Mtrrgt/gt mice have memory impairment. In the first objective, we examined the consequence of Mtrr deficiency in young male mice in the cortex and hippocampus and showed disturbances in acetylcholine metabolism. Since the mid-90's, grains and cereals have been fortified with folic acid in North America and there has been an increased consumption of vitamin supplements. This has led to higher folate intake in some segments of the general population, particularly in women of childbearing age, with some concerns about too much folate.  In a second objective, we examined the effects of a high folate diet in wild-type female mice during pregnancy on offspring brain development and memory. We showed that high folate intake during pregnancy resulted in pseudo-MTHFR deficiency in mothers and offspring, and disturbances in choline/methyl metabolism. Offsping had memory impairment and embryos showed growth delay and altered brain development. In the aging population, low folate and elevated levels of homocysteine are common and are considered risk factors for neurodegeneration and cognitive decline, particularly in Alzheimer's disease (AD). In a third objective, we used aged MTHFR heterozygote mice fed a low folate diet to provide further insight into the mechanisms by which disturbances in folate metabolism (dietary and genetic) affect the aging brain and cognitive function. Memory was assessed in these mice at 8 and 10 months of age and we showed that 10-month-old mice had short-term memory impairment, altered choline metabolism in the cortex, minor disturbances in genes involved in synaptic transmission and epigenetic modifications.  The data from this thesis suggest that folate metabolism disturbances, genetic and/or dietary can have adverse consequences on brain biochemistry and cognition in all periods of life (development, young and aging) and that the brain requires an optimal dose of folate intake for proper function.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rima Rozen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm72m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r9676053</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kd029"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Conformal symmetries and variations of the spectral Zeta function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bachrachas Peterburg, Janine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nous étudions deux problèmes de géométrie spectrale conforme; les propriétés conformes et les invariants conformes sont le théme unificateur de cette dissertation. Nous nous concentrons sur l'obtention des formules explicites, qui pourraient être utiles pour les calculs lors de l'étude d'exemples spécifiques. Premièrement, nous étudions les symétries conformes des opérateurs (conformément covariants) Yamabe et Paneitz, où nos formules explicites récupèrent et complètent les résultats correspondants dans la littérature existante. Deuxièmement, nous étudions la deuxième variation de la fonction Zêta spectrale par rapport aux perturbations conformes de la métrique sur les sphères, où nous dérivons également des formules explicites, qui peuvent être utilisées pour étudier l'extrémalité de la métrique ronde pour cette fonctionnelle.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>We study two problems in conformal spectral geometry; conformal properties and conformal invariants are the unifying theme in this dissertation. We focus on obtaining explicit formulas, that could be useful for computations when studying specific examples. First, we study conformal symmetries of the (conformally covariant) Yamabe and Paneitz operators, where our explicit formulas recover and complement the corresponding results in the existing literature. Second, we study the second variation of the spectral Zeta function with respect to conformal perturbations of the metric on spheres, where we also derive explicit formulas, that can be used to study extremality of the round metric for this functional.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Niky Kamran</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Dmitry Jakobson</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r542j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kd029</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics and Statistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128d31r"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identity in relationships: Its development and role in daily life</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Auger, Emilie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les relations interpersonnelles occupent une place importante au cœur de nos vies. Cependant, maintenir des relations significatives, satisfaisantes et durables peut s'avérer un réel défi. En effet, nous devons souvent affronter des situations difficiles et faire des sacrifices afin de les maintenir. Or, certaines personnes perçoivent leur relation comme une partie importante de qui elles sont. Cette représentation constitue une force motivationnelle importante qui favorise l'engagement de ces individus envers la relation en situation d'adversité. Malgré son importance, les raisons pour lesquelles les individus viennent à développer un fort sentiment d'identification à l'endroit d'une relation demeurent largement méconnues. Plusieurs théories et études en psychologie sociale suggèrent que se sentir compris est essentiel, car cette expérience nous permet de valider notre concept de soi (par ex., nos valeurs) et notre vision du monde. En m'appuyant sur ces travaux, je propose qu'une relation qui nous aide à mieux nous comprendre est plus susceptible de devenir un aspect central de notre identité. Cinq études, utilisant différentes méthodologies, suggèrent que se sentir compris amène les individus à percevoir leur relation comme une partie importante de leur identité. Les résultats de l'étude 1 ont révélé que les individus perçoivent une personne comme étant plus identifiée à sa relation si elle se sent fortement comprise par son partenaire. L'étude 2 visait à examiner l'association entre le fait de sentir compris et l'identification à une relation à travers le temps. Les résultats ont démontré que se sentir compris par son partenaire amoureux est lié à l'identification à la relation 8 mois plus tard. Cependant, se sentir accepté et apprécié par son partenaire n'était pas lié à l'identification de la même façon. L'objectif de l'étude 3 était de manipuler de façon expérimentale le sentiment d'être compris par un partenaire amoureux. Afin de manipuler ce sentiment, j'ai eu recours à l'heuristique de disponibilité, soit la tendance des individus à former un jugement en se basant sur facilité avec laquelle certains exemples viennent en tête. Les résultats ont révélé que plus il était difficile pour les participants de se rappeler des situations où ils se sont sentis compris, moins ces derniers rapportaient être identifiés à leur relation, car ils se sentaient moins compris. Les études 4 et 5 visaient à reproduire ces résultats au sein d'un autre type de relation : l'amitié. Les résultats ont démontré que se sentir compris par un ami accroît l'identification envers la relation d'amitié. Enfin, l'étude 6 visait à démontrer que s'identifier à une relation est associée à des répercussions importantes dans la vie quotidienne. En effet, les résultats ont révélé que plus les individus étaient identifiés à leur relation de couple, plus ils étaient susceptibles de protéger la confiance générale qu'ils entretenaient envers celle-ci, et ce, malgré la présence de conflits et de déceptions. Bref, l'ensemble de ces études suggèrent que les relations dans lesquelles on se sent compris sont plus susceptibles de devenir centrales à notre identité, ce qui revêt une grande importance lorsque vient le moment de surmonter les défis du quotidien.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Close relationships are an essential aspect of our existence. However, maintaining meaningful, satisfactory, and long-lasting relationships can be challenging. Indeed, we often face difficult situations and make sacrifices in order to maintain them. Recent research suggests that for some individuals, their relationship may become centrally important to who they are (i.e., those high in relationship identification) and this helps them meet relationship challenges as they arise. Despite its importance for relationship maintenance, the reasons why individuals come to see their relationship as a core part of who they are have been largely unexplored. What types of relational experiences can change how the self is perceived in relation to a romantic partner or a friend? Theory and research in social psychology suggest that interpersonal understanding is critical, as it allows us to validate ourselves and worldviews. Consistent with this, I theorize that intimate interactions in which one feels understood may meet epistemic needs, which in turn may foster identification. That is, I propose that feeling understood by a romantic partner or a friend is a specific social experience essential to building a strong relational identity. In 5 studies using experimental, survey, and longitudinal methods, I examined whether understanding fosters identification with a specific relationship. In Study 1, I used a person-perception paradigm and found that participants perceived someone as more identified with their romantic relationship when partner understanding was high and partner caring was low rather than the reverse (low understanding, high caring). Study 2 extended these results by examining people in romantic relationships longitudinally. High levels of felt understanding predicted increased identification over time. I also examined the importance of feeling cared for and accepted, and showed that understanding was uniquely linked to relationship identification. Studies 3–5 experimentally manipulated felt understanding. Using the ease of retrieval paradigm, Study 3 revealed that romantically-involved participants assigned to recall 9 instances of partner understanding, relative to those who were assigned to recall only 3 instances, perceived the task to be more difficult, which led them to feel less understood and less identified with their relationship. Study 4 extended these results to friendships: Participants reported being more identified with their friendships when it was easy (vs. difficult) to recall instances in which their friend understood them. Study 5 replicated this finding using a more direct manipulation of perceived understanding: Participants visualized a close friend being understanding or not. As expected, perceived understanding affected relationship identification. Finally, I provide evidence that relationship identification is important in daily life: Highly identified individuals did not allow daily negative events to impact their overall feelings about their relationship. Taken together, these studies provide compelling evidence that understanding increases relationship identification, and this, in turn, is important for coping with everyday challenges couples experience. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Lydon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m419h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128d31r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53wz12w"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Temporal representation learning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bacon, Pierre-Luc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse, je propose l'idée que le problème d'apprentissage de bonnes abstractions temporelles est intimement lié à un problème d'apprentissage de représentation que j'appelle "apprentissage temporel de représentation". Ce choix de terminologie vise à rappeler le fait que le temps est un aspect indissociable d'un système d'apprentissage plongé dans son expérience d'apprentissage avec son environnement. La réconciliation de la notion du temps avec celle de l'apprentissage mène à des solutions qui s'intègrent mieux dans un paradigme d'apprentissage continuel (Ring, 1991). Basé sur ce principe, je propose l'architecture option-critic pour construire des abstractions temporelles bout-en-bout (end-to-end) dans le cadre théorique des options (Sutton et al., 1999a). De plus, reconnaître l'importance du temps rend inévitable le fait que l'apprentissage doit être le plus efficace possible lorsque soumis à des limites en resources. Je développe cette idée dans le cadre de la notion de rationalité limitée (Simon, 1957) et montre comment elle peut être intégrée dans l'architecture option-critic pour apprendre de meilleures options. Je montre également qu'apprendre des options du point de vue de la rationalité limitée est lié au problème de construction de bons préconditionneurs de matrices en algèbre numérique linéaire. Je démontre cette idée formellement en établissant que les méthodes à pas multiples (multi-step) en apprentissage par renforcement ainsi que les options ont en commun une structure mathématique dont les origines proviennent du concept de matrix splitting de Varga (1962).</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Throughout this thesis, I develop the idea that the problem of learning good temporal abstractions in reinforcement learning is intimately tied to a kind of representation learning problem that I call "temporal representation learning". This choice of terminology is meant to highlight the fact that time is an indissociable aspect of learning systems experiencing their environment. Reconciling the notion of time with learning leads us to solution methods that better fit into a continual learning paradigm (Ring, 1991). Based on this principle, I propose the option-critic architecture for constructing temporal abstractions end-to-end, in the options framework (Sutton et al., 1999a). Furthermore, acknowledging the importance of time renders inevitable the fact that learning should be as efficient as possible when facing limited resources. I express this idea in the bounded rationality framework of Simon (1957) and extend the option-critic architecture accordingly to learn better options. I also establish a connection between the bounded rationality perspective on options discovery and the problem of finding good matrix preconditioners in numerical linear algebra. I show this point formally by exposing a common mathematical structure between multi-step RL methods and options using matrix splitting theory (Varga, 1962).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Doina Precup</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rr14p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wz12w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An296x149v"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Information Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comparison between a Chinese bibliometric database and the Web of Science in terms of authors and their output</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shu, Fei</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis I compare the Web of Science (WoS) with a Chinese bibliometric database in terms of authors and their output, and address the issues that could interpret the results. This is done in three chapters, constituting a comparison between two bibliometric databases, a methodological contribution, and an investigation on the monetary reward policies in China.In the first chapter I compare Web of Science (WoS) with a Chinese bibliometric database in terms of authors and their output, demonstrate the extent of the overlap between the two groups of Chinese scientific elites in both international and Chinese bibliometric databases, and determine how different disciplines may affect this overlap. The results of this study indicate that Chinese bibliometric databases, or a combination of WoS and Chinese bibliometric databases, should be used to evaluate Chinese research performance except in few disciplines in which Chinese research performance could be assessed using WoS only.Since WoS adopts the journal classification system while a paper classification system is applied in Chinese bibliometric databases, in the second chapter I compare the science classification systems at the journal level and paper level for the same data set using the same classification scheme. Results show almost half of papers may be misclassified in the current journal classification system, which could methodologically explain the difference found in the first chapter. In the third chapter I investigate the China's monetary reward policies and present the landscape of the cash-per-publication reward policy in China and reveal its trend since the late 1990s. Since the monetary reward policies may influence Chinese scholars' publication activities reported in the first chapter. The investigation could explain why the difference found in the first chapter exist by analyzing the impact of science policies on Chinese scholars' publishing activities.In summary, this thesis presents three original research papers that advance knowledge in bibliometrics and scholarly communication. This thesis also lays the necessary foundation for further study on research evaluation, classification of science, and science policies. The most notable implication for the future research is to investigate the impact of metrics-based science policies, which focus on outcomes such as number of publications and rankings, on research output, either in China or worldwide.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse porte sur une étude de la production scientifique des chercheurs chinois en comparant les données disponibles dans le Web of Science (WoS) et dans une base de données chinoise. Dans le but d'identifier les problèmes qui pourraient survenir lors de l'interprétation des résultats, cette thèse est organisée en trois chapitres où nous détaillons les différentes caractéristiques des deux bases de données utilisées lors de notre recherche, nous précisons l'apport méthodologique de cette étude et nous analysons les politiques de récompenses monétaires octroyées pour le travail scientifique en Chine. Le premier chapitre explique les différences entre le WoS et la base de données chinoise en utilisant les variables des auteurs et de leurs production. Nous y exposons l'étendue du chevauchement entre deux groupes de chercheurs élites et la manière dont les pratiques disciplinaires déterminent ce chevauchement. Les résultats de cette étude indiquent que l'usage des bases de données bibliométriques chinoises ou une combinaison du WoS et de bases de données chinoises constituer un moyen plus fiable pour l'évaluation de la recherche dans le contexte chinois. Des exemptions peuvent se faire dans le cas de quelques disciplines pour lesquelles l'usage du WoS semble approprié. Dans le chapitre 2, nous nous intéressons aux différences entre les systèmes de classification scientifique du WoS (fait à partir des revues) et de la base de données chinoise (fait à partir des articles). En comparant un même ensemble de données dans l'une et l'autre base de données, nous arrivons à la conclusion que le système fondé sur la classification des revues (WoS) génère une classification erronée pour près de la moitié des articles, ce qui explique – en termes méthodologiques – les différences rapportées dans le premier chapitre.Le troisième chapitre présente une étude des politiques des récompenses monétaires et de la politique de récompense par publication (cash-per-publication) et un portrait général de la politique monétaire mise en place en Chine dans les années 1990. Considérant que les récompenses monétaires peuvent déterminer les pratiques de publication des chercheurs analysées dans le premier chapitre, nous étudions les résultats obtenus lors des évaluations de l'impact des politiques scientifiques sur les pratiques de publication des chercheurs chinois. En résumé, cette thèse présente trois articles de recherche originaux qui contribuent à l'avancement des recherches en bibliométrie et en communication savante. Cette thèse contribue également à la poursuite des études sur l'évaluation de la recherche, la classification des sciences et les politiques scientifiques. L'implication la plus notable pour la recherche future est d'étudier l'impact des politiques scientifiques basées sur les métriques qui se concentrent sur les résultats tels que le nombre de publications et les classements, ou encore sur les retombées de la recherche, en Chine ou ailleurs dans le monde.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Charles Antoine Julien</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Vincent Lariviere</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784p04m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x149v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Information Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amw22v785z"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A qualitative exploration of the experiences of general education teachers in the transition planning process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sobel, Hailey</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The transition from school to assuming adult roles is difficult for many, but individuals with disabilities often face additional challenges during this time.  A variety of stakeholders are involved in helping students during the transition process and teachers, in particular, guide students through many transitions.  Using a phenomenological approach, this study explored teacher perspectives and understanding of the transition planning process (TPP).  Thirteen elementary and high school general education teachers completed questionnaires and participated in semi-structured interviews.  The responses to their questionnaires were explored using descriptive analyses while interview data were examined using thematic analysis. The results focus on teacher perceptions in three overarching areas: skills important for transition planning, roles of stakeholders, and the larger policy context. The themes that emerged highlighted the skills deemed important for transition planning: interpersonal, academic, coping, learning, and self-determination skills. Themes related to the role of stakeholders underscored the notions of stakeholders as providers of knowledge, the importance of interactions between stakeholders, and involvement in procedural aspects of the TPP. The larger policy context revolved around a discussion of legislation, procedural components of the TPP, and the timing of transition planning. An examination of the barriers and supports to the TPP revealed challenges that elementary and middle school teachers encounter and how stakeholders such as psychologists and administrators can support teacher involvement in the TPP. Recommendations for practice, policy, and future research will be presented that center around resources and training for teachers, starting transition planning earlier in a child's education, and utilizing community resources.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La transition de l'école à la vie active est difficile pour de nombreux individus, mais pour ceux qui sont en situation d'handicap, il y a souvent des défis supplémentaires durant cette période. Divers intervenants sont impliqués dans ce processus de transition, et les enseignants, en particulier, guident les étudiants à travers de nombreuses transitions. En utilisant une approche phénoménologique, cette étude à explorer les perspectives des enseignants, ainsi que leur compréhension de la préparation d'un plan de transition (PPT). Treize enseignants des niveaux primaires et secondaires ont rempli des questionnaires et ont participé à des entretiens semi-directifs. Les réponses aux questionnaires ont été explorées à l'aide d'analyses descriptives, tandis que les données des entretiens ont été examinées à l'aide d'une analyse thématique. Les résultats se concentrent sur les perceptions des enseignants dans trois domaines généraux: les compétences importantes pour la planification de la transition, les rôles des intervenants et le contexte politique plus large. Les thèmes clés de l'étude ont soulevé les compétences jugées importantes pour la planification de la transition: les compétences interpersonnelles, académiques, d'adaptation, d'apprentissage et d'autodétermination. Les thèmes liés au rôle des parties prenantes ont souligné l'importance des parties prenantes en tant que fournisseurs de connaissances ; l'importance des interactions entre les parties prenantes; ainsi que la participation des intervenants aux aspects procéduraux du PPT. Le contexte politique plus globale était axé sur une discussion de la législation, des composantes procédurales du PPT et du calendrier de la planification de la transition. L'examination des obstacles et des soutiens PPT ont révélé des défis auxquels sont confrontés les enseignants du primaire et du secondaire, et la façon dont les intervenants, tels que les psychologues et les administrateurs, peuvent soutenir la participation des enseignants au PPT. Des recommandations pour la pratique, la politique et la recherche seront présentées et organisées autour de ressources et de programmes de formation pour les enseignants; de la création d'un PPT plus tôt dans l'éducation de l'enfant; et de l'utilisation de ressources communautaires.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tara Flanagan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tr643.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v785z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak930c0657"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Correlator and calibration for the Canadian hydrogen intensity mapping experiment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mena, Juan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse décrit la conception, construction et caractérisation de l'expérience CHIME (Canadian Hydrogen Intensity Mapping Experiment), un radiotélescope interférométrique qui mesurera l'émission des radiations à 21 cm provenant des atomes d'hydrogène neutres afin d'étudier l'histoire de l'expansion de l'univers et la nature de l'énergie sombre. Nous discutons premièrement de la motivation scientifique du télescope CHIME, sa conception et caractérisation. Nous présentons ensuite le 'CHIME pathfinder' qui est un prototype qui a servi de preuve de concept pour le développement du hardware et des techniques d'étalonnage et d'analyse des données du CHIME. Nous décrivons également le corrélateur du CHIME, qui est le plus grand corrélateur radio qui a été construit à ce jour en permettant le calcul en temps réel des tous les produits entre les 2048 entrées du télescope sur une bande passante de 400 MHz. Nous ensuite décrivons le système 'ICE', qui est le matériel et le logiciel spécialiséconçu pour effectuer l'acquisition de données, la séparation des fréquences, la réorganisation des données et leur transmission au corrélateur. Nous demontrons ensuite que le corrélateur satisfait tous les requis de l'expérience CHIME. L'un des défis les plus importants de CHIME vient de l'étalonnage précis qui est requis pour détecter les signaux de 21 cm en présence des sources astrophysiques qui sont plusieurs ordres de grandeur plus lumineuses. Nous avons utilisé le pathfinder comme une plateforme d'essaipour développer plusieurs techniques d'étalonnage des récepteurs et d'étalonnage numerique du corrélateurAfin de satisfaire les prérequis de CHIME. Nous discutons les prérequis d'étalonnage de CHIME et présentons les différentes techniques d'étalonnage, l'instrumentation, les performances actuelles avec pathfinder, et le développement vers la mise en œuvre du système d'étalonnage de CHIME.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the design, construction, and characterization of the Canadian Hydrogen Intensity Mapping Experiment (CHIME), a transit radio interferometer that will measure the emission of 21 cm radiation from neutral hydrogen in order to study the expansion history of the universe and probe the nature of dark energy. We discuss the scientific motivation of CHIME, followed by a description of the telescope design and characteristics. The CHIME pathfinder, which is a hardware, calibration, and data analysis proof-of-concept for CHIME is also presented. The CHIME correlator processes 2048 inputs across 400 MHz of bandwidth and it is the largest radio correlator that has been built. We have developed a general purpose hardware, firmware, and software framework -the 'ICE' system- that has been specialized to implement the data acquisition, F-engine, and the networking engine of this correlator. We describe the design of the ICE system, its use for the CHIME correlator, and demonstrate that the correlator complies with all the requirements for the experiment. A major challenge of CHIME comes from the calibration needed in order to detect the 21 cm signal in the presence of astrophysical foregrounds that are many orders of magnitude brighter. We have used the pathfinder as a test-bed to develop a number of receiver-gain and digital calibration techniques in order to meet the stringent calibration requirements for full CHIME. We discuss the calibration requirements and present the different calibration strategies, the instrumentation, the current performance on the pathfinder, and the development towards the implementation for full CHIME.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Matthew Adam Dobbs</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236446n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c0657</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9z9032224"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Whole genome sequencing for mutation discovery in rare neurodevelopmental disorders</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poquerusse, Jessie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les développements récents dans le séquençage nouvelle génération (NGS) du génome ainsi que les outils de bioinformatique qui les accompagnent font que nous entrons une ère  de  progrès  rapide  en  recherche  sur  les  désordres  génétiques  rares.  Ici,  nous développons  un  workflow  pour  l'analyse  des  données  NGS  et  l'appliquons  pour chercher  les  mutations  pathogènes  dans  quatre  individus  atteints  d'une  maladie neurodéveloppementale  rare.  Une  liste  de  variantes  probables  pathogènes  a  été développée  pour  tout  individu.  Notre  workflow  et  trouvailles  permettent  d'avancer notre  recherche  en  analyse  fonctionnelle  des  mécanismes  pathogénétiques  de  la mutation.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Recent  developments  in  next  generation  sequencing  (NGS)  technologies  and  their accompanying  bioinformatic  tools  have  set  the  stage  for  an  era  of  unprecedented progress  in  research  on  rare  genetic  disorders.  Here,  we  develop  a  whole  genome sequencing workflow for the analysis of NGS data and apply it to search for pathogenic mutations in four individuals affected by rare neurodevelopmental disorders. A list of high confidence pathogenic variants  was finalized for all individuals. Our developed workflow  and  findings  pave  the  way  for  further  functional  analyses  of  the  brain developmental pathogenesis of the novel mutation(s).  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carl Ernst</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw899.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9032224</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>