<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429c39b"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The evaluation of SPECTMR registration error from the internal landmark matching technique</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lukban, Andrew F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In using the internal landmark matching technique for registering brain volumes from single photon emission computed tomography (SPECT) and magnetic resonance (MR) imaging, the resulting errors are different from similar registrations of positron emission tomography (PET) and MR volumes because of the anisotropic nature of SPECT's tomographic resolution. SPECT/MR registration errors are investigated with point simulation to allow a controlled study of the dependence of the translation and rotation errors on different factors. These factors include: the number of point pairs, m, the error in point pair homology (characterised by the FWHM of a 3-D Gaussian error envelope), and the configuration of the point sets (as they depend on their radius from their centroid). The results of this study are used to interpret the results from studies based on a 3-D brain phantom fitted with external fiducials to provide the basis for true registrations. It is found that the same error distributions may not be expected across ordinates. Based on the imaging capabilities of the sensors used in this study, (a) maximum translation errors or $ pm$2.1 mm in the anterior-posterior orientation are found to be a consequence of SPECT's anisotropic resolution and the brain's major axis in that orientation, and (b) rotation errors of about $ pm$2.1$ sp circ$ in the coronal plane are larger than in the transaxial because of the comparative dimensions in those planes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dean, G. W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956h99j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c39b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acv43p026h"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exploiting short-lived variables in superscalar processors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lozano, C. Luis Alfonso</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Modern superscalar processors use advanced features like dynamic scheduling and speculative execution to exploit fine-grain parallelism. In order to support these features, they use complex hardware mechanisms like reorder buffers, instructions windows and renaming buffers. In this thesis, we have made an observation about the use of these mechanisms: a significant number of program variables are short-lived in the sense that their whole live ranges occur entirely within the reorder buffer. Therefore, the values produced by these short-lived variables do not need to be written back (committed) to the register file. Based on this observation, we have proposed a compiler analysis, which we call short-live-range analysis, and a simple architecture feature to avoid the useless commits of the values generated by these short-lived variables. Moreover, we have proposed a new register allocation scheme to assign these variables to the locations provided for register renaming (rather than to the register file), thus decreasing the register pressure. We have implemented his hardware/software codesign scheme using the McCAT testbed and the simulation results show: (1) the short-live-range analysis and the proposed architecture feature can be successfully used to avoid the useless commit of instructions to the register files; (2) the above mechanism can reduce the number of write ports to the register files without affecting performance; (3) the allocation of short-lived variables to the locations provided by the register files without affecting performance; (3) the allocation of short-lived variables to the locations provided by the register renaming mechanism can significantly reduce the introduction of spill code and improve the overall performance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gao, Guang R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s2211.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p026h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acf95jd41c"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Study of neutrophil diapedesis across a bovine mammary epithelium in vitro</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lin, Yongqing</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bovine mastitis due to bacterial infection is one of the most costly diseases affecting the dairy industry. The polymorphonuclear neutrophils (PMNs) present in milk have a central protective role against invading pathogens, However, the manner by which PMNs traverse the secretory epithelia and the relationship between PMN diapedesis and the epithelial damage are unclear. This in vitro study investigated the process and rate of bovine PMN transepithelial migration. The bovine mammary epithelial cell line, MAC-T, formed a confluent monolayer with characteristic tight junctions, polarity and functional barrier to the dye trypan blue. In the first series of experiments, neutrophils were added into the upper compartment of the culture insert and stimulated to migrate across the epithelium in an apical-to-basal direction by the addition of Staphylococcus aureus to the lower compartment. Light and transmission electron microscopy revealed the following series of events for PMN transmigration: (1) adherence of PMNs to the surface of the epithelium; (2) projection of pseudopods toward the intercellular junction; (3) migration between adjacent epithelial cells; and (4) re-approximation of epithelial cell membranes and reformation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zhao, Xin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k014z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jd41c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neutrophils -- Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dairy cattle -- Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mastitis -- Immunological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zj792"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Glandular and gastrointestinal (GI) amyloidosis and the chemical nature of GI amyloid in alveolar hydatid cyst infected mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Weihua, 1965-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Patients with systemic amyloidosis frequently show gastrointestinal (GI) tract and adrenal gland involvement with amyloid. However, the evolution of amyloid-related pathological changes in humans is unknown. Conversely, although GI amyloidosis has been described in casein-stimulated mice, the chemical nature of the GI amyloid have not been carried out. Here we report studies on these and related aspects using alveolar hydatid cyst (AHC)-infected mouse model of reactive amyloidosis. Paraffin sections from the adrenal gland, stomach, small and large intestine were obtained from AHC-mice at different time period post-infection (p.i.) and stained with Congo red or immunohistochemically with antibodies against mouse AA amyloid (RAA) or bovine ubiquitin (RABU). The GI-amyloid was purified by column chromatography and analyzed. In the adrenal gland, amyloid deposits were first detected at 4 weeks p.i. in the cortical-medullary junction which then extended into the adrenal parenchyma. In the GI tract, submucosal blood vessels, the first site of amyloid deposition, became amyloidotic at 1 week p.i. With time, the amyloid deposits extended into the lamina propria of the mucosa. Ileum was the most severely affected region in the GI tract. Both RAA and RABU reacted specifically with the GI amyloid. Amyloid was purified by exclusion chromatography in 4M guanidine. The purified amyloid on Western blotting reacted with RAA and on N-terminal amino acid sequence analysis revealed homology with murine serum amyloid A$ sb2$ (SAA$ sb2$) indicating its derivation from SAA$ sb2.$ Both the similarities and the differences between the GI amyloid-related pathological changes in humans and mice are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ali-Kahn, Zafer</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956j003.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj792</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698959c"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Airway smooth muscle orientation using en-face dissection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lei, Min</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Airway smooth muscle (ASM) shortening is the key event leading to broncho-constriction. The degree of airway narrowing which occurs with ASM shortening is a function both of the mechanical properties of the airway wall as well as the angle of orientation of ASM. If ASM is oriented very obliquely, ASM shortening would in part be transduced to a change in airway length rather than airway narrowing. Previous reports have suggested that the angle of ASM orientation may be as high as 30$ sp circ.$ To measure ASM orientation we have developed a technique based on en-face dissection. The lungs from 4 cats and one human were fixed with 10% buffered formalin at 25 cmH$ sb2$O for 48 hrs. The airway generations 4 to 17 were dissected out from the left lower lobes. Each airway generation was individually embedded in paraffin from which 5$ mu$m thick serial sections were cut parallel to the airway long axis ("en-face") and stained with haematoxylin-phloxine-saffron. Each block yielded 3-5 sections in which the orientation of ASM nuclei relative to the airway long axis ($ theta$) was measured as an index of ASM orientation. $ theta$ was measured clockwise and counterclockwise to the short axis by using a digitizing tablet and a light microscope (X250) equipped with a drawing tube attachment. Inspection of the sections revealed extensive ASM crisscrossing without a homogeneous orientation. Between 29 and 102 nuclei were measured per generation. Although there was considerable variation within airway generations, $ theta$ clustered between $-$20$ sp circ$ and 10$ sp circ$ in all generations and did not vary significantly between generations in any of the subjects. When $ theta$ was converted to an acute angle without regard to sign($ Theta$), the mean angle was 12-13$ sp circ$ both in cat and the human lung. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chen, M. F.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Eidelman, D. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m887n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698959c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vd59v"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Forest clearance and lake water quality on the Canadian Shield</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lehmann, Renate</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Forest clearance can affect the levels of dissolved organic carbon (DOC), nutrient concentrations and algal biomass in streams, but the possible effect of these inputs on downstream lakes is usually surmised rather than demonstrated. To evaluate the effect of forest clearance on DOC and nutrient cycling in lakes, DOC, total phosphorus (TP), total nitrogen (TN) and chlorophyll (chl a) concentrations were measured in 47 Canadian Shield lakes in Quebec. Of these lakes, 25 were located in drainage basins that were partially clear-cut one to four years previously. In the disturbed sites, an uncut 20-m bufferstrip was left around the lakes and permanent water courses. To account for differences among the watersheds that are not related to forest harvesting, I also collected a series of catchment and morphometric variables (watershed area, lake area, drainage ratio, forest, wetland, and upstream lake area, watershed slope, water residence time and lake depth). Lake characteristics in undisturbed and disturbed watersheds were compared to determine if forest clearance has a detectable effect on the water quality of downstream lakes. Although comparisons of seasonal and monthly means of the water quality variables between disturbed and reference sites were inconclusive, likely because of high natural variability, the size of the clear-cut was significantly related to means of the water quality characteristics. DOC, TP, TN and chl a increased in lake water with the area of the clear-cuts when large portions of the watershed ($&gt;$50%) were cleared. The results of this study suggest that logging has an effect on water quality and even though a bufferstrip of twenty meters reduces this effect largely, it may not be enough to provide complete protection against the effects of logging activities.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peters, Robert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg514.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd59v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Clearcutting -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Laurentian Mountains</dc:subject><dc:subject>Water quality -- Québec (Province) -- Laurentian Mountains</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053j22d"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structure-function analysis of TIF4631, the large subunit of the yeast cap binding protein complex</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Han Sung</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The cap binding protein complex (elF-4F) has been shown to play an important role in the regulation of gene expression. The cloning of the genes encoding the large subunit of eIF-4F in yeast and mammals (p150 and p220 respectively) have provided the opportunity to characterize this little understood polypeptide. In this study, two functions of the yeast homolog, TIF4631 (p150), were analyzed: (1) complex formation with eIF-4E, and (2) RNA binding. Interaction with eIF-4E was found to require the presence of an internal region of p150 surrounding an evolutionarily conserved 9 amino acid motif. The RNA-binding capacity of p150 was also demonstrated by UV-induced crosslinking and by binding to a poly-uridylic acid resin. Deletion analysis identified the presence of two RNA-binding domains, one within the N-terminal portion of the protein and the other immediately C-terminal to the eIF-4E binding region. A sequence resembling the RGG-box RNA binding motif was found in the N-terminal domain, whereas the internal RNA binding domain is localized around the previously identified RS-motif-like region.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sonenberg, Nahum</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w37n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053j22d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A707959750"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of winter flounder (Pleuronectes americanus) for aquaculture : effects of weaning, food type, density and temperature on growth and survival of wild and laboratory-reared juveniles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Gillian W. Y. (Gillian Wai Yien)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Winter flounder, Pleuronectes americanus, is being developed for aquaculture in Atlantic Canada. Since larval culture has been successful, research can now address problems at the juvenile stage such as weaning, diet and optimal growth environment. Weaning, a critical stage in culture of any flatfish species, is the switch from live food to an artificial diet. In a three month study, I was able to wean wild young-of-the year winter flounder from live, cultured Artemia onto dry food. Specific growth rates and food conversion indicated the artificial diet was a better food source than Artemia. In a second study, I was able to wean recently-metamorphosed winter flounder reared in the laboratory, onto two artificial diets which differed in price and lipid content. There was no difference between the inexpensive salmonid starter diet and the more costly Nippai diet on growth and survival. In a third study, I examined the effects of temperature and density on wild year 0 and 1 winter flounder reared on dry salmonid diet. There was no effect of density on growth and survival over the ranges tested. Greatest growth occurred at 15$ sp circ$C, although survival was highest at ambient temperature.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Litvak, Matthew K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tr41s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/707959750</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Winter flounder</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fish culture</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acf95jd42n"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of turbulence with a wind profiler</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leblanc, Sylvain G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In Doppler radar analysis of the atmosphere the spectrum width is rarely used but it contains information about turbulence. Turbulence is not the only effect that contributes to the broadening of the spectrum. Another effect is the cross-beam wind, which can be dominant in broad-beam radars such as wind profilers. Once this effect is removed, the so-called residual width then serves as an indication of turbulence. A large snowstorm is used in this study for the computation of the residual width. Strong wind and wind shear were observed during the storm. The time-height pattern of residual width bears a close resemblance to that of wind shear. This supports the interpretation of the residual width as being an indication of turbulence induced by wind shear. Energy dissipation rates are also estimated for the snowstorm. In some regions values as large as 800 cm$ rm sp2 s sp{-3}$ are observed. These are large, but within the range of what has been reported by others. The same techniques were applied to the study of clear-air turbulence to relate radar reflectivity with turbulence.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rogers, R. R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m397p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jd42n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fq960"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les tensiometres pour l'irrigation en milieu tourbeaux</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lebeau, Benoit</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Water management for the irrigation of containerized production remains a task reserved to a highly qualified personnel. Without proper instruments to determine the actual water needs, nursery crops can face growth losses of 20 to 30%. Reviewing the different methods that are used in field production, tensiometer have shown the greatest potential of adaptation to potted plants. Tests on the utilization of tensiometer were realized on two peat-vermiculite substrates, using two types of porous cup (1 bat--standard flow and 1 bar--high flow). The instruments were tested while permanently fixed in the growing medium, and temporarily fixed for three hours in the growing medium. The results show that the instruments give excellent measurements for normal condition of growth, requiring saturation level between 50 and 100%, and that for both mode of operation. Preferably, the choice of the instrument should be based on the hydraulic characteristics of the substrate. Little difference has been found using both instrument in the substrate 1, but in substrate 2 however, the high flow porous cups have given better response. The high flow cups have higher porosity and bigger pores that suit better substrate 2, which is made of coarser particles.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barrington, Suzelle</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301345h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fq960</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Horticultural crops -- Water requirements</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil moisture -- Measurement</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bn806"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Age-related changes in a compartmentalized motoneuron pool-muscle complex in rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Latham, Nancy K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To determine if the form of muscle compartmentalization, in which a deep region of oxidative fibres surrounded by a superficial region of low-oxidative fibres, is maintained in old Sprague-Dawley rats at the 50% survival age (n = 8; 24-26 mo) compared to weight-matched controls (n = 14; 5-7 mo), isometric contractile properties, muscle histochemistry and the motoneuron pool were examined for medial gastrocnemius (MG) using its two nerve branches (NBr). Old muscle showed atrophy, less force and slower contractions. Although the cross-sectional area of the oxidative region did not change, the percentage of its oxidative fibres increased (myosin ATPase). The unique soma size distribution of horseradish peroxidase-labelled motoneurons which innervate the oxidative region was maintained in old animals, despite atrophy. Findings suggest that this form of muscle compartmentalization is maintained in animals at the 50% survival age. Further, age-related changes in muscle function reflect the morphological changes of the muscle fibres and innervating motoneurons.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Noven, Sharyn Vanden</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x817.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn806</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amw22v7603"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Observer problems in multifractals : the example of rain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Larnder, Chris</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Non-linear phenomena exhibit extreme variability over a wide range of scales and intensities. In multifractal processes, variability increases algebraically with resolution: as we approach the small scale limit, we develop a highly singular field of diverging and vanishing densities. Even over a finite range of scales, the variability can readily exceed the finite signal-response range capabilities of measuring devices. In face of such extreme behavior, one can no longer consider the problems of observing such processes as "merely" experimental ones. Detectors will rarely be capable of handling the full dynamic range of intensities, missing either the extreme events or the small input signal. Therefore it is of fundamental importance to understand what multifractals "look like" when observed through a detector having only a finite dynamic range. Limitations on the observable dynamic range affect intensities at nearby scales, breaking the scale invariance and imposing a limit on the range of scales over which scaling behaviour can be observed. A simple model of a threshold-type problem, in which a detector has a (finite) minimum detectable signal level, is solved in the multifractal framework. Results include a breaking of the scaling symmetry for scales particularly close to the scale corresponding to the resolution of the detector. The scaling improves as we as we degrade further to lower resolutions. It also improves as we move to higher moment statistics. Rainfall time series from time scales of 180 years to 5 minutes are analysed, revealing, in particular, a break in the spectral scaling behavior near 2.4 hours. Some of the theoretical results are used to show that this break is likely to be caused by instrumental problems at low signal intensities. The correct scaling behavior is successfully recovered from the low resolution information.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lovejoy, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq22h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v7603</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4x51hm28n"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanistic study on toxicity of positively-charged liposomes containing stearylamine to blood : use of carboxymethyl chitin to reduce this toxicity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lam, Robert Tai-Thinh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Toxic effects have been reported for positively-charged liposomes containing stearylamine (SA-liposomes). We have observed that hemolysis and turbidity changes in native plasma were induced by the presence of SA-liposomes. In order to study the mechanism of the SA-liposomes toxicity to blood, we have examined the interaction of SA-liposomes with erythrocyte ghosts (EG) by resonance energy transfer for the lipid mixing and by Terbium/Dipicolinate (Tb/DPA) assay for the mixing of aqueous contents. The results demonstrate that SA-liposomes and EG, after aggregation, have a tendency to mix their lipid before mixing of their internal contents. This interaction was reduced by the presence of 10$ sp{-3}$ or 10$ sp{-2}$% (w/v) carboxymethyl chitin (CMC). We have also explored the properties of the association of SA-liposomes with CMC, using fluorescein labeled CMC (Flu-CMC). The polarization value of Flu-CMC increased upon SA-liposomes binding, the amount of Flu-CMC on the liposome surfaces increased with increase in the concentration of phospholipid and SA, and it decreased by 20-40% in the presence of 10 mM Ca$ sp{2+}.$ These results indicate that association of SA-liposomes to CMC reduces the propensity of SA-liposomes to interact with blood components and this association is due to predominantly electrostatic interactions and possibly some hydrophobic interactions between SA-liposomes and CMC. Finally, using the resonance energy transfer assay, preliminary results indicate that there is lipid mixing between SA-liposomes and platelets. This is not inhibited by phagocytosis inhibitors such as EDTA, 2,4-dinitrophenol with iodoacetate and cytochalasin B, suggesting that the lipid mixing is not accompanied by phagocytosis of SA-liposomes by platelets.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nishiya, Takako</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268725d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hm28n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Toxicology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g471d"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pubescence in red clover : its inheritance and its relationship to potato leafhopper resistance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kusmiyati, Florentina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Potato leafhopper causes considerable damage in red clover. The main objectives of this study were to clarify the inheritance of pubescence and to evaluate the relationship between pubescence and potato leafhopper (Empoasca fabae (Harris) resistance. Thirteen red clover clones of diverse origin, including both pubescent and non-pubescent types were used as parents. A series of crosses were made in all possible combinations among the 13 parental clones. Seedlings of F$ sb1$ progeny and stem cuttings from parents were planted in the field in the summer of 1993 in a randomized complete block design. Based on the results, the inheritance of pubescence type on red clover stems, petioles and abaxial leaf surfaces was best explained individually by two-locus models showing dominant and recessive interaction. A two locus model with recessive epistasis was proposed for pubescence on stipules and basal internodes, but there were a number of crosses that deviated from expected ratios. There was quantitative variation for trichome density on red clover and it appeared to be inherited as a quantitative trait. Based on mid-parent offspring regression, the heritability estimates of trichome density on petioles, stems, abaxial leaf surfaces, and adaxial leaf surfaces were 0.16, 0.77, 0.50 and 0.48, respectively. Pubescence was apparently associated with potato leafhopper resistance. Visual ratings of feeding injury, the numbers of leafhopper nymphs per plant and the numbers of nymphs per gram of dry plant material were higher on glabrous plants than on pubescent plants. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mather, D. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f342f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g471d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Red clover -- Disease and pest resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trichomes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Empoasca fabae</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290c614"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Segmental and heterosegmental effects of repeated transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (TENS) on voluntary motor functions in spastic hemiparetic subjects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kim, Yu Kyung</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We conducted two studies to examine the changes in voluntary motor functions in spastic hemiparetic muscles, their relationship to clinical spasticity and the reliability of these measures, as well as to investigate the effects of transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (TENS) on spasticity and voluntary motor functions in hemiparetic subjects. In our first study, the alterations in voluntary motor functions in the upper and lower limb muscles of spastic subjects were delineated through a comparative study with age-matched controls. Moreover, the test-retest reliability was evaluated for each measure. We noted a marked reduction in peak isometric torques, associated with a tendency towards an increase in antagonist co-contraction ratios for all the muscles tested in these spastic subjects. Of interest is that the elbow flexion torque was inversely related to the clinical severity of spasticity--especially that of its upper extremity score. Furthermore, the peak torque was the most reproducible measure. In our second study, the effects of 20 sessions of TENS applied to the radial nerve for 60 min every weekday over 4 weeks was investigated. In contrast to placebo stimulation, TENS produced a significant reduction in upper extremity spasticity after 4 weeks and a significant decrease in the tibialis anterior co-contraction ratio after 2 weeks of stimulation. Furthermore, 4 weeks of TENS, but not placebo stimulation, led to a significant improvement in elbow extension torque as compared with the control values in the majority (67%) of hemiparetic subjects. Such a reduction in spasticity and improvement in voluntary motor functions could have involved segmental reciprocal inhibitory mechanisms as well as non-segmental mechanisms via descending pathways.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mui-Chan, Christina</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t411h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c614</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gv75c"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Compensatory articulation in aphasia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kim, Jean H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Compensatory articulation was investigated in normal and brain-damaged individuals by comparing vowel production under normal and perturbed speaking conditions. The effects of fixed mandibular positioning on first and second formant frequencies of the vowels (u i ae a) were investigated in ten normal subjects, six nonfluent aphasics and six fluent aphasics. Adaptation to perturbation was examined under compensatory and noncompensatory conditions, in which the degree of mandibular opening posed maximal and minimal interference respectively, with reference to normal articulatory positioning. F1 and F2 values, determined by linear predictive coding, were measured at the onset and midpoint of glottal pulsing to identify changes in compensation over time. Results of statistical analyses indicated variable effects of perturbation in both the normal and aphasic subject groups. Analyses of the data with respect to perceptual difference limens suggested that formant deviations in compensatory and noncompensatory productions of all subjects groups would have resulted in changes in vowel quality. The results were interpreted as indicating that compensatory performance, although evident, was neither complete nor immediate in any of the subject groups tested. Moreover, articulatory reorganization and compensation for fixed mandibular positioning appeared to be preserved in nonfluent and fluent aphasics. The findings are discussed with respect to models of speech motor programming and neurogenic models of speech production.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baum, Shari R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hb93f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv75c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A000002169"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Impinging jet studies of polyelectrolyte adsorption</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kelemen, S. J. (Susan J.)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objective of this study was to better understand the kinetics of competitive deposition between polyelectrolyte-coated particles and polyelectrolyte molecules occurring simultaneously on the same surface. In the study with cationic polyethylenimine (PEI), increasing the polyelectrolyte concentration showed six regimes of particle deposition. In the first regime, no particle deposition was observed, since the quantity of adsorbed polyelectrolyte was less than sufficient to create an electrostatic attraction between the partly coated particle and the surface. In the second regime, a fast rate of deposition is observed, where all of the PEI is adsorbed for complete coverage of particles except for a very small concentration in solution. In the third regime, initially fast deposition is followed by a slowing down of the rate until no deposition occurs due to a competition between free PEI in solution with coated particles for sites at the surface. In the fourth regime, no deposition is observed, since the concentration of PEI is high enough to adsorb extremely quickly using up all the surface sites available, reversing their charge to positive, repelling coated particles. In the fifth regime, slow deposition is observed, since high PEI concentrations screen the electrostatic repulsion. In the sixth regime, no deposition is observed possibly due to steric stability. In the study with an anionic polyelectrolyte, NaPSS (sodium polystyrenesulphonate), it was shown that the equilibrium adsorption was independent of molecular weight for molecular weights of 18,000 to 220,000. For these molecular weights, no conditions for sufficient electrostatic or steric repulsion between fully-coated particles and the surface was obtained to prevent deposition. The deposition is ascribed to the small polyelectrolyte layer thickness on TiO$ sb2$ and the collector surface, as well as electrostatic screening by salt. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ven, T. G. M. van de</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d626t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000002169</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr1720337"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of DNA methyltransferase expression during spermatogenesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jue, Kathleen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Patterns of methylation at the 5-position of cytosine are postulated to be involved in several mammalian processes such as the regulation of gene expression, genomic imprinting and X chromosome inactivation. Disruptions in methylation patterns affect embryonic development and are involved in carcinogenesis, indicating the importance of regulating these patterns. The establishment of methylation patterns is believed to be initiated during gametogenesis and continue during early embryonic development. DNA (cytosine-5)-methyltransferase (EC2.1.1.37) (DNA methyltransferase) is the only known mammalian enzyme that catalyzes the formation of 5-methyl cytosine. Here, DNA methyltransferase is proposed to play a key role in establishing and maintaining methylation patterns during male gametogenesis and is predicted to be regulated during spermatogenesis. The regulation of DNA methyltransferase mRNA during testicular development in mouse and rat was first established as preliminary evidence for the regulation of DNA methyltransferase during spermatogenesis. Highly enriched populations of spermatogenic cell types were then isolated from mouse testes and examined for DNA methyltransferase mRNA and protein expression. Expression of DNA methyltransferase protein was proportional to the levels of a 5.2 kb mRNA. Substantial levels of protein and 5.2 kb mRNA were observed in mitotic types A and B spermatogonia, preleptotene spermatocytes, meiotic leptotene/zygotene spermatocytes and postmeiotic round spermatids but barely detectable in pachytene spermatocytes in which a large decrease in 5.2 kb mRNA levels and the appearance of a 6.2 kb transcript was observed. The subcellular localization of DNA methyltransferase in germ cells was also regulated. These findings reveal DNA methyltransferase to be highly regulated during spermatogenesis and support a role for the enzyme in events associated with germ line methylation changes such as developmental gene regulation, genomic imprintin</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Trasler, Jacquetta</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw624.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr1720337</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agm80hx516"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Examination of PCR parameters for the detection of low numbers of bacteria in potable water : development of a nested PCR protocol</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Juck, David F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A simple and sensitive technique was developed for the detection of bacterial cells in a water sample using the nested Polymerase Chain Reaction (nested PCR). The test organism, Escherichia coli, was detectable at an absolute value of 1-5 cells/50 mL of spiked water using ethidium bromide staining and ultraviolet light visualization of PCR product formation on DNA agarose gels. Different parameters of the PCR were examined to determine which ones are the most critical in the design of a detection method for very low numbers of cells in potable water samples. The presence of the filters used for sample concentration in the PCR reaction tube was found to be the most inhibitory component of the procedure and the nested PCR protocol was used to circumvent this inhibitory effect.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ingram, J. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq55g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hx516</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Environmental</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613n078q"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of reactive oxygen species on mouse sperm hyperactivation and capacitation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jiang, Hong, 1964 Dec. 6-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Capacitation of spermatozoa is essential for fertilization. This process is associated with a change of motility pattern of the spermatozoon called hyperactivation. The possibility that reactive oxygen species play a role in mouse sperm hyperactivation and capacitation was investigated. In this work, we demonstrate that the generation of reactive oxygen species by the reaction xanthine + xanthine oxidase stimulates hyperactivation and capacitation. Reactive oxygen species scavengers such as N-tert-butyl-$ alpha$-phenylnitrone, superoxide dismutase, catalase, dimethysulfoxide, benzoic acid and salicylic acid inhibit basal as well as (X + XO)-induced sperm hyperactivation and capacitation. These results suggest that ${ rm cdot}O sb{2-}$ and H$ sb2$O$ sb2$ react together through the iron catalysed Haber-Weiss reaction to form OH. Investigation of possible $ cdot$OH targets suggest that this radical promotes sperm hyperactivation and capacitation via modification of levels of membrane lipid peroxides and of cellular free -SH groups on small molecules, proteins or both.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gagnon, Claude</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f37f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n078q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axp68kj35c"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biochemical changes associated with Rhizopus fermentation of soybean</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ismoyo, Fenny</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The conversion of soybeans to tempe is achieved through fermentation by Rhizopus. This fermentation process leads to hydrolysis of both proteins and lipids. The present work investigated certain biochemical changes which accompany the conversion of soybeans to tempe. The contents of non-protein nitrogen and free $ alpha$-amino nitrogen increased from 2.34 to 15.14%, and 2.03 to 5.22%, respectively after 48 h fermentation. SDS electrophoresis showed that a substantial quantity of the proteins in raw soybeans were hydrolysed by the Rhizopus to low molecular species (molecular weight $&lt;$13,000 Daltons). Trypsin inhibitor activity found in tempe was lower than that of soybean and soaked soybean (an intermediate step in tempe preparation). The protein digestibilities of tempe and soaked soybean were higher than that of soybean. Reversed phase HPLC showed that the peptide separation profile of tempe was different from that of soybean and soaked soybean. The ESI/MS of the RP-HPLC fractions gave molecular weight of soybean peptides ranging from 1962 Da to 22,699 Da and tempe peptides ranging from 569 Da to 16,688 Da. The fatty acid compositions of tempe, soybean and soaked soybean were similar; relatively high levels of linoleic acid followed by oleic, linolenic and stearic acids were found. The acid values increased from 1.49 to 11.42 during the fermentation of soybeans. The total soluble carbohydrate contents of soybean, tempe and soaked soybean as well as the types and quantities of individual sugars were similar. The fermentation of soybean by Rhizopus had only a minor effect on the proximate composition of soybean; however, the soybean and fungal enzymes contributed primarily to changes in protein composition.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nk27h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj35c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fermentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fermented soyfoods -- Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tempeh</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0z708z986"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The purification and characterization of the baculovirus-induced RNA polymerase</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Iorio, Cathy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The transcription of baculovirus genes can be divided into three major temporal classes--early, late, and very late. Early transcription occurs prior to DNA synthesis and is carried out by the host RNA polymerase II. The late phases of viral expression occur during and after DNA replication. Very late transcription is distinguished from late transcription by the synthesis of large amounts of mRNA that remain elevated for extended periods of time. The high level of expression from the very late promoters is characteristic to those genes (polyhedrin and p10) whose products play a role in the formation of occlusion bodies, structures that protect virions from environmental stress. Viral transcription from the late and very late promoters is $ alpha$-amanitin resistant suggesting that a polymerase other than RNA polymerase II is responsible for the expression of these genes. Chromatographic studies have shown that this polymerase is a novel virus-induced enzyme with polypeptide components that are distinct from those of the host polymerases. This thesis describes the purification of the baculovirus-induced RNA polymerase as a means to identify the components that comprise this enzyme. A number of polypeptides associated with the enzymatic activity were identified. In addition, immunoblot analysis of the purified viral polymerase fractions has demonstrated that neither LEF-1 nor LEF-2 are found in the polymerase complex. However LEF-8, a 96 kDa protein containing a motif characteristically found in polymerases, appears to be associated with the enzyme. In addition, LEF-B was also found to be present in the mature budded virions. Furthermore, both p78/83 (a nucleocapsid associated phosphoprotein) and pp31 (a non-specific DNA-binding protein associated with the virogenic stroma) copurify with the baculovirus-induced RNA polymerase through several chromatographic steps. The potential subunit composition of the baculovirus-induced RNA polymerase is also discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Richardson, Chris</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc60r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z986</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axp68kj36n"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Three dimensional graphics tool for motion design</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Iarocci, Maria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the creation of a three dimensional graphics tool that helps a user design, understand and visualize motion of articulated bodies. The linkages that can be considered are closed chains of links or open chains of links having zero to two fixed joints. An open linkage can be viewed as a robot arm, where vertical connecting edges of the linkage are analogous to joints connecting segments of a robot arm. A closed linkage can be viewed as two arms cooperating to move a single point. The visualization tool is an application which animates the linkages moving from an initial to final configuration in three space. The moves permitted by the application are limited to translations, rotations and "line tracking" motions (7). Spherical obstacles may be added to the environment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Whitesides, Sue</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n2041286.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj36n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd375z50v"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of malnutrition in prolonged respiratory failure : the effect of accelerated nutritional rehabilitation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hinze, Candace</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To investigate the possibility that malnutrition is an important factor that prolongs respiratory failure (PRF), I studied the effects of pharmacologic injections of recombinant human growth hormone (rhGH), an important anabolic stimulus, on nutritional and respiratory parameters in patients requiring mechanical ventilation for more than three days. Patients were excluded from consideration if dominating factors known to prolong ventilatory failure had not been stabilized. Over ten months, 106 patients in PRF were evaluated, but only six met the selection criteria. Three patients were randomized to receive standard nutritional support, and three into a group that received the equivalent nutrition plus 5 mg/day of rhGH for 14 days or until withdrawal of mechanical ventilation. Baseline characteristics of the selected patients were divergent as demonstrated by body mass indexes ranging from 14 to 42 (kg/m$ sp2),$ baseline maximal inspiratory pressures (PI$ sb{ max}$ from $-$15 to $-$70 cm H$ sb2$O, and Day 1 N balances from $-$13.5 to 1.2 g N/day. Despite increased plasma insulin-like growth factor-1 concentrations, the mean daily N balances of the rhGH-treated group were no better than the controls (1.3 $ pm$ 5.0 vs. 0.4 $ pm$ 2.6 g N/day; Mean $ pm$ SD), nor were there differences in PI$ sb{ max},$ level of ventilatory assistance required, and days to weaning. The persistence of respiratory failure in the overwhelming majority of patients in PRF appears to be due to factors already known to prevent weaning from mechanical ventilation. Even the carefully selected patients enrolled in the present study were insufficiently homogeneous or stable enough to allow proper testing of the experimental hypothesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hoffer, John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354h39z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375z50v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Respiratory organs -- Diseases -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lungs -- Diseases, Obstructive -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Respiratory insufficiency -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3r074x278"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Habitat selection by breeding American black ducks (Anas rubripes) in northeastern Nova Scotia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hewitson, Stacy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Habitat selection by breeding black ducks (Anas rubripes) was studied in Antigonish County, Nova Scotia during April-September 1990 and 1991. Black duck pairs selected deciduous shrub ponds and sparsely vegetated ponds and avoided estuarine marsh and large lake habitat. Hens with broods preferred the deciduous shrub habitat while they avoided large lakes. Black duck pairs appeared to use the distance to a brood-rearing pond as a cue in site selection. The closer a pond was to a suitable rearing pond the more likely it was occupied by a pair, regardless of food or cover resource availability. Black ducks, however, likely used site attributes such as the perimeter of the pond, the availability of aquatic invertebrates and the relative abundance of alder, willow and dead timber as cues in the selection brood-rearing habitat. Black duck duckling survival, an estimate of recruitment, was the highest on preferred deciduous shrub ponds. Duckling survival was also higher on ponds with only one brood as opposed to ponds with several broods. The most productive habitat for black ducks in the Antigonish study area were isolated, deciduous shrub ponds influenced by beaver activity. Black duck population numbers can be enhanced by managing local beaver populations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Titman, Rodger D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257h01s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074x278</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Black duck -- Nova Scotia -- Reproduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Black duck -- Habitat -- Nova Scotia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Habitat selection</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>