<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak643b156m"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Implementing and evaluating network positioning in the resource addressable network</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yuanyuan, Gao, 1980-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis focuses on the design, implementation and evaluation of a coordinates-based mechanism to compute network positions of Internet hosts in the resource addressable network. This mechanism is based on absolute coordinates calculated from modelling the Internet as a D-dimensional Cartesian space. A small distributed set of infrastructure hosts called landmarks is chosen to first compute their coordinates and serves as a frame of reference for other hosts. I study two algorithms for landmark positioning: distributed spring algorithm and spring equilibrium algorithm. The position of the non-landmark host is calculated using a centralized algorithm. I also evaluate a schema to adjust a host's position based on the positions of its nearby peers. A location-based RAN prototype is implemented by integrating network positioning with naming and discovery modules. The prototype distribution is installed on 127 PlanetLab machines for evaluation. By performing real-time experiments on the distributed testbed, I show that the spring equilibrium algorithm outperforms the distributed spring algorithm in the aspects of efficiency and stability. Furthermore, the adjustment schema based on nearby peers is beneficial to stabilize host's position under normal network variance.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q424t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b156m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354f53c"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The application of Web Ontology Language for information sharing in the dairy industry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gao, Yongchun, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis the Semantic Web and its core technology---Web Ontology Language (OWL)---were studied. Considering the features of the different units involved in the dairy industry, OWL, in its capacity as an ontology description language, can be used to encode and thus exchange ontology among the units in the dairy industry. After creation of OWL file using Protege, an OWL parser was programmed to decode the ontology and data contained in the OWL file. Based on these investigations, it was determined that OWL can be used to encode, exchange, and decode data between farms and the units that interact with them, although large volumes of data among the service agencies pose certain challenges in terms of transfer size. A structure of the Semantic Web services in the dairy industry is proposed for Semantic Web Service registration, search and usage related to certain farm-management tasks. With the help of the Semantic Web and OWL, one can expect a more efficient data processing in the future dairy industry.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655g98h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f53c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dairying -- Information technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Knowledge acquisition (Expert systems)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ontology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Semantic Web</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591886z"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of charged amino acids flanking the LXXLL motifs in modulating the interaction between coactivators and estrogen receptors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Emtiazjoo, Amir Mohammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Estrogens are steroid hormones responsible for the proper function of a variety of mammalian physiological processes. In addition to their central role in reproduction, estrogens also affect the cardiovascular, skeletal, immune and nervous systems and play a role in the initiation and progression of breast cancer. The biological actions of estrogens are mediated by the products of two genes within the nuclear receptor superfamily (NRs), estrogen receptor alpha (ER(alpha) and estrogen receptor beta (ERbeta). Upon interaction with estrogens, ERs recognize specific DNA sequences and modulate the transcription of neighboring target genes via recruitment of coactivators. A diverse group of proteins has emerged as potential coactivators for ERs. Among the best characterized ER coactivators, the p160 family of coactivators consists of three members, SRC1/NCOA1, TIF2/GRIP1 and SRC3/AIB1/RAC3, which associate with p300 and CBP, coactivators with HAT activity. Recruitment of HAT activity at the promoter regions of the target genes results in histone modification and chromatin remodeling to facilitate transcription initiation. Most coactivator proteins contain one or more copies of a helical LXXLL motif, called NR-box, in which L denotes leucine and X denotes any amino acids. Distinct LXXLL motifs display varying degrees of selectivity for nuclear receptors, and artificial LXXLL peptides interacting ERbeta but not ERalpha were identified. Here we have investigated using the Bioluminescence Resonance Energy Transfer and GST pull down assays the role of flanking charged amino acids in LXXLL motifs in interaction with ERalpha and ERbeta. The BRET assay was more sensitive than the GST pull down assay for detection of the interaction between estrogen receptors and LXXLL motif derivatives, which was promoted by 17beta-estradiol (E2) in an H12-dependent manner and at physiological concentration of ligands, but prevented by ER antagonists 4-hydroxy-tamoxifen (OHT) and ICI182, 780. Two Lys residues in the first motif of AIB1 play a crucial role, while Lys at position -2 in the second TIF2 motif only modulates the interaction with ERalpha. The differential effect of mutations at position -2 on interaction with ERalpha and ERbeta suggests that the flanking sequences of LXXLL motifs may modulate selectively binding to the two ERs.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x430x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591886z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g305m"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Poultry manure and inorganic fertiliser effects on soil fertility and microbial communities in wheat and corn agroecosystems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dupuis, Eartha M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Many producers in North America are finding it profitable to make the transition from conventional farming to organic agriculture. Organic fertilisers may affect crop production and soil quality differently than inorganic fertilisers. The objectives of this study conducted in Ste.-Anne-de-Bellevue. Quebec were to examine crop yield, grain quality, soil fertility and microbial community parameters in wheat and corn agroecosystems receiving poultry manure or inorganic fertiliser. Wheat grain yield declined and corn grain yield did not increase with higher N rates, suggesting that increased N supply did not encourage grain production. Soil analyses demonstrated high inherent soil fertility at the study site, and fertilisation led to an environmentally undesirable increase in residual soil NO3 concentrations. Microbial biomass and respiration in corn agroecosystems were greater with poultry manure amendments than inorganic fertiliser, but not in wheat agroecosystems due to significant variation among field replicates. Phospholipid fatty acid analysis revealed significant differences between wheat and corn soil microbial community composition, but differences due to fertilisation were less evident. Further work is needed to uncover the relationships among N fertilisation, crop nutrition and soil microbiology in organic agroecosystems.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b11w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g305m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nitrogen fertilizers -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wheat -- Fertilizers -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Fertilizers -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Poultry -- Manure -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xm27v"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>ERR [alpha] and ERR [gamma] target gene identification by genome-wide : location analysis in the mouse heart</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dufour, Catherine Rosa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Transcriptional regulation by nuclear receptors is vital for a number of different biological processes such as cellular differentiation, embryo development and homeostasis. Recent studies on the roles of estrogen-related receptor alpha (ERRalpha) and gamma (ERRgamma) have demonstrated an important function of these orphan receptors in the control of cardiac energy metabolism. Chromatin immunoprecipitation (ChIP)-on-chip was optimized and then performed using chromatin from mouse hearts on a genome-wide basis to provide further insight into the roles of these ERRs in the heart. In this thesis, we report the identification of ERRalpha and ERRgamma direct target genes in cardiac tissue implicated in various processes such as apoptosis, transcriptional regulation, signal transduction, heart development, electron transport/oxidative metabolism, as well as lipid, carbohydrate, and protein metabolism. However, one important and unexpected outcome of the experiments was the significant number of ERR target genes associated with cardiac hypertrophy in humans.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gd30q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xm27v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xf55j"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Three dimensional N = 2 supersymmetry on the lattice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Elliott, Joshua Wright, 1980-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We show how 3-dimensional, N=2 supersymmetric theories, including super QCD with matter fields, can be put on the lattice with existing techniques, in a way which will recover supersymmetry in the small lattice spacing limit, with O(a) lattice spacing suppressed SUSY breaking effects.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m685p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xf55j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Theory</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290968n"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dangerous bedfellows, industry and medicine : life savers or disease makers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chomey, Brenda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Advertising of products and services has become an accepted and integral part of everyday life, and advancements in mass media technology have made it easy to convey information to a large proportion of the population. However, when addressing health related services and products, the messages contained in today's advertisements have taken on a new purpose and tone. The healthcare industry in North America, especially pharmaceutical companies, and to a lesser extent the diagnostic imaging and the medical device industry, use direct-to-consumer (DTC) advertising to convey a message to a target population. On its face, the promotion of health awareness is an acceptable and worthy practice, but ethical concerns are raised when the health industry plays an instrumental role in creating "illnesses" or "conditions" for which they are providing treatments. At one time, to protect health consumers, legislation and regulations prohibited directly advertising of prescription healthcare products and services to consumers, since it was thought that physicians were the ones best equipped to deal with this information. However, times have changed, and DTC advertising now is openly allowed in some countries, and in others in some narrowly specific situations. This thesis examines the ethical and practical issues raised by this development, arguing that the negative consequences of permitting Direct-to-Consumer advertising far exceeds any positive benefits. If governments do not take an active role in preventing the further commercialization of medicine, Canada (and other countries as well) may be destined to become a nation of worried well.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sw12q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290968n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, General</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sociology, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fx181"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Large-scale precursors to Mesovortices in Alberta</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chouinard, Sébastien</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Using the reflectivity and Doppler data of the Carvel radar, located near Edmonton, Alberta, for the summer of 2000 to 2004, we produced a mesocyclone climatology for a region within 120 km from the radar using the mesocyclone detection algorithm of the McGill Radar data Analysis, Processing and Interactive Display (RAPID) software system. The Upper level Vertically Integrated Liquid water content (UVIL) algorithm of the same software package has been used to detect strong convection. Two datasets were built. The first one consists of dates when mesocyclones occurred while the other includes dates characterized by strong convection but without mesocyclonic activity. A synoptic-scale analysis is conducted to identify the main differences between the atmospheric circulations of the two datasets. The upper-tropospheric flow associated with the mesocyclonic events shows a highly amplified meridional circulation. A strong trough-ridge couplet is evident 48 hours prior to the event. This atmospheric feature is responsible for the development of a vorticity maximum that is advected into Alberta. Lee cyclogenesis in noticeable on the sea-level pressure field associated with mesocyclone activity along with a significant low-level warm temperature input in the region of study. The corresponding atmospheric patterns associated with non-mesocyclonic events do not present such large-scale precursors. The different atmospheric fields act to favour large-scale forcing for ascent when mesocyclones are going to occur.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jf135.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fx181</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atmospheric Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445cd42r"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Understanding factors affecting food intake in elderly women living in the community</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cheung, Winnie, 1979-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Many community-dwelling seniors are reported to have inadequate dietary intakes. Factors affecting food intake have been studied mainly from the perspectives of health professionals. As the reasons for adequate food intake are complex, understanding the seniors' perspective could provide further help in understanding their needs. Three semi-structured interviews were conducted with each of eight community-dwelling women aged 73 to 91 who were at-risk of malnutrition. A qualitative analysis showed the women were reporting three essential aspects: struggling to maintain their independence (i.e., frustration with health care, stereotyping seniors, simplifying cooking); learning new ways of functioning (i.e., adapting to health limitations, simplifying meals etc) and; taking control (i.e., planning own meal and food supplies, monitoring health and keeping physically and mentally active). Finally, this qualitative research paradigm was useful and it demonstrated how careful listening could help to understand the individual needs of free-living seniors at risk of malnutrition.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838084c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cd42r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Older women -- Nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Older women -- Nutrition -- Social aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad217qp89s"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Absence of an elective on-site neurological service : impact on outcomes in severely injured head trauma patients in a tertiary referral trauma center</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chughtai, Talat S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A retrospective study was conducted to compare two groups of patients treated at the Montreal General Hospital (MGH) for traumatic brain injuries (TBI). The time to neurosurgery, vital status and length of stay in the ICU was evaluated in 299 patients treated before (1997-1998), and 307 patients after (2000-2001) an elective neurosurgery service was eliminated from the NIGH. The outcomes were not significantly different between the two groups. There were trends towards a shorter time to neurosurgery in the group treated in 2000-2001 (4.5 hours) compared to the group treated in 1997-1998 (5.5 hours; p=0.32). Mortality and length of stay in the ICU did not significantly differ between the two groups. This study suggests the provision of adequate neurotrauma care with respect to acute outcomes in the absence of an on-site neurosurgery service, at our institution.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w95050881.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qp89s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ast74cq769"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An examination of peripheral dose in linac-based cancer treatment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ceusan, Florin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thesis work contains two related projects. The first project examines the characteristics of the Farmer-type ionization chamber (Farmer-type IC 2571 A) used in our experiments. An investigation was carried out to determine if the simplified "two-voltage technique" used in clinics is sufficiently accurate for saturation current estimation. Three models were used to fit the measured currents and to estimate the saturation current. The estimation was carried out by measuring the currents set-up in the Farmer-type IC while varying the applied voltages, for both polarities, for fixed and variable dose rates. The second project investigated peripheral dose in 6 MV beam using the Farmer-type IC. The signal produced in the ionization chamber when measuring the peripheral dose is 2 to 3 orders of magnitude lower than the signal produced with the chamber in the primary beam, thus, the leakage and saturation characteristics of the ionization chamber had to be investigated to ensure that they do not have adverse effects on the chamber reading. Measurements were acquired in open field (10x10 cm2) and in a dynamic MLC field (10x1 cm2), with the IC at the machine's isocenter. Measurements allowed us to determine peripheral dose due to scatter and leakage radiation. Measurements were repeated for a blocked beam, which allow us to determine only the leakage radiation component of the peripheral dose. The two components of the peripheral dose depend strongly on the linac head configuration and shielding. Leakage radiation per MU for a dMLC field is similar or higher than the leakage radiation for a static field, which implies an increase in peripheral dose for IMRT-type treatments. Knowledge of peripheral dose can be useful in estimating dose and risk to sensitive structures outside of the primary treatment field.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b384w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cq769</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics, Medical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Radiation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r593g"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the interaction between E4orf4 and the B alpha subunit of PP2A</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chan, Francine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The human adenoviral protein E4orf4 has been shown to induce p53-independent cell death in cancer cells. Interaction with the Balpha subunit of protein phosphatase 2A (PP2A) is essential for E4orf4-mediated cell death. PP2A is a trimeric serine/threonine phosphatase, consisting of a structural A subunit, a catalytic C subunit and a regulatory B subunit. Four families of regulatory subunits have been identified to date: B, B', B" and B"'. The B-family subunits, of which there are 4 isoforms, contain 7 WD-repeats and are predicted to fold into a beta-propeller structure with 7 blades. Recent studies have shown that E4orf4 induces death by inhibiting Balpha-specific phosphatase activity of PP2A against certain substrates. Thus, the goal of this project was to study the interaction between E4orf4 and the Balpha subunit of PP2A. To map the PP2A Balpha E4orf4-binding site, point mutants were constructed for Balpha, converting conserved residues amongst E4orf4-binding proteins to alanines. The results indicated that leucines L43 and L112 within WD-repeats 1 and 2 respectively, are important for binding of PP2A Balpha to E4orf4. Furthermore, efforts to map the minimum sequence in PP2A Balpha required by E4orf4 were undertaken using truncation and internal deletion mutants. Small N-terminal deletions did not have an effect on the interaction of Balpha with E4orf4; however the binding reactions suggested that E4orf4 appears to interact with all 7 blades within the Balpha subunit. These studies suggested that although blades 1 and 2 may be critical for the interaction with E4orf4, association with the PP2A Balpha subunit may be complex.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zd833.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r593g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440s77k"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anthropometric correlates and underlying risk factors for type 2 diabetes mellitus among Inuit</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Charbonneau, Guylaine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Type 2 diabetes mellitus (DM) is an emerging problem among Inuit of Circumpolar Countries. However, Canadian Inuit health surveillance data are limited. Data from the Nunavik Health Survey were used to evaluate the prevalence of overweight and obesity using the observed body mass index (BMIob) and the standardized BMI adjusted for sitting height (BMIstd). Also, data from Pangnirtung, Nunavut in the Baffin Region pilot health screening were used to evaluate anthropometric correlates of indices of insulin resistance. Obesity among the Nunavik study population (29.8%) is more prevalent than among general Canadians (23.1%), but the prevalence rates are more comparable when using BMIstd (21.5%). In Pangnirtung, anthropometric measures BMIob, BMIstd, waist circumference and percent body fat were associated with indices of insulin resistance/sensitivity (p ≤ 0.05). BMIstd showed similar results to BMIob and does not better predict the indices of insulin resistance/sensitivity.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53ww01z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440s77k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Diabetes -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inuit -- Diseases -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Centre for Indigenous Peoples' Nutrition and Environment</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s280z"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of fatty acid composition of plant sterol esters on blood lipid profiles and plasma plant sterol levels in hypercholesterolemic subjects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chan, Yen-Ming, 1980-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To evaluate the relative efficacy of plant sterols (PS) esterified with the fatty acids from fish oil (PS-FO), olive oil (PS-OO) and sunflower oil (PS-SO) on blood lipid and PS concentrations, 21 hyperlipidemic subjects were randomly assigned to each of five treatments for 28 days using a cross-over design. The results showed that: (1) in a comparison of olive oil (OO), fish oil (FO), PS-FO and PS-SO subgroup, PS-FO reduced triacylglycerols (TG) relative to PS-SO. Total cholesterol (T-C)/high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C) ratio was reduced with PS-FO compared with FO. Plasma PS levels were increased with PS-SO and PS-FO. (2) in a comparison of OO, PS-SO and PS-OO subgroup, PS-OO had a larger decrease in T-C than OO, while PS-SO and OO reduced T-C equally. Both PS-SO and PS-OO elevated plasma PS levels. Overall, PS-FO and PS-OO have a higher potential for decreasing the risk of cardiovascular disease in hyperlipidemic subjects than PS-SO and OO supplementations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268545g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s280z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hypercholesteremia -- Treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sterols -- Physiological effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>Phytosterols</dc:subject><dc:subject>Blood lipids</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abv73c082k"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mercury diagenesis in the Saguenay Fjord</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bernier, Geneviève</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mass flow event resulting from the 1996 flood in the Saguenay region buried the mercury-contaminated indigenous sediments at the head of the Saguenay Fjord under up to 50 cm of postglacial deltaic sediments. This study investigated whether this deposit served as an efficient geochemical barrier to the remobilization of mercury and its availability to the benthic organisms. The vertical distributions of total mercury and methyl mercury (MeHg) in the sediments and pore waters were measured in box cores recovered at three stations along the main axis of the Saguenay Fjord and in the Baie des Ha!Ha!, in successive years between 1996 and 2002. The total solid mercury profile time-series shows that most of the mercury remobilized from the contaminated, indigenous sediments was trapped below or slightly above the former sediment-water interface. Strong correlations with acid-volatile sulphide profiles and extractions of pyrite-associated mercury indicate that most of this mercury was co-precipitated with authigenic iron sulphides. The mercury that was not sequestered by iron sulphides, diffused into the flood layer where it was scavenged by organic matter or methylated. Mercury sequestration at SAG-05 occurred within the older indigenous sediments, in contrast to SAG-09 where it occurred at or above the original sediment-water interface. The sediments are richer in organic matter, more reducing and, thus, establishment of suboxic conditions and precipitation of authigenic iron sulphides occurred more rapidly. The abundance of mercury at the former sediment-water interface and the low dissolved SigmaH2S concentrations, buffered by acid-volatile sulphide precipitation, both favored mercury methylation. A strong correlation between the distribution of acid-volatile sulphides and methyl mercury in the sediment also reveal that the former may serve as a sink for the latter. Throughout the sediment cores, sediment-water partitioning of MeHg as well as Hg(II) is controlled in great part by the residual organic matter content of the sediment.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w259g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c082k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xr90w"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Laser ablation inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry for human hair analyses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bemben, Kevin J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The goal of this study was to explore the use of laser ablation inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (LA-ICP-MS) for a variety of human hair analyses. Optimization of the inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) operating parameters, radiofrequency (RF) power and carrier gas flowrate, for solid sample introduction showed more than one operating condition can (1) produce a statistically similar maximum elemental signal and (2) have statistically similar optimum signal-to-noise (S/N) ratios. The use of an internal standard was shown to increase the number of operating conditions with statistically similar optimum S/N ratios, and the value of S/N ratios. The high degree of precision exhibited by 34S along hair strands from the same individual (2 - 3 % hair strand to hair strand RSDs) suggests that sulphur may be a suitable internal standard for elements in hair. The single and multi ablation detection limits (DLs) obtained for elements in powdered hair certified reference materials (CRMs) were similar to what was expected for biological materials using LA-ICP-MS. The possibility of using LA-ICP-MS to depth profile elements in a hair strand was explored. With the correct operating conditions, LA-ICP-MS may be an effective analytical tool for depth profiling elements in a hair strand. LA-ICP-MS was used to construct mercury calibration plots using powdered hair CRMs and calibrated hair strands having R2 values of 0.9775 and 0.9522, respectively. Exogenous deposits lead to confusion in the interpretation of findings from hair. LA-ICP-MS was used to remove an artificial exogenous deposit from a hair strand.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n203z43q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xr90w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Analytical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sociology, Criminology and Penology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78tc302"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Redirecting lentiviral integration : a study of human immunodeficiency virus integrase</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Belzile, Jean-Philippe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite great advances in our understanding of the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) life cycle, the mechanisms that underlie the progression of HIV from cellular entry of the viral core to stable integration of the provirus are poorly understood. Sites of integration of the HIV provirus are distributed along the full length of actively transcribed genes and appear to be determined through protein-protein interactions between the viral integrase and cellular proteins. Two cellular proteins have been proposed to perform integration targeting roles, the chromatin-remodeling factor integrase interactor 1 (INI1/hSNF5/BAF47) and the lens epithelium-derived growth factor/transcriptional co-activator (LEDGF). Here, we report the initiation of two novel integration assays to study the contribution of INI1 and LEDGF in target site selection. Elucidating these molecular determinants and their functional implications is also of particular interest to anti-HIV therapy and could have major impact on the safety of gene therapy protocols.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fr68q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc302</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Virology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354f54n"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Circadian regulation of the mouse presenilin-2 gene : how is the molecular clockwork involved?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bélanger, Valérie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Several evidence indicate that presenilin-2 gene is rhythmically regulated in the mouse suprachiasmatic nuclei (SCN), which is the master circadian clock in mammals, as well as in the liver. We investigated the mechanism of circadian modulation behind presenilin-2 oscillation. CLOCK and BMAL1 are the two major transcription factors for circadian gene expression. We demonstrated that CLOCK and BMAL1 partially modulate presenilin-2 gene expression in vitro. In vivo, we showed that the gene does not oscillate in the muscle, spleen, thymus, heart and kidney. On the other hand, we demonstrated a circadian oscillation of presenilin-2 in the liver. We suspect another posttranscriptional mechanism to act in cooperation with the transcriptional mechanism regulated by CLOCK/BMAL1 for the circadian modulation of presenilin-2. We showed that the full-length transcript of presenilin-2 does not oscillate in the liver, but shorter transcripts, potentially issued from alternative spliced mRNA, do oscillate.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rk63w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f54n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429947m"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship between diagenetic cycles of reducible iron and maganese oxides and dissolved organic carbon (DOC)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Barazzuol, Lisa Nicole</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Field evidence suggests that the fate of sedimentary dissolved organic carbon (DOC) is linked to the diagenetic cycles of iron and manganese in marine sediments. Co-variations of their concentrations in sediment porewater, as well as the release of DOC upon the reductive dissolution of authigenic iron and manganese oxides lead us to believe that sorption (i.e., co-precipitation and/or adsorption) onto these oxides may play an important role on the diagenetic behavior of DOC. This DOC sink, if it exists, would considerably alter our views of the mechanisms that regulate DOC fluxes across the sediment-water interface as well as their quantification. Sorption onto authigenic metal oxides may also lead to a molecular and isotopic fractionation of DOC. Oxic surface sediments recovered from the Amundsen Gulf, located south of Banks Island, Northwest Territories, Canada and the Saguenay Fjord, Quebec, Canada were extracted with two different mild reducing agents to determine the amount and composition (molecular and isotopic) of the DOC associated with the authigenic iron and manganese oxides. The reducing agents employed were: (i) 0.25 M hydroxylamine with 0.25 M HCl (HA, pH=1.7) and (ii) 1 N HCl (pH=0). Our results suggest that the sorbed DOC from the Saguenay Fjord sediment is both isotopically (delta13Corg) and molecularly fractionated with respect to the sedimentary particulate organic carbon (POC) pool whereas only molecular fractionation was evident in the Amundsen Gulf samples. The lack of isotopic fractionation in the latter sample set could be attributable to the inefficient extraction of iron oxides (50%) or simply isotopic uniformity, thereby limiting the isotopic fractionation. Molecular analyses by Fourier-Transform Infra-Red Spectroscopy (FTIR) indicate that the porewater and adsorbed DOC pools are most likely dominated by carbohydrates. Our results suggest that the adsorbed DOC pool may buffer the porewater DOC concentration and composition. Based on our preliminary results, we propose that authigenic and detrital iron and manganese oxides that accumulate in oxic sediments scavenge oxygen-rich organic acids diffusing upwards through the sediment column, thereby creating an "aging" reservoir in the oxic sediments. Slow diffusion across the sediment-water interface and desorption upon resuspension of these sediments in the overlying bottom waters may contribute to the "old" DOM pool found in benthic marine waters.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rw990.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429947m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw3763708t"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of additional genes in the cyclohexanol degradation pathway in Rhodococcus maris HI-31</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bakheit, Halla</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Many bacteria have the ability to degrade cyclohexanol through a five-step biochemical pathway that leads to the production of adipic acid. Adipic acid is then processed by beta-oxidation to succinyl-CoA and acetyl-CoA. The original goal of this study was to locate and characterize the gene that is responsible for the first dehydrogenation step of the cyclohexanol ( chn) degradation pathway in the Grampositive bacterium Rhodococcus maris strain HI-31 in order to obtain the full gene complement for cyclohexanol degradation. Instead, three new open reading frames (ORFs) or genes were obtained as the result of cloning and sequencing of a 5-kb SacI fragment upstream of the known chn gene cluster in strain HI-31. Two of the ORFs, designated chnB2 and chnC2, were found to be homologs of the chnB and chnC encoding a cyclohexanone monooxygenase (CHMO) and hydrolase, respectively. This implies possible gene duplication of this portion of the pathway. A third ORF is a potential long-chain fatty acid Co-A ligase. Characteristics of the three ORFs are described. In addition, attempts were made to sub-clone the 5-kb SacI fragment into pT7-6 expression vector for activity assays, etc.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053g34s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763708t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1z40kt14m"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Morphologic and molecular investigation of pulmonary branching in the Nitrofen-rat model of congenital diaphragmatic hernia with or without tracheal occlusion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baird, Robert, 1976-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Fetal tracheal occlusion (TO) has been investigated as a treatment option for lung hypoplasia secondary to Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia (CDH). While it has been shown to promote larger lungs, it is unclear whether TO stimulates mature lung growth or simply induces alveolarization without concomitant bronchial development, a distinction with important clinical implications. We employed the Nitrofen rat model of CDH to investigate the effect of TO on fetal lung branching through morphometric examination, lung casting, lung histology and comparison of two molecular markers involved in lung growth. Nitrofen administration retarded lung growth through decreased lung branching and delayed molecular marker expression profiles. TO did not promote lung branching as manifest by unchanged gross branching, although TO and the stress of in utero surgery may induce late lung maturation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jb78m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kt14m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqv33rx00j"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of color vision in shape discrimination</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Azeff, Liza</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this project is to study the role of human color vision in shape processing. We examine the extent to which color vision can contribute to complex shape processing tasks or whether they are accomplished mainly by the achromatic pathways of the brain. We tested normal human visual performance using psychophysical experiments. The stimuli were presented on a monitor and the task of the subject is to indicate whether shape differences in the stimuli have been seen. Each psychophysical trial was run four-to-five times using a two-interval forced choice paradigm. Stimuli were calibrated so that they selectively activate either the achromatic pathways (black &amp; white) pathways or the color (red-green and blue-yellow) pathways of the human brain. The results of the study show that color vision can perform many of the various types of shape discrimination tasks at similar levels to achromatic vision.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45q9241.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rx00j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Ophthalmology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75dc78g"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Purification, characterization, and hydrolytic activity of alpha-galactosidase from Lactobacillus helveticus ATCC 10797</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al-kandari, Sharifa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this study, alpha-Galactosidase (alpha-D-galactoside-galactohydrolase, EC 3.2.1.22) has been isolated, purified, and characterized from intracellular fraction of Lactobacillus helveticus ATCC 10797. It was purified by a combination of ammonium sulfate precipitation and fast performance liquid chromatography system using ion exchange and gel-filtration columns. This enzyme was purified to only 9.44 fold over the crude extract with a recovery of 1.8%. The km of 3.83 mM and Vmax of 416.44 mumol/min/mg protein were calculated from PNPG. The molecular mass was estimated to be 188 kDa by gel-filtration, but 90 kDa by SDS-PAGE, indicating two similar molecular weight subunits. The optimum temperature for enzyme activity was 37°C, but with a stability below 30°C. The optimum pH was at 6 with a stability of pH 4-8 range. This enzyme was activated by 10 mM monovalent ions such as K+ , NH4+, Li+ and CS +, while the activity was inhibited by divalent ions such as Cu +2, Zn+2, F+2. About 40% of the enzyme activity was inhibited with 100 mM EDTA. alpha-Galactosidase was inhibited by 1mM glucose and galactose, 10 mM sucrose, high concentrations of melibiose, or raffinose and stachyose, but the least inhibitory effect was shown with fructose. When the sugars were incubated with alpha-galactosidase, melibiose was hydrolyzed to glucose and galactose, raffinose to galactose and sucrose, while stachyose to galactose and sucrose with raffinose as intermediate product.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676v92b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dc78g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lactobacillus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glycosidases</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859f94h"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of genes involved in protein-O-glycosylation in yeast, using a network of genetic interactions : Mohamad Jad Al-Shami</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al-Shami, Mohamad Jad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The PMT (Protein O-mannosyl transferase) family members are involved in the initial step of protein-O-mannosylation. A large scale procedure (Systematic Genetic Array) was performed using pmt1, pmt2, pmt3, pmt5, and pmt6 as query deletions and a set of 4700 non-essential array gene deletions, to screen for query/array double deletion mutant combinations affecting growth of Saccharomyces cerevisiae. This procedure revealed a genetic interaction network consisting of 53 interacting genes. Functional grouping of these 53 genes revealed 9 functional categories that were analyzed according to gene function to elucidate how they might buffer defects in protein-O-mannosylation. Synthetic genetic interactions were also identified between PMT family members demonstrating redundancies among them. Protein-O-mannosylation is a protein modification conserved from yeast to human. POMT1 and POMT2 (Human PMTs counterparts) catalyze mannosyl residue transfer in mammals, with mutations identified to be involved in Walker-Warburg Syndrome (WWS). ~72 % of the genes in the yeast PMT genetic network have human homologs, and ~55 % of these are associated with human disease. Using the yeast genetic interaction network as a model for human genetic interactions may help in the understanding of complex inherited human disease.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wj737.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859f94h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Glycosylation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515n680"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Delivery of marrow stromal cells for angiogenesis : therapeutic implications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alsabti, Hilal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is tremendous enthusiasm for the utilization of angiogenesis as a therapeutic modality for atherosclerotic arterial disease. Augmentation of physiological neo-vascularization in cardiovascular disease can be achieved through different pathways. Marrow stromal cells may serve as an ideal cellular vehicle for the in vivo delivery of therapeutic proteins or production of these proteins by the cells themselves. The use of autologous marrow stromal cells is highly desirable since marrow stromal cells are abundant and available in all human of all ages and they are easy to harvest and reimplant without the fear of rejection. Our primary data showed that marrow stromal cells injected locally into ischemic animals promote angiogenesis. Exploring various routes of delivery is important for developing these cells as a novel therapeutic tool for treatment. We found that injecting these cells intravenously in high doses has a beneficial effect in restoring blood flow into the ischemic area in the ischemic hind limb animal model. Implantation of these cells into distant organs did not show any local or remote effects.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430496b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515n680</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>