<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289j62m"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Theory and simulation of texture selection mechanisms in mesophase carbon fibers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sharma, Dinesh, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Carbon fiber precursors are spun from carbonaceous mesophases  using standard melt spinning techniques. These melt spun carbon fibers exhibit a  multitude of cross sectional fiber textures. The two widely reported textures in  literature are planar radial (PR) and planar polar (PP). This thesis uses a  mesoscopic model, based on the classical Landau de-Gennes theory of liquid crystals  and adapted here to carbonaceous mesophases, to study the steady state and transient  phenomena involved in the mesophase carbon fiber texture formation. The model is  successfully able to capture the microstructure and the formation of the PR and PP  textures. A phase diagram for classical PR and PP textures has been constructed  cylindrical carbon fibers in terms of temperature and fiber radius, thus  estabilishing the processing conditions and geometric factors that lead to the  selection of these textures. The multi-path formation process of the planar polar  texture through defect splitting, direct planar polar formation, and defect  annihilation has been thoroughly characterized. A detailed analysis of defect core  structure for defects of strengths s = +1 and s = +1/2 has be undertaken. The effect  of various parameters namely temperature, elastic anisotropy, and fiber radii on the  defect core structures of commonly observed fiber textures has been studied. The  model is well suited for studying the defect core textures which are in the nano  range and could be applied to the new emerging field of nano fibers. The results of  this thesis provide us with knowledge for optimization and control of mesophase  carbon fiber texture, and lay the ground work for the study of nano scale phenomena  in nano fibers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rey, A. D.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290b06v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289j62m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aff365573w"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of structural steel diagonal reinforcement in coupling beams</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lai, Katharine, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Coupling beams are a key structural element for resisting  seismic loading because of their energy dissipating capabilities and high  ductilities. In coupling beams with short span-to-depth ratios, diagonal  reinforcement is used to provide the amount of ductility required. Because of the  large amount of steel congestion within traditionally reinforced diagonally  reinforced coupling beams, however, alternative reinforcement layouts are desired to  simplify their construction. Two specimens were constructed and tested under  reversed cyclic loading. The results were then compared to previous experimental  results to evaluate the viability of these construction techniques. One specimen  contained No. 20 diagonal bars placed in a symmetrical arrangement and confined with  closely spaced headed reinforcing bars in place of hoops. The second specimen used  diagonal reinforcement constructed using structural steel elements that were  anchored in the shear wall elements with shear studs. For comparison, the structural  steel elements used in the design of the second specimen were chosen to match the  yield force of the diagonal reinforcement of the first specimen. The hysteretic responses of the two specimens showed that the  specimen containing the structural steel diagonal reinforcement had a higher  ductility and was able to dissipate more energy than those using headed reinforcing  bars or traditional hoops. This indicates that the use of structural steel is a  viable alternative for the diagonal reinforcement of coupling beams. In addition,  these results also demonstrated that the use of headed reinforcing bars as  confinement for diagonal reinforcement is similar to, and therefore a feasible  replacement for, diagonal reinforcement confined with closely spaced  hoops.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mitchell, D.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vk67q.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365573w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn009z44h"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamic analysis of a power line subjected to longitudinal loads</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lapointe, Marc, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this research, numerical models are used to perform dynamic  nonlinear analyses of a line section subjected to sudden component failures. This  line section is composed of five suspension structures and two dead-end structures,  for a total of six spans. The event studied involves the simultaneous rupture of two  conductors that initiates the subsequent failure of two suspension towers in  torsion. For each analysis performed, cable tensions at suspension  points, insulator string rotations and the longitudinal reactions at supports are  computed. For the first time, numerical results are reported based on the response  at dead-end structures in the line section subjected to cable ruptures. As observed,  the peak longitudinal load at dead-end structures is significant. (Abstract  shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McClure, Ghyslaine</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p0976.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z44h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nh70c"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>High-speed structures for dynamically clocked and multi-clock systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chattopadhyay, Atanu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>With an ever-decreasing minimum feature size, integrated  circuits have more transistors, run faster and are larger than ever before. As a  result, problems such as heat dissipation, clock generation and clock distribution  are at the forefront of challenges facing chip designers today. A Globally  Asynchronous, Locally Synchronous (GALS) system combined with dynamic voltage and  frequency scaling is an architecture that can combat many of these issues while  allowing for high performance operation. In this thesis, we investigate three  distinct circuit designs compatible with, but not limited to, such a system. The  first uses a novel bi-directional asynchronous FIFO to communicate between  independently-clocked synchronous blocks. The second is an All-Digital Dynamic Clock  Generator designed to glitchlessly switch between frequencies with very low latency.  The third is a Digitally-Controlled Oscillator that can either be used stand-alone  or as part of an all-digital PLL (ADPLL) to generate the global fixed frequency  clocks required by the All-Digital Dynamic Clock Generator. These designs have been  designed, simulated and shown to perform all the tasks required to implement a  Globally Asynchronous, Locally Dynamic System (GALDS) in either a traditional ASIC  design or a newer System-on-Chip (SoC).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zilic, Zeljko</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579s82f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nh70c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237hs51z"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Performance improvement of a dual-layered pixellated scintillation block using DETECT2000 Monte Carlo simulations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cayouette, François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We have used DETECT2000, a Monte-Carlo simulation program, to find the theoretical performance of a dual-layered pixellated scintillation block used in high-resolution positron emission tomography. With DETECT2000, the best and worst-case scenarios for light photon transport were analyzed. It was found that certain crystals composing the scintillation block could not be recognized. Simulations about the removal of these crystals have shown no negative effect on the scintillation block performance. With the help of actual data results collected on the scintillation block, the parameters for the model were improved in order to fit simulation results with practical data. When a good set of parameters was found, simulations were done in order to find other modifications in the scintillation block geometry that would increase its performance. We have found that these modifications that require relatively few manipulation steps give almost ideal results. A scintillation block that was modified according to the simulation model later confirmed the simulations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thompson, C. J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n864w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hs51z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77fr92s"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of a medium chain triglyceride oil mixture and alpha lipoic acid diet on body composition, antioxidant status and plasma lipid levels in the Syrian hamster</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wollin, Stephanie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objective of this study was to examine the effects of a  medium chain triglyceride oil mixture (MCTo), designed to increase energy  expenditure and improve lipid profiles containing medium chain triglycerides,  phytosterols and n-3 fatty acids in the form of flaxseed oil, versus the antioxidant  alpha-lipoic acid (ALA). Forty-eight hamsters were fed (i) hypercholesterol emic  (HC) control, (ii) HC MCTo, (iii) HC ALA, (iv) HC MCTo/ALA diets for 4 weeks. No  effects on food intake, body weight, total body water, lean body mass, fat mass, and  tissue thiobarbituric acid-reactive substances (TBARS) were observed. ALA alone had  no effect on total cholesterol (TC); however, MCTo feeding increased TC with (p  &lt; 0.03) and without (p &lt; 0.003) ALA when compared to control. ALA  increased HDL levels compared to control (p 0.04) and MCTo/ALA (p &lt; 0.007)  groups. MCTo, with (p &lt; 0.0001) or without (p &lt; 0.006) ALA, increased  non-HDL cholesterol levels versus control. The non-HDL:HDL ratio was decreased by  ALA compared to MCTo (45%) and MCTo/ALA (68%) (p &lt; 0.0001), a similar trend  was seen when compared to the HC control (22%) group (p &lt; 0.14). Triglyceride  levels were not altered by any of the dietary treatments. Liver and heart tissue  reduced glutathione (GSH) was increased (p &lt; 0.05) by all three treatments  when compared to control. Both tissues showed an increase (p &lt; 0.05) in  oxidized glutathione (GSSG) when fed ALA compared to all other treatments. Hamsters  fed ALA had a lower (p &lt; 0.05) GSH/GSSG ratio compared to all treatment  groups. In conclusion, MCTo feeding does not elicit beneficial effects on  circulating plasma lipids and measures of body composition. In addition, our results  do not clearly support an improvement in oxidative status through supplementation of  ALA. However, our results do support the existence of beneficial effects of ALA on  circulating lipoprotein content in the hamster.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jones, Peter J. H.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mv82j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fr92s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Thioctic acid -- Health aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oils and fats in animal nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Body composition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Golden hamster -- Nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Triglycerides -- Health aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Blood lipids</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q459x"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reproductive toxicity and bioavailability of arsenic in contaminated artificial and natural soils using the earthworm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wong, Stephen W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>High concentrations of arsenic are found near gold-mine  tailings. The most common form of arsenic found in soil is arsenate, which is a  known toxicant. We used the standardised earthworm reproduction test for the species  Eisenia andrei (E. andrei) to study the toxicity and bioavailability of  arsenic-contaminated soil. Arsenic is toxic to earthworms as indicated by the  decrease in survival and reproduction. Arsenic-spiked artificial soil was more toxic  than arsenic-spiked field soil based on total arsenic concentration in soil.  Moreover, soil from near mine tailings showed a reduced toxic effect despite its  high soil arsenic concentration as compared to spiked field soil. Measurements of  arsenic tissue concentrations in the earthworm indicated that uptake of arsenic into  earthworm tissue was higher in spiked artificial soil as compared to spiked field  soil and that the maximal body burden was 396 mug As/g dry tissue weight. However,  when considering tissue arsenic concentration, spiked field soil is more toxic than  spiked artificial soil. Therefore the tissue rather than soil content may better  reflect the magnitude of arsenic toxicity to E. andrei.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chan, H. M.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999729s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q459x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earthworms -- Effect of chemicals on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gold mines and mining -- Environmental aspects -- Northwest Territories -- Yellowknife Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arsenic -- Bioavailability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil pollution -- Northwest Territories -- Yellowknife Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arsenic -- Toxicology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5138jf37r"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Zinc and copper uptake by wheat and buckwheat under two transpiration rates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tani, Fahima</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Wastewater has become a vital new supply for irrigation;  however, concerns are mounting about environmental and health hazards related to  heavy metals present in wastewater. Experiments were conducted to evaluate wheat (  Triticum aestivum L.) and buckwheat (Fagopyrum esculentum L.) uptake of copper (Cu)  and zinc (Zn). Some 15 plants per pot were allowed to establish themselves in  the greenhouse for 4 and 6 weeks for buckwheat and wheat, respectively. Plants were  then transferred to one of two growth chambers differing in the vapor pressure  deficit (VPD), creating conditions for two different transpiration rates to occur:  high (HT) and low (LT). A total 48 pots for each crop were seeded in order to  evaluate the effect of 8 treatment combinations of Cu and Zn (0/0, 5/0, 15/0, 30/0,  0/25, 5/25, 15/25, 30/25) levels (mg L-1). Treatments were laid out in a completely  randomized design within each growth chamber. Three plants were harvested from each pot at days 10 and 20 for  wheat, and days 6, 12 and 18 days for buckwheat to measure dry mass and Cu and Zn  content in different plant parts. Heavy metal treatments had no significant effect  on transpiration rate for either crops. The higher transpiration rate increased  Cu/Zn uptake. A Zn amendment in the absence of Cu had a beneficial effect on  buckwheat growth, whereas with Cu at 15 mg Cu L-1 or 30 mg Cu L-1 the lowest dry  weights were recorded, regardless of the transpiration rate. Roots contained greater  concentrations of Cu and Zn, irrespective of the treatment level and transpiration  rate, than did stems, leaves or grain. High retention of heavy metals in the roots  of cereal crops may be desirable because these parts are not generally utilized as  food or feed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barrington, Suzelle</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3655745.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jf37r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Wheat -- Irrigation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wheat -- Effect of heavy metals on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Buckwheat -- Effect of heavy metals on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wheat -- Effect of water pollution on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Buckwheat -- Effect of water pollution on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Buckwheat -- Irrigation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad217qq21b"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Social and Transcultural Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship between acculturation and positively and negatively defined mental health for the Iranian migrant community of Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Taleshi, Maziar M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is a paucity of research literature on the relationship  between acculturation and positive indices of mental health for migrant populations.  The objective of this study is to investigate the nature of this relationship for  the Iranian migrant community of Canada. Eighty-six Iranian migrants living in Montreal and Toronto  filled a self-report questionnaire. Acculturation was measured through an  acculturation attitude, overt behavioural and self-report Canadian contact scales.  Positive mental health was measured through WHO's cross-culturally validated  subjective quality of life (SQOL) scale and the level of psychological distress was  measured with the SCL-25. Pertinent demographic variables were considered to control  for intra-group differences. Moreover, since data collection for this project occurred just  after the events of September 11 we partially modified our research plan to include  specific questions on the impact of this even. Because of its overt politicization  and its salience to Iranian ethnicity we also sought to explore the effect of  religiosity on mental health of this group. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mercier, Celine</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Rousseau, Cecile</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386j855.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qq21b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Clinical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Social</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sociology, Ethnic and Racial Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An009w292h"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comparing machine learning and hand-crafted approaches for information extraction from HTML documents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Singer, Ron</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The problem of automatically extracting information from web  pages is becoming very important, due to the explosion of information available on  the World Wide Web. In this thesis, we explore and compare hand-crafted information  extraction tools with tools constructed using machine learning algorithms. The task  we consider is the extraction of organization names and contact information, such as  addresses and phone numbers, from web pages. Given the huge number of company web  pages on the Internet, automating this task is of great practical interest. The  system we developed consists of two components. The first component achieves the  labeling or tagging of named entities (such as company names, addresses and phone  numbers) in HTML documents. We compare the performance of hand-coded regular  expressions and decision trees for this task. Using decision trees allows us to  generate tagging rules that are significantly more accurate. The second component is  used to establish relationships between named entities (i.e. company names, phone  numbers and addresses), for the purpose of structuring the data into a useful record  (i.e. a contact, or an organization). For this task we experimented with two  approaches. The first approach uses an aggregator that implements human-generated  heuristics to relate the tags and create the records sought. The second approach is  based on Hidden Markov Models (HMM). As far as we know, no one has used HMM before  to establish relationships between more than two tagged entities. Our empirical  results suggest that HMMs compare favorable with the hand-crafted aggregator in  terms of performance and ease of development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Precup, Doina</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j6275.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w292h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Artificial Intelligence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Information Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akk91fm098"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of the translational inhibitor 4E-BP1</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sirry, Baheya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Regulation of translation has long been recognized as a crucial  event in the control of gene expression. It allows for rapid changes in gene  expression in response to a wide-range of extracellular stimuli. Variations in  nutrient availability for instance are detected and transmitted through the protein  kinase FRAP/mTOR to key translational regulators such as the CAP-dependent  translation inhibitor 4E-BP1. 4E-BP1 function is regulated mainly by  phosphorylation. The focus of this thesis is to better understand signalling  involved in 4E-BP1 regulation. We first decided to examine 4E-BP1 phosphorylation against the  background of an embryonic lethal mutant of FRAP/mTOR, the flat-top mutant, in order  to elucidate the effect of this point mutation on FRAP/mTOR function. Our results  revealed that signalling leading to 4E-BP1 phosphorylation is impaired in these  mutants. We were then interested in establishing 4E-BP1's role in the  cell cycle by examining its phosphorylation state during mitosis. This study was  based on the finding that CAP-dependent translation is inhibited in mitotic cells.  Using 2-dimensional gel electrophoresis we detected two new isoforms of 4E-BP1  during mitosis. The above studies demonstrate the essential role of 4E-BP1 in  mammalian development and the cell cycle, emphasizing the need to better understand  mechanisms involved in its regulation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sonenberg, Nahum</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gk48c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm098</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pb046"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Association between GLC-4 and AVR-14 : role of GluCl subunit composition in Caenorhabditis elegans ivermectin sensitivity and behaviour</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pellegrino, Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The glutamate-gated chloride (GluCl) channel family of receptors  are members of the ligand-gated ion channel (LGIC) family. In addition to being  essential for physiological and behavioural aspects of an organism, they are also  exploited as a target for the drug ivermectin. A novel GluCl subunit in C. elegans,  GLC-4, was characterized in order to further understand the diversity of GluCls and  their implications in biological and behavioural processes. Sequencing of cDNAs  generated by RT-PCR indicate that GLC-4 possesses the typical features of a GluCl  subunit. In addition, they also suggest possible alternative splicing of glc-4  resulting in a slightly truncated transcript. A glc-4 mutant, glc-4(ok212), was used  to investigate the role of GLC-4 in C. elegans ivermectin sensitivity and behaviour.  Glc-4(ok212) worms were found to be hypersensitive to low concentrations of  ivermectin and experienced a slight hyperreversal behaviour. Genetic, molecular, and  electrophysiological evidence is also provided suggesting an interaction between  GLC-4 and AVR-14, another GluCl subunit in C. elegans. We hypothesize a direct  association between GLC-4 and AVR-14 which together form a heteromeric channel in  vivo .</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dent, Joseph</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wd34j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pb046</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Drug resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ivermectin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chloride channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3f4626102"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expression and analysis of deletion mutants of polyomavirus large T antigen</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pavlovic, Cliff</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Polyomavirus large T antigen (LTAg) is the main regulatory  protein in the life cycle of polyomavirus. It binds to consensus sequences GA/GGGC  in sites 1/2, A, B and C, which are found in and around the origin of viral DNA  replication. It was shown before that polyomavirus large T antigen binds  cooperatively to origin DNA, aiding the protein to stay bound long enough for  accumulation of LTAg to form the hexameric complex needed for DNA replication. We  set out to find where the domain(s) responsible for this cooperative binding are  located within LTAg by using DNAse I footprinting. Domain deletions of LTAg were made to create LTAg proteins  lacking the N-terminal domain, the C-terminal domain or both. LTAg and the deletion  LTAg proteins were engineered with the His-6 tag at their C-terminal ends. These  proteins were produced in Pichia pastoris and were purified using the Ni-NTA agarose  method. The proteins were analyzed for DNA-binding activity using a modified DNA  immunoprecipitation assay (McKay assay). (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Acheson, Nicholas H.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903059c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f4626102</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zf13m"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of ethanol on the Jak-Stat pathway : is this an NMDA mediated event?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paliouras, Grigorios Nikiforos</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Alcohol affects many neurochemical processes, causing  long-lasting changes in both the adult and developing brain. The Jak-Stat  transcriptional activation pathway plays a role in the control of neuronal  proliferation, survival and differentiation, but the effects of ethanol on the  system have not been fully elucidated. The goal of this project was to define the  effects of acute and subchronic ethanol exposure on the expression of proteins in  the Jak-Stat pathway, using cultured NG108-15 cells, and in addition, to test the  hypothesis that these effects are mediated through the NMDA receptor. I found that  ethanol dose-dependently decreased Jak2 and Stat3 following subchronic exposure of  NG108-15 in culture. Acute ethanol exposure caused a dose-dependent decrease in  Stat3 protein levels. Incubation with MK-801 or ketamine, two noncompetitive NMDA  receptor antagonists, or the receptor agonist NMDA, produced dose-dependent  decreases in Stat3 protein as well.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Palmour, Roberta M.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306sz82k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zf13m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Methyl aspartate -- Receptors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Alcohol</dc:subject><dc:subject>Protein-tyrosine kinase</dc:subject><dc:subject>Receptors, N-Methyl-D-Aspartate</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac247ds737"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Isolation and characterization of Jurkat-derived signaling-deficient T cell lines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Majdalawieh, Amin F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this study, we describe the isolation and characterization of  a functionally signaling-deficient Galpha16-negative somatic mutant (hereafter  referred to clone 43) derived from the wildtype Jurkat T cell line by means of an  activation-induced cell death resistance-based selection strategy. The catalytic  activity of Lck in abrogated in clone 43 most likely due to a lack of  autophosphorylation at the stimulatory site within the kinase domain of Lck, Y394.  Based on Galpha16 cDNA sequencing data, the deficiency presented in clone 43 is most  likely due to one or two point mutations located at amino acid residues 26 and 300  of the Galpha16 subunit. Importantly, these signaling defects were fully reversed by  re-introduction of wildtype Galpha16 version into clone 43. Indeed, our findings are  the first of their kind to validate the proposed model by which the Galpha subunit  modulates the activity of Src family of protein tyrosine kinases. These studies  underscore the integral role played by Galpha 16 in TCR-mediated signaling and offer  a powerful genetic tool to strengthen our knowledge about the regulation and  function of G proteins in T lymphocytes. We also describe the phenotype of two other  signaling-deficient, Jurkat-derived clones, named clone 15 and clone 21. (Abstract  shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Couture, Clement</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343s84r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247ds737</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483j94c"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The design of a distributed, object-oriented, component-based framework in multidisciplinary design optimization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mahdavi, Babak</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Multidisciplinary Design Optimization (MDO) can be defined  as a methodology for the design of complex engineering systems where collaboration  and abilities to mutually interacting between different disciplines are fundamental.  In this thesis, Virtual Aircraft Design and Optimization fRamework (VADOR), a  distributed, object-oriented, component-based framework enabling MDO practice at  Bombardier Aerospace is introduced. The purpose of the VADOR framework is to enable  the seamless integration of commercial and in-house analysis applications in a  heterogeneous, distributed computing environment, and allow the management and  sharing of the data. The VADOR distributed environment offers visibility to the  process, permitting the teams to monitor progress or track changes in design  projects and problems. Documentation of the MDO process is vital to ensure clear  communication of the process within the team defining it and in the broader design  team interacting with it. VADOR is implemented in Java, providing an  object-oriented, platform-independent framework. The concepts of design pattern and  component-based approach are used along with multi-tiered distributed design to  deliver highly modular and flexible architecture. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jm03c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483j94c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Aerospace</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anc580n19p"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>N = 2 partial supersymmetry breaking in brane-world scenarios</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Larose-Filotas, Elise</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We describe brane-world models which partially break  supersymmetry from N = 2 to N = 1. The brane models we consider are embedded within  a 4-dimensional N = 2 locally supersymmetric bulk-space. We devise the following  models: a single-brane action, a single-antibrane action and a two-brane action. In  these models the membrane linearly realises one supersymmetry of the bulk and  spontaneously breaks the other. We also construct the action for a brane free bulk  with a cosmological constant term. This model is different from the previous  examples because both supersymmetries are broken. We also attempt to devise a  brane-antibrane action. This model has the particular feature of breaking both  supersymmetries of the bulk-space. Effects of this investigation on our  understanding of the mechanism of partial supersymmetry breaking in brane-world  scenarios will be discussed. In particular, the contribution to the cosmological  constant via this mechanism will be examined. In order to construct such a model, we  use the previous actions and the concepts developed throughout their construction.  This investigation constitutes a firm foundation toward the construction of a  successful brane-antibrane model.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burgess, C. P.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816n15h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580n19p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p779w"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Study of the formation dynamics of self-assembled alkanethiol monolayers by ellipsometry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laroche, Olivier</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The motivation of the present work is our research on a  cantilever-based chemical sensor. We are addressing the question of the source of  the surface stress on a gold-coated cantilever due to alkanethiol adsorption. By  simultaneously measuring layer thickness and cantilever stress during alkanethiol  monolayer self-assembly, the aim is to gain some insight on where the surface stress  comes from. The technique we used to monitor layer thickness is ellipsometry. The  ellipsometer is used to measure, in situ, the formation dynamics of self-assembled  alkanethiol monolayers under different conditions. The thickness evolution is  interpreted in terms of monolayer phases (lying-down and standing-up). During these  experiments, the ellipsometer is proven to have Angstrom resolution. Following our  objectives, a combined stress-thickness set-up is designed and built. Preliminary  results are presented while further investigations are currently being  made.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grutter, Peter</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f180f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p779w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acr56n178m"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Heating behavior and quality factor retention in canned potatoes as influenced by process variables during end-over-end rotational processing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jobe, Baboucarr</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Thermal processing involves application of heat to destroy  pathogenic microorganisms of public heath concern and to reduce the activity of  microorganisms and enzymes that spoil the food. However, the technique is associated  with considerable degradation of taste, color, texture, flavor and nutritional  quality of processed foods. Data on kinetics of changes in quality factors and their  temperature dependence, as well as the heat penetration behavior of the food during  processing are necessary to predict and optimize the extent of quality retention.  The objectives of this study were: (a) to evaluate the kinetics of thermal  softening, color degradation and loss of ascorbic acid in potato (Solanum tuberosum)  at selected temperatures (70--100°C) and to evaluate their temperature  dependence; (b) to evaluate the effect of process variables (temperature, rotational  speed, can size and nature of the covering fluid) on heating behavior of canned  potatoes and (c) to determine the influence of the above process variables on  process time and product quality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ramaswamy, H. S.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515p023.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n178m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Potatoes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canned vegetables -- Quality</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z1427"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of high pressure treatment of milk on microbial destruction as influenced by product and process related factors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jin, Hong, 1964-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The traditional way of processing milk is the application of  heat to destroy undesirable microorganisms. Though heat is an effective means of  doing the job, it is associated with several limitations. High pressure (HP)  processing has the potential for eliminating microorganisms without affecting the  natural quality of the raw material. As a result, it has become a promising  technique in recent years. Many factors are reported to influence HP destruction of  microorganisms, the most important ones include food composition (i.e., lipid,  carbohydrate and protein contents), water activity, process temperature, and mode of  pressure treatment. Therefore, the objectives of this research were to: (a) evaluate  the effect of milk composition on destruction of E. coli by HP, (b) evaluate kinetic  models for spoilage and pathogenic microorganism in milk and the effect of different  pressure mode (pulse and static) on the destruction rates; and (c) to evaluate the  effect of milk type (UHT and raw milk) and temperate on destruction of  microorganism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ramaswamy, Hosahalli</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182k80n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z1427</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>High pressure (Technology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Milk -- Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap5547s05f"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Water table management for cranberry production on sandy and peat soils Québec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Handyside, Patrick E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The North American cranberry plant (Vaccinium macrocarpon Aiton)  is a wetland crop species grown commercially in natural or constructed peat or sandy  soil basins. Since production is highly water dependent, water requirements are very  significant and have prompted growers to explore new water management practices to  improve irrigation efficiency and protect water resources. One way of conserving and  better managing water, given the infrastructure in place, would be to develop  sub-irrigation. The design of a subsurface irrigation system requires the  evaluation of various soil properties. This was undertaken at four established  cranberry production sites, situated near Saint-Louis-de-Blanford, Quebec. Two of  the fields contained a sandy soil, and the other two were peat soils. Soil physical  properties measured included: saturated hydraulic conductivity, bulk density,  porosity, soil moisture characteristic curves and particle size distribution.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madramootoo, C. A.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g573w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547s05f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Water table -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Subirrigation -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cranberries -- Soils -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aww72bc17v"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Otolaryngology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of stroboscopic variations in a normal sample</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haben, Michael C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An analysis of stroboscopic variations in a normal sample has  been created. To most sub-specialized laryngologists and voice therapists, the  results confirm primarily anecdotal experience concerning the nature of the various  stroboscopic findings. The analysis provides epidemiologic data inferring the  normalcy, or likelihood of pathology, of non-symmetric stroboscopic variations, thus  providing evidence in support of intervention, or observation. This analysis may  serve as a foundation, promoting further analyses of targeted populations for  further epidemiological, normative, and descriptive purposes. For many  otolaryngologists just beginning to use videostroboscopy, this analysis illustrates  the wide range of normal variations, and provides a reference point from which  presumed abnormal findings may be compared. For the voice researcher, the results  may encourage modeling of common stroboscopic variations, to provide a more accurate  representation of the intricate and complex physiology of normal voice production.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Franco, Eduardo</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Kost, Karen</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687j07c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bc17v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9w032367v"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigations into the role of substance P and the NK-1 receptor in an animal model of neuropathic pain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fallis, Brooks A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigates the role of substance P and NK-1  receptors in an animal model of neuropathic pain. Unlike naive animals, innocuous  peripheral stimulation of neuropathic animals was determined to cause  heterosegmental inhibition in the tail-flick test as well as increased plasma  extravasation in the paw. These effects were prevented by administration of  CP-96,345 before stimulation. Additionally, CP-96,345 or an antisense  oligonucleotide against NK-1 receptors significantly alleviated mechanical allodynia  in neuropathic animals. Finally, mass spectrum of lumbar spinal cord of neuropathic  but not naIve animals showed a significant upregulation of substance P. We conclude  that innocuous stimulation of a neuropathic area could trigger activation of NK-1  receptors, presumably due to binding of substance P. Furthermore, this activation of  NK-1 receptors could be central to the perception of mechanical allodynia in  neuropathic pain. These results justify the investigation of inhibiting the  interaction between substance P and the NK-1 receptor for the treatment of drug  resistant neuropathies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Henry, James L.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752h377.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032367v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd375w99w"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gene expression is differentially regulated in the epididymis after orchidectomy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ezer, Nadine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The epididymis is the site for the transport, maturation and  storage of spermatozoa. It is well established that epididymal structure and  function are dependent on the testis for circulating androgens and factors in  luminal fluid. Using cDNA microarrays, our objective is to characterize the  expression of genes that are regulated over the first week post-orchidectomy in the  epididymis of the adult Brown Norway rat. We describe four patterns of gene  expression that are simultaneously activated in the epididymis after orchidectomy.  We identify potential androgen-dependent genes including glutathione S-transferases  and calcium-binding proteins, as well as potential androgen-repressed genes such as  glutathione peroxidase-1. The expression of heat shock proteins, cyclins, and  apoptosis-associated genes are described in the epididymis after orchidectomy. These  results form the first comprehensive analysis of testis-regulated gene expression in  the epididymis. This study is the first to demonstrate that gene expression is  differentially regulated in the epididymis after orchidectomy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robaire, Bernard</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nf37h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375w99w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278t644"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Impacts of long term tillage and residue practices on selected soil properties</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dam, Rikke Friis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A two year study was initiated in 2001 on a 2.4 ha site of  mostly St. Amable loamy sand and shallow loamy sand at the Macdonald Campus Research  Farm. This study sought to assess the effects of long term tillage and residue  practices on soil physical properties and to relate these properties to their  influence on total carbon, total nitrogen and soil microbial biomass-carbon. The  site was set up as a factorial experiment with three tillage practices (no  till---NT; reduced till---RT; and conventional till---CT) and two residue practices  (with residue (grain corn), +R; without residue (silage corn), -R). Soil physical  properties measured were bulk density, macroporosity at -6 kPa, saturated hydraulic  conductivity (Ksat ), dry aggregate distribution, soil moisture and soil  temperature. Wheel versus non-wheel track bulk density was also determined in the NT  plots. Total porosity, soil water characteristic curves and pore volume distribution  were derived from field samples. Crop yield was also assessed. Tillage alone had an  effect on total porosity, bulk density, pore diameter and macroporosity. No  individual physical property was significantly affected by the residue treatments;  however, the tillage and residue interaction was significant for Ksat, soil moisture  and soil temperature. Dry aggregate distribution was not affected by either tillage,  residue or the combination of the two. Tillage affected total carbon and total  nitrogen in the 0--0.10 m depth. Soil microbial biomass-carbon was affected by  residue inputs. Total carbon and nitrogen were influenced by the bulk density, but  none of the other soil physical properties. Soil microbial biomass-carbon was not  influenced by any of the physical properties. Tillage and residue practices had no  significant effect on crop yield for either year.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madramootoo, Chandra</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c817d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278t644</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soil physics -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Residues -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Crop residue management -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tillage -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Conservation tillage -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>