<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak643b299m"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Enhanced fluctuation-driven neutrino scattering behind supernova shocks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aghababaie, Yashar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We describe a general formalism for computing scattering rates of weak probes in macroscopic systems, based on a density matrix formalism. We show that weak probes in general scatter off fluctuations in the medium. In the limit that the neutrino wavelength is much larger than the lengthscale of the fluctuations, we show that the scattering rate can be calculated from knowledge of the equation of state of the medium through which the neutrinos travel. Using radial profiles of a post-bounce, shocked supernova core and a well-established equation of state for nuclear matter we compute these scattering rates for various times in the vicinity of the shock. We find that, behind the shock, these correlative effects can enhance neutrino scattering rates by factors of 8 compared to standard calculations which ignore interactions in the nuclear medium. These results may have implications for how efficiently neutrinos can restart a stalled shock, although firm conclusions regarding the ultimate effects of such an enhancement await full hydrodynamic simulations, which are not performed here.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burgess, C. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225c853.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b299m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Astronomy and Astrophysics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bk02z"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Distributed multi-processing for high performance computing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Algire, Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Parallel computing can take many forms. From a user's perspective, it is important to consider the advantages and disadvantages of each methodology. The following project attempts to provide some perspective on the methods of parallel computing and indicate where the tradeoffs lie along the continuum. Problems that are parallelizable enable researchers to maximize the computing resources available for a problem, and thus push the limits of the problems that can be solved. Solving any particular problem in parallel will require some very important design decisions to be made. These decisions may dramatically affect portability, performance, and cost of implementing a software solution to the problem. The results gained from this work indicate that although performance improvements are indeed possible---they are heavily dependent on the application in question and may require much more programming effort and expertise to implement.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Landry, Jacques-Andre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k96n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bk02z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electronic data processing -- Distributed processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Environmental sciences -- Data processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>High performance computing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128ng51j"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A decision-support system for optimal operation of hydropower stations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gauthier, Jean-Maurice</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Hydro-Quebec utilizes a one-dimensional hydrological model called H2RM to simulate the evolution of flow on harnessed rivers. The model produces reliable results but its application is restricted to so-called 'hydrological domains', that define the flow routing pattern in-between hydroelectric facilities. When many power stations are present on a river, each hydrological domain must be treated separately, then linked to the next one. No information is provided on storage in head reservoirs nor electric production from power stations. A computer program (shell) has been developed to simulate a complete hydropower system comprising a number of head reservoirs, hydrological domains and power stations. In this program, head reservoir behavior is reproduced by computing a mass balance, flow routing within a hydrological domain is simulated using the H2RM model, and production from each power station is estimated through an optimization procedure. The shell program can be used as a decision support tool by allowing the comparison between various water management schemes and by displaying stage and discharge at any point of the hydropower system, storage in head reservoirs, and optimal power output from the turbines for the head and flow conditions prevailing at each power station. Examples of application are provided.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nguyen, V. T. V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558g104.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng51j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject><dc:subject>Energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Operations Research</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hh43q"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Understanding indigenous rights : the case of indigenous peoples in Venezuela</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Frías, José</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>On December 15, 1999, the people of Venezuela approved a new Constitution, which is the first Venezuelan constitution to entrench the rights of indigenous peoples. The purpose of this thesis is to analyze the different theoretical issues raised by the problem of rights for indigenous peoples. It is argued that indigenous rights are collective rights based on the value of cultural membership. This implies both an investigation of the value of cultural membership and of the criticisms that the multicultural perspective has offered against that point of view. Indigenous peoples have the moral right to preserve their cultures and traditions. It is submitted that indigenous peoples have a double moral standing to claim differential treatment based on cultural membership, because they constitute cultural minorities and they were conquered and did not lend their free acceptance to the new regime imposed upon them. Therefore, they constitute a national minority, with moral standing to claim self-government and cultural rights.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lametti, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n18b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh43q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Indigenous peoples -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Venezuela</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indigenous peoples -- Civil rights -- Venezuela</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gm76r"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Responsibility in international law for commercial space activities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gouesse, Emmanuel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Space activities are increasingly undertaken by private companies. Space law, however, was mainly developed in the beginning of the space age, at a time where space activities were predominantly state activities. The rules that developed were thus focusing on the duties of states and concerned private entities only through the intermediary of states. This thesis explores the applicable principles of space law and of the international law of responsibility. Taking into account the recent practice of private companies engaged in space business, the work also focuses both on its impact on the responsibility and liability regime as well as on the legal efficiency of the links between private entities and states. In conclusion, the thesis makes several recommendations to improve the responsibility regime for space activities.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494b25d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm76r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Liability for space vehicle accidents</dc:subject><dc:subject>Space law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Liability (Law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Space industrialization -- Law and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053h94f"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'autonomie de la clause compromissoire en droit du commerce international</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Duquenne, Céline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The arbitration clause is the clause by which the parties to a contract agree to submit the conflicts that may rise from their contractual relationship to an arbitral tribunal. A principle of autonomy is associated to this type of clause: on the one hand, the arbitration clause is separable from the main contract; on the other hand, it is independent from any state law. To a certain extent, one may even link this principle to other principles concerning the arbitration clause, such as the Kompetenz-Kompetenz principle. The question is to know whether special rules apply to the arbitration clause.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Saumier, Genevieve</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp99x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h94f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Arbitration and award, International</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arbitration agreements, Commercial</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A37720f742"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cooperative learning in a Cree community : a small experiment, 1996-1998</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Savides, Daphne M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>"Cooperative Learning in a Cree Community" is a study of the implementation of innovative teaching methods in a cooperative learning environment at Sabtuan Cree Adult Education. The implementation was a response to the historical context of education in Mistissini Lake. I was the English Language Arts teacher for the adult sector in Mistissini Lake between 1996--1998. My students ranged between the ages of 16 and 50. In addition to Language Arts I taught optional courses like Economics, History, Word Processing and Personal and Social Development. I determined to investigate the potential of cooperative, and student self-evaluation as a valid instructional model for Cree adult learners. My primary objective was to increase critical thinking, learner confidence, and self-directed activity in the classroom. My aim was to study the correlation between interactive pedagogy and student engagement. One indicator of student involvement is student absenteeism. Thus one component of this study examines the correlation between cooperative learning and student attendance. In the introduction I discuss the problems indigenous people have encountered and my understanding and assessment of the present situation in Cree schools. The second section gives a summary of the Cree context, their culture and history, particularly as it pertains to education, and largely from the Cree perspective. The third section contains my classroom activities, the goals I set for the students and the indicators with which I gauged and measured the effectiveness of the project. In conclusion, the implementation of cooperative learning methods yielded positive results both in student achievement and in decreasing truancy for Cree adult learners. The study confirms that cooperative learning can address students' needs to increase language proficiency and to be active participants in classroom activity. This model is congruent with Cree learners' collaborative and egalitarian values that are inherent in the traditional Cree culture.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>White, Boyd</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn17f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720f742</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Adult education -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indians of North America -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Group work in education -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859h450"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le moi et l'autre : le sujet dans le discours et le recit de soi</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rivet, Isabelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis attempts to address different problems pertaining to the concept of subject. These problems might appear remote from one another, but their juxtaposition reveals possible interactions that yield rich avenues of research. The ensuing dialogue provides an interesting portrait of the contemporary subject. Enunciation theories are the point of departure of this thesis. They contend that the subject constructs itself in and by discourse. A link is then made with certain problems put forward by Charles Taylor who also sets the contemporary subject in discourse, seen as essential material for its construction. The elaboration of a personal morality is the foundation of what he calls the self. The exploration of these problems draws our attention toward some questions which are tackled in the two last chapters. The first question concerns the mode of construction of the subject. In accordance with our modern episteme, the subject constructs itself as narrative. The second question aims at understanding the role of the Other in the construction of the subject. The contact with the Other and the recognition of this difference are the motors of this construction.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lane-Mercier, Gillian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg25h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h450</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Self (Philosophy) in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Philosophy, Modern</dc:subject><dc:subject>Taylor, Charles, 1931- Sources of the self</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290c347"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"...Templum nova forma constructum..." : early 17th-century late Gothic churches in Wolfenbüttel and Bückeburg</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roy, Francine, 1948-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the years around 1600, a change was noted in architecture towards a return to Gothic elements in Europe. The Gothic, in contrast to the Classical or Ancient, became a "new manner", a modern style. The residence churches at Wolfenbuttel and Buckeburg, which were erected around 1600 by Lower Saxon territorial princes, are Late Renaissance constructions that were made to look partly Gothic. This was neither a lingering on of Late Gothic design nor a misunderstanding of Renaissance architecture: it was rather a conscious evocation of the past and its merger with contemporary architecture. The forms of the churches recreated thus the sociopolitical reality of both Roman antiquity and the Middle Ages. This architecture was also emblematic in that it used the concrete objects of the churches as a means to convey an abstract content. Indeed, the aim was to provide a powerful political message, the confirmation of princely rule. In the rising absolutism of the beginnings of the 17th century, the builders of the Wolfenbuttel Marienkirche and the Buckeburg Stadtkirche used court architecture to construct their princely image and house mythology.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Böker, Hans J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qb671.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c347</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Architecture, Renaissance -- Germany -- Wolfenbüttel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hauptkirche Beatae Mariae Virginis (Wolfenbüttel, Germany)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stadtkirche (Bückeburg, Germany)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Church architecture -- Germany -- Bückeburg</dc:subject><dc:subject>Architecture, Renaissance -- Germany -- Bückeburg</dc:subject><dc:subject>Church architecture -- Germany -- Wolfenbüttel</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acv43p0036"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Personality and the awareness of God in Zinaida Gippius's theory of androgyny</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Robinson, Liam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Zinaida Gippius's literary works are striking for the development of the theme of androgyny. Chapter One examines the major Russian Symbolist intellectuals in their treatment of androgyny, which was animated by a desire to transfigure the world. Gippius's treatment of androgyny was at odds with the prevailing theory because it was not based on the defeminization of humanity. Chapter Two addresses Gippius's reconstruction of Symbolist androgyny theory and explains the rejection of gender-based motivation in her metaphysical system by its orientation toward personality and an awareness of God. Chapter Three shows how she used her poetry and prose to advance her belief that a perfect, androgynous love could reunite humanity with God. While Gippius's prose describes the search for this type of love, her poetry deals with it as a lyric experience. The religious motivations of Gippius's redefinition of Symbolist androgyny indicate the need to re-evaluate the place of Orthodox Christianity in the evolution of Russian Symbolism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beraha, Laura</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r743p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p0036</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gippius, Z. N. (Zinaida Nikolaevna), 1869-1945</dc:subject><dc:subject>Androgyny (Psychology) in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cz377"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Learning orientation in an educational organization : a contextually-based model of employee motivation to learn</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hamon, Suzanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This exploratory study examined the predictive ability of perceived work environment characteristics on employees' level of motivation to learn and growth need strength. It looked at motivation to learn within the context of two types of training: formal training and on-the-job training. It also examined the existence of group differences in motivation and in perceptions of the work environment. The sample was 117 middle management staff at a Canadian research university, varying in age, level of education, job classification, work unit, and job and institutional tenure. Data was collected using a questionnaire consisting of scales from the management and educational literature. Using multiple regression analysis and MANOVAs, workplace environmental characteristics were found to be predictors of employee motivation. The best predictor of motivation to learn was a composite measure of incentives, while the best predictor of growth need strength was a composite measure of lack of independence and freedom of choice. No group differences in motivational characteristics were found, however, there were differences in perceptions of the work environment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Donald, J. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cc76n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz377</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Motivation in education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Training of</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nc97s"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Neoliberal globalization and its critics : theory, practice and resistance in the Americas</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hidalgo, Luis F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper advances a theoretical construct entitled "neoliberal globalization" to explain the transformations in state form since the late 1970s which have been inspired by neoliberalism, an ideology privileging market mechanisms for capital accumulation and social organization. The essay will then examine the phenomenon of Canada's and Quebec's integration into the North American and the hemispheric economies since the mid-1980s. The following section will focus on the impact of neoliberal globalization on Quebec's idiosyncratic modalities of state organization and social integration. Lastly, the essay will investigate a transnational resistance movement in the Americas opposing neoliberal hemispheric integration, as well as recent mutations on Quebec's social and political left. The growth of cross-border coalitions opposing the Free Trade Area of the Americas (FTAA) and transformation of left politics in Quebec will be accounted for by reviewing theories of social movement internationalism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gagnon, Alain-G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x322k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nc97s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Globalization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Free trade -- North America</dc:subject><dc:subject>Québec (Province) -- Economic conditions -- 1991-</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Economic conditions -- 1991-</dc:subject><dc:subject>Protest movements -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p8946"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Jewish Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>R. Joseph della Reina and his damnation in the fiction of I. B. Singer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Johnson, Kelly Scott</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The following thesis focuses on the medieval kabbalistic legend of R. Joseph della Reina who, using traditions of esoteric magic, conjured Satan in order to slaughter him in an unsuccessful bid to force the Redemption of Israel. A translation of a version from eighteenth century Amsterdam is presented. Influenced by the heretical ideas of Sabbatianism, this version carries two opposing significations: that of a cautionary tale on one hand, that of a tragic tale of mystical heroism on the other. Based on evidence from the fiction of Isaac Bashevis Singer, the case is made that the modern author, in line with his philosophy of political passivism and historical pessimism, makes full use of the Faustian fascination of R. Joseph della Reina's fearsome story while repeatedly presenting the legend in such a way as to purge it of traditional ambiguity, undermine its tragic character, and leave behind only the aspect of caution or warning.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Orenstein, Eugene</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096907f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p8946</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Singer, Isaac Bashevis, 1904- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Legends, Jewish</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b071s"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cautious steps : the development and use of tactical air power by the RAF during the Second World War</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lawrence, Keith Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the doctrinal and practical development of tactical air forces by the Royal Air Force until the end of the Second World War. It focuses on the fundamental disagreements over the uses of air power, the preference for a strategic vision and the pressing need for tactical air forces in the face of the exigencies of war. This paper will trace the gradual provision of air support to the land forces and the formidable and fundamental changes that occurred during operations in various theatres in the Second World War.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Senior, Hereward</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k452x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b071s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Aerial operations, British</dc:subject><dc:subject>Air power</dc:subject><dc:subject>Great Britain. Royal Air Force -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207tr14w"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Participation incentives of skiers with a disability</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bilek, Jodi Lee, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to determine if age, gender, level of participation, onset of disability and sport classification have an impact on participation incentives (ego, fitness, social affective, social integration and task) in skiers with a disability. One hundred seventy-seven individuals between the ages of 4 and 66 years participated. The participants were described according to gender, time of onset of disability (congenital Vs acquired), level of sport involvement (recreation, local competition, provincial competition, national competition and international competition), and sport classification (LW1-LW9, LW10-LW12, blind, deaf and other [i.e. autistic, Down's Syndrome]). All the participants were active members of the Canadian Association of Disabled Skiing (CADS). The reasons for participation were evaluated using the Participation Reasons Scale (Brasile, 1988). MANOVA analysis indicated that significant relationships existed between age and individual items within the social affective and social integration incentive factors; gender and individual items within the ego incentive factor; level of participation and individual items within the ego, social affective, social integration and task incentive factors; onset of disability and individual items within the ego, social affective and social integration incentive factors; and sport classification and individual items within the social affective incentive factor. These results indicate that reasons for participation do differ among skiers with a disability and knowledge of these reasons may be important to be better able to design attractive and successful programs for the individual with a disability. These results are consistent with the Personal Investment Theory (Maehr and Braskamp, 1986) in that individuals will invest time and effort into physical activities that appeal to them and will be motivated by different aspects of the sport.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, Greg</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j47f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tr14w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Incentive (Psychology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sports for people with disabilities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Skiers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s202t"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les impacts constitutionnels et politiques du renvoi relatif a la secession du Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Berard, Frederic</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Un autre essai sur la sempiternelle question de l'unite canadienne, deplorez-vous presentement. Pis encore, ajoutez-vous, on y aborde une fois de plus l'ennuyeuse et l'ennuyante problematique constitutionnelle. Et pourquoi l'auteur a-t-il choisi un tel sujet? Parce qu'il fait partie de la race des fatigants mais infatigables maniaques de cet incessant debat qu'est celui des Deux Solitudes? Possible. Surement meme. Mais il y a plus: le Renvoi relatif a la secession du Quebec ne represente pas qu'un simple episode de la saga constitutionnelle canadienne. Vraisemblablement, ces implications pratiques pourraient un jour sceller l'issue du debat. Certes, le mouvement separatiste quebecois, loin d'etre moribond, ne s'eteindra pas sur la seule base d'une decision de la Cour supreme du Canada. Pretendre le contraire releve de la fantaisie, de l'outrecuidance ou encore, d'un manque tangible de pragmatisme politique. Toutefois, un fait persiste: applique in extenso, l'Avis s'avere une serieuse embuche sur le chemin menant a l'independance. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Manfredi, Christopher P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tt45q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s202t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Québec (Province) -- History -- Autonomy and independence movements</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada. Dept. of Justice</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada. Supreme Court</dc:subject><dc:subject>Constitutional law -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Secession -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Self-determination, National -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053h960"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Official language policy in Canada and Switzerland : language survival and political stability</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blaser, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The official language policies and their basic concepts, the principle of personality in Canada and the principle of territoriality in Switzerland, are critically analyzed. The two democratic federations are compared as two multination states since 'nation' is defined in cultural terms. Language survival is justified in liberal theory through minority rights. The principle of territoriality that assures the dominance of the linguistic majority over a territory within the federation is in accordance with liberal democracy if fundamental rights are protected. The principle of territoriality contributes thus to political stability within a multination federation. There is no movement in Switzerland that is fed by a language-based grievance despite the existence of three linguistic minorities: Switzerland accommodates successfully linguistic diversity. In Canada, the perception that the survival of the French language might not be sustained fuels a secessionist movement threatening the unity of the federation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gagnon, Alain-G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mk774.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h960</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Québec (Province) -- History -- Autonomy and independence movements</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language policy -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language policy -- Switzerland</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af4752j71r"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulatory focus and attachment models in close relationships</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bartz, Jennifer A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study first investigated the association between individuals' chronic regulatory styles and their attachment models in adult close relationships, and then looked at how individuals' chronic regulatory styles interact with their attachment models to influence relationship maintenance strategies (RMS) such as accommodating one's partner's transgressions and making personal sacrifices for the relationship. One hundred twenty-one dating-students completed the computerized Selves Questionnaire (Higgins et al., 1997) assessing ideal and ought discrepancies and their chronic accessibility (promotion and prevention focus strength), and then answered questions addressing attachment, accommodation and willingness to sacrifice. Results revealed that ought discrepancies were associated with avoidant attachment for high prevention focus strength individuals, whereas ideal discrepancies were associated with anxious attachment for low promotion focus strength individuals. Furthermore, prevention focus strength interacted with avoidant attachment, such that individuals with a strong prevention focus engaged in RMS to the extent that they were not avoidantly attached.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lydon, J. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h468.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j71r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Self</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wishes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interpersonal relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Attachment behavior</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128ng52t"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design of reconfigurable manipulation assist aids by fourier methods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nie, Xichun, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Our interest is in designing reduced degree-of-freedom articulated mechanical assistive devices capable of tracing desired end-effector paths in the plane with the ability to be easily reconfigured for different sets of tasks. We examine the use of a manipulator configuration called Single Degree-of-freedom Coupled Serial Chains (SDCSC). Such SDCSC configurations combine the motion flexibility due to multiple articulations with the simplicity of reduced-degree-of-freedom control and actuation due to the presence of hardware constraints and offer a low-cost alternative to expensive robotic manipulators. Our interest is in designing manipulators, based on such an SDCSC configuration, whose end-effector can match or closely approximate a set of positions along a desired planar path in the so-called Path Following problem. Past efforts examined the design of such manipulators for open-loop curves with limited applicability to closed-loop curves. To this end, we examine the development of a novel method for kinematic synthesis of such SDCSC mechanisms for such planar closed-loop path-following tasks. We also examine some of the issues related to converting the mathematical model into the physically realizable design of a reconfigurable prototype based on the SDCSC configuration. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Krovi, Venkat</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v79q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng52t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8336h366x"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Desalination by membrane distillation : a comparative study of tubular and hollow fibre membrane units</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Plasse, Ludovic</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Membrane distillation was considered as an alternative to traditional desalination processes because this technique produces ultra-pure water without requiring high temperatures nor high pressures. The driving force of membrane distillation is a temperature difference across a microporous membrane leading to a vapour pressure gradient. Hydrophobic membranes are used for membrane distillation in order to permit the passage of vapours through the pores while preventing the liquid phase from passing. The thickness of the membrane is a key variable which affects heat and mass transfers between the warm feed side and cooling side. In this thesis, a module with thin-walled hollow fibres was compared to a module with thicker tubular membranes. The permeate flux produced was compared at different operating conditions. Feed and cooling water flow rates and temperatures were varied. The impact of salt concentration in the feed was also examined. Different models based on first principles were developed and compared to a semi-empirical model based on the experimental determination of the mass transfer coefficient. Their predictions were compared with experimentally obtained permeate fluxes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Simandl, Jana</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010s04b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h366x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zg37d"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Composite bicycle fork design for vacuum assisted resin transfer moulding</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Octeau, Marc-Andre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The carbon fork developed for this thesis is a lightweight fork intended for the road racing athletes and amateurs. The work performed for this thesis includes geometrical and structural design of the fork but also concentrates on developing and optimizing a manufacturing process to create a complete solution for composite fabrication using vacuum assisted resin transfer moulding (VARTM). In the past many research projects concentrated on structural design and finite element analysis but failed to show satisfactory practical results due to poor manufacturing method for prototypes. This thesis emphasizes the development of the fabrication process. The stages for this thesis consist of analyzing previous work done on a carbon fibre fork and, from there, creating and developing a new fork whose weight will be reduced and performance increased. Using this new design, a new custom manufacturing process is implemented for VARTM. The final stage consists of producing prototypes and evaluating their performance and resistance under static and fatigue loadings.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lessard, Larry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d180v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg37d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bn57d"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of pressure on the rheological properties of three polyethylenes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Park, Hee Eon, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effect of pressure on the viscosity of polyethylenes was studied using a newly developed high-pressure, sliding-plate rheometer. The rheometer subjects the sample to a homogeneous pressure and temperature at levels up to 70 MPa and 225°C. Simple shear is generated in the sample, and the resulting shear stress is measured locally in the center of the sample by means of a shear stress transducer. Viscosity curves were generated at four pressures from 0.1 to 70 MPa, and it was found that the pressure data could be shifted onto the ambient pressure curves by means of a pressure shift factor. The viscosity increases exponentially with pressure. Long chain branching increases the pressure sensitivity, but the polydispersity has little effect. The effect of pressure on the creep behavior of polyethylenes was also studied. It was observed that pressure decreases the creep compliance. Careful tuning the controller is required to obtain reliable data when operating the rheometer in the creep mode.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dealy, John M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tt478.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn57d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plastics Technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aww72bd546"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Confinement of columns using headed bars</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Deng, Ying, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Eight full-scale columns were constructed and tested under monotonic axial compression loading to investigate the influence of headed bars on the confinement of the concrete. One column represented a column with no transverse reinforcement and another column had poor detailing and little confinement. A third column contained seismic hoops and crossties, which represented current detailing practice for significant confinement. A fourth column test investigated the response with the seismic crossties replaced by headed bars. Finally, two column specimens were constructed and tested with all of the transverse reinforcement provided by headed bars. These six specimens enabled an assessment of the effectiveness of headed bars in confining the concrete. It was found that the use of headed bars improved the confinement of the columns. Two additional specimens were constructed without any transverse reinforcement. These columns were later retrofitted, by drilling horizontal holes in the columns, adding special headed bars (one head fixed and one head threaded) and then filling the drilled holes with epoxy. These retrofitted specimens had two different spacings for the added headed bars. The improvement of the response with these added headed bars provided insight into the rehabilitation of older structures containing poorly detailed columns. All of the test specimens were instrumented to determine strain localization during failure and to monitor the strains in the longitudinal and transverse reinforcement.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mitchell, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rg33c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd546</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asj1393890"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A stochastic pool-based electricity market simulator</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chua, Cheong Wei, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In Part I, two pool-based electricity market models are compared in terms of their economic impact on the market participants, the Lossless Economic Dispatch (LED) and the Optimal Power Flow (OPF). The OPF is shown to be economically more efficient, more accurate and more equitable to the participants. In Part II, a stochastic electricity market simulator (SEMS) is designed using elements of Monte Carlo methods and game theory. Each generator is assumed to operate in a stochastic manner, according to a bid strategy composed of a set of pre-established bid instances and a corresponding set of bid probabilities. The Pool dispatches power and defines prices according to either the LED or OPF models from Part I. Generators can update their bidding strategies according to a profit performance index reflecting their degree of risk tolerance, Chicken (risk averse), Average, and Cowboy (risk taker). SEMS can predict issues such as unintended collusion, as well as to evaluate bidding strategies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Galiana, F. D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj286.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1393890</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economics, Commerce-Business</dc:subject><dc:subject>Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amp48sf50c"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The wear resistance of commercially produced aluminum oxide ceramics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cloutier, Caroline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>High hardness, fracture toughness, modulus of rupture and fine grain size are material properties that are desired for components employed in aggressive wear environments. Since aluminum oxide offers such properties, this type of material is often selected for applications that demand wear resistance. Aluminum oxide materials commercially produced at Superior Technical Ceramics were investigated to find a correlation between their mechanical properties and wear resistant performance. A pin-on-disc apparatus and a tumbling test were employed to determine the relative difference in wear between different alumina compositions. The selected 88%, 96%, 98% purple, 98% alumina and zirconia toughened alumina were subjected to four different wear tests in order to determine their wear behavior in each system. The objective was to characterize the compositions according to their mechanical properties and to establish a wear material selection guide for Superior Technical Ceramics. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>ew, Robin A. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m5868.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sf50c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>