<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860936n"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Component Reading Skills Training of Children with Different Types of Reading Disabilities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fierdorowicz, Christina A.M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Fifteen reading disabled boys classified according to reading subskill deficits formed three subgroups: Oral Reading, Associative, and Sequential. On the rationale that training procedures emphasizing accuracy and speed of response to letters, syllables, and words would improve reading skills, the children were trained daily for 2 months. Two schedules of testing and training allowed for an untrained control group and a follow-up group. An average reader sample of 45 boys were also assessed to obtain comparative data on a computerized battery of component reading skills. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Quinze garçons présentant des problèmes en lecture et classés selon leurs déficiences particulières ont été répartis en trois groupes: lecture orale, lecture associative, lecture séquentielle. A partir du principe qu'un entrainement visant 1' exactitude et la rapidité~ de la response aux lettres, aux syllabes, et aux mots puisse améliorer leur aptitude à lire, les enfants ont subi un entrainement quotidien pendant 2 mois. Deux différentes séquences d'administration de tests et d'entrainement ont pu inscrire au programme un groupe controle et un groupe de relance. Un groupe type de 45 garçons, d'aptitude moyenne en lecture, a été évalué afin d'obtenir des normes pour une batterie de tests informatisés mesurant les habilités fodamentales en lecture. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Doehring, D. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mh913.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860936n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Reading disability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reading (Elementary) -- Computer-assisted instruction</dc:subject><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching (Elementary)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gw07f"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Charge Transport in Electrostatic Radiography</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fallone, B. Gino</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The charging characteristics of ionographic latent images are discussed in terms of saturation characteristics of ionographic chambers. Latent images are essentially foil électrets with surface charge densities proportional to the x-ray transmission through the object. A hyperbolic expression is developed which accurately describes the full saturation curve for x-rays and cobalt-60 gamma rays of parallel-plate ionization chambers filled with air, or with high atomic number gases at elevated pressures. Foil électrets with surface charge densities of up to 10-6 C/cm2 and ionographic latent images are formed by blocking the collecting electrode of the chamber with a polymer. The hyperbolic expression is utilized to derive an accurate representation of the charging and discharging dynamics of the latent image. The theory of linear systems is used to derive the electric field and potential inside the électret chamber, and the solutions are equal to those obtained from Gauss' law at the surface of the électret, and to those obtained from a dipole layer model at large distances from the surface. An analog radiographic image subtraction technique based on the charging characteristics of ionographic latent images, formed either with a solid photoconductor or with a gas as the radiation sensitive medium, is described. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La formation de l'image latente ionographique est traitée en termes de phénomène de saturation des chambres ionographiques. L'image latente est constituée par la densité de charge à la surface d'électrets minces. La densité de charge est reliée à la transmissiondes rayons X par l'objet étudie. Une expression de forme hyperbolique décrit entièrement la courbe de saturation des chambres d'ionisation à électrodes parallèles, irradiées par rayons X ou par photons de cobalt-60. Elles peuvent être emplies d'air, ou de gaz de numéro atomique élevé à haute pression. Des électrets minces, de densité de charge atteignant le microcoulomb par centimètre carre, sont réalises en interceptant sur un polymère les charges attirées par une des électrodes. L'expression hyperbolique permet une représentation fidèle de la charge et de la décharge de l'électret. La théorie des systèmes linéaires fournit le champ et le potentiel à l'intérieur de la chambre d'ionisation à électret. Les mêmes résultats sont obtenus soit par !'application de la loi de Gauss à la surface de l'électret, soit par le calcul à grande distance d'un feuillet dipolaire. On décrit aussi une technique de soustraction analogique basée sur les caractéristiques de charge et de décharge des images latentes ionographiques. Le milieu sensible peut être un gaz ou un photoconducteur solide.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Podgorsak, E. B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892d40r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gw07f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Radiography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electric charge and distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electrostatics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amp48sg04g"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Syntheses et Reactions de Quelques Complexes Hydrures et Hydruro-Olefiniques de l’Iridium</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Drouin, Michel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The main objective of this work was the generation of the species IrH(CO)(PPh3)2 at low temperature in order to check whether trans oxidative addition of dihydrogen to this intermediate may occur. The strategy adopted was the synthesis of a series of complexes IrH(CO)(PPh3 ) 2 (ol), where ol is an asymmetrical and labile alkene. In the case where ol = styrene, the complex exhibited optimum properties and it has been shown that concerted addition of H2 to IrH(CO)(PPh3 ) 2 gave only the cis products. These hydrido-olefinic compounds, with ol = CH2=CHX, X= CN, COOCH3 , c6a5 , Cl and CH2=C(Cl)CN, were characterized by IR and NMR; the 1H-NMR spectra were particularly interesting and indicated the presence of two rotamers in equilibrium for each species. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le principal objectif de ces travaux était de générer l'espèce IrH(CO)(PPh3 ) 2 à basse température dans le but de vérifier si l'addition oxydante de dihydrogène à cet intermédiaire était possible. La stratégie adoptée consistait dans la synthase des complexes IrH(CO)(PPh3 ) 2 (ol) ou ol = alcène asymétrique et labile; cette approche s'est avérée une réussite avec ol = styrène et il a été démontré que l'addition concertée de H2 à IrH(CO)P2 conduisait exclusivement aux produits cis. Ces composés hydruro-oléfiniques ou ol = CH2=CHX, X = CN, COOCH3 , c6H5 , Cl, et CH2=C(Cl)CN, lesquels existent sous la forme de deux rotamères en équilibre, ont été caractérisés par IR et RMN. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Harrod, John F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sz39j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sg04g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hydrides</dc:subject><dc:subject>Alkenes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iridium</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rn59q"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the Effect of the Phenolic Antioxidant Butylated Hydroxyanisole on Staphylococcus Aureus Wood 46</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Degré, Richard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L’activité antimicrobienne de l’antioxidant phénolique butyl-hydroxyanisole (BHA) est connue depuis quelque années déjà mais ses effets sur le métabolisme bactérien demeurent cependant inconnus. Nous avons donc étudier ses effets chez Staphylococcus aureus Wood 46, un microorganisme implique dans de nombreuses intoxications alimentaires. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The antimicrobial activity of the phenolic antioxidant butylated hydroxyanisole (BHA) has been known for several years but the lack of knowledge of its specific effects n bacterial metabolism prompted us to study how the antioxidant affected the food-borne pathogen Staphylococcous aureus Wood 46. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sylvestre, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq881.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rn59q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Staphylococcus aureus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anti-infective agents</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antioxidants</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445cg84p"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A Neuropharmacological Study of Homosynaptic Depression of the Spinal Stretch Reflex Loop: The Actions of Benzodiazepines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Davies, M. Frances</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The actions of benzodiazepines on homosynaptic depression of the spinal stretch reflex were examined in spinal cats. On the biceps semitendinosus pathway (BST), clonazepam enhanced the depression of the second response of the early tetanic rundown (ETR) (10 stimuli at 10, S, and 2 Hz every EO seconds) without affecting the first response or the plateau level. This effect was antagonized by an antagonist for the central benzodiazepine receptor, Ro15-17BB, and by reducing GABAergic transmission with semicarbazide or bicuculline. On the triceps surae (TS) pathway, clonazepam increased the first response and alleviated the depression of the second response without changing the plateau level. Clonazepam appeared to influence BST homosynaptic depression by lengthening the primary afferent depolarization (PAD). The PAD also underwent depression, therefore later responses in the ETR were unaffected by clonazepam. TS ETRs were not similarly affected because activation of TS afferents did not cause a significant PAD of its own afferents. Mercaptopropionic acid was shown to be unsuitable as a GABA depleting agent for in vivo experiments in the feline spinal cord. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The actions of benzodiazepines on homosynaptic depression of the spinal stretch reflex were examined in spinal cats. On the biceps semitendinosus pathway (BST), clonazepam enhanced the depression of the second response of the early tetanic rundown (ETR) (10 stimuli at 10, S, and 2 Hz every EO seconds) without affecting the first response or the plateau level. This effect was antagonized by an antagonist for the central benzodiazepine receptor, Ro15-17BB, and by reducing GABAergic transmission with semicarbazide or bicuculline. On the triceps surae (TS) pathway, clonazepam increased the first response and alleviated the depression of the second response without changing the plateau level. Clonazepam appeared to influence BST homosynaptic depression by lengthening the primary afferent depolarization (PAD). The PAD also underwent depression, therefore later responses in the ETR were unaffected by clonazepam. TS ETRs were not similarly affected because activation of TS afferents did not cause a significant PAD of its own afferents. Mercaptopropionic acid was shown to be unsuitable as a GABA depleting agent for in vivo experiments in the feline spinal cord. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Capek, Radan</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Esplin, Barbara</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn94j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg84p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Homosynaptic Depression</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214r60t"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Philosophy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reasons and Oughts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Conter, David Barnet</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Si ce qu'une personne devrait faire s'entend en termes de ce pour quoi il y a une raison pour ainsi faire, alors ce que cette personne devrait faire légalement (moralement, médicalement, etc.) n'est pas une question de ce qu'un être parfait devrait faire. Une proposition spécifie une raison pour une personne de faire une chose précisément dans le cas où elle est positivement pertinente à la probabilité objective de l'hypothèse qu'il est maximalement bon pour cette personne d'agir ainsi. Une personne devrait faire une chose dans les cas ou (i) il y a une raison pour qu'elle agisse ainsi et (ii) si elle ne le fait pas il y a une raison pour critiquer son comportement. Il est possible qu'une personne ne doive pas faire ce qui est logiquement nécessaire afin de faire ce qu'elle devrait faire. En termes légaux (moraux, etc.) une personne devrait faire une chose exactement dans le cas où elle devrait faire cette chose précisément à condition que ses propres priorités reflètent les priorités légales. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>If what a person ought to do can be understood in terms of what there is reason for the person to do, then what he or she ought to do, legally speaking (morally speaking, medically speaking, etc.), is not a matter of what some ideal agent ought to do. A proposition specifies a reason for a person to do something iff it is positively relevant to the prior objective probability of the hypothesis that it is maximally good for the person to do that thing. A person ought to do something iff (i) there is a reason for the person to do that thing and (ii) if the person does not do it, there is a reason to review the person's conduct critically. So understood, «ought» is not closed under entailment. Legally speaking (morally speaking, etc.), a person ought to do something iff the person ought to do that thing just in case the person's own priorities reflect legal (moral, etc.) priorities. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Trentman, John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj717.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r60t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Reason</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ethics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Conduct of Life</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35tb771"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Health</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comparative Clinical Efficacy of Computed Tomography, Ultrasonography, and Nuclear Medicine in Abdominal Application – A Clinical Trial</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boyle, Pierre B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Although computed tomography has received wide acceptance and rapid diffusion, its clinical efficacy relative to that of competing technologies has not been clearly demonstrated in non-neurological applications. Two-hundred and thirty-one consecutive in-patients investigated for suspected hepatic masses or pancreatic disorders at Royal Victoria Hospital were randomly assigned to computed tomography, nuclear medicine or ultrasonography. Each of the three technologies was assessed on various measures of diagnostic and management efficacy. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Malgré que la scanographie fut rapidement acceptée et diffusée, son efficacité clinique relativement à celle de technologies alternatives n'a pas été démontrée clairement dans des applications non-neurologiques. Deux cent trente et un patients consécutifs admis à l'hôpital Royal Victoria pour étude de masses hépatiques ou de maladies du pancréas furent assignes aléatoirement à la scanographie, a la médecine nucléaire ou à l'échographie. Chaque technologie fut évaluée selon divers indicateurs d'efficacité diagnostique et de prise en charge. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hoey, John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010s51q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb771</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ultrasonography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tomography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bw92v"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An Investigation of the Divergent Thinking Skills of Emotionally Disturbed Adolescents of Emotionally Disturbed Adolescents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Berman, Steven L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study explored the ability of public students labelled emotionally disturbed toI school think divergently. The specific purpose was to discover whether these students would have greater difficulty than normal students on divergent thinking tasks. A second purpose was to evaluate the effects of an intervention course in creative problem-solving that was taught to a sample of students labelled emotionally disturbed. Subjects consisted of forty-five students from one of three public high schools under the Protestant School Board of Greater Montreal. Twenty-two of these subjects were labelled emotionally disturbed and the remaining twenty-three were classified as normal. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette étude porte sur l'habileté des élèves appelés émotionnellement handicapes dans les écoles publiques à penser d'une manière originale. Le but précis en était de voir si ces élèves éprouveraient plus de difficultés que les élèves dits normaux dans des taches ou cette qualité serait requise. On désirait aussi évaluer les effets d'un cours dispense a un échantillon d'élèves émotionnellement handicapés sur la créativité dans la solution de problèmes. Les sujets de l’étude étaient au nombre de quarante-cinq et venaient d'une des trois écoles secondaires du Bureau des Eccles protestantes du Grand Montréal. Sur ces quarante-cinq, vingt-deux sujets étaient émotionnellement handicapes, le reste étant considéré comme normal. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mager, George C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cw517.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw92v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Children with mental disabilities -- Psychological testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Problem solving in children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thought and thinking</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278w795"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quantification and Characterization of the Motion and Shape of a Moving Cell</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Youssef, Youssry M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The main function of a blood cell's surface is to receive information the environment. Recently, experiments have indicated that the cell membrane plays a vital role in the life, development, and regulation of cells. However, there is no existing method to quantify the observable changes in   membrane shape that occur in locomotion. To achieve this objective using automatic techniques of digital image processing, the main goal of this research is to develop an image interpretation system capable of analyzing the structural changes in the morphology of a non-rigid moving object from a sequence of pictures. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La principale fonction de la membrane d'un globule est de recevoir de l’information de son environnement. Recemment, des expériences ont démontré que la membrane joue un role primordial dans la vie, le développement et la régulation des globules. Toutefois, il n'existe pas de méthode permettant de quantifier les changements observables de la forme de la membrane au cours de la locomotion. Afin d'atteindre cet objectif tout en utilisant des techniques automatiques de traitement des images digitales, le but principal de cette recherche est de concevoir un système d'interprétation d'images capable d'analyser les changements structuraux de la morphologie d'un objet non-rigide en mouvement à partir d'une séquence d'images. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Levine, M. D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw09x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278w795</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cells -- Motility -- Data processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Blood cells</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amc87ps98r"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Adaptive Transform Coding of Speech Signals</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pinnell, Richard James</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les techniques de codage dans le domaine fréquentiel ont récemment fait l'objet d'une attention considérable. Le codage de transformées par adaptation y occupe une place de choix, parce qu’il permet une excellente qualité de transmission de la parole pour des débits faibles ou moyens (8-16kHz). Les systèmes de codage de transformées par adaptation effectuent une segmentation de la parole en diverses composantes fréquentielles grâce à l'utilisation d'une transformée appropriée et transmettent ces composantes à l’aide de la modulation par impulsion et codage (MIC). […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Frequency domain coding techniques have recently received considerable attention. Prominent among these techniques, adaptive transform coding offers excellent speech quality for low to medium data rates (8-16 kb/sec ). Adaptive transform coders divide speech into frequency components by using a suitable transform and transmit these components using pulse code modulation (PCM). […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kabal, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p970t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87ps98r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Speech processing systems</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw9505279g"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Convergence Properties of Fractionally-Spaced Equalizers for Data Transmission</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pekiner, M. Melih</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis considers the convergence properties of adaptive equalizers used for data transmission. In the conventional form of a tapped delay line equalizer, the tap spacing is equal to the symbol interval T. Two other cases are discussed. The fractional-spaced equalizer has tap spacing less than T ( T /2 is considered in detail). A hybrid configuration uses both T spaced and fractional T spaced tap is also considered. From the mathematical derivations and the computer simulations the properties, the relative advantages and drawbacks of the three cases are analysed. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette the traite des propriétés de convergence des égaliseurs conventionnels dans le domaine des transmissions de données. Dans un égaliseur conventionnel la distance entre perforations correspond à l'intervalle entre symboles T. Deux autres configurations sont ici considérés: l'égaliseur à espace fractionnel dont la distance entre perforations est inferieure a T, et l'égaliseur hybride, utilisant des distances de perforation égales à T et inferieures à T. Les différentes propriétés, avantages et inconvénients des trois types d'égaliseurs sont comparés sur une base mathématique et de simulation par ordinateur. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kabal, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qm285.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505279g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Data transmission systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>Equalizers (Electronics)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97ks866"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of Reticulocyte Surface Specific Antigens: Their Induced Redistribution and Externalization by the Specific Antibodies in Sheep Reticulocytes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pan, Bin-Tao</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des antigènes spécifiques de la surface membranaire de réticulocytes de mouton ont été isoles en utilisant des anticorps spécifiquement développés contre la surface cellulaire. Le récepteur de la transferrine a été identifié comme l'antigène spécifique majeur des membranes. La caractérisation du récepteur a permis de déterminer un poids moléculaire d'environ 93,000 pour sa forme monomérique et qu'il existe probablement in situ sous une forme dimérique. Il a été aussi établi que les sites antigéniques diffèrent de ceux impliques pour la liaison avec la transferrine. De plus, mous avons montré que la quantité de récepteurs de la transferrine décroit pour éventuellement devenir nulle lorsque les réticulocytes sont cultivés in vitro. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Sheep reticulocyte surface specific antigens have been isolated by anti-reticulocyte surface specific antibodies. Moreover, the major specific antigen has been identified as the transferrin receptor. Characterization of the receptor has shown it has a monomeric molecular weight of approximately 93,000 and that it probably exists as a dimer in situ. It has been shown that the antigenic sites differ from the transferrin binding sites and that the receptor spans the membrane. Moreover, it has been shown the transferrin receptors decrease and disappear when reticulocytes are cultured in vitro. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Johnstone, Rose M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mh92c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks866</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Antibodies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zg88w"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Economic and Legal Developments on Carriage of Goods by Air</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ndum, Fidelis Nkom</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'industrie du fret aérien est en plein expansion et ses lois doivent devélopper en fonction. Simple constituant négligeable du trafic passagers autrefois, le trafic fret est devenu au cours des années une industrie à part entier, très rentable et marquée par des développements économiques galopants, d'une part, et par des développements légaux qui trainent, d'autre ~art. La plupart des lois qui gouvernent 1' industrie proviennent des traités internationaux dont 1' un des plus important, la Convention de Varsovie, s'avère de plus insatisfaisante en raison de son obsolescence. Alors, devient-il impératif que soient ratifiée toutes les protocoles portant sa modification ainsi que les nouvelles conventions supplémentaires en vue de leur mise en rigueur dans les meilleurs délais. Entretemps, la jurisprudence restera l'instrument le plus important pour réduire l'écart entre devéloppements économiques et développements légaux.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The Air freight industry is a progressive industry which requires progressive laws. Over the years, carriage of goods by air has evolved from a mere by-product of air-passenger carriage to a full-fledged remarkably profitable market characterized by fast-paced economic developments on the one hand, but slow-paced legal developments on the other hand. The primary source of the law regulating the industry is international treaties. One of the most important of them is the Warsaw Convention which now risks losing its utility because of its obsolescence. It is very important, therefore, that the various protocols amending, as well as the new conventions supplementing, it are given the required ratifications to enter into force as soon as possible. Unless and until that is done, however, case law remains the most significant recourse for narrowing the gap between the economic and legal developments. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bradley, Martin A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jx02w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg88w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Air freight</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cd27x"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electronic Model of Turbine Generator Including Reheaters, Governor and Shaft Torsional System</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Legault, Pierre R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An analog simulator for the turbine-generator shaft assembly has been developed. The simulator consists of the following electronic modules: 1) Inertia-Shaft Modules1) Turbine Section 2) Generator Unit 2) Exciter Module 3) Steam Distribution Modules 4) Speed-Governor Module These modules offer flexibility of simulating a variety of turbine-reheat configurations. The design of the modules has been proven by frequency domain test of individual modules, and their combination as a system. This simulator has been developed as an addition to the existing electronic simulator of generators and power systems at the Institut de Recherche de l'Hydro-Quebec.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Un simulateur analogique pour l'assemblage axial d'un turbo-générateur a été développe. Ce simulateur est compose des modules électroniques suivants: 1) des modules d'inerties axiales pour i) une section de turbine ii) un générateur 2) un module d’excitateur 3) un module de distribution de vapeur 4) un module de régulateur de vitesse Ces modules offrent la possibilité de simuler une variété de configurations pour turbines avec resurchauffage. La validitédes modules a été demontré par une série de tests dans le domaine de fréquences, pour chaqu'un des modules individuellement, ainsi que pour (un système particulier au complet). Ce simulateur a été developpé pour augmenter les (capacités) existances d'un simulateur électronique de générateurs et de réseaux de puissance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ooi, B. T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z769b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cd27x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Steam-turbines -- Models -- Data processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Steam-boilers -- Models -- Data processing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386m86v"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plastic Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bone Grafting: A Comparative Analysis of Vascularized and Non Vascularized Autografts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lalonde, Donald H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Vascular perfusion studies, histology, tetracycline labelling, and technitium99 scintigraphy were used to compare conventional rib grafts with and without periosteum to rib grafts vascularized by vascular bundle implantation, by dermis island flaps, and by microvascular anastomosis of graft nutrient vessels in dogs. Results indicated that: 1) The vascular pattern of posterior microvascularized rib grafts is identical to that of normal ribs. 2) Implanted vascular bundles remain patent and revascularize bone grafts. 3) Circulation in rib grafts and the patency of anastomoses of microvascularized rib grafts are accurately reflected in technitium99 bone scans. 4) Tetracycline labelling is not a reliable indicator of the patency of a bone graft's pedicle blood supply. 5) The vascular invasion of failed microvascularlzed rib grafts is slower than that of conventional rib grafts. 6) The presence or absence of periosteum has no observable effect on graft revascularization. 7) Dermis island flaps did not enhance graft vascularization.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Nous avons mené des études de perfusion vasculaire, de marquage à la tétracycline, de scintigraphie osseuse au technitium99 et d'histologie pour comparer les greffes costales conventionelles, avec ou sans périoste, aux greffes costales nourries par implantation du paquet vasculaire, par ilot dermique et par anastomose microvasculaire des vaisseaux nourriciers du greffon dans le chien. Nos résultats indiquent que: 1) La vasculature des greffons costaux postérieurs microvascularisés est identique à celle des cotes normales. 2)Les implants du paquet vasculaire demeurent perméables et revascularisent les greffes osseuses. 3) la scintigraphie au technitium99 est un reflet précis de la circulation dans les greffons osseux et de la perméabilité des anastomoses dans les greffons microvascularises, 4)Le marquage a la tétracycline n'est pas un indicateur fiable de la perméabilité des vasseaux sanguins nourriciers de greffons osseux. 5)L'invasion vasculaire d'un greffon costal microvascularisé non-perméable est plus lente· que celle observée dans un greffon costal conventional. 6)La présence ou l'absence de périoste n'a pas d'effet observable sur la revascularisation du greffon, 7)Les ilots dermiques n’ont pas accéléré la vascularisation des greffons.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Williams, Bruce</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ck02h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m86v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Vascular perfusion</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag732dc30m"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Time Independent Spreading of One Liquid on the Surface of Another Liquid</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Labib, Samy E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse investigue l'épandage régulier et unidirectionel d'une couche d'huile sur une surface d'eau. L'étude est constituée de trois parties principales. Dans le première partie, le répandage régulier et unidirectionel d'une couche d'huile soumise à un débit d'eau décrivant les déplacements dans ce cas sont solutionnées numériquement. Dans la deuxième partie, les effets de la variation de la pression due au changement de vélocité du substrat en fonction de la position sont examinés pour le cas étudié dans la première partie. Telle variation de la vitesse du substrat en fonction de la position est due à la dépression de la surface commune hui1e-eau. Les équations gouvernantes pour ce cas sont obtenue et solutionnées numériquement. Dans la dernière partie, des expériences destinées à reproduire les situations ce-haut mentionnées sont effectuées. Les resultats obtenus sont comparés aux solutions théoriques et numériques. Une bonne correspondance est généralement observée.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In this thesis, the steady uni-directional spreading of an oil layer on the surface of water is investigated. This study consists of three main parts. In the first part, the steady uni-directional spreading of an oil layer against a uniform flow of water is considered. The general equations describing the motion for this case are solved numerically. In the second part, the effect of pressure variation due to the change in the substrate velocity with position is examined for the case studied in the first part. Such variation in the substrate velocity with position is caused by the depression of the oil-water interface. The governing equations for this case are obtained and solved numerically. In the last part, experiments designed to duplicate the above mentioned situations are performed. The experimental results are compared to both the theory and the numerical solutions obtained. A generally good agreement is observed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paidoussis, M. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3613.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732dc30m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Oil spills -- Fluid dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Liquids</dc:subject><dc:subject>Liquid films</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acz30pw11z"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Effect of Randomly Varying Added Mass on the Dynamics of a Flexible Cylinder in Two-Phase Axially Flowing Fluid</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Klein, Christophe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates the effect of randomly varying added mass on the dynamics of a flexible cylinder in an external axial two-phase flow, bounded by a rigid immobile channel. The behaviour of a cylinder in two-phase flow has been found to be very different and less predictable than in single-phase flow. Experiments have shown that damping is significantly higher in simulated two-phase flows, depending on the flow regime, and that the hydrodynamic or added mass decreases with increasing void fraction, but at a higher rate than that of the mixture density. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse traite de l'effet de fluctuations aléatoires de la masse ajoutée sur le comportement dynamique d'un cylindre flexible soumis à un écoulement externe, axial et diphasique, limité par un conduit rigide et immobile. Il a été établi que le comportement d'un cylindre dans un écoulement diphasique est très diffèrent et mains prévisible que dans un écoulement  monophasique. Des expériences ont montre que l'amortissement est nettement plus élevé dans des écoulements diphasiques simules, suivant le régime d'écoulement, et que la masse hydrodynamique, ou masse ajoutée, décroit lorsque le pourcentage de vapeur s'accroit, mais ceci plus rapidement que ne le fait la densité du mélange. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paidoussis, M. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g5094.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pw11z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cylinders -- Vibration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Two-phase flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cylinders -- Hydrodynamics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236461r"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Women and water «wahala»: Picturing gendered waterscapes in Southwest Cameroon</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thompson, Jennifer</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>With gendered divisions of labour, many women play an important role in daily water management. Women therefore have specific experiential knowledge with water and are disproportionately impacted by water access challenges. Yet women’s priorities and the gendered nature of water use, access, and control are often overlooked in water policy and research. This bias perpetuates ‘gender-neutral’ water management strategies and distorts how water problems are addressed. Responding to calls for broader approaches to water governance that include social power, this study explores the gendered politics of the waterscape in Cameroon. Bringing together feminist intersectionality theory and new thinking about the politics and materiality of water, I explore through participatory visual methodologies women’s and men’s everyday water experiences. In collaboration with a civil society organization, Changing Mentalities and Empowering Groups (CHAMEG), I co-facilitated photovoice and participatory video processes in two urban and two rural communities in Cameroon’s Southwest Region involving 130 participants (96 women and 34 men). Participant-produced images and participant-led analysis emphasize women’s daily problems or troubles (wahala in Pidgin English) with water. Despite an abundance of freshwater available in the vicinity of Mount Cameroon, the services from both partially privatized and community-managed water supply networks tend to be unreliable. Multiple alternative sources such as wells, springs, and streams provide resilience for communities to fulfill their daily water needs. Yet these alternatives also present gendered concerns about, for example, the embodied and emotional labour related to searching for water, sexual and gender-based violence, intra-household dynamics, and the technologies of water access, storage, and treatment. Participants also identified the gendered nature of planning and sanitation in relation to water quality, source protection, and sustainability. A discussion forum with local decision-makers provided an opportunity to interrogate the implications of the research for local change, which highlighted the politics of participation, community, authority, and water decision-making. In applying an intersectional lens that attends to social difference and the complexity of gender, the materiality of water and water infrastructure also emerged as critical factors influencing experience. I suggest that these interconnections between the social and the material have implications for intersectionality theory. Offering a deconstruction of the theory, I propose four analytic tools for looking at intersectionality: Simultaneity, situated specificity, relationality, and fluid consistencies. These tools or mechanisms help to widen the analytical frame of intersectional thinking to include the mutual entanglements between gendered social relations of power and the materiality of water. The thesis contributes to the areas of gender and development in Cameroon, participation in water governance, feminist intersectionality theory, and the use of visual methodologies for water research.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Compte tenu de la division du travail entre les sexes, de nombreuses femmes jouent un rôle important dans la gestion de l’eau au quotidien. Les femmes détiennent donc des connaissances expérientielles particulières sur l’eau, et elles sont affectées de manière disproportionnée par les problèmes d’accès à l’eau. Pourtant, les priorités des femmes et la nature genrée de la consommation d’eau, de l’accès à l’eau, et de son contrôle sont souvent négligées dans les politiques et les recherches sur l’eau. En conséquence, on tend à perpétuer des stratégies de gestion de l’eau qui ne tiennent pas compte du sexe, et à aborder les problèmes relatifs à l’eau de manière faussée. Répondant aux appels à des approches plus globales de la gestion de l’eau qui tiennent compte du pouvoir social, la présente étude explore les politiques genrées du paysage hydrique au Cameroun. Convoquant à la fois la théorie féministe de l’intersectionnalité et les nouvelles approches concernant la politique et la matérialité de l’eau, j’y explore par l’intermédiaire de méthodologies visuelles participatives les expériences que les femmes et les hommes ont avec l’eau au quotidien. En collaboration avec une organisation de la société civile, Changing Mentalities and Empowering Groups (CHAMEG), j’ai coanimé des processus photovoice et de vidéo participative dans deux collectivités urbaines et deux collectivités rurales de la région du Sud-Ouest du Cameroun auprès de 130 participants (96 femmes et 34 hommes). Les images produites par les participants et les analyses qu’ils ont dirigées mettent l’accent sur les problèmes ou difficultés (wahala, en pidgin anglais) qu’éprouvent les femmes au quotidien en ce qui a trait à l’eau. Malgré l’abondance d’eau douce à proximité du mont Cameroun, les services des réseaux d’approvisionnement en eau y sont peu fiables, qu’ils soient partiellement privatisés ou gérés par la collectivité. De nombreuses autres sources d’eau, comme des puits, des sources, et des ruisseaux, permettent de répondre aux besoins des collectivités au quotidien. Cependant, ces autres sources posent aussi des problèmes genrés, par exemple, en ce qui concerne le travail incorporé et le travail émotionnel associés à la recherche d’eau, la violence sexuelle et fondée sur le sexe, les dynamiques intrafamiliales et les technologies d’accès à l’eau, de même que les technologies d’entreposage et de traitement de l’eau. Les participants soulignent également la nature genrée de la planification et de l’assainissement relativement à la qualité de l’eau, à la protection des sources, et à la durabilité. Un forum de discussion avec des décideurs locaux a été l’occasion d’interroger la contribution de la recherche au changement à l’échelle locale, ce qui a mis en relief les politiques liées à la participation, à la collectivité, à l’autorité, et à la prise de décisions concernant l’eau. Sous une perspective intersectionnelle portant attention à la différence sociale et à la complexité du genre, la matérialité de l’eau et de l’infrastructure de l’eau sont également ressortis comme étant des facteurs cruciaux influençant l’expérience. Je suggère que ces interconnexions entre le social et le matériel ont des implications sur la théorie de l’intersectionnalité. Offrant une déconstruction de cette théorie, je propose quatre outils analytiques pour l’envisager: la simultanéité, la spécificité située, la relationalité, et les constantes fluides. Ces outils ou mécanismes aident à élargir le cadre analytique de la pensée intersectionnelle pour y inclure les enchevêtrements mutuels entre les relations de pouvoir genrées à l’échelle sociale et la matérialité de l’eau. La présente thèse apporte une contribution aux domaines du genre et du développement au Cameroun, de la participation à la gouvernance de l’eau, à la théorie féministe de l’intersectionnalité, et à l’utilisation de méthodologies visuelles pour la recherche sur l’eau.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Claudia A. Mitchell</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Susan J. Gaskin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440w14x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236461r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t449f"><ual:graduationDate>1933</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The unstriated muscle fibre of the female pelvis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Power, Richard M. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The problems of mechanics of the uterine supports have attracted the attention of investigators for the past century. The early workers devoted themselves to the anatomy of the "ligamentous supportsx of the uterus". It seems to have been assunmed that these uterine ligaments were in reality fibrous structures and it was not until 1888, whejn Ziegenspeck and Winckel demonstrated the presence of smooth muscle in the base of the broad ligament, that the notion of a possible muscular support for the uterus, othe than that provided by the levator ani, was conceived.[...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qv34n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t449f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pelvis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214r613"><ual:graduationDate>1932</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cyclic acetal formation, the ring-partition principle and their relation to the structure of carbohydrates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Platt, Muriel Estelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The importance of cyclic acetal and ketal glycerols has long attracted the interest of investigators in the fireld of carbohydrate chemistry. Such workers as Tollens, Fischer, Karer, Irvine and Hibbert have studied, or used this class of compounds int heir efforts to explain, by analogy, certain features of the chemical behaviour fo sugars and the more complex polysacharides.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hibbert, Harold</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053j63n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r613</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sugars</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zd59k"><ual:graduationDate>1932</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the Double Striations in Hydrogen</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Katzman, John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It has been known for many years that when an electric current passes through gases at pressures of the order of 1 mm. of mercury the continuous positive oolumn breaks up into discontinuous luminous di~ce, called etriationa. Such striations were first observed by M~ Abria in 1843 and independently reobserved by Sir William Grove in 1862(1). The most interesting classical work is -that of De la Rue and Miller(2). These authors experimented with tubes of various sizes and shapes obtaining many remarkable and interesting phenomena. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Keys, D. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257h32s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd59k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623f99p"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Céline dans les Pamphlets</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Delguste, Christian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'œuvre de Céline, apparemment double, -- celle d'un romancier et celle d'un moraliste -- tire son homogénéité! profonde du caractère même de l'auteur. La présente thèse prétend définir cette personnalité! dans ce qu'elle a de créateur, à travers les écrits polémiques. Deux grilles d'interprétation se présentent: l'interprétation psychanalytique et 1'interprétation socio-, historique. L'auto-portrait de Céline a-t-il une valeur représentative? […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The literary output of Céline would appear to be a dual one: the work of a novelist and the work of a moralist. Yet its fundamental homogeneity can be attributed to the author's personality. This thesis undertakes to define the creative aspect of Céline’s personality as it appears in his polemical writing and to do so we have resorted to two distinct but complementary interpretations: psychoanalytic and socio-historic. To what extent can it be said that Céline’s self-portrait is authentic? </dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nt353.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623f99p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Céline, Louis-Ferdinand, 1894-1961 -- Political and social views</dc:subject><dc:subject>Céline, Louis-Ferdinand, 1894-1961 -- Psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Céline, Louis-Ferdinand, 1894-1961 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cw52h"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Sun Also Rises and the Production of Meaning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Deller, Susan Margaret</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une étude sur la critique de The Sun Also Rises par Hemingway révèle une grande diversité de methodes et d'approches. Cependant, sous cette apparente diversité il existe depuis longtemps des présuppositions fondamentales (quoique rarement articulées). Inconnu par les critiques eux mêmes, ces présuppositions les obligeaient à employer des règles semblables pour construire des concepts de bases et leurs théories. Les recherches qui ont été faites dans la linguistiques et les domaines apparentes, ces dernières décennies, nous permettent de mettre en question ces présuppositions et, alors, d'établir la possibilité d'un nouveau depart de critique litéraire. Le chapitre final de cette thèse introduit trois "nouveaux departs" proposer par les critiques Roland Barthes, Jacques Derrida et Michel Foucault, examine les implications que portent leurs stratégies dans la façon dont nous lisons et comprenons ce livre d'Hemingway, et indique quelques problèmes soulevés par leurs methodes. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A survey of the criticism on Hemingway’s The Sun Also Rises reveals a broad diversity of methods and approaches. Yet, beneath the apparent diversity there exist certain fundamental and longstanding (although rarely articulated) assumptions; assumptions which, unbeknownst to the critics themselves, compelled them to employ similar rules to build their concepts and their theories. The researches that have been carried out in recent decades in linguistics and related areas now permit us to challenge these assumptions, thereby establishing the possibility of a. new beginning for criticism. The final chapter of the thesis introduces three such "new beginnings" as they have been set forth by the French critics Roland Barthes, Jacques Derrida, and Michel Foucault, examines the implications their strategies have for the ways in which we can read and understand Hemingway's book, and indicates some of the problems raised by their methods. </dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881p44t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cw52h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961. Sun also rises</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gn40k"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Effects of an Outward Bound Experience on the Self-Concept and Attitude toward School of Adolescent Males</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cukier, Ed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>On a conçu cette étude pour mesurer les effects de sorties de plein air sur la connaissance de soi et l'attitude envers l'école d'un groupe d'adolescents. Les résultats servaient à même d'évaluer si les éléments de ce programme Outward Bound (Project Challenge), tels qu'organisé dans une serie de randonnées en fin de semain pourraient changer de manière significative la connaissance de soi et l'attitude enver l'école des participants. A partir de cette recherche on pourrait formuler des suggestions. On a choisi 84 étudiants de 9e année dont 45 furent soumis à l'épreuve alors que 39 appartenaient au groupe de contrôl. On a donné à ce groupe de contrôl un placebo qui consistaint à vivre des activités éducatives de plein air, tandis que le groupe expérimental prenait part à plusieurs sorties de fin de semaine pendant une période de six mois. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This study was designed to determine the effects of an Outward Bound experience (Project Challenge), on the self-concept and attitude toward school of a group of male adolescents.The findings of this study would determine whether the elements of the Outward Bound program as they were organized in a series of weekend field trips could produce significant changes in the self-concept and school attitude of the participants. From this research, suggestions could be made regarding Outward Bound programs as they relate to self-concept and school attitude. Eighty-four male Grade 9 students, 45 experimental and 39 control, were subjects in the experiment. The control group was given a placebo treatment which involved vicarious outdoor education activities and the experimental group was taken out on several weekend trips over a six-month period. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Donald, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wq27w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gn40k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Teenage boys</dc:subject><dc:subject>Outdoor education -- Research</dc:subject><dc:subject>Self-perception</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1z40kw248"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Morning in the Tropics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cox, Christopher R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les dernières années ont vu le tropique luxuriant qui était le Panama enfonce dans les manchettes universelles à cause de plusieurs drames, parmi lesquels: l'exil du Chah Iranien et les négociations pour le Traite du Canal de Panama avec les États Unis. Cependant, tous ces reportages n'étaient pas plus long que trois ou quatre paragraphes. Ces courts passages ne se concernent pas avec l'humanité et la nature sans bornes qui fleurissent derrière cette égide Américaine. Matin en les Tropiques, une collection de six contes, cherche à développer ces quelques lignes de journalistes et, pour paraphraser Guy de Maupassant, à embellir encore plus ce qui est la réalité; à comprende encore plus le peuple Panamien. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The past few years have seen the lush tropical backwater that was Panama thrust into worldwide headlines concerning the Panama Canal Treaty negotiations and the late Shah of Iran's exile, yet, past the large type, every newspaper story seemed just three or four paragraphs long and never dwelt with the boundless diversity of native humanity and nature blossoming behind the American aegis. Morning in the Tropics, a collection of six works of short fiction, seeks to expand between the few lines of news copy that people know about Panama and to portray the United States' presence there, to paraphrase Guy de Maupassant, in embellished terms more cogent than reality itself. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elliott, Lorris T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827d98h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kw248</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Panama</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>