<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8s45qc25q"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Finite element design and manufacturing of a nylon-string guitar soundboard from sandwich-structured composites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abaeian, Negin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L’objectif de ce projet était d'utiliser la Méthode des Éléments Finis (FEM) pour concevoir et fabriquer une table d'harmonie de guitare à cordes en nylon à partir de composites sandwiches en se référant à une table en bois existante, et d'évaluer la validité des modèles numériques de la table d'harmonie en bois, de la plaque supérieure en composite sans renforts et de la table d'harmonie composite renforcée au moyen d'une analyse modale expérimentale.Le comportement modal de la table d'harmonie existante en bois a été étudié au moyen de l'analyse modale expérimentale et de la simulation numérique. En utilisant la MEF, l'effet de la variation de certaines propriétés physiques, géométriques et élastiques des matériaux utilisés dans la table d'harmonie a été déterminé sur ses fréquences propres en utilisant des Conditions aux Limites (CL) soit libres soit immobiles (c. à-d., sans translations). La table d'harmonie en composite, dont on a déterminé qu'elle avait des fréquences propres relativement similaires à celles de la table d'harmonie en bois sous CL immobiles, et qui peut être construite à partir de matériaux disponibles dans le commerce, a été produite. Pour vérifier les résultats prédits numériquement, des analyses modales expérimentales ont été effectuées sur la plaque supérieure composite et la table d'harmonie en composites sous CL non contraintes.Les fréquences propres expérimentales et les différents modes propres de la plaque supérieure construite sans renforts correspondent à celles prédites par la simulation dans la gamme de fréquences inférieures à 200 [Hz], tout en divergeant dans la plage de fréquences plus élevées. Les résultats expérimentaux pour la table d'harmonie composite avec renforts se sont également révélés relativement similaires aux valeurs prédites numériquement, la plupart des formes de modes propres correspondantes, et certaines différences dans les fréquences propres, principalement dans les plages de basses et moyennes fréquences. Dans l'ensemble, un accord satisfaisant a été obtenu entre les résultats numériques et les résultats expérimentaux.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The aim of this project was to use the Finite Element Method (FEM) to design and manufacture the soundboard of a nylon-string guitar from sandwich-structured composites, with reference to an existing wooden soundboard, and to evaluate the accuracy of the numerical models of the wooden soundboard, the brace-less composite top plate and the braced composite soundboard by means of experimental modal analysis. The modal behaviour of the existing wooden soundboard was studied through experimental modal analysis and numerical simulation. Using FEM, the effects of varying certain physical, geometric and elastic properties of the materials used in the soundboard were determined on its natural frequencies under free and hinged Boundary Conditions (BCs). The composite soundboard that was determined to have natural frequencies relatively similar to those of the wooden soundboard under hinged BCs, and could be built from commercially available materials was constructed. To verify the results predicted numerically, experimental modal analyses were performed on the brace-less composite top plate and the braced composite soundboard under free BCs. The experimental natural frequencies and mode-shapes of the constructed brace-less top plate were found to match those predicted by the simulation in the frequency range below 200 [Hz], while slightly diverging in the higher frequency range. The experimental results for the braced composite soundboard were also found to be relatively similar to the numerically predicted values, with most mode-shapes matching, and some differences in the mode-frequencies, mostly in the low and mid-frequency ranges. Overall, a reasonable agreement was achieved between the numerical and the experimental results. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gary Scavone</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Larry Lessard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k975f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qc25q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386m88d"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Peering into the body: tracing the visual culture of Magnetic Resonance Imaging and the construction of a "Transparent" body</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chatzifilalithis, Maria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis uses Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) technology as an entry point from which to discuss themes of representation, objectivity, transparency and authoritative knowledge. Popular discourses regarding MRI technologies, and medical imaging technologies more broadly, reflect and reinforce cultural narratives about images and machines. The MRI occupies a privileged position by virtue of being an imaging device in a culture that often conflates images with notions of ‘reality’ and ‘proof’ and technology as ‘unmediated’ and ‘objective’. Despite these narratives, medical imaging devices such as the MRI are not neutral procurers of objective knowledge. They are implicated in and reflect the wider culture they are a part of. This work challenges the common erasure of elements such as cultural narratives, a diversity of actors, work practices, human agency and history in the discourse of MRI technology and offers a nuanced understanding of the decisions and context involved in creating scans. In addition it sheds light on how objective knowledge, and authoritative representation are not static, and change over time and how these themes not only add to discourses pertaining to medical images but come to influence our conceptions of bodies, health and control over illness.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse utilise la technologie de l'imagerie par résonance magnétique (IRM) comme point d’entrée pour discuter des thèmes de la représentation, de l'objectivité, de la transparence et des connaissances autorisées. Les discours populaires concernant les technologies IRM et les technologies d'imagerie médicale plus largement, reflètent et renforcent les récits culturels sur les images et les machines. L'IRM occupe une position privilégiée en vertu d’un dispositif d'imagerie dans une culture qui confond souvent les images avec des notions de «réalité» et de «preuve» et de technologie comme  «non médiatisé» et «objectif». Malgré ces récits, les dispositifs d'imagerie médicale tels que l'IRM ne sont pas des chercheurs neutres de connaissances objectives. Ils sont impliqués et reflètent la culture plus large  qi’ils font partie. Ce travail remet en question l'effacement commun d'éléments tels que les récits culturels, la diversité des acteurs, les pratiques de travail, l'agence humaine et l'histoire dans le discours de la technologie IRM et offre une compréhension nuancée des décisions et du contexte impliqués dans la création d’analyses. En outre, il met en lumière comment la connaissance objective et la représentation autorisée ne sont pas statiques, et changent avec le temps et comment ces thèmes s'ajoutent aux discours sur les images médicales mais influencent nos conceptions du corps, de la santé et du contrôle de la maladie.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barney, Darin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fv00p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m88d</ual:fedora3Handle></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zw901"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fractional exhaled nitric oxide (FeNO) as inflammatory biomarker in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and asthma-COPD overlap (ACO)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mostafavi PourManshadi, Seyed MohammadYousof</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background and Objectives: Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and asthma are the most common inflammatory airway diseases. Some individuals share features of both asthma and COPD called asthma-COPD overlap (ACO) syndrome (ACOS). These individuals have worse symptoms and health status as well as lower pulmonary function than COPD-only. There is a remarkable need to have access to a biomarker that could be used in a clinical setting to be able to differentiate ACO(S) from COPD-only. Fractional exhaled nitric oxide (FeNO) is a promising biomarker identifying eosinophilic and T-helper cell 2 (Th2)-mediated airway inflammation in asthma. Its measurement is easy, sensitive, reproducible, and non-invasive. The exact role of FeNO in COPD and in differentiating COPD from ACO(S) is still unclear and needs to be defined. We aimed to systematically search the literature to present an overview of the existing literature in a field of interest, i.e., FeNO in COPD, and as well synthesize and aggregate findings from different studies. Furthermore, we conducted a study embedded in the Canadian Cohort Obstructive Lung Disease (CanCOLD) to evaluate the role of FeNO and determine if there is a cut-off value that can differentiate ACO(S) from COPD-only. Methods: Firstly, we conducted a systematic scoping review to determine key concepts, and to explore gaps within a developing field of research. Secondly, we carried out a study embedded in CanCOLD with new measurement including FeNO level. The COPD participants were divided into ACO and COPD-only (non-ACO). The different levels of FeNO and its utility were assessed between ACO and COPD-only. The optimal cut-off values and the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves were obtained to evaluate the clinical utility of FeNO in diagnosing ACO(S). Results: From the scoping review, 38 studies were selected, 24 were on modifying factors in FeNO measurement in COPD patients, 18 were on FeNO in COPD and compared to healthy subjects, 22 on FeNO and disease severity or progression, 7 on FeNO and ACO(S), 12 on FeNO and biomarkers, and 8 on FeNO and treatment response. From the original study embedded in CanCOLD, a total of 169 subjects were enrolled, of those 95 were COPD with ACO, N=46, and COPD-only, N=49. The mean FeNO level was higher but not statistically significant between ACO and COPD-only. The significant optimal cut-off values to differentiate ACO from COPD-only was for Def 1 FeNO ≥36 ppb with the sensitivity of 39%, specificity of 88% and AUC of 0.63, p=0.046, and Def 3 FeNO ≥23.5 ppb with the sensitivity of 80% and specificity of 50%, and area under the curve of 0.65, p=0.047.Conclusion: From the scoping review when measuring FeNO, the evidence is still lacking preventing us from recommending the general use of FeNO in clinical practice for COPD patients. Although FeNO level is higher in ACO(S) patients than COPD-only, it is still unclear if there is a FeNO cut-off that can be used to make the diagnosis of ACO(S) and/or to guide therapy with inhaled corticosteroids/glucocorticoids in COPD patients. After studying FeNO in a population-based sample of COPD, we were not able to show that FeNO levels could be used as a biomarker for differentiating ACO from COPD-only, and it is still too soon to be able to make a recommendation of using it in clinical practice. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Contexte et objectifs: La maladie pulmonaire obstructive chronique (MPOC) et l'asthme sont les maladies inflammatoires des voies respiratoires les plus courantes. Certaines personnes partagent les caractéristiques de l'asthme et de la MPOC, appelées syndrome de chevauchement de la MPOC (ACOS). Ces personnes présentent des symptômes et un état de santé moins bons, ainsi qu'une fonction pulmonaire inférieure à celle de la MPOC uniquement. Il existe un besoin remarquable d'avoir accès à un biomarqueur qui pourrait être utilisé dans un cadre clinique pour pouvoir différencier l'ACO (S) de la MPOC seulement. L'oxyde nitrique exhalé fractionné (FeNO) est un biomarqueur prometteur qui identifie l'inflammation des voies respiratoires éosinophiles et des lymphocytes T auxiliaires 2 (Th2) dans l'asthme. Sa mesure est facile, sensible, reproductible et non invasive. Le rôle exact du FeNO dans la MPOC et dans la différenciation de la MPOC de l'ACO (S) n'est pas encore clair et doit être défini. Nous avons cherché à rechercher systématiquement dans la littérature pour présenter un aperçu de la littérature existante dans un domaine d'intérêt, à savoir, FeNO dans la MPOC, et ainsi synthétiser et agréger les résultats de différentes études. De plus, nous avons mené une étude intégrée dans la maladie pulmonaire obstructive de la cohorte canadienne (CanCOLD) afin d'évaluer le rôle du FeNO et de déterminer s'il existe une valeur limite pouvant différencier l'ACO (S) de la MPOC seulement.Méthodes: Tout d'abord, nous avons procédé à un examen systématique de la portée afin de déterminer les concepts clés et d'explorer les lacunes dans un domaine de recherche en développement. Deuxièmement, nous avons réalisé une étude intégrée dans CanCOLD avec une nouvelle mesure incluant le niveau de FeNO. Les participants à la MPOC étaient divisés en ACO et MPOC seule (non-ACO). Les différents niveaux de FeNO et son utilité ont été évalués entre ACO et MPOC seule. Les valeurs de seuil optimales et les courbes de caractéristiques de fonctionnement du récepteur (ROC) ont été obtenues pour évaluer l'utilité clinique du FeNO dans le diagnostic de l'ACO (S).Résultats: 38 études ont été sélectionnées sur les facteurs de modification du FeNO chez les patients atteints de MPOC, 18 sur FeNO dans la MPOC et comparées à des sujets sains, 22 sur FeNO et la gravité ou la progression de la maladie, 7 sur FeNO et ACO (S), 12 sur FeNO et les biomarqueurs, et 8 sur FeNO et la réponse au traitement. De l'étude originale incluse dans CanCOLD, un total de 169 sujets ont été inscrits, parmi lesquels 95 étaient atteints de MPOC avec ACO, N = 46, et COPD seulement, N = 49. Le niveau moyen de FeNO était plus élevé mais non statistiquement significatif entre ACO et MPOC seule. Les valeurs de seuil optimales significatives pour différencier l'ACO de la MPOC seulement étaient pour Def 1 FeNO ≥ 36 ppb avec une sensibilité de 39%, une spécificité de 88% et une AUC de 0,63, p = 0,046 et Def 3 FeNO ≥23,5 ppb avec la sensibilité de 80% et la spécificité de 50%, et l'aire sous la courbe de 0,65, p = 0,047.Conclusion: À partir de l'examen de la portée lors de la mesure du FeNO, les données probantes font encore défaut, ce qui nous empêche de recommander l'utilisation générale du FeNO en pratique clinique chez les patients atteints de MPOC. Bien que le taux de FeNO soit plus élevé chez les patients ACO (S) que chez les patients atteints de MPOC, on ignore encore s'il existe un seuil de FeNO pouvant être utilisé pour établir le diagnostic d'ACO (S) et / ou guider le traitement par corticoïdes inhalés / glucocorticoïdes chez les patients atteints de MPOC. Après avoir étudié le FeNO dans un échantillon de MPOC basé sur la population, nous n'avons pas pu démontrer que les niveaux de FeNO pouvaient être utilisés comme biomarqueur pour différencier l'ACO de la MPOC seulement, et il est encore trop tôt pour pouvoir recommander l'utilisation dans la pratique clinique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jean Bourbeau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vk22n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw901</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak643b351n"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Appropriate surgical education for countries with limited resources. Cognitive Apprenticeship: The why, when and how of surgical practice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lewis, Lowell</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>  “Appropriate surgical education for Countries with limited resources”Cognitive Apprenticeship.  The Why, When and How of surgical practiceThe role of surgical education in the prevention and management of surgical disorders continues to be an important subject for study, as we struggle in developing countries, to meet the growing demands, in the absence of sufficient resources, for the provision of adequate surgical services. Persons living in remote areas which are also undeveloped and without modern medical facilities, are at risk of significant disruption of their lives and increased morbidity and mortality.Correction of this problem requires the identification and implementation of educational programs and curricula which provide training and experience which can be delivered in communities which are at remote locations and have limited resources. This title  “Appropriate surgical education for countries with limited resources”,  reflects the need for the identification, retention and development of  methods of surgical practice and education, that will ensure acceptable levels of care for surgical patients living in remote communities or communities with limited resources, who have no access to current gold standards of care.The main objectives of this thesis are to share information and document educational activities that will have a significant impact on the global burden of surgical disease, and also to promote an approach to surgical care, which is affordable and can be applied in varying ways to achieve good outcomes, depending on local circumstances. ” Prevention and management of surgical disorders”, will be the theme of this review of current surgical educational practices and the options for care. The final chapter of this thesis begins with a list of questions for surgeons practicing in remote communities, with limited resources and restricted access to the current standards of care established in university teaching centers.I then review the published descriptions of programs and recommendations for improving surgical services to developing countries.The chapter ends with a template for self assessment of surgeons who wish to provide evidence of competence in the provision of essential surgical services in resource limited communities, and justification for continuation of medico-legal insurance coverage for their surgical services. It also serves as a guide for the content of training and revalidation programs required for such surgeons. With this Thesis, I verify,  and  illustrate the importance of surgical training programs built on a foundation of  cognitive apprenticeship, consistent with the Applied Clinical  surgery course designs,   Animal Laboratory Competency based training programs ,  Health Technology Assessments and Validation Protocols advocated in this Thesis.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Formation chirurgicale appropriée pour les pays ayant des ressources limitées - Apprentissage cognitifLe pourquoi, le quand et le comment de la pratique chirurgicaleLe rôle de l'éducation chirurgicale dans la prévention et la gestion des troubles chirurgicaux continue d'être un sujet d'étude important, car dans les pays en développement nous luttons pour répondre aux demandes croissantes, en l'absence de ressources suffisantes, pour la prestation de services chirurgicaux adéquats. Les personnes vivant dans des zones reculées qui sont également sous-développées et dépourvues d'installations médicales modernes risquent de subir des perturbations importantes et d'accroître la morbidité et la mortalité. La correction de ce problème nécessite l'identification et la mise en œuvre de programmes éducatifs et de programmes d'études qui fournissent une formation et une expérience pouvant être dispensées dans des communautés qui sont situées dans des endroits éloignés et qui disposent de ressources limitées. Ce titre "Formation chirurgicale appropriée pour les pays à ressources limitées" reflète la nécessité d'identifier, de retenir et de développer des méthodes de pratique et d'éducation chirurgicale qui assureront des soins acceptables aux patients chirurgicales vivant dans des communautés éloignées ou aux ressources limitées, qui n'ont pas accès aux normes de soins actuelles. Les principaux objectifs de cette thèse sont de partager des informations et de documenter les activités éducatives qui auront un impact significatif sur le fardeau mondial de la maladie chirurgicale, ainsi que de promouvoir une approche des soins chirurgicaux, abordable et pouvant être appliquée de différentes manières pour obtenir de bons résultats, selon les circonstances locales. "Prévention et gestion des troubles chirurgicaux", sera le thème de cette revue des pratiques éducatives chirurgicales actuelles et des options de prise en charge. Le dernier chapitre de cette thèse commence par une liste de questions pour les chirurgiens pratiquant dans les communautés éloignées, avec des ressources limitées et un accès restreint aux normes de soins actuelles établies dans les centres d'enseignement universitaire.  Je passe ensuite en revue les descriptions publiées de programmes et de recommandations pour améliorer les services chirurgicaux dans les pays en dévelopement. Le chapitre se termine par un modèle d'auto-évaluation des chirurgiens qui souhaitent fournir une preuve de compétence dans la prestation de services chirurgicaux essentiels dans les communautés de ressources limitées, et la justification de la poursuite de la couverture d'assurance médico-légale pour leurs services chirurgicaux. Il sert également de guide pour le contenu des programmes de formation et de revalidation requis pour ces chirurgiens. Avec cette thèse, je vérifie et illustre l'importance des programmes de formation chirurgicale fondés sur l'apprentissage cognitif, en accord avec les cours de chirurgie clinique appliquée, les programmes de formation basés sur les compétences des laboratoires d'expérimentation animale, les évaluations des technologies de la santé et les protocoles de validation préconisés dans cette thèse.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael L. Hoover</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Tarek Razek</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246v40v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b351n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042w410"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of a foliar nutrient product in relieving herbicide-induced defects in crop growth and development in «Zea mays, Triticum aestivum,» and «Glycine max»</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haley, Olivia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Puisque l’assimilation du gaz carbonique via la photosynthèse par les plantes cultivées est étroitement liée à leur croissance et développement, une baisse du taux de photosynthèse induite par les herbicides peut avoir un effet négatif sur les rendements des cultures. De plus, comme plusieurs éléments minéraux portent un effet direct ou indirect sur la photosynthèse, cette étude vise à étudier l’efficacité des solutions nutritives foliaires contenant N, P, K, Mn, Zn, B, et Mo en réparant la suppression de la photosynthèse causée par l’application des herbicides. Les produits Coup de Fouet (CB), Crop Booster 2.0 (CB2), et RR Soy Booster 2.0 ont été testés dans les champs afin d’identifier leur capacité à soulager les effets phytotoxiques associés avec l’application des herbicides en le blé (Triticum aestivum), le maïs (Zea mays), et le soja (Glycine max). Pendant la première saison, les applications de post-levée consistées de : contrôle (H2O), seulement les herbicides, et une combination des herbicides et CB2 ; bromoxynil/MCPA, glyphosate et atrazine, et glyphosate/fomesafen ont été appliqué sur le blé de printemps, le maïs, et le soja respectivement. La deuxième saison, les applications de post-levée sur le maïs et le blé de printemps consistées de contrôle (H2O), seulement les herbicides, seulement le CB2, et une combination des herbicides et CB2 ; bromoxynil/MCPA et glyphosate plus atrazine/dicamba ont été appliqué sur le blé de printemps et le maïs respectivement. Sur le soja, SB2 et les herbicides glyphosate et chlorimuron ethyl ont été appliqués. Les formulations nutrititives ont été appliquées en liason avec les herbicides lorsque le soja est au stade de la troisième feuille trifoliée, le maïs est au stade de la sixième feuille, et le blé est au stade de la sixième feuille. Les variables photosynthétiques, les variables de croissance (la hauteur, la surface foliaire, et la masse sèche), et les variables de récolte ont été notés pour évaluer les effets des traitements sur le développement des plantes cultivées. L’application de CB2 portait un rétablissement partiel du taux de photosynthèse dans les champs. Cependant, le rétablissement partiel n’avait aucun effet sur ni la plupart des variables de croissance, ni les variables de récolte. Dans la serre, bien que l’application de CB2 n’eût pas un effet sur le taux de photosynthèse, il y avait des différences statistiquement significatives dans la hauteur et la masse sèche associée avec l’application de bromoxynil/MCPA.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>As the rate of carbon dioxide assimilation via photosynthesis is closely related to crop growth and development, there are concerns that herbicide-induced decreases in photosynthetic rate could be negatively impacting crop yields. Furthermore, as many mineral elements have direct or indirect roles in maintaining the photosynthetic apparatus, this study aims to investigate the efficacy of foliar nutrient solutions containing N, P, K, Mn, Zn, B and Mo in reversing herbicide-induced photosynthetic suppression. The products Crop Booster (CB), Crop Booster 2.0 (CB2) and RR Soy Booster 2.0 (SB2) were tested in the field setting for their capacity to relieve the phytotoxic effects associated with herbicide usage in wheat (Triticum aestivum), corn (Zea mays), and soybean (Glycine max). During the first field season, post-emergence treatments consisted of water only (control), herbicide only, and a combination of herbicide and CB; bromoxynil/MCPA, glyphosate plus atrazine, and glyphosate/fomesafen were used in wheat, corn and soybean, respectively. During the second crop year, post-emergence treatments consisted of water only (control), herbicide only, CB2 only and a combination of herbicide and CB2; bromoxynil/MCPA and glyphosate plus atrazine/dicamba were used in wheat and corn, respectively. For soybean, SB2 and the herbicide combination glyphosate plus chlorimuron ethyl were used. Experiments with CB2 usage in spring wheat were repeated in the greenhouse setting. The nutrient formulations were applied in conjunction with the herbicide treatments at the third trifoliate stage for soybean, sixth to eighth leaf stage for corn and sixth to early flag leaf stage in wheat. Photosynthetic variables, growth variables and harvest variables were measured to determine the treatments’ effects on plant development. Both CB2 and SB2 resulted in partial recovery of the negative herbicide effects on photosynthetic rate under field conditions. However, the photosynthetic recovery did not result in changes in the growth variables at most stages, or increase harvest variables. Under greenhouse conditions, while CB2 application did not result in photosynthetic recovery, there were statistically significant differences in height and dry weight due to the application of bromoxynil/MCPA. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Donald L. Smith</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jh07f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042w410</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870z48w"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Porous graded biomaterial for a tibial-knee implant with minimum bone resorption and bone-implant interface micromotion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rahimizadeh, Amirmohammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Numerous patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty (TKA) suffer from post-operative complications associated with TKA, namely end of stem pain and aseptic loosening. The mechanical mismatch between the implant and the surrounding bone has been identified as one major cause for implant failure. After primary TKA, the mechanical bio-incompatibility of the implant with the surrounding bone tissue results in bone resorption, which leads to revision surgery. Revision surgeries are generally more complex and often associated with a lower chance of success when compared to primary TKA. Excessive micromotion at the bone-implant interface raised from periprothesis bone resorption is attributed to the end-of-stem pain following primary TKA. The-incidence of end-of-stem pain is documented to be 7% for patients undergoing primary TKA. In revision surgery, furthermore, end-of-stem pain affects 16% of patients. Substantial amount of work exists in literature attempting to improve the design of knee implants for enhanced performance and reduced clinical problems. Elastic property tailoring in hip stems was recognized already in the 1990s as a promising mean to reduce bone resorption. Whereas those studies focused on the use of functionally graded solid materials, only recently porous materials with tailored cellular architecture have been successfully exploited to create locally controlled compliant implants with reduced bone resorption.In this thesis, we propose a fully porous tibial knee implant which features an optimally customized lattice microarchitecture. Its cellular microstructure contributes to a notable increase of the implant compliance, which leads to a simultaneous minimization of bone resorption and interface micromotion. A tetrahedron based cell unit is used as a building block for the lattice microarchitecture of the implant and its mechanical properties are characterized via Asymptotic Homogenization (AH) theory. A scheme combining multiscale mechanics and topology optimization is employed to tailor the material distribution of the implant against fatigue failure. The results show the amount of bone resorption around the graded lattice implant to be 25% lower than that around a conventional fully dense titanium implant currently in the market. In addition, an improved interface micromotion which is as low as 17 μm and 22 μm respectively during the gait cycle and deep bend, is guaranteed by the newly introduced implant, thereby alleviating the post-operative end of stem pain which patients with current implants can suffer from.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>De nombreux patients soumis à une arthroplastie totale du genou (TKA) souffrent de complications post-opératoires associées à TKA, à savoir la fin de la douleur de la tige et le relâchement aseptique. L'incomparabilité mécanique entre l'implant et l'os environnant a été identifiée comme la principale cause de défaillance de l'implant. Après le TKA primaire, la bio-incompatibilité mécanique de l'implant avec le tissu osseux environnant entraîne une résorption osseuse, ce qui conduit à une chirurgie de révision. Les chirurgies de révision sont généralement plus complexes et souvent associées à une plus faible chance de succès par rapport à la TKA primaire. Une micromotion excessive à l'interface os-implant élevée à partir de la résorption osseuse de la periprothèse est attribuée à la douleur de fin de tige après TKA primaire. L'incidence de la douleur à la fin de la tige est documentée à 7% pour les patients soumis à une TKA primaire. En chirurgie de révision, en outre, la douleur à la fin de la tige affecte 16% des patients.Il existe une quantité considérable de travail dans la littérature visant à améliorer la conception des implants au genou pour améliorer les performances et réduire les problèmes cliniques. L'adaptation élastique de la propriété dans les tiges de la hanche a déjà été reconnue dans les années 1990 comme un moyen prometteur de réduire la résorption osseuse. Alors que ces études ont porté sur l'utilisation de matériaux solides fonctionnellement classés, seuls des matériaux poreux récents avec une architecture cellulaire sur mesure ont été exploités avec succès pour créer des implants conformes contrôlés localement avec une résorption osseuse réduite.Dans cette thèse, nous proposons un implant de genou tibial entièrement poreux qui présente une microarchitecture en treillis personnalisée. Sa microstructure cellulaire contribue à une augmentation notable de la compliance de l'implant, ce qui conduit à une minimisation simultanée de la résorption osseuse et de la micromotion de l'interface. Une unité de cellules à base de tétraèdre est utilisée comme élément de construction pour la microarchitecture en réseau de l'implant et ses propriétés mécaniques sont caractérisées par une théorie de l'homogénéisation asymptotique (AH). Un schéma combinant l'optimisation de la topologie et la mécanique multiscalaire est utilisé pour adapter la distribution matérielle de l'implant contre une panne de fatigue.Les résultats montrent que la quantité de résorption osseuse autour de l'implant en treillis gradué est inférieure de 25% à celle d'un implant de titane classique entièrement dense actuellement sur le marché. De plus, une micromotion d'interface améliorée de 17 μm et 22 μm respectivement pendant le cycle de marche et le virage profond est garantie par l'implant nouvellement introduit, ce qui atténue l'extrémité post-opératoire de la douleur de la tige que les patients présentant des implants actuels peuvent souffrir de.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Damiano Pasini</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429c799.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870z48w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913s30p"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Avicennian natural philosophy and the alchemical theory of al-Tughra'1 in «Haqa'iq al-istishhad»</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Inoue, Takatomo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse vise à préciser comment les alchimistes et les non alchimistes ont étudié et discuté de l'alchimie dans l'Islam médiéval. Pour atteindre cet objectif, nous examinons d'abord et réinterprétons les réalisations des alchimistes musulmans et pré-islamiques, ainsi que les types multiples de classification de l'alchimie par des auteurs non alchimistes. En outre, nous examinons les discussions théoriques des non alchimistes sur l'alchimie, qui ont eu une grande influence sur le développement de l'alchimie dans l'Islam médiéval ainsi que dans les détails des alchimistes. Enfin, afin de clarifier les deux positions, nous étudions le Ḥaqā'iq al-istishhād de al-Ṭughrā'ī, qui compare le fondement théorique des alchimistes concernant les théories alchimiques avec les non alchimistes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis aims at clarifying how alchemists and non-alchemists studied and discussed alchemy in medieval Islam. In order to attain this objective, we first review and reinterpret the accomplishments of Muslim and pre-Islamic alchemists, as well as multiple types of classification of alchemy by non-alchemist authors. Also, we examine in detail non-alchemists’ theoretical discussions of alchemy, which had a large influence on the development of alchemy in medieval Islam, as well as discussions by alchemists. Finally, in order to clarify both stances, we investigate al-Ṭughrāʾī’s Ḥaqāʾiq al-istishhād, which compares alchemists’ theoretical foundation concerning alchemical theories with that of non-alchemists.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Faiz Ragep</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq92m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913s30p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2v23vw445"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Eligibility traces for options</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jain, Ayush</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les actions abstraites temporellement ne représentent pas seulement des connaissances en configuration hiérarchique dans l’apprentissage par renforcement, ils améliorent également l’exploration tout en réduisant la complexité pour choisir les actions. Les options fournissent un cadre concret pour mettre en œuvre et de raisonner quant aux actions temporellement abstraites. Cette thèse tente de tester l’utilité des traces d’éligibilité avec des options et de trouver de bonnes façons de faire des mises à jour intra-options multi-étapes. Trois algorithmes, basés sur des méthodes hors-politique - échantillonnage préférentiel, tree backup et retrace(λ), sont proposés pour utiliser les traces d’éligibilité avec les options.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Temporally extended actions not only represent knowledge in the hierarchical setup in reinforcement learning, they also improve exploration while reducing the complexity of choosing actions. The option framework provides a concrete way to implement and reason about temporal abstraction. This thesis attempts to test the utility of eligibility traces with options and find good ways of doing multi-step intra-option updates. Three algorithms, based on off-policy methods - importance sampling, tree backup and retrace(λ), are proposed for using eligibility traces with options.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Doina Precup</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj1394543.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vw445</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aww72bf19t"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Approximating gains from trade in two-sided markets via simple mechanisms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhao, Mingfei</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We design simple mechanisms to approximate the Gains from Trade (GFT) in two-sidedmarkets with multiple unit-supply sellers and multiple unit-demand buyers. A classical impossibilityresult by Myerson and Satterthwaite [22] showed that even with only one sellerand one buyer, no Individually Rational (IR), Bayesian Incentive Compatible (BIC) andBudget-Balanced (BB) mechanism can achieve full GFT (trade whenever buyer's value ishigher than the seller's cost). On the other hand, they proposed the "second-best" mechanismthat maximizes the GFT subject to IR, BIC and BB constraints, which is unfortunatelyrather complex for even the single-seller single-buyer case. Our mechanism is simple, IR,BIC and BB, and achieves 1/2 of the optimal GFT among all IR, BIC and BB mechanisms.Our result holds for arbitrary distributions of the buyers' and sellers' values and can accommodateany downward-closed feasibility constraints over the allocations. The analysis of ourmechanism is facilitated by extending the Cai-Devanur-Weinberg duality framework [4] totwo-sided markets.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Nous concevons des mécanismes simples qui ont des gains de commerce près de lidéalsur des marchés à deux côtés avec plusieurs vendeurs et acheteurs qui sintéressent à un seularticle. Un résultat d'impossibilité classique par Myerson et Satterthwaite [22] a montré quemême avec un seul vendeur et un seul acheteur, les meilleurs gains de commerce possible nepeuvent être atteints par un mécanisme qui est à la fois individuellement rationnel, au budgetéquilibré et qui incite les participants à révéler leur vraie valeur pour larticle. Dautre part,ils ont proposé le mécanisme qui obtient les meilleurs gains de commerce et respecte les troiscontraintes. Malheureusement, ce dernier est relativement compliqué, même pour le cas dunseul vendeur et dun seul acheteur. Notre mécanisme est simple, individuellement rationnel,au budget équilibré et incite les participants à révéler leur vraie valeur pour larticle, touten atteignant 1/2 des meilleurs gains de commerce possible. Notre résultat sapplique auxdistributions arbitraires sur les valeurs des acheteurs et des vendeurs et aux contraintes surla distribution des articles qui permettent tous les sous-ensembles dun ensemble dans lafamille. Lanalyse de notre mécanisme est facilité par lextension du système de dualité deCai-Devanur-Weinberg [4] aux marchés à deux côtés.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yang Cai</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149s121.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bf19t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rr33w"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Geochemical detection of shallow mantle fluid along the San Andreas Fault</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Balkwill Tweedie, Victoria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La faille San Andreas (FSA) est un danger de tremblement de terre pour des millions de gens vivant à proximité de la faille en Californie. Les fluides entraînent le mouvement et provoquent une redistribution du stress le long de la FSA mais leur origine et migration sous-sol n'est pas bien comprise. Les preuves isotopiques d'hélium suggèrent une contribution fluide du manteau à la faille près de Parkfield et dans le sud de la Californie au sud du Big Bend mais des études antérieures ont échoué à détecter ces signatures dans le système de faille peu profonde. Les mesures isotopiques (δ13C) des gaz de CO2 du sol ont été recueillies le long des transects perpendiculaires à la faille dans le Comté de San Benito, Parkfield et la Plaine Carrizo, et ont été analysées à l'aide d'un spectromètre de cavite anneau-bas (SCAB). Les mesures de haute précision ont été analysées avec des parcelles de Keeling, révélant des signatures δ13C représentatives pour chaque transect (δ13CY). Les valeurs de la littérature ont été utilisées pour établir les signatures δ13C des membres finaux pour l'écosystème biogène CO2 (δ13CR) et le CO2 du manteau (δ13CM). La proportion de δ13CR et δ13CM requis pour produire la signature δ13CY de chaque transect a ensuite été calculée et utilisée pour determiner le flux de CO2 de la manteaux (Mf) dans le système. La respiration de l'écosystème biogénique était incapable de tenir compte des signatures observées dans sept transects, révélant que les fluides du manteau sont présents et détectables dans le système de faille peu profonde. Les proportions de manteau présentes dans les transects révèlent un enrichissement du nord (0 per mil) vers le sud (38.16 per mil). Les résultats sont soutenus par des concentrations accrues de 222Rn dans le sud révélant une perméabilité accrue dans la Plaine Carrizo. Ces résultats ne reflètent pas les differences géochimique entre les segments rampants et verrouillés de la faille; il peut refléter comment l'interaction du Big Bend et du système de failles Garlock-Big Pine près de la Plaine Carrizo influence la migration des fluides et l'accumulation du stress.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The San Andreas Fault (SAF) is an earthquake hazard to millions of people living proximal to the fault system in California. Fluids drive movement and cause stress redistribution along the SAF but their origin and subsurface migration are not well understood. Helium isotopic evidence suggests some mantle fluid contribution to the fault near Parkfield and in southern California south of the Big Bend but previous studies have been unsuccessful in detecting these signatures in the shallow fault system.Isotopic measurements (δ13C) of soil CO2 gas were collected along transects perpendicular to the fault in San Benito County, Parkfield, and the Carrizo Plain, and analyzed using a portable cavity ring down-spectrometer (CRDS). The high precision measurements were analyzed with Keeling plots, revealing representative δ13C signatures for each transect (δ13CY). Literature values were used to establish end-member δ13C signatures for biogenic ecosystem CO2 (δ13CR) and mantle CO2 (δ13CM). The proportion of δ13CR and δ13CM required to yield each transect’s δ13CY signature was then computed and used to determine the flux of mantle CO2 (Mf) to the system. These results were compared with 222Rn measurements gathered from four of the seven transects. Biogenic ecosystem respiration was unable to account for the signatures observed in seven transects, revealing that mantle fluids are present and detectable in the shallow fault system. Mantle proportions and fluxes present in the transects reveal enrichment from north (0 per mil) to south (38.16 per mil). Findings are supported by enhanced 222Rn concentrations in the south revealing enhanced permeability in the Carrizo Plain. These findings do not reflect geochemical differences between creeping and locked segments of the fault; they may reflect how the interaction of the Big Bend and the Garlock-Big Pine fault system near the Carrizo Plain influences fluid migration and stress accumulation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Stix</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666717j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rr33w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A000002479"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Medical Physics Unit</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spatial distortion and image quality assessment of gradient echo imaging for radiation therapy planning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Modchalingam, Mithunan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Imaging is crucial prior to the administration of radiation therapy for the delineation of critical structures. Though CT scans are the standard for radiation therapy planning images, MRI provides increased soft tissue contrast leading to more accurate target delineation. One disadvantage of MR images however is that they suffer from geometric image distortions that reduce spatial precision. System-specific distortions were measured using a pelvis sized grid phantom and a non-linear demons registration. Radial distances from the isocenter with spatial distortions below 2 mm were determined for the T1-w 3D GRE, T2-w 2D SE, T2-w 3D SE, and T1-w THRIVE on a Philips 3 T Ingenia MRI. They were found to be 255 mm, 154 mm, 250 mm, and 230 mm respectively. The distortions were seen to be reduced with increasing bandwidth. Sequence independent distortions were also measured to be below 1.5 mm for radial distances below 270 mm. Areas of high expected patient-dependent distortions were then determined in the head of a healthy volunteer and seen to be at air-tissue and air-bone interfaces. These distortions were also reduced with an increase in bandwidth, at the cost of SNR. Multi-echo averaging and conventional signal averaging were performed to regain SNR and compared in terms of SNR, CNR and qualitative image quality. Multi-echo averaging outperformed conventional signal averaging in terms of SNR and CNR, and was equivalent to or better than conventional signal averaging in terms of qualitative image quality. Altogether, the use of high readout bandwidth and multi-echo averaging improves the quality of three-dimensional gradient echo MRI for use in radiation therapy.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L’imagerie est cruciale pour le tracé des structures critiques avant l’administration de la radiothérapie. Quoique la tomodensitométrie est la norme pour les images de planification en radiothérapie, l’imagerie par résonance magnétique (IRM) fournit un contraste accrue des tissus mous menant à une délimitation plus précise de la cible. Un inconvénient des images IRM est cependant qu’elles souffrent de distorsions géométrique qui réduisent la précision spatiale. Les distortions spécifiques au système ont été mesurées à l’aide d’un fantôme à structure de grille et grâce au recalage non linéaire par la méthode Demons. Les distances radiales de l’isocentre acceptable pour la planification de la radiothérapie sur un Philips 3 T Ingenia mesurées pour les séquences d’écho de gradient 3-dimensions pondérée T1, écho de spin pondérée T2 (2 et 3 dimensions), et « THRIVE » pondérée T1 sont avéré être 255 mm, 154 mm, 250 mm et 230 mm, respectivement. Les distorsions ont été réduites avec une augmentation de la bande passante en réception. Les distorsions indépendantes de la séquence ont également été mesurées et se situent au-dessous de 1,5 mm pour une distance radiale de 270 mm. Les zones de grandes distortions dûes au patient furent ensuite mesurées dans la tête d'un volontaire humain et observées aux interfaces air-tissus et air-os. Ces distorsions furent également réduites avec une augmentation de la bande passante en réception, au détriment du rapport signal-bruit. Une pondération multi-écho et une pondération de signal conventionnel ont été évaluées pour rétablir le rapport signal-bruit original, et comparées en termes de rapport contraste-bruit et de qualité d'image. La pondération multi-écho a surpassé le signal conventionnel en termes de rapport signal-bruit et contraste-bruit et était équivalent ou mieux que le signal conventionnel en termes de qualité d'image qualitative. En somme, l’utilisation d’une large bande passante de réception et la pondération multi-écho améliore la qualité d’image IRM d’écho de gradient 3D pour l’utilisation en radiothérapie.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ives Levesque</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cn33d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000002479</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zk15q"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of computer-aided design evaluation (CADE) system for binder jetting additive manufacturing process from a manufacturability perspective</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yang, Fan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>De par sa capacité à fabriquer des pièces par couche, la fabrication additive (raccourci en “AM ”, pour Additive Manufacturing en anglais) est soumise à moins de contraintes de conception que les techniques de fabrication traditionnelles. Les structures complexes qui ne peuvent pas être fabriquées par des méthodes traditionnelles peuvent être réalisées par AM. Cependant, il faut noter que les possibilités qu’offre la fabrication additive ne sont pas sans limites. La liberté de conception sans précédent de l’AM ne peut être pleinement utilisée que lorsque ses capacités sont bien étudiées et que la méthodologie de conception spécialement conçue pour l’AM, connue sous le nom de Design for Additive Manufacturing (DFAM), est développé.Un sujet populaire de la recherche sur DFAM est de développer des lignes directrices de conception basées sur des recherches expérimentales. Ces règles simples simplifient grandement la relation de dépendance entre les possibilités de fabrication et leurs paramètres de fabrication associés. Pour compenser ce raccourci dû à ces méthodes de conception, une analyse de la fabrication est nécessaire pour examiner les designs avant la fabrication. Dans cette thèse, un système d'évaluation de la conception assistée par ordinateur (“CADE ” pour Computer-Aided Design Evaluation en anglais) est proposé afin effectuer une analyse de la fabrication sur des modèles 3D pour le processus AM. Le système CADE se compose de trois modules consécutifs: la détection des fonctionnalités, l'évaluation des fonctionnalités et l'optimisation de l'orientation. Respectivement, La méthode basée sur les règles logiques, le réseau neuronal artificiel (“ANN ”, Artificial Neural Network) et l'algorithme génétique (“GA”, Genetic Algorithm) sont utilisés pour développer les trois modules. Une méthode de plan d'expériences (“ DoE ”, Design of Experiment) est proposée pour étudier la fabricabilité de l’AM par rapport à certains aspects de la dimension géométrique et du tolérancement (“GD &amp; T”, Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing) de manière globale et économique.Le cadre proposé est mis en place pour le processus de fabrication additive de dépôt par jet de liants (“ BJAM ”, Binder Jetting Additive Manufacturing). La fabrication de la structure en porte-à-faux et du trou est étudiée par rapport à l'angularité et la cylindricité respectivement. Les connaissances et les données expérimentales obtenues avec ce travail expérimental sont ensuite utilisées pour développer le système CADE. En utilisant le système CADE développé, les concepteurs peuvent examiner les caractéristiques critiques de leurs conceptions du point de vue spécifique de la fabrication par BJAM. De cette façon, les fonctionnalités susceptibles d'être défaillantes sont identifiées à l'avance afin que les concepteurs puissent les modifier pour diminuer le risque de problèmes lors de la fabrication.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Due to the additive way of manufacturing parts layer by layer, additive manufacturing (AM) is subjected to fewer design constraints than traditional manufacturing techniques. The intricate and complex structures that cannot be fabricated by traditional methods can be realized by AM. However, it should be noted that the manufacturing capability of AM is not limitless. The unprecedented design freedom of AM can only be fully utilized when the unique manufacturability of AM is well investigated and the design methodology specially for AM, also known as design for AM (DFAM), is developed.One popular topic of the DFAM research is to propose feature-based design guidelines based on experimental investigations. These simple-to-follow rules normally oversimplify the dependent relation between the manufacturability of features and their corresponding manufacturability parameters. To compensate for this shortcoming in the design guidelines, manufacturability analysis is needed to examine designs before manufacturing takes place. In this thesis, a computer-aided design evaluation (CADE) system is proposed to perform manufacturability analysis on computer-aided design (CAD) models for the specific AM process. The CADE system consists of three consecutive modules: feature detection, feature evaluation and orientation optimization. Logical rule-based method, artificial neural network (ANN) and genetic algorithm (GA) are used to develop the three modules, respectively. A design of experiments (DoE) method is proposed to study the AM manufacturability with respect to selected aspects of geometric dimensioning and tolerancing (GD&amp;T) in a comprehensive yet economical way. The proposed framework is implemented for the binder jetting additive manufacturing (BJAM) process. Based on the proposed DoE method, the manufacturability of overhang structures and through holes are investigated experimentally with respect to angularity and cylindricity respectively. The knowledge and experimental data gained in the extensive experimental work are then used to develop the CADE system. With the support of the developed CADE system, designers can examine critical features in their designs from the manufacturability perspective for the specific BJAM process. In this way, the features that are prone to failing are identified in advance so that designers could modify them to decrease the risk of manufacturing failures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yaoyao Zhao</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rz96k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zk15q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bk682"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of locomotor skills in typically developing children</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chan Viquez, Daniela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study of the neurological mechanisms that underlie movement maturation is important for the understanding of how motor skills are acquired during early childhood. The maturation of the control of reaching behavior in infants has been described using dynamical approaches. We extended these approaches to the explanation of the maturation of locomotor skills in typically-developing (TD) children based on the referent body configuration hypothesis. This hypothesis suggests that during rhythmical movement, the actual and referent configuration of the body may transiently coincide resulting in the minimization of activity in multiple muscles, expressed as a global EMG minimum. The presence of global EMG minima during a movement are typical of mature movement patterns.The objectives of the study were to 1) identify whether referent control is associated with the maturation of locomotor skills in young children and 2) determine whether the maturation of locomotor tasks is associated with participation levels of young children. For Objective 1, we hypothesized that a) acquisition of locomotor skills is characterized by the appearance of global EMG minima in specific phases of the movement cycle; and b) the acquisition of the jumping forward skill occurs through the combination of movement patterns for walking and vertical jumping. For Objective 2, we hypothesized that children with more mature locomotor movement patterns have higher levels of participation.Eleven TD children between 3 and 5 years old (mean age 4.1 ± 1.2 yrs.) and 10 young adults (controls) between 18 and 25 years old (mean age 21.7 ± 1.25 yrs.) were recruited. In children, the Test of Gross Motor Development 2nd edition, and the Young Children’s Participation and Environment Measure were evaluated. During the experiment, kinematics leg movements (24 markers; 12-camera Vicon 512 system) and EMG (Wave Wireless and Noraxon systems) from 5 muscles bilaterally were recorded during walking, vertical jumping and jumping forward. The percentage and location of global EMG minima in the movement cycle, as well as the ankle marker displacement measured as slope angles, for all 3 tasks were evaluated.Children had fewer movement cycles with global EMG minima for both jumping tasks (vertical jumping: 38.1 ± 20.4%, jumping forward: 64.1 ± 22.2%) compared to the young adults (vertical jumping: 93.9 ± 17.1%, jumping forward: 86.3 ± 16.7%). The locations of the global EMG minima were different between groups for the vertical jumping task. In terms of combinations of movement patterns, walking-jumping forward slope angles were unrelated in children but had a positive and significant relationship in adults, whereas vertical jumping-jumping forward slope angles tended to be positively related in children but not in young adults.Greater frequency of participation in the home and community settings were significantly correlated with a greater number of global EMG minima and higher slope angles during walking. The differences in characteristics of global EMG minima and movement patterns between groups, and their relationships with participation levels may be indicators of the maturation of locomotion in TD children. Absence of global EMG minima and dependence of movement patterns between jumping tasks may help to objectively identify developmental disorders and delays in motor skills.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L’étude des mécanismes neurologiques à la base de la maturation motrice est primordiale pour mieux comprendre l’acquisition des capacités motrices durant la petite enfance. La maturation du contrôle du comportement d’atteinte chez le nourrisson a généralement été décrite à l’aide d’approches dynamiques. Ces approches ont aussi été étendues à l’étude de la maturation des habiletés motrices chez l’enfant ayant un développement typique (DT) et ce basé sur l’hypothèse de configuration de référence. Cette hypothèse suggère que, lors d’un mouvement rythmique, la configuration réelle et référentielle du corps peut coïncider de manière transitoire entrainant une minimisation de l’activité électromyographique (EMG) dans plusieurs muscles. La présence de minima globaux de l’EMG lors d’un mouvement serait typique des schémas de mouvements dits matures.Cette étude vise, chez les jeunes enfants, à déterminer si 1) le contrôle référentiel est associé à une maturation des habiletés locomotrices et si 2) la maturation des tâches locomotrices est associée aux différents niveaux de participation. Pour l’objectif 1, l’hypothèse est que a) l’acquisition des habiletés locomotrices est caractérisée par l’apparition de minima globaux de l’EMG lors de phases spécifiques du cycle de mouvements et b) l’acquisition de l’habileté à sauter vers l’avant est le produit d’une combinaison des schémas de mouvements lors de la marche et lors du saut vertical. Pour l’objectif 2, l’hypothèse est que les enfants ayant des schémas de mouvements locomoteurs matures ont également des niveaux de participation plus élevés.Onze enfants au DT âgés entre 3 et 5 ans (âge moyen 4.1±1.2 ans) et 10 jeunes adultes âgés entre 18 et 25 ans (âge moyen 21.7±1.25 ans) ont été recrutés. Chez les enfants, les Tests de Développement de la Motricité Globale et la Mesure de l’Environnement et de la Participation des Jeunes Enfants ont été évalués. Durant l’expérimentation, les mouvements cinématiques (24 marqueurs; systèmes 12-caméra Vicon 512) et EMG (Systèmes Wave Wireless et Noraxon) de cinq muscles bilatéraux des jambes et ont été enregistrés lors de la marche, le saut vertical et le saut vers l’avant. Le pourcentage et l’emplacement des minima globaux de l’EMG durant le cycle du mouvement et le déplacement du marqueur de la cheville ont été évalués pour les trois tâches et ont également été mesurés en angle de pente.Les enfants ont eu moins de cycles de mouvement avec minima globaux de l’EMG lors des deux sauts (saut vertical: 38.1±20.4%, saut vers l’avant: 64.1±22.2%) comparativement aux jeunes adultes (saut vertical: 93.9±17.1%, saut vers l’avant: 86.3±16.7%). L’emplacement des minima globaux d’activité musculaire était différent entre les deux groupes lors du saut vertical.  Pour la combinaison de marche et saut vers l’avant, les angles de pente de l’inclinaison vers le bas n’étaient pas significativement liés chez les enfants, bien qu’ils montraient une relation positive et significative chez les jeunes adultes. Pour la combinaison de saut vertical et saut vers l’avant, les angles verticaux de pente avaient tendance à être liés positivement chez les enfants, mais pas chez les jeunes adultes. Une fréquence accrue de la participation aux activités effectuées à la maison et dans la communauté fût significativement corrélée à un plus grand nombre de minima globaux de l’EMG et à des angles de pente plus élevés pendant la marche. Les différences observées entre les caractéristiques des minima globaux de l’EMG et les patrons de mouvement entre les groupes, ainsi que leurs relations à la participation, pourraient être des indicateurs de la maturation de la locomotion chez les enfants au DT. L’absence de minima globaux de l’EMG et de dépendance des patrons de mouvements entre les tâches de sauts pourrait faciliter l’identification objective des troubles du développement et du retard dans l’acquisition des habiletés motrices.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mindy Levin</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Anouk Lamontagne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp82b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bk682</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akk91fp17c"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Variation of the frog skin microbiota across an environmental gradient: taxonomic diversity and potential function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Varela, Brandon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Research on the amphibian skin microbiota has focused on identifying bacterial taxa that deter a pathogenic chytrid fungus (Batrachochytrium dendrobatidis - Bd), and on describing patterns of microbiota variation.  However, it remains unclear how environmental variation affects amphibian skin bacterial communities, and whether the overall functional diversity of the amphibian skin microbiota is associated to such variation.  I sampled skin microbial communities from three dendrobatid frog species before and after the onset of the wet season in one site, and from one dendrobatid frog species across an environmental gradient along the Panama Canal.  I found frog skin microbial alpha diversity to be highest in frogs from sites with low soil pH, but no clear effect of the onset of the wet season.  However, I found frog skin microbial community structure (beta diversity) to be affected by soil pH and the onset of the wet season, which also resulted in a decrease of between-samples variation.  Across the sampled frog species, bacterial functional groups changed with the onset of the wet season, with certain bacterial functional groups entirely disappearing and others differing in their relative abundances after the onset of the wet season.  In particular, I found proportion of Bd-inhibiting bacteria to correlate with mean soil pH, and to increase in two of the frog species with the onset of the wet season.  Taken together, my results suggest that the host’s requirements facilitated by bacteria, including disease resistance, may be site-specific and follow seasonal patterns.  These new insights should be considered when implementing conservation programs that include a probiotic bacteria treatment.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La recherche sur le microbiote de la peau des amphibiens a pris plusieurs chemins dans les dernières années.  Elle s’est principalement concentrée sur l’identité des bactéries dissuadant le champignon pathogène chytride (Batrachochytrium dendrobatidis - Bd) et sur la description de la variation du microbiote.  Toutefois, il n’est pas encore clair comment la variation environnementale affecte la communauté bactérienne sur la peau des amphibiens.  De plus, on s’interroge encore sur la diversité fonctionnelle du microbiote associée à une telle variation environnementale.  J’ai échantillonné la communauté microbienne cutanée de trois espèces de grenouille de la famille Dendrobathidae avant et après le début de la saison humide.  J’ai également échantilloné la communauté microbienne cutanée d’une espèce de Dendrobathidae à travers un gradient environnemental le long du canal de Panama.  J’ai trouvé que la diversité alpha de la communauté microbienne cutanée était plus grande entre les grenouilles provenant de sites où le site avait un pH bas.  Cependant, il n’y avait pas d’effet clair par rapport au début de la saison humide.  Toutefois, j’ai trouvé que la structure de la communauté microbienne (la diversité béta) était affectée par le pH du sol et le début de la saison humide.  Ceci résultait en une diminution de la variation entre les échantillons.  À travers les espèces de grenouilles échantillonnées, les groupes fonctionnels bactériens changeaient avec l’arrivée de la saison humide, avec même une disparition de certains groupes entièrement, ainsi qu’une différence en abondance relative des autres.  Particulièrement, j’ai trouvé que la proportion de bactéries dissuadant le Bd corrélait avec la moyenne du pH du sol et avec l’augmentation de deux des espèces de grenouilles au début de la saison humide.  Ensemble, ces résultats suggèrent que les besoins d’hôtes facilités par la bactérie, incluant la résistance aux maladies, pourraient être spécifiques aux sites et suivrent un caractére saisonnier.  Ces nouvelles perspectives devraient être considéré lors de l’implentation de programmes de conversation, incluant un traitement de bioaugmentation probiotique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David M. Green</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Roberto Ibáñez</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>David A. Lesbarreres</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hf69p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fp17c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67jt716"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Tips of Fingers, Tips of Tongues: Emulating authentic dialogue in roleplaying video games</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Caskenette, Stephanie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dialogue systems are integral mechanics in roleplaying video games, as forms of worldbuilding that acknowledge player choice. Early conceptions of game dialogue in text adventure games let players type in whatever they want to say, in attempts to emulate true conversational fidelity. However, their rudimentary structures limit the possibility of direct and topical responses to typed input, breaking immersion within the game. Furthermore, consumer shifts in primary gaming platforms, from personal computers to dedicated video game consoles, influence how dialogue is designed within technological restraints. This thesis examines how video game dialogue effectively mimics conversations with the player while maintaining a sense of immersion despite platform limitations. An exploration of critical game design factors, including the balance between gameplay and narrative, reveals how dialogue systems historically shift from freeform designs to more scripted structures. Though a consideration and application of commonly-used game design strategies in other development areas, this thesis promotes innovation in dialogue system design, offering new potentials for play. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les systèmes de dialogue sont des mécanismes intégraux qui reconnaissent les choix du joueur dans les jeux de rôle en tant que formes de worldbuilding. Les premières conceptions du dialogue dans les jeux d'aventure textuels permettent aux joueurs d’entrer ce qu’ils veulent, afin d'imiter la fidélité d’une conversation. Cependant, leurs structures rudimentaires limitent la possibilité de réponses directes et topiques à l'entrée dactylographiée, brisant l'immersion dans le jeu. De plus, les changements de consommation dans les plates-formes de jeu primaires depuis les ordinateurs personnels jusqu'aux consoles de jeux vidéo dédiées influencent la façon dont le dialogue est conçu dans le cadre des contraintes technologiques. Cette thèse examine comment le dialogue dans le jeu vidéo imite efficacement les conversations avec le joueur tout en conservant un sentiment d'immersion malgré les limites de la plate-forme. Une exploration des facteurs critiques de la conception du jeu, y compris l'équilibre entre le gameplay et le récit, révèle comment les systèmes de dialogue se sont historiquement éloignés des conceptions libres vers des structures plus scénarisées. Bien qu'il s'agisse d'une considération et d’une application de stratégies de conception de jeu couramment utilisées dans d'autres domaines de développement, cette thèse encourage l'innovation dans la conception de systèmes de dialogue, offrant de nouveaux potentiels de jeu.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sterne, Jonathan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c0835.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt716</ual:fedora3Handle></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795b15r"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The roles of cysteinyl leukotriene receptors in chlorine mediated irritant induced asthma</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Simon, Leora</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract> Dans le contexte de l’asthme allergique, il est bien connu que la signalisation par les récepteurs cysteinyl leucotriènes 1 et 2 (CysLTR1 et 2) induit la bronchoconstriction, la perméabilité vasculaire, l’œdème pulmonaire, la sécrétion et élimination de mucus ainsi que l’hyperplasie des muscles lisses des voies aériennes.  Cependant, il existe peu d’informations concernant les rôles du recepteur CysLTR1 et 2 dans l’asthme irritant.  Dans ce projet, nous avons approfondi des résultats antérieurs suggérant que CysLTR1 a un rôle protecteur dans une modèle murin de l’asthme irritant provoqué par l’exposition aiguë au chlore. Notre but premier était de confirmer les résultats antérieurs montrant que les souris ne disposant pas du gène pour CysLTR1 (CysLTR1-/-) présentent une augmentation de l'inflammation des cellules innées inflammatoire dans la lavage broncho-alvéolaire et de l'hyperréactivité bronchique (HRB) 24h avant l’exposition au chlore. Auparavant, l'hypothèse a été faite que l’augmentation de l'inflammation et de l’HRB des souris CysLTR1-/- est causée par l’incapacité du facteur érythroïde nucléaire 2-comme 2 (Nrf2), un facteur de transcription qui contrôle une grande partie des réponses antioxydantes, à se déplacer vers le noyau. Pour cette raison, nous avons comparé les réponses des souris Nrf2-/- avec les CysLTR1-/-.  Nos résultats montrent une augmentation de l’HRB mais pas de l’inflammation chez les souris CysLTR1-/- 24h après l’exposition au chlore en comparaison avec les souris exprimant le gène CysLTR1. Il n'y avait pas de différences en terme d’inflammation et de l’HRB à 48h.  L’inflammation et l’HRB n’étaient pas résolus chez les souris Nrf2-/- à 48h. Nous avons alors conclu qu’il n’existe pas de mécanisme direct entre la signalisation de CysLTR1 et la translocation de Nrf2 dans la pathogenèse de l’asthme irritant. Ce résultat a été confirmé par des expériences menées en utilisant une lignée de cellulaires bronco-épithéliales, Beas-2B.   Notre but secondaire consistait à déterminer si l’augmentation de l'inflammation et de l’HRB dans les CysLTR1-/- étaient causés par une augmentation de la signalisation de CysLTR2 en l’absence du récepteur principal. Nous avons inhibé CysLTR2 avec HAMI 3379, un antagoniste sélectif pour CysLTR2 dans les souris CysLTR1-/- et avons observé la réponse 24h avant le chlore. Il y avait une petite augmentation de HRB dans les souris ayant reçu HAMI 3379 par rapport aux contrôles mais pas de changement de en terme d’inflammation. Ces résultats réfutaient notre hypothèse. CysLTR2 étant plus connu pour son rôle de fuite vasculaire, nous avons évalué la concentration de fibrinogène dans les lavages broncho-alvéolaires (LBA), entre 30 min et 3h pour les souris normales et CysLTR1-/-. La fuite vasculaire s'avérait être la plus grande à 30 min et était résolue à 3h dans les deux cas. Nous avons donc évalué l’effet de l'administration de HAMI 3379 sur la fuite vasculaire à 30min. Nos résultats montraient que CysLTR2 induisait la fuite micro-vasculaire mais que la fuite vasculaire n’était pas importante dans la pathogenèse de l’asthme irritant. Nous planifions des expériences additionnelles pour déterminer la raison pour laquelle CysLTR2 est pathologique immédiatement après exposition au chlore (30min) mais protecteur à 24h. L’asthme irritant reste encore une énigme et il est impératif que nous fassions plus de recherches pour comprendre comment le traiter.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>  In allergic asthma, signalling through cysteinyl leukotriene receptors 1 and 2 (CysLTR1 and 2) mediates bronchoconstriction, increased vascular permeability, pulmonary edema, mucus secretion and clearance and airway smooth muscle hyperplasia.  However, little is known about the role of these receptors in irritant asthma.  In this project, we expanded on previous findings suggesting a protective role for CysLTR1 in a murine model of acute chlorine induced irritant asthma and explored potential roles of CysLTR2.   Our first aim was to replicate previous findings that CysLTR1 knockout (CysLTR1 -/-) mice had increased inflammation and airway hyperresponsiveness (AHR) at 24h following chlorine exposure.  As it was previously hypothesized that CysLTR1 -/- mice display increased AHR and inflammation due to the inability of nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (Nrf2), a transcription factor responsible for induction of many antioxidant mechanisms, to translocate to the nucleus, we also compared the phenotypes of Nrf2 -/- mice to their CysLTR1-/- counterparts at 48h.  The results showed an increase in AHR but not inflammation in CysLTR1 -/- mice 24h post exposure and no difference 48h post exposure compared to their wild type counterparts.  As Nrf2-/- mice have unresolved inflammation and AHR at 48h post chlorine, we concluded there was no direct mechanism linking signalling through CysLTR1 and Nrf2 translocation in the pathogenesis of irritant asthma.  This was reinforced by in vitro experiments on a bronchiolar epithelial cell line, BEAS-2B.  Our second aim was to determine if the increase in AHR and inflammation seen in CysLTR1-/- mice could be explained by increased signalling through CysLTR2 in the absence of CysLTR1.  We explored this by inhibiting CysLTR2 using HAMI 3379, a selective antagonist of CysLTR2, in CysLTR1-/- mice and looking at response 24h post chlorine.  Mice administered HAMI 3379 displayed a slightly more severe phenotype in terms of AHR than CysLTR1-/- mice administered vehicle alone, disproving our initial hypothesis.  Since CysLTR2 is most commonly reported in the literature for its role in vascular leak, we evaluated the concentration of fibrinogen in the bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) as a marker of vascular leak at 30 minutes and three hours post chlorine exposure in wild type and CysLTR1-/- mice.  Fibrinogen concentration peaked at 30 min in both genotypes and returned to basal levels by three hours.  Therefore, we evaluated fibrinogen levels in CysLTR1-/- mice administered HAMI 3379 at 30 min post chlorine exposure to determine the role of CysLTR2 in vascular leak.  The data suggest that CysLTR2 mediates microvascular leak, although this event is not crucial in the overall pathogenesis of irritant asthma.  Further study is needed to explore the mechanisms causing increased AHR and inflammation in CysLTR1-/- mice and explain the switch of CysLTR2 from a pathogenic role immediately following irritant exposure (30 min) to a protective one in later stages (24h).  Irritant asthma remains a poorly understood asthma phenotype which requires further study to ensure appropriate treatment. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>James G. Martin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227ms317.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795b15r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g748z"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Thermal performance of low porosity architected materials for film cooling applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Reynolds, Gerard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Plusieurs problèmes d'ingénierie nécessitent une conception pour des températures environnemental extrêmes et des gradients thermiques sévères où les composants subissent une contrainte et une déformation élevés. L'air de refroidissement est souvent introduit par des trous pour refroidir la structure et permettre un plus grand gradient thermique. Malheureusement, ces trous de refroidissement présentent des concentrations de stress indésirables. Cette thèse étudie des structures planaires à basse porosité subissant un refroidissement du film pour améliorer l'efficacité du refroidissement, la durée de vie et la fiabilité dans des conditions de température extrêmes. Une famille de formes de voûte planaire est générée à l'aide de superellipses et d'arcs superelliptiques comme blocs de construction pour tesseller une gamme de motifs géométriques diversifiés. La performance thermique des architectures poreuses est étudiée en utilisant une approche combinée de plans d'expériences et d'optimisation avec des algorithmes évolutionnaires. L'étude montre que les formes de ratio d'aspect élevé dans un motif étalé sont préférées pour une efficacité de refroidissement plus élevée.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Many engineering problems require design for extreme operating temperatures and severe thermal gradients where components experience high stress and strain. Cooling air is often introduced through holes to cool the structure and allow for a greater thermal gradient. Unfortunately, these cooling holes introduce unwanted stress concentrations. This research studies low porosity planar structures undergoing film cooling for improved cooling efficiency, service life, and reliability under extreme temperature conditions. A family of planar void shapes are generated using superellipses and superelliptical arcs as building blocks to tessellate a range of diverse geometric patterns. The thermal performance of the porous architectures is investigated using a combined approach of design of experiments and population-based optimization. The study shows that high aspect ratio shapes in a staggered pattern is preferred for higher cooling efficiency.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Damiano Pasini</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bh51r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g748z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f6075"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gendered urbanness and women's self-defence in Mexico: from the right to the city to the right to be safe</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maldonado Dorantes, Itzel Danae</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette recherche explore les liens entre l’activisme contre le harcèlement de rue et les différents niveaux d’accès au droit à la ville selon le genre. Plus précisément, je me penche sur l’importance politique des pratiques et politiques d’autodéfense à Mexico déclenchées par une lutte nationale et régionale qui se bat pour une vie urbaine sûre. Cette lutte prend la forme de manifestations autant discursives que corporelles et incarnées, revendique le droit des femmes de naviguer la ville, et se déploie sur fond d’un ensemble de relations de pouvoir socialement et spatialement construites qui se manifestent dans l’espace public.Je commence par retracer les textes fondamentaux sur le droit à la ville et ses invocations, avancés et interrogations contemporaines; d’Henri Lefebvre, qui est l’auteur de ce concept, aux universitaires de gauche qui reprochent à ce dernier de ne pas prendre en compte les différences entre les individus. Puis, j’examine les mandats, stratégies pratiques et mouvements féministes populaires contre le harcèlement de rue à Mexico et le rôle qu’ils jouent en appelant les femmes à s’approprier les rues au travers d’intervention politisées dans la vie urbaine. Prenant en compte les conceptualisations théoriques du droit à la ville et guidée par les orientations féministes développées par Tovi Fenster et Shelley Buckingham—pionnières de l’analyse du droit à la ville sous l’ange du genre—Je propose de comprendre les gestes féminins d’appropriation perturbatrice de l’espace public au moyen d’une culture d’autodéfense contre le harcèlement de rue comme forme d’action politique qui recrée l’espace urbain et contribue à re-signifier le sens de la ville.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This research explores the connection between anti-street harassment activism and the gendered right to access the city.  Specifically, I address the political significance of self-defence politics and practices in Mexico City that are ignited by a national and regional women’s struggle which reclaims a safer urban experience as a form of both discursive and embodied protest that advocates women’s right to navigate the city against the backdrop of a socially and spatially constructed set of power relations that unfold in public spaces.First, I map the foundational scholarship on the right to the city and its contemporary uses, advances and interrogations, from Henri Lefebvre’s coining of the concept to the left academic critiques of the term’s dismissal of identity-related differentiations among individuals. Then, I examine the mandates and hands-on strategies of grassroots female activism against street harassment in Mexico City and the role these play in calling upon women to appropriate the streets as a politicized intervention in the city life.Considering the theoretical conceptualization of the right to the city and guided by the feminist orientations developed by Tovi Fenster and Shelley Buckingham —pioneer scholars of the analysis of the right to the city from a gender perspective— I suggest understanding women's disruptive appropriation of public spaces through anti-street harassment and self-defence culture as a form of political action that recreates the urban environment and contributes to signifying the meaning of the city.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Straw, William O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795b161.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f6075</ual:fedora3Handle></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anz806244x"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Contemporary American Zika virus isolates elicit differential growth kinetics and interferon responses in human astrocytoma cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rajah, Maaran</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The recent emergence and rapid geographic expansion of Zika virus (ZIKV) poses a significant challenge for public health. Although historically causing only a mild febrile illness, recent ZIKV outbreaks have been associated with more severe neurological complications such as Guillain-Barré syndrome and fetal microcephaly. In this investigation, we demonstrate that the contemporary American ZIKV isolates replicate to higher titers at early time points post-infection and are less cytopathic than the historical African ZIKV strain in a human astrocytoma cell line. Interestingly, we found that that contemporary epidemic isolates differentially induce type I and type III IFN-mediated signaling. Specifically, the contemporary strain elicited a robust induction of several anti-viral ISGs and induced STAT1 and STAT2 protein expression and phosphorylation to a greater extent than both the historical African, and the early Asian isolates. This research suggests that ZIKV isolates may have evolved mechanisms to increase viral replication kinetics without increasing cytopathicity, while also highlighting the importance of cell-intrinsic factors in studies of viral fitness.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'émergence récente et l'expansion géographique rapide du virus Zika (ZIKV) posent un défi important pour la santé publique. Bien qu'historiquement causant seulement une maladie fébrile légère, les récentes épidémies de ZIKV ont été associées à des complications neurologiques plus graves telles que le syndrome de Guillain-Barré et la microcéphalie fœtale. Dans cette étude, nous démontrons que les isolats de ZIKV américains contemporains produisent des charges virales plus élevées au début de l'infection et sont moins cytopathogènes que la souche ZIKV africaine historique dans une lignée cellulaire d'astrocytome humain. De plus, nous avons constaté que les isolats épidémiques contemporains induisent différemment la signalisation médiée par l'IFN de type I et de type III. En effet, la souche contemporaine provoque une robuste induction de plusieurs ISG antiviraux et induit une expression et une phosphorylation des protéines STAT1 et STAT2 dans une plus grande mesure que les isolats africains historiques et que les premiers isolats asiatiques. Cette recherche suggère que les isolats de ZIKV peuvent avoir évolué des mécanismes augmentant la cinétique de la réplication virale sans augmenter les effets cytopathogènes, tout en soulignant l'importance des facteurs intrinsèques aux cellules lors d’études de la capacité réplicative du virus.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Selena Sagan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x3839.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806244x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kq58w"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>sccaws: an R package for two models of multipopulation canonical correlation analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Knowlton, Newman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'analyse canonique des corrélations (ACC) est une méthode pour décrire la relation entre deux ensembles de données multivariés. Mathématiquement, l’ACC est très générale, ce qui en fait un candidat populaire pour l'extension mathématique. Cependant, la complexité computationnelle de l'ACC et de ses extensions peut les rendre inaccessibles pour de nombreux chercheurs appliqués. Ce papier résume deux extensions de l’ACC pour l'analyse de plusieurs populations et introduit un paquet R, sccaws, qui rend ces extensions immédiatement accessibles aux chercheurs appliqués. L'introduction du paquet sccaws inclue une vue d’ensemble des fonctions du paquet et deux exemples d'analyses illustrant son utilité. Les exemples sont extraits de Goria et Flury (1996) et de Gu et Wu (2017), qui ont introduit les premiers les extensions ACC multipopulation. Le paquet sccaws reproduit parfaitement les résultats originaux.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Canonical correlation analysis (CCA) is a method for describing the relationship between two multivariate data sets. Mathematically, CCA is very general, which has made CCA a popular candidate for mathematical extension. However, the computational complexity of CCA and its extensions can make them inaccessible for many applied researchers. This thesis summarizes two extensions of CCA for the analysis of multiple populations and introduces an R package, sccaws, that makes these extensions immediately accessible to applied researchers. The introduction of the sccaws package includes an overview of the package's functions and two example analyses illustrating the utility of the package. The examples are pulled from Goria and Flury (1996) and Gu and Wu (2017), who first introduced the multipopulation CCA extensions. The sccaws package perfectly replicates the original results.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Heungsun Hwang</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t938.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kq58w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988n48s"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of selected additives on the mechanical and rheological properties of an amorphous Poly(Hydroxyalkanoate)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bustos, Marlon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>RésuméDans cette étude, plusieurs mélanges d'un poly(hydroxyalcanoate) (PHA) amorphe avec divers additifs ont été préparés par extrusion et testés pour évaluer leur effet sur les propriétés mécaniques et thermiques du polymère. Plus précisément, on a étudié le succinate de diheptyle (DHpS) et l'huile de soja époxydée (ESO), tous deux plastifiants biodégradables, ainsi que la charge de carbonate de calcium, préalablement traitée en surface avec 2% en poids d'acide stéarique pour améliorer la dispersion dans la matrice. En outre, du peroxyde de dicumyle (DCP) a été ajouté à la formulation pour favoriser la réticulation du polymère. Aucun changement significatif dans la température de transition vitreuse (Tg) n'a été causé par l'ESO, alors que DHpS a provoqué de faibles diminutions de Tg suggérant un effet de plastification. Aucun des plastifiants n'a amélioré l'allongement à la rupture, le module de Young ou la contrainte maximale par rapport à la résine de base. ESO a fourni une lubrification et facilité la dispersion de la charge. L'ajout de charge en combinaison avec ESO a produit des incréments dans le module de Young dans tous les cas, et jusqu'à 20 parties par cent de caoutchouc (PHR) de charge ont été ajoutés au polymère tout en maintenant des valeurs d'allongement à la rupture. L'extrusion réactive avec DCP a montré des incréments allant jusqu'à 130% sur l'allongement à la rupture et jusqu'à 250% sur la contrainte maximale par rapport aux valeurs du biopolymère non traité. L'extrusion réactive avec DHpS et la charge n'a pas amélioré l'allongement à la rupture ni la contrainte maximale par rapport aux valeurs du polymère réticulé. Tous les mélanges plastifiés, avec ou sans charge, et avec ou sans DCP, ont présenté un comportement visqueux dans la masse fondue, les mélanges produits uniquement en ajoutant DCP ont montré un comportement plus élastique, ce qui expliquait l'amélioration des propriétés mécaniques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>AbstractIn this study, several blends of an amorphous poly(hydroxyalkanoate) (PHA) with various additives were prepared by extrusion, and tested to evaluate their effect on the mechanical, thermal, and rheological properties of the polymer. Specifically, diheptyl succinate (DHpS) and epoxidized soybean oil (ESO), both biodegradable plasticizers, were blended along with calcium carbonate filler, which had been previously surface treated with 2 wt% stearic acid to improve dispersion into the matrix, were studied. Additionally, dicumyl peroxide (DCP) was added to the formulation to promote crosslinking of the polymer. No significant changes in glass transition temperature (Tg) were caused by ESO, whereas DHpS caused small decreases in Tg suggesting a plasticization effect. Neither of the plasticizers improved the elongation at break, Young’s modulus, or maximum stress compared to the base resin. ESO did provide lubrication and ease the dispersion of the filler. The addition of filler in combination with ESO did produce increases in Young’s modulus in all cases, and up to 20 parts per hundred rubber (PHR) of filler were added to the polymer while the values of elongation at break improved slightly. The reactive extrusion with DCP showed increments up to 130% on elongation at break and up to 250% on maximum stress compared to the values of the untreated biopolymer. The reactive extrusion with DHpS and filler did not improve the elongation at break nor the maximum stress compared to the values of the crosslinked polymer. All plasticized blends, with or without filler, and with or without DCP, exhibited viscous-like behavior in the melt, the blends that were produced only adding DCP showed a more elastic behavior, which explained the improvement in the mechanical properties.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milan Maric</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Richard L. Leask</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827f035.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988n48s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xx35k"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Towards plurilingualism in Montreal French Schools: a critical discourse analysis of current governmental and school board policies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Courtemanche, France</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Plusieurs études démontrent que les pratiques plurilingues ont des avantages positifs sur le développement social et cognitif d’un enfant.  Plusieurs initiatives de recherche au Québec démontrent aussi qu’accorder une importance particulière à l’ouverture aux langues et au plurilinguisme peut faciliter l’apprentissage du français. Cependant, il est plutôt rare que les écoles publiques franco-montréalaises encouragent ce type d’approche. Le parcours historique de la province démontre qu’après avoir milité longuement pour faire reconnaitre le français comme langue commune, une loi assez musclée a été créée afin de perpétuer l’apprentissage du français chez les populations d’accueil et améliorer la qualité de la langue chez les Québécois de souche. La Charte de la langue française dicte aujourd’hui les mesures que doivent mettre en œuvre les commissions scolaires pour assurer la vitalité du français. Ces mesures sont articulées dans des politiques linguistiques qui sont propres à chacune des commissions scolaires. Cette étude vise à mieux comprendre et identifier les facilitateurs et les barrières au plurilinguisme. Avec une analyse critique du discours intégré dans les politiques gouvernementales et des commissions scolaires montréalaises, j’aspire à mieux comprendre le hiatus entre les discours d’équité et de valorisation culturelle de cette commission et les pratiques unilingues actuellement privilégiées à l’école. Le but de cette étude est d’informer les éducateurs au sujet des facilitateurs du plurilinguisme dans les politiques en place, d’encourager les intervenants en milieu scolaire à participer à des activités de perfectionnement professionnel et d’offrir des recommandations équitables qui respectent les droits de la personne afin d’informer la révision de la politique. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Many studies demonstrate that plurilingual practices in an educational setting have positive advantages on the social and cognitive development of a child. Initiatives within Québec research fields demonstrate that paying attention to language awareness and plurilingualism can facilitate the learning of French. Nonetheless, it is rare for Montréal French public schools to encourage these approaches. The socio-historical evolution of the province demonstrates that after a continuous fight to get French recognized as the language of the public sphere, legislation was used as a tool to ensure the learning of French by newly arrived immigrants as well as to improve the quality of French language-use among all Quebecers. Today, the Charter of the French Language dictates measures that school boards must take to assure the vitality of the French language. These measures are articulated in language policies that are elaborated in each school board. This study seeks to identify and better understand the facilitators and barriers of plurilingualism. Through a Critical Discourse analysis of the discourse in governmental and the Commission Scolaire de Montréal policies, this study aims to better understand the gap between the equity and cultural valorization discourse in policy and the unilingual practice currently privileged in Québec schools. The research will be used to inform school educators about ways to support education for plurilingualism in current educational policy, encourage education stakeholders to engage in professional self-development about education for plurilingualism, and offer equitable recommendations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Naomi Nichols</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mekhala Sarkar</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qr985.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xx35k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az029p7212"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The cost of compliance to the Paris agreement and its distribution: An input-output analysis of Canada’s commitment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beaulieu-Guay, Louis-Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To fulfill its Paris Agreement commitment, Canada must find a way to substantially reduce its greenhouse gas emissions. Given the Canadian political system, where regulation and taxation powers are divided between different levels of government, a nation-wide action plan against climate change calls for a high level of coordination and agreement between provinces. The goal of this research is to propose a way to limit Canada’s GHG emissions without placing an unacceptable burden on the highly emitting provinces. Using a subnational interregional input-output model with interprovincial trade and GHG emissions, the economic impact of an hypothetical carbon pricing policy is assessed according to three burden allocation scenarios and nine sub-scenarios accounting for technological changes. The first allocation evenly assigns the GHG emission reduction across all industrial sectors. The second and third allocations put the burden of the abatement costs on the largest GHG emitting sectors of the Canadian economy. By simulating these different policy scenarios, this study looks at the trade-offs between their overall economic costs and the geographical distribution of those costs amongst provinces. Results show distributing the GHG emission cut evenly across industrial sectors is the highest cost alternative. On the other hand, targeting only the largest GHG emitting sectors places an excessive burden on the western provinces, preventing the policy to be realistically implemented in Canada. A compromise between these two options is proposed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Afin de respecter l’engagement contracté sous l’Accord de Paris, le Canada doit trouver comment réduire de façon substantielle ses émissions de gaz à effet de serre (GES). Étant donné les particularités du système politique canadien, où les pouvoirs de taxation et de réglementation sont divisés parmi les différents niveaux de gouvernement, un plan national de lutte aux changements climatiques nécessite un niveau de coordination et de coopération important entre les provinces. Le but de cette recherche est de proposer une façon de limiter les émissions de GES canadien sans attribuer un trop lourd fardeau aux provinces particulièrement polluantes. En utilisant un modèle entrée-sortie interrégional liant les différentes régions canadiennes et intégrant les émissions de GES en unité de masse, l’impact économique d’un hypothétique prix sur le carbone est évalué selon trois scénarios distribuant différemment le fardeau de l’effort environnemental et selon neuf sous-scénarios impliquant des changements technologiques. La première distribution considérée répartit la réduction de GES également parmi tous les secteurs industriels canadiens. Les deuxième et troisième distributions répartissent l’effort environnemental aux secteurs industriels produisant le plus de GES. En simulant ces trois scénarios de politique environnementale, cette étude examine les compromis à faire entre leurs coûts totaux et la distribution de ces coûts parmi les provinces. Les résultats de cette analyse démontrent qu’attribuer la réduction d’émission de GES également parmi les différents secteurs économiques est une option coûteuse. D’un autre côté, cibler uniquement le plus important producteur de GES place un fardeau très important sur les épaules des provinces de l’Ouest, empêchant ainsi la politique environnementale d’être appliquée sous le contexte canadien. Un hybride entre ces deux façons de procéder est proposé.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul Thomassin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gn44p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p7212</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd375z913"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The legal aspects of permanent human settlement on celestial bodies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kerkonian, Aram</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis will consider the legal aspects of permanent human settlement on celestial bodies.  Aside from the primal yearning to explore, humanity must soon begin space settlement activities to ensure the continued survival of the species.  Chapter 1 will briefly describe the value of preserving the human genome, outline why space settlement is necessary for such preservation and discuss the various public and private preparatory activities currently underway.  Chapter 2 will present, as a backdrop, the current legal regime of outer space and simultaneously apply its principles to permanent human settlement, paying particular attention to the now-fifty-year-old Outer Space Treaty.  Chapter 3 will explore the apparent contradiction resulting from a contextualized reading of Articles I and II (in light of permanent human settlement) and offer a potential solution by way of a human-first international settlement organization.  Given humanity’s innate desire to explore new worlds, coupled with the numerous cosmological and anthropological threats to its survival, this thesis offers a topical analysis of how a burgeoning space activity can be harmonized with a legal regime meant to ensure the exploration and use of space benefits all of humanity indefinitely into space and time.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire examinera les aspects légaux de l’établissement de civilisations humaines permanentes sur les corps célestes. Mis à part la soif élémentaire d’exploration, l’humanité devra bientôt commencer à peupler l’espace pour assurer la survie de notre espèce. Le premier chapitre décrira brièvement la pertinence de préserver le génome humain et ainsi que la nécessité de l’établissement dans l’espace pour se faire. Il discutera aussi des activités préparatoires publiques et privées qui sont déjà entamées. Le chapitre 2 présentera, en guise de trame de fond, le régime légal actuel de l’espace et appliquera ces principes à l’établissement permanent des humains dans l’espace, en portant une attention particulière au Traité de l’espace qui date maintenant de cinquante ans. Le chapitre 3 explorera l’apparente contradiction qui résulte d’une lecture contextualisée des articles I et II (à la lumière de l’établissement permanent des humains dans l’espace) et offre une solution potentielle, soit une organisation internationale d’établissement centrée d’abord sur l’humain. Compte tenu du désir inné qu’ont les humains d’explorer des mondes nouveaux ainsi que des menaces cosmologiques et anthropologiques à leur survie, ce mémoire offre une analyse contemporaine pour harmoniser l’activité bourgeonnante dans l’espace avec un régime assurant une exploration et une utilisation de l’espace bénéficiant l’humanité indéfiniment dans l’espace et le temps. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ram S. Jakhu</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nt396.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375z913</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289m443"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Medical Physics Unit</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Secondary neutrons around clinical electron and proton beams</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al Makdessi, Georges</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As is the case for high-energy photon beam therapy (&gt; 10 MV), secondary neutrons are produced during electron and proton therapy. These neutrons, which extend in energy up to the maximum energy of the primary beam, result in a whole-body radiation dose to the patient that presents a risk for a second, radiation-induced, cancer. To account for the second-cancer risk, it is necessary to understand the spectra of the neutrons involved.In this research project, the spectra of secondary neutrons arising from clinical electron and proton beams were measured. The neutron spectra around electron beams were measured for a Varian linear accelerator with maximum electron energy of 20 MeV. The neutron spectra around proton beams were measured in a treatment room with a gantry and a dedicated nozzle at the Skandion proton therapy clinic in Uppsala, Sweden. The proton beams were generated by the compact IBA Proteus Plus cyclotron, which has a maximum proton energy of 230 MeV.Measurements were performed using the Nested Neutron Spectrometer (NNS™, Detec Inc, Gatineau Quebec). The NNS™ comprises a central He-3 detector (active neutron detection) with seven high density polyethylene shells that may be arranged around the detector in Russian doll fashion. The neutron spectra arising from proton beams were measured using a modified version of the NNS™ incorporating a brass moderator shell to provide an extended energy range (EER) for the detection of high-energy neutrons. The raw neutron data were unfolded using the Maximum a Posteriori (MAP) method (custom-written in C++) and the vendor-supplied moderator response functions for the NNS™. Note that the MAP is a modified version of the Maximum Likelihood Estimation Method (MLEM) that penalizes any high noise component. To plot the secondary neutron fluence as a function of energy, the ROOT data analysis library from CERN was used.  Additionally, the ICRP conversion coefficients were used to calculate the neutron ambient dose equivalent rates around the electron and proton beams.The effect of several parameters on the neutron fluence rate and on the neutron dose equivalent rate were studied for each primary beam situation. For the electron beams, it was observed that as the energy of the primary electron beam increases, the neutron fluence rate and dose equivalent rate increase. In addition, the presence of a solid water phantom in the primary electron beam does not affect the neutron spectra. However, when closing the jaws in the treatment head, the neutron fluence rate and dose equivalent rate increase significantly which means that the main production of secondary neutrons around electron beams lies in the treatment head of the linear accelerator.For the proton beams, it was observed that as the energy of the primary proton beam increases, the neutron fluence rate and dose equivalent rate increase. The presence of a water phantom in the primary beam significantly enhances the direct and evaporation peaks of the neutron spectra which indicates that an important production of secondary neutrons around proton beams happens in the patient body. The evaporation and direct peaks of the neutron spectrum dominate the thermal peak when measuring on the couch (close to the neutron source), while the thermal peak dominates when measuring in the maze-room junction (far from the neutron source).</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Des neutrons secondaires sont produits pendant la thérapie par des faisceaux d’électrons et de protons, comme dans la thérapie par des photons à haute énergie (&gt; 10 MV). Ces neutrons, qui s'étendent en énergie jusqu'à l'énergie maximale du faisceau primaire, entraînent une dose de radiation au corps entier du patient présentant un risque pour un second cancer induit par radiation. Pour tenir compte du deuxième risque de cancer, il est nécessaire de comprendre les spectres des neutrons impliqués.Dans ce projet de recherche, on a mesuré les spectres des neutrons secondaires issus des faisceaux cliniques d'électrons et de protons. Les spectres de neutrons autour des faisceaux d'électrons ont été mesurés autour d’un accélérateur linéaire Varian avec une énergie électronique maximale de 20 MeV. Les spectres de neutrons autour des faisceaux de protons ont été mesurés dans une salle de traitement à la clinique Skandion à Uppsala, en Suède. Les faisceaux de protons ont été générés par le cyclotron compact IBA Proteus Plus, ayant une énergie maximale de protons égale à 230 MeV.Les mesures ont été réalisées à l'aide du Spectromètre Nested Neutron Spectrometer (NNS™, Detec Inc, Gatineau Québec). Le NNS™ comprend un détecteur central He-3 (détection active de neutrons) avec sept coques en polyéthylène haute densité qui peuvent être disposées autour du détecteur à la manière d’une poupée russe. Les spectres de neutrons issus des faisceaux de protons ont été mesurés à l'aide d'une version modifiée du NNS™ incorporant une coque de modérateur en laiton pour fournir une gamme d'énergie étendue (EER) pour la détection de neutrons à haute énergie. Les données de neutrons brutes ont été déployées en utilisant la méthode Maximum a Posteriori (MAP) (langage C++) et les fonctions de réponse du modérateur fournies par le fournisseur du NNS™. Notons que le MAP est une version modifiée de la méthode d'estimation de la vraisemblance maximale (MLEM) qui pénalise tout composant à haut niveau de bruit. Pour tracer le flux des neutrons secondaires en fonction de l'énergie, la librairie d'analyse de données ROOT du CERN a été utilisée. En outre, les coefficients de conversion de l'ICRP ont été utilisés pour calculer les taux de la dose équivalente ambiante des neutrons générés autour des faisceaux d'électrons et de protons.L'effet de plusieurs paramètres sur le flux des neutrons secondaires et sur le taux de la dose équivalente de ces neutrons a été étudié pour chaque situation de faisceau primaire.Par rapport aux faisceaux d'électrons, on a observé que lorsque l'énergie du faisceau d'électrons primaires augmente, le flux des neutrons et le taux de la dose équivalente augmentent. En outre, la présence d'un fantôme d'eau solide dans le faisceau d'électrons primaires n'affecte pas les spectres de neutrons. Cependant, lors de la fermeture des mâchoires dans la tête de traitement, le flux des neutrons et le taux de la dose équivalente augmentent de manière significative ce qui signifie que la majeure production de neutrons secondaires autour des faisceaux d’électrons se passe dans l’accélérateur linéairePour les faisceaux de protons, on a observé que lorsque l'énergie du faisceau de protons primaires augmente, le flux des neutrons et le taux de dose équivalente augmentent. La présence d'un fantôme d'eau dans le faisceau primaire augmente significativement les pics directs et d'évaporation des spectres de neutrons ce qui peut signifier qu’une partie importante de la production des neutrons secondaires autour des faisceaux de protons se passe dans le corps du patient. Le pic direct et celui d’évaporation du spectre de neutrons dominent le pic thermique lors de la mesure sur la table de traitement (près de la source de neutrons), tandis que le pic thermique domine lors de la mesure dans la jonction du labyrinthe (loin de la source de neutrons).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Kildea</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408057s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m443</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>