<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn009z47b"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>spa</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Hispanic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Narrativa arquetípico-novalesca y narrativa dramática de la poesía galaicoportuguesa medieval</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nodar Manso, Francisco</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this study the dramatic and novelistic aspects of Galaico-Portuguese poetry are analysed. We point out the dramatic tendency of the cantigas showing that the troubadours and jougleurs grouped together a certain number of cantigas with a dramatic purpose. This is demonstrated by the 12 cantigas with which Lopo L(')ias has created a satirical play, which we have entitled Os Zevroes, and which will be studied in the last chapter of this study. Secondly, the narrative and thematic structures of some 1.150 love songs are analysed. In this case, the cantigas de amigo and the cantigas de amor are seen by us as if they had been written by only one author, who had proposed to create with them a complex sentimental plot in dialogue. In order to prove the existence of a sentimental narrative romance in the Cancioneiros, the cantigas de amigo and the cantigas de amor have been classified into three categories: (a) third-person cantigas, in which the poet describes what the young girl (Amiga) does and says; (b) polyphonic cantigas, in which the poet dialogues with a female character (the pastourelle represents a particular kind of polyphony) and (c) sentimental cantigas, in which the poet disappears altogether, leaving way for the archetypal characters (the Amiga, the Amigo, the Mother, the Go-Between, etc) to express themselves freely, enabling us to reconstruct a dramatic-narrative romance. The analysis of this romance is based upon the formal and thematic particularities of the sentimental cantigas. The sentimental cantigas, in monologue or dialogue form, are open utterances. They are mutually complementary and they are spoken by archetypal characters, always denominated in the same manner, but who lack a proper name, who communicate among themselves, but are not described by the poet. These characters are "voices" that have been grouped together in this study in a causal and chronological order, so as to define the theme and the plot of the archetypal romance of the Cancioneiros. The narrative structure of the archetypal romance can be appreciated in the 374 cantigas de amor and de amigo which are found in the Appendix to this study, titled "Narrative anthology of Galaico-Portuguese love poetry".</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g817k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z47b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Galician poetry -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Galician poetry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62f888z"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Symbol and archetype in the music of Igor Stravinsky : a study in the correlation of myth and musical form</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nevile, Donald Cavendish</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study uses analysis, comparison, analogy, and inductive reasoning, to defend the thesis that a theological interpretation of the musical imagination can be arrived at through a correlation of myth and musical form. The first part of the study develops the approach to musical symbolism called presentational idealism, from Plato and Aristotle, through Kant, to Susanne Langer. This approach is then developed alongside evidence from various sources for a relationship between myth and music, to reach the conclusion that a mythical analysis of music is productive and practical. The second part of the study uses selected compositions of Stravinsky to illustrate the application of mythical analysis. By analyzing formal aspects of Stravinsky's music in terms of their mythic, ritual, and archetypal symbols, a theological quest is perceived in his work, which is dominated by three interrelated symbols: death, rebirth, and eternal life. These three symbols parallel another set of symbols which derives from his aesthetic stance: chaos, discipline, and freedom. By treating Stravinsky's compositions chronologically, a development is observed through his Russian, Neo-classical, and Serial periods, which indicates that these symbolic clusters, death/rebirth/eternal life, and chaos/discipline/freedom, are keys both to his aesthetics and to the spiritual development of his imagination. Evidence from Stravinsky himself is given priority, with analysis by scholars and critics introduced where it will clarify the thesis.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hj732.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f888z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 -- Symbolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Symbolism in music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anc580n21q"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Entomology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The taxonomy of the Chrysopidae of Canada and Alaska (Insecta: Neuroptera)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Garland, J. A. (John Allan)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Chrysopidae of Canada, and of Alaska, are reviewed and revised. The fauna consists of twenty-four species, as follows: Chrysopinae Chrysopa chi Fitch, C. coloradensis Banks, C. excepta Banks, C. nigricornis Burmeister, C. oculata Say, C. pleuralis Banks, and C. quadripunctata Burmeister; Chrysoperla carnea (Stephens), C. harrisii (Fitch) Comb. nov., and C. rufilabris (Burmeister) Comb. nov.; Chrysopiella brevisetosa Adams &amp; Garland Sp. nov. {published separately}; Eremochrysa canadensis (Banks), E. fraterna (Banks), and E. punctinervis (McLachlan); Glenochrysa lineaticornis (Fitch) Comb. nov.; Mallada perfectus (Banks), and M. slossonae Sp. nov. {in prep.}; Meleoma dolicharthra (Navas), M. emuncta (Fitch), M. schwarzi (Banks), and M. signoretti Fitch; Nineta gravida (Banks) Comb. nov.; and Oviedus placitus (Banks) Comb. nov. Nothochrysinae Nothochrysa californica Banks. Established changes in nomenclature include: Chrysopa crotchi Banks Syn. nov. under C. nigricornis, Chrysopa assimilis Banks Syn. nov. under C. oculata, Chrysopa downesi Smith Syn. nov. under Chrysoperla carnea, and Chrysoperla comanche (Banks) Comb. nov. Figures and geographical distribution, together with any biological notes pertaining to Canada, are included for each of the species in this fauna.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278t66p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580n21q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kn77p"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Thermodynamics of r-mer fluids and their mixtures : zeroth and first approximations in the equation of state approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Panayiotou, Constantinos G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This work is focussed on the equilibrium properties of r-mer fluids and their mixtures with particular emphasis on the limiting case of polymer mixtures. The Flory-Patterson-Prigogine corresponding states theory of Polymer Solutions is corrected for non-randomness and extended to multicomponent multigroup systems. A novel equipment for vapor sorption measurements in concentrated polymer solutions is described. With this equipment five polymer-polymer-solvent and one block copolymer-solvent systems have been studied. The Flory-Huggins (chi) interaction parameters for the polymer pairs have been determined. The experimental data have been treated with the non-random new Flory theory. Interactional constants for the polymer pairs have been determined. A new interaction parameter has been introduced which considerably simplifies the treatment of ternary systems. Two new statistical-thermodynamic theories of the fluid state have been developed and tested against existing experimental data.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wq82d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kn77p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Polymers -- Thermal properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>Equations of state</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xv60h"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Neurohumoral regulation of adrenal ornithine decarboxylase activity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alamzàn, Guillermina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of this study has been to elucidate the neural pathways involved in the regulation of adrenal ornithine decarboxylase (ODC) activity. Administration of the dopamine-receptor agonists apomorphine (APM) and piribedil (PBD) to rats led to an increase in ODC activity of both the adrenal medulla and cortex. These effects were blocked by giving the animals the dopaminergic antagonist haloperidol. The APM-induced increase in adrenomedullary ODC activity was largely prevented by denervation of the adrenal, transection of the spinal cord, and transection of the mesencephalon-diencephalon. Section of ventral spinal roots reduced the induction to varying extents, depending on the number of roots cut and their location between T(,4) and T(,12). The inducing effect of APM on adrenocortical ODC was abolished by hypophysectomy. Splanchnicotomy, rhizotomy and bilateral adrenal demedullation each attenuated the action of the drug. In contrast to this, section of the spinal cord or surgical isolation of the hypothalamus (preparation of "hypothalamic island") potentiated its effect. Impairment of serotonergic nerve function by systemic administration of p-chlorophenylalanine and intraventricular injection of 5,6'-dihydroxytryptamine or electrolytic potentiated the effect of APM in the adrenal medulla, but reduced it in the cortex. These observations suggest that adrenal ODC activity is predominantly regulated by one or more central facilitatory dopaminergic pathways. The pathway for the regulation of the medullary enzyme involves nuclei in the diencephalon-telencephalon and ultimately acts through the sympathetic nervous sytem. The pathway for the cortex involves the hypothalamus and acts via the anterior pituitary gland. These pathways include serotonergic components, which have opposite net effects on the induction of ODC produced by APM: inhibitory for the medulla and facilitatory for the cortex.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603qz10f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xv60h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ornithine decarboxylase</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genetic regulation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dn01p"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Actin in adrenal medullary chromaffin cells in cultrure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Raymond W. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It has been proposed that contractile proteins may mediate the events of the exocytotic release of hormones or neurotransmitters because of the similarities between the process of stimulus-secretion coupling and excitation-contraction coupling. Bovine adrenal medullary chromaffin cells were isolated and cultured and the morphological and secretory characteristics of these cells investigated. The results demonstrated that cultured chromaffin cells were a good model for developmental and secretory studies. Two isomeric forms of actin ((beta) and (gamma)), differing in isoelectric properties, were purified from chromaffin cells and characterized. The immunocytochemical localization of actin using an anti-chicken gizzard actin antibody showed that actin is distributed in a granular pattern in chromaffin cells in culture and that this distribution was similar to that of dopamine (beta)-hydroxylase. This suggested that actin might be associated with the chromaffin granules and indeed, actin was found when chromaffin granule membrane proteins were analyzed by SDS gel electrophoresis. This evidence supports our hypothesis that actin, along with the other contractile proteins, may mediate the process of stimulus-secretion coupling.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nx62s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dn01p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axp68kh05f"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Induced polypeptide synthesis during the development of bioluminescence in Beneckea Harveyi</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Michaliszyn, George A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>I. The function of aldehyde in the bacterial luminescent reaction was investigated using {1-('14)C} decanol in a coupled enzyme system. The substrates for the bioluminescent reaction, {1-('14)C} decanal and FMNH(,2), were generated in the reaction mixture by horse liver dehydrogenase and bacterial FMN reductase. Analysis of the reaction products indicated that aldehyde is exclusively convertted to the corresponding acid by bacterial luciferase. A linear relationship between light emission and acid production was obtained with a resulting quantum yield of 0.10 quanta per molecule of acid produced. II. In order to determine if the lag period in luminescence observed during early exponential growth of Beneckea harveyi reflects the repression of synthesis of one or both subunits of luciferase at the level of gene transcription/translation or the synthesis of one or both polypeptide(s) in the form of an inactive precursor, a double labelling experiment was performed such that, the proteins synthesized during the luminescence lag and inductions periods were labelled with ('3)H-leucine and ('14)C-leucine respectively. Analysis of the radioactivity incorporated into the (alpha) and (beta) subunits of luciferase indicates that both subunits are coordinately controlled and that the induction of luminescence is reflected by preferential de-novo synthesis of luciferase during the induction period. Analysis of the soluble protein indicates that five additional polypeptides are co-induced with luciferase and that one polypeptide appears to be repressed during the induction period. Analysis of the radioactivity incorporated into NAD(P)H:flavin oxidoreductase (the major NADH dependent FMN reductase and a supplier of FMNH(,2) for the luminescent reaction) in Beneckea harveyi indicates that its synthesis is constitutive. III. NAD(P)H:flavin oxidoreductase has been purified with the aid of affinity chromatography of (epsilon)-amino hexanoyl-FMN-Sepharose. The enzyme is composed of a single polypeptide chain of 24,000 daltons. Kinetic studies indicate that the higher specificity of the enzyme for NADH, riboflavin and FMN as opposed to NADPH and FAD is due primarily to variations in the Michaelis constants for the different substrates. Initial velocity studies with all pairs of substrates gave intersecting patterns supporting a sequential mechanism for the NAD(P)H:flavin oxidoreductase.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n866f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kh05f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207tp99s"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ethico-religious ideas of ʻUmar II</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Murād, Ḥasan Qāsim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This intellectual biography of 'Umar comprises detailed description and discussion of some aspects of his religious thought. These aspects, especially the spiritual-moral vision of 'Umar, which forms the very core of his thought--as has emerged particularly in the middle chapter--, are central and fundamental to any fresh, meaningful study not only of 'Umar's political thought--which seems to be firmly grounded in his religious thought--but also of his policies and activities as caliph and, more directly, of his political objectives and motives. Being a deeply religious man 'Umar sought primarily to ensure the safety of his soul. He strove to approximate to the letter and spirit of the personal and social teachings of the Prophet. The religious ideology as crystalized in the Qur'an and such other sources seems to have established both the outer limits and a great many inner details of his theoretical constructions.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765371859.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tp99s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religion, History of</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50gw814"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Surface jets and surface plumes in cross-flows</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abdelwahed, Mohamed Samir Tosson</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The subject of the thesis is concerned with the study of the turbulent spreading and the gravity spreading processes in surface jets and surface plumes influenced by the cross-flow. A total of five different discharge and cross-flow configurations were under investigation. They are, namely, (i) submerged jets in unconfined cross-flow, (ii) surface jets in deep and shallow cross-flows, (iii) surface plumes in deep cross-flow, (iv) full-depth jets in cross-flow and (v) full-depth plumes in cross-flow, reported in Chapters IV, V, VI, VII and VIII respectively. The effect of the gravity stratification, the effect of the free water surface and the confined effect of the channel bottom on the spreading of the turbulent flows have been determined from control experiments. The experimental data have been correlated in a unified manner, using suitable scales and dimensionless parameters. They are also related to a general integral formulation, established for this type of problems. The results of an extensive series of previous experimental investigations, of related problems of jets and plumes in cross-flow have been reanalysed and they are integrated into the various parts of the thesis to complement and confirm the present investigation. On the whole, the thesis has succeeded in providing a general description of the turbulent spreading and the gravity spreading processes in flows of different discharge and cross-flow configurations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bx80r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gw814</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Shear flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jets -- Fluid dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plumes (Fluid dynamics)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290b120"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The intellectual Odyssey of Henri Barbusse (1873-1935)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Weems, Constance Dulles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Neither a great man nor a great writer, Henri Barbusse aspired to greatness in the sincerity of his convictions, the ambition of his experiments, the constancy of his commitment. A youthful revolt against convention, the impact of the Dreyfus affair, the traumatic experience of trench warfare in the First World War left Barbusse a disillusioned pacifist and a social rebel. The inadequacies of the Allied peace settlement and the example of the successful revolution in Russia led him to espouse the Communist cause as the only movement adhering in deed as well as word to goals of social equity and peace. As critic of capitalist injustice and imperialist adventure, as a leader of the anti-Fascist movement, as theorist of proletarian literature, as experimental artist, he remained loyal to that cause for the rest of his life. An early prototype of the committed intellectual, Barbusse attempted to reconcile his aesthetic principles and moral values with the exigencies of political activism.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k55s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290b120</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Barbusse, Henri, 1873-1935 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88ch13m"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electrofiltration of hydrophobic colloids in fluidized bed bipolar electrodes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Seoud, Hicham F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new process was developed for the filtration of hydrophobic colloids without the assistance of chemical coagulants. The process consists of passing the suspension through a bed of electrically conducting granules which are fluidized by the upward flow of the suspension and simultaneously exposed to a D.C. electric field. The process was demonstrated on an aqueous polystyrene latex of mean particle size 0.34 (mu)m. At optimum conditions a bed of iron granules retained 98% of the entering particles. Experiments showed that the following variables increased the retention: increasing electric field strength, increasing static bed height, decreasing electrical conductivity of the feed, and decreasing the superficial velocity. Retention was independent of inlet particle concentration. A model of the process was formulated including various mechanisms of deposition and surface forces. It contained no empirical factors from filtration experiments except the mean particle size in the effluent when electric field is applied. Electrocoagulation of the polystyrene latex was observed under the microscope and the mechanisms involved were elucidated.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569519f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ch13m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrodes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Colloids</dc:subject><dc:subject>Separation (Technology)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924c37t"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comparative field and laboratory investigation of Typhlocoelum cucumerinum (Digenea: cyclocoelidae) in various duck and snail hosts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Scott, Marilyn Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An extensive field survey of 12 duck species yielded two morphologically distinct populations of Typhlocoelum (Digenea: Cyclocoelidae). Studies on the variability of these two populations in conjunction with experimental cross infections provided conclusive evidence that they must be considered as subspecies of Typhlocoelum cucumerinum. A laboratory comparison of their survival strategies revealed that, in the definitive host, Typhlocoelum cucumerinum cucumerinum develops slowly, survives for an extended time and has a high fecundity, whereas Typhlocoelum cucumerinum sisowi develops more quickly, has a shorter longevity and a lower fecundity. In the intermediate host, T. c. cucumerinum develops more slowly than T. c. sisowi. The almost complete segregation of these two subspecies into dabbling and diving ducks in the field may be maintained by an ecological separation of the ducks as well as intrinsic differences between the two host-parasite associations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x463g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c37t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gastropoda -- Parasites</dc:subject><dc:subject>Birds -- Parasites</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p781x"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Program in Communications</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modes of medical instruction : a semiotic comparison of textbooks of medicine and popular home medical books</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kahn, Joan Yess, 1935-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Following an initial observation that current North American books purporting to instruct their readers in the subject of medicine dislay broad variations both in their form as well as in their contents, an investigation was undertaken of eight such 'books of medical instruction': three textbooks of medicine and five popular home medical books. Based on a semiotic analysis of these two kinds of books of medical instruction (i.e. an analysis of their constituent linguistic and non-linguistic signs), textbooks were distinguished from popular books on the levels of both form and contents. With respect to form, textbook style was found to be formal and authoritative, hence high in accountability. Popular style on the other hand, was found to be informal and authoritarian, hence low in accountability. With respect to contents, the two groups of books were found to differ on two accounts: (a) their scope (i.e. the kinds and numbers of topics addressed), and (b) the manner in which each group characteristically portrayed homo medicabilis (defined as 'man as the object of a medical description').</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rv09w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p781x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Medicine -- Study and teaching</dc:subject><dc:subject>Medicine -- Textbooks</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859g330"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Class, contact, and location as factors in the spread of community development in India</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bandyopadhyay, Suraj</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This is a study of the causes of the failure of the Community Development Program in India. The method used is a sample survey of all family heads in twenty-one villages in a rice producing area in West Bengal, combined with extensive qualitative interviewing of informants, government officials, and other relevant personnel. The study shows that a principal cause of the failure of the program is the steep system of stratification--in terms of economic resources, prestige, and power--that characterizes rural society in this area and the high degree of village fragmentation resulting, in part, from the caste system. The conclusion of the study is that the Community Development Program will be unable to attain its ends until a substantial redistribution of economic and political resources is carried out and a sustained attack on the caste system is made.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kh06q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859g330</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Community development -- India</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82k7904"><ual:graduationDate>1970</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Ahmadīyah movement : its nature and its role in nineteenth and early twentieth century India</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lavan, Spencer</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d037c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k7904</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ahmadiyya</dc:subject><dc:subject>India -- Religion</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290b138"><ual:graduationDate>1970</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Catheptic enzymes of Bovine skeletal muscle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lutalo-Bosa, Albert James</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644s17g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290b138</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Muscles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Meat</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kr09w"><ual:graduationDate>1970</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Royal Institution for the Advancement of Learning : the correspondence, 1820-1829 : a historical and analytical study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boulianne, Réal G. (Réal Gérard)</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612p24c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr09w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Royal Institution for the Advancement of Learning -- History -- Sources</dc:subject><dc:subject>McGill University -- Archives</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education -- Canada -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>McGill University -- History -- Sources</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agm80hv964"><ual:graduationDate>1970</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sulfur analogues of B-diketones and their metal chelates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Siimann, Olavi</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h2581.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hv964</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ketones</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sulfur</dc:subject><dc:subject>Organometallic compounds</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abv73c110j"><ual:graduationDate>1969</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An ecological study of the cerrado vegetation of South-Central Brazil</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Goodland, Robert J. A., 1939-</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gw83p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c110j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant ecology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cerrado plants -- Brazil</dc:subject><dc:subject>Botany -- Brazil</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cerrados -- Brazil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386j880"><ual:graduationDate>1969</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Solution of unbounded field problems by boundary relaxation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cermak, Ivan Anthony</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gd574.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386j880</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Differential equations -- Numerical solutions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Boundary value problems</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924c39c"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vacuum refining in molten steel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harris, Ralph L.</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881m60s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c39c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Vacuum metallurgy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Steel -- Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amp48sd36b"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Plasma amino acids in epilepsy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aslam Janjua, Najma</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977v51n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sd36b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Amino acids -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Epilepsy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afq977v52x"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le miroir de mariage d'Eustache Deschamps : édition critique accompagnée d'une étude littéraire et linguistique</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dufournaud-Engel, Monique</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720d43v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977v52x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Deschamps, Eustache, 1346?-1406. Miroir de mariage</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301199d"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Extrapharmacological factors in marihuana intoxication</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stark-Adamec, Cannie</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xx961.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301199d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Marijuana -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1n79h507v"><ual:graduationDate>1975</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Internal migration and re-settlement of East Indians in Guyana, 1870-1920</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Potter, Lesley Marianne</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c111t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h507v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Land settlement -- Guyana</dc:subject><dc:subject>Migration, Internal -- Guyana</dc:subject><dc:subject>East Indians -- Guyana</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>