<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515q941"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of DNA methylation in common disease: analysis of two asthma-associated regions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al Tuwaijri, Abeer</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two chromosomal regions, 5q31 and 17q21, are both among the best replicated asthma-associated regions from genome-wide association studies (GWAS) and share certain characteristics.They are among the highest genome-wide significance allele-specific expression differences: in the 17q region, the childhood asthma-associated allele shows increased expression of gasdermin B (GSDMB) and ORMDL sphingolipid biosynthesis regulator 3 (ORMDL3) genes and in the 5q31 region the asthma-associated allele shows increased expression of the solute carrier family 22 (organic 3 cation/carnitine transporter) member 5 (SLC22A5) genes. This suggests that cis-regulatory mechanisms may influence disease development in these regions. Among children, the prevalence of asthma is higher in boys than girls, 5q31 and 17q21 regions show sex specificity of genetic association: the association with asthma is stronger in males than females, and both are associated with several autoimmune disorders such as asthma and Crohn’s disease, among different populations. We hypothesize that variation in DNA methylation at regulatory elements within asthma-associated genomic regions 5q31 and 17q21 may acts as a modifier of the effect of genotype on phenotype. To better understand the relationship between genetic variation in these regions, DNA methylation, and predisposition to asthma, we established DNA methylation profiles of 13 genes. We used sodium bisulfite sequencing methylation assay to examine the effects that genotype has on DNA methylation in the peripheral blood cells from individuals in the Saguenay-Lac-Saint-Jean (SLSJ) asthma familial collection and lymphoblastoid cell lines (LCLs). We found a single regulatory region, the zona pellucida binding protein 2 (ZPBP2) promoter, which showed a statistically significantly higher methylation level in females compared to males. The local genotype influenced methylation levels of SLC22A5, ZPBP2 and gasdermin A (GSDMA) promoter regions. The genotype had a dominant effect on SLC22A5, ZPBP2 and GSDMA methylation, with lower methylation levels in individuals that carry the asthma-predisposing alleles. To understand whether the moderate change in DNA methylation leads to a change in gene expression levels in 5q31 and 17q21, the effect of treatment with DNA methyltransferase inhibitor 5-aza-2'-deoxycytidine (5-aza-dC) on expression and promoter methylation of genes in 5q31 and 17q21 in the human airway epithelium cell line, NuLi-1 and embryonic kidney epithelium cell line, HEK293T/17 was assessed. We found that SLC22A5 and GSDMA were upregulated after 5-aza-dC treatment in both cell lines. ZPBP2 expression was increased in NuLi-1 but remained silent in HEK293T/17, while ORMDL3 showed upregulation in HEK293T/17 but not NuLi-1. Increased2expression of ZPBP2 and GSDMA was accompanied by a reduction in promoter methylation, whereas no change in SLC22A5 promoter methylation levels was observed. Furthermore, we noticed modification in allelic expression of ZPBP2 and ORMDL3, suggesting that each region may react in uniquely to 5-aza-dC.We hypothesized that sex-specific differences in DNA methylation levels at the ZPBP2 promoter resulted from the dosage of the sex chromosomes. Thus, ZPBP2 DNA methylation was analyzed using the sodium bisulfite sequencing assay in DNA samples from fibroblast cell lines derived from individuals with different sex phenotypes and sex chromosome dosages. No significant influence of the sex phenotype was detected. However, a significant positive correlation was found between ZPBP2 methylation levels and the number of X chromosomes. Our results suggest that the presence of more than one X in the absence of the sex-determining region Y (SRY) gene is associated with higher methylation levels.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Deux régions chromosomiques, 5q31 et 17q21, font partie des régions associées à l’asthme les mieux répliquées des études d’association pangénomique (GWAS) et partagent certaines caractéristiques. Ces régions ont les plus grandes différences significatives d’expression génique associée aux allèles au niveau du génome : dans la région 17q, l’allèle associé à l’asthme chez l’enfant montre une augmentation de l’expression des gènes gasdermin B (GSDMB) et «Régulateur de biosynthèse des sphingolipides ORMDL 3» (ORMDL3); alors que c’est le gène «famille de support de soluté 22 (transporteur de 3 cation / carnitine organique) membre 5» (SLC22A5) qui est augmenté dans la région 5q31. Ceci suggère que les mécanismes régulés en cis peuvent influencer le développement des maladies dans ces régions. Chez les enfants, la prévalence de l’asthme est plus élevée chez les garçons que chez les filles. Les régions 5q31 et 17q21 montrent une association génétique spécifique liée au sexe: l’association avec l’asthme est plus forte chez les males que chez les femelles, et les deux sont associés à de nombreux troubles auto-immunes, tels que l’asthme et la maladie de Crohn, dans les différentes populations. Nous posons l’hypothèse que la variation de la méthylation de l’ADN des éléments régulateurs dans les régions génomiques associées à l’asthme, 5q31 et 17q21, peut agir comme modificateur des effets du génotype sur le phénotype. Afin de mieux comprendre la relation entre la variation génétique de ces régions, la méthylation de l’ADN et la prédisposition à l’asthme, nous avons établi les profils de méthylation d’ADN de 13 gènes. Nous avons utilisé des essais de méthylation au bisulfite de sodium et de séquençage pour examiner les effets que le génotype a sur la méthylation de l’ADN dans les cellules du sang périphérique provenant d’individus de la collection familiale asthmatique du Saguenay-Lac-Saint-Jean (SLSJ) et les lignées de cellules lymphoblastoïdes (LCLs). Nous avons identifié une seule région régulatrice, le promoteur de «zona pellucida binding protein 2» (ZPBP2), lequel a montré un plus haut niveau statistiquement significatif de la méthylation chez les femelles comparativement aux males. Le génotype local a influencé les niveaux de méthylation des promoteurs de SLC22A5, ZPBP2 et gasdermin A (GSDMA). Le génotype avait un effet dominant sur la méthylation de SLC22A5, ZPBP2 et GSDMA, avec des niveaux de méthylation plus bas chez les individus porteurs des allèles de prédisposition à l’asthme. Pour comprendre comment le changement modéré dans la méthylation d’ADN mène à un changement dans les niveaux de l’expression des gènes dans les régions 5q31 et 17q21, nous avons examiné les effets d’un traitement à l’inhibiteur de la méthyltransférase de l’ADN 5-aza-2’-4déoxycitidine (5-aza-dC), lequel induit la déméthylation de l’ADN, sur l’expression et la méthylation des promoteurs des gènes situés aux chromosomes 5q31 et 17q21 dans les lignées de cellules humaines épithéliales des voies aériennes (NuLi-1) et du rein embryonnaire (HEK293T/17). Nous avons trouvé que SLC22A5 et GSDMA étaient régulés positivement suite à un traitement au 5-aza-dC dans les deux lignées cellulaires. L’expression de ZPBP2 était augmentée dans les cellules NuLi-1 mais restait silencieuse dans les cellules HEK293T/17, tandis qu’ORMDL3 montrait une régulation positive dans les HEK293T/17 mais pas dans les NuLi-1. Les expressions augmentées de ZPBP2 et de GSDMA étaient accompagnées par une diminution de la méthylation du promoteur, alors qu’aucun changement des niveaux de méthylation du promoteur de SLC22A5 n’a été observé. De plus, nous avons remarqué une modification dans l’expression allélique de ZPBP2 et ORMDL3, suggérant que chaque région peut réagir de façon unique au 5-aza-dC.Nous avons émis l’hypothèse que les différences liées au sexe dans les niveaux de méthylation de l’ADN du promoteur de ZPBP2 étaient dues au dosage des chromosomes sexuels.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anna Naoumova</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10ws88g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q941</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xx420"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cerebellar pathophysiology and its treatment in spinocerebellar ataxia type 6 mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jayabal, Sriram</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L’ataxie spinocérébelleuse de type 6 (SCA6) est une maladie neurodégénérative qui débute en milieu de vie.  Cette maladie est causée par l’expansion d’une séquence poly-Q répétée dans le gène CACNA1A qui code pour la sous-unité α1A ainsi que la terminaison C-terminal, α1ACT, du canal calcique à voltage-dépendant de type P/Q. Les individus affectés par SCA6 souffrent progressivement d’une déficience au niveau de leur coordination motrice menant à une anormalité de leur démarche. Des évaluations post-mortem chez des patients atteint d’SCA6 ont démontré une dégénérescence des cellules de Purkinje dans le cervelet. Malheureusement, la physiopathologie d’SCA6 demeure incomprise et il n’existe, à ce jour, aucun traitement. Grâce à un modèle de souris qui exprime une répétition 84-poly-Q dans le canal de type P/Q, j’ai pu explorer la physiopathologie sous-jacente à la maladie d’SCA6. En utilisant une multitude d’essais de comportement, j’ai pu démontrer que l’ataxie se manifeste rapidement entre 6 à 7 mois d’âge. La dégénérescence des cellules de Purkinje ne coïncide pas au moment où le déficit moteur est observé mais plus tardivement vers l’âge de 24 mois. Durant l’étude des propriétés neuronales, j’ai observé les cellules de Purkinje vers l’âge de 7 mois chez nos souris SCA6. Celles-ci démontraient une réduction dans le taux et la précision des influx nerveux. Lors de l’administration d’un bloqueur pour le canal potassium à voltage-dépendant, 4-aminopyridine (4-AP), une amélioration de la précision des potentiels d’action ainsi que des performances motrices fût observée. Les symptômes d’SCA6 se manifestent seulement en milieu de vie malgré le fait que la mutation génétique est présente dès la conception. Nos études ont démontré que lors du développement du cervelet chez les souris SCA6, les cellules de Purkinje présentaient des anomalies dès l’âge de 10 jours, tels qu’un taux élevé d’influx nerveux, ainsi qu’une innervation accrue des fibres grimpantes. Cependant, dès l’âge du sevrage, les anomalies retrouvées chez les souris SCA6 deviennent indiscernable de nos souris de type sauvage. Les résultats mentionnés dans cette thèse ont permis d’approfondir la compréhension de la physiopathologie d’SCA6 et de proposer une approche pharmacologique potentielle, 4-AP, afin de traiter cette maladie. Cette étude souligne également l’importance des changements développementaux chez les maladies neurodégénératives tardives. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Spinocerebellar ataxia type 6 (SCA6) is a late-onset neurodegenerative disease that is caused by a poly-Q repeat expansion in the CACNA1A gene that encodes the α1A subunit of the P/Q-type voltage-gated calcium channel (P/Q channel) and its C-terminus, α1ACT. Affected individuals experience progressive impairment of motor coordination resulting in gait abnormality, typically starting at midlife. Human post-mortem studies have shown that Purkinje cells degenerate in the SCA6 cerebellum. However, the pathophysiology giving rise to SCA6 is poorly understood and there is no treatment available. Using a mouse model that expresses an 84 polyQ repeat in the P/Q channel, I explored the pathophysiology underlying SCA6. First, using a barrage of behavioral assays, I found that ataxia manifests rapidly between 6 and 7 months of age. Second, Purkinje cells do not degenerate at a time when motor deficits are first seen but much later at 24 months old. Third, upon studying their firing properties, I found that 7-month-old SCA6 Purkinje cells show reduced firing rate and precision. When the voltage-gated potassium channel blocker, 4-aminopyridine (4-AP), is administered to SCA6 mice, it improved the firing precision of Purkinje cells and improved motor function. Fourth, to understand why SCA6 manifests at mid-life despite harboring mutated gene since conception, I studied the development of SCA6 cerebellum. I found that the SCA6 brain developed abnormally as Purkinje cell firing rate and precision were enhanced in 10-day-old SCA6 mice, and SCA6 Purkinje cells received innervation from surplus climbing fibers. However, at weanling age, SCA6 Purkinje cell firing properties and climbing fiber innervation is indistinguishable from WT mice. The results reported in this thesis extends the understanding of the pathophysiology of SCA6 and proposes a potential pharmacological treatment strategy with 4-AP. This study also highlights the potential importance of developmental changes in late-onset neurodegenerative diseases.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alanna Watt</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pq46v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xx420</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gw14v"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nuclear exclusion of AID limits off target activity by enforcing productive targeting</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Methot, Stephen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Activation induced deaminase (AID) is an enzyme that deaminates deoxycitidine to deoxyuridine on single stranded DNA. AID expression is mostly restricted to antigen activated B-lymphocytes, wherein its activity is critical for both somatic hypermutation (SHM) and class-switch recombination (CSR), which underpin secondary antibody diversification. This is due to the targeted activity of AID at the immunoglobulin (Ig) genes, which encode for the antibody genes. DNA deamination catalyzed by AID initiates the generation of single point mutations for SHM, and double stranded breaks for CSR, both potentially harmful lesions. Importantly, multiple mechanisms regulate AID in order to limit its off-target activity, outside the Ig loci, which has been found to be potentially oncogenic and cytotoxic. For my thesis, I used structure-function studies of AID in order to better understand post-translational regulation of its activity.In a first chapter, evolutionary comparison and structure-function analyses revealed that a structural conformation of a C-terminal domain of AID was required for its association to eEF1A1, which mediated the retention of AID in the cytoplasm. Mutations that disrupted AID cytoplasmic retention, or pharmacological inhibition of eEF1A1, caused AID to accumulate in the nucleus and to generate more mutations on- and off- target. This demonstrated that eEF1A1-dependent retention of AID in the cytoplasm was necessary to restrict its activity.In a second chapter, a structure-function study of AID identified a domain dispensable for its catalytic activity, but critical for SHM and CSR activity in B cells. Mutants of this domain were able to functionally distinguish the recruitment of AID to the chromatin from its mutagenic activity in B cells. This revealed that at the chromatin AID requires a licensing step in order to associate with the elongating transcription machinery, and become mutagenic. Interestingly, this licensing is bypassed when AID is forced to accumulate in the nucleus.In a third chapter, studies of the C-terminal region of AID further clarified its role during CSR. This study identified a structural requirement of the C-terminus during CSR, downstream from DNA deamination. This study supports a role for AID, via the C-terminus, to recruit other factors during CSR, likely to mediate proper DNA repair.All together, these studies highlight the intricate regulation of AID activity in B cells.  They also suggest that preventing accumulation of AID in the nucleus limits off-target activity by enforcing a regulatory licensing step at the chromatin.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Désaminase induite par l’activation (AID) est une enzyme qui désamine le désoxycytidine au désoxyuridine sur l’ADN simple brin. Après avoir reconnu spécifiquement des antigènes, les lymphocytes B vont exprimer AID pour mettre en place l’hypermutation somatique (SHM) et la commutation de classe (CSR), deux mécanismes essentiels pour la diversification des anticorps. L’activité d’AID est alors restreinte aux régions des immunoglobulines (Ig) du génome, qui codent pour les gênes d’anticorps. La désamination par AID initie la génération de mutations simples pour le SHM, et des cassures d’ADN double brins pour le CSR, les deux comprenant des lésions potentiellement néfastes. Plusieurs mécanismes régulent AID avant et après sa transcription afin de limiter son activité en dehors des régions Ig, qui peut être potentiellement oncogénique et cytotoxique. Pendant ma thèse, j’ai effectué des études sur la relation structure-fonction d’AID pour mieux comprendre la régulation de son activité au niveau protéique.Dans un premier chapitre, une comparaison évolutionnaire et une analyse de structure-fonction révèlent que la conformation structurale de la région C-terminal d’AID est essentielle à sa rétention au cytoplasme, ainsi que son association avec la protéine eEF1A1. Des mutations simples qui empêchent la rétention cytoplasmique d’AID ou des inhibiteurs de eEF1A1, entrainent l’accumulation d’AID dans le noyau et augmentent sa capacité à générer des mutations ciblées et non-ciblées. Ceci démontre ainsi que la rétention cytoplasmique d’AID, dépendant de la protéine eEF1A1, est nécessaire pour restreindre son activité mutagènique.Dans un deuxième chapitre, une analyse de structure-fonction d’AID a révélé qu’une de ces régions n’est pas nécessaire pour son activité catalytique, mais est critique pour induire le SHM et le CSR dans les cellules B. Des mutants de cette région d’AID sont toujours recrutés à la chromatine mais n’exercent plus d’activité  mutagènique. Cela démontre qu’au niveau de la chromatine, AID a besoin d’une étape supplémentaire pour initier son activité mutagènique aux sites du génome qui y sont spécifiquement sensibles. De plus, cette étape d’activation peut être contournée si AID s’accumule dans le noyau.Dans un troisième chapitre, l’étude de la région C-terminal d’AID a permis également de clarifier son rôle pendant le CSR. En effet, la région C-terminal d’AID joue un rôle primordial dans son activité mutagènique lors du CSR, via le recrutement de facteurs, qui sont probablement impliqués dans la réparation de l’ADN.L’ensemble de ces études confirme la régulation complexe de l’activité d’AID dans les cellules B en particulier au niveau de la chromatine et souligne l’importance d’empêcher son accumulation dans le noyau pour limiter son activité mutagénique non-ciblée.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Javier Di Noia</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580q150.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gw14v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25xc02x"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of inhaled nebulized furosemide on breathlessness during exercise in the setting of abnormal restrictive constraints on tidal colume expansion: a randomized, double blind, placebo contolled, crossover, dose-response study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Waskiw-Ford, Marcus</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction: The worldwide prevalence of physical activity-related breathlessness among adults aged 40 years and older is ~27%, with this value expected to rise into the future as our population continues to age. In adults with advanced disease across a range of both malignant and non-malignant diagnoses (e.g., chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, interstitial lung disease, cancer), physical activity-related breathlessness is the hallmark symptom as well as an independent predictor of adverse health outcomes, including exercise intolerance, hospitalization and death. Many of these patients suffer from chronic breathlessness syndrome: breathlessness that persists despite optimal treatment of the underlying pathophysiology and that results in disability. It follows that alleviating breathlessness is amongst the primary goals in the medical management of these individuals. However, there is currently no formal pharmacotherapeutic strategy to manage chronic breathlessness syndrome.  Experimental and clinical research suggests that inhalation of the diuretic furosemide can alleviate breathlessness provoked experimentally in health and disease. However, these findings are inconsistent. We reasoned that if inhaled nebulized furosemide relieves breathlessness by mimicking greater VT expansion via altered vagal afferent feedback activity from pulmonary stretch receptors, perhaps it would best accomplish this under conditions of abnormal restrictive constraints on VT expansion in healthy adults.Objective and hypothesis: The primary objective of this study was to examine the acute effect of inhaled nebulized furosemide at doses of 40 mg and 120 mg on ratings of perceived breathlessness during cycle endurance exercise testing in the setting of abnormal restrictive constraints on VT expansion. We hypothesized that single-dose inhalation of nebulized furosemide would be associated with dose-dependent relief of exertional breathlessness compared with nebulized 0.9% saline.Methods: Twenty-four healthy men inhaled nebulized furosemide (40 mg and 120 mg) and nebulized 0.9% saline (placebo) in a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover study. Following inhalation, participants completed a symptom-limited constant-load cycle endurance exercise test at 80% of their peak incremental power output in the setting of external thoracic restriction via chest wall strapping to reduce slow vital capacity by ~20%. Detailed assessments of breathlessness, ventilation, breathing pattern, the behaviour of dynamic operating lung volumes, and cardiometabolic function were performed at rest and during exercise. Diuresis was assessed via post-dose quantification of urine production rate. Results: Compared with nebulized 0.9% saline, neither 40 mg nor 120 mg of inhaled nebulized furosemide had a statistically significant effect on Borg 0-10 scale intensity and unpleasantness ratings of breathlessness during exercise. Similarly, neither dose of inhaled nebulized furosemide had an effect on cardiometabolic, ventilatory, breathing pattern and dynamic operating lung volume responses to exercise compared with placebo. Compared with placebo, a significant effect of 120 mg, but not 40 mg, of nebulized furosemide on urine production rate was observed. No other side effects were reported. Conclusion: Under the experimental conditions of this study, inhalation of nebulized furosemide at doses of 40 mg and 120 mg did not alleviate the perception of breathlessness during exercise in healthy men. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introduction : La prévalence mondiale de l'essoufflement lié à l'activité physique chez les adultes âgés de 40 ans et plus est de ~ 27 %, avec cette valeur attendue pour s'élever dans l'avenir que notre population continue à vieillir. Chez les adultes atteints d'une maladie avancée dans une gamme de diagnostics malins et non malins (p. ex., la maladie pulmonaire obstructive chronique, la maladie pulmonaire interstitielle, le cancer), l'essoufflement lié à l'activité physique est le symptôme distinctif ainsi qu'un prédicteur indépendant des effets néfastes sur la santé, y compris l'intolérance à l'exercice, l'hospitalisation et la mort. Beaucoup de ces patients souffrent de syndrome de dyspnée chronique : essoufflement qui persiste malgré le traitement optimal de la physiopathologie sous-jacente et qui se traduit par un handicap. Il s'ensuit que la réduction de l'essoufflement est parmi les principaux objectifs de la gestion médicale de ces individus. Cependant, il n'existe actuellement aucune stratégie formelle de pharmacothérapeutique pour gérer le syndrome de l'essoufflement chronique.Des recherches expérimentales et cliniques suggèrent que l'inhalation du furosémide diurétique peut atténuer l'essoufflement provoqué expérimentalement dans la santé et la maladie. Toutefois, ces résultats sont incohérents. Nous avons raisonné que si le furosémide nébulisé inhalé soulage l'essoufflement en imitant une plus grande expansion de VT par l'activité altérée de rétroaction afférente des récepteurs de l'étirement pulmonaire, peut-être qu'il serait mieux d'accomplir ce dans des conditions de contraintes restrictives anormales sur l'expansion du VT chez les adultes en bonne santé.Objectif et hypothèse : L'objectif principal de cette étude était d'examiner l'effet aigu du furosémide nébulisé inhalé à des doses de 40 mg et de 120 mg sur les classements de l'essoufflement perçu pendant l'essai d'endurance de cycle dans le cadre de contraintes restrictives anormales sur l'expansion du VT. Nous avons émis l'hypothèse que l'inhalation d'une dose unique de furosémide nébulisé serait associée à un soulagement dose-dépendante de l'essoufflement de l'effort par rapport à la solution de 0,9 % salin nébulisée.Méthodes : Vingt-quatre hommes sains ont inhalé furosémide (40 mg et 120 mg) et 0,9 % salin nébulisé (placebo) dans une étude randomisée, à double insu, contrôlée par placebo et croisée. À la suite de l'inhalation, les participants ont effectué un essai d'endurance à cycle constant à charge limitée par symptôme à 80 % de leur puissance incrémentale maximum dans le cadre de la restriction thoracique externe par l'intermédiaire du cerclage de la paroi thoracique pour réduire la capacité vitale lente de ~ 20 %. Des évaluations détaillées de l'essoufflement, de la ventilation, de la respiration, du comportement des volumes de poumon d'exploitation dynamique et de la fonction cardiométabolique ont été effectuées au repos et pendant l'exercice. La diurèse a été évaluée par quantification du taux de production d'urine après la dose.Résultats : Comparativement à salins 0,9 % nébulisés, ni 40 mg ni 120 mg de furosémide nébulisé inhalé ont eu un effet statistiquement significatif sur l'intensité de l'échelle de Borg 0-10 et les cotes de désagrément de l'essoufflement pendant l'exercice. De même, aucune dose de furosémide nébulisé inhalée n'a eu d'effet sur la cardiométabolique, la respiration, le modèle respiratoire et les réponses dynamiques du volume pulmonaire à l'exercice par rapport au placebo. Comparativement au placebo, on a observé un effet significatif de 120 mg, mais non de 40 mg, du furosémide nébulisé sur le taux de production d'urine. Aucun autre effet secondaire n'a été rapporté.Conclusion : Dans les conditions expérimentales de cette étude, l'inhalation de furosémide nébulisé à des doses de 40 mg et de 120 mg n'a pas atténué la perception de l'essoufflement pendant l'exercice chez les hommes sains.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dennis Jensen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60d007w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xc02x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8s45qc278"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigation into the sensations of muscle pain and fatigue induced by selective and physiological activation of metabosensitive and mechanosensitive muscle afferent fibers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hoeppli, Marie-Eve</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the project that is the core of this thesis, psychophysical responses and cerebral representations of muscle pain and fatigue are investigated in young and elderly healthy participants. Although muscle pain and fatigue are major health issues, in particular in elderly individuals, underlying mechanisms of these issues are still unclear. This project includes four experiments, which were performed over the course of three sessions. The first experiment focused on developing and validating a two-dimension (2D) scale for simultaneous ratings of muscle pain and fatigue. Results of this experiment, which are reported in chapter 3, show that participants can accurately rate two dimensions simultaneously on a scale. Furthermore, no effect of age on the ability to rate on a 2D scale was highlighted. These results suggest that the use of this scale is appropriate for participants to rate fatigue and pain sensations in the three other experiments of this project.In the second experiment, the effect of age on muscle pain and fatigue sensations induced by selective activation of metabosensitive and mechanosensitive muscle afferent fibers was analyzed. Metabosensitive muscle afferent fibers from group III and IV, which signal muscle pain and fatigue, were activated by infusions of mixes of endogenous agonists of purinergic receptor (P2X), transient receptor potential vanilloid type 1 (TRPV1), and acid-sensing ion channel (ASIC), aka adenosine triphosphate (ATP), lactate, and protons. Mechanosensitive muscle afferent fibers were activated by passive movement of the previously infused muscle. As detailed in chapter 4, results show that age decreases muscle pain and fatigue sensations, but does not impact on the effect of the activation of mechanosensitive muscle afferent fibers after infusions of mixes of metabolites on these sensations. The third experiment, described in chapter 5, analyzed the reproducibility of muscle pain and fatigue sensations. Results show moderate correlations of the time courses of muscle pain and fatigue ratings between two sessions, suggesting similar experience of muscle pain and fatigue in both sessions. Further analyses reported no effect of age on the reproducibility of muscle pain and fatigue sensations.In the fourth experiment, cerebral representations of muscle pain and fatigue induced by selective and physiological activation of metabosensitive and mechanosensitive muscle afferent fibers were analyzed. Although analyses, reported in chapter 6, were unsuccessful in highlighting activations associated with muscle pain and fatigue, results suggest that stimulation of metabosensitive and mechanosensitive muscle afferent fibers inducing muscle pain and fatigue is associated with low-frequency fluctuations in brain activation. The results of this project not only contribute to the current knowledge of muscle pain and fatigue. They also introduce a new technique to measure two dimensions simultaneously and continuously, opening new opportunities in the investigation of complex stimuli, such as muscle pain and fatigue, and potentially increasing our knowledge on interactions between these stimuli and their dimensions.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le projet présenté dans cette thèse s’intéresse aux réponses psychophysiques et aux représentations cérébrales de la douleur et la fatigue musculaires parmi des populations jeunes et âgées. Bien que la douleur et la fatigue musculaires représentent des problèmes de santé fréquents, en particulier parmi les personnes âgées, leurs mécanismes sous-jacents sont encore peu clairs. Ce projet inclut quatre expériences réalisées au cours de trois sessions de tests. Dans la première expérience, une échelle à deux dimensions (2D) est développée et validée. Les résultats de cette expérience, reportés dans le chapitre 3, montrent que les participants évaluent simultanément deux dimensions d’un même stimulus sur une échelle 2D de façon précise. De plus, il n’y a pas d’effet d’âge sur la précision des évaluations. Ces résultats suggèrent que l’utilisation de cette échelle 2D est appropriée pour les évaluations de douleur et fatigue musculaires collectées dans les trois expériences ultérieures.La seconde expérience se concentre sur l’effet de l’âge sur la douleur et la fatigue musculaires, induites par l’activation sélective et physiologique des fibres afférentes musculaires métabosensibles et mécanosensibles des groupes III et IV. Les fibres métabosensibles, signalant la douleur et la fatigue musculaires, étaient activées par injection de solutions d’agonistes endogènes des récepteurs purinergiques (P2X), des récepteurs transitoires à potentiel vanilloïde de type 1 (TRPV1), et des canaux à ions acide-sensibles (ASIC), c-à-d adénosine triphosphate (ATP), lactate et protons. Les fibres mécanosensibles étaient activées par un mouvement passif du muscle ayant auparavant reçu une injection. Les résultats de cette expérience, détaillés dans le chapitre 4, montrent que l’âge affecte négativement les sensations de douleur et fatigue musculaires, mais n’affecte pas l’effet de l’activation des fibres mécanosensibles après des injections de métabolites sur les sensations de fatigue et douleur musculaires.La troisième expérience, décrite dans le chapitre 5, analyse la répétabilité des sensations de douleur et fatigue musculaires entre deux sessions. Les résultats de ces analyses mettent en évidence des corrélations modérées entre les changements de sensations de douleur et fatigue musculaires au cours du temps. Ces résultats suggèrent une expérience similaire de douleur et fatigue musculaire entre les deux sessions. Ces analyses ne reportent pas d’effet d’âge sur la répétabilité des sensations de douleur et fatigue musculaires.Dans la quatrième expérience, les représentations cérébrales de la douleur et la fatigue musculaires, induites par l’activation sélective des fibres métabosensibles et mécanosensibles sont investiguées. Les analyses exécutées dans le chapitre 6 ne mettent pas en évidence les activations cérébrales associées avec la fatigue et la douleur musculaires de façon incontestable. Cependant, les résultats de ces analyses suggèrent que la stimulation sélective et physiologique des fibres métabosensibles et mécanosensibles, provoquant des sensations de fatigue et douleurs musculaires, pourrait être associée avec des fluctuations de basse fréquence dans l’activation cérébrale.D’une part, les résultats de ce projet ajoutent aux connaissances actuelles sur la fatigue et la douleur musculaires. D’autre part, ils présentent une nouvelle méthode pour mesurer deux dimensions simultanément et de façon continue, créant de nouvelles opportunités pour l’investigation de stimuli complexes, tels que la fatigue et la douleur. De plus, cette nouvelle méthode de mesure pourrait fournir des informations importantes pour notre compréhension des interactions entre ces stimuli et leurs dimensions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Petra Schweinhardt</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw16b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qc278</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An870zt053"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on modified C- and G-rich oligonucleotides - towards investigating the role of i-motif structures in telomere biology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abou Assi, Hala</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis focuses primarily on studying DNA sequences with tandem G-rich and C-rich repeats that fold into G-quadruplex (G4) and i-motif structures, respectively. While G4 structures likely play a role in transcriptional regulation and telomere maintenance, much less is known about the role of i-motif structures in biological processes, especially in telomere biology. Our ability to chemically synthesize and stabilize both of these structures provides an opportunity to correlate structural and functional information of transient arrangements of G4 and i-motifs under physiological conditions. In this work, we show that replacing 2'-deoxycytidine (dC) with 2'-deoxy-2'-fluoro-arabinocytidine (2'F-araC) leads to significant stabilization of i-motifs over a wide pH range, including pH 7.0. This finding is significant because, with a few exceptions, i-motif structures unfold at pH greater than 6, making it difficult to evaluate these structures under physiological conditions. NMR experiments revealed that the stabilization provided by the 2'F-araC residues likely results from favorable electrostatic interactions that occur in the major groove of the modified C-quadruplex.  Next, we sought to determine the impact of combining the two most stabilizing sugar (2'F-araC) and nucleobase (5-methylcytidine, 5-Me-dC) modifications on the structure and stability of i-motifs. In this context, we synthesized a novel nucleoside analogue, namely 2'-deoxy-2'-fluoro-5-methyl-arabinocytidine (5-Me-2'F-araC), and incorporated it into the C-rich telomeric sequence. We found that 5-Me-2'F-araC was very well tolerated and led to structural stabilization at physiological pH similar to 2'F-araC. We also investigated the effect of combining several cytidine modifications within the same i-motif structure and determined that 5-Me-dC/2'F-araC base pairing leads to the highest thermal stability at physiological pH.These findings paved the way to investigations concerning the possible role of telomeric i-motif structures. First, we prepared 2'F-araG modified G4 structures, which like the modified i-motifs, exhibited greater thermal stability relative to the unmodified structures. Furthermore, they were readily elongated by the enzyme telomerase in direct telomerase activity assays.  Additionally, 2'F-araG and 2'F-araC substitutions allowed for the simultaneous formation of stable G4 and i-motif structures, respectively, at neutral pH. Remarkably, despite their close proximity, they remained as “trapped” G4 and i-motif structures for several weeks without associating into a duplex. Preliminary in vitro assays suggested that 2'F-araC modified sequences can inhibit telomerase activity. Thus, our work shines a new light on the telomeric i-motif structure, and possibly function, and provides probes for use in the discovery of small molecule ligands and proteins that bind these structures under physiological conditions.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse s’articule principalement autour de l’étude de séquences d’ADN contenant des répétitions de bases guanine et cytosine en tandem conduisant respectivement à la formation de structures en G-quadruplex (G4) et en motif-i. Les structures en G4 sont probablement impliquées dans la régulation de la transcription du message génétique et dans la maintenance des télomères. En revanche, le rôle biologique des structures en motif-i est beaucoup moins clair, et ce en particulier dans la biologie des télomères. La synthèse chimique ainsi que notre capacité à stabiliser à la fois G4 et motif-i offre la possibilité d’établir un lien entre structure et fonction au sein de ces formations transitoires en milieu physiologique. Dans cet ouvrage, nous montrons que le remplacement d’un nucléoside 2'-déoxycytidine (dC) par un analogue 2'-déoxy-2'-fluoro-arabinocytidine (2'F-araC) conduit à une forte stabilisation de motifs-i sur une large plage de pH et notamment à pH neutre. La stabilisation de motifs-i à pH neutre est une avancée importante car, en dehors de quelques cas particuliers, ceux-ci se désassemblent au-delà d’un pH 6, ce qui limite drastiquement leur étude en conditions physiologiques. Des expériences menées par RMN ont permis d’attribuer l’origine de cette stabilisation à la présence d’interactions électrostatiques favorables provoquées par les nucléosides 2'F-araC et se manifestant au sein du grand sillon des motifs-i.Ensuite, nous nous sommes intéressés à la combinaison d’analogues de nucléoside avec sucre modifié (2'F-araC) et base modifiée (5-méthylcytidine, 5-Me-dC), tous les deux stabilisateurs de motifs-i et avons souhaité déterminer l’impact de cette combinaison sur leur structure et leur stabilité. Pour ce faire, nous avons synthétisé un nouvel analogue de nucléoside, la 2'-déoxy-2'-fluoro-5-méthyl-arabinocytidine (5-Me-2'F-araC) et l’avons incorporé dans la séquence télomérique riche en cytosines, laquelle s’est retrouvée stabilisée à pH physiologique ; un effet similaire à l’incorporation de la 2'F-araC. En outre, nous avons étudié l’effet induit par la présence de multiples combinaisons de cytidine modifiées et en avons conclu que l’appariement de la 5-Me-dC et de la 2'F-araC s’accompagne d’une forte augmentation de la stabilité thermique à pH physiologique.Ces découvertes ont posé les fondations permettant l’étude du possible rôle biologique des structures télomériques en motif-i. Ainsi, ont été préparées des structures G4 modifiées avec des nucléosides 2'F-araG, lesquelles se sont révélées être plus stables que les G4 non modifiés. Ces structures sont des substrats de l’enzyme télomérase et leur élongation se produit naturellement lors d’un test d’activité enzymatique. Par ailleurs, la présence de substitutions 2'F-araG et 2'F-araC respectivement dans des G4 et motifs-i permet de former, simultanément, des G4 et motifs-i stables à pH neutre. Il est important de noter que ces structures se maintiennent pendant plusieurs semaines sans se réassocier en duplex, et ce malgré leur proximité. Enfin, des expériences menées in vitro sur des séquences modifiées avec 2'F-araC pointent vers leur action inhibitrice de la télomérase. En conclusion, le travail de cette thèse porte un regard nouveau sur la structure et peut-être aussi la fonction de la séquence télomérique en motif-i. Ce travail a, de plus, permis de concevoir des sondes utiles en milieu physiologique pour la découverte de petites molécules ou de protéines agissant comme ligands de ces structures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Masad J. Damha</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720g40f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zt053</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52jb417"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The phenomenon of receptive field remapping and its neural mechanism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Neupane, Sujaya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Eye movements cause displacement and smearing of images on the retina. Yet, we experience a stable and seamless visual sensation as if eye movements never occurred. This is because the brain has a mechanism for compensating for self-generated movements. This thesis is a compiled series of findings obtained by investigating such a compensatory mechanism of mammalian brain in the context of saccadic eye movements. The doctoral work specifically focuses on a neural phenomenon called receptive field remapping. Remapping refers to a property of certain visual neurons that can predictively respond to visual stimuli outside their classical response field whenever there is an impending eye movement. Chapter 1 provides a literature review of receptive field remapping. The chapter ends with an outline of the objectives of this doctoral work which are to characterize the phenomenon of receptive field remapping to reconcile apparent discontinuity in the literature and to investigate the mechanism of remapping. Chapter 2 contains the results from the first study undertaken during the PhD work. It shows that there are two types of remapping in primate cortical area V4 and provides a ground to reconcile recently published incompatible findings on the phenomenon of remapping. Chapter 3 provides further evidence for dissociating the two types of remapping obtained by carefully choosing a saccade vector based on the receptive field location of the neurons under study. Chapter 4 contains the results from a study undertaken during this PhD work to understand the neural mechanism of remapping. Using simultaneous recording from multiple neurons, this work shows the role of coherent oscillations in remapping thus providing evidence for a dynamic mechanism of activity transfer during saccades. Overall, the results presented in this thesis helps reconcile recently surfaced apparent controversy on the phenomenon of remapping and provides evidence for communication through coherence as a putative neural mechanism of remapping. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les mouvements de l'oeil provoquent le déplacement et l’obscurcissement des images sur la rétine. Pourtant, nous avons la sensation visuelle stable comme si les mouvements des yeux n'ont jamais eu lieu. C’est parce que le cerveau emploie un mécanisme pour compenser les mouvements auto-générés. Cette thèse consiste d’une série de résultats obtenus sur le mécanisme compensatoire du cerveau mammalien dans le contexte des mouvements saccadiques des yeux. Le travail de doctorat se concentre spécifiquement sur un phénomène neuronal appelé ‘receptive field remapping’.Remapping réfère à une propriété de certains neurones visuels qui peuvent répondre de manière prédictive à des stimuli visuels  à l’extérieur de leur champ de réponse classique à chaque fois qu'il y a un mouvement imminent des yeux. Le chapitre 1 présente une revue de la littérature sur receptive field remapping. Le chapitre se termine avec une liste des objectifs de la thèse, consistant de caractériser le phénomène de receptive field remapping, de concilier la discontinuité apparente dans la littérature et d’étudier le mécanisme de remapping.Le chapitre 2 contient les résultats de la première étude réalisée au cours du travail de doctorat. Il montre qu'il existe deux types de remapping dans la zone corticale V4 du primate et fournit une plateforme permettant de réconcilier les résultats incompatibles récemment publiés sur le phénomène de remapping. Le chapitre 3 fournit des preuves supplémentaires pour dissocier les deux types de remapping obtenus en choisissant soigneusement un vecteur saccade basé sur l'emplacement du receptive field des neurones étudiés.Le chapitre 4 présente les résultats d'une étude réalisée au cours de ce travail de doctorat pour comprendre le mécanisme neuronal de remapping. En utilisant l'enregistrement simultané de plusieurs neurones, ce travail montre le rôle des oscillations cohérentes dans le processus de  remapping, ce qui fournit des preuves d'un mécanisme dynamique de transfert d'activité lors des saccades.Dans l'ensemble, les résultats présentés dans cette thèse permettent de réconcilier une controverse apparente qui a récemment survenu sur le phénomène de remapping et fournissent des preuves sur la communication par cohérence en tant que mécanisme neuronal putatif de remapping.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daniel E. Guitton</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Christopher Pack</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967619f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jb417</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad217qs018"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An examination of validity threats in preclinical research: systematic review of three cancer drugs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Demko, Nadine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L’application clinique des résultats pré-cliniques est une démarche coûteuse et de longue haleine accablée par de forts taux d’attrition. Puisque le développement clinique est essentiellement justifié par des études pré-cliniques chez les animaux, la problématique d’attrition est d’avantage liée aux lacunes méthodologiques dans la réalisation de ces études. Les travaux de recherche sur le cancer font face à des enjeux distincts de généralisation des modèles animaux et du profil toxicologique des substances cliniques à l’essai. Cette thèse se fonde sur une revue systématique et une méta-analyse des methodes et des résultats d’essais pré-cliniques d’une cohorte de médicaments (un approuvé pour traitement oncologique et deux autres sans licence en oncologie). Globalement, les expériences menées pour l’ensemble des médicaments privilégient, sur un plan statistique, un traitement dans 75% des cas mais les relations dose-réponse de ces médicaments ne sont pas précisées. Nous avons également constaté que les pratiques expérimentales de la recherche pré-clinique ne répondent pas adéquatement à tous les risques encourus pour fonder une déduction clinique valable présentée par les variations aléatoires, la subjectivité, et la non-publication. Nous avons observé que les mesures visant à réduire ces risques n’ont pas été prises. Nous concluons en faisant des suggestions afin d’améliorer le déroulement et l’élaboration de rapports des études pré-cliniques en cancer et à encourager les décideurs clés comme les chercheurs scientifiques et les examinateurs à suivre une politique fondée sur des preuves.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Clinical translation is an onerous and time-consuming process that is burdened by high attrition rates. Since clinical development is largely justified by studies of preclinical efficacy in animals, the attrition problem is increasingly being linked to methodological flaws in the conduct of these studies. Cancer studies face distinct issues regarding generalizability of animal models and drug toxicity profiles. This thesis uses a systematic review and meta-analysis of the designs and outcomes of preclinical trials for a cohort of one licensed and two unlicensed agents in oncology. Overall, experiments across all drugs statistically favoured the treatment 75% of the time and dose-response relationships were not elucidated in any of the drugs. We also found that experimental practices in preclinical research do not appropriately address threats to valid clinical inference presented by random variation, bias, and non-publication. We found that measures to reduce these threats were not taken in either licensed or unlicensed groups. We conclude by making suggestions for improving the conduct and reporting of preclinical cancer studies and encourage key decision makers, such as researchers and reviewers, to follow an evidence-based policy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jonathan Kimmelman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz8062499.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qs018</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b8557"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Tip enhanced Raman spectroscopy and cantilever sensors for studying Li-ion battery materials</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aiken, Connor</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Current battery technologies must be improved if they are to be used as the energy storage solution that enables the transition to renewable global energy production. The study of batteries, in particular, lithium ion batteries, requires new or previously unutilized techniques that can provide fundamental understanding of the phenomena that affect performance. Among these phenomena, a solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) develops on the surface of the battery electrodes that can result in reduced energy storage capacity and power delivery, and increased degradation. Understanding the SEI requires a dynamic understanding of its chemistry and structure, and how those affect battery performance.Combined tip-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (TERS) and atomic force microscopy (AFM), as well as cantilever sensing were investigated as new measurement techniques for the study of the solid electrolyte interphase formation in lithium ion batteries. Confocal Raman microscopy on LiFePO4 and partially delithiated LixFePO4 was able to reproduce literature results and detect spatial variation on the delithiated sample with 0.5 um resolution. The presence of two distinct phases were observed, with spectra suggesting that the phases possibly contained different lithium concentrations. Despite success with confocal Raman microscopy experiments, advancement to TERS experiments did not prove successful. The gold tips required for field enhancement cannot currently be fabricated and utilized for AFM while still providing reliable excitation of a localized surface plasmon resonance and reliable Raman scattering.Cantilever sensors were designed to mimic a commercial battery electrode; that is a battery electrode cantilever. The design implemented a mica substrate, a metal thin film current collector and an active material layer. An electrochemical chamber was designed, with optical access to enable combined electrochemical-surface stress measurements on the battery electrode cantilevers. The chamber was made air-tight to enable use of air-sensitive battery materials for future tests. Tests in aqueous electrolytes showed that reaction and/or delamination of the metallic current collector layer compromised the conductivity of the cantilevers before lithium could be removed from the active materials.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La transition vers une production globale d’énergie par des sources renouvelables, plutôt que par la combustion de matières fossiles, est nécessaire pour prévenir des dommages irréparables l’environnement. La production d’énergie à partir de sources renouvelables nécessite un système de stockage d’énergie pour pallier aux intermittences de service. Les technologies de batterie actuelles doivent toutefois être améliorées si elles veulent devenir cette solution de stockage d’énergie qui permet la transition vers une production globale d’énergie renouvelable. Les recherches sur les batteries, en particulier sur les batteries lithium-ion, nécessitent de nouvelles techniques de mesures pour fournir une compréhension fondamentale des phénomènes qui affectent leur performance.La combinaison de la spectroscopie Raman exaltée par effet de pointe (TERS) et la microscopie à force atomique (MFA), ainsi que la détection par cantilever ont été utilisées comme techniques de mesure pour l’étude de l’interphase solide électrolyte formée dans les batteries lithium-ion. La microscopie Raman confocale sur du LiFePO4 et du partiellement délithié LixFePO4 a permis de reproduire des résultats de la littérature et de détecter une variation spatiale sur l’échantillon délithié avec une résolution de 0.5 um. La présence de deux phases distinctes a été observée, avec des spectres suggérant que ces phases contiennent des concentrations différentes de lithium. Malgré le succès des expériences de microscopie Raman confocale, nos expériences de TERS ne sont pas avérées aussi fructueuses. Les pointes d’or nécessaires pour exalter le champ proche ne peuvent présentement pas être fabriquées et utilisées pour la MFA. Celles-ci ne peuvent pas garantir simultanément une excitation des résonances locales des plasmons de surfaces ainsi qu’une diffusion Raman fiable.La détection par cantilever a été conçue pour imiter une électrode de batterie commerciale. Le système consiste d’un substrat de mica, d’une couche métallique mince comme collecteur, d’une couche de matériel actif et du cantilever comme électrode. Une cellule électrochimique a été conçue avec un accès optique pour permettre de combiner des mesures d’électrochimies et des mesures de tension de surface sur le canitlever. La chambre a été conçue pour être hermétique à l’air permettant ainsi l’étude de matériaux sensibles á l’atmosphère. Des tests dans un électrolyte aqueux montrent que la réaction et/ou la délamination de la couche métallique compromet la conductivité du cantilever avant que le lithium ne puisse être retiré de la couche de matériel actif.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peter H. Grutter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p9799.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b8557</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77ss314"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional analysis of the lipid phosphatase, Inpp4b, in osteoblast physiology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liu, William</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bone homeostasis requires a strict balance between bone formation and bone resorption, mediated by osteoblasts and osteoclasts, respectively.  Perturbation of these activities can give rise to bone disorders such as osteoporosis and osteopetrosis.  Osteopetrosis is an inheritable bone disorder characterized by dense, brittle bones prone to fracture as a result of defects in the osteoclast.  Our laboratory characterized the Ostm1 gene, which is responsible for the most severe form of osteopetrosis in both mice and humans.  Through expression profiles of these Ostm1-deficient osteopetrotic mice, we isolated and characterized the lipid phosphatase, Inpp4b, as a negative regulator of osteoclastogenesis.  Expressed in osteoblasts and osteoclasts, systemic Inpp4b loss-of-function in mice resulted in increased osteoclast differentiation and function, leading to an osteoporotic phenotype.  Importantly, these mice exhibited an increased mineral apposition rate in vivo as well as increased mineral nodule formation ex vivo, demonstrating an osteoblast-specific role for Inpp4b.  These findings prompted us to investigate the role of this gene in osteoblasts using conditional knock-out and transgenic mouse models.  To this end, we used a combination of ex vivo and in vivo analyses to determine the function of Inpp4b in the mature osteoblast using a human osteocalcin (hOcn) promoter.  Inpp4blox/lox;hOcn-Cre mice exhibited defects in mineral nodule formation and gene expression kinetics ex vivo.  Histomorphometry of these mice revealed an increase in osteoblast population and activity at 8 weeks of age, with no observable effects in osteoclast differentiation.  Despite this, bone mass remains comparable to control mice.  Interestingly, hOcn-Inpp4b-hGH transgenic mice displayed bone mass reduction, concomitant with reduced osteoblastic activity and increased capacity for inducing osteoclast differentiation.  Taken together, our results have demonstrated that Inpp4b exerts a role in the mature osteoblast, independent of osteoclasts, and that Inpp4b osteoblast-specific function is critical for bone homeostasis.   </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L’homéostasie osseuse repose sur un strict équilibre entre la formation de l’os par l’ostéoblaste et sa résorption par l’ostéoclaste. Des pathologies osseuses comme l'ostéoporose et l’ostéopétrose découlent d'un débalancement entre la résorption et la formation osseuses. L’ostéopétrose réfère à un groupe d'anomalies osseuses rares et héréditaires, caractérisées par une augmentation de la densité osseuse due à un défaut de développement ou de fonction des ostéoclastes. Notre laboratoire a caractérisé le gène Ostm1, responsable de la forme la plus sévère de l’ostéopétrose chez l’Homme et les souris.  Lors de nos études génétiques chez les souris ostéopétrotiques déficientes en Ostm1, nous avons caractérisé Inpp4b comme un régulateur négatif de l’ostéoclastogenèse.  Inpp4b est exprimé dans les ostéoblastes et les ostéoclastes. L’ablation systémique de ce gène chez la souris résulte en une augmentation du nombre d’ostéoclastes et en un phénotype ostéoporotique.  Le nombre des ostéoblastes ainsi que leur capacité à minéraliser a été aussi augmenté chez ces souris suggérant un rôle spécifique d’Inpp4b dans les ostéoblastes.  Afin de caractériser le rôle d’Inpp4b dans les ostéoblastes nous avons utilisé des souris transgéniques où Inpp4b a été spécifiquement invalidé ou surexprimé dans ces cellules sous le contrôle du promoteur du gène humain ostéocalcine (hOcn).  Les souris Inpp4blox/lox;hOcn-Cre présentent un défaut de minéralisation et une perturbation de l’expression des gènes associés à la différentiation des ostéoblastes.  L’analyse histomorphométrique de ces souris à l’âge de 8 semaines révèle une augmentation du nombre et de l’activité des ostéoblastes. Cependant, la différentiation des ostéoclastes ainsi que la masse osseuse totale ne semblent pas être affectées.  De façon intéressante, les souris transgéniques hOcn-Inpp4b-hGH montrent une réduction de la masse osseuse due à une réduction de l’activité ostéoblastique et une augmentation de la différentiation ostéoclastique.  L’ensemble de ces résultats montre que Inpp4b joue un rôle important dans l’ostéoblaste mature, indépendamment de sa fonction ostéoclastique, et que la fonction spécifique d’Inpp4b dans les ostéoblastes est cruciale pour l’homéostasie osseuse. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jean Vacher</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/794080582.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77ss314</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623g06w"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Essays on exchange rate and inflation dynamics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Uddin, Noor Mohammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores the relationship between the exchange rate and the domestic price level in three essays. The first essay (Chapter 2) examines the causality between the exchange rate and consumer prices, and estimates the extent of the exchange rate pass-through to consumer prices for 12 OECD countries for the period 1974 to 2016. Using the adoption of the Euro and the adoption of the policy of targeting inflation in these countries, which represent changes in the monetary policy regime, I divide this time period into two groups and examine causality and pass-through behaviour separately for each country. Based on a newly developed causality measure for multiple horizons, I found that the direction of causality from consumer prices to exchange rate becomes stronger for the countries with the Euro while the direction of causality from the exchange rate to consumer prices becomes stronger for the inflation targeting countries after their respective regime change. By deriving the impulse response functions from a recursive vector autoregressive model, I found that the exchange rate pass-through to consumer prices is not statistically different from zero for the countries with the Euro while the pass-through is statistically significant in four out of the six remaining countries. Before the regime change, the evidence on both fronts was somewhat mixed among these two sets of countries. The second essay (Chapter 3) examines whether the aggregate price level responds asymmetrically to exchange rate appreciations and depreciations in 12 Asian countries for the period 1994 to 2016. Using a recently developed response-based test, I found evidence of asymmetric responses of the consumer price index to exchange rate appreciations and depreciations in 6 out of the 12 countries. The slope-based test also provides evidence of asymmetry for 6 countries, but the results are the same as the response-based tests only for 4 countries. Further, depreciations are not necessarily passed-through to prices more than the appreciations. The third essay (chapter 4) examines the purchasing power parity (PPP) hypothesis for our selected 12 Asian countries for the period 1974 to 2016. Since stationarity of the real exchange rate implies that PPP holds, I employ unit root tests on the real exchange rate in the presence of multiple structural breaks. Our findings support the PPP hypothesis for six countries. Further, there is no additional evidence of trend stationarity of the series in these countries, so that there is no support for the Harrod-Balassa-Samuelson hypothesis. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse explore la relation entre le taux de change et le niveau des prix intérieurs dans trois essais. Le premier essai (chapitre 2) examine la causalité entre le taux de change et les prix à la consommation et évalue l'ampleur de la répercussion des taux de change sur les prix à la consommation de 12 pays de l'OCDE pour la période 1974 à 2016. Avec l'adoption de l'euro et l'adoption de la politique de ciblage de l'inflation dans ces pays, qui représente les changements de politique monétaire, je divise cette période en deux groupes et examine séparément le comportement causal et le comportement de transmission pour chaque pays. Sur la base d'une mesure de causalité nouvellement développée pour plusieurs horizons, j'ai trouvé que la direction de la causalité entre les prix à la consommation et le taux de change devient plus forte pour les pays ayant adopté l'euro. Au contraire, la direction de la causalité du taux de change vers le prix à la consommation devient plus forte pour les pays ciblant l'inflation après leurs changements de régime respectifs. En dérivant les fonctions de réponse impulsionnelle d'un modèle vectoriel autorégressif récursif, j'ai constaté que l'impact des taux de change sur les prix à la consommation n'est pas statistiquement différent de zéro pour les pays euro, alors que l'impact est statistiquement significatif dans quatre des six pays restants. Avant le changement de régime, les éléments de preuve sur les deux fronts étaient quelque peu mitigés entre ces deux ensembles de pays.Le deuxième essai (chapitre 3) examine si le niveau agrégé des prix répond de façon asymétrique aux appréciations et aux dépréciations de taux de change dans 12 pays asiatiques pour la période 1994-2016. En utilisant un test basé sur la réponse récemment développé, j'ai trouvé des preuves de réponses asymétriques de l'indice des prix à la consommation aux appréciations et aux dépréciations de taux de change dans 6 des 12 pays. Le test basé sur la pente fournit également des preuves d'asymétrie pour 6 pays, mais les résultats sont les mêmes que les tests basés sur la réponse seulement pour 4 pays. En outre, les dévaluations ne sont pas nécessairement reflétées dans les prix plus que les appréciations.Le troisième essai (chapitre 4) examine l'hypothèse de la parité de pouvoir d'achat (PPA) pour nos 12 pays asiatiques sélectionnés pour la période 1974 à 2016. Étant donné que la stationnarité du taux de change réel implique que la PPA est maintenue, j'utilise des tests de racine unitaire sur le taux de change réel en présence de ruptures structurelles multiples. Nos résultats soutiennent l'hypothèse PPA pour six pays. De plus, il y avait peu de signes de stationnarité tendancielle de la série dans ces pays de sorte que l'hypothèse Harrod-Balassa-Samuelson n'est pas soutenue.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jagdish Handa</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784p16d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623g06w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4x51hm71x"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Constraining cosmological parameters with gravitational lensing of the cosmic microwave background</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Simard, Gabrielle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les fluctuations du fond diffus cosmologique (CMB) découlent directement des processus physiques à l'oeuvre dans l'Univers primordial.Ces anisotropies portent également une quantité importante d'information sur l'Univers récent par l'entremise de plusieurs effets secondaires, incluant l'effet de lentille gravitationnelle.Durant leur parcours de la surface de dernière diffusion jusqu'à nous, les photons du CMB primaire sont déviés par les structures à grandes échelles, ce qui crée de subtiles distortions dans les cartes en température et polarization du CMB pouvant être détectées statistiquement.Dans cette thèse, nous présentons des contraintes sur les paramètres d\'ecrivant notre Univers aux échelles cosmologiques obtenues à l'aide de données de l'effet de lentille gravitationnelle dans le CMB.Nous décrivons d'abord le modèle cosmologique actuel et poursuivons avec une revue des effets du lentillage gravitationnel sur les quantités observables du CMB.Nous présentons ensuite des contraintes sur les paramètres cosmologiques placées par une mesure du spectre en puissance de l'effet de lentillage.Ce spectre de puissance correspond à une carte du potentiel de lentillage calculée à partir d'observations combinées du CMB en température par le satellite Planck et le télescope SPT sur une surface de 2500 degrés carrés.Ajouter des mesures de lentillage gravitationnel aux mesures du CMB primaire permet de reserrer les contraintes sur les paramètres cosmologiques affectant l'Univers récent, telles que l'amplitude des fluctuations de densité aujourd'hui, la courbure de l'espace et la masse totale des neutrinos.Les mesures de la polarisation du CMB créée dans l'Univers primordial sont entravées par la polarisation additionnelle produite par les déflections du lentillage gravitationnel; ce signal contaminant issu du lentillage peut être estimé et retiré.Nous discutons des contraintes prévues sur la dépendance à l'échelle angulaire du signal primordial en polarisation en assumant que le signal contaminant du lentillage peut être retiré à l'aide de différentes méthodes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The cosmic microwave background (CMB) anisotropies are a direct probe of early Universe physics. They also carry information about the late Universe through different secondary effects, including gravitational lensing. Propagating away from the last scattering surface, the primary CMB photons are deflected by the intervening large-scale structure, creating slight distortions in the CMB radiation temperature and polarization patterns that can be detected statistically. In this thesis, we present constraints on the parameters describing our Universe on cosmological scales obtained with the use of CMB gravitational lensing measurements. We begin with a description of the current cosmological model and follow with a review of gravitational lensing effects on the CMB observables.We then present bounds on cosmological parameters set by the lensing power spectrum estimated from a combined SPT+Planck CMB temperature map on the SPT-SZ 2500 square-degrees patch of sky.Adding lensing information to primary CMB data helps tightening constraints on cosmological parameters affecting late-time growth, such as the matter fluctuation amplitude today, the spatial curvature and the sum of neutrino masses.Measurements of the CMB polarization sourced in the early Universe are hindered by the additional polarization created by the gravitational lensing deflections; this contaminating lensing signal can be estimated and removed. We discuss projected constraints on the scale-dependence of the primordial CMB polarization signal assuming that the lensing induced contamination can be subtracted through different scenarios.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Matthew Adam Dobbs</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Gilbert Holder</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zr06h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hm71x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811kn23p"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Distribution ambiances magnétiques etcetera and constellation records: DIY record labels and the Montreal experimental music scene</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mouillot, Francois</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette dissertation examine le rôle des petites marques de disques dans la scène musicale expérimentale montréalaise. Partant du concept de ‘scène culturelle’ tel que définit par Will Straw, je soutiens que les labels indépendants sont des vecteurs essentiels qui énergisent et adaptent les activités inhérentes aux scènes culturelles. En développant l'idée que les scènes culturelles sont, dans un sens, des matrices de réseaux et d'infrastructures, j'examine également comment les labels interagissent avec d'autres acteurs scéniques - tels que les lieux de musique et les instruments de musique – qui prolongent et créent un lien entre différents aspects des labels. Cette dissertation est articulée autour des cas de deux labels: Distribution Ambiances Magnétiques Etcetera (DAME), une petite entreprise qui se concentre principalement sur le mouvement musical de Musique actuelle, et Constellation Records, une étiquette qui favorise la musique populaire expérimentale. Chaque cas considère le rapport des labels à l'identité culturelle de Montréal, et conduit à des analyses de la salle de concert Casa del Popolo et des pratiques spécifiques du saxophone comme «ponts» entre l'esthétique et les activités des labels.Je soutiens que, à l'ère numérique, la fonction des petites maisons de disque  indépendantes est remise en cause par l'apparition d'un nouvel ensemble de pratiques et d'outils technologiques, mais que ces structures doivent être considérées comme des générateurs importants de connaissances sur les scènes culturelles urbaines auxquelles elles participent. Grâce à ces connaissances, des labels tels que DAME et Constellation Records ont contribué à la construction de l'identité culturelle contemporaine de Montréal ainsi qu’à sa représentation à l'échelle locale et internationale.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This dissertation examines the role of small record labels in the Montreal experimental music scene. Drawing and expanding on Will Straw’s conception of scene, I argue that independent record labels are crucial vectors of production and distribution that are energizers and adapters of the activities inherent to cultural scenes. Developing the notion that cultural scenes are, in one sense, matrixes of networks and infrastructures, I also examine how record labels interact with other scenic actors – such as music venues and musical instruments – that at times offer continuation of and unexpected bridges between the activities of labels. This dissertation is articulated around the cases of two record labels: Distribution Ambiances Magnétiques Etcetera (DAME), a small company that focuses primarily on the Musique actuelle musical movement, and Constellation Records, a label that has long promoted experimental popular music stemming out of the city’s Anglophone communities. Each case considers the labels’ relationship to the cultural identity of Montreal, and leads into analyses of the Casa del Popolo concert venue and of specific practices of the saxophone as ‘bridges’ between the labels’ aesthetics and activities. I argue that, in the digital era, the function of small independent labels like the ones examined in this dissertation is challenged by the rise a new set of practices and technological tools, but that these structures must be considered as important generators of knowledge about the urban cultural scenes they participate in. Through this knowledge, labels such as DAME and Constellation Records have contributed to the construction of Montreal’s contemporary cultural identity and to the city’s representation locally and internationally.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Straw, William O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m929z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kn23p</ual:fedora3Handle></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225d56v"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spontaneous imbalance in rotating stratified turbulence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Amini Kafiabad, Hossein</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Whereas high-frequency waves are valid solutions to the Boussinesq equations in certain limits, their amplitudes are generally observed to be small in large-scale atmospheric and oceanic data.  Traditionally, this has led to the development of balance models, reducing the dynamics to only the slow subset. Their solutions, however, can spontaneously generate imbalance in the context of the full equations. To study this phenomenon, we perform high-resolution turbulence simulations of the non-hydrostatic Boussinesq equations, starting with a high-order nonlinearly balanced initial condition. To produce this initial condition, we employ the nonlinear normal mode initialization scheme that was introduced by Baer and Tribbia (1977) up to second order in the Rossby number as the next-order improvement to quasigeostrophic theory. This initialisation is devised to limit the growth of high-frequency modes initially. To keep the flow predominantly balanced, we set the initial Rossby, Ro, and Froude, Fr, numbers to small values. By increasing these dimensionless parameters slightly, we investigate at what scales balance breaks down and after how long. Our results show that the balanced initial condition displays a steep geostrophic energy spectrum and an even steeper ageostrophic energy spectrum. However, a shallow tail later develops in the ageostrophic energy spectrum at small scales if Ro and the Reynolds number, Re, are large enough. This shallow range moves toward smaller wavenumbers if Ro is increased. Increasing N/f (while f is held nearly constant) leads to a shift of the shallow tail to smaller scales due to lower amplitudes of the unbalanced modes. By implementing a Baer-Tribbia-based balance/imbalance decomposition at the end of the integration time, we show that the unbalanced component of the dynamics accounts for the shallow range in the energy spectrum. This breakdown of balance, which leads to a change of slope in the energy spectrum, is consistent with observed atmospheric and oceanic spectra.  The disparity between the fast and slow timescales, which is a requirement of balance, is shown to break down at scales where the energy spectrum is still steep and the scale-dependent Ro and Fr are small. Spontaneous imbalance, which is the energy transfer from the balanced to the unbalanced modes, is also quantified in this study. More particularly, the scale at which it occurs and its dependence on the flow parameters are investigated. In our simulations, this quantity is shown to scale approximately as Ro^4.4 for our decomposition, accurate to second order in Ro. However, the wavenumber at which the maximum energy transfer from balance to imbalance occurs is invariant to Ro and Fr but dependent on the large-scale flow characterised by the Rossby radius of deformation. This wavenumber is found to be smaller than the wavenumber characterising the transition between the large scales and the shallow tail but larger than the peak of the energy spectrum. By comparing the results at different orders of balance, it is determined that all qualitative conclusions of this study are robust to the precise definition of balance. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Bien que les ondes à haute fréquence soient des solutions valides aux équations de Boussinesq dans certaines limites, leurs amplitudes sont généralement petites dans les données atmosphériques et océaniques à grande échelle. Traditionnellement, cela a mené au développement de modèles équilibrés, réduisant la dynamique à sa partie lente. Leurs solutions, cependant, peuvent générer spontanément un déséquilibre dans le contexte des équations complètes, ce qui consistue le sujet central de cette étude. Nous effectuons des simulations à haute résolution des équations non hydrostatiques de Boussinesq en débutant avec une condition initiale non linéairement équilibrée à ordre élevé. Pour produire cette condition initiale, nous utilisons le schéma d'initialisation non linéaire de Baer-Tribbia jusqu'au deuxième ordre du nombre de Rossby en tant qu'incrément à la théorie QG. Cette initialisation est conçue pour limiter la croissance initiale des modes haute fréquence. Pour maintenir l'équilibre de l'écoulement, nous assignons de petites valeurs initiales aux nombres de Rossby et de Froude. En augmentant légèrement ces paramètres sans dimension, nous étudions à quelle échelle se produit le bris d'équilibre et après combien de temps.Nos résultats montrent que la condition initiale équilibrée présente un spectre d'énergie géostrophique abrupte et un spectre d'énergie agéostrophique encore plus abrupte. Cependant, une queue plus douce se développe dans le spectre d'énergie agéostrophique aux petites échelles après un certain temps si Ro et Re sont assez grands. Cette gamme d'échelles moins escarpée se déplace vers les petits nombres d'onde si Ro est augmenté. Augmenter  N / f (alors que f est maintenu presque constant) mène à un décalage de la queue vers les petites échelles. En utilisant la décomposition équilibre-déséquilibre de Baer-Tribbia à la fin du temps d'intégration, nous montrons que la composante déséquilibrée de la dynamique domine la portion douce du spectre énergétique. Ce bris d'équilibre, qui entraîne un changement de pente du spectre énergétique, est en accord avec les spectres atmosphériques et océaniques observés. L'écart entre les échelles de temps rapide et lente, une condition d'équilibre, disparaît à des échelles où le spectre d'énergie est encore abrupte et Ro et Fr sont petits.La génération spontanée du déséquilibre, qui représente le transfert d'énergie des modes équilibrés vers les modes déséquilibrés, est également quantifiée dans cette étude. Plus particulièrement, l'échelle à laquelle elle se produit ainsi que sa dépendance aux paramètres de l'écoulement sont étudiés. On montre que cette quantité augmente selon Ro^{4.4} pour la décomposition équilibre-déséquilibre exacte au deuxième ordre en Ro. Cependant, le nombre d'onde auquel survient le transfert d'énergie maximum entre modes équilibrés et déséquilibrés est indépendant de Ro et Fr, mais dépendant de l'écoulement à grande échelle caractérisé par le rayon de déformation de Rossby. Ce nombre d'onde est plus petit que celui de la transition spectrale, mais plus grand que celui du pic du spectre énergétique. En comparant les résultats à différents ordres d'équilibre, on confirme que toutes les conclusions de cette étude sont robustes à la définition précise d'équilibre.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peter Bartello</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655k00r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d56v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pq474"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Great powers and intervention: transition from empire to nation-states, and the origins of nationalist and irredentist grievances</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zeren, Ali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La présente thèse examine les différents aspects de la transition d’un empire à un état-nation, et l’émergence du nationalisme et de l’irrédentisme. Elle est composée de quatre articles. Le premier article explore les facteurs menant à la séparation avec l’empire, et au moment où a lieu l’indépendance. Cet article se base sur un ensemble de données des anciens territoires et provinces ottomans qui a été produit grâce à des recherches dans les archives ottomanes, suite à des analyses générales. L’article examine aussi divers documents et correspondances diplomatiques de l'époque pour justifier les conclusions émises. Ensuite, le deuxième article étudie d’un côté, l’apparition de différentes couches sociales parmi lesquelles l’irrédentisme est le moteur idéologique, et d’un autre, les politiques misent en place pour édifier la nation et l’état qui mènent à la création et à la sur-expansion de ses couches sociales. Il y est aussi démontré comment ces irrédentistes ont été amenés à influencer et à affecter les politiques domestiques et étrangères. Cet article se sert d’analyses sur des dizaines de groupes irrédentistes qui ont existé dans les Balkans durant le XIXe et le début du XXe siècle, et sur les politiques d’édification de l’état et de la nation dans leurs pays respectifs. De plus, le troisième article se concentre sur le monde contemporain et examine ce qui détermine les guerres postindépendance durant les deux derniers siècles, ainsi que le moment où ont lieu ces guerres. L’analyse est basée sur un large ensemble de données qui couvrent plus de 200 états-nations entre 1816 et 2010 afin de comprendre les facteurs, les corrélats et le moment où ont lieu les guerres après la création de l’état-nation. Finalement, le quatrième article présente une analyse de l’impact des politiques d’éducation unitaires, homogènes et nationalistes durant la fin du XXe siècle. Cette analyse examine l’effet de telles politiques sur un groupe ethnique vivant sur le même territoire en proie à l’émergence de nationalismes rivaux. Ceci est illustré en analysant le lien entre éducation et l’émergence du PKK avec le cas des kurdes en Turquie. Cet article se base sur trois larges ensembles de données qui prennent en compte des milliers d’événements violents entre 1984 et 1995, des informations biographiques de milliers d’insurgés du PKK morts lors de confrontations ou en prison entre 1979 et 2010, et enfin diverses variables économiques, politiques et sociodémographiques au niveau des districts.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This dissertation analyzes various dimensions of the transition from empire to nations states and the emergence of nationalism and irredentism. It consists of four papers. The first of these, analyzes the determinants of separation from empires and the timing of independence. It utilizes a data-set of former Ottoman territories and provinces, created through research in the Ottoman archives, for general testing, and analyzes various correspondences, and documents related to diplomatic history to substantiate the findings. The second paper, analyzes the emergence of strata among which irredentism is the driving ideology, and the type of nation-building and state building policies that lead to their creation and over-expansion. It also demonstrates the way in which these irredentists come to influence and affect domestic and foreign policy. The paper utilizes analysis of dozens of irredentists groups that have operated in the Balkans in the 19th and early 20th centuries, and the state-building and nation-building policies of their respective countries. The third paper analyzes the determinants and the timing of post-independence wars in the modern world, during the last two centuries. It utilizes a large data-set that covers over 200 nation-states between 1816 and 2010 to understand the determinants, correlates and the timing of the onset of wars after nation-state creation. The fourth paper analyzes the impact of unitary-homogenizing and nationalist education policy in the late 20th century. It looks at the impact of such policies on a geographically concentrated ethnic group with its own emerging nationalisms: the Kurds in Turkey, by looking at the link between education and the emergence of PKK. This paper utilizes three large data-sets that code thousands of violent events and incidences between 1984-1995, biographical information of thousands of PKK guerillas killed in confrontations or prisons between 1979-2010, and various economic, political and socio-demographic variables coded at the district level.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hall, John Anthony</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182n63d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pq474</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60d0085"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Essays on international currency, trend inflation, and policy uncertainty</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhao, Hong</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse analyse des questions entourant le rapport entre les devises internationales, l'inflation tendancielle et l'incertitude des politiques. Le premier essai étudie l'impact de l'inflation tendancielle sur le rôle de la principale devise internationale dans les paiements mondiaux. En construisant un modèle à trois pays avec une inflation tendancielle dans laquelle la part de la principale devise internationale est endogène, nous constatons que la position de la principale devise internationale persiste même si le taux d'inflation dans son propre pays augmente de $0$ à $8$ pour cent. En outre, l'incorporation de l'inflation tendancielle dans le modèle de l'économie ouverte révèle que l'inflation tendancielle domestique amplifie les effets de retombées d'un choc technologique domestique sur les pays étrangers. La tendance de l'inflation dans les pays étrangers renforce ces retombées négatives par une dispersion des prix. Dans l’optique d’explorer les coûts et les avantages d’une devise internationale, le deuxième essai construit un modèle à deux pays, dans lequel le pays d'origine fournit la devise internationale et le pays étranger l'utilise pour acheter des importations. Les conséquences de ce modèle sont analysées grâce à deux hypothèses de tarification. Dans la première, les prix de tous les biens échangés sont fixés dans la monnaie nationale et dans la seconde, les prix de tous les biens échangés sont fixés par la devise internationale. Nous identifions ensuite les avantages et les coûts découlant de ce choix d’une devise internationale. Le troisième essai examine comment l'incertitude de la politique monétaire affecte la macroéconomie par des frictions financières. Nous appliquons un nouveau modèle keynésien avec un mécanisme d'accélération financière et introduisons l'incertitude de la politique monétaire comme un choc de conservation significatif pour la variation du choc du taux d'intérêt. Les résultats montrent un impact négatif de l'incertitude politique sur la macroéconomie. Le mécanisme d'accélération financière amplifie ces effets néfastes. Il apparaît ainsi qu’au sein de l'incertitude de productivité et le choc de risque, l'incertitude des politiques induit les réponses les plus fortes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis addresses questions concerning international currency, trend inflation, and policy uncertainty. The first essay studies the impact of trend inflation on the share of the leading international currency in global payments. By constructing a three-country model with trend inflation in which the share of the leading international currency is endogenous, we find that the position of the leading international currency persists even if the inflation rate in its own country increases from $0$ to $8$ percent. Moreover, incorporation of trend inflation in the open-economy model reveals that domestic trend inflation amplifies the spillover effects of a domestic technology shock on foreign countries. Trend inflation in foreign countries reinforces these spillover effects through the effect of price dispersion. To explore the costs and benefits of having an international currency, the second essay constructs a two-country model in which the home country provides the international currency and the foreign country uses it to purchase imports. Implications of this model are derived under two pricing assumptions. One, where the prices of all traded goods are set in the domestic currency and the other, where the prices of all traded goods are set in the international currency. We identify new sources of benefits and costs of having an international currency. The third essay investigates how monetary policy uncertainty affects macroeconomy under financial frictions. We apply a New-Keynesian model with a financial accelerator mechanism and introduce the monetary policy uncertainty as a mean preserving shock to the variance of the level interest rate shock. Results show a negative impact of policy uncertainty on macroeconomy. Financial accelerator mechanism amplifies this adverse effects. Furthermore, among the productivity uncertainty and risk shock, policy uncertainty induces the strongest output responses.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jagdish Handa</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Francisco Ruge-Murcia</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n767.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d0085</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77fv027"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Information Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysing file management behaviour</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dinneen, Jesse</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis I examine and improve upon the state of knowledge about a task ubiquitous in and fundamental to the use of computers, file management (FM). This is done in three chapters, constituting a review of the relevant scholarly literature, a methodological contribution, and an empirical study of the FM behaviour of 301 computer users, respectively.In the first chapter I synthesise hundreds of studies about various aspects of FM to identify a large but previously unacknowledged body of research into FM, and characterise the knowledge and knowledge gaps the literature evinces. I find that studies of FM are typically motivated by understanding users' FM behaviour, the factors that determine this behaviour, and how FM can best be supported by systems and services. After examining the studies’ methods and findings, I conclude that the differing goals of past studies have entailed small sample sizes, inconsistent data collection, and incommensurable contexts that preclude deriving a quantitative description of users' behaviour necessary for understanding such behaviour, and that such a description can not currently be derived as no tool exists that collects the necessary data. In the second chapter I describe developing and testing novel data collection software designed to address this knowledge gapand overcome limitations of practicality seen in existing tools, specifically by facilitating collecting extensive data from large and heterogeneous population samples. The software was built with open-source tools and shared with the research community, and can be used and reused in future studies to treat the gaps in knowledge identified in the firstchapter.The third chapter then describes the first use of this software to examine in detail the file systems of 301 participants, producing a broad, quantitative description of typical FM behaviour and facilitating comparison across previously incommensurable studies. The collected data are found to be log-normally distributed, and so the statistical analysesnecessary for deriving a meaningful description of such data are made, and indication of this for the accuracy of analyses made in previous studies is discussed. In describing users' behaviour I find that despite the proliferation of alternatives to traditional FM, users are now keeping considerably larger collections than previously observed, and storing these in folder trees that exhibit stable internal structure and file categorisation while becoming taller and wider. These results establish a basic quantitative description of typical FM behaviour, thus laying the necessary foundation for further study of FM, including modelling users and their collections, studying the factors that determine FM behaviour, and advancing theory about the management and organisation of information. The results may also aid in the interpretation of qualitative studies of FM and the design of software and services to support it. Such advances – in knowledge and practical action – are required to better support FM, a daily and fundamental part of using a computer and managing digital content, and are enabled by the problem identification, methodological contribution, and findings of this thesis.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans la thèse, j’examine et j’améliore l’état de la connaissance concernant une tâche omniprésente et fondamentale à l’utilisation d’un ordinateur : la gestion des fichiers électroniques (GFE). La thèse comprend trois chapitres : un recensement de la littérature scientifique sur le sujet, une contribution méthodologique et une étude empirique du comportement de GFE de 301 utilisateurs d’ordinateurs.Dans le premier chapitre, je synthétise des centaines d’études sur divers aspects de la GFE pour relever un corpus important de recherches encore méconnues sur le sujet, caractériser la connaissance et déterminer quelles sont les lacunes dans la connaissance telles que relevées dans les publications. On y découvre que les études de la GFE sont généralement motivées par la compréhension du comportement des utilisateurs, les facteurs déterminant ce comportement et comment la GFE peut mieux s’appuyer sur les systèmes et les services. Après un examen des méthodes et des résultats des études, je conclus que leurs objectifs différents impliquent des échantillons restreints, des collectes de données inconsistantes et une diversité de contextes qui limitent la capacité des chercheurs à décrire quantitativement le comportement des utilisateurs pour mieux le comprendre et qu’une telle description n’est pas possible à l’heure actuelle puisqu’il n’existe aucun outil pour en recueillir les données nécessaires. Dans le deuxième chapitre, je décris le développement et le test d’un nouveau logiciel de collecte de données conçu pour étudier les lacunes dans la connaissance et surmonter les limites pratiques des outils existants, spécifiquement en facilitant une collecte exhaustive des données à partir d’un vaste échantillon hétérogène issu de divers contextes. Le logiciel a été conçu à partir d’outils en libre accès et partagé avec la communauté de la recherche. Celui-ci peut être utilisé et réutilisé pour d’autres études sur les lacunes dans la connaissance relevées dans le premier chapitre.Dans le troisième chapitre, je décris la première utilisation du logiciel pour examiner en détail le système de fichiers de 301 participants, permettant ainsi une description générale et quantitative du comportement typique en matière de GFE et facilitant la comparaison entre un nombre incommensurable d’études existantes. Les données recueillies suivent une distribution log-normale et permettent les analyses statistiques requises pour en extraire une description significative. Je discute enfin de l’exactitude de l’analyse des études antérieures. Relativement au comportement des utilisateurs, malgré une prolifération de méthodes de rechange aux solutions traditionnelles en GFE, les utilisateurs conservent maintenant des collections beaucoup plus volumineuses qu’observées auparavant et conservent les fichiers dans une arborescence qui témoigne d’une structure interne et d’une catégorisation des fichiers stables. Par ailleurs, ces structures sont également plus profondes et plus extensives. Les résultats permettent d’établir une description quantitative de base du comportement typique en matière de GFE, posant les fondations nécessaires à de futures études de la GFE, y compris la modélisation des utilisateurs et de leurs collections, l’étude des facteurs déterminant le comportement de GFE, et l’avancement de la théorie de la gestion et de l’organisation de l’information. Les résultats pourront également contribuer à l’interprétation d’études qualitatives de la GFE et à la conception de logiciels et de services pour la soutenir. De telles avancées, à la fois théoriques et pratiques, sont requises pour mieux soutenir la GFE, une tâche quotidienne fondamentale à l’utilisation d’un ordinateur et à la gestion de contenu numérique, et le tout est rendu possible par l’identification de la problématique, la contribution méthodologique et les résultats de la thèse.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Charles Antoine Julien</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430715r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fv027</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bk746"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of physical factors on the structure of communities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Portalier, Sébastien</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une grande partie des études en écologie des communautés se concentrent sur les interactions entre espèces, alors que le rôle joué par le milieu environnant est souvent négligé. Les composants physiques du milieu créent des contraintes mécaniques sur les espèces au niveau des individus. Ces contraintes affectent tous les organismes, depuis les producteurs primaires comme le phytoplancton qui a besoin de rester dans la zone éclairée, jusqu'aux prédateurs qui ont besoin de se mouvoir pour trouver une proie. De plus, les effets de ces facteurs peuvent potentiellement agir en cascade le long de la chaîne trophique. Ces effets sont liés à la taille des organismes, et existent dans tous les types d'écosystèmes. Cette thèse étudie la façon dont ces contraintes mécaniques affectent la structure des communautés à chaque niveau trophique, pour un vaste éventail de tailles d'organismes. Dans le Chapitre 2, je me concentre sur les producteurs primaires, représentés par le phytoplancton. Les espèces de phytoplancton ont tendance à couler à cause de l'interaction entre la gravité, la densité du milieu, la densité de l'organisme et la viscosité du milieu. La disponibilité en lumière diminue avec la profondeur et un mélange turbulent affecte les particules dans la colonne d'eau. Je montre que les cellules de phytoplancton peuvent persister dans une gamme de turbulence dépendante de la taille, et au-dessus d'une profondeur critique également dépendante de la taille. Dans le Chapitre 3, j'étudie la façon dont la relation prédateur-proie est contrainte par la gravité, la densité et la viscosité pour une vaste gamme de tailles d'organismes pour le prédateur et la proie, dans les système aquatiques et terrestres. Un prédateur doit chercher, capturer et maintenir une proie, ce qui génère des dépenses énergétiques. Les processus de prédation limitent la gamme de tailles de proies qu'un prédateur peut consommer. La taille supérieure de proie est déterminée par la capacité de capture de la proie (une limite mécanique), alors que la taille inférieure de proie est déterminée par des coûts énergétiques  (essentiellement liés au maintien de la proie). Enfin, le Chapitre 4 étudie la façon dont ces facteurs affectent la structure de tailles et la dynamique de modules de réseaux trophiques. Je montre que la taille des consommateurs dirige la dynamique des systèmes prédateur-proie. Les prédateurs plus grands excluent habituellement les prédateurs plus petits, alors que les proies plus petites excluent habituellement les proies plus grandes. Les ratios prédits de tailles prédateur-proie sont en accord avec les données existantes. Cette thèse tente de déduire la persistance des espèces et leurs interactions à partir de contraintes mécaniques dues au milieu, pour un large éventail de tailles d'organismes. Cette thèse apporte un nouvel éclairage sur l'écologie des communautés en liant les composantes biologiques et physiques des écosystèmes, revenant ainsi aux racines même du concept d'écosystème.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A large part of studies in community ecology focus on species interactions, while the role played by the surrounding medium is often neglected. The physical components of the medium create mechanical constraints on species at the individual level. These constraints affect all organisms, from primary producers such as phytoplankton that need to stay in the light zone, up to predators that need to move to find prey. Moreover, effects of these factors potentially cascade throughout the whole food chain. These effects are size-related, and they exist across any type of ecosystem. The present thesis investigates how these mechanical constraints affect community structure at any trophic level across a wide range of body sizes. In Chapter 2, I focus on primary producers, represented by phytoplankton. Phytoplankton species are prone to sinking due to the interplay between gravity, medium density, body density, and medium viscosity. Light availability decreases with depth and turbulent mixing affects particles in the water column. I show that phytoplankton cells can persist within a size-dependent range of turbulence, and above a size-dependent critical depth. In Chapter 3, I investigate how predator-prey relationship is constrained by gravity, density and viscosity for a wide range of predator and prey body sizes, in aquatic and terrestrial systems. A predator needs to search, capture and handle prey, which leads to energy expenditure. Predation processes limit the range of prey sizes that a predator can consume. Upper prey size is determined by predator ability to capture a prey (a mechanical limit), while lower prey size is determined by energetic costs (mostly related to handling). Lastly, Chapter 4 investigates how these factors affect the size structure and dynamics of food web modules. I show that consumer size drives the dynamics of predator-prey systems. Larger predators usually outcompete smaller predators, while smaller prey usually outcompete larger prey. Predicted predator-prey body size ratios are consistent with existing data. This thesis tries to deduce species persistence and interactions from mechanical constraints due to the medium, across a wide range of body sizes. This thesis provides novel insights on community ecology by linking the biological and physical components of ecosystems, thus going back to the roots of the ecosystem concept.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michel Loreau</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Gregor Fussmann</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z94x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bk746</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqv33s001d"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Coupled thermodynamic modeling and experimental study of Li2O-Na2O-MgO-CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Konar, Bikram</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les diagrammes de phase et les propriétés thermodynamiques du système Li2O-Na2O-MgO-CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 sont importants dans diverses applications industrielles et processus scientifiques et pour comprendre divers phénomènes minéralogiques. Ce système multicomposant, en tout ou en partie, a également été utilisé pour diverses applications en verre et en céramique. En effet, plusieurs phases contenant du Li2O forment des composants clés en tant que matériaux pour des céramiques nucléaires, prothèses en vitrocéramique et électrodes de semi-conducteurs pour des cellules électrochimiques. L'introduction de Li2O dans le système d’enduits conventionnels employés pour les moules peut réduire l'utilisation de fluorures nuisibles à l'environnement pendant le processus de coulée de l’acier. En dépit de ses nombreuses applications, les équilibres de phase et les propriétés thermodynamiques du système d’enduits contenant du Li2O sont limitées. Les expériences en laboratoire et les données sur les essais en usine sont limitées en raison de la forte pression de vapeur, de l'hygroscopicité, de la haute réactivité et des défis dans la caractérisation du Li2O. En conséquence, les processus industriels impliquant des systèmes contenant Li2O sont souvent optimisés en utilisant une approche d'essai et d'erreur, ce qui entrave le développement rigoureux de nouveaux produits et processus. Des diagrammes de phase et des informations thermodynamiques exactes et complètes pour ces systèmes bénéficieront à de nombreux processus industriels. Par conséquent, une base de données thermodynamique du système Li2O-Na2O-MgO-CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 est développée dans la présente étude.Afin d'aider au développement de la base de données thermodynamique, des études expérimentales de diagramme de phase clés ont été réalisées dans plusieurs sous-systèmes où les données étaient limitées ou absentes. Dans la plupart des cas, un ensemble d'expériences de calorimétrie à balayage différentiel (DSC) a d’abord été réalisé avec des creusets de Pt-Rh ou Au-Pd scellés pour identifier les transitions de phase. Afin de déterminer l'évolution exacte des phases, des expériences de trempe classiques suivies d'une diffraction des rayons X (XRD) et d'une micro-analyse de la sonde électronique (EPMA) ont été effectuées. Les nouvelles expériences menées dans cette étude fournissent non seulement des informations précieuses sur les équilibres de phase, mais aussi la résolution d'incohérences entre les données expérimentales existantes. L'évaluation critique de tous les diagrammes de phase disponibles et les données de propriétés thermodynamiques ont conduit à l'optimisation thermodynamique du système Li2O-Na2O-MgO-CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 où les énergies de Gibbs du liquide et toutes les phases solides ont été systématiquement évaluées. Cela a entraîné un développement rigoureux et cohérent de la base de données thermodynamique du système avec les paramètres du modèle optimisés dans les systèmes binaires et ternaires.La nouvelle base de données thermodynamiques du système Li2O-Na2O-MgO-CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 a été appliquée pour comprendre le processus de production des vitrocéramiques d’aluminosilicate de lithium et pour illustrer une stratégie de conception d’enduit de moule contenant du Li2O pour la coulée d'acier à haute teneur en aluminium. La conception du flux a été déterminée par une approche logique basée sur les calculs de diagramme de phase, de solidification et de viscosité. La base de données développée dans cette étude est compatible avec les bases de données thermodynamiques FactSage et peut être utilisée pour prédire tout diagramme de phase inexploré ou propriétés thermodynamiques dans le système à six composants. De telles prédictions de diagramme de phase multicomposant ont été validées avec des expériences de diagramme de phase. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The phase diagrams and thermodynamic properties of the Li2O-Na2O-MgO-CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 system are important in various industrial applications and scientific processes and to understand various mineralogical phenomena. This multicomponent system, in whole or in part, has also been used for various glass and ceramic applications. Indeed, several Li2O-containing phases form key components for nuclear ceramics materials, prosthetic glass-ceramics and solid-state electrodes for electrochemical cells. The introduction of Li2O to the conventional mold flux system can reduce the usage of environmentally harmful fluorides during the steel casting process. Inspite of its numerous applications, the phase equilibria and thermodynamic properties data of the Li2O-bearing system are limited. The laboratory experiments and plant trials data are restricted due to the high vapor pressure, hygroscopicity, high reactivity and challenges in characterization of Li2O. As a result, the industrial processes involving Li2O-containing systems are often optimized using a trial and error approach, which hinders the rigorous development of new products and processes. Accurate and comprehensive phase diagrams and thermodynamic information for these systems would benefit many industrial processes. Thus, a thermodynamic database of the Li2O-Na2O-MgO-CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 system is developed in the present study.In order to aid the thermodynamic database development, key phase diagram experimental studies were performed in several subsystems where data were limited or absent. In most of the cases, a set of differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) experiments were first carried out with sealed Pt-Rh or Au-Pd crucibles to identify the phase transitions. In order to determine the exact evolution of the phases, classical quenching experiments followed by X-ray diffraction (XRD) and electron probe micro-analysis (EPMA) were performed. Determination of the eutectic temperatures of the binary Li2O-MgO and Li2O-CaO systems were conducted for the first time.The new experiments conducted in this study, provide not only valuable phase equilibrium information but also resolve inconsistencies between existing experimental data. Critical evaluation of all available and new phase diagram and thermodynamic property data led to the thermodynamic optimization of the Li2O-Na2O-MgO-CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 system where the Gibbs energies of the liquid and all the solid phases were systematically assessed. This resulted in a rigorous and self consistent thermodynamic database development of the Li2O-Na2O-MgO-CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 system with the model parameters optimized in binary and ternary systems.The new thermodynamic database of the Li2O-Na2O-MgO-CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 system was applied to understand the lithium-aluminosilicate glass-ceramic production process and to illustrate a Li2O-containing mold flux design strategy for the casting of high-Al steel. The design of the flux was determined with a logical approach based on phase diagram, solidification and viscosity calculations. The database developed in this study is compatible with the FactSage thermodynamic databases and can be used for the prediction of any unexplored phase diagram or thermodynamic properties within the six-component system. Such multicomponent phase diagram predictions were validated with phase diagram experiments. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>In-Ho Jung</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gg41n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s001d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042w44t"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Resilient responses: coping with racial microaggressions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Houshmand, Sara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Racial microaggressions are commonplace, brief, subtle denigrating messages targeted at people of colour because they belong to a racial minority group (Pierce, Carew, &amp; Pierce-Gonzalez, 1978; Solórzano, Ceja, &amp; Yosso, 2000; Sue, 2010; Sue, Capodilupo et al., 2007). Because of their subtle and nebulous nature, these incidents may require complex coping strategies (Lewis et al., 2013; Noh, Kaspar, &amp; Wickrama, 2007; Pierce, 1995). In this dissertation, I examined responses among racialized university students and community members in Montreal, Canada. Research questions were as following: (a) how do individuals who experience racial microaggressions respond to or cope with racial microaggressions?; (b) what effects, if any, do intersecting social group identities (e.g., race, ethnicity, gender, and social class) have on individuals’ responses to racial microaggressions?This dissertation comprises two studies. In study one, I conducted focus groups with five groups of students (i.e., East Asian, South Asian, Black, and Arab Canadians and Aboriginal students; n = 32) at a predominantly White Canadian university. To analyze the data, I used the consensual qualitative research approach (CQR; Hill et al., 1997, 2005) that has been utilized often in microaggression research (e.g., Sue, Capodilupo et al., 2007, 2008). In study two, I conducted individual interviews with Black Canadian (n = 5) and Indigenous (n = 5) community members who pursued employment directly following secondary education. I utilized interpretative phenomenological analysis (IPA; Smith, Flowers, &amp; Larkin, 2009), a complementary qualitative approach to augment my earlier investigation. Across both the student and community samples, findings demonstrated that participants used a range of collective, protective, and resistant strategies in response to experiences with racial microaggressions. At times, participants’ strategies differed based on intersecting social group identities. Response strategies convey three important features: (a) the influence of racial/ethnic identity in the use of resistance; (b) deliberate strategies of disengagement as a form of resistance; and, (c) participants’ use of humour to serve different functions depending on the context. Finally, I offered directions for future research, re-conceptualization of responses to racial microaggressions, and practice.   </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les microagressions raciales sont des messages habituels, brefs et subtiles qui visent les membres de groupes minoritaires visibles (Pierce, Carew, &amp; Pierce-Gonzalez, 1978; Solórzano, Ceja, &amp; Yosso, 2000; Sue, 2010; Sue, Capodilupo et al., 2007). En conséquence de leur nature subtile et nébuleuse, ces incidents peuvent mettre en marche des mécanismes de défense complexes (Lewis et al., 2013; Noh, Kaspar, &amp; Wickrama, 2007; Pierce, 1995). Dans cette thèse, j’ai examiné les réactions d’étudiants racialisés à l’université et d’individus racialisés dans la communauté. Les questions de recherche étaient les suivantes : (a) comment est-ce que les individus qui vivent des microagressions raciales répondent aux microagressions raciales? ; (b) quels est l’impacts de différents facteurs identitaires et sociales (par ex. rage, origine ethnique, genre ou classe sociale), les cas échéant, sur la réaction d’un individu?Cette thèse comprend deux études. Dans la première, j’ai dirigée des groupes de discussions avec cinq groupes d’étudiants (c.-à-d. étudiants Autochtone et d’origine ethnique Est-Asiatique, Sud-Asiatique, Noirs, et Arabes Canadiens, n = 32) dans une université canadienne. J’ai employé la recherche qualitative consensuelle (CQR; Hill et al., 1997, 2005) qui a souvent était utilisé en investiguant les microagressions (par ex. Sue, Capodilupo et al., 2007, 2008). Dans la deuxième étude, j’ai tenu des entrevues individuelles avec des membres de communauté Noirs Canadiens (n = 5) et des membres de communauté Autochtone (n = 5) qui ont poursuivi un emploi immédiatement après leur éducation secondaire. J’ai utilisé l’analyse phénoménologique interpretative (IPA; Smith, Flowers, &amp; Larkin, 2009), une approche qualitative afin de complémenter mon investigation initiale. À travers des groupes d’étudiants et des groupes de la communauté, les résultats démontrent que les participants ont utilisé une gamme de stratégies collectives, protectives et résistantes en réponse aux microagressions raciales. Les stratégies employées par les participants variaient dépendamment de l’intersection de plusieurs facteurs identitaires et sociales. Ces stratégies expriment trois traits importants: (a) l’identité raciale/ethnique influence l’utilisation de résistance; (b) des fois, l’utilisation de stratégies de désengagement par les femmes se manifestait sous la forme d’une stratégie de résistance; et (c) l’utilisation d’humour par les participants à servi des buts différents dépendent de contexte. Enfin, j’offre des directions pour le future de la recherche, pour la re-conceptualisation des réponses aux microagressions raciales et pour l’application pratique. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jack Destefano</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Lisa Spanierman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687k66r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042w44t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anv935538j"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experimental and theoretical investigation of the dynamics and stability of hanging tubular cantilevers subject to internal and external flow</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Minas, Sophie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'instabilité fluide-élastique des tubes suspendus en porte-à-faux soumis à des écoulements internes et externes est étudiée. À des vitesses d'écoulement suffisamment élevées, ces tubes flexibles présentent des oscillations dynamiques (battement) et/ou une divergence statique (flambage). Plus précisément, le système étudié se compose d'un encastré-libre, qui est suspendu de manière concentrique à l'intérieur d'un plus grand tube rigide externe. Le fluide circule à l'intérieur du porte-à-faux, ainsi que à l'extérieur dans l'espace annulaire. Deux configurations d'écoulement sont considérées ici. Pour la configuration (iii)2, le fluide est dirigé de l'extrémité serrée du porte-à-faux à l'extrémité libre et s'écoule dans la direction opposée dans la région annulaire entre le porte-à-faux et le tube extérieur. Pour la configuration (iv), le fluide est aspiré dans le tube en porte-à-faux et déchargé dans l'espace annulaire. Ce système est entièrement contenu dans une cavité fermée et immergé dans un fluide. La modification de l'écoulement axial à un écoulement radial dans l'extrémité libre du tube a été réalisée en utilisant une extrémité avec de trous perpendiculaires à l’axe du tube. Cet embout crée un effet de masse ajouté en plus de dévier radialement l'écoulement.Pour la configuration (iv), les résultats expérimentaux n'ont pas montré un changement dans le comportement du système avec circulation axial ou radial. Pour la configuration (iii), les résultats expérimentaux ont montré que la décharge de l'écoulement radial à l'extrémité libre du porte-à-faux a abouti à une stabilité et aucun flottement, tandis que avec écoulement axial à l'extrémité libre ont montré une perte de stabilité avec du flottement.Un modèle linéaire a été dérivé sur la base de travaux antérieurs de Païdoussis et al. (2014), dans lesquels des solutions en série ont été employé en utilisant des fonctions propres des poutres Euler-Bernoulli et en appliquant la méthode de Galerkin pour la configuration (iii).Les résultats expérimentaux ont été comparés avec résultats du modèle théorique. Les effets de la masse des extrémités, de l'enfouissement, de la longueur de la conduite et des comparaisons entre l’écoulement radial et axial ont également été étudiés.Les prédictions théoriques de ce système ont été examinées en variant plusieurs paramètres, tels que la masse de l'extrémité (m_e), le diamètre de l’anneau (r_ann) et la longueur du tube (L). Les résultats indiquent qu’avec un embout plus massif, le porte-à-faux était déstabilisé. En ce qui concerne le blocage partiel du tube, la stabilité expérimentale a été obtenue dans tous les cas et théoriquement prévue pour la plupart des cas. Théoriquement et expérimentalement, la stabilité de tous les modes a été observée pour toutes les longueurs de tube considérées, ce qui suggère que la stabilité peut être indépendante de la longueur en porte-à-faux.Ce système est pertinent pour la production de saumure ainsi que pour l'industrie du stockage des hydrocarbures à base de sel dans lequel la tuyauterie transmettant de la saumure / de l'huile est soumise à des vibrations et des instabilités induites par le flux. Les paramètres du système de la saumure concernée ont été exécutés dans le modèle théorique et ont entraîné une stabilité pour plusieurs combinaisons de paramètres du système.En outre, le rapport entre la vitesse d'écoulement externe et interne a été étudié pour la configuration (iii) et a montré que des ratios plus élevés ont un effet déstabilisant.2 Les conﬁgurations (i) et (ii) ont déjà été étudiées d´etaillées dans cette thèse [17]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The ﬂuid-elastic instability of hanging cantilevered tubes subject to internal and external ﬂows has been studied. At high enough ﬂow velocities, these ﬂexible tubular cantilevers experience ampliﬁed oscillations (ﬂutter) and/or static divergence (buckling). Speciﬁcally, the system studied consists of a ﬂexible tubular hanging can- tilever, which hangs concentrically within a larger diameter outer rigid tube. The ﬂuid ﬂows inside the cantilever as well as externally in the annular space. Two ﬂow conﬁgurations are considered here. For conﬁguration (iii) 1 , ﬂuid is directed from the clamped end of the cantilever to the free end and ﬂows in the opposite direction in the annular region between the cantilever and the outer tube. For the conﬁguration (iv) case, the ﬂuid is aspirated through the cantilever tube and discharged in the an- nular space. This entire system was contained within a closed cavity and immersed in surrounding ﬂuid. Modiﬁcation of the traditional system from axial to radial ﬂow at the tube free end was accomplished with the use of end-pieces with holes perpendicular to the tube. The end-piece created an added mass eﬀect in addition to diverting ﬂow radially. For conﬁguration (iv), experimental results indicated no changes in system behavior between axial and radial ﬂow. For conﬁguration (iii), the experimental results showed that discharging radial ﬂow through the free-end of the cantilever resulted in stability and no ﬂutter, while cantilevers conveying axial ﬂow through the free-end displayed loss of stability by ﬂutter. A linear model is derived based on earlier work by Paidoussis et al. (2014), in which series solutions are em- ployed using Euler-Bernoulli beam comparison functions and applying the Galerkin method, for conﬁguration (iii) [22]. The experimental results are compared with the theoretical model results. The eﬀects of end-piece mass, conﬁnement, pipe length, and comparisons between radial and axial ﬂow have also been studied. Theoretical predictions for this system were examined by varying several parameters including the mass of the end-piece (m_e ), conﬁnement length fraction (r_ann ), and pipe length (L). The results indicated that, as the mass of the end-piece was increased, the can- tilever was destabilized. With regards to conﬁnement, experimentally stability was seen for all cases and theoretically predicted for most cases. Theoretically and exper- imentally, stability for all modes was seen for all tube lengths considered, suggesting that stability may be independent of cantilever length. This system is relevant to brine production as well as to the salt-cavern hydrocarbon storage industry, in which piping conveying brine/oil is subject to ﬂow-induced vibrations and instabilities. Rel- evant brine-string system parameters were run in the theoretical model and resulted in stability for several combination of system parameters. Additionally, the ratio between external and internal ﬂow velocity was investigated for conﬁguration (iii) ﬂow direction and proved that higher ratios have a de-stabilizing eﬀect.1 Conﬁgurations (i) and (ii) have been previously studied and are not detailed in this thesis [17]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael P. Paidoussis</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Farhang Daneshmand</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qs02j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935538j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1n79h6934"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Passive macromodeling of interconnect structures using LOEWNER matrix interpolation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kabir, Muhammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Signal and power integrity have become a dominant performance limiting factor in the designof integrated circuits. This has led to the need for accurate time-domain models for signalinterconnects, power delivery networks, and other passive structures used for signal and powerdelivery. Such models are difficult to obtain using analytical physics based approaches. However,it is possible to characterize such structures by using measurement or full-wave simulationin order to obtain their sampled frequency-domain S - or Y-parameters. The objective of thisthesis is to develop a systematic and automated algorithm for obtaining a time-domain SPICEcompatiblemacromodel from measured or computed frequency-domain S - or Y-parameterdata. In particular, a set of tools based on Loewner Matrix (LM) interpolation are developedfor generating a macromodel, reducing its order and guaranteeing its accuracy and passivity.This is done for both S - and Y-parameter data. In addition, a modeling tool is developed togenerate a parametric macromodel based on LM interpolation. Furthermore, the proposed approachhas the advantage of improving the CPU cost of standard full-wave analysis methodsby taking advantage of the developed interpolation methods.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L’int´egralit´e des signaux et de l’´energie est devenue le principal facteur limite dans la performancede la conception des circuits int´egr´ees. Ceci cr´ea le besoin de mod`eles pr´ecis dans ledomaine du temps pour des interconnectes de signaux, des r´eseaux de distribution d’´energie,et d’autres structures passives utilis´ees pour distribuer les signaux et l’´energie. Ce type demod`ele est difficile `a obtenir avec les approches bas´ees sur la physique analytique. Par contre,il est possible de caract´eriser les structures mentionn´ees en utilisant des simulations demesur ou de Full-Wave (FW) pour obtenir les donn´ees de param`etres-S ou Y du domaine de lafr´equence. L’objective de cette th`ese est de d´evelopper un algorithme syst´ematique et automatis´e qui obtient, en utilisant des donn´ees de param`etres -S ou -Y dans le domaine de fr´equenceen provenance de mesures ou du calcul, un macro-mod`ele dans le domaine du temps qui estcompatible avec SPICE. En particulier, un ensemble d’outils bas´e sur l’interpolation par leLoewner Matrix (LM) est d´evelopp´e pour g´en´erer un macro-mod`ele, r´eduire sa grandeur, et degarantir sa pr´ecision et sa passivit´e. L’ensemble d’outils peut traiter les donn´ees de param`etre-S et -Y. Aussi, un outil de mod´elisation est cr´e´e pour g´en´erer un macro-mod`ele param´etriquebas´e sur l’interpolation LM. De surcroˆıt, l’approche propos´ee a l’avantage d’am´eliorer le coˆuten CPU de la m´ethode d’analyse Full-Wave standard en prenant d’avantage les m´ethodesd’interpolation d´evelopp´ees.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roni Khazaka</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q6735.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h6934</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515q959"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History and Classical Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The business of butchery: Bellona and war, society and religion from republic to empire</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poplacean, Danielle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bellona, déesse de la guerre, animée d'une frénésie sanglante, a joué un rôle intégral dans les combats de la République Romaine. Son temple est devenu, de fait, le lieu de congrès du sénat pour presque toutes les affaires concernant la guerre—traités, triomphes, engagements, l'accueil des ambassadeurs, et même sa déclaration ritualisée. Or, malgré la domination de Bellona dans le cadre de la guerre, il reste qu'aucune œuvre a été consacrée a son étude. Notre connaissance de l'histoire militaire de Rome -- tant les aspects plutôt idéologiques, que révèle l'étude de n'importe quel dieu, tant les réalités matérielles, voire comment une guerre s'est manifestée de son début jusqu'à sa fin—ne peut s'achever sans une connaissance au moins rudimentaire du rôle de Bellona.A mesure que le sujet de Bellona est resté pour la plupart ignoré, ce projet sera nécessairement préliminaire. Cette recherche vise a peindre à grands traits, mais comprenant autant de détail que possible, une image de la vie de Bellona chez les Romains. La programme sera diachronique: on commencera d'un point de départ aussi reculé que nous permettent nos témoignages—c'est a dire d'un temps antérieur au troisième siècle av. J. C—et on avancera jusqu'en plein troisième siècle de notre ère. On suivra le fil de l'évolution de Bellona, de ses origines comme déesse sabine à sa place privilégiée auprès du sénat, et ensuite à son caractère d'une déesse qui s'abime dans la folie, devenant une figure orientale et exotisée en compagnie de Cybele, Attis, et Isis. On vera que des familles particulières—les Claudiens, les Corneliens, et les Juliens—vont jouer des rôles cruciaux dans sa transformation. Bien entendu, ce ne sera pas possible de préciser tous les aspects de Bellona, et il faut encore souligner que cette recherche sert comme premier pas, la base nécessaire de futures études.En gros, ceci est une enquête sur la religion Romaine. Cependant, nous constatons, avec les autres spécialistes de la religion antique, qui en ont fait presqu'une maxime, que nous ne pouvons dégager la religion de la politique, de la société, de l'art, et, plus généralement, de la vie quotidienne de la communauté. Inévitablement, ce qui suit va porter sur d'autres thèmes, à savoir l'histoire militaire de Rome, la politique de la gens chez la République, la topographie et la politique de l'éspace, les mémoires collectifs et individuels, le culte des ancêtres, la religion civique, et l'appropriation des cultes orientaux.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Bellona, blood-frenzied goddess of war, played an integral role in Roman Republican warfare. Hertemple became the de facto meeting place of the Senate for nearly all matters concerning war;treaties, triumphs, engagements, meetings with ambassadors, even its ritualized declaration.Despite Bellona’s dominion over warfare, there has yet to be a single monograph dedicated to herstudy. Our understanding of Roman military history—not only the more ideological aspects as thestudy of any deity reveals, but even the concrete practicalities like how war was actualized fromstart to finish—cannot be complete without at least a basic understanding of Bellona’s role.Because the topic of Bellona has remained largely unexplored in current scholarship, thisproject will necessarily be preliminary. This thesis will paint a large, yet as detailed as possible,image of Bellona’s life at Rome. The approach is diachronic. We begin as far back as our evidenceallows, to somewhere before the 3rd century BC, and move forward into the 3rd century AD. Wetrace Bellona’s evolution from an Italian, Sabine goddess of war and victory, to one closely linkedto the Senate, to a goddess who would descend into madness, becoming an exoticized Easterndivinity in the company of Cybele, Attis and Isis. We will see that individual families—theClaudians, Cornelians, and Julians—will play vital roles in her transition. Naturally, not everyaspect of Bellona can possibly be detailed in the following, and it must be reiterated that this thesisserves as the necessary first step, the much needed foundation, for further study.Broadly speaking, this is a work on Roman religion. However, as has almost become amaxim among scholars of ancient religion, we cannot extricate religion from politics, society, thearts and daily life more generally. The following inevitably touches upon topics like Romanmilitary history, gens based politics in the Roman Republic, topography and the politics of space,collective and individual memory, ancestral worship, civic religion, and the importation of Easterncults.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hans Beck</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd64f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q959</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042w453"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of TMED2 in murine labyrinth layer development and non-alcoholic fatty liver disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hou, Wenyang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>TMED2 fait partie de la famille de protéines TMED (transmembrane emp24 domain).  Celles-ci jouent un rôle dans le transport membranaire ainsi que dans la sécrétion des protéines entre le réticulum endoplasmique (RE) et l’appareil de Golgi. Le gène Tmed2 est exprimé dans les tissus pré-placentaires de la souris, soit l’allantoïde et le chorion.  De plus, une mutation homozygote de Tmed2 (la lignée murine 99J), provoque une fusion anormale de ces deux tissus, empêchant la formation de la région du labyrinthe du placenta.  L’expression des gènes associés à la différenciation des spongiotrophoblastes, Tpbpα, et des syncytiotrophoblastes, Gcm1, est diminuée dans les placenta Tmed299J/99J.  De plus, les embryons mutants Tmed299J/99J meurent à la mi-gestation.  Des données provenant d’hybridation in situ montrent un patron d’expression de Tmed2 tissu et temps spécifique chez l’embryon murin. De manière intéressante, une forte expression de Tmed2 a été observée dans le bourgeon hépatique.    Notre hypothèse est que 1) Tmed2 joue un rôle spécifique dans le chorion, crucial à la fusion chorio-allantoïde et que 2) son inhibition partielle perturbe la fonction hépatique. Pour tester notre première hypothèse, nous avons mis au point un système de culture ex vivo du chorion et de l’allantoïde murin, qui récapitule la formation de la couche placentaire du labyrinthe.  En utilisant des tissus pré-placentaires de la souris mutante Tmed299J/99J ou de type sauvage dans ce système ex vivo, nous avons pu évaluer le rôle de Tmed2 exprimé exclusivement dans le chorion ou l’allantoïde dans la formation de la région du labyrinthe.  Ainsi, nous avons déterminé que Tmed2 est requis dans le chorion pour qu’il y ait un mélange des deux types de tissus.  D’un autre côté, les cellules allantoïdes Tmed299J/99J pouvaient se mélanger aux cellules du chorion de type sauvage mais une diminution de leur prolifération a été observée.  Malgré la mort au stade embryonnaire des souris Tmed299J/99J, les souris hétérozygotes quant à elles sont viables et fertiles.  Des analyses histologiques et moléculaires des foies de souris Tmed299J/+ ont révélées une augmentation de l’incidence de NAFLD (Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease).  De plus, nous avons démontré une diminution significative de l’expression génique et protéique de TMED2 et TMED10, une dilatation de la membrane du réticulum endoplasmique (RE), une augmentation de la phosphorylation d’un marqueur de stress du RE, eIF2, l’activation du UPR (unfolded protein response) et finalement, une augmentation des facteurs de transcription Srebp 1a et 2 (Sterol regulatory element binding protein).  Pris dans leur ensemble, nos travaux mettent de l’avant un nouveau modèle murin pour étudier NAFLD et suggèrent un nouveau rôle de TMED2 dans le fonctionnement hépatique. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>TMED2 belongs to the transmembrane emp24 domain (TMED) protein family, which is the key protein in the early transport of transmembrane and secretory proteins between the Endoplasmic Reticulum (ER) and the Golgi apparatus. Tmed2 was expressed in the allantois and the chorion, two pre-placental tissues, and homozygous mutation of Tmed2 (a 99J mouse line) resulted in abnormal chorioallantoic fusion and failure of placental labyrinth formation. Expression of genes associated with spongiotrophoblast, Tpbpα, and syncytiotrophoblast, Gcm1, differentiation was reduced in Tmed2 null (Tmed299J/99J) placenta, and all Tmed299J/99J embryos died by mid-gestation. In situ hybridization using a Tmed2 probe revealed a tissue and temporal specific pattern of Tmed2 expression in the embryo. Furthermore, Tmed2 was highly expressed in the liver bud at embryonic day (E)9.5.  Thus, we hypothesized that Tmed2 exhibits a tissue-specific role in the chorion for normal chorioallantoic fusion and that disrupted TMED2 levels could result in perturbed function in the liver. We established a novel ex vivo culture model of pre-placental tissues of chorion and allantois, which recapitulated events associated with early placental labyrinth layer development. Then, we investigated the tissue-specific requirement for Tmed2 using this ex vivo model. Recombinants of Tmed299J/99J and wildtype pre-placental tissues suggested that Tmed2 is required in the chorion for mixing of allantoic and chorionic cells. Tmed2 mutant allantoic cells could mix with wild type chorionic cells, but Tmed2 was found to be required in the allantois for proliferation. Although homozygous mutation in Tmed2 led to embryonic lethality, Tmed2 heterozygous mice (Tmed299J/+) were viable and fertile. Histological and molecular analysis using livers from Tmed299J/+ mice revealed a requirement for TMED2 in liver health. We showed that Tmed299J/+mice had decreased levels of TMED2 and TMED10, dilated endoplasmic reticulum membrane, and increased phosphorylation of an ER stress marker, eIF2α, and activation of the Unfolded Protein Response (UPR). Increased expression of sterol regulatory element binding protein (Srebp) 1a and 2 at the newborn stage and increased incidence of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) were also found in Tmed299J/+ mice. Our data established Tmed299J/+ mice as a novel mouse model for NAFLD and suggests a novel role for TMED2 in liver health.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Loydie Majewska</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795b19v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042w453</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93h206h"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of endothelial function in the relationship between depression and cardiovascular disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mercer, Darren</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Depression independently and consistently predicts a doubling of risk for developing cardiovascular disease (CVD) and CVD mortality.  Despite significant research, the identification of pathways explaining this relationship remains challenging.  This thesis explores the role of the endothelium, a layer of cells lining vascular walls that regulate homeostatic functions.  Depressive disorders have previously been associated with impaired endothelial function (EF).  The first study assessed whether this relationship may have an interaction with anxiety, and whether this relationship could be observed with subclinical continuous measures of depressive symptoms.  The second study utilized a structural equation modeling approach to identify mechanisms that may explain the relationship between depression and EF, utilizing a sample of cardiac outpatients.  Two significant pathways, one featuring physiological markers of CVD risk and another including behavioural factors, were identified.  The third study used longitudinal data to determine if EF would mediate a relationship between depression and CVD outcomes over a six-year time period.  EF was found to significantly mediate the relationship between depression and future coronary artery bypass graft surgery, after adjusting for age, sex, and presence of CVD at baseline.  Overall, increasing evidence exists to suggest that endothelial health and associated pathways may link depression to CVD.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La dépression indépendamment et consistante prédit un doublement du risque de développer une maladie cardiovasculaire (MCV) et une mortalité par MCV.  L'identification des parcours expliquant cette relation reste difficile. Cette thèse explore le rôle de l'endothélium, la couche la plus interne des vaisseaux sanguins, qui régulent les fonctions homéostatiques. Des troubles dépressifs ont déjà été associés à une fonction endothéliale (FE) altérée. La première étude a évalué si cette relation peut avoir une interaction avec l'anxiété et si cette relation peut être observée avec des mesures continues sous-cliniques des symptômes dépressifs. La deuxième étude a utilisé la modélisation de l'équation structurale pour identifier les mécanismes qui peuvent expliquer la relation entre la dépression et la FE, en utilisant un échantillon de patients cardiaques. Deux voies significatives, l'une présentant des marqueurs physiologiques du risque MCV et une autre, y compris les facteurs comportementaux, ont été identifiées. La troisième étude a utilisé des données longitudinales pour déterminer si la FE affecterait une relation entre la dépression et les résultats de MCV sur une période de six ans. La FE s'est révélée faire le médiateur significativement la relation entre la dépression et la chirurgie de pontage aorto-coronarien, après ajustement pour l'âge, le sexe et la présence de MCV au départ. Dans l'ensemble, des preuves croissantes existent pour suggérer que la santé endothéliale et les voies associées peuvent relier la dépression à la maladie cardiovasculaire.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Blaine Ditto</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483m63s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h206h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>