<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab2773x190"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Poetics of the body in feminist art : three modalities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baert, Renee</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>My thesis is centered on poetics of the body in contemporary feminist art. Poetics, understood as the languages, materials and forms of composition, underscores the symbolically and socially mediated body so rendered, rather than its biological, anatomical, or otherwise 'natural' definition. A feminist poetics is at once a politics, and a creation, of language. I proceed through a close reading of a number of artworks by Canadian artists. These works 'resist' representation, foregoing a biologically grounded figuration to propose in more allusive terms the psychic and conceptual impulses through which the body is apprehended or might be imagined. Influenced by the writings of Luce Irigaray on the structural isomorphism between logos, the phallus, and a privileged masculine model of subjectivity, the thesis investigates the construction within feminist art of alternative and contestatory poetics of the body potentially productive of other knowledge-effects. Situating my investigation within the context of numerous 'figurations' of the subject that have emerged in recent feminist theory, I propose that feminist art practices provide a corollary contribution, in material form, to the theoretical project of thinking 'difference' beyond dualism. I identify three modalities of practice that 're-make' the body/embodiment vis a vis a 'phallomorphic' model of identity, unity, self-sameness: (a) the body in/of language, as the imbrication of the two identified by Julia Kristeva through the category of the semiotic; (b) morphologies of the body as the imaginary body produced through an interweaving of the body's form, psychic dispensations and social/symbolic inscriptions; (c) constructed spatialities in which the material spaces of exhibition sites become enacted metaphoric spaces, and foreground the potential and import of spatial representations in the production of personal and social experience. I argue that the forms, materialities and spatialities specific to visual art can serve to constitute analogues for the materiality of the body. The thesis considers the artworks as embodiments: at once material, textural and spatial 'bodies' of art. Interdisciplinary in scope, this thesis brings together visual and textual sources drawn from contemporary art and the literatures of feminist (and) poststructuralist theory, cultural studies, postcolonial theory and the field of art history and criticism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ross, Christine</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Straw, Will</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq49m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x190</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Art, Canadian -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women artists -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women in art</dc:subject><dc:subject>Feminism and art -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mk50q"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Clustered time warp and logic simulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Avril, Hervé</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this research, the feasibility of using parallel discrete-event simulation techniques to run logic-level circuit simulations on general purpose distributed memory architectures is investigated. After studying the characteristics of VLSI models, we introduce Clustered Time Warp (CTW), a novel approach to parallel discrete event simulation. In CTW, the logical gates of a circuit are partitioned into clusters and the synchronization algorithm makes use of an optimistic approach between the clusters and a sequential approach within the clusters. We also present a new family of three space-based checkpointing algorithms for use with CTW. Results show that each checkpointing algorithm developed for CTW occupies a different point in the spectrum of possible trade-offs between memory usage and execution time. We also present a dynamic load balancing algorithm developed for Clustered Time Warp which focuses on distributing the load of the simulation evenly among the processors and then tries to reduce inter-processor communications. We make use of a triggering technique based on the throughput of the simulation system. Performance results show that by dynamically balancing the load, the throughput of the simulation system could be improved by more than a 100%. No substantial improvement was observed on the overall simulation time when trying to minimize inter-processor communications, suggesting that load distribution is the most important factor to be taken into consideration in speeding up the simulation of digital circuits. Furthermore, we examine the impact of partitioning and mapping on the performance and behavior of the Clustered Time Warp algorithm. We show that partitioning algorithms which try to minimize the number of cutsets between the partitions do not necessarily succeed in minimizing inter-processor communications. We also show that in our environment, load imbalance has a stronger effect than rollback overhead. Finally, we study the problem of scalability encountered when using optimistic techniques. We show that the performance of Time Warp can greatly suffer from rollback explosions or when the dog chasing its tail phenomenon is observed. We also show that Clustered Time Warp is less sensitive to these phenomenons and as such, is more scalable than Time Warp.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tropper, Carl</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg43z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk50q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3r074w74f"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Occupational Health</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Measurement of ventilation efficiency for indoor air quality in office buildings using carbon dioxide as a tracer gas</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Auger, Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The work describes the results obtained following the development and testing of a new device used to measure ventilation efficiency for indoor air quality (IAQ) in office buildings. The method uses concentration data obtained by the repeated injection of CO$ sb2$, used as a tracer gas simulating human respiration. The device measures the efficiency of the ventilation in reducing and evacuating pollutants. Ventilation efficiency was measured in a test chamber and was demonstrated in an office building. The method was tested to determine if it responded well to the effect of air flows, air velocities, air temperatures, number of diffusers and room temperatures. Results compared well with the theoretical predictions obtained from a two-chamber compartment model and could be predicted using simple regression models (r = 0.85). The work concludes that the new method can be used to measure ventilation efficiency and a chart is proposed for using the method with respect to recommended outdoor air flow rates in an office.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Farant, Jean Pierre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qd69q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074w74f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bn24v"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Testosterone regulation of stress-related hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal activity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Viau, Victor</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Most studies examining hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) function, have been performed in the male as this gender is believed to represent a comparatively stable gonadal environment. However, gonadal activity in the male is subject to variation, as evidenced by marked changes in testosterone (T) release as a function of social and reproductive status and in response to stress. In the studies reported here we have examined the extent to which variations in circulating T levels could influence the magnitude of the adrenocorticotropin (ACTH) and corticosterone (B) response to stress. Significantly lower peak ACTH and B responses to 10 min of restraint stress were found in intact animals with high basal levels of T (4.0 $ pm$ 0.6 ng/ml) compared to animals with low levels of T (1.2 $ pm$ 0.3). No differences were found in prestress, basal levels of ACTH and B as a function of T. To assess the importance of these naturally occurring variations in T levels on HPA activity, animals were gonadectomized (GDX) and replaced with subcutaneous steroid implants supplying physiological levels of T (1 to 5 ng/ml). Significantly lower ACTH and B responses to restraint stress were observed in high (5.1 $ pm$ 0.6 ng/ml) compared to low (1.7 $ pm$ 0.3 ng/ml) T-replaced animals. Plasma and intra-pituitary CBG levels were also reduced in GDX animals replaced with high T levels. Although T had no effect on median eminence CRH levels, arginine vasopressin (AVP) content was significantly lower in GDX animals replaced with elevated T levels. A strong negative correlation (r = $-$0.9) was found between pre-stress levels of T and AVP content in the median eminence. We then characterized corticosteroid receptor binding as a function of circulating T levels. The results revealed a dose-dependent relationship between plasma T levels and glucocorticoid type II binding that was apparent only in the medial preoptic area (MPOA) of the brain. No differences were found in GC type I receptor binding in the brain, pituitary, and liver as a function of T replacement. Glucocorticoid type II binding was significantly higher in the MPOA of the brain and liver in high T-replaced animals. Implants of crystalline B or T into the MPOA caused a significant decrease in ACTH and B responses to restraint. These implants also caused a decrease in median eminence AVP content, but not CRH. Lesions of the MPOA blocked the inhibitory effects of high peripheral T levels on ACTH responses to stress. Taken together, these results suggest that individual differences among male rats in circulating levels ofT have substantial effects on stress-related HPA activity. These effects may be related to the ability ofT to regulate the
efficacy of glucocorticoid negative-feedback regulation ofHPA activity at the level of the
MPOA.
</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Meany, M. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hd71h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn24v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537264r"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Array processing for detection and localization of narrowband,wideband and distributed sources</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Valaee, Shahrokh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The detection and estimation techniques that are used in array processing depend on the spatial and temporal characteristics of the signals that arrive at the array. In this dissertation, we consider narrowband as well as wideband signals. For narrowband signals, a detection method based on the predictive stochastic complexity (PSC) is developed. The PSC of data is computed for all the models with order smaller than the number of sensors. The number of signals is selected by choosing the minimum of the PSC over all models. The PSC criterion is on-line and can be used for time varying systems and target tracking. We also consider wideband signals. One approach to wideband array processing is based on sampling the spectrum of the source signals to generate narrowband signals. Then, using a focusing approach, the information at different frequency bins are combined. Here, an optimal method to select a focusing subspace for the well-known coherent signal-subspace method (CSM) is proposed. It is also shown that with the CSM method unbiased estimation of the directions-of-arrival (DOAs) is not possible. Inspired by the CSM algorithm, a new method for wideband array processing is developed which is based on two-sided transformation of the correlation matrices (TCT). The TCT estimator can generate unbiased estimates of the DOAs and has a lower resolution threshold than the CSM algorithm. In array processing it is frequently assumed that the signals are generated by point sources. This is an assumption which is not satisfied in reality. In this dissertation, a method is developed for localization of spatially distributed sources. The method is based on generalization of the MUSIC algorithm and is applied to coherent and incoherent distribution of sources.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kabal, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p1832.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537264r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f275s"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Subirrigation of maize using saline-sodic water</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hoyningen Huene, Bernhard von</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A field subirrigation experiment, using saline-sodic water, was carried out on a loamy sand soil in southwestern Quebec. The experimental field was divided into 16 plots with 4 treatments; saline-sodic water, "fresh" water, controlled drainage and non-irrigated. Each treatment had four replicates. Maize yield, hydraulic conductivity, salt concentration, and salt movement through the soil were recorded in all plots. No significant difference in maize yield occurred between plots irrigated with saline-sodic or fresh water in any of the three years. Irrigated maize plots yielded approximately 30% more than non-irrigated plots. Hydraulic conductivity reductions in the saline plots were noted in May 1986, after the first snowmelt. From statistical analysis carried out, it appears that the saline-sodic water had an effect on hydraulic conductivity, significant at the 0.05 level. From the measurements taken from piezometer stations, located throughout the field, salt concentrations and salt movement through the saturated soil profile were determined. Using salt concentration data from both irrigation water and soil water, an average effective field porosity was calculated with a computer program. The results obtained were within 4% of those obtained in laboratory tests. Moreover, the program was then used to model the salt balance of the soil from May 85 to May 87. Results indicated that most salts were removed with the rainfall and snowmelt of the winter months of 85/86 and 86/87.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Broughton, Robert S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd236.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f275s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sandy soils -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Irrigation -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Saline irrigation -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3j333383t"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the mechanisms of heterogeneous nucleation of grains and pores in aluminum castings</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mohanty, Pravansu Sekhar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the present study, a fundamental theoretical and experimental investigation has been carried out on the mechanisms of heterogeneous nucleation of grains and pores in aluminum castings. A direct addition technique has been developed to introduce known types and quantities of inoculants into liquid aluminum alloys, irrespective of their wettability and chemical reactivity while preserving the surface characteristics and melt chemistry. Many different types of inoculants such as: $ rm Al sb2O sb3$, SiC, MgO, $ rm Mg sb2AlO sb4$, TiB$ sb2$, TiC, SrO and Sr(OH)$ sb2$ have been successfully added into liquid aluminum alloys, yielding single particulate distributions while avoiding incorporation of naturally occuring oxide films. The commercial grain refining practice of Al and its alloys has been experimentally simulated by introducing synthetic TiB$ sb2$ and TiC crystals into melts containing dissolved Ti. Experimental findings indicate that in the absence of dissolved Ti, TiB$ sb2$ crystallites alone do not nucleate $ alpha$-Al. TiC particles which are generally believed to be the nucleating substrate are unstable and form various complex carbides. In the presence of dissolved Ti even below the peritectic level, an interfacial layer of TiAl$ sb3$ is formed at the TiB$ sb2$/melt interface which subsequently nucleates the $ alpha$-Al. A 'duplex' nucleation mechanism is proposed based on the solute segregation phenomenon to the substrate/melt interface. In the case of hypoeutectic Al-Si alloy, this interfacial layer was found to be a ternary compound of Al-Si-Ti, however, a drastic drop in the peritectic solidification temperature presumably reduces its grain refining potency at higher Si content. Particles which do not nucleate the solid phase and/or do not get engulfed by the growing solid, are continuously rejected by the solid/liquid (S/L) interface until the end of local solidification. These substrates act as a barrier to the fluid flow as well as to the diffusion field at the S/L interface, giving rise to enhanced gas segregation and viscous pressure drop. A novel theoretical mechanism for the heterogeneous nucleation of pores has been proposed, based on this behaviour of foreign particles at the advancing S/L interface. Mathematical analyses have been employed to predict the gas segregation and pressure drop in the gap between the particle and the S/L interface. An order of magnitude analysis is done, and it is shown that pressures in the range of the activation barrier can be obtained in normal castings. To substantiate the mechanism further, experimental studies were carried out by introducing various possible inclusions into liquid aluminum. The experimental findings are in line with the theoretical predictions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gruzlaski, J. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698897k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333383t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn107064m"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of macrophage function during intracellular infection with Leishmania donovani</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moore, Kathryn J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Investigation of the molecular alterations of macrophage function during intracellular infection by Leishmania donovani revealed both adverse and positive influences of this protozoan on host cell function. Chapter I delineates a negative effect which this parasite has on signal transduction pathways in its host cell. In macrophages put in contact, or infected with L. donovani, c-fos gene expression mediated through protein kinase A was unaffected under conditions where there was an impairment of protein kinase C-mediated c-fos gene expression. Selective impairment of protein kinase C-, or, calmodulin-dependent protein kinase-mediated signal transduction in the macrophage was found to influence the establishment of infection. Chapters two and three describe a positive enhancement of macrophage function by L. donovani. Intramacrophage infection with L. donovani was shown to enhance host cell viability in the absence of growth factor. This was attributable to the elaboration of a soluble factor(s) by infected macrophages into the cell culture supernatant, which enhanced macrophage viability in a manner independent of cell replication. Further characterization of the mechanism of this enhancement revealed that L. donovani infection, and lipophosphoglycan, inhibited macrophage death by apoptosis. Cell supernatants derived from L. donovani infected cells were also capable of inhibiting macrophage apoptosis. To identify the active factor in infected cell supernatants, the cytokine gene expression profile of L. donovani infected macrophages was delineated and possible candidate cytokines were further investigated. Levels of TNF-$ alpha$ capable of causing an abrogation of apoptosis were found to be produced by infected macrophages. However, antibody neutralization of TNF in infected cell cultures could not reverse the inhibition of apoptosis by L. donovani, implicating the involvement of multiple factors in the abrogation of apoptosis by L. donovani.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Matlashewski, Greg</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn254.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107064m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Leishmaniasis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Macrophages</dc:subject><dc:subject>Leishmania</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qn50m"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vapour phase synthesis of AIN using a transferred arc plasma system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moura, Francisco José</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This work introduces a new concept for the synthesis of ultrafine aluminum nitride powder. A transferred arc plasma torch of 6.5 kW was used as a heat source to vaporize an aluminum ingot as a source of aluminum vapour for the synthesis of aluminum nitride outside the plasma chamber. The aluminum vapour produced in the plasma chamber was carried by the argon plasma gas to a tubular synthesis reactor where it reacted with ammonia injected radially. The effects of arc current, arc length and argon flow rate on the aluminum evaporation rate and the gas temperature reached in the mixing zone were studied. The results show that long arcs, high currents and high argon flow rates were best to maximize the temperature in the mixing zone and short arcs, high current and high argon flow rate were best for high evaporation rates. Experiments were performed to study the effect of arc length, nitriding agent used, ammonia jet momentum, ammonia flow rate, residence time and temperature on the conversion to aluminum nitride. Conversions up to 100% were achieved. The aluminum nitride produced had an average particle size of approximately 20 nm and specific surface area of about 90 m$ sp2$/g. A numerical model, describing the aerosol particle size evolution, developed by Proulx and Bilodeau was successfully applied to the system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Munz, Richard J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg029.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn50m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tn55r"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Male song and sexual selection in the European starling</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mountjoy, Donald James</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The function of the complex song of the European Starling (Sturnus vulgaris) was examined. Song playback experiments showed that both male and female starlings were attracted by song, and complex song inhibited males from entering nestboxes. Wild starlings (at least two years old when first recorded) showed extensive changes in the composition of their song phrase repertoires and most also increased the size of their repertoires, which will result in a correlation between age and repertoire size in this species. Females prefer males that have more complex song, and this preference remained significant when preferences for certain nest sites were controlled. Males with larger repertoires did not spend more time incubating or make more feeding visits to nestlings than did males with smaller repertoires. The evolution of complex song in the European starling is consistent with an age-indicator model of sexual selection, in which aspects of male quality correlated with age are advertised by the complexity of male song.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lemon, R. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375x91w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tn55r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sturnus vulgaris -- Behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Birdsongs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sexual selection in animals</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aff365681s"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Qualitative spatial reasoning with applications to planar mechanism analysis and motion planning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liu, Jiming</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a framework for qualitatively representing and reasoning about spatial configurations in the two-dimensional case. The framework contains interval/region based formalisms for describing distances, angles, and locations. These representations lead to the formulation of inference rules, as well as search-heuristics which enable the derivation of spatial relationships and paths among objects. In order to generate approximate quantitative configurations, local search strategies such as simulated annealing are applied within the configuration space deduced from the qualitative spatial description. The qualitative framework can be used in two principal ways: first, to formulate solutions to spatial configuration problems where exact geometric knowledge is not available, and second, to provide guidance for the application of quantitative configuration analysis and planning methods. These have direct relevance to, and implications for, computer-aided mechanism design and robotics. In this thesis, two applications of this framework are demonstrated. The first application is concerned with inferring the instantaneous configurations, coupler curves, and relative velocities in one-degree-of-freedom planar linkages, given their qualitative link lengths. Based on the qualitative framework, algorithms have been developed and implemented to tackle each aspect of the linkage problem. The simulation results show that the coupler curves derived from the proposed algorithms can correctly capture the significant topological and geometric properties of the actual curves. The second application deals with planning collision-free paths for open-chain planar mechanisms moving among static obstacles. Using the qualitative framework, a quantitative path can be composed by generating and connecting a sequence of path segments based on a global route found in the qualitative spatial planning. This approach to path planning is illustrated in two case studies; one involves a single mobile robot whereas the other considers a serially coupled manipulator.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505202v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365681s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agm80hx03j"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of temperature and pressure on the vibrational spectra of some organometallic and organosilicon ring compounds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Honqi, 1958-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The vibrational spectra (3200-50 cm$ sp{-1}$ region) of the solid, mono- and disubstituted chromium(0) carbonyl complexes, Cr(CO)$ sb5$(CNBu-t) and cis-Cr(CO)$ sb4$(CNBu-t)$ sb2,$ have been recorded at selected temperatures (down to ${ sim}{40}$ K) and pressures (up to ${ sim}{40}$ kbar). The structure of Cr(CO)$ sb5$(CNBu-t) has been determined by X-ray crystallography. The solid-state splittings observed in the spectra of the two complexes are discussed in terms of their known space groups. Pressure-induced, solid-solid phase transitions were detected for both compounds by Raman and IR spectroscopy. From an examination of the pressure dependences of selected vibrational modes, it is concluded that the CNBu-t ligand is a weaker $ pi$-acceptor and stronger $ sigma$-donor than is CO. The effects of low temperatures and high external pressures on the vibrational spectra of ($ rm SiMe sb2) sb6, (SiPh sb2) sb6,$ all-trans-$ rm lbrack Si(H)CH sb2Ph rbrack sb6,$ all-trans-$ rm lbrack Si(H)Ph rbrack sb6,$ (O-$ rm SiMe sb2 rbrack sb{n}$ (n = 3,4), and (N(H)-SiMe$ rm sb2 rbrack sb{n}$ (n = 3,4) have been investigated. These eight cyclic organosilicon compounds are representative examples of polysilanes, polysiloxanes and polysilazanes; the vibrational assignments proposed are based chiefly on the local symmetries of the ring skeletons and the substituent groups attached to the silicon atoms. Substantial evidence has been obtained from these spectroscopic measurements (together with differential scanning calorimetric studies) for ring conformational changes, side-group rotation and solid-solid phase transitions. The possible origin of these solid-state structural changes are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Butler, Ian S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv28p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hx03j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Inorganic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak930bz77n"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional roles of adenosine in synaptic transmission in the hippocampus in vitro</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, He, 1952-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis focuses on the functional roles of adenosine on neuronal excitability and synaptic transmission in the rat hippocampal CA1 region in vitro. Hippocampal slices were placed in an interface recording chamber and constantly superfused with oxygenated artificial cerebral fluid at $30 sp circ$C. Intracellular (current-clamp) recording techniques were used to measure the spontaneous and evoked inhibitory and excitatory synaptic potentials as well as resting membrane potential and input resistance. Our findings indicate that adenosine induces the opening of potassium channels in the postsynaptic membrane of CA1 neurones, including $ rm K sb{ATP}$ channels. Adenosine-induced attenuation of EPSPs and poly-synaptic IPSPs may be due to the activation of adenosine $ rm A sb1$ receptors at both the pre- and postsynaptic sites of excitatory synapses onto the pyramidal cells and interneurones. On interneurones, adenosine appears to have two different effects: one is a hyperpolarization and decrease in input resistance, similar to the inhibitory effect on pyramidal cells, and the other is a depression of the amplitude and duration of afterhyperpolarization which characterizes the action potential of these interneurones. A scheme is proposed in which adenosine $ rm A sb1$ receptors may be present at pre- and postsynaptic sites of excitatory synapses but not at presynaptic sites of inhibitory synapses. Adenosine was also found to tonically inhibit spikes associated with NMDA receptor activation and that at least some of these NMDA receptors may be present in the dendritic trees of the pyramidal cells. The slow excitatory effects of adenosine may be due to activation of adenosine $ rm A sb2$ receptors at both pre- and postsynaptic sites in the hippocampal CA1 region. The inhibitory and excitatory effects of adenosine on CA1 pyramidal cells and inhibitory effects of adenosine on interneurones suggest that adenosine may be a homeostatic neuromodulator regulating neuronal excitability and synaptic transmission in the hippocampus in mammalian brain.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f748c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bz77n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bg576"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>DNA organization and replication in the cell cycle of mouse duodenal crypt cells as revealed by the osmium-ammine technique, Bromodeoxyuridine immunogold labeling and radioautography</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liu, Dong Feng</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>DNA has been visualized at high magnification in nuclei and mitochondria by the osmium-ammine technique. Newly-synthesized DNA has been localized by combining this technique with bromodeoxyuridine immunogold labeling. In mitochondria, DNA forms nucleosome-free filaments. In non-proliferating cells, nuclear DNA is visualized as nucleosomes forming nucleofilaments, which are either dispersed throughout the nucleoplasm or compacted into heterochromatin. In proliferating cells, changes in the nuclear DNA make it possible to divide their cycle into eleven stages. During the first stage, the DNA mainly consists of dispersed nucleofilaments as in non-proliferating cells. In stages II-V, nucleofilaments are packaged into larger and larger clusters. At prometaphase (early stage VI) the clusters coalesce to form metaphase chromosomes. Bromodeoxyuridine labeling demonstrates that the S-phase takes place from mid-stage I to mid-stage IV. The DNA synthesis is localized to dispersed nucleofilaments in early S and to nucleofilaments extending out of the clusters in late S. Within an hour in either case, the labeled nucleofilaments are incorporated into a nearby cluster. In conclusion, chromosome formation occurs in two steps: a slow packaging of nucleofilaments into clusters followed by a rapid coalescence of the clusters into chromosomes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leblond, C. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v675.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bg576</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655j13m"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Toward discrete geometric models for early vision</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Iverson, Lee A. (Lee Allan)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Early vision is usually considered to involve the description of geometric structure in an image or sequence of images. Whether biological or artificial, the behavioural constraints on real-time visual systems typically require that this first stage of visual processing be fast, reliable, general and automatic. The design of a visual system which is general enough to handle a wide variety of tasks is thus most likely to be highly parallel, and involve distributed representations of geometric objects. In this work, we investigate some of these general principles and propose both general methodology and specific applications. We build on a general theory of distributed, local representations which we call thick traces. Thick trace descriptions of continuous graphs preserve topological properties such as connectivity, and allow for the descriptions of multi-valued mappings. Local operators for extracting image curves have been a focus of machine vision research for twenty years. Considered in the context of thick traces, however, we can reassess the goals of these operators and provide a clear description of when they should respond positively and when they should not. In order to achieve this behaviour, we develop an algebra, the Logical/Linear algebra, which incorporates features of both Boolean and linear algebra into a set of non-linear combinators. This algebra is then used to design a family of local operators which explicitly test the logical preconditions underlying the definition of an image curve. Relaxation labelling is a highly parallel, distributed method of extracting consistent structures from a set of labels. There is a natural match between the representations used in relaxation labelling and thick traces. We exploit this connection by developing a general method for relaxing a set of potentially noisy initial estimates of thick traces (as produced by image operators) into descriptions which are thick traces of geometric models. Furthermore we show how such a system can interpolate into gaps in the traces while simultaneously respecting legitimate discontinuities and boundaries. Finally, we apply these methods to two problems in early vision: the description of curves and texture flow fields. For image curves, the resulting descriptions of piecewise smooth curves include both local orientation and curvature information. The entire process accurately describes end-points, corners, junctions and bifurcations by allowing many consistent traces to be incident on a single point in the image. The term texture flow is used to describe a class of static textures with locally parallel dense orientation structure (e.g. Glass or hair patterns). We derive a geometric model of these textures from a smooth non-deforming velocity field. Initial operators and a relaxation network are then defined to interpolate dense, piecewise smooth flow from sparse inputs. The resulting system produces accurate descriptions even in the presence of discontinuities, holes, and overlapping textures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zucker, Steven W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tn579.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655j13m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bn27p"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Numerical solution of reacting laminar flow heat and mass transfer in ducts of arbitrary cross-sections for power-law fluids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Isazadeh, Mohammad Ali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study is concerned with the numerical analysis, formulation, programming and computation of solution of steady, 3D conservation equations of reacting laminar duct flow heat and mass transfer in ducts of arbitrary cross-sections. The non-orthogonal boundary-fitted coordinate transformation method is applied to the Cartesian form of overall-continuity, momenta, energy and species-continuity equations, parabolized in the axial direction. The boundary conditions are also transformed accordingly. In the mathematical modelling of the system under consideration, variable physical and transport properties of fluid, viscous heat-dissipation and buoyancy effects are also considered. The non-Newtonian power-law constitutive equation is employed to express the rheology of the purely viscous fluid considered. Applying a novel feature of the solution procedure, the contravariant velocity components are introduced into the transformed equations while the physical Cartesian velocity components are retained as dependent variables of the velocity field in the equations. This approach greatly simplifies the subsequent finite-difference formulation of the transformed equations. The latter equations are discretized by the control-volume finite-difference method in which a suitably-adopted staggered grid is employed using Patankar's B-type arrangement in the transformed plane. For discretization, the transformed equations are integrated over 3D control-volumes, followed by differencing the convective and diffusive terms employing upwind and central-difference schemes respectively. A modified version of the SIMPLER algorithm is introduced in the solution procedure and a line-by-line TDMA algorithm is employed for the solution of the discretization equations. A computer-programme is developed for the generation of non-orthogonal grids corresponding to the B-type arrangement in the transformed plane. A general computer programme in Fortran is developed in this study for the solution of flow, heat and mass transfer problems for laminar reacting fluids in straight ducts of arbitrary cross-sections for Newtonian and purely viscous non-Newtonian fluids. The model and computer codes are validated by theoretical, experimental and numerical results from various sources. The computer programmes are employed for studies in the analysis of hydrodynamics and heat transfer in the thermal entrance regions of ducts of arbitrary cross-sections for Newtonian and non-Newtonian fluids. Relevant results are documented for triangular, trapezoidal and pentagonal ducts. The computer programmes are ultimately employed for simulation of the production of polystyrene in arbitrary cross-sectional duct reactors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mujumdar, A. S.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hasan, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dt58b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn27p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75df03t"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Systematics and biogeography of eastern Caribbean frogs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaiser, Hinrich</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines the systematics and biogeography of frogs in the Eastern Caribbean, a biogeographical province consisting of the Lesser Antilles, Trinidad, and Tobago. A comprehensive collection of specimens was subjected to an analysis incorporating morphometric, osteological, and biochemical approaches. An investigation of $ alpha$-level taxonomy revealed the presence of four additional taxa: Colostethus chalcopis sp. nov. on Martinique, Eleutherodactylus amplinympha sp. nov. on Dominica, E. euphronides comb. nov. on Grenada, and E. shrevei comb. nov. on St. Vincent. Based on species distributions and detailed analyses of the largely congruent data sets, Eastern Caribbean frogs can be grouped into two major categories, those originating with South American stock and those of Greater Antillean ancestry. A South American origin is obvious for species which have no congeneric relatives in the Greater Antilles, e.g. C. chalcopis, Leptodactylus fallax, L. wagneri. Among the Eleutherodactylus species, northern Eastern Caribbean taxa form a monophyletic group within the E. auriculatus species group; the topology of relationships is ((E. barlagnei, E. pinchoni) ((E. amplinympha, E. martinicensis) E. johnstonei)). The southern Eastern Caribbean species may or may not form a monophyletic group, but E. euphronides and E. shrevei are sister taxa. The topology for these species is (E. urichi (E. terraebolivaris (E. euphronides, E. shrevei))). Thus, the Eastern Caribbean forms a biogeographic link between the large South American and Greater Antillean radiations of Eleutherodactylus; Eleutherodactylus is the only truly circum-Caribbean frog genus. Furthermore, historical evidence shows that the patchy, Caribbean-wide distribution of E. johnstonei is the direct result of accidental introduction mitigated by humans during the past three centuries.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Green, David M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qr13v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df03t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Eleutherodactylus -- Antilles, Lesser -- Geographical distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Eleutherodactylus -- Antilles, Lesser -- Classification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Eleutherodactylus -- Trinidad and Tobago -- Geographical distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Eleutherodactylus -- Trinidad and Tobago -- Classification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Colostethus -- Martinique</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j267j"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Learnability and the lexicon in second language acquisition : Chinese learners' acquisition of English argument structure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Juffs, Alan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates the knowledge of semantics-syntax correspondences in second language acquisition (SLA) within the Principles and Parameters framework. A parameter of semantic structure is proposed to account for crosslinguistic syntactic differences between two previously unrelated, and superficially distinct, verb classes: change of state locatives and 'psychological' verbs. Chinese and English contrast in terms of the parameter setting. Experimental evidence indicates that adult Chinese learners of English L2 initially transfer parameter settings, but are able to reset the proposed parameter. However, they only acquire L2 lexical properties and concomitant syntactic privileges with ease when L2 input adds a representation to their grammar. When positive L2 input should pre-empt overgeneralizations based on representation transferred from the L1, it is shown that L1 influence may persist until quite advanced stages of acquisition. The implications of the results are discussed for the parameter setting model of SLA.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>White, Lydia</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wh53t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j267j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Chinese speakers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Semantics, Comparative</dc:subject><dc:subject>Second language acquisition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Principles and parameters (Linguistics)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language transfer (Language learning)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak930bz80z"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spontaneous mutations in a chromosomally-located HSV-1 thymidine kinase gene</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brisebois, Josée J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Spontaneous mutations occur in all genomes as the result of normal cellular mechanisms and interactions with the environment. In addition to their important contribution to genetic diversity and evolution, spontaneous mutations are associated with several genetic disorders and certain cancers. Spontaneous mutational events comprise an impressive heterogeneity of DNA alterations which can be categorized into two major classes: "moderate" and "potent" mutations. Spontaneous moderate mutations are defined here as comprising mutations with a subtle (i.e. leaky, reversible) effect on the encoded phenotype of a gene. In contrast, potent mutations can severely and permanently alter a gene's phenotype and may result in more important DNA alterations. The selective enrichment for the isolation and characterization of potent mutations can be hindered by the frequent occurrence of more moderate mutations. A selection procedure was thus developed to enrich for spontaneous potent mutations in the KT cell line, comprising a chromosomally-integrated, single-copy plasmid pSV2neoKT, which contains the $neo sp{ rm R}$ and the HSV-1 thymidine kinase (tk) genes. Spontaneous $tk sp-$ mutants were selected on the basis of their resistance to nucleoside analogues (acyclovir (ACV), trifluorothymidine (TFT), and ganciclovir (DHPG)). In order to enrich for potent mutations bearing severe consequences for the function of the tk gene, over the "background" of more simple moderate mutations, an enrichment procedure was established and verified. Combinations of nucleoside analogues reduced the apparent mutation frequency in the tk gene and allowed the enrichment for potent mutations with a severe impact on the TK phenotype. The different potencies of the compounds and their potential synergisms during the selection for $tk sp-$ mutants is also discussed. Mutants resistant to ACV + TFT + DHPG demonstrated a stable TK$ sp-$ phenotype, as they did not revert to wild type at a detectable frequency, and the severe effect on gene function was exemplified by the absence of a TK protein, discernible by Western blotting, in $&gt;$85% of these multiple drug resistant mutants. In contrast, the moderate $tk sp-$ mutants resistant to TFT only, demonstrated phenotype reversal at a high frequency and a detectable TK polypeptide. Between 14.5% and 25% of the potent $tk sp-$ mutants resistant to combinations of drugs underwent a major DNA alteration, consisting mostly of partial, or complete, deletions of the tk gene. Complex rearrangements of the tk gene were also obtained, and an intragenic deletion/duplication event is presented and characterized. However, it was observed that more than 75% of the spontaneous potent mutational events implicated less than 5 bp of the tk gene, yet presented a null phenotype of stable complete alteration of the TK phenotype. The level of mutated tk transcripts was affected in 64% to 70% of the small potent $tk sp-$ mutants, as demonstrated by Northern blotting. Extensive DNA methylation and multidrug resistance (MDR) seemed not to be implicated in the generation of the TK$ sp-$ phenotype observed in the small potent $tk sp-$ mutants. Thus, the KT cell line, combined with the use of multiple nucleoside analogues, allows the enrichment for, and the characterization of, potent (and infrequent) spontaneous mutations in a human chromosomal context. The mutational events characterized in this study may then reflect the diversity, the complexity, and the dynamics of the human genome.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd073.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bz80z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajd472z02f"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Centre for Medical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reasoning about therapeutic and patient management plans in respiratory medicine by physicians &amp; medical students</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chaturvedi, Rakesh K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Recently, there has been extensive research in the area of diagnostic expertise. The model of diagnostic reasoning and clinical expertise has been well documented (Patel et al., in press). This study attempts to extend this research in order to include therapeutic reasoning. Using the expert-novice paradigm, this study attempts to investigate the use of knowledge, specifically, both biomedical and clinical sciences, and the directionality of reasoning during decision making about patient management and therapeutic planning in respiratory medicine. Subjects at four levels of expertise were given two clinical problems with the diagnosis and asked (a) to provide therapeutic plans, and (b) describe the underlying pathophysiological explanations of the diseases. Think-aloud protocols were audio-taped and analyzed using methods of protocol analysis. The results showed that the use of basic medical sciences increased as a function of expertise in the procedure-oriented decision-making tasks. The novices generated rule-based prototypical textbook descriptions based on the clinical information, and the diagnosis given in the task. In contrast, the experts' therapeutic responses showed a predominance of causal-level inferences, reflecting more backward-directed inferences than novices. Although both the novices and experts generated forward-directed inferences, the novices were unable to provide accurate and adequate explanations for their decisions. Finally, the pathophysiological explanations of the disease were generated from a different knowledge source than that used to develop therapeutic decisions. The implications of these findings for development of theory of expertise and for education in the medical domain are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Patel, Vimla L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375x94q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z02f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Respiratory organs -- Diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Therapeutics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diagnosis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atd96k417b"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Improved learning strategies for small vocabulary automatic speech recognition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cardin, Régis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There are basically three areas which can be explored to improve an HMM based recognizer, namely, parameter extraction, training methods and vocabulary representation. The goal of parameter extraction is not only to find a compact and robust parametric representation of the speech signal, but also to find one which allows the HMMs to obtain the best possible recognition performance. Historically, improvements at this level have usually been obtained on a trial and error basis, using as much knowledge as possible about both the speech production and speech perception mechanisms. That is, the acoustic parameter extraction module has always been viewed as a separate module from the HMMs. This thesis will explore the concept of performing parameter extraction with a connectionist model, whose parameters can be learned from training data. Two HMM training techniques are used in this thesis, namely MLE and MMIE. Parameter initialization, of critical importance for both, will be investigated for discrete, semi-continuous and continuous HMMs. Training processes involving a combination of MLE and MMIE training are studied. Other issues such as codebook exponents and the use of pause and silence models will also be explored. Even if the vocabulary contains only 11 words, its representation is a very important issue. The effects of vocabulary representation with phoneme based, word based (with no sharing) and inter-word models will be experimentally evaluated. It will be shown how a word error rate of 0.23% and a string error rate of 0.68% can be achieved on the TIDIGITS corpus--a performance rivalling the best results ever reported by any group of researchers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>De Mori, Renato</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn80k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k417b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Artificial Intelligence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q557k"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sociology of popular drama in medieval egypt : Ibn Dāniyāl and his shadow plays</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Buturović, Amila, 1963-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis discusses the shadow play in mediaeval Arabo-Islamic societies, and the most outstanding playwright in that genre, Ibn Daniyal (d.710/1310). Despite the lack of other extant plays, it is shown that the shadow play had a long and dynamic tradition in mediaeval Islam, as attested to by various written sources that refer to it through two 'frames' of perception: as allegory and as theatre. These two frames indicate that there is a close link between the intrinsic development of this theatrical genre and the coinage of allegorical expressions geared to the understanding of the cosmological order. The principal features of the shadow theatre are analyzed in the light of theatrical semiotics, focusing on Ibn Daniyal's trilogy Kitab Tayf al-khayal. It is argued that Ibn Daniyal's dramaturgy, emphasizing a collective social experience, relies strongly on the peculiarities of the genre in the process of foregrounding the playwright's ideological concerns. Ibn Daniyal's possible worlds, seeking to harmonize the contending ideologies of Mamluk society, are familiar yet saliently delimited, as the theatrical frame through which they are induced is consciously highlighted.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boullata, Issa J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df043.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q557k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ibn Dānīyāl, Muḥammad, 1249 or 50-1310 or 11 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000163g"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Surface properties of some diblock copolymers adsorbed onto solid substrates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bossé, Francis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Surface and interaction characteristics of poly(styrene-b-4vinylpyridine) (S-4VP) and poly(styrene-b-methacrylic acid) (S-MAA) diblock copolymers were investigated by the method of inverse gas chromatography (IGC). Not surprisingly, the MAA segments were found to be acidic, while the polystyrene (PS) and the 4VP blocks were found to be basic, the 4VP moiety being the stronger base. For the S-4VP diblocks, when adsorbed onto particulates with acidic surfaces, the 4VP block is preferentially oriented to the substrate, leaving an air interphase which is enriched in PS. For the S-MAA diblock, at higher interphase thicknesses, the bulk and surface compositions became similar, and the interphases are non-isotropic with respect to local composition, and molecular conformation. For both diblocks, it was shown that the adsorbed layers form interphases in which the local composition varies with the adsorbed mass and the composition of the copolymer diblock. The effect was more pronounced when the strength of the acid/base interactions at the interface was increased. The experimental finding also permits the calculation of thicknesses for the adsorbed interphases (100-1000 A). Proton nuclear magnetic resonance was used to determine the quantities of S-4VP diblocks in solution. In a selective solvent (toluene), it was found that surface interactions lead to preferential adsorption of the 4VP chain segments onto the particulates. Isotherms show that there is a direct correlation between the normalized equilibrium quantities of adsorbed copolymer diblocks and the length of the 4VP anchor. A linear relationship also was obtained between the equilibrium quantities per unit area of substrate, and the acid/base properties of the particulates. Using a published scaling model, good agreement was found between the experimental and predicted equilibrium quantities of adsorbed material. For these systems, it was demonstrated that the prefactor of the scaling law relation was directly related to the acid/base properties of the substrate, as expressed by the values of the acid/base surface indices obtained by IGC. Composites based on PS and polychloroethylene were analyzed by dynamic mechanical thermal analysis and differential scanning calorimetry methods. The composites were formulated with four loading levels (2, 5, 20 and 35 wt %) of uncoated and coated (S-4VP modified) particulates. A chain overlap region at the boundary of the particulate was determined. The extent of this region was found to increase in parallel with the PS diblock segments, and with favorable acid/base interactions between the composite constituents.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eisenberg, Adi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wr76g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000163g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ans0647405"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Growth, development and mortality in metazoan early life histories with particular reference to marine flatfish</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bertram, Douglas F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Patterns of variability in growth, development and mortality in early life histories were examined at two levels--general and specific. At the general level, I examined the functional significance of larvae in metazoan life cycles. This was achieved by surveying the metazoa at the class level and categorizing mode of development by habitat. Three long-standing hypotheses for the paucity of larval development in fresh water were rejected. I argue that viewing metazoan larvae as a means for feeding and growth provides a unifying framework for evaluating the features of habitats which correlate with the range of variation expressed in development modes. I offer a modelling framework to investigate variation in developmental modes within and between habitats. The suggested model requires input on larval growth rates, larval period duration (development time), and size-specific mortality rates. These variables, and the interactions between them, are also central to the specific analysis which addresses the ecological processes and mechanisms which affect survival and hence recruitment during the early life histories periods of marine fishes. Winter flounder (Pleuronectes americanus) was used as a model species to investigate phenotypic variability in patterns of growth and development and their survival consequences. Using laboratory-reared fish, I demonstrate that size-at-age does not diverge continuously during the larval and juvenile periods. The results show that fish which grow slowly as larvae, compensate for their slow growth by growing rapidly as juveniles. This compensation in growth rate causes juvenile size-at-age to converge, or at least, prevents divergence in juvenile size-at-age. In addition, I provide some of the first estimates of individual variability in larval growth trajectories for a marine fish. I conducted the first experiment which separates the effects of both size and age on the vulnerability to predation in recently metamorphosed fishes. Th</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leggett, W. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z694g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns0647405</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Metazoa -- Larvae</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pleuronectes -- Growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pleuronectes -- Larvae</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gf58m"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The international politics of ethnic conflict : the interstate dimensions of secession and irredenta in the twentieth century, a crisis-based approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carment, David, 1959-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the most challenging issues for students of international relations is the interstate dimension of ethnic conflict in both its secessionist and irredentist forms. This thesis contributes to an understanding of the interstate dimension of ethnic conflict in three ways. First, the thesis provides a more precise delineation of the causal relationship between ethnic and interstate conflict. Second, the thesis develops a model to identify the conditions under which ethnic conflict is most likely to lead to interstate conflict. Third, and finally this thesis provides insight into a theory and policy for management and resolution of ethnic conflict. The results of this research are used to identify the international conditions and actions that affect the dynamics and resolution of ethnic conflict. From that perspective, the central goal of this inquiry is to lay the groundwork for preventive peacekeeping. The inquiry unfolds in five stages. First, a formal model, specifying the precise causal relationship of the selected variables and their interaction effects, is presented. Second, two cases (Somali irredentism and the Indo-Sri Lankan crisis) are used to test the assumed linkage. Third, aggregate data from the International Crisis Behavior Project data base, for the period 1918-1988, are used to test the explanatory power of variables derived from the combined framework. Fourth, two additional cases (Thai Malay separatism and the Balkans War) are used to test the most relevant propositions from the previous phase. Fifth and finally, based on the degree of support for propositions from both quantitative and qualitative analysis, the model is refined. Policy relevant and theoretical contributions are presented in the light of the findings. Directions for further research also are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brecher, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pv14k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gf58m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Irredentism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Secession</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ethnic relations -- Political aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>