<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A79408025h"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Johann Bernhard Fischer von Erlach and political rhetoric under Karl VI (1712-1722)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brillant, Louis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The late imperial architecture of Johann Bernhard Fischer von Erlach presents works (Entwurf einer historischen Architektur, Karlskirche and Hofbibliothek; 1712-1722) in which the intentions manifested are expressions of the political programs of the emperor Karl VI. In this imperial rhetoric, the accent is placed on the confirmation, through time, of the authority. Allegory appears as confirmation, through time, of the authority. Allegory appears as a proper means to convey the public manifestations of this propaganda. Whether at an urban scale, with Karlskirche, or at a more private, smaller scale, as in the Entwurf, Fischer is shown to master the integration of these programs, while maintaining a genuine interest in architectural tradition's history. In fact, the articulation of these two domains will lead to the production of a highly original architecture, which still fascinates today. Three aspects will be especially developed: the initiation of Karlskirche; the imperial promenade through the Hofbibliothek; and the fifth book of the Entwurf, on monumental vases and urns. Through these, it is the importance of constructed-ness, as seen in Fischer's praxis of history, that will emerge.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tf15c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79408025h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fischer von Erlach, Johann Bernhard, 1656-1723. Entwürf einer historischen Architektur</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fischer von Erlach, Johann Bernhard, 1656-1723 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82k932n"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The development of the picturesque and the Knight-Price-Repton controversy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dyck, Dorothy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In recent years the history of the garden has enjoyed increased attention within scholarly circles. Of particular interest is the history of the formation of the Picturesque garden. The ideas of three men, Richard Payne Knight, Uvedale Price, and Humphry Repton, are central to the evolution of Picturesque theory as related to the garden. The conflict among them has become known as the Picturesque Controversy. Due to misguided interpretations by modern scholars, however, the essence of the dispute has been obscured. Through a discussion of the development of Picturesque theory and a comparison of the actual points of difference between the above mentioned theorists, this paper proposes to expose the essential elements of the debate. It also demonstrates that, while all three participants are attempting to reach beyond the practices of their own century, it is Humphry Repton who distinguishes himself as the true herald of modern society and its attitude toward the garden.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204131h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k932n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Price, Uvedale, Sir, 1747-1829</dc:subject><dc:subject>Picturesque, The</dc:subject><dc:subject>Landscape gardening</dc:subject><dc:subject>Knight, Richard Payne, 1750-1824</dc:subject><dc:subject>Repton, Humphry, 1752-1818</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn999873j"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A woman's place : gender and class in Manet's Paris</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Patten, James</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Edouard Manet's paintings of working-class women reflect the dramatic social changes which occurred in Paris during the late nineteenth century. This thesis examines Manet's paintings which represent some of the sites of femininity within modern Paris: the home and garden, the prostitute's bedroom, and the new public sphere of the boulevards and cafes. With references to contemporary writings and social histories, the result of this study is a more profound understanding of how Modernism affected women's lives and the way in which they were represented in art.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr721.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999873j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women in art</dc:subject><dc:subject>Manet, Edouard, 1832-1883</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m616s"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The history and exegesis of pop : reading "All summer long"</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Keightley, Keir</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study of popular music has experienced an astonishing growth in the past two and a half decades; however, the detailed analysis of musical texts has lagged far behind other areas, such as the sociology of the youth audience and analysis of the visual components of music video. This thesis undertakes a survey of recent approaches to popular music at the textual level, before examining the construction of an individual song, the Beach Boys' 1964 recording of "All Summer Long". While many parameters affecting the creation of the cultural significance of the text in question are discussed, ultimately the exegesis serves to problematize larger issues in scholarly work on popular music, particularly the dominance of the paradigms of rupture, rebellion, and authenticity in relation to the historiography and criticism of the formation known as "rock".</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qr69q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m616s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Popular music -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Beach Boys</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A765373169"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Leopold and Loeb : texts and contexts of an American cause célèbre</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Potter, Holly</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis situates the famous Leopold and Loeb case within the context of social discourse about the criminal. I will argue that this case played an important role in mediating social attitudes towards criminality at two moments in American history: first, in the 1920s, when defense attorney Clarence Darrow used the Leopold and Loeb trial to challenge traditional assumptions about innate criminality and the existence of a criminal type; and later, in the post World War Two epoch, when concern with various forms of "deviant" behaviour intensified. This analysis of one particular criminal case and its manifold repercussions might also prove useful for opening similar inquiries into other causes celebres.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qf12s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765373169</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Leopold, Nathan Freudenthal, 1904 or 5-1971</dc:subject><dc:subject>Criminal justice, Administration of -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Loeb, Richard A., 1905 or 6-1936</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2227ms007"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some rhythmic theories compared and applied in an analysis of El decameron negro by Leo Brouwer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Crago, Bartholomew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the first section of this thesis rhythmic theories of Leonard Meyer and Grosvenor Cooper, Wallace Berry, William Benjamin, Joel Lester, Fred Lerdahl and Ray Jackendoff, and Jonathan Kramer are discussed. Each theortician's treatment of meter and grouping is compared. The appropriateness of each theory as an analytic tool for the analysis of El Decameron Negro by Leo Brouwer is evaluated. The analysis itself concerns a section of music in which written meter changes at almost every barline. Within the measures binary and ternary rhythmic groups occur in the context of a continuous pulse. The analysis explicates the metric organization of the section. Suggestions are given for a performance which will project the underlying organization of the section of music.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j917.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227ms007</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Brouwer, Leo, 1939- Decamerón negro</dc:subject><dc:subject>Musical meter and rhythm</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52jb05c"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Religion and Philosophy in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>John Dewey, Rudolf Laban and the development of American movement education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Penny, William, 1947-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the influence the educational theories of John Dewey have had on the development of modern movement education in American schools. It does this in three parts. Firstly through an examination of the educational writings of John Dewey within the general context of his philosophical writings and as they are directly related to pedagogical principles. Secondly through an examination of the development of movement education with particular reference to the theories of Rudolf Laban. Thirdly by tracing modern American Movement education historically and developmentally. The third aspect examines the strong theoretical relationship between Laban and Dewey. It also illustrates the link between them as developed by the current theorists and practitioners of movement education.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gv79g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jb05c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Laban, Rudolf von, 1879-1958 -- Contributions in education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Movement education -- United States -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dewey, John, 1859-1952 -- Contributions in education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988n182"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identifying the level of flexibility a single-family home may require in order to meet changing needs during the family life cycle with special reference to seniors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ritchie, John Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Flexibility in housing has been studied and implemented both in Europe and North America. However, there is a need for more research on which spaces in the home and which elements in those spaces require flexibility to accommodate all phases of the family life cycle. The particular spaces in a single-family home requiring this flexibility were determined in five case studies covering a minimum span of 15 years of the family life cycle. The spaces that underwent changes most frequently were dens, studies and recreation rooms. Bedrooms changed frequently only when there were crowded conditions or when residents were unhappy with the status quo. Through a review of the physical limitations of the elderly, it was determined that a sensitive application of accessibility standards in all homes would extend the usefulness of the homes as the occupants enter the final stage of the life cycle.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cz71j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988n182</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Housing, Single family</dc:subject><dc:subject>Older people -- Dwellings</dc:subject><dc:subject>Architecture, Domestic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sc37q"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le "je"-narrateur : la nouvelle esthétique du roman québécois</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stewart, Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since 1960, the first-person narrative form has dominated the Quebec novel. As first-person novels often imitate non-fiction forms (autobiographies, diaries, etc.), it follows that this narrative choice would involve a certain degree of self-revelation. We will see though that this is not the case in the "nouveau roman" of Quebec. In fact, the Quebec narrator employs a number of techniques to distance him or herself from the "I" that is the object of the narrative. In this work, we will attempt to identify some of the main characteristics of this new face of the Quebec novel. We will start with an exploration of two novels from the pre-1960 period: Maria Chapdelaine and Poussiere sur la ville. We will then study the contemporary era through our choice of four of Quebec's most famous novels: Le Libraire, Prochain episode, Kamouraska and L'Hiver de force. We will see that the "nouveau roman" is not as "personal" as its form suggests and that the distance between the narrator and his or her "self" is not only a constant but is also an evolving characteristic of the Quebec novel. This work is therefore a study of the contemporary Quebec novel and its narrative properties, and of the distance that the narrator imposes between his or her present and past self.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c269f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sc37q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French-Canadian fiction -- Québec (Province) -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>French-Canadian fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870z053"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The artist and the Opéra : Manet, Degas, Cassatt</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bronfman, Beverly</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Edouard Manet, Edgar Degas and Mary Cassatt had unique visions of the Paris Opera House. Thus each artist perceived and portrayed the pageant of fashionable contemporary life at the Opera from diverse perspectives. Manet rendered a singular image of this world, that of a masked ball, which elicits an extraordinary insight into the manners and mores of an era. The focus by Degas on the dancers on stage invites a penetrating look into the spectacle of the performance from exceptional viewpoints. Mary Cassatt's depictions, exclusively of the female spectators in the audience, intimate a serious reflection of her earnest feminist attitudes. From the costumed revellers in the foyer, to the brilliant presentation on stage to the elegant spectators in the loges, these images inspired by the Opera endure as remarkably distinctive.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d6337.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870z053</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cassatt, Mary, 1844-1926</dc:subject><dc:subject>Degas, Edgar, 1834-1917</dc:subject><dc:subject>Opéra de Paris</dc:subject><dc:subject>Manet, Edouard, 1832-1883</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An296x1258"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The prevention of muscle atrophy following peripheral nerve repair using an implantable electrical system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Durand, Daniel L. (Daniel Lucien)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite the best of modern microsurgical skills, the functional result that is achieved following the repair of a severed peripheral motor nerve has usually been less than complete. In an attempt to reduce or prevent denervation atrophy we have devised a totally implantable system of electrical stimulation and have examined its effect on the target muscle of a repaired peripheral nerve. In this study, twenty New Zealand white rabbits were divided into two groups: in one group the rectus femoris muscle is electrically stimulated after microsurgical repair of the femoral nerve; whereas the control group undergoes microsurgical repair of the femoral nerve only. Comparing the muscles to their contralateral counterparts at eight weeks post-op we found that electrical stimulation resulted in (a) the retention of 79+/$-$5(SEM)% of muscle bulk (compared to 42+/$-$3% in the non-stimulated group) p $&lt;$ 0.001, (b) a maximum force of tetanic contraction averaging 41+/$-$5% of normal (compared to 19+/$-$4% in the non-stimulated group) p $&lt;$ 0.01, (c) less myofiber atrophy, interfascicular fibrosis, and fatty infiltration, (d) significantly less myofilamentous disruption at the ultrastructural level, and (e) a preferential atrophy of type-II fibres (p $&lt;$ 0.001) in the absence of electrical stimulation. There was no statistical difference between the two groups in the compound action potential waveform or amplitude of evoked contractions. In conclusion, these results suggest that the electrical stimulation of skeletal muscle will improve the ultimate functional results in patients undergoing peripheral motor nerve repair.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sz02w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x1258</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am039k722k"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The making of a corporate : elite adult targeted comic magazines of Japan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kondo, Tomoko</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the popularity of comic magazines among Japanese adult readers--primarily it looks at the male audience, but it also considers female response. It analyses texts of specific men's comics to illustrate the discourse of "masculinity-through-occupation" which these magazines offer to readers. In addition it explores the phenomenon of "readership response" by examining a selection of "reader letters." The role-adaptation-through-enjoyment possibilities these comic magazines provide to male readers is compared to parallel possibilities for female readers by examining both women's responses to male comics, and the nature of narrative in women's comics.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx95f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k722k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Comic books, strips, etc. -- Japan</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322g425"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Air cabotage : current legal issues</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vilao, Maria Cristina G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The term air cabotage refers to the carriage of air traffic between two points within the territory of the same state. This carriage is generally reserved to the aircraft of the territorial state and is thus inaccessible to foreign carriers. This thesis gives a brief account of the origins of the concept of cabotage in maritime law and of its introduction in the early international air law conventions. The thesis then proceeds to focus on the problem of air cabotage in the North-American context and particularly on the current bilateral negotiations between the USA and Canada at which cabotage rights in the USA are being sought by Canada. It further projects on the EEC context, where air transport liberalization measures toward the completion of a single integrated market will eventually (perhaps very soon) lead to the availability for Community carriers of cabotage rights within any EEC Member State. The creation of a "Community cabotage area" where only Community carriers would be able to carry Community traffic is also analyzed. Finally, the consequences of these developments are examined as far as EEC Member States' obligations under the Chicago Convention and relations with third states are concerned. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jt32h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g425</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xg94f"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of tort law in the medical context</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Turner, Gabrielle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Current proposals in the United Kingdom and Canada recommend the implementation of no-fault compensation schemes for victims of medical accidents. This thesis argues that although such schemes provide an efficient method of distributing general compensation, there is nevertheless a continuing role for the tort liability mechanism. Due to the fact that tort liability is founded on an ethic of individual responsibility, the potential for public accountability of particular medical professionals will be maintained by preserving the common law action in negligence. There is also an important role for tort law doctrine in reflecting a move away from the traditional paternalistic structure of the doctor-patient relationship towards a desirable shared decision-making model. The fact that compensation schemes are not amenable to these goals indicates the necessity of maintaining a dual system, in order to accommodate the plurality of objectives that should be achieved in this context.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mm028.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xg94f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tx26v"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Strontium extraction by aluminothermic reduction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Langlais, Joseph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Melt-Leach-Evaporation (MLE) process is under development for the extraction of valuable Group IA or IIA metals of the Periodic Table, such as lithium, calcium, magnesium and strontium. The process consists of mixing and contacting the value metal source material, which might be an ore or concentrate, with an excess of molten metal which is acting as a reductant and lixiviant. In the process, the value metal extracted from the source material is dissolved in the excess molten metallic solvent and is subsequently extracted as a vapour by vacuum distillation. The vapour is condensed and recuperated in the metallic state. An experimental program involving eight experiments was carried out. The experimental procedure consisted in essence of melting the aluminum reductant in a crucible and adding the source material, SrCO$ sb3,$ and other reactant (Mg or Bi). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w452z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tx26v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A41687k32x"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Melt treatment effects on porosity and impact strength in hypoeutectic aluminum silicon alloy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>La-Orchan, Wittaya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effects of the three factors (modification, grain refinement, and hydrogen level) on the amount of porosity, impact strength, and performance of the reduced pressure test in A356 alloy have been studied. It was found that grain refinement, acting singly and in combination with modification, reduces the porosity by inducing mass feeding. However, this beneficial effect may not be found at all cooling rates and casting sizes. There is less total shrinkage in Sr-alloyed samples than in those which are non Sr-alloyed. The reason for this is supposed to be a difference in the liquid density which may be higher in Sr-alloyed samples. Modification has the strongest effect on improving the impact strength of A356 alloy. Hydrogen reduces it slightly. On the other hand, grain refinement, acting singly or in combination with modification, was not found to improve the impact strength of the alloy. To obtain optimum impact strength, it is recommended that a combination of modification and degassing to about 0.1 ml.H$ sb2$/100 g. Al. be used. An excellent linear relatiosnhip between density and hydrogen level exists for all combinations of melt treatment processes when the redued pressure test is used. Three methods of predicting the true hydrogen level are proposed and calculated hydrogen levels agree reasonably well with measured melt hydrogen within the error range of $ pm$0.05-0.1 ml./100 g. Al.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gz256.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687k32x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An296x126j"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le langage du théâtre de l'absurde : suivi de Resolutions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Perrault, Jean-François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis in creative writing comprises two sections. The first is an essay on the theatre of the absurd. The introduction sets the genre in its historical context and briefly describes its aesthetic qualities. Four plays by reputed "absurd" playwrights are studied in the body of the essay: La cantatrice chauve (The Bald Soprano) by Eugene Ionesco, Fin de partie (Endgame) by Samuel Beckett, Le balcon (The Balcony) by Jean Genet, and Les voisins (not translated) by Claude Meunier and Louis Saia. The conclusion examines the difference between dramatic and comic plays found within the theatre of the absurd. It also touches on the legacy of the theatre of the absurd. The second section of the thesis is a play in one act entitled Resolutions. It respects the principal characteristics of the theatre of the absurd which are described and analysed in the first section.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418q29g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x126j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Theater of the absurd</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128d054"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The personalgroup discrimination discrepancy : the role of social identity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Porter, Lana E. (Lana Elizabeth)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Recent research has unveiled a robust and pervasive phenomenon: individual members of a group consistently perceive higher levels of discrimination directed at their group as a whole as compared to themselves personally as members of that group. This phenomenon has been labelled the "personal/group discrimination discrepancy". Two studies were conducted using female subjects to investigate possible explanations underlying the personal/group discrimination discrepancy. Study 1 examined the effect of question wording employed in previous research. Study 2 investigated the relationship between an individual's perceptions of personal and group discrimination and her personal and social identity with respect to women as a group. Contrary to the main hypothesis, those subjects who made stronger associations between themselves personally as women and women as a group demonstrated a larger discrepancy between ratings of personal and group discrimination as compared to those subjects who less strongly associated themselves personally with the group. This result is discussed in terms of Turner's (1982) concept of depersonalization.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r765q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128d054</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Discrimination</dc:subject><dc:subject>Group identity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881p17x"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Immobilization of lactococcus lactis subsp. cremoris within cross- linked protein microcapsules</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hyndman, Caroline Louise</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lactococcus lactis subspecies cremoris was encapsulated by cross-linking emulsified gelatin at an oil/water interface. The organic phase in the emulsion step consisted of nontoxic vegetable or silicone oil and the exposure of the cells to cross-linking agent was minimized in two ways. The concentration of tolylene-2,4-diisocyanate was reduced to 34 mM and a lower viscosity oil was used as the continuous phase in the emulsion step so as to decrease the specific surface area of the microcapsules. Viable cell count (cfu/ml milk) was estimated to be reduced by five orders of magnitude for microcapsules formed in sunflower seed oil while a reduction of only two orders of magnitude resulted from the encapsulation process when using the lower viscosity silicone oil. Growth within the microcapsules occurred during fermentation and activity of the encapsulated cells increased when the microcapsules were used in subsequent assays. In the third sequential activity assay for cells encapsulated using silicone oil the time to reduce the pH of milk to 5.5 was 2.8 hours and the estimated initial intracapsular cell density was 10$ sp9$ cfu/g microcapsules.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sf72d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881p17x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An296x127t"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional recovery following upper extremity peripheral nerve repair in children and adults</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Joubert, Diane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A study was conducted to investigate the effects of age on functional recovery following a median and/or ulnar nerve repair. A group of 17 children was compared to a group of 17 adults with nerve injuries of similar severity and site. Motor and sensory function, tactile gnosis, manual dexterity, pain and perception of disability were assessed by an independent examiner. The results indicate a better qualitative and quantitative recovery in children than in adults, with respect to two-point discrimination, grip strength, tactile gnosis, manual dexterity and self-report of performance in daily activities. In conclusion, age at the time of injury was found to influence the extent of functional recovery following peripheral nerve injuries. Other factors, such as cortical plasticity, rate and extent of nerve regeneration, attitudes and psychological adjustment to disability, may further explain the differences observed between the two groups.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tf16n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x127t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak643b3269"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relevance of the structure-conduct-performance paradigm to horizontal merger analysis under the competition act</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bellemare, Daniel Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The merger provisions of the Competition Act proclaimed on June 19, 1986 are similar in with section 7 of the Clayton Act and the decisions of U.S. Courts in antitrust merger cases. In the U.S. and Canada a merger may be enjoined only if it is likely to lessen competition substantially. Subsection 92(2) and section 93 of the Competition Act supply a list of factors that may be used in the assessment of the probable impact on competition that a merger could have. The author discusses the meaning of subsection 92(2) of the Competition Act and the relevance of the "structure-conduct-performance paradigm" to horizontal merger analysis in the Canadian context. The author proceeds to a comparative analysis of the U.S. and Canadian antitrust regimes. The meaning of subsection 92(2) remains unsettled since the Competition Tribunal has not yet made a decision on the merits in a contested merger. The interpretation of subsection 92(2) suggested differs from that of the Director of Investigation and Research (Bureau of Competition Policy) and most antitrust commentators in Canada. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vj878.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b3269</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, Public Administration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economics, Commerce-Business</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mm03j"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bernini's S. Andrea al Quirinale : the triumph of martyrdom</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kelly, Kevin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>S. Andrea al Quirinale, by Gian Lorenzo Bernini, is undoubtedly one of the great achievements of the Italian Baroque. No less spectacular is its message, though art historians have generally regarded it as simply a Jesuit church housing the glorious scene of the martyrdom and apotheosis of St. Andrew. This view, however, is clearly misleading since a closer examination of the building and its contents shows that the devout and learned Bernini intended to suggest a number of other important related themes. This thesis focuses on the concept of martyrdom through a thorough analysis of not only the dominant religious event above the high altar area, but the entire iconographic scheme of the church, which is reinforced by the architectural setting. This Jesuit building is further examined in the light of several artistic influences. The most obvious, yet most overlooked of these is the literary source of the Spiritual Exercises by St. Ignatius of Loyola. S. Andrea al Quirinale is also considered in terms of the architectural heritage of early Christian churches and martyria. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z482.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mm03j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bernini, Gian Lorenzo, 1598-1680</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chiesa di S. Andrea al Quirinale (Rome, Italy)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Martyrdom in art</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rome (Italy) -- Buildings, structures, etc</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak3569649c"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Acoustical optimization of control room 'A' at the McGill University Recording Studios</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Klepko, John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The loudspeaker system and the room interface are the two main components in any listening environment. Research will be conducted focusing on the room component using Control Room 'A' of the McGill University Recording Studio in an attempt to optimize the monitoring situation. The sound field of the room will be broken down and analyzed in both time and frequency domains. The problem areas of the room will be identified and the surfaces altered by means of absorption, reflection and diffusion.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cz72t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569649c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sound studios -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acoustical engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject>McGill University. Faculty of Music. Sound Recording Studio</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xk71g"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Neoplatonic influences in Hildegard of Bingen's Ordo Virtutum : with Latin text and English translation of the play</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jolliffe, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Hildegard of Bingen's Ordo Virtutum (c.1141), the earliest liturgical morality play, presents in small compass some of the Neoplatonic doctrines which formed the common property of theologians in the twelfth century, the most pervasive of which was that which posited a disparity between the sense-perceptible and intelligible realms, true reality being supposed to belong to the latter. For Hildegard, like her contemporaries, such a world-view is inseparable from symbolist modes of thought, and in this thesis explanations for the form and effect of Hildegard's use of rhetorical devices such as symbol and metaphor in the Ordo will be sought within the framework of a discussion of "medieval linguistic epistemology" (Neoplatonic). The Latin text and English translation of the play are also provided.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gg10n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk71g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hildegard, Saint, 1098-1179. Ordo virtutum -- Criticism, Textual</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9c67wp88d"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Social integration of two girls with Down syndrome attending a summer camp</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fridell, Sari R. (Sari Robin)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigated friendship formations of two girls with Down Syndrome who were integrated into a unit of 34 ten and eleven-year-old girls at a residential summer camp. While acting as participant observer, in the role of co-counsellor, I recorded behavioural observations and informal interviews in a journal, friendship log and personal log. A quantitative data analysis investigated the frequency with which campers elected to be with these two girls, as well as the number of campers who chose them as their best friends, as preferred bunkmates for next year and as those with whom they would want to keep in touch. A qualitative data analysis investigated the comments made by campers and counsellors concerning the program and the two girls of interest to this study. Results indicated that these two girls formed friendships during this month-long program. Limitations of this investigation are considered and some suggestions for further research are explored.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gn050.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wp88d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Down syndrome</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social integration</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>