<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89db651"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of the CNC and small MAF transcription factors in placental and myometrial cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Massrieh, Wael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Members of the MAF (proto-) oncogene and CNC families of basic leucine zipper transcription factors (bZIP) play important roles in development, differentiation, mammalian gene expression and stress signalling. We analyzed the regulation of the human small MAF transcription factor family members, MAFF, MAFG and MAFK, as well as two CNC family members, NRF2 and NRF3, in human reproductive tissue. We found that MAFF expression was induced by the proinflammatory cytokines interleukin 1 beta (IL1B) and tumor necrosis factor (TNF) in PHM1-31 myometrial cells. It was particularly interesting that the proinflammatory cytokine Interleukin 6 not affect the expression of MAFF. Additionally, the transcript and protein levels of the highly homologous MAFG and MAFK genes were not modulated by these cytokines. Using electromobility shift assays (EMSA)s we showed that MAFF is capable of heterodimerzing with NRF3, and since they are both highly expressed in the placenta we investigated their role in more detail in this tissue. We found that MAFF and NRF3 are expressed in the anchoring villi from 12 weeks to term. Furthermore, we demonstrated that MAFF and NRF3 are highly expressed in primary placental cytotrophoblasts, but not in placental fibroblasts. This led us to examine whether NRF3 is also regulated by proinflammatory cytokines and we showed that NRF3, is also modulated by TNF in the human JAR placental cell line. Parallel studies investigated the role NRF2 plays in the antioxidant response of placental cells due to exposure to arsenic. We provided evidence for the involvement of NRF2 by confirming the increase in binding of endogenous NRF2/small MAF heterodimers to Stress Response Element (StRE), and the upregulation of heme oxygenase-1 (HOI) expression, upon exposure of JAR cells to arsenic. Our results suggest a role for MAFF, NRF3 and NRF2 in proinflammatory cytokine control of myometrial and placental gene expression as well as arsenic mediated stress in placental cells.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85ng37z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89db651</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xn87s"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the localization and functions of the adenovirus E4orf4 protein</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Miron, Marie-Joëlle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The adenovirus protein E4orf4 kills cancer cells but not normal primary cells. The possibility of developing a drug that mimics the killing by E4orf4 for cancer therapy is therefore of great interest but its mechanisms of action first need to be elucidated. Studies over the past decade have shown that E4orf4 induces p53-independent, caspase-independent cell death in a PP2A Balpha-dependent manner. In an effort to better understand its mechanism of action and identify putative cell death targets, the localization to function relationship of E4orf4-induced cell death was investigated. Here, I show that E4orf4 has a predominant nuclear localization following expression even though small amounts are observed in the cytoplasm and that, in addition, it can induce cell death both from the nucleus and from the cytoplasm when artificially targeted to these sites using well-characterized, exogenous localization signals. Furthermore, I identify an arginine-rich signal in E4orf4 spanning residues 66 to 75 (E4ARM) that mediates nuclear and nucleolar localization of E4orf4 and I show that, importantly, it contributes to at least 50% of E4orf4-induced cell death activity. Finally, I demonstrate that wild-type E4orf4 associates with several nuclear bodies such as viral replication centers, nucleoli, perinuclear bodies and PML bodies during adenovirus infection but that association with these structures is not essential for virus growth as mutants that are defective for E4orf4 expression generally replicate as efficiently as wild-type virus. However, I also show that a virus encoding a mutant form of E4orf4 accumulating at PML bodies during infection has a dominant negative effect on virus growth, thus highlighting the functional importance of nuclear bodies during cellular growth and adenovirus infection.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rd10w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xn87s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579x607"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of surface topography and chemistry on new bone formation and osseointegration</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hacking, Steven Adam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The specific stimuli for osteogenesis are not clearly defined. It has been generally assumed that the chemical similarity of some biomaterials, such as hydroxyapatite and tri-calcium phosphate, to the mineral phase of bone generates a favorable osseous response. However, this does not account for the osseous response observed with a diverse range of metallic biomaterials that when placed in an osseous environment under appropriate conditions become osseointegrated. In this context, microtexture is essential for osseointegration; implants with irregularly microtextured surfaces (Ra 1-7 μm) are generally apposed by bone whereas those with polished surfaces (R a ≪ 0.5 μm) are generally apposed by fibrous tissue. Understanding the specific local stimuli for osteogenesis provides important information to optimize cementless implant design and new bone formation. This thesis suggests that surface topography is a specific local stimulus for osteogenesis as demonstrated in the context of in vivo and in vitro models. To test the stimulatory effect of surface texture, a technique was developed to apply an irregular microtexture to sintered beaded porous coatings which doubled the amount of bone ingrowth. Another technique was developed to mask the chemistry of plasma sprayed hydroxyapatite without altering its topography. Plasma sprayed hydroxyapatite coatings possess a distinct microtexture comparable to that found on commercially available microtextured implants. In this in vivo model nearly 80% of the osseous response to hydroxyapatite coated implants was attributed to surface topography not chemistry. Further studies were undertaken to determine if a biological analog existed for the rough irregular surfaces found on commercially available microtextured implants. A fracture model was developed that generated a range clinically observed of fracture types. Overall the different fracture surfaces possessed an irregular microtexture (Ra = 2.85 +/- 1.32 μm) that was not statistically different from those found on commercially available microtextured implants (Ra = 2-5 μm). A novel method was developed to examine the response of pre-osteoblast cells to bone fracture surfaces. Disks of bone were fabricated from bovine tibia for in vitro study. A fractured surface was produced on these disks by splitting them with an osteotome. From each fractured disk pair, one half was polished to a smooth surface and the other left as fractured. A further subset of disks was produced by masking the surface chemistry with a nanometer thin layer of titanium using the technique previously described. Regardless of surface chemistry, bone or bone masked by titanium, formation of a mineralized matrix was observed only on the fractured surfaces. This suggested that the microtexture of the fracture surface may be a stimulus for new bone formation. Furthermore, the osseous response to microtextured implants may in fact be a response to what is perceived as a fracture surface.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vw18t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579x607</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956m154"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ascending and descending projections of cholinergic, GABAergic and glutamatergic basal forebrain neurons and their role in cortical activity and sleep-wake states</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Henny V., Pablo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The basal forebrain (BF) plays multiple and divergent roles in the modulation of cortical activity and the control of sleep-wake states. BF neurons project to cortex, where they promote cortical activation during wakefulness (W) and paradoxical sleep (PS). Other neurons may conversely promote the appearance of slow wave activity (SWA) that occurs during slow wave sleep (SWS). BF neurons also send projections to the lateral hypothalamus (LH), a wake- and arousal-promoting region and whose inhibition by the BF is thought to facilitate the appearance of behavioral quiescence and sleep. It is likely that these multiple roles are carried out by the heterogeneous population that comprises the BF, which include cholinergic, GABAergic and as yet putative glutamatergic neurons which, as shown by retrograde tracing, innervate these areas. To better understand the mechanisms through which BF neurons modulate cortical activity and sleep-wake states, research was carried out to determine the numbers of cholinergic, GABAergic and putative glutamatergic neurons in the BF, and to examine their respective efferent projections to the cortex and LH. Following stereological quantification of immunohistochemically identified ACh-, GABA- and glutamate-synthesizing neurons, anterograde transport of biotinylated dextran amine 10,000 MW (BDA) in magnocellular BF neurons was combined with immunohistochemistry for vesicular transporter proteins (VTPs) for ACh (VAChT), GABA (VGAT) or glutamate (VGIuT) for identification of BF terminals in prefrontal cortex (PFC) and LH. Subsequent stereological analysis was used to determine contributions of cholinergic, GABAergic and newly identify glutamatergic BF axon terminals to these areas. There, triple fluorescent staining was performed to describe the innervation by BF terminals of pyramidal and interneuronal cell groups in the PFC and of the orexin/hypocretin cell population in the LH. Additional triple staining with postsynaptic markers was used to provide evidence for synaptic contacts. Together, these findings demonstrate the existence of at least three neuronal contingents of BF neurons, which may have the capacity to modulate the activity of cortical or LH neurons and thus, to control different aspects of cortical activity and sleep-wake states.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483p394.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956m154</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw95054737"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mucosal immunizations in a humanized transgenic mouse model and development of novel multimeric tools for detection of cellular immunity towards an HIV vaccine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kalfayan, Lina H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Viral vector-based vaccines represent an effective means of in vivo antigen expression and the ensuing generation of a sustained immune response in the host. These new generation vaccines are deemed promising against pathogens for which researchers have so far failed to put forth preventive strategies and/or effective, accessible, treatment modalities. HIV-1 stands at the foremost of this list. In the current study, we have evaluated the use of two different viral vector-based vaccines against Clade A of HIV-1, namely recombinant modified vesicular stomatitis virus (VSV-AV3) and Adenovirus serotype 5 (Ad5) expressing the Gag protein from subtype A. These viral vectors, which are also inherently endowed with adjuvant properties, were delivered via a mucosal immunization strategy in a humanized transgenic mouse model. Transgenic mice expressing both HLA-A*0201 and HLA-DR*0101 represent a versatile model in which HIV-specific immunogenic epitopes and the resulting T cell receptor (TCR) specificity can be determined. We show that following mucosal delivery of vaccine, there is induction of antigen-specific systemic T cells against epitopes which were previously shown to be immunogenic in humans. We next developed novel multimeric reagents for the detection of CD4 + T cells, namely dodecameric HLA-DR1 molecules using a murine immunoglobulin M (IgM) scaffold. These reagents aim at increasing the overall avidity of peptide-MHC Class II complexes to detect low-affinity TCRs. These multimers were able to activate in vitro a Jurkat T cell line in an antigen-specific manner. The identification and characterization of the molecular requirements boosting the qualitative and quantitative features of the immune response to HIV vaccines, in addition to the development of novel state-of-the-art immune monitoring tools, will be crucial in better understanding of the mechanisms of interaction between the virus and the host immune system, leading to rational strategies in the fight against the AIDS epidemic.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rj695.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95054737</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak643b5334"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Depression, medication use, and cognitive functioning in older medical patients</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Han, Ling, 1955-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The inter-relationship between depression, medication use and cognitive decline in older persons has potentially important clinical and public health implications, yet research findings on the nature of this relationship remain inconclusive. This thesis presents a systematic investigation into this topic in a sample of 281 medical inpatients aged 65 and over, who were followed for up to 12 months after admission. In the first three chapters, the concept, population burden and measurement of depression and cognitive function in the elderly population are described. The relevant literature is reviewed, and the rationale and approaches of this thesis are presented. In the fourth chapter (1st manuscript), the short-term temporal relationship between depression and cognitive functioning was explored using an interviewer-rated depression severity scale. Based on competing mixed effects models under alternative temporal assumptions, the severity of depression symptoms appeared to have a concurrent rather than prospective relationship with cognitive functioning. In the fifth chapter (2nd manuscript), diagnostic criteria were used to define depression. After adjusting for covariates, both major and minor depression were significantly predictive of subsequent cognitive decline, and the strength of the association appeared to increase with the duration of "exposure". In the sixth chapter (3rd manuscript), using a provincial prescription database, the effects of medication exposure on cognitive function were evaluated. Antidepressant use was not associated with cognitive decline in general, but interacted with depression diagnoses. In exploratory analyses, antidepressant use appeared to be associated with improved cognitive function over time in the minor depression group, independent of comorbid diseases, current depression symptoms and concomitant medications. Both major and minor depression were independently predictive of subsequent cognitive decline, especially in those not prescribed antidepressants. In summary, this thesis demonstrates that, in this sample of older medical inpatients, both major and minor depression are independent risk factors for 12-month cognitive decline. The potentially beneficial effects of antidepressants for patients with minor depression should be investigated.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bt532.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b5334</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85ng39h"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis, characterizations and applications of C2'-modified oligonucleotide analogues</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Peng, Chang Geng</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During the past two decades, oligonucleotide analogues have drawn considerable attention as potential therapeutic and diagnostic agents. Gene silencing through "RNA interference" (siRNA) or the more mature "antisense" technology (AONs) have proven to be powerful tools for studying gene functions. Chemical modifications of these compounds are generally required to improve their "drug-like" properties such as potency, selectivity and delivery, particularly in the development of oligonucleotide-based therapeutics. Aptamers are another emerging class of oligonucleotide therapeutics and diagnostics. This thesis focuses on oligonucleotides containing 1-(2-deoxy-2-alpha-C-hydroxymethyl-beta- D-ribofuranosyl)thymine (2'-alpha-hm-dT, abbreviated as "H") and 2'-deoxy-2'-fluoroarabinonucleotides (2'F-araN), and their applications. A major component of this work focused on the synthesis of 2'-alpha-hm-dT (H) and the first investigation of oligoribonucleotides containing this nucleoside analogue. Specifically, 2'-CH2O-phosphoramidite and 3'-O-phosphoramidite derivatives of H were synthesized and incorporated into both 2',5'-RNA and RNA chains. Incorporation of 3',5'-linked H units into a DNA, 2',5'-RNA or RNA strand led to significant destabilization of duplexes formed with unmodified RNA targets. 2',5'-Linked H units into 2',5'-RNA or RNA caused significantly less destabilization, and in fact, they were shown to stabilize the loop structure of some RNA hairpins. These results were rationalized in terms of the "compact" and "extended" conformations of nucleotides. A series of branched RNAs (Y-shaped) related to yeast pre-mRNA splicing intermediates were synthesized incorporating both natural (i.e., ribose) and nonnatural (i.e., H, and acyclic nucleoside) branch points in order to examine the effect of sugar conformation and phosphodiester configuration on yeast debranching enzyme (yDBR) hydrolytic efficiency. The results indicate that 2'-phosphodiester scission with yDBR occurs only with a ribose-phosphate backbone at the branch point, whereas some of the H-containing branched RNAs were found to competitively inhibit yDBR hydrolytic activity. This thesis also examines the stabilization of DNA guanine-quadruplexes (G-quadruplexes) by replacing the deoxyribose sugar by a 2-deoxy-2-fluoroarabinose. The effect of this substitution was assessed in the well-known thrombin-binding DNA aptamer d(G2T2G2TGTG2T 2G2), the telomeric DNA d(G4T4G 4) sequence and a phosphorothioate octanucleotide PS-d(T2G 4T2), all of which are known to fold into G-quadruplex structures. Stabilization of the G-quadruplexes was possible provided that the arabinose sugar was introduced at guanosine residues adopting an anti N-glycosidic bond conformation. Some of the arabinose modified thrombin-binding aptamers not only exhibited superior thermal stability and nuclease resistance, but also maintained high thrombin binding affinity. Finally, this thesis examines the ability of DNA polymerases to recognize and utilize 2'-deoxy-2'-fluoro-beta-D-arabinonucleoside 5'-triphosphates (2'F-araNTPs) as building blocks for the synthesis of 2'-deoxy-2'-fluoro-beta- D-arabinonucleic acids (2'F-ANA). The results obtained indicate that a few DNA polymerases can synthesize 2'F-ANA and 2'F-ANA-DNA chimeras on a DNA template. Conversely, certain enzymes were shown to catalyze 2'F-ANA template-directed DNA synthesis. While it was not possible to synthesize 2'F-ANA strands on a 2'F-ANA template, it is possible for some DNA polymerases to catalyze the formation of multiple 2'F-ANA:2'F-ANA base pairs within a DNA-FANA chimeric duplex. These results suggest that it should be possible to evolve FANA-modified aptamers via SELEX.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hh48b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85ng39h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Oligonucleotides -- Derivatives -- Synthesis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042z340"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Nursing</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of appreciative inquiry on the retention of nurses and other professionals and on the development of innovative ideas in health care</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Richer, Marie-Claire</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background. Factors such as the shortage of personnel, hospital closures and mergers, the ageing of the population combined with the evolution of medical technologies have all added pressure to the health care system. These pressures have had an impact on current work environments and health care workers' satisfaction. In light of the evidence on the influence of job satisfaction and retention on the quality of tare and patient safety, interventions are needed to address these issues. Objective. The objective were to examine the effect of Appreciative Inquiry on: (1) the development of innovative ideas regarding work organization; (2) changes in health care professionals' and particularly nurses' job satisfaction and intent to stay; and, (3) levels of empowerment, social network and perceived organizational support. Research design. The study used a multiple embedded case study design to access the multifaceted aspects relating to retention and innovation and examine the changes engendered by an AI intervention. Participants and setting. Two oncology ambulatory clinics constituted the cases; the embedded units were the health care and the management teams (N = 47 and 5) of an adult oncology division in a multi-site university affiliated health care centre in a large Canadian city. Methods. Multiple sources of evidence were used. They consisted of participant observation, questionnaires providing quantitative and qualitative evidence, interviews, direct observation and documentation. Results. AI provided a way to involve health care professionals in change processes by creating the opportunity and the conditions that promoted the emergent of innovative ideas. Some of these ideas were implemented during the study period. AI did not result in improved psychological empowerment, perceived organizational support, support network or decreased intent to stay. Job satisfaction decreased over time. Perceptions of organizational support and psychological empowerment were found to influence job satisfaction and intent to stay. Conclusion. This study makes a contribution to micro-systems examination of change processes and reveals how ideas evolve and are developed in a multidisciplinary context. AI represents a way to tap into the innovative potential of individuals within an organization. The findings suggest that upper and middle management support is required throughout change processes and that multilevel interventions need to be pursued to facilitate the implementation of innovative ideas and subsequently improve work environments.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vs786.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042z340</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Health Care Management</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Nursing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zg23m"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A time-based approach for multi-GHz embedded mixed-signal characterization and measurement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Safi-Harab, Mouna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The increasingly more sophisticated systems that are nowadays implemented on a single chip are placing stringent requirements on the test industry. New test strategies, equipment, and methodologies need to be developed to sustain the constant increase in demand for consumer and communication electronics. Techniques for built-in-self-test (BIST) and design-for-test (DFT) strategies have been proven to offer more feasible and economical testing solutions. Previous works have been conducted to perform on-chip testing, characterization, and measurement of signals and components. The current thesis advances those techniques on many levels. In terms of performance, an increase of more than an order of magnitude in speed is achieved. 70-GHz (effective sampling) on-chip oscilloscope is reported, compared to 4-GHz and 10-GHz ones in previous state-of-the-art implementations. Power dissipation is another area where the proposed work offer a superior solution compared to previous alternatives. All the proposed circuits do not exceed a few milliWatts of power dissipation, while performing multi-GHz high-speed signal capture at a medium resolution. Finally, and possibly most importantly, all the proposed circuits for test rely on a different form of signal processing; the time-based approach. It is believed that this approach paves the path to a lot of new techniques and circuit design skills that can be investigated more deeply. As an integral part of the time-based processing approach for GHz signal capture, this thesis verifies the advantages of using time amplification. The use of such amplification in the time domain is materialized with experimental results from three specific integrated circuits achieving different tasks in GHz high-speed in-situ signal measurement and characterization. Advantages of using such time-based approach techniques, when combined with the use of a front-end time amplifier, include noise immunity, the use of synthesizable digital cells, and circuit building blocks that track the technology scaling in terms of area and speed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n5333.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zg23m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Systems on a chip -- Testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mixed signal circuits -- Testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Signal processing -- Digital techniques</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35td37g"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Postgenomic studies of Candida albicans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martchenko, Mikhail</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We assembled the genome of the human fungal pathogen Candida albicans into eight chromosomes, and annotated each of its genes. A genome comparison with Saccharomyces cerevisiae revealed an increased number of C. albicans superoxide dismutase genes. We analyzed the expression patterns and the function of one of these genes, SOD5, whose role is to protect the pathogen against extracellularly produced, neutrophil-generated superoxide radicals. Comparative genomics also showed that although many of the C. albicans transcription factors, such as Gal4p and Gcn4p, have homologues in S. cerevisiae, the sequence similarities occur only in the DNA binding motifs of those proteins. Deletion analysis of CaGcn4 and CaGal4 proteins show that the N' and C' termini respectively are needed for their transactivation ability. These two transactivation regions show no sequence similarity to the equivalent domains in their S. cerevisiae homologues, and the two C. albicans transactivatiog domains themselves show little similarity. A comparative analysis of the transcriptional machinery between C. albicans and S. cerevisiae showed low sequence similarity of the mediator complex that bridges activation domains of transcription factors to the RNA polymerase II complex. We performed a comparison of intergenic DNA regions to identify the cis-regulatory elements from Candida and Saccharomyces species to examine the organization of the transcriptional regulatory networks between these two organisms. We observed that the C. albicans GAL genes lack Gal4p binding sites, but that such sites are found upstream of telomeric genes and genes involved in glycolysis, and we show that CaGal4p regulates the expression of those genes. We identified the regulatory DNA sequences in the promoters of GAL genes, including a GAL-specific palindrome necessary for GAL10&amp;ogon; expression. Cph1p, the C. albicans homolog of the Ste12p transcription factor controlling pheromone-induced gene expression in yeast, acts through this GAL-specific palindrome, functioning as an activator in the presence of galactose. This shows C. albicans and S. cerevisiae can regulate the same process by different regulatory circuits.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257j869.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35td37g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Candida albicans -- Genome mapping</dc:subject><dc:subject>Candida albicans -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53x112g"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The genetics of potential albendazole and ivermectin resistance in lymphatic filariae</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schwab, Anne Elisabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A current initiative to eliminate lymphatic filariasis (LF), headed by the World Health Organization, aims to interrupt transmission of the disease through yearly community-wide treatment with the broad spectrum anthelmintic albendazole (ABZ), in combination with ivermectin (IVM) or diethylcarbamazine (DEC). Over the years, the use of both ABZ and IVM in the treatment of veterinary parasites has led to widespread anthelmintic resistance against these drugs. In this study, we genotyped microfilaria of Wuchereria bancrofti, a causative agent of LF, in order to detect the presence of mutations which confer ABZ resistance in other parasites, and we identified such mutations in worms obtained from untreated patients in Ghana and Burkina Faso, West Africa. Microfilaria from patients who had been treated with ABZ + IVM, had a significantly higher frequency of the resistant genotype, and this frequency was even higher in worms from patients that had received two rounds of treatment. In addition, the untreated population of microfilaria had an excess of homozygotes in the population. This excess homozygosity was equivalent to a Wright's Inbreeding Statistic of FIT= 0.44, and we found that the population was significantly subdivided between patients. In order to better understand the mechanisms and factors involved in the potential spread of ABZ resistance, caused by such mutations, through a population of Culex-transmitted W. bancrofti, we developed a deterministic model that incorporates genotype structure into the epidemiological model EPIFIL. This model predicts that the combination of ABZ + DEC leads to stronger selection for the resistant genotype than ABZ + IVM, and that drug efficacy assumptions are an important factor affecting the spread of drug resistance. Treatment coverage, non-random mating, initial allele frequency and number of treatments also had substantial impact on the speed and magnitude of the spread of ABZ resistance. When we expanded this model to include potential IVM-resistance alleles we found that, under ABZ + IVM treatment, selection for resistance to either drug is enhanced by the presence of resistance against the second drug. Similarly, excess homozygosity caused by parasite non-random mating may increase selection for a dominant IVM resistance allele through enhancing the spread of a recessive ABZ resistance allele. Resistence developed more slowly when it was inherited as a polygenic trait. Results from this study suggest that resistance monitoring is crucial, as resistance may not be apparent until treatment is stopped, recrudescence occurs and treatment is reapplied.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cf915.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x112g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Elephantiasis -- Chemotherapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ivermectin -- therapeutic use</dc:subject><dc:subject>Elephantiasis, Filarial -- drug therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Albendazole -- therapeutic use</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wuchereria bancrofti -- drug effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Filarial worms -- Effect of drugs on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drug Resistance -- genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Albendazole</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drug resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ivermectin</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dr33k"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A direct temporal domain approach for ultrafast optical signal processing and its implementation using planar lightwave circuits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xia, Bing, 1972 Nov. 7-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ultrafast optical signal processing, which shares the same fundamental principles of electrical signal processing, can realize numerous important functionalities required in both academic research and industry. Due to the extremely fast processing speed, all-optical signal processing and pulse shaping have been widely used in ultrafast telecommunication networks, photonically-assisted RFlmicro-meter waveform generation, microscopy, biophotonics, and studies on transient and nonlinear properties of atoms and molecules. In this thesis, we investigate two types of optical spectrally-periodic (SP) filters that can be fabricated on planar lightwave circuits (PLC) to perform pulse repetition rate multiplication (PRRM) and arbitrary optical waveform generation (AOWG). First, we present a direct temporal domain approach for PRRM using SP filters. We show that the repetition rate of an input pulse train can be multiplied by a factor N using an optical filter with a free spectral range that does not need to be constrained to an integer multiple of N. Furthermore, the amplitude of each individual output pulse can be manipulated separately to form an arbitrary envelope at the output by optimizing the impulse response of the filter. Next, we use lattice-form Mach-Zehnder interferometers (LF-MZI) to implement the temporal domain approach for PRRM. The simulation results show that PRRM with uniform profiles, binary-code profiles and triangular profiles can be achieved. Three silica based LF-MZIs are designed and fabricated, which incorporate multi-mode interference (MMI) couplers and phase shifters. The experimental results show that 40 GHz pulse trains with a uniform envelope pattern, a binary code pattern "1011" and a binary code pattern "1101" are generated from a 10 GHz input pulse train. Finally, we investigate 2D ring resonator arrays (RRA) for ultraf ast optical signal processing. We design 2D RRAs to generate a pair of pulse trains with different binary-code patterns simultaneously from a single pulse train at a low repetition rate. We also design 2D RRAs for AOWG using the modified direct temporal domain approach. To demonstrate the approach, we provide numerical examples to illustrate the generation of two very different waveforms (square waveform and triangular waveform) from the same hyperbolic secant input pulse train. This powerful technique based on SP filters can be very useful for ultrafast optical signal processing and pulse shaping.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f784g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dr33k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Optical data processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Signal processing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avt150p26k"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Galloping, bounding and wheeled-leg modes of locomotion on underactuated quadrupedal robots</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith, James Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents advances in the state-of-the-art in legged locomotion through the development of bounding and galloping gaits as well as new modes of hybrid wheeled-leg modes of locomotion. Two four-legged running robots, Scout II and PAW, are examined, the latter of which is distinguished by actuated wheels at the ends of its legs. First, hybrid modes of locomotion are demonstrated which use legs to dynamically reposition wheels at specific locations with respect to the body. These modes improve the stability and tire-wear of turning and braking manoeuvres and allow pitch-controlled slope ascent and descent in a wheeled-leg vehicle such as the PAW robot. Second, through hip actuation, passive leg compliance and controlled wheel action it is possible to make the same vehicle run using a dynamically stable legged gait called the bound. Experimental evidence of this is presented and compared to similar experiments on the same robot with mechanically blocked wheels, a 3D simulation of the same, as well as bounding on a completely different quadrupedal robot, Scout II. While a casual observer finds no difference in blocked-wheel and active wheel control modes, detailed examination of the gaits reveals lower speeds and efficiency as well as decreased repeatability when the wheels are actively controlled. A new method of forward speed control is presented for the bounding gait using liftoff, as opposed to touchdown, leg angles. The liftoff angle method of speed control is shown to be particularly suited to fine-tuning of certain gait performance indices. Third, the underactuated bounding gait is extended to demonstrate, for the first time, that robotic galloping is possible and that it can be achieved in two underactuated quad-rupedal robots and with varying levels of decoupled control. In the Scout II robot the front leg pair and rear leg pairs function independently; while in the PAW robot galloping is achieved with no controlled coupling between any of the four legs. The rotary gallop gait demonstrated by both robots is characterized by a significant yaw component and is compared to another bound-derived turning gait which uses liftoff angles to produce yaw. In particular, the correspondence of lead leg to yaw direction in both cases is found to match results from biology. In contrast, while it is thought that animals pivot about their lead leg to turn, the rotary gallop demonstrated by these robots shows that yaw occurs primarily in the leg behind the lead leg.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sz03f.NR32240</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150p26k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Quadrupedalism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mobile robots</dc:subject><dc:subject>Robots -- Motion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Robots -- Control systems</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r5191"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interactive hashing and reductions between Oblivious Transfer variants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Savvides, George</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Interactive Hashing has featured as an essential ingredient in protocols realizing a large variety of cryptographic tasks. We present a study of this important cryptographic tool in the information theoretic context. We start by presenting a security definition which is independent of any particular setting or application. We then show that a standard implementation of Interactive Hashing satisfies all the conditions of our definition. Our proof of security improves upon previous ones in several ways. Despite its generality, it is considerably simpler. Moreover, it establishes a tighter upper bound on the cheating probability of a dishonest sender. Specifically, we prove that if the fraction of good strings for a dishonest sender is f, then the probability that both outputs will be good is no larger than 15.6805· f. This upper bound is valid for any f and is tight up to a small constant since a sender acting honestly would get two good outputs with probability very close to f. We illustrate the potential of Interactive Hashing as a cryptographic primitive by demonstrating efficient reductions of String Oblivious Transfer with string length k to Bit Oblivious Transfer and several weaker variants. Our reductions incorporate tests based on Interactive Hashing that allow the sender to verify the receiver's adherence to the protocol without compromising the latter's privacy. This allows a much more efficient use of the available entropy without any appreciable impact on security. As a result, for Bit OT and most of its variants n = (1 + epsilon) k executions suffice, improving efficiency by a factor of two or more compared to the most efficient reductions that do not use Interactive Hashing. As it is theoretically impossible to achieve an expansion factor n/k smaller than 1, our reductions are in fact asymptotically optimal. They are also more general since they place no restrictions on the types of 2-universal hash families used for Privacy Amplification. Lastly, we present a direct reduction of String OT to Rabin OT which uses similar methods to achieve an expansion factor of 2 + epsilon which is again asymptotically optimal.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n738m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r5191</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149t79m"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Longitudinal dynamics of the therapy process during and following brief treatment for depression</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hawley, Lance</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Given the pervasive, debilitating nature of major depressive disorder, a large body of clinical research has evaluated the efficacy of short-term treatments for depression. Researchers have attempted to understand the complex mechanism of therapeutic change by examining treatment response, which is typically defined as the extent of symptom change between the intake and termination sessions. However, this approach fails to recognize that therapy is a non-linear, dynamic longitudinal process. An alternative approach involves analysis of longitudinal repeated measures process and outcome indicators in order to examine change both during treatment as well as following treatment. In order to evaluate dynamic, longitudinal hypotheses, it is necessary to use an appropriate analytical framework. A structural modelling technique termed Latent Difference Score Analysis (LDS) is well suited for this purpose, allowing for evaluation of longitudinal growth within a time series, while also considering multivariate relationships and determinants. The purpose of this research was to evaluate established theories of depression vulnerability as well as theories of psychotherapy process, both during and following depression treatment. The research described in Chapter 2 examined several theories of the longitudinal relationship between depression and perfectionism during depression treatment, while considering the role of the therapeutic alliance. Longitudinal LDS analyses supported a "personality vulnerability" model of depression, in which perfectionism predicted the subsequent rate of depression change throughout treatment. Results indicate that patients with high levels of perfectionism experience less reduction in their depression scores throughout treatment. Furthermore, the strength of the therapeutic alliance significantly predicted the rate of change in personality vulnerability throughout therapy. The research described in Chapter 3 examined several theories of the longitudinal relationship between depression and stress following treatment termination. Results supported a "stress reactivity" model, in which stressful events led to elevations in the rate of depression change following therapy. Multigroup LDS analysis indicated that stress reactivity only occurred for patients who had been treated with medication, and not for those who had received psychotherapy. These findings have several implications. First, comprehensive analyses of treatment efficacy can move beyond symptom reduction by examining mechanisms underlying treatment response using an appropriate statistical framework. The first paper demonstrates that an efficient route to symptom reduction involves establishing an adequate therapeutic alliance in order to target personality vulnerability. The second paper demonstrates that importance of evaluating treatment efficacy by considering whether a treatment leads to enduring change. Specifically, results indicate that the enduring effects of psychotherapy (in comparison to medication treatments) following treatment termination involves increased resiliency to stressful life events.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kf93z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149t79m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Depression, Mental -- Treatment</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613n268w"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of selected microbial lipoxygenase extracts and immobilization and stabilization of an enzymatic preparation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hall, Colin Eric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Aspergillus niger and Penicillium candidum were grown and harvested on days 6 and 8, which corresponded to their maximal biomasses and lipoxygenase (LOX) activities. The extracts were enriched with ammonium sulfate precipitation at 30 to 70% and 20 to 60% of saturation, respectively. The LOX activity was assayed with linoleic, linolenic and arachidonic acids as substrates. Both enriched microbial LOXs demonstrated preferential substrate specificities towards free fatty acids, over acyl esters of linoleic acid. The LOXs had the highest catalytic efficiency values (ratio of V max to Km) for linolenic acid biocatalysis. Major and minor pH optima at 5.0 and 10.5 were observed for A. niger, whereas for P. candidum they were at 6.0 and 8.5. Normal phase high-performance liquid chromatography (NP-HPLC) and gas-liquid chromatography/mass spectrometry (GC/MS) characterization of end products revealed that both LOXs produced the 10-hydroperoxide of linoleic acid (10-HPOD) at 15 to 16% of total isomers detected, respectively. Chiral studies of the P. candidum LOX catalyzed hydroperoxides revealed an excess in the production of (S) stereo-isomers resultant from linoleic, linolenic and arachidonic acids bioconversion. Penicillium camemberti was grown and harvested at its maximal biomass and LOX activity. The microbial extract was ultrafiltered (30 kDa NMWCO) and KCI (7.5 ppm) was added prior to lyophilization for the stabilization of enzyme activity. The LOX and hydroperoxide lyase (HPL) activities were assayed using linoleic acid and the 10-HPOD as substrates, respectively. The post-lyophilization residual activities were 93% and 223% for LOX and HPL, respectively. The long-term storage stability (-80°C) of the extract (KCI 7.5 ppm) was ~100% after 8 and 4 weeks for LOX and HPL, respectively. The investigated stabilizing chemical additives included glycine, mannitol, glycerol, sucrose and polyethylene glycol. The lowest Kinactivation values were observed with glycine with 0.136 and 0.0296 for LOX and HPL, respectively. Thermostability studies indicated that 5 and 10% (w/v) mannitol and glycine effectively stabilized LOX and HPL, respectively. Immobilization of an enzymatic extract from P. camemberti containing LOX and HPL activities was performed on EupergitRTMC and EupergitRTMC250L-iminodiacetate (IDA), respectively. The free and immobilized extracts both possessed LOX activity with a pH optimum of 6.0, whereas pH 6.0 and 4.0 were the optima of the HPL activity for free and immobilized extract, respectively. Optimal LOX reaction temperatures were 30 and 55°C for the free and immobilized extract, respectively, whereas 45 and 30°C were determined for the HPL activity of the free and immobilized extract, respectively. Long-term stability (-80°C) of the immobilized extract containing LOX and HPL activity showed residual activities of 82.6 and 93.8% after 4 and 8 weeks, respectively.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60d181c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n268w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Penicillium camemberti</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aspergillus niger</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lipoxygenases -- Separation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gj11b"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functionalized ionic liquid-supported organic synthesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>He, Xun, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ionic liquid-supported synthesis is a new concept in organic chemistry. This concept has been well demonstrated in this thesis including ionic-liquid-supported Swern oxidation, oligosaccharide synthesis, imidazolium oligomer synthesis and peptide synthesis. Ionic liquid-supported Swern oxidation provided a new odorless approach to oxidize primary and secondary alcohols into aldehydes and ketones as compared to the conventional method where DMSO was used as an oxidant and the toxic and volatile compound dimethylsulfide was generated quantitatively. The new ionic liquid-supported organosulfur reagents were thermally stable, nonvolatile and odorless, which were recoverable and recyclable after Swern oxidation. Chapter 3 of this thesis described the first example in the research field of ionic liquidsupported oligosaccharide synthesis. This new approach possesses the advantages of both conventional solution phase synthesis and solid phase-supported synthesis. It made possible the chemical assembling of glycals and the cleavage of oligosacharide from the support without need of chromatography to purify the products. Ionic liquid-type oligomers were designed to solve the problems involved in the oneionic-unit ionic liquid-supported biopolymer synthesis because these compounds could have stronger ionic effects on support-bound molecules, which made easier the chemical assembling and purifications of large biopolymers than one-ionic-unit ionic liquidsupported organic synthesis. The thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) showed that these imidazolium oligomers have very good thermal stability. They also have great potential application in the electrochemistry. Imidazolium oligomer-supported peptide synthesis provided a new approach to prepare peptides in a straightforward way. The amino acid coupling reactions were conducted in homogeneous solution phase, which did not require largely excess of reagents to push the reaction to completion and the purification could be performed in a simple way such as centrifugation, decantation and washing without need of special solvents. Moreover, the cleavage of the peptide from the imidazolium oligomer support was done by hydrolysis under basic conditions and the product was obtained in NMR and MS purity. Importantly, imidazolium oligomer-supported peptide block coupling proceeded very well, which provided an approach to convergently synthesize peptides. This approach is very useful for the peptide synthesis in industry especially for the synthesis of peptides with less than 20 amino acids.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838468t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gj11b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hf03w"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Morphology and phylogeny of Sarcophaginae and the systematics of Neobellieria (Diptera:Sarcophagidae)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Giroux, Marjolaine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A comprehensive Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM) study of the distal portion of the male phallus (acrophallus), in 42 species of the flesh-fly subfamily Sarcophaginae, was undertaken to clarify its morphology, to homologize its parts and to define male genital characters. In addition, to better understand the phylogenetic implications of the male genitalia, the generic relationships of 19 sarcophagine genera were tested using a parsimony analysis of 72 examplar species, based on 41 male genitalic characters and 33 other morphological characters of larvae, males and females. The monophyly of Ravinia Robineau-Desvoidy, Oxysarcodexia Townsend, Titanogrypa Townsend, Helicobia Coquillett, Lepidodexia Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm and Sarcophaga s.l. Meigen was supported, but Blaesoxipha Loew appeared paraphyletic. The genus Helicobia was nested within Sarcophaga and the subgenus S. (Neobellieria) Blanchard was found to be polyphyletic. The analysis also supported a sister-group relationship between the type species of S. (Neobellieria) and the subgenus S. (Tolucamyia) Dodge. Based on that cladistic analysis, S. (Tolucamyia) was synonymized with S. (Neobellieria) which was redefined to include the five species of the S. (N.) polistensis group, those previously assigned to S. (Tolucamyia) and one new species. To accommodate the four species of the S. (N.) semimarginalis Hall group and four new species, a new subgenus, S. (Bulbostyla) Giroux &amp; Wheeler, was erected. Finally, Robackina Lopes was reinstated as a subgenus of Sarcophaga to accommodate the single species S. triplasia Wulp.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021k34h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hf03w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sarcophagidae -- Phylogeny</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sarcophagidae -- Classification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sarcophagidae -- Morphology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cz48b"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of treatment of soybean meal on the availability of amino acids and the efficiency of nitrogen usage for milk production in dairy cows</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Borucki Castro, Sylvia Irene</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the first of three experiments, four Holstein multiparous dairy cows, equipped with ruminal and duodenal cannulas, were used to determine the impact of different methods of treating soybean meal (SBM) on ruminal degradability and intestinal digestibility of CP and amino acids (AA). Solvent extracted SBM (SE), expeller SBM (EP), lignosulfonate SBM (LS) and heat and soy hulls SBM (HS) were incubated in the rumen, in nylon bags, for various intervals up to 48h. Additional samples incubated for 16 h were pre-treated with pepsin HCI, and then used for determination of intestinal digestibility either in situ (mobile bag technique) or in vitro. Treatment of SBM (EP, LS, HS) increased rumen undegradable protein (RUP), and AA availability in 30%. Estimates of intestinal digestibility of AA and CP were lower when measured in vitro than in situ. Among the treated SBM products, four EAA (Ile, Leu, Phe and Val) showed differences in availability, with values consistently lower for HS than for LS. The second experiment involved a comparative assessment of the availability of lysine in SE and rumen protected SBM products (EP and LS). Lysine availability was assessed either by the increment in plasma flux of 15N lysine, the increment in intestinally digestible lysine (using chromic oxide as a digesta marker) or by the use of a "plasma lysine response curve" designed to predict intestinally available lysine. The plasma Lys flux was not different between the different SBM products. However, SE + 70 g.d-1 omasal infusion of Lys (SE70) increased Lys flux by exactly 70 g.d -1 above the SE treatment. No differences were observed on duodenal Lys flow, post-ruminal digestion and digestible Lys between the SBM diets (SE, EP, LS). Irrespective of the method of assessment, lysine availability was not altered by the method of treating SBM. The third study evaluated the relative impact of supplying rumen-undegraded protein (RUP) versus altering the carbohydrate source on milk yield and efficiency N usage for milk production. Protein supplementation (SE and EP) increased DMI, whereas the inclusion of beet pulp (BP) replacing 50% of high moisture shelled corn decreased DMI. The results of this research suggest that, under normal conditions of feeding, supplying rumen protected SBM to enhance the supply of intestinally available essential AA does not improve lactation performance; providing beet pulp as a source of readily fermentable fibre also failed to affect milk yield or efficiency of N usage for milk production by dairy cattle.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483p40w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cz48b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dairy cattle -- Feed utilization efficiency</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dairy cattle -- Feeding and feeds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soybean meal as feed</dc:subject><dc:subject>Milk yield</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w8836"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Discrete and statistical approaches to genetics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bruen, Trevor Cormac Vincent</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a number of major innovations in related but different areas of research. The contributions range along a continuum from mathematical phylogenetics, to development of statistical methodology for detecting recombination and finally to the application of statistical techniques to understand Feline Immunodeficiency Virus (FIV) an important pathogen. An underlying theme is the application of combinatorial and statistical ideas to problems in evolutionary biology and genetics. Chapter 2 and Chapter 3 give a number of results relevant to mathematical phylogenetics, in particular maximum parsimony. Chapter 2 presents a new formulation of maximum parsimony in terms of character subdivision, providing a direct link with the character compatibility problem, also known as the perfect phylogeny problem. Specialization of this result to two characters gives a simple formula based on the intersection graph for calculating the parsimony score for a, pair of characters. Chapter 3 further explores maximum parsimony. In particular, it is shown that a maximum parsimony tree for a sequence of characters minimizes a subtree-prune and regraft (SPR) distance to the sets of trees on which each character is convex. Similar connections are also drawn between the Robinson-Foulds distance and a new variant of Dollo parsimony. Chapter 4 presents an application of the work in Chapters 2 and 3 to develop a statistical test for detecting recombination. An extensive coalescent based simulation study shows that this new test is both robust and powerful in a variety of different circumstances compared to a number of current methods. In fact, a simple model of mutation rate correlation is shown to mislead a number of competing tests, causing recombination to be falsely inferred. Analysis of empirical data sets confirm that the new test is one of the best approaches to distinguish recurrent mutation from recombination. Finally, Chapter 5 uses the test developed in Chapter 4 to localize recombinant breakpoints in 14 genomic strains of FIV taken from a wild population of cougars. Based on the technique, three recombinant strains of FIV are identified. Previous studies have focused on the epidemiology and population structure of the virus and this study shows that recombination has also played an important role in the evolution of FIV.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hh49m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w8836</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahh63t0983"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification and characterization of the BRX gene family of Arabidopsis thaliana : investigation of functional redundancy in the root and emerging roles in shoot gravitropism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Briggs, Georgette C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The model plant Arabidopsis thaliana has been very successful thus far as a tool for understanding and studying the genetics of plant development. Analysis of its sequenced genome revealed the occurrence of duplicated chromosome blocks, resulting in duplicated genes. Duplicated genes, high in sequence and/or structure similarity, form gene families. One such family, of BRX-like genes, is presented in this thesis. All members contain a characteristic "BRX" domain that is required for BRX activity in planta. BRX (BREVIS RADIX), is a novel regulator of root growth in Arabidopsis. However, analyses of Arabidopsis single and double mutants with other gene family members, suggests that BRX is the only member with a dominating role in root development. Interestingly, BRXL1, although having BRX activity in the root, does not act redundantly with BRX in vivo, presumably because it is expressed at much lower levels than BRX. These two gene family members demonstrate the uncommon phenomenon of unequal genetic redundancy in plants. Another gene family member, BRXL4, although non-redundant with regards to BRX activity in the root, did display novel shoot-related phenotypes when over-expressed. In these lines the lateral shoots and hypocotyls showed increased Gravitropic Set-Point Angles resulting in the downward growth of the adult lateral shoots and a wide range of growth directions in the hypocotyls. Over-expression lines of BRXL4 also displayed seedling agravitropism. Auxin-induced transcription as monitored by the DR5::GUS reporter, is altered in these lines compared to wild-type. Additionally, hypocotyl curvature, stem bending and amyloplast localization profiles in response to a change in gravity vector, are also altered in these over-expression lines and in the brxl4 mutant compared to wild-type.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jt00j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63t0983</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Arabidopsis thaliana -- Roots</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arabidopsis thaliana -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axw42nd12z"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Shedding new light on random trees</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Broutin, Nicolas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We introduce a weighted model of random trees and analyze the asymptotic properties of their heights. Our framework encompasses most trees of logarithmic height that were introduced in the context of the analysis of algorithms or combinatorics. This allows us to state a sort of "master theorem" for the height of random trees, that covers binary search trees (Devroye, 1986), random recursive trees (Devroye, 1987; Pittel, 1994), digital search trees (Pittel, 1985), scale-free trees (Pittel, 1994; Barabasi and Albert, 1999), and all polynomial families of increasing trees (Bergeron et al., 1992; Broutin et al., 2006) among others. Other applications include the shape of skinny cells in geometric structures like k-d and relaxed k-d trees. This new approach sheds new light on the tight relationship between data structures like trees and tries that used to be studied separately. In particular, we show that digital search trees and the tries built from sequences generated by the same memoryless source share the same stable core. This link between digital search trees and tries is at the heart of our analysis of heights of tries. It permits us to derive the height of several species of tries such as the trees introduced by de la Briandais (1959) and the ternary search trees of Bentley and Sedgewick (1997). The proofs are based on the theory of large deviations. The first order terms of the asymptotic expansions of the heights are geometrically characterized using the Crame'r functions appearing in estimates of the tail probabilities for sums of independent random variables.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795c97f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nd12z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Trees (Graph theory) -- Data processing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xn89b"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A developmental study of normative ritualistic and compulsive behaviour in elementary school children</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zygmuntowicz, Catherine E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The high prevalence of compulsive-like behaviours in normal childhood suggests that these behaviours may play an important role in development. Furthermore, the similarities between the typical compulsive behaviours of childhood and the clinically significant behaviours that characterise Obsessive Compulsive Disorder (OCD) suggest that these two phenotypes may share similar neuropsychological profiles. In this study, two theories are investigated; one, that the neuropsychological deficits attributed to the pathogenesis of OCD also play a role in the manifestation of typical compulsive behaviours of childhood. Two, that compulsive behaviour supports the advancement of adaptive behaviour. The participants were 48 elementary school children (19 males) between the ages of 72 and 152 months (M= 106.5, SD = 24.49). Parents rated the frequency of typical compulsive behaviour on the Childhood Routines Inventory (CRI; Evans et al., 1997). Adaptive behaviour was assessed with the Vineland Adaptive Behavior Scales---Survey Form (VABS; Sparrow, Balla, &amp; Cicchetti, 1984). The measure of set shifting was the manual 64-card version of the Wisconsin Card Sort Task (WCST; Kongs, Thompson, Iverson, &amp; Heaton, 1981). Response inhibition was tested with the Conners' Continuous Performance Test (CPT; Conners, 2000) and the Tapping Test (Diamond &amp; Taylor, 1996). Stepwise multiple regressions were performed to examine the relationships amongst variables of interest. The participants were later divided into three groups (seven years and younger, seven to ten years, ten years and older) to examine relationships by age. Adaptive behaviour and response inhibition were predictive of levels of typical compulsive behaviour across the age range. Together, coping skills and play and leisure skills as assessed on the VABS emerged as the most important predictors of the repetitive compulsive behaviours. Response latency on the tapping task was the strongest predictor of increased levels of just right compulsive behaviour. Set shifting did not predict levels of compulsive behaviour although positive correlations were found in the youngest group. Overall, the data support the notions that clinical OCD and the typical compulsive and ritualistic behaviour of childhood share similar neuropsychological profiles, and that compulsive behaviour in childhood supports the development of increasingly advanced adaptive behaviour.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jw29m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xn89b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Adaptability (Psychology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Compulsive behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Child development</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag732df17g"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of Al- and Mg-based nanocomposites via solid-state synthesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al-Aqeeli, Naser</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le broyage mécanique est une technique hors équilibre qui permet la fabricationde nouveaux alliages avec des propriétés exceptionnelles. Lors de cette recherche, unbroyeur SPEX 8000 a été utilisé pour développer une nouvelle classe denanocomposites à base d'aluminium et de magnésium. Ces nanocomposites tirent leurspécificité de leur dispersion de nanocrystaux dans une matrice amorphe. Duzirconium a été ajouté aux alliages d'aluminium et de magnésium pour promouvoirl'amorphisation. Les échantillons de poudres broyées ont été recuits à 400°C pour 1heure pour évaluer la stabilité thermique des différentes phases. Leur évolution a étécaractérisée par diffraction par rayon-X et par MEBIEDS. TI fut démontré que lesphases métastables obtenues dépendent fortement de la composition des alliages dedépart.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Mechanical milling (alloying) is one of the non-equilibrium techniques used to prepare alloys with exceptional properties. This technique was employed in this research to develop a new class of Al- and Mg-based nanocomposite alloys using SPEX high energy milling. These nanocomposites are characterized by the dispersion of nanocrystals in an amorphous matrix. Zirconium was added to the Al-Mg alloys for the purpose of promoting glass formability. As-milled samples were annealed at 400°C for 1 hour to investigate the thermal stability of the nanostructure. The phase evolution of the resulting alloys was studied using XRD and TEM/EDS, which showed a strong dependence of the resulting metastable phases on the starting alloys compositions. The nanocomposite structure was developed at Zr concentrations of 20 and 35 at.% regardless of the Al/Mg ratio and with some traces of oxidation. However, the amount of amorphous phase was varied in each case depending on the Al concentration into the alloy, since in low Al-containing alloys the amount of amorphous phase was less pronounced. It was found that higher Zr concentrations will lead to greater refinement of the nanostructure. These nanocomposites showed improved mechanical properties, in terms of higher hardness values, in addition to improved thermal stability. The improvement in thermal stability was attributed to the presence of Al3Zr which proved to contribute significantly to retarding grain growth via grain boundary pinning. Additionally, the employment of mechanical alloying was beneficial in producing Al3Zr in the cubic L12 ordered structure which improves the ductility of the alloy. Moreover, the homogeneity ranges of gamma-Al 12Mg17 and Al3Zr were extended significantly due to the nature of the non-equilibrium processing. In this research, the alloy with the maximum hardness was Al40Mg25Zr35, which has an average hardness value close to 780 HV and average crystallite size of about 10 nm. A common observation in the alloys that showed a higher hardness values combined with improved thermal stability, is that they contain higher Al and Zr concentrations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80j0807.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732df17g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Composite materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mechanical alloying</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nanostructured materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>Zirconium alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aluminum-magnesium alloys</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hk808"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Metabolic profiling of potato cultivars varying in horizontal resistance to late blight, Phytophthora infestans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abu-Nada, Yousef</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Potato is one of the most important crops grown in Canada and all over the world. Late blight caused by P. infestans is one of the major diseases of potato and is mainly managed by fungicides application. The extensive use of fungicides not only causes adverse effects on the environment but also accelerates the development of resistance in this pathogen. Horizontal resistance is considered as the best choice to control P. infestans as it is durable over years. Breeding for durable resistance requires evaluation of hundreds of breeding lines in greenhouses and in the field. This is usually done by testing several epidemiological parameters such as infection efficiency, lesion size, latent period, and area under disease progress curve (AUDPC). These methods are time-consuming and expensive. The present study reports standardization of metabolic profiling protocols and exploration of metabolic profiling based on GC/MS as an additional tool to discriminate resistance in potato against late blight. Potato cultivars varying in horizontal resistance against late blight have been inoculated with water or the pathogen and more than 100 metabolites have been tentatively identified by GC/MS. Univariate analysis has been used to identify several pathogenesis related (PR) and defense related (DR) metabolites that have potential for application as resistance biomarker metabolites. Multivariate analysis of the abundances of metabolites (the mass spectral (MS) ion trap detector outputs were obtained using Saturn Lab Software Version 5.52 and these abundances are positively proportional to the concentration of mass ions of metabolites) in cultivars were mainly used to identify pathogenesis and resistance functions. Following pathogen inoculation, several metabolites such as amino acids, organic acids, fatty acids and sugars, were significantly increased in abundances, especially in the resistant cultivar. Other metabolites such as phenylalanine, tyrosine, shikimic acid and malonic acid detected here are well known for their direct participation in the shikimic acid, the phenylpropanoid, and the malonic acid metabolic pathways. These pathways lead to the production of several defense metabolites including antimicrobial compounds including phenolics, flavonoids and phytoalexins. The metabolic profiling technology developed here has the potential application for screening of potato breeding lines for horizontal resistance against late blight.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dt626.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hk808</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Potatoes -- Disease and pest resistance -- Genetic aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Phytophthora infestans</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>