<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25xb48b"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of prenatal fluoxetine exposure on hippocampal serotonergic 1A receptors in adult male guinea pig offspring</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Malik, Saima</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Fluoxetine is a commonly used serotonin reuptake inhibitor effective in the treatment of depression. The aim of this study was to test if fluoxetine exposure during pregnancy has long-term effects on the serotonin system in offspring. The study initially determined the half-life and steady state levels of fluoxetine and its metabolite, norfluoxetine, in the nonpregnant female guinea pig, to enable dosage selection comparable to that therapeutically attained in humans. The main experiment assessed effects of gestational fluoxetine exposure on dams and pups. Pregnant guinea pigs received no treatment, or once daily injections of fluoxetine (7 mg/kg) or vehicle, from gestation day 1 until delivery. Hippocampal (CA1, CA2, CA3, dentate gyrus) serotonin 1A (5-HT1A) receptor densities were measured in male offspring at 63 days of age. Pregnancy length, number of stillborns, live litter size, and maternal and pup weight, were also examined. There were no significant differences in any of the pregnancy characteristics, dam or pup weight, or pup 5-HT1A receptor density, between the 3 treatment groups.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boksa, Patricia</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967562h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb48b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p906s"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dimethyl sulfide oxidation in the polluted marine boundary layer : a zero dimensional model study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Matthews, Desjanelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A comprehensive DMS oxidation reaction mechanism was added to a chemical box model (Model of Chemistry Considering Aerosols - MOCCA) to investigate how atmospheric sulfate levels are affected by pollution in the marine boundary layer. The interaction of a remote air mass with a polluted coastal air mass containing elevated NOx, alkane, and alkene levels was simulated for a mid-latitude region of the Northern Hemisphere. Model runs from different settings were compared with respect to species concentrations, branching ratios, and product yields. Results showed moderate decreases in gas phase DMS, DMSO, DMSO2, and MSA concentrations, and increases of approximately 7% and 100% for SO2 and H2SO4 , respectively. A sensitivity analysis was completed to determine how variations in temperature, DMS emission, NO emission, aerosol characterization, accommodation coefficients, PAN reactions, and a background SO2 emission influence the results.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ariya, Parisa</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps371.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p906s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290c42x"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis and characterization of optical fibres made from organic polymers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lugassy, Cyrille</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objective of the thesis is the preparation and study of properties of polymer optical fibres. The first part of the thesis describes the complete process of making polymer optical fibres from a monomer using styrene as a reagent. A solid preform is obtained from the polymerization before being drawn into a fibre. Once obtained, the fibre is characterized in terms of its chemical (composition), optical (acceptance angle, attenuation, refractive index profile), physical (elongation-to-break) and spectroscopic (Infrared, Raman, NMR) properties. Polarized Raman spectroscopy is employed to analyse the conformation of the polymer molecules in the fibre. The results of the spectroscopic studies show an axial symmetry around the main axis of the fibre. Symmetry is created when the fibre is drawn. In the second part of the project, styrene is copolymerized with glycidyl methacrylate. The latter has an epoxy group on its side chain that can be polymerized independently from the vinyl group. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Andrews, Mark P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225c942.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c42x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw0892c76x"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Habitat selection by red-tailed hawks (Buteo jamaicensis) in prairie landscapes managed for enhanced waterfowl recruitment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fontaine, Alain Jacques</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the Canadian prairies, native grasslands have been largely replaced by an agricultural landscape with a mosaic of habitats now better described as aspen parkland. Although habitat requirements of true prairie Buteo species, Swainson's (Buteo swainsoni) and ferruginous hawks (B. regalis), are relatively well identified, little is known about habitat use by red-tailed hawks (B. jamaicensis ) in this ecoregion. This study, evaluating productivity and habitat selection of red-tailed hawks breeding in aspen parkland, was conducted on Prairie Habitat Joint Venture (PHJV) assessment sites in central Saskatchewan in 1997 and 1998. Red-tailed hawk nesting densities and productivity were determined at three sites. Home ranges were mapped. Macrohabitat use and availability data were generated from digitized aerial photographs of PHJV assessment sites using a Geographic Information system. Microhabitat variables were measured in 0.04 ha plots centered on nests and random locations. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, David M.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Titman, Rodger D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816p41b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c76x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Habitat selection</dc:subject><dc:subject>Red-tailed hawk -- Habitat -- Saskatchewan</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kc58z"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expression, purification, and NMR of two archaebacterial proteins in the context of structural genomics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Finak, Grzegorz</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The NMR solution structure of TM0983, a thermostable protein from Thermo-oga Maritima was solved with minimal constraints as part of a large scale structural proteomics project. A putative function for this protein was assigned based on a structural homolgy search using DALI. Measurements of 15N-1H residual dipolar couplings were performed and used to further refine the structure. These restraints decreased the backbone RMSD from 0.9 to 0.683, and helped to identify a cis peptide bond between C36 and P37. Another thermostable protein, MTH1440, from Methanobacter Thermoautotrophicus was purified for the purpose of NMR structural studies. The purification procedure was optimized to increase sample solubility for NMR. Phi-BLAST identified MTH1440 as a member of the Sm protein family. In other organisms these proteins form the core of the spliceosome. Additionally, several bottlenecks were identified in the process of the purification and NMR of these two proteins with repercussions on large-scale structural proteomics projects.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gehring, Kalle</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rq60k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc58z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av979v487f"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Textural and mass transfer characteristics of chicken nuggets during deep fat frying and oven baking</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>El-Dirani, Khaldoun</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effects of deep fat frying and oven baking on mass transfer (moisture loss and oil uptake), color and textural characteristics of chicken nuggets were studied. Deep fat frying was performed at three oil temperatures, namely 150, 170 and 190°C. The frying times were 1, 2, 3 and 4 min. Oven baking was accomplished at three temperature levels: 200, 220, and 240°C, and the baking times were 10, 15, 20 and 25 min. Moisture content of the breading portion of the fried chicken nuggets decreased following a typical drying curve and ranged from 0.90 to 0.22 g/g (db), while the moisture content of the core portion of the chicken nuggets decreased almost linearly and ranged from 1.96 to 1.4 g/g (db). Fat contents of the breading and core portions increased linearly with time. Generally, frying temperature significantly affected the moisture contents of the breading and core. It also affected the fat content of the core but not that of the breading. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ngadi, Michael O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h3722.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v487f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cookery (Chicken)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Convenience foods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Deep frying</dc:subject><dc:subject>Baking</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237ht69m"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"I can't see your eyes well 'cause your nose is too short" : an interactivity account of holistic and configural face processing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Farivar, Reza</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>What is meant by configural and holistic processing? The present project attempts to answer this question by formalizing configural and holistic processing as interactive processing of face parts. Four face images were created from one main face by varying the eye distance and nose length of the face to yield a 2x2 feature-complete factorial combination set of stimuli. Participants viewed each version of the face for 100 msecs, and then identified the face they saw. Their responses were subjected to multidimensional signal detection analysis to obtain estimates of different types of perceptual interactions defined by General Recognition Theory (Ashby &amp; Townsend, 1986). It is shown here that perception of upright faces exhibits a number of interactions that are not present for inverted faces. The nature of these interactions are linked to concepts of holistic and configural face processing. A computational justification is forwarded for this interactivity account of face processing.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chaudhuri, Avijit</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r5108.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237ht69m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Face perception</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab2773x628"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The distribution of a water strider, Aquarius remigis, among habitat patches explained by sex specific dispersal strategies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bang, H. Helen (He Won Helen), 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A survey of a natural population of Aquarius remigis, a stream dwelling water strider, living in East Turkey Creek, Arizona, USA, revealed that they were mostly found in either pairs consisting of one male and one female, or in small female biased groups. Chi-squared analysis confirmed that this finding was not due to random chance. The sex ratios were manipulated to further test this observation, that is, that the water striders would return to the most commonly observed sex ratio combinations even after being deliberately rearranged. Pairs of water striders or female biased sex ratios were observed in the experimental pools after a 24 hour period. Behavioural experiments conducted in the laboratory were performed to investigate the possible behavioural interactions that could influence the sex ratios observed in the field. Artificial pools with three water striders, in four sex ratio combinations, and four water striders, in five sex ratio combinations, were used. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lewis, David</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jablonski, Piotr</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150m02k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x628</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sexual behavior in animals</dc:subject><dc:subject>Water striders -- Dispersal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Water striders -- Reproduction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719p16r"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Public opinion and international development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Klyve, Christoffer Ringnes</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores public attitudes towards international development cooperation. Noting the lack of previous academic treatment of this particular topic, it includes an overview of available polling data on relevant questions, followed by a review of more general literature pertaining to public opinion towards foreign policy, as a macro-level concept. Finding the macro-level perspective insufficient, the thesis then explores one particular model for understanding public opinion on the individual level. The final chapter discusses in some detail how one particular form of development assistance---child sponsorship---might influence public opinion. Claims that child sponsorship necessarily has detrimental effects on public opinion are found to have little foundation in either empirical studies or relevant theory. Conclusive statements concerning any effect child sponsorship might have on public opinion are not made, but the thesis does argue that public opinion towards development assistance can, under certain conditions, be considered reasonable.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Straw, Will</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698943g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719p16r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economic assistance -- Public opinion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economic development -- Public opinion</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pc39h"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Implementation of Monte Carlo treatment planning for lung cancer patients</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al-Yahya, Khalid S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Current dose photon calculation algorithms have shortcomings in calculating dose distributions accurately in complex, heterogeneous phantoms. In this work, using existing Monte Carlo (MC) algorithms, we implemented and validated a comprehensive MC treatment planning system (MCTPS). We compared MCTPS with the corrected pencil beam algorithm used in the commercial TPS, CadPlan (V2.7.3). The accuracy of dose distributions calculated by MCTPS was studied for six lung cancer patients in two modes: without correction for inhomogeneity (the clinically used method) and with the equivalent tissue air ratio (EgTAR) inhomogeneity correction switched on. Without the use of inhomogeneity corrections, absorbed dose estimated by CadPlan is in error by more than 10% in the planning target volume (PTV). With the EgTAR correction, good agreement was observed for the dose to the PTV, however, in regions close to an interface, where a significant density gradient occurs, the error is up to 10%. Dose errors in other organs were studied using differential dose volume histograms.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Seuntjens, Jan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk464.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc39h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Radiation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612q56v"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synoptic-scale signatures of warm-season mesoscale vortices in the Montreal region</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bocquet, Florence</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two classes of warm-season meteorological events in Southern Quebec have been studied. (1) thunderstorms and (2) mesocyclones detected by radar. Characterization of the synoptic-scale flow accompanying warm-season mesoscale vortices and isolation of the moisture flow are documented. A comparison of both 500-hPa height and dynamic tropopause potential temperature composite fields between each set is completed. Precipitable water content and mixing ratio composites of the two classes are diagnosed. The storm sample associated with mesocyclones show an organized trough-ridge couplet 3 to 4 days before the onset time. Strong precursors of coherent dynamic tropopause forcing seen several days in advance for the mesoscyclones are not as apparent in the thunderstorm sample. During several days prior to the events, the Atlantic Ocean, the Gulf of Mexico and the Great Lakes form a wider and more active area feeding moisture into the mesocyclonic systems than into the thunderstorms.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gyakum, John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816p42m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612q56v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aww72bd56r"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The underground press of the sixties</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ruvinsky, Maxine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse décrit la presse clandestine aux États-Unis dès le commencement du mouvement des journaux secrets dans les années 60's jusqu'à sa mort apparente vers le début de la décennie suivante. J'utilise des articles des journaux clandestins aussi bien que des idées et de:; théories littéraires et socio-culturelles pour illustrer l'essence du mouvement et la façon dont il se reflète dans la langue et la littérature des journaux, afin de comprendre son développement rapide et sa disparition évidente au début des années 70's. Je me concentre sur l'idéalisme qui démontre ces journaux clandestins. Par ce terme "l'idéalisme journalistique" je veux dire la conviction que la société serait améliorée si ses malheurs étaient dévoilés et démasqués par un journalisme qui fait preuve de civisme - une conviction qui représente la pierre angulaire de la presse quotidienne en Amérique du Nord. Dans ce sens-là, les journaux clandestins ont réanimé les idéaux précédents d'une presse libre dans une société démocratique. Je conclus que l'idéalisme journalistique de la presse clandestine des années 60's a été maîtrisé, contenu et travesti, mais non détruit. Néanmoins, parmi les questions que pose cette thèse, les plus profondes sont celles de nature hégémonique et celles des mouvements populaires pour la justice sociale plus particulièrement, celles des problèmes qu'ont vécu les journaux concernant le statu quo et ses autorités officielles. La ralionale théorique pour traiter l'écriture journalistique d'un genre littéraire (plutôt qu'une sorte de moyen de communication) c'est justement d'en faire ressortir certains des codes dont dépend l'écriture journalistique pour communiquer la signification (et non pas seulement les informations) d'un texte.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the underground press of the sixties in the United States, from the beginning of the movement in mid-decade to its apparent demise in the early seventies. I use articles from the underground papers to illustrate the nature of the underground press and apply literary and socio-cultural theories and thinking to the phenomenon in order to chart and analyze its rapid development and speedy disappearance early in the seventies. I focus on the journalistic idealism represented by the papers. By journalistic idealism, I mean the belief that society could be improved if its ills were exposed by journalism conducted in the public interest--the founding faith of the daily press in America. In this sense the underground papers recalled the earlier ideals of a free press in a democratic society. I conclude that the journalistic idealism of the sixties was contained and perverted, but not destroyed. The deeper questions posed here, however, concern the nature of hegemony and of social movements for change and their particular problems with respect to the status quo and its official authorities. The theoretical justification for treating newswriting (generally) as a form of literature (rather than a form of "communications"), is to reveal some of the codes it relies upon to convey meaning (rather than simply information).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Szanto, George</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193b87t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd56r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Underground press -- United States</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zw37h"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of the mouse DNA methyltransferase gene expression</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rouleau, Julie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A hallmark of DNA methylation is the fact that 60 to 80% of CpG dinucleotide sequences in the vertebrate genome are methylated at the 5th-position of cytosine while the remaining unmethylated sequences are nonrandomly distributed throughout the genome generating a pattern of methylation that is both tissue and gene specific. Several lines of evidence suggest that methylation patterns correlate with the expression level of eukaryotic genes and that DNA methylation plays an important role in regulating the state of differentiation of mammalian cells. The methylation of DNA is catalyzed by the DNA methyltransferase (DNA MeTase) enzyme, which transfers a methyl group from S-adenosylmethionine to DNA. Cells that exhibit different DNA methylation patterns express similar mRNA levels and DNA MeTase activities. It has therefore been suggested that patterns of methylations are the result of an interplay between the level of the nonspecific DNA MeTase enzyme and other site- or tissue-specific nuclear factors; changing either one of these parameters will result in a change in DNA methylation patterns. In accordance with this hypothesis it has been proposed that regulation of DNA methyltransferase gene expression plays a role in the maintenance and generation of DNA methylation patterns, as is the case in prokaryotic systems. Bestor et al., cloned the cDNA encoding the mouse DNA MeTase gene but nothing was known about the elements regulating its expression. To further understand regulation of the mouse DNA MeTase gene expression I cloned and sequenced the 5$ sp prime$-upstream region of the gene and demonstrated that: (A) The mouse DNA MeTase promoter is a unique housekeeping promoter lacking the classical binding sites for known transcription factors. (B) The mouse DNA MeTase is induced by the Ras-AP-1 pathway. (C) Induction of the mouse DNA MeTase by the Ras-AP-1 leads to profound changes in cell morphology, methylation patterns and tumorigenicity all of which can be inhib</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Szyf, Moshe</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w9346.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw37h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9306t1095"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Toward the paradigm of a knowledge based electromagnetic design system : a case based reasoning approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rong, Ruowen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Human designers use previous designs extensively in solving new design problems and Case-Based Reasoning (CBR) provides a knowledge representation paradigm which attempts to model such process. In this thesis we present a case-based approach to solving design problems by retrieving similar previous designs and adapting them to meet the new problem. A system called CBEDS (Case-Based Electromagnetic Design System) has been developed. The thesis describes the knowledge organization for a case database which represents the semantic content of electromagnetic device designs and how to use feature extraction methods to reduce the indexing dimension of designs. A method based on interval constraint propagation has been developed to determine the valid range of design parameters. We argue that the adaptation of retrieved design cases requires an understanding of how the parameters of the device behave to accomplish the device's function. The thesis presents a case adaptation method which is based on algebraic constraint propagation and a primitive type of qualitative mathematical reasoning system which can predict how a change in one design parameter would affect the others. The advantage of our approach in building a knowledge based systems is the ease of adding new knowledge. Once a new design problem has been solved, it can be added to the case library updating the knowledge base. Such a system can be adaptive and will incrementally improve itself over time.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lowther, D. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dv02p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t1095</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811km579"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dependency and self-criticism : individual differences in strategies for negotiating changes in and threats to social rank</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Santor, Darcy A. (Darcy Allan)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The two studies reported in this thesis examine the influence of two depressive personality styles, dependency and self-criticism, on how individuals respond to potentially disruptive events, such as a change in or threat to social rank. The studies used an experimental protocol in which participants were allowed to believe firstly that they outperformed a close friend or were outperformed by a close friend and secondly that friends generally agreed or disagreed with them. Findings offer support for the integration of depressive personality styles and interpersonal factors within a social rank framework. Results from the two studies suggest that dependency and self-criticism (a) moderate the impact of interpersonal events, (b) influence how individuals behave towards close friends, (c) affect how individuals remember interpersonal interactions with others, and (d) moderate the manner in which individuals actively structure their social environments. Depressive personality styles may contribute to maladaptive environments and depressive processes in complex ways by influencing the types of strategies individuals adopt to deal with threats to interpersonal relatedness and self-definition.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zuroff, David C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634570r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km579</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Self-esteem</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dependency (Psychology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Depression, Mental -- Social aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278w16w"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Communication et interculturalité en Afrique de l'Ouest francophone</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Péricard, Alain</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study of interculturality ("intercultural competence"), its foundations and its effects in francophone Western Africa reveals the need for a reconceptualization of intercultural communication. A theory of interculturality should be interdisciplinary, non-positivist, critical and reflexive. Because conventional approaches and their applications create a spatial and temporal distance, and undervalue endogenous knowledges, they limit understanding and hamper reciprocal intercultural exchanges. The observation of communication processes around a sub regional West African organization (the "Communaute economique de l'Afrique de l'Ouest") reveals that interculturality is not a characteristic of better educated Africans or of those most exposed to foreign cultures, and even less of Whites or of other members of dominant groups. Rather, it is more pronounced among women, members of marginalized ethnic groups and, above all, among urban marginals. Interculturality manifests itself through interactions. It is the result of singular positions (standpoints) rooted in endogenous knowledges, in training (in its broadest sense) and in the experience of subordination in pluriethnic contexts. The texts that inform the dominant definitions of situations create a communicational and intercultural handicap, also linked to a superior status in the informal hierarchy. On the opposite, the mobility of an insider-outsider position confers an advantage, an aptitude for conversation, or for an egalitarian exchange in various local and imported spaces of culture and power. Such a position is a condition for intercultural studies and practices. Individually, it can be developed through a formal or informal initiation, empathy and an awareness of one's own limits. In development programs, the interculturality acquired by certain members of marginal groups is at the origin of processes of diversion--a reorientation of resources towards locally negotiated ends--which reveal the endogenous conceptions of participation and social change. The study of interculturality in Africa thus supports the idea that a communicational approach to intercultural problems could be fruitfully applied in other contexts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robinson, Gertrude J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m1283.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278w16w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Intercultural communication -- Africa, French-speaking West</dc:subject><dc:subject>Africa, French-speaking West -- Social conditions</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zq43f"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of aging and Parkinson's disease on reflex interactions during dynamic head-and-body tilts in human subjects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paquet, Nicole</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This doctoral thesis reports a series of studies aimed at exploring the control of body equilibrium during perturbations of the bipedal stance in healthy humans, and its modifications by aging and Parkinson's disease (PD). With the use of two unique experimental paradigms, we investigated reflex interactions during forward whole head-and-body tilts (WHBT) in healthy young and elderly subjects, and PD patients. We discovered that the excitability of extensor muscle responses to the stimulation of flexion reflex (FR) afferents was enhanced during WHBTs in young normal subjects. Such a functional output suggested that the specific needs of balance maintenance could have governed the reflex interaction during WHBTs rather than limb withdrawal. A significantly smaller proportion of elderly than young subjects showed an increase or a decrease of the FR in their ipsilateral tibialis anterior muscle (iTA) during WHBT. This indicated a lack of FR modifiability during dynamic perturbations of standing balance with aging. Such a change in reflex interaction could originate from a defect in the sensorimotor integration needed for the proper control of forward WHBT. PD patients were first characterized by a large increase in the excitability of their muscle responses to forward WHBT, which was accompanied by a much smaller increase in soleus H-reflex excitability during similar WHBTs. Second, they manifested a reduced FR modifiability during WHBT in comparison with age-matched normal subjects. Our findings suggest that PD might involve a specific difficulty to generate appropriate output from the interaction between flexor and extensor muscle responses. We hypothesise that an abnormal control of spinal interneurons in PD could be responsible for the tilting disorder and altered reflex interactions observed in these patients.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hui-Chan, Christina W. Y.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc597.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq43f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Human Development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956h813"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expression of the murine chromobox-containing genes M31 and M32</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Peterson, Karen R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Somatically heritable change in regional chromatin structure leading to transcriptional inactivation is observed in a variety of organisms. Euchromatic and heterochromatic domains have been proposed to be formed and maintained by the action of nonhistone chromosomal proteins that either bind directly to DNA or are members of chromatin binding protein complexes. The nonhistone chromosomal proteins M31 and M32 are candidate inducer or maintenance genes of repressed chromatin states in the mouse. I have investigated M31 gene organization and M31 and M32 gene expression to further examine the possible role of these genes in the formation or maintenance of heterochromatic domains. Investigation of the organization of the M31 gene reveals that at least five M31 transcripts are produced by alternative splicing of 9 exons and/or premature termination with polyadenylation. Several transcripts are present before cytologically visible heterochromatin is detected, suggesting that the products of these transcripts have a role in the formation of heterochromatic domains. M32 produces only one transcript whose tissue pattern of expression is similar to that of M31.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sapienza, Carmen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881n928.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h813</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8623j0800"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Complexity doctrines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Otto, James R. (James Ritchie)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We characterize various complexity classes as the images in set$ sp2,$ set$ sp{V},$ and set$ sp3$ of categories initial in various complexity doctrines. (A doctrine consists of the models of a theory of theories.) We so characterize the linear time, P space, linear space, P time, and Kalmar elementary functions as well as the linear time hierarchy relations. (Our machine model is multi-tape Turing machines with constant number of tapes.) These doctrines extend, using comprehensions, the first order doctrines GM and JB. We show, using dependent product diagrams, how to so extend the higher order doctrine LCC. However, using Church numerals, we show that the resulting LCC comprehensions do not provide enough control over higher order types to characterize complexity classes. We also show how to use sketches and orthogonality for almost equational specification.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barr, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv70p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j0800</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mp235"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Concrete properties and thermal stress analysis of members at early ages</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khan, Arshad A. (Arshad Ahmad)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research program presents an experimental study on the mechanical and thermal properties of different types of concretes at very early ages, (i.e., during hydration). These properties are investigated for temperature-matched curing, sealed curing and air-dried curing. Three types of concretes are studied including normal-strength (30 MPa), medium-strength (70 MPa) and high-strength (100 MPa) concretes. About 300 cylinders and 175 flexural beams were tested to determine the early-age mechanical properties including compressive stress-strain responses, gain of compressive strength, change in elastic modulus and variation of tensile strength. Creep frames and measuring devices were built to enable the experimental determination of early-age creep, with unloaded, companion specimens giving the corresponding shrinkage strains. A temperature-matched curing bath was developed to measure the heat of hydration and to subject 15 cylinders and 12 flexural beams to temperature-matched curing. The thermal properties investigated included the heat of hydration, the thermal conductivity, the specific heat and the coefficient of thermal expansion. Expressions are proposed to predict the development of compressive strength, elastic modulus and modulus of rupture as a function of the type of concrete and the type of curing. Sub-routines were developed for a finite element thermal analysis program "DETECT" to predict the variation of temperatures during hydration. Additional sub-routines, using the maturity concept, predicted the compressive strength, elastic modulus and tensile strength of each element, in the time domain. An experimental study was performed to observe the effect of different curing conditions and early-form stripping on the temperature and strain development in structural concrete members. Comparisons are made between the measured and predicted temperatures in large concrete columns and precast tee beams and slabs. Sub-routines were developed to enable incremental stress analysis in the time domain to account for the rapidly changing material properties and the influence of creep. Predictions of the risk of cracking were made and compared with observations from experiments on concrete elements during hydration. Parametric analyses were carried out to determine the influence of key thermal properties, time of formwork removal, creep, and concrete strength on the thermal gradients developed and the risk of thermal cracking.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mitchell, Denis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fz607.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp235</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject><dc:subject>Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dp29k"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of low pressure nitrogen on titanium cathode sources in TiN arc ion-plating</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kim, George E. (George Ea-Hwan)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The arc ion-plating technique is used in the industrial coating processes where TiN thin films are deposited onto various base materials. The overall objective of this research was to study the effects of low pressure nitrogen introduced into a continuous, titanium vacuum arc. An arc ion-plating system was designed and built to allow for as much flexibility as possible. Permanent magnets were placed behind the cathode surface to confine and rotate the arc. Changes in cathode, arc and emission properties were noted with respect to vacuum, argon and nitrogen ambients. The introduction of nitrogen, above a critical pressure ($ sim$1 $ times 10 sp{-3}$ Torr), increased arc velocity and decreased crater diameter, erosion rate and ion emission. This occurred when arc rotation was combined with nitrogen introduction. Thermal properties of the cathode during arcing seemed to play an important role in determining the extent of nitrogen-cathode interaction. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analysis has shown that nitriding occurred within the regions of arcing and was dependent on nitrogen pressure (with all other parameters remaining constant). The most encouraging result found was the complete elimination or macroparticles normally present in the coating/film.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Meunier, Jean-Luc</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q58d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp29k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225c95b"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Flow and drying characteristics of a rotating jet spouted bed</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jumah, Rami Yousef</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A novel rotating jet spouted bed (RJSB) is developed and tested. It consists of a rotating air distributor with two radially located spouting air nozzles. The effects of bed height, distributor rotational speed, nozzle diameter and particle properties on the flow characteristics were examined. Various flow regimes were mapped as functions of distributor rotational speed and superficial air velocity for different materials and column dimensions. Empirical correlations were developed for the minimum spouting velocity, peak pressure drop and steady spouting pressure drop. Drying kinetics of corn as a test material was investigated using both continuous and intermittent (on/off) spouting/heating schemes. The parameters investigated include inlet air temperature, bed height, superficial air velocity, nozzle diameter, distributor rotational speed and intermittency of spouting and heat input. The results indicate that the drying kinetics are comparable with conventional spouted and fluidized beds for slow drying materials and that intermittent drying can save up to 40% of the thermal energy consumption. A fully predictive diffusion-based mathematical model was developed and validated for both continuous and intermittent drying in the RJSB. Several other time-dependent spouting/heating schemes were evaluated numerically in the light of their potential practical applications.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mujumdar, A. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hb704.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225c95b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g2076"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Higher order QCD corrections to processes with polarized particles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kamal, Basim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>QCD higher order corrections (HOC) to three processes are considered: (i) Direct photon production in longitudinally polarized hadron-hadron collisions with numerical applications to proton-proton collisions; (ii) lepton-pair production in transversely polarized hadron-hadron collisions with numerical applications to proton-proton collisions; (iii) heavy quark pair production by polarized and unpolarized photons. The HOC to all three processes are found to be significant. Processes (i) and (ii) are shown to be sensitive probes of the proton's polarized gluon distribution and the transversity distributions, respectively. The asymmetries are found to exhibit perturbative stability. Process (iii) is considered as a background to $ gamma gamma rightarrow H sp* rightarrow b =b$ (standard model). As well, top-quark production not too far above threshold is considered.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Contogouris, A. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h13b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g2076</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53wx767"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Kinematics of manipulators with parellelism, modularity and redundancy : analysis and design</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Etemadi-Zanganeh, Kourosh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A general class of manipulators with hybrid kinematic chains is introduced. These manipulators are modular and can readily lead to kinematically redundant structures. Moreover, they may contain serial subchains as well as subchains of parallel modules, acting in parallel and connecting a base to a common end-effector. At the onset, a novel formalism is introduced to study modular kinematic structures. This includes some new concepts and definitions. The proposed formalism provides a systematic way to represent a complex hybrid manipulator through a hierarchy of its constituting modules. Next, a formulation is devised to study the instantaneous kinematics of these manipulators. The proposed formulation is general and can be applied to most of the existing parallel and hybrid manipulators. To realize the concept of general hybrid manipulator in practice, a few prototype designs are also introduced. The proposed prototypes are superior to their conventional counterparts in terms of dexterity and the volume of their workspace. The study is then extended to the theory of hyper-redundant manipulators that comprise, as a subclass, the variable-geometry trusses. A spline-based solution method is proposed for the inverse kinematics of hyper-redundant manipulators. The method is applicable to both extensible and nonextensible cases and includes planar as well as spatial manipulators. Also, a new variable-geometry truss is introduced whose modules themselves are kinematically redundant. Another practical aspect of redundancy is the use of redundant-sensor data to simplify inherent nonlinear direct kinematics of parallel manipulators. For a six-degree-of-freedom general parallel manipulator, we introduce a formulation of the direct kinematics whereby the positioning and orientation problems are decoupled by introducing two auxiliary parameters in the forms of either two angles or two lengths. This is in accordance with the type of redundant sensors, i.e., rotary or translational, to be used. Moreover, a real-time implementation of extra-sensor data, with a unique direct kinematics solution, is proposed by resorting to an eigenvalue problem. The parallelism in the proposed formulation enables the user to benefit from a parallel-computing environment. Hence, we introduce a parallel-computing algorithm that highly increases the robustness of the computational algorithm. The concept of kinematic isotropy has been used as a criterion in the design of serial and parallel robotic manipulators. However, all notions adopted to express isotropy in parallel manipulators have been based on the structure of the Jacobian matrices of serial manipulators. Here, we introduce a definition of kinematic isotropy that is well-suited to parallel manipulators. This is done by identifying the special structure of the Jacobian matrices involved in the differential kinematics of such manipulators. This leads to a partitioning of the Jacobian matrices into submatrices with dimensionally homogeneous entries. Moreover, based on the proposed definitions of isotropy and kinematic optimality, a set of conditions is derived that provides a systematic way for the optimum kinematic design of parallel manipulators, with or without structural constraints.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Angeles, Jorge</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm89z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx767</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arj4306636"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Novel thermally stable polymers synthesis and characterization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Elce, Edmund</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Novel amorphous thermoplastic poly(phenylquinoxaline)s (PPQ), poly(aryl ether ketone)s (PAEKs) and poly(aryl ether phthalazine)s have been synthesized. The reaction of an aromatic Schiff's base and a tertiary amine incorporating an activated methylene moiety in the presence of strong base to produce an enamine has been investigated. Hydrolysis of the resulting enamines resulted in deoxybenzoins which were converted to benzils by a mild oxidation reaction. This chemistry was investigated as a possible method for the synthesis of the tetraketone compounds (sometimes called bisbenzils) which serve as monomers for poly(phenylquinoxaline) polymers. Two novel monomers have been prepared, the corresponding polymers with 1,1$ sp prime$,2,2$ sp prime$-tetraminobiphenyl were synthesized and their physical properties evaluated. The novel polymers exhibited increased solvent resistance as compared to other PPQ polymers reported previously in the literature. Two novel fluorine containing monomers were synthesized and polymerized with commercial biphenols to produce amorphous, fluorinated poly(aryl ether ketone)s. The physical properties of these polymers were evaluated and compared to those of analogous nonfluorinated polymers in order to determine what benefits can be obtained by introducing fluorine into the polymer architecture. The fluorinated polymers were found to show enhanced solubility. They were readily soluble in solvents which contain a ketone moiety, such as acetone, or cyclohexanone. A novel dihalide monomer incorporating bulky 2-naphthalenyl moieties was synthesized and polymerized with commercial biphenols in an attempt to obtain poly(aryl ether ketone)s with extremely high glass transition temperatures (Tg's). Several poly(aryl ether ketone) polymers were reacted with hydrazine monohydrate in the presence of a catalytic quantity of acid to produce poly(aryl ether phthalazine)s via ring closure of the o-diketone moiety in the backbone of the PAEKs. The resulting polymers are amorphous thermoplastics which displayed increased glass transition temperatures (Tg) and Young's moduli. It was found that the poly(aryl ether phthalazine)s undergo a thermal reaction above the Tg of the polymer resulting in a rearrangement of the phthalazine moiety to a quinazoline moiety. Some crosslinking of the polymers also occurs, resulting in insoluble polymers which showed an increase in the Tg.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hay, Allan S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hm131.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj4306636</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>