<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zq115"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Being alive well : indigenous belief as opposition among the Whapmagoostui Cree</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Adelson, Naomi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Through an analysis of Cree concepts of well-being, I challenge conventional social scientific definitions of health. In this dissertation I argue that there exists a fundamental biomedical dualism in health studies and, using cross-cultural examples, explore an expanded notion of "health". I then introduce the Cree concept of miyupimaatisiiu ("being alive well") and explain that for the Whapmagoostui Cree there is no term that translates back into English as health. I present the core symbols of "being alive well" and in their analysis find a persistence of traditional meanings. For the Cree "being alive well" is consonant with "being Cree", simultaneously transcending the individual and reflecting current political realities. Miyupimaatisiiu for the adult Cree of Whapmagoostui is a strategy of cultural assertion and resistance and hence situated within the realm of political discourses.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268675d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq115</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cree Indians -- Social life and customs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cree Indians -- Health and hygiene</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50tt29b"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic and phenotypic parameters of lifetime performance traits in Canadian Holsteins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jairath, Lalit Kumar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Estimates of genetic and phenotypic parameters of lifetime performance traits and estimates of correlations between these and first lactation traits were obtained using multitrait mixed model and Restricted Maximum Likelihood (REML) methodologies, and accounting for all known additive genetic relationships amongst animals in sires pedigree. Part-lifetime performance traits, i.e. two-, three, and four-parity totals of yield and profit, were also included in the analysis. Data were on 82,835 Holstein cows, daughters of 703 sires, calving first between September 1979 and December 1984 in the herds enrolled in Quebec Dairy Herd Analysis Service (QDHAS). Lifetime performance records, however, continued through December 1989. Results of analysis indicated low estimates of heritability for lifetime performance traits, e.g., lifetime production and profit (.11$ sim$.13) and longevity (.07$ sim$.09). However, production per day of productive life traits had moderate heritability (.28$ sim$.32). Estimates of genetic and phenotypic parameters decreased from part-lifetime to total lifetime performance because residual variances increased at a greater rate compared to rate of increase in sire variances. Both genetic and phenotypic correlations amongst lifetime production, lifetime profit and longevity traits were very high and approached unity in all cases. Estimates of genetic and phenotypic correlations of first lactation production and profit traits with all measures of part and total lifetime performance were positive and high. These correlations decrease from part-lifetime to total lifetime performance due to part to whole relationships. Estimates of parameters of lifetime performance traits were mostly free of the effects of selection on milk production. Positive and high genetic correlation of first lactation milk yield with all lifetime performance traits indicated that selection on first lactation milk yield alone will improve all measures of lifetime performance. However, some consideration should be given to measures of reproduction and health which may help in improving the longevity of dairy cattle. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161782x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt29b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Holstein-Friesian cattle -- Canada -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Milk yield</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085m90v"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biological and biochemical properties of crystalline and amorphous proteins from Phaseolus beans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Zhuo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bipyramidal crystalline, spheroidal crystalline and amorphous proteins were prepared from following four seeds: white kidney, navy (Phaseolus vulgaris) beans; baby lima, large lima (Phaseolus lunatus) beans. A study of the biological properties of the proteins which exhibit the different microstructures, was carried out. The nature of tryptic inhibitory activity and alpha-amylase inhibitory activity were investigated. All protein showed both trypsin inhibitory and alpha-amylase activities; the kinetics of the alpha-amylase revealed non-competitive mechanism. The crystalline isolates showed lower trypsin inhibitory (TI) and alpha-amylase inhibitory (AI) activities than the amorphous isolates. The extents of tryptic hydrolysis (in vitro) were not related to TI indicating involvement of some other factors, in addition to trypsin inhibitory activity. Electropherograms of SDS-PAGE indicated that the major proteins of P. lunatus beans were more resistant to tryptic hydrolysis than the major fractions of the P. vulgaris. Phytate was found to have an effect on trypsin inhibition as well as on alpha-amylase inhibition; in the latter case, however, phytate complexed to protein was required for the inhibitory effect. There were no relationships between tannin content of the proteins and biological activity. Fractionation of bipyramidal crystalline and amorphous proteins by size exclusion chromatography showed that each isolate contained three fractions having approximate MW of 443,000, 200,000 and 150,000 daltons. The 200,000 MW fraction was a principal fraction. The fraction of 150,000 contained most of the trypsin inhibitory activity, alpha-amylase inhibitory activity was not detected in any of the fractions.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c217p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085m90v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Beans</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plant proteins -- Analysis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j709f"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of dietary cation-anion balance, stage of lactation and ration ingredients on acid base metabolism and productivity of dairy cows</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Delaquis, Annick Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Experiments were conducted to investigate the effects of formulating rations using different ingredients and of manipulating the cation-anion balance of the rations on production, acid-base status, metabolism of macrominerals and renal function of dairy cows. The effects of dietary cation-anion balance were studied during early, mid and late lactation as well as during the dry period. Feeding an alfalfa-haylage based diet vs a corn silage based diet, both having the same cation-anion balance did not affect the voluntary consumption, milk yield or milk composition of cows in early lactation. The acid-base status of the animals was not affected by dietary treatment. The lower urinary bicarbonate concentration observed with the alfalfa haylage-based diet was not associated with a lower total urinary bicarbonate excretion since urine volume was significantly higher than when cows were fed the corn silage-based diet. Manipulating dietary cation-anion balance, however, resulted in changes in acid-base status at all stages of lactation studied. Urinary bicarbonate concentration and total daily excretion were increased by a higher dietary cation-anion balance at all stages of lactation. Similar effects of dietary cation-anion balance on urinary bicarbonate did not, however, translate into similar changes in production or intake by cows at differing stages of lactation. Cows in early and mid lactation seemed to have benefited more from a highly positive dietary cation-anion balance than cows in late lactation or dry period.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xb10d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j709f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dairy cattle -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dairy cattle -- Feeding and feeds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Milk yield</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acid-base imbalances</dc:subject><dc:subject>Milk fever in animals</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2v23vv86g"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Renewable Resources</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of corn production and nitrogen cycling in the soil-plant system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liang, Baochang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Increased N fertilizer efficiency in crop production is essential for agronomic, economic, and environmental improvement. In order to increase efficiency, a basic knowledge of fertilizer-soil-crop relationships and components is required. Nitrogen components in the soil-corn system were determined on two soils (Chicot sandy clay loam, Grey Brown Luvisol; Ste. Rosalie clay, Humic Gleysol). Fall soil NO$ sb3 sp-$-N levels increased linearly with increasing N rates above the 170 kg ha$ sp{-1}$ N rate. Changes in soil NO$ sb3 sp-$-N over winter were a function of both fall soil NO$ sb3 sp-$-N levels and winter precipitation. Denitrification rates during the non-growing season ranged from 7 to 24 kg N ha$ sp{-1}$, mainly dependent on N fertilizer rates the previous growing season on the Ste. Rosalie soil. Denitrification losses were a small portion of NO$ sb3 sp-$ disappearance over the non-growing season. Almost all fertilizer N at 170 kg N ha$ sp{-1}$ was recovered as crop N, clay fixed NH$ sb4 sp+$ and organic immobilized N at the end of the growing season, where at 400 kg ha$ sp{-1}$ N fall mineral N and unaccounted for N were a major component of the N fractions. High rates (400 kg N ha$ sp{-1}$) compared to normal rates (170 kg N ha$ sp{-1}$) resulted in some increase in yield, greater microbial activity and greater soil organic N, and a significant loss of fertilizer N by denitrification or leaching.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v56d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vv86g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nitrogen cycle</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Fertilizers -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f757b"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Improvement of HAZ in multi-pass NG submerged arc welding</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lin, Yanping</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study emphasizes the effects of multi-pass narrow gap (NG) Submerged-Arc welding (SAW) on the Heat Affected Zone (HAZ). The differences between the HAZ of single-pass welds and multi-pass welds are radical and are caused by the subsequent thermal cycles which only exist in multi-pass welding. A series of experiments were carried out to establish the relationship between the welding thermal cycles and the mechanical and microstructural properties of a HAZ. Both real and Gleeble simulated HAZ's were investigated. Theoretical and experimental analyses indicate that the HAZ's in multi-pass welds can be improved significantly by the welding process itself. However, multi-pass welding does not always improve its HAZ. To realize the improvement, some special criteria must be met. The most important parameters are heat input, welding speed, deposit thickness and inter-pass temperature. This study establishes the relations between these parameters and the effects of HAZ refinement. There are some domains of the parameters in which HAZ refinement can be realized. The research reveals that in multi-pass NG welding, a set of welding parameters can always be found to fulfill the conditions for HAZ improvement. Real welding processes, with welding parameters optimized according to the analyses, were performed and a totally refined HAZ was achieved under laboratory conditions. It is suggested that the method can be applied to in situ welding situations. High heat input does not necessarily lead to inferior microstructural and mechanical properties in multi-pass NG welding. As long as the conditions for HAZ refinement are satisfied, an improved HAZ will be obtained no matter how high the heat input is. This also leads to the conclusion that the HAZ in multi-pass NG welding is less sensitive to heat input than that in single pass welding. The tempering parameter, which has been used to evaluate the tempering effects at constant temperature, is successfully introduced into welding (non-isothermal) conditions. The effects of precipitates in 2.25Cr-1Mo steel are theoretically investigated.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085m914.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f757b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290c126"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>X-ray diffraction analyses of synthetic polymers in the 3,3-substituted polyoxetane family and their copolymers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Parris, Juanita M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A series of crystalline, substituted polyoxetanes were studied using X-ray fibre diffraction as the primary investigative tool. Three systems were probed, each presenting a unique facet of structure analyses. The structure of poly(3,3-bis(hydroxymethyl)oxetane) using X-ray fibre diffraction was proposed. Modelling studies and FT-IR have been used to arrive at a probable conformation in which the backbone was found to be planar zigzag and the hydroxyls in the sidechain were extended. Few reflections were observed and it was not possible to grow lamellar single crystals for electron diffraction. The preliminary structure of poly(3,3-bis(hydroxymethyl)oxetane) diacetate using X-ray fibre diffraction on films and fibres and electron diffraction on lamellar single crystals provided a tentative packing scheme based on the most intense equatorial reflections. CP/MAS $ sp{13}$C NMR indicates slight deviations in the environments for the acetate groups on the same residue. X-ray fibre diffraction of atactic P(MHMO) resulted in a unit cell of comparable dimensions as in P(BHMO). The intensity and quality of the fibre patterns suggest identical structures. P(BHMO-co-MHMO) is a random copolymer in which the MHMO units are incorporated into the crystalline lattice of P(BHMO). One melting endotherm is observed for all compositions and decreases linearly with increasing content of MHMO. These data support a phenomenon known as isomorphism.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jg476.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c126</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Physical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj9602245w"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Case and syntactic geometry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Noonan, Máire B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The first part of this thesis addresses the following questions: where in the syntactic tree, and at what representational level is an NP Case-checked. To this end, it presents converging data from French, Welsh and Irish, which suggest (i) that Case-checking may be accomplished under a variety of functional projections (subject to parametric variation); and (ii) that Case positions are--at least partially--independent of the A/A$ sp prime$-distinction. It furthermore presents evidence from Irish and Welsh--VSO languages in which NPs typically raise to their Case position only at LF--that NPs are, under certain conditions, Case-checked at S-structure. Chapter 2 investigates word order and cliticisation in Standard French and Quebec French interrogatives and proposes a typology of interrogatives. Chapter 3 and 4 account for complementizer variation, pre-verbal particles and agreement patterns in Welsh and Irish under a Case-theoretic approach. The second part of this thesis concerns the conditions on the availability of structural accusative Case. A theory of structural Case is proposed according to which accusativity is a configurational rather than a lexical property--i.e., resulting from syntactic geometry and not from lexical feature specifications on verbs. To this end, a comparison between the syntactic mapping of stative and perfective predicates in Irish and English is undertaken.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v9500.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602245w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Case</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Noun phrase</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Syntax</dc:subject><dc:subject>French language -- Interrogative</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741t453"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Three essays on the theory and practice of defence procurement : the case of shipbuilding</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liston, Catherine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis we examine three aspects of procurement policy in the context of asymmetric information. In Chapter 1, we identify an incentive for the contracted firm to underinvest in the comprehensiveness of its internal accounting system, a result similar to that due to Averch and Johnson (1962). The policy implications of this distortion are analysed using both a theoretical construct and numerical simulation. In Chapter 2, we identify a class of distortions generated by the practice of paying 'progress payments' to contracted firms in a model in which 'real' and 'symbolic' progress are not inextricably linked, and in which the procurement agency observes only the latter. In Chapter 3 we construct a simple dual-sector model in which a paternalist government uses bailouts to sustain faltering firms. The firm, knowing the motivation of its client, has an incentive to exploit that knowledge. This complicates the procurement problem in a manner explored in Chapter 3.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967527x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t453</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Armed Forces -- Procurement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shipbuilding</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5m60qt602"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Réal Benoît : l'homme et l'oeuvre 1916-1972</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Desjardins, Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Real Benoit (1916-1972), a native of Sainte-Therese-de-Blainville, studied at Sainte-Therese Seminary and at Sainte-Croix College. His early career in journalism involved writing for "Le Soleil", "Le Petit Journal", "La Presse", "Horizons", "Le Jour" and "Regards". In the latter publication his first fiction appeared. In 1945 his anthology of fiction, Nezon, was well-received by the critics. Later, Benoit became news editor and music programmer for Canadian Broadcasting Corporation. After a trip to Brazil, he founded Benoit- de Tonnancour Films, a concern which ended in 1959. In 1960, Benoit became supervisor of network films for Canadian Broadcasting Corporation. From then until his demise in 1972, Benoit, profoundly affected by his long-time companionship with Andree Lariviere and by his second marriage to Francine Laurendeau, became a prolific writer: he published Rhum soda (trip novel), Mes Voisins (short novel), Quelqu'un pour m'ecouter (novel which obtained in 1965 The Grand Prix de la Ville de Montreal), and the dramas Le Marin d'Athenes and La Nuit de la Saint-Theodore, adapted for television by Jean-Paul Fugere. The drama Le Chant des grenouilles apres la pluie was published posthumously in 1973 by La Cercle du livre de France. Benoit's work was coloured by numerous personal sorrows, not the least of which were the breakup of his first marriage to Marthe Lafontaine, and the accidental death of his first son.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cv643.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt602</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Benoît, Réal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Benoît, Réal -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqv33rz275"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interannual temperature variability and cyclone frequency over eastern Canada and the New England States : a case study: winter seasons 1931-32 to 1984-85</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Daoust, Mario</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Interannual variability of temperature and cyclone frequencies for Eastern Canada and the New England States have been investigated for the winter seasons 1931-32 to 1984-85. Seasonal analyses have revealed that cyclone frequency has decreased by 21% over the research area; the highest losses occurring over the Maritimes and the New England States (30%) and in the southern Quebec-southwestern Ontario region (31%). The seasonal average temperature has remained fairly stable during the research period. However, the Temperature Variability Index (TVI) suggests that the interannual variability of temperature has been through some changes since 1931-32. The latest shift indicates that, since the early seventies, the temperature variability appears to be increasing during the winter season. Half-month periods were analyzed which revealed some features of the climatic variability during the winter season since 1931-32. Average temperature for the first 15 days of January recorded a significant decrease over the last 54 years. On the other hand, the last half of February presented a general increase in temperature. Parallel to that, the last half of January and the first 15 days of February have recorded substantial decreases in cyclone frequency. Thus, these half-month periods reveal trends which indicate that the overall winter season of the mid-seventies--early eighties differs from the prevailing winter climatic conditions of the thirties and forties.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074w85z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz275</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cyclones -- Canada, Eastern</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cyclones -- New England</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hb35j"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of maternal diabetes on fetal development in rats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Conliffe, Phyllis R. (Phyllis Rowena)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mechanisms underlying the high incidence of fetal abnormalities including fetal lung immaturity during maternal diabetes are not fully understood. Utilizing streptozotocin-diabetic rats as the model, I have examined the role of fetal hyperglycemia and hyperinsulinemia and other factors on fetal adrenal and lung functions in culture. Insulin and glucose did not alter fetal adrenal and lung cell proliferation and adrenal corticosterone output. On the other hand, a novel protein-bound, low molecular weight non-proteinaceous cytotoxic factor was detected in the serum of diabetic animals. In addition, a novel protein with cytostatic activity was found in fetal lungs, the concentration of which increased during diabetes. Partial amino acid sequence and Western Blot analysis revealed this protein to be similar to histone H2B. An extra-nuclear role is suggested for this protein because it appears to be present in the microsomal fraction of fetal lungs. It is concluded that fetal lung immaturity during diabetes may be contributed by cytotoxic and cytostatic factors contained in the serum and fetal lungs, respectively.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tq95w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb35j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Human Development</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pc05p"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comparison of microblade cores from East Asia and northwestern North America : tracing prehistoric cultural relationships</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Chun, 1948-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Intercontinental similarities in microblade technology have long been used as evidence in support of the hypothesis that human populations migrated from East Asia to northwestern North America during the late Pleistocene. This study synthesizes the available data in an effort to provide a preliminary overview of this technological tradition. Comparative analysis reveals that wedge-shaped cores from Chinese Upper Paleolithic assemblages, the Dyuktai Culture of eastern Siberia, Japan, and the American Paleo-Arctic Tradition of Alaska share many similarities in the selection of raw materials, core morphology, platform preparation and rejuvenation, and edge angle variation. However, it also reveals that Alaskan wedge-shaped cores are more closely related to Dyuktai Culture cores than they are to Hokkaido cores. The study concludes that the distribution of microblade complexes is best explained by migration and/or diffusion from inland Asia to North America during the late Pleistocene.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n80k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc05p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tools, Prehistoric -- East Asia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tools, Prehistoric -- North America</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m562p"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Theoretical and experimental study of the stability of clamped-free coaxial cylindrical shells subjected to internal and annular flows of viscous liquid</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nguyen, Vinhson Ba</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a theoretical and experimental study of the stability of cantilevered coaxial cylindrical shells conveying incompressible, viscous fluid inside the inner shell and/or in the annulus between the two shells. Two analytical models are developed with experimental verification. In the first model, fluid viscous effects are partially taken into consideration. Both shells are generally considered flexible. Shell motions are described by Flugge's shell equations, modified to take into account the steady viscous loads--flow pressurization and skin friction--acting on the shells. These equations are solved by means of the extended Galerkin method, in which the shell equations and the free-end boundary conditions can be satisfied simultaneously. The unsteady viscous forces are approximated by their inviscid counterparts, the formulation of which is based on linearized potential-flow theory with the assumption that the fluid is inviscid. The solution for these forces is obtained with the Fourier-transform technique; in connection with this technique, different so-called out-flow models are examined, concerning the effect of the downstream flow perturbations on the dynamics of the system. The second analytical model, on the other hand, fully accounts for the viscous effects of the flow. Here, only the inner shell is flexible, while the outer shell is replaced by an identical rigid cylinder. Shell motions are also described by Flugge's modified shell equations, which incorporate the steady viscous loads exerted on the shell. These equations are solved numerically with the finite-difference method. The unsteady viscous forces are evaluated from flow perturbations which are the solution of the linearized, unsteady Navier-Stokes equations subject to the divergence-free constraint on the flow velocity perturbation. A recently developed, time-marching finite-difference method using "artificial compressibility" is applied to solve the Navier-Stokes equations; for the problem under consideration, this method employs the pressure and velocity perturbations as the dependent flow variables on a staggered grid. In the experimental part of the thesis, tests involving either annular or inner flow are conducted on cantilevered silicone rubber shells concentrically located within rigid plexiglas cylinders. Measurements are made of (i) the critical flow velocity of the system for various lengths of the shell and annular widths, and (ii) the dominant frequencies of oscillation of the shell for certain selected cases. Both divergence- and flutter-type instabilities are observed. Comparisons between analytical results and test measurements show that the agreement between experiment and the two proposed analytical models is generally good, both qualitatively and quantitatively, in terms of the overall (lowest) critical flow velocities and frequencies of oscillation (first model only) of the tested shells. Finally, future work is suggested with regard to improving the second model and conducting further calculations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qr30h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m562p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A37720f44b"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The synthesis and biological activity of angularly functionalized decalin compounds against the spruce budworm, choristoneura fumiferana</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schwerdtfeger, Annette Elisabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A tandem Michael-Claisen (4C + 2C) annelation reaction based on the propensity of siloxy diene, 1-(tert-butyldimethylsiloxy)-1-methoxy-3-(phenylthio)-$ 5$-(methoxycarbonyl)-penta-1,3-dienoate, to undergo Michael reaction with 2-cyclohexen-1-one under Lewis acid catalyzed conditions was developed to give 3-(phenylthio)-4-methoxycarbonyl-$ 4$a,5,6,8a-tetrahydronaphthalene-1,8(4H,7H)-dione. Two functionalized 1,8-$ beta$-dicarbonyl decalin compounds, prepared via the tandem Michael-Claisen condensation, were hydroxymethylated at the angular position as the benzyloxymethoxy derivatives with diisopropylethylamine and benzyl chloromethyl ether in the presence of paraformaldehyde. The nature of this reaction was examined. The stereochemistry of cis-8a- ( ((benzyloxy)methoxy) methyl) -3-(phenylthio)-4a,5,6,8a-tetrahydronaphthalene-1,8(4H,7H)-dione was confirmed by X-ray analysis of its ethylene ketal derivative. The ((benzyloxy)methoxy) methyl derivative mentioned above was employed as the intermediate in the preparation of a variety of angularly functionalized decalin compounds leading to the synthesis of three key keto diacetates. The methylenation of these keto diacetates was not successful, due to the steric hindrance experienced by the ketone functionality in these cis-fused decalin systems. When the angularly functionalized decalin compounds were tested for their biological activity against the spruce budworm, Choristoneura fumiferana, seven compounds were found to exhibit moderate activity similar to a specionin analog prepared earlier in this laboratory.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j711g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720f44b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Organic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Agricultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az029p630t"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Upper Devonian buildup development in the southern Canadian rocky mountains : a sequence stratigraphic approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McLean, David J. (David John)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Buildup interior cycle stacking patterns and buildup margin geometries of Frasnian Fairholme Group reef complexes suggest that deposition and buildup stratigraphy were controlled by short-term and long-term fluctuations in relative sea-level. Correlation of these stacking patterns, and regional trends in buildup margin morphology, reveal a hierarchy of fifth, fourth, and third order sea-level changes driven by an allocyclic mechanism. The Caim Formation consists of shallowing upward hemicycles (fifth order). These are grouped into larger, broadly shallowing upward trends (fourth order). The Caim Formation and the overlying Peechee Member represent a single third order depositional sequence deposited during an overall period of sea-level rise. The dominantly retrograding buildup margins of the Peechee Member also reflect the influence of rising sea-level, punctuated by relative stillstands. Reciprocal siliciclastic basin sedimentation and buildup carbonate sedimentation characterized Peechee buildup margins. The dominantly retrograding buildup margins of the Fairholme Group are characteristic of transgressive systems tracts. Buildup margins developed progradational or vertically aggradational geometries due to prevailing circulation patterns and the manner of basin filling.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz175.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p630t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c4337"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The muscle activation and reflex modulation pattern during locomotion in normal and spastic paretic subjects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fung, Joyce</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The lower limb electromyographic (EMG) patterns of 5 normal and 8 spastic paretic subjects during walking were compared. A dynamic EMG profile index, proposed to quantify spastic locomotor dysfunction, was found to be homogeneously low in normal subjects and abnormally high in spastic subjects. In another study, the normally phase-dependent modulation of the soleus H-reflex during walking was found to be decreased or absent in 21 spastic paretic subjects, suggesting the possibility of defective reflex gating mechanisms. The conditioning effects of plantar cutaneomuscular stimulation were further examined in 10 normal and 10 spastic paretic subjects. The conditioned H-reflex was inhibited in a task and phase-dependent manner, such that the effects were most marked during early stance and swing, restoring a near normal modulation pattern during walking in the severely spastic subjects who showed no modulation previously. The possible underlying mechanisms and implications for rehabilitation are discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z366.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c4337</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bg690"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigation of vapor explosions with single molten metal drops in water using flash X-ray</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ciccarelli, Gaby</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the present study, flash x-ray photography as well as high speed regular photography was used to investigate the fragmentation process during the vapor explosion of single drops of molten metal in water. For drops heated to 700$ sp circ$C, a vapor bubble is formed around the drop after a short induction time of about 80 $ mu$s which grows to a maximum diameter and then collapses. X-ray radiographs, which can "see through" the vapor bubble, show that filaments of metal protruding from the drop surface are produced during the bubble growth. At the time of the bubble collapse, the drop surface is highly convoluted and a second interaction is initiated producing an even larger second bubble in the case of tin drops. A mechanism based on nonuniform superheating and evaporation of the water upon unstable film collapse is proposed to describe the origin of the melt filaments. For liquid drops under isothermal conditions with the water, fragmentation occurs as mass is stripped off the surface due to relative motion of the water. For hot drops at higher flow velocities (i.e., $&gt;$45 m/s) initially a vapor bubble forms but it is quickly displaced downstream. It is proposed that evaporation at the upstream surface of the bubble generates a vapor flow around the drop surface which strips the drop surface. The vapor flow carries the fragments into the bubble region behind the drop. The vapor later condenses leaving a cloud of fragments which are subsequently dispersed by the water. The dynamics of the vapor bubble produced by the explosion of a hot drop under low flow conditions is modeled using a parametric model incorporating the Rayleigh equation for bubble dynamics and an energy equation for the vapor to account for added heat transfer from the distorting drop surface. Estimates of the total heat transferred from the drop show that only 3% of the initial drop thermal energy is converted into work done by the vapor bubble.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s1617836.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bg690</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rw08t"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The struggle for authority in the nineteenth century Shiʻite community : the emergence of the institution of Marjaʻ-i Taqlīd</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kazemi-Moussavi, Ahmad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Shi'ite orthodoxy, represented by the Usuli trend, introduced a new institution, i.e. marja'-i taqlid, in the middle of the thirteenth/nineteenth century when the struggle for the authority of the Imam was heightened by the representatives of speculative thought in Shi'ism. This institution combined the status of the most learned mujtahid with the charisma derived from the vicegerency of the Imam of the Age without committing itself to miraculous performances or directly jeopardizing the ruling establishments. The Usuli orthodoxy successfully fought the Akhbaris' detachment from the formal bases of argumentation on the one hand and the direct pretension to the authority of the Imam by the Sufis and Shaykhis on the other hand. The Usulis not only placed the marja'-i taqlid at the head of the Shi'ite learned hierarchy, but gave his pronouncements as of binding authority for the community. Marja'-i taqlid benefitted from the growth of popular religion among post-Safavid Iranians whose religious alms and charities guaranteed the financial independence of the supreme mujtahids. Marja'-i taqlid played important roles in the socio-political development of the Shi'ite people of Iran and Iraq either by legitimizing their constitutional and reformist movements or opposing colonialist and Westernizationist processes. However, in practice, the institution of marja'iyat escaped any attempts to embed the institution into the constitutional system or into any formal structure of juristic hierarchy.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v7094.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw08t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Shīʻah -- Doctrines</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islamic law -- Sources</dc:subject><dc:subject>Authority -- Religious aspects -- Islam</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q793b"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Licensing and the representation of floating nasals</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tourville, José</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is commonly agreed that phonological elements must be prosodically licensed in order to be interpreted phonetically (cf. Ito, 1986). The licensing of segments is generally assumed to follow from the Universal Association Conventions. The licensing of phonological units smaller than the segment, however, has not been fully addressed. There is no agreement on the exact licensing mechanisms at play and on what constitutes a proper anchor for the initial association of floating subsegmentals. This thesis proposes a principled account of subsegmental licensing within the theory of segmental structure known as feature geometry, as modified by Piggott (to appear). It is shown that the manifestation of nasality in Maukaka, Koyaga, Jula, and Terena result from the way licensing operates. It is argued that, universally, floating subsegmental units are licensed through mapping, which associates a unit to an available position. It is also proposed that whenever there is no proper position for the mapping of a subsegmental element, this element may be licensed by Chomsky-adjunction. This type of adjunction has played a role in syllabification but not in the organization of feature.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j956n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q793b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nasality (Phonetics)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Terena language -- Phonology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mau dialect (Côte d'Ivoire) -- Phonology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dyula language -- Phonology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483k89q"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Islam, Islamic leadership and community development in Tanga, Tanzania</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chande, Abdin Noor</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study which focusses on a coastal Swahili society, examines the economic, political and social evolution of the Tangan Muslim community through the various phases of its history. The study pays specific attention to the role played by religious leaders, whether as competitors, or simply as madrasa teachers in a community with a tradition of Islamic scholarship. At the macro-level, the relationship between various Muslim organizations and the state also receives our scrutiny. This is done through analysis of the educational system and its structuring of the social order. Finally, we assess the views of the Tangan religious leadership regarding religion and society against a general discussion of intra-religious issues and political developments in the country, thereby achieving a better understanding of Islam in contemporary Tanzania.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96022465.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483k89q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tanga (Tanzania) -- Religious life and customs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islam -- Tanzania -- Tanga</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ulama -- Tanzania -- Tanga</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islamic education -- Tanzania -- Tanga</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j712r"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Nursing</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Conjugal support, family coping behaviours and well-being of the elderly couple</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ducharme, Francine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to test the relationship between conjugal support, family coping behaviours and the well-being of the elderly couple. A multistage sample of 135 couples, 65 years and over, was drawn from users of the health and social system, as well as from non-service users, in a large metropolitan area. Data were collected through home visits. A series of questionnaires to measure conjugal support, family coping behaviours, three indicators of well-being (self-assessed health, life satisfaction and marital satisfaction), and selected control variables were presented in interview format separately to each marital partner by two interviewers. Data analysis was performed on individual and couple data. Results revealed significant positive correlations between availability and reciprocity of conjugal support and well-being of both marital partners and a negative association between conflict within the conjugal relationship and well-being of husbands and wives. Only two cognitive family coping strategies, reframing and avoidance of passive appraisal, were positively related to the well-being of both partners. External family coping strategies related to seeking help outside the elderly dyad were not associated with well-being. Paired t-tests revealed that husbands tended to perceive more support from their spouse and to be more satisfied with their marital life than wives. Wives more than husbands perceived the couple to use more external social support and spiritual support. Repeated measures analysis of variance revealed that congruency of perception between husbands and wives had an effect on the well-being of the wives only. A path model in which conjugal support has direct and indirect effects on well-being through cognitive family coping strategies is proposed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537273q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j712r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology, Individual and Family Studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Nursing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gerontology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613n022v"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A unified ligand effect in Co(III) complexes : decarboxylation, phosphate diester hydrolysis and methyl acetate hydrolysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moore, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effect of ligand structure on the reactivity of a diverse group of aqua-hydroxytetraazacobalt(III) complexes towards the hydrolysis of phosphate diesters and carboxylic esters has been investigated. It has been shown that the magnitude of the N-Co-N bond angle that lies opposite to the aqua-hydroxy ligands is influential in determining which complexes are best able to stabilize a strained four-membered ring, and this has been related to the relative rates at which these complexes promote reactions involving four-membered ring formation. The great range of rates of acid catalyzed decarboxylation of the carbonato derivatives of these complexes has been explained in terms of the same ligand-effect, and a correlation between the rate of this reaction and Co(III) aqua-hydroxy promoted phosphate diester hydrolysis and carboxylic ester hydrolysis has been established. The relationship between reactivity of a complex towards phosphate diester hydrolysis and mode of binding of inorganic phosphate has been elucidated. The true catalysis of methyl acetate hydrolysis by the two complexes ((13aneN$ sb4)$Co(OH)(OH$ sb2)$) $ sp{2+}$ and ((cyclen)Co(OH)(OH$ sb2)$) $ sp{2+}$ has been demonstrated, it has been shown that complexes which are capable of this kind of catalysis can bind acetate as a chelate.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm59b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n022v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m563z"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Human Communication Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Communicative features in early conversation building hearing-impaired and normally hearing children and their caregivers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Caissie, Rachel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigated the conditions under which communicative interactions were facilitated in hearing-impaired children and their caregivers as compared to normally hearing children and their caregivers. Participants were six normally hearing children and five hearing-impaired children, and their caregivers. Each interactant's communicative behaviors were coded for the intentions conveyed, discourse turn types, and verbal or nonverbal modalities of expression. Patterns emerged regarding caregiver communicative behaviors that facilitated children's participation in ongoing conversations. Caregiver behaviors most likely to be followed by on-topic responses from normally hearing and hearing-impaired children included caregiver requests, messages expressed through simultaneous verbal and nonverbal means, and turns that extended topics of conversations. Hearing-impaired children tended to produce more partially inadequate on-topic responses to their caregivers' turns than did the normally hearing children. Results are discussed with regard to clinical implications for the improvement or intervention with hearing-impaired children.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w910m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m563z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Human Development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m340j"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Measurements of wall pressure fluctuations on cylinders in a bundle in turbulent axial flow</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Curling, Llewelyn R. V. (Llewelyn Renard Vaughn)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis contains measurements of the wall pressure fluctuations on cylinders in a bundle in turbulent axial flow in a cylindrical channel. The measurements were made for the purposes of obtaining insight into the nature of the turbulent pressure field and providing analytical approximations of wall pressure correlations required by a previously derived theory for predicting the flow-induced vibration of cylinders in axial flow. The turbulent pressure field at the walls of the cylinders is examined in both the frequency and time domains via measured power-spectral densities, cross-spectral densities, auto-correlations and cross-correlations in azimuthal and longitudinal planes in the cylinder bundle over a range of flow velocities. The data is then nondimensionalized to give dimensionless power-spectral densities and azimuthal (or lateral) and longitudinal correlation functions, which are then approximated analytically and compared to a previous analytical approximation for pipe flow. Typical force-per-unit-length spectra are also obtained from the pressure measurements.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v193.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m340j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>