<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f4909"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A method for determining the solubility of sulphides</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Relly, Bruce. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Many orebodies have been formed in low temperature environments, distant from any known source and beyond the influence of ground water. These facts imply that ore metals travel in some way from a source to the places where they are found. Various theories have been put forward which purport to explain how this may happen. Because metals and their common silicates and sulphides are, with a few exceptions, volatile only at temperatures considerably above the temperatures at which epithermal deposits are thought to form, most theories postulate the presence of water to act as a moving flux in which the ore constituents are carried along.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Saull, V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892f73h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f4909</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83m311b"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the Ordovician conglomerates near Matane, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rejhon, George</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A large volume of literature has accumulated dealing with the problem of the limestone conglomerates of the Quebec Group. Most of the field work has been restricted to the vicinity of Quebec City, where the occurrence is not representative of the whole. The present investigation evaluates existing ideas on the origin of the conglomerate on the basis of field evidence collected mainly near Grosses Roches and also at Trois Pistoles. A new approach, the gravitational gliding hypothesis, is proposed. It is postulated that the limestone conglomerate formed as a beach talus below Lower Cambrian to Lower Ordovician limestone cliffs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stearn, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vs24w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m311b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149t330"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors affecting the rate of fermentation of apple juice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Reid, John. E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Very little appears to be known about many physical and chemical factors that specifically affect the rate of fermentation of apple juice. Indeed, before the work by Clark et al. (1954) at the Bacteriology Department of Macdonald College, it appears that factors other than those tested by Barker (1908) bad not been studied. Barker studied the affect of seration, the temperature of incubation used, the kinds of yeast used, and dissolved nitrogenous matter on the rate of alcohol formation in apple juice. Clark et al. (1954) studied the effect of the age of inoculum, the concentration of yeast extract, and the presence of non-fermenting yeasts on the rate of alcohol production in apple juice.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clark, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vp67b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149t330</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Bacteriology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354j972"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Siblings of Children with Disabilities: Examining Sibling Well-Being and Sibling Relationship Quality</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Woo, Amelia Huibin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les effets de troubles de santé sur le bien-être d'enfants de même famille et sur lesrelations entre frères et soeurs furent évalués. Particulièrement, deux syndromes, lesyndrome de Phelan-McDermid et le Trouble du Déficit de l'Attention avec ou sansHyperactivité (TDAH), qui ont implications pratiques significativement différentes furentexaminés. Les entants de même famille ont complété des questionnaires sur leurfonctionnement émotionnel et comportemental, leur concept de soi et la qualité de larelation avec leur frère ou leur soeur. Pour les deux groupes d'enfants avec un frère ouune soeur atteinte d'un trouble quelconque, aucun effet positif ou négatif sur le bien-êtrefut découvert comparativement aux enfants de familles typiques. Toutefois, la qualité desrelations entre enfants de même famille était différente dans les trois groupes. Quand l'undes enfants était atteint d'un trouble, moins d'intimité était rapportée dans la relationentre frères et soeurs. Les frères et soeurs d'enfants atteints du syndrome de PhelanMcDermidont déclaré qu'ils éprouvaient plus d'admiration, plus de pouvoir et moins deconflits entre eux que chez des enfants de familles typiques. Ils ont aussi exprimé plus detendresse dans leur relation que dans les familles d'enfants avec un TDAH. Cet ouvragesouligne également l'importance de comprendre comment les problèmes de santé d'unenfant peuvent affecter les autres enfants de leur famille.11</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The effects of disability on sibling well-being and sibling relationship quality wereevaluated. Particularly, two disabilities (Phelan-McDermid syndrome and attentionhyperactivity disorder) with significantly different functional implications were examined.Siblings completed measures on behavioural and emotional functioning, self-concept,and sibling relationship quality. For both disability groups, no positive or negative effectson sibling weIl-being were found when compared to siblings oftypicaIly developingchildren. Sibling relationship quality was different for aIl three groups of siblings. Whenthere was disability in the home, siblings reported less intimacy in their relationships.Siblings of children with Phelan-McDerrnid syndrome reported more mutual admiration,more power and less conflict in their relationships than siblings oftypically developingchildren. They also reported more warmth in their relationship than siblings of childrenwith attention deficit hyperactivity disorder. The importance of understanding howdisability in the home can affect siblings is emphasized.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gp70h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354j972</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Children with disabilities -- Family relationships</dc:subject><dc:subject>Brothers and sisters</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60d1294"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Noise origin, power and spectra of ducted centrifugal fans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Real, Roderick. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Forward and backward curved blade centrifugal fans as noise sources were subjected to an analysis employing the matched acoustic waveguide measuring technique. There are three major findings: 1. The noise output from homologous series of fans can be defined by one V - shaped specific noise power vs. log specific curve, with minimum close to maximum static efficiency. Fan noise "laws" differ as the slope of the branches of this curve. 2. Fan outlet noise power at maximum fan efficiency approximates 10^-5 times the input fan power.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Howes, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr779.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d1294</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr1721902"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the effect of the micro-environment on the free-living stages of some parasitic nematodes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Prasad, Devendra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In relatively recent years, biologists have become interested in ecology, a science which considers organisms in their relation to environment. In other words ecological research sets out to define the relations between animais and their environments. Besides endeavouring to describe and understand the natural habitats and environments of animals and plants, ecological investigations are also concerned with theoretical questions such as to what extent and therefore why an animal can exist under one set of environmental conditions and not under another. Unfortunately very little is known of this aspect. Most of the past studies on animal ecology have been chiefly concerned with the relation of organisms to each other than to their relations to the physical and chemical environment. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cameron, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z887g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr1721902</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Parasites</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579x00s"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The geology of the Addington-Preston area</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pollock, Donald. W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Addington-Preston area is bounded on the east and west by longitudes 74°45’ and 75°15’ and on the north and south by latitudes 46°15’ and 46°00’ North and it encompasses an area of approximately 430 square miles (Figure 1). It was mapped by the writer during the summers of 1955 and 1956 and the preliminary reports were published by the Quebec Department of Mines (Pollock, 1956, 1957). The area includes parts of Amherst, Addington, Preston and Papineau townships in Papineau county and parts of La Minerve, Clyde, Joly, Lesage, Rivard, Rocheblave, and all of Labelle and Gagnon townships in Labelle county.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stevenson, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fg53v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579x00s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajd4731128"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The physiology of the paroxysmal afterdischarge</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pinsky, Carl</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since biblical times, physicians have been challenged by the difficulties of finding the proper treatment for the disease of epilepsy. That challenge has not gone unanswered at any time in the recorded history of medical science. The quest for the solution of this problem is being carried out vigorously today on many fronts. The clinician and the research worker are helping each other to understand the nature of the disease, and to provide a rationale for its causes and treatment. Advances in the treatment of all diseases have gone hand in hand with increasing knowledge of fundamental biological phenomena.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burgen, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128f69w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd4731128</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nj48n"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Migration and the French Canadian extended family</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pineo, Peter. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis, dealing with the migration and kinship structure of contemporary French Canada, presents the results of eleven months' work by an anthropologist. It is self-consciously written within a certain theoretical framework or tradition, which can be codified under two words: culture and function. In the first place, this means that I expected, throughout doing the work, to find a variation in both structure and character between the French Canadian norm and that of ether societies. This expectation, or assumption, is the core of the cultural approach; ether postulates, such as that culture is learned, follow from the observation of difference.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Garigue, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860b53h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj48n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anthropology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w8373"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The use of snake venom phospholipase A in a study of mitochondria</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Petrushka, Evelyn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>When heated snake venom solution is added to a suspension of respiring rat liver, kidney or brain mitochondria, there is an initial stimulation of the rate of respiration, a rapid release of soluble protein, a progressive appearance of ATPase activity, an uncoupling of oxidation from phosphorylation and a gradual decrease in the optical density of the suspension. It has been shown that the lecithin of these mitochondria is susceptible to the hydrolytic action of the thermostable phospholipase A of heated snake venoms and that lysolecithin is produced. The action of the heated venom and the effect of the lysolecithin which accumulates lead to the changes in mitochondrial structure and function.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Quastel, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72pc03c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w8373</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3j333603h"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microstructure of impure ice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Perey, Francis. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>By far the most common form of ice covering a body of water is "sheet ice". Wilson Zumberge and Marshall (1) have recently done a classification of lake ice and reported that two basic structures were found: i) a coarsely crystalline columnar aggregate, ii) a finely crystalline granular aggregate. This crystalline granular aggregate is produced by the affects of heavy snow fall at the time of freeze-up or by snow fall on the ice surface which, by a process of wet and dry snow metamorphism, changes into the granular aggregate, forming a miner portion of the ice sheet.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pounder, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z70g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333603h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5712mb57b"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The place of social work in town planning: some practical and theoretical considerations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pearl, Frances</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis concerns the social welfare aspects of town planning and the implications these have for collaboration between social workers and town planners. The thesis contends that social work can be of assistance to the town planner on questions of social policy and on methods and techniques of town and community planning. The writer examines three phases of town planning: survey, development plan and program, and seeks to determine the relationship of social work practice in community agencies and in the town planning team to planning practice in each of the three phases.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Younge, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wv17x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712mb57b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zs12v"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the English-Canadian novel since 1939</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Passmore, Marian. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Canadian is a social, geographical, psychological and literary phenomenon who in his never-ending search to define himself has only succeeded in adding acute self-consciousness to the list of his maladies. But no Massey Report, no article by a member or the Canadian Authors' Association, and certainly no sociological treatise, will ever tell the impatient Canadian what he is. In the period of the past twenty years, particularly since 1939, the Canadian has examined himself with morbid and adolescent curiosity forgetting that his growing nationalism can beat be studied in the books his countrymen are writing, that it is through its art that a nation defines itself.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacLennan, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462895s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zs12v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A736668423"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on carbohydrate metabolism in the central nervous system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Parmar, Surendra. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There have been remarkable developments in the field of the intermediary metabolism of carbohydrates during the past twenty five years. These developments were due (1) the elucidation of the anaerobic glycolytic breakdown of carbohydrate having its origin in Embden's discovery of phosphoglyceric acid in 1933 and (2) the oxidative tricarboxylic acid cycle discovered by Krebs and Johnson in 1937.The present concepts of the metabolism or carbohydrates centres round these two themes. However, the central role of these pathways is being challenged by the discovery and elucidation of alternative pathways of metabolism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Quastel, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bj63r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736668423</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw3763b55t"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The foreign trade of Edinburgh, 1500-1542</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Parker, Thomas. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Restricted in bulk though it was by comparison with that of neighbouring England, the foreign trade of Scotland at the close of the Middle Ages was far greater than the actual volume of traffic would suggest. Only a small minority of the Scottish population actually earned a livelihood by the sale and purchase of goods overseas, but is is probable that almost everyone who grew to maturity depended on importation from abroad for at least one item essential to his wellbeing. The country, as foreign travellers and commentators were not slow to remark, was poor, deficient indeed in many commodities necessary to civilized existence.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q0815.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763b55t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1n79h8155"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>a Study of Stage Fright</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paivio, Allan U.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1935, H. L. Hollingworth wrote that, "among the numerous familiar fears of mankind none is more common than 'stage fright' (22, p. 173). Yet, despite its ubiquitous nature, the phenomenon is only poorly understood. The broad aim of the present study is to extend this understanding in the conviction that "stage fright" is of interest in its own right and that the concept is of theoretical value for psychology, particularly that aspect of social psychology concerned with group phenomena.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lambert, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f4628962.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h8155</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2b88qg847"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Compression of Silt Under Model Footings</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Padopulos, Diogenes</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The experimental work described in the thesis consisted of a series of tests of model footings on dry silt of various porosities. It was done from the point of view of settlement-pressure relationship. Also, one of the theories of settlement is examined, and the results of the tests are compared with that theory. The principal factors affecting the tests are pointed out, and suggestions are made to guide further studies of the subject.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Coates, D. F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w838c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qg847</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9z903372j"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>the Educational Philosophies of Russell and Whitehead; a Comparison and Assessment in Terms of Present Day Problems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Overing, Robert L.R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bertrand Russell, the man who was to become the most outspoken and best known philosopher of the first half of the twentieth century, was born in England in 1873, the second son of Lord and Lady Amberley. He knew little of his parents for, when only two years old, both parents died within a year leaving as orphans Bertrand and an older brother, Frank. Russell's life for the next sixteen years was to be spent in the home of his grandparents, Lord and Lady Russell. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t2988.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903372j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tq65d"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>the Lactic Dehydrogenase of the Mammalian Erythrocyte</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ottolenghi, Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The beginning of our knowledge of the enzyme lactic dehydrogenase, dates back to Otto Meyerhof's discovery (1) in 1919, that washed muscle preparations can oxidise lactic acid. The enzyme was obtained in soluble form by Stephenson (2) in 1928, from cultures of E. coli, and Bernheim (3) prepared a similar extract from yeast and identified pyruvic acid as the product of the reaction. [...] </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denstedt, O. F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rm95m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tq65d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afb494d042"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Zoology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>the Systematics of Certain Small Mammals of the Quebec Peninsula</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Osborn, Dale James</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Size, color phases, molar tooth complexity, and post-palatal margin variations were studied as individual characters in C. gapperi in the Quebec Peninsula. These were found to have discordant patterns of distribution. A significant gradient in size increase was found from the neck to the eastern and northern portions of the Peninsula. Brown-back and the fifth angle showed a general increase northward in frequency within the confines of the Peninsula compared with contiguous regions. Local variations within the study area occurred.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440x46d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494d042</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Zoology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zs134"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>an Experimental Investigation into Certain Aspects of Rock Failure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ortlepp, W. David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An understanding of the behavior of brittle solids subjected to stresses is not only of academic interest, but is of great importance in engineering practice. In particular, the stress response of rock masses merits doser attention. Most large engineering projects utilize rock materials either directly, as part of the structure, or indirectly, as the foundation upon which the structure will rest. In tunneling and in mining, excavations are completely surrounded by rock and usually induce in it the extreme stress response of ultimate failure. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666843c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zs134</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s619k"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>an Inequality in the Geometry of Numbers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oler, Norman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There appeared in 1883 an article by Barlow [1] in Nature in which the problem of the densest packing of spheres is discussed from the point of view of the physical chemist. While Thue [2,3] may be credited with the earliest mathematical formulation of a packing problem, namely that of the densest packing of equal circles in the plane it was not until H. Minkowski [4] had laid a firm foundation to the Geometry of Numbers that wider interest was stirred in problems of this type. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zassenhaus, Hans</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jc51p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s619k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject><dc:subject/></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bz04n"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Investigative Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>the Participation of Bone in the Sodium and Potassium Metabolism of the Rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Norman, Nils</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The investigative work presented in this thesis is a contribution to the great amount of knowledge that already exists in the field of sodium and potassium metabolism. The study has been done on rats, but differs from earlier work in the method used. The experimental approach combines previously described techniques, modified for the purpose, and new procedures created for special needs. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beck, J. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408174n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bz04n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Investigative Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5138jj21g"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Serological Tests in Canadian Hydatid Disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nommik, Salme</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Hydatid disease has been known since the early days of medicine and is widely distributed throughout the world. It is prevalent in South America, Iceland, Australia, New Zealand and is frequently encountered in regions along the Mediterranean Sea, in Central Europe, Russia and South Africa. Infection in the native-born population of North America has been considered to occur rarely.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cameron, T. W. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80j0280.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jj21g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Parasitology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asj139578w"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Entomology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Population Behaviour of the Sheep Ked, Melophagus Ovinus (L.), in Relation to Endocrine Mechanisms in Sheep</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nelson, W.A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Compared with the advances of the past twenty years in special branches of insect physiology, and in biology of insects attacking plants and stored products, progress in veterinary entomology has been indeed slow. This is particularly true of the obligate parasites which spend all or a major part of their lives on or in the host animal. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>DuPorte, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z180x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139578w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>