<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021f84w"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The requirement of p56Lck tyrosine kinase in the modulation of fas-mediated apoptosis by HIV-1 Nef protein</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jao, Kevin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The HIV-1 protein Nef is a critical factor in the viral  pathogenesis and decline of CD4 T-cells during HIV infection. Nef has been  implicated in modulating several cellular pathways, including apoptosis. This thesis  herein describes our attempt to elucidate the mechanism by which Nef modulates  apoptosis in T-cells. Using Jurkat cells inducibly expressing wild-type Nef, we  observe that Nef renders cells more sensitive to apoptosis upon cross-linking with  anti-Fas or TRAIL. Enhancement of Fas-mediated apoptosis required the presence of  Lck, as apoptosis was abrogated in Nef expressing Lck-/- cells as compared to wild  type Jurkat cells. Nef does not modulate expression of pro or anti-apoptotic  proteins, or cell surface Fas receptor. Furthermore, Nef differentially mediates  activation signaling pathways upon anti-CD3 stimulation. Enhancement of apoptosis by  Nef may represent one of the mechanisms by which HIV depletes CD4 T-cells during  infection.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sekaly, Rafick-Pierre</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm266.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021f84w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av979v3699"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Humoral response to M. tuberculosis antigens in patients with tuberculosis in the Gambia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Greenaway, Chris</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>New tests to diagnose active tuberculosis (TB) that are simple,  rapid and inexpensive, yet sensitive and specific are urgently needed. We assessed  the sensitivity and specificity of seven different M. tuberculosis antigens for the  diagnosis of active pulmonary TB in The Gambia. Three of the antigens tested were  restricted, i.e. absent from BCG and some non-tuberculous mycobacteria (ESAT6,  CFP-10 and Rv3871), and four shared, i.e. common to most mycobacteria (38kDa, GLU-S,  19kDa and 14kDa). Sera from 100 patients with active pulmonary TB, 100 household  contacts, and 100 healthy neighborhood controls, in the Gambia, were tested by ELISA  for antibodies to these 7 antigens. The sensitivity and specificity of both the  shared and the restricted antigens were unacceptably low. In countries with high,  rates of TB, such as the Gambia, the clinical utility of serologic testing to  diagnose active tuberculosis remains limited.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Menzies, Dick</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h503r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v3699</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25x921q"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Scalar fields generating contemporary inflation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grenier, Patrick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The evidence for an accelerating expansion of our Universe at  the present epoch have led us to look for an energy component which could generate  it. That may consist in quintessence in the form of a system of scalar fields  {φa} rolling down a potential V({φ a}). This master's thesis  presents the equations relevant to the cosmological evolution of such a system,  along with the different conditions required for a viable cosmology. Also, via the  exploration of two distinct models, two fundamental problems of quintessence theory  are outlined. The impossibility of escaping the fine-tuning of initial conditions is  first presented in link to the Liouville's theorem, and second the difficulty of  avoiding the coincidence of the recent rise of quintessence even in the presence of  attractors is shown.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burgess, Clifford P.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vh341.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25x921q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236262m"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Transport of proteins across the nuclear envelope : the Ran GTPase system and nuclear import of heat shock proteins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gao, Huanhuan, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nucleocytoplasmic trafficking of macromolecules and heat shock  proteins are key elements of the stress response; the analysis of nuclear transport  and hsp70s will therefore contribute significantly to our understanding of cell  physiology. To study the formation of the Ran/Gsp1p nucleocytoplasmic  gradient, an essential component of many nuclear transport reactions, I have used  mutant strains of the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae. My experiments have identified  the nucleoporins Nup133p, Rat2p/Nup120p, Nup85p, Nic96p and the enzyme acetyl-CoA  carboxylase (MTR7) as proteins that regulate the distribution and cellular  concentration of Ran/Gsp1p. Moreover, I have defined the mechanisms that underlie  the control of the Ran/Gsplp gradient formation by these factors. Using HeLa cells as a model system, I have demonstrated that the  C-terminal part of mammalian hsc73 contains a unique targeting signal that is  necessary and sufficient for stress-induced nuclear accumulation. This C-terminal  segment promotes shuttling between nucleus and cytoplasm and has unique requirements  for stress-dependent nuclear import.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stochaj, Ursula</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mj66d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236262m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722h946v"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nanolithography using an atomic microscope</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gagnon Morris, Alexis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, I study the nanolithography of gallium arsenide  samples by local oxidation with an atomic force microscope (AFM). I examine the  current theoretical descriptions of the reaction kinetics and compare the results to  experimental data. The main goal is to characterize the AFM oxidation process such  that high quality features can be routinely patterned. I also investigate the use of  alternative oxidation environments in an attempt to improve the height and aspect  ratio of the AFM local oxidation features. An alternative lithography technique  involving scratching under a high contact force is also studied. Finally, I discuss  the steps that are necessary in order to fabricate a quantum structure with the AFM  local oxidation lithography technique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hilke, Michael</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx59q.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722h946v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515p00j"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identificaiton and characterization of the antitumor suppressor activity of interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF-3) in B16 melanoma tumor model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Duguay, Delphine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Delivery of transcription factor to cancer cells to reprogram  gene expression may represent a novel strategy to augment the production of immune  stimulatory cytokines and trigger a more potent antitumor response. In this study,  we used a syngeneic mouse tumor model system involving the poorly immunogenic murine  B16 tumor to evaluate whether delivery of the interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF-3)  can be used as an immunomodulator. The low immunogenicity of B16 melanoma cells may  be due to their deficient cytokine expression, as well as their inefficient  MHC-restricted epitope presentation. Gene-modified B16 melanoma cells were selected  for their ability to express and to activate the IRF-3 protein. When injected into  C57BL/6 mice, tumor growth was inhibited and tumors that developed from these mice  had significant infiltration of inflammatory cells. Our observations demonstrated  that gene transfer of IRF-3 into B16 melanoma could mediate important antitumor  response by restoring both the deficient cytokine profile and the MHC class I  protein expression.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hiscott, John</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429970d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515p00j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g0791"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An RXTE archival search for coherent -X-ray pulsations in low mass x-ray binary 4U 1820-30</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dib, Rim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As part of a large-scale search for coherent pulsations from  LMXBs in the RXTE archive, I have completed a detailed series of searches for  coherent pulsations of 4U 1820--30---an ultracompact LMXB with a binary period of  11.4 minutes located in the globular cluster NGC 6624. The small binary period leads  to a very high acceleration, so I used phase modulation searches as well as  acceleration searches to give significant sensitivity to millisecond pulsations. I   searched a total of 34 archival RXTE observations, 32 of which had an on-source  integration time longer than 10 ks, and some of which were made consecutively which  allowed me to combine them. While I found no pulsations, I have been able to place  the first stringent (95% confidence) pulsed fraction limits of ≲ 0.8% for  all realistic spin frequencies (i.e. ≲ 1 kHz) and likely companion masses  (0.02 M⊙ ≤ Mc≤ 0.3 M⊙ ). By contrast all five LMXBs  known to emit coherent pulsations have intrinsic pulsed fractions in the range 3% to  7% when pulsations are observed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kaspi, Victoria M.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pq89c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g0791</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Astronomy and Astrophysics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xj255"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aids, poverty and inequality : implications of the socioecological medicine approach for controlling the HIVAIDS pandemic</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Comber, Julie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Southern Africa is experiencing an HIV/AIDS pandemic with  devastating effects. In this thesis I suggest why prevention efforts have failed to  stem the pandemic. Then I argue that developed countries have a duty to help the  developing world fight the HIV/AIDS pandemic. Arguments grounded in justice and in  vulnerability are used to reach this conclusion. Next, I suggest that developed  countries have not done enough to help. I develop and advocate the Socioecological  Medicine Approach as a conceptual framework to help address the HIV/AIDS pandemic.  This approach is a useful perspective because it is holistic, embraces web  causation, emphasizes interconnectedness, encourages communities to play an active  role in responding to the HIV/AIDS pandemic, and encourages humans to adopt a more  harmonious place in our environment. The most important conclusion is that HIV/AIDS  is a symptom of inequality and poverty, therefore both symptoms and their root  causes must be addressed to stem the HIV/AIDS pandemic.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Glass, Kathleen</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n203z73f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xj255</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rh594"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Patterns of sustainable agriculture adoptionnon-adoption in Panamá</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cochran, Jason</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The promoter system of agriculture extension has been widely  studied and accepted as a tool for agriculture development where local resources are  scarce. Much development work has been done in Panama using the promoter model. In  order to ascertain the local success of this model, promoters trained by World  Vision were visited. The adoption of sustainable agriculture practices were measured  in five communities where 7 promoters were trained and placed in Veraguas, Panama.  Despite the long-term presence of World Vision and trained promoters, only six  farmers have adopted at least one sustainable agriculture technique as a result of  these extension efforts. Low adoption rates do not necessarily indicate project  failure, but does indicate several barriers. These barriers are explored as well as  reasons farmers gave for land use. Reasons for S/A use are also explored. Finally,  recommendations for improving extension methods and future research are  made.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bonnell, Robert</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p525r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rh594</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural extension work -- Panama -- Veraguas (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sustainable agriculture -- Panama -- Veraguas (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn009z38c"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors associated with diet behaviour among individuals with type 2 diabetes mellitus attending an outpatient clinic</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Belfer, Bonnee</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Diet recommendations to achieve target metabolic control for  prevention of micro and macrovascular complications have been outlined. Although  previous studies in individuals with type 2 diabetes have identified certain factors  associated with adherence to diet recommendations, adherence is multi-factorial in  nature and includes demographic, biological and psychosocial variables. Our main  objective was to identify factors associated With dietary behaviour among  individuals with type 2 diabetes attending an out-patient clinic. Furthermore, we  attempted to identify factors associated with frequency of seeing the dietitian and  stages of change far lower fat intake. Principal hypothesis: those who are younger,  female, lower in body mass index (BMI), higher in education level, exposed to a  dietitian in the past year, higher in stage of change, having greater nutrition  knowledge, greater perception of risk and benefits as well as fewer perceived  barriers, would consume less total and saturated fat. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yale, Jean-Francois</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dg29x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z38c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Low-fat diet</dc:subject><dc:subject>Non-insulin-dependent diabetes -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Non-insulin-dependent diabetes -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62f8811"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Measuring dependence using information gain when data are length-biased and right-censored</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bergeron, Pierre-Jérôme</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In epidemiologic studies, prevalent cases with a disease are  often identified through a cross-sectional study. These cases are then followed for  a fixed period of time at the end of which the subjects will either have failed or  have been censored. When interest lies in estimating the survival distribution, from  onset, of subjects with the disease one must take into account that the survival  times of the cases ascertained in such fashion are left truncated. When it is  possible to assume that there has not been any epidemic of the disease over the past  period of time that covers the onset times of the subjects, one may assume that the  disease has stationary incidence. Under such a stationarity assumption, the survival  times of the recruited subjects are called "length-biased". Measures of  dependence have been extensively treated in statistical literature. In the context  of survival analysis with length-biased data the literature is rather poor. It is  the purpose of this thesis to establish a measure of dependence for length-biased  right-censored observations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Asgharian, M.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qj28r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f8811</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Statistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hq24w"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of planar photonic band gap structures with controllable bandstop widths</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wu, Jay-Hsing, 1979-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effects of planar PBG structure with microstrip transmission line were investigated. Both measurement and simulation results are compared and the bandstop characteristics such as 3 dB bandstop width, central bandstop frequency, and maximum attenuation were examined. Also, various dimensions of PBG structure were explored to demonstrate the correlation to the bandstop effects. It was found that the central bandstop frequency is directly depended on the period distance (a). Meanwhile, the maximum attenuation was observed to depend on the number of periods presented in the ground plane. Furthermore, the vertical scale of the square perforation to the period distance ratio (d/a) was found to affect the left bandstop edge consistently. As the ratio is increased from 0.2 to 0.9, the left bandstop edge shifts toward the lower frequencies steadily and the range of the frequency shift is around 3.5 GHz. This important finding gives the PBG structure the potential to be tuned. Moreover, the possibilities of switching and tuning of the PBG structure were also investigated. Switching of the PBG structure with a gold metal piece electrically was successfully demonstrated. At 16 GHz, the bandstop effect is being switched off from -35 dB to -1 dB. Also, tuning of the bandstop edge was demonstrated and the range of frequency shift measured is 1.5 GHz. Therefore, the switching and tuning abilities of the PBG structure can be utilized as tunable filters.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shih, I.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn009z39n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hq24w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1831ck569"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Squeeze casting of magnesium matrix composites reinforced with alumina short fibers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Xin, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Magnesium matrix composites are very promising materials in the  transportation and aerospace industries due to their enhanced characteristics and  cost effectiveness. Based on the new AJ52 alloy, special attention is given to  squeeze casting MMCs, with Saffil(TM) Al2O3 fibers used as the reinforcement. In  order to obtain an even distribution of the fiber in the matrix, a porous preform  was produced using vacuum filtration. The composites with fiber volume fraction of  5, 10, and 15% were squeeze cast and the microstructure and mechanical properties  were investigated. The main advantage of squeeze casting in fabricating of MMCs is  that it can overcome the poor wettability of magnesium alloys on ceramic fibers,  enhancing the bonding at the interface and transferring the load from the weak  matrix to the high strength short fibers. The results showed an increase of tensile strength by 40%, i.e.,  from 169 to 237 MPa despite a 13% increase of the density from 1.80 to 2.04 g/cm 3.  Also an increase of the matrix hardness was observed which is attributed to the  reinforcement. Moreover, a correlation between tensile and shear punch tests was  developed in order to overcome the difficulty of machining large composite tensile  samples.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>ew, Robin A. L.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kg97z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831ck569</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483j92t"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Theoretical and experimental investigation of all-optical gain-clamped discrete fiber raman amplifiers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zambelis, Theodore</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Using numerical simulations, we design and analyze the  performance of gain-clamped discrete fiber Raman amplifiers. In particular, we  investigate a configuration which generates a feedback signal through the use of  fiber Bragg gratings. We examine the impact of the feedback wavelength on the  gain-clamping properties. From the simulation results, we conclude that in order to  achieve uniform gain-clamping across the DWDM band of interest, the optical pumps  must be depleted evenly by the feedback signal. The effect of the feedback signal on  the amplifier may be mostly predicted based on the Raman gain coefficients  corresponding to the frequency separation between the feedback signal and the pumps.  A 58 nm wide uniformly gain-clamped Raman amplifier having over 20 dB gain and a  critical power of -3 dBm is developed. We also verify gain-clamping for this configuration  experimentally.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chen, L. R.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nb80d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483j92t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2r36tz17t"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Learning-based detection of people for automated video surveillance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nair, Vinod</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis addresses the problem of automatically detecting  people from images. Our work is motivated by, and demonstrated on, an automated  video surveillance application that aims to monitor people appearing in a scene. We  adopt a machine learning-based approach to detection: first, a two-class classifier  that can accurately distinguish cropped person images from all other types of images  is automatically learned from examples. It is then used to spot instances of the  person class within a given image. We have developed and implemented two detection  systems using this approach. The first detector is based on the Viola-Jones object detection  algorithm [30], which uses the AdaBoost learning algorithm [7] and labeled training  examples to learn the image classifier. This system is designed specifically for  implementation on a field programmable gate array. The second system demonstrates a  new, unsupervised, online learning framework for detecting people (or any other type  of moving object, such as cars) from video. In this framework, motion information is  used to automatically label training examples collected directly from the live  detection task video. An online learner based on the Winnow algorithm [15]  incrementally trains a task-specific classifier with these examples. For the person  detection task, we use background subtraction to automatically label the training  data. After the initial manual effort of implementing the automatic labeler, the  framework runs on its own on the scene video stream to gradually train an accurate  classifier.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clark, James J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hq255.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36tz17t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n4002"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stress : a tactile display using lateral skin stretch</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pasquero, Jérôme</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes a new tactile display device (Stimulator  of Tactile Receptors by Skin Stretch or STReSS) exploiting lateral skin stretch of  the fingertip to create tactile sensations. The device consists of an array of one  hundred piezoelectric bending actuators applying local strain patterns on the user's  fingertip. It was found that manufacturing the piezoelectric material in a comb  shape facilitates the device's fabrication process, allows for a spatial resolution  of one actuator per mm2, and guarantees high structural strength for the display.  Simple but creative electronics drive the system at a 700 Hz refresh rate and keep  the device compact and portable. The tactile display's manufacturing process and the  controlling electronics are described. Finally, some tactile sensations experienced  with the display are reported informally.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hayward, Vincent</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526c91t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n4002</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bh82g"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>SOVA based on a sectionalized trellis of linear block codes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kovacevic, Sanja</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The use of block codes is a well known error-control technique  for reliable transmission of digital information over noisy communication channels.  However, a practically implementable soft-input soft-output (SISO) decoding  algorithm for block codes is still a challenging problem. This thesis examines a new decoding scheme based on the  soft-output Viterbi algorithm (SOVA) applied to a sectionalized trellis for linear  block codes. The computational complexities of the new SOVA decoder and of the  conventional SOVA decoder based on the bit-level trellis are theoretically analyzed  and derived. These results are used to obtain the optimum sectionalization of a  trellis for SOVA. The optimum sectionalization of a trellis for Maximum A Posteriori  (MAP), Maximum Logarithm MAP (Max-Log-MAP), and Viterbi algorithms, and their  corresponding computational complexities are included for comparisons. The results  confirm that SOVA based on a sectionalized trellis is the most computationally  efficient SISO decoder examined in this thesis. The simulation results of the bit error rate (BER) over additive  white Gaussian noise (AWGN) channel demonstrate that the BER performance of the new  SOVA decoder is not degraded. The BER performance of SOVA used in a serially  concatenated block codes scheme reveals that the soft outputs of the proposed  decoder are the same as those of the conventional SOVA decoder. Iterative decoding  of serially concatenated block codes reveals that the quality of reliability  estimates of the proposed SOVA decoder is the same as that of the conventional SOVA  decoder.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171x780.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bh82g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10wq80v"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microencapsulated genetically engineered Lactobacillus plantarum 80 (pCBH1) for bile acid deconjugation and its implication in lowering cholesterol</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jones, Mitchell Lawrence</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A novel approach whereby one can use genetically engineered cells for the purpose of deconjugating bile acids and lowering cholesterol is presented in this thesis. The concept of oral administration of artificial cells has been used for this purpose. In concurrence to these requirements, several in-vitro methods are designed and discussed in this report. For these studies, alginate-polylysine-alginate microcapsules were used. Process parameters for Lactobacillus plantarum 80 (pCBH1) cell microencapsulation have been presented. Results show the possibility of using these artificial cells for various applications. For in-vitro experiments, immobilized bacteria and artificial cells containing the genetically engineered organism were challenged with physiologically relevant levels of bile acids. Results show that immobilized and microencapsulated genetically engineered bacterial cells are capable of lowering physiological levels of bile acids in-vitro. Further, this report summarizes the physiological interrelationship between bile acids and cholesterol and predicts oral doses of microencapsulated cells required for lowering cholesterol.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Prakash, Satya</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cw90b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wq80v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f6485"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hydrodynamic characterization of a Denver laboratory flotation cell</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Do, Sung-Su, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gas dispersion in a laboratory Denver flotation cell was  characterized by measuring the superficial gas velocity (Jg), bubble size (d b) and  estimating the bubble surface area flux, Sb as a function of impeller speed, frother  concentration (Dowfroth 250), and solids content (-30mum silica). The cell was  operated by self-aspiration or forced air. The air flow rate was measured using a  McMillan meter (self-aspiration) and a mass flow meter (forced air). The bubble size  was measured by a photographic technique developed at McGill. From repeat  experiments, the average relative standard deviation on Jg was ca. 2% and on db was  ca. 13%. No effect of location on bubble size was found. In self-aspiration mode Jg increased with impeller speed due to  increased suction and decreased with increasing frother concentration and solids  content. The effect of frother was attributed to increased recirculation of air as  the bubble size was reduced. The effect of solids appears related to sedimentation.  Bubble size increased with increasing impeller speed, which was attributed to the  increase in Jg. Solids did not affect the bubble size. Bubble size decreased with  frother most notably at low concentration then remained almost constant at high  frother concentration. The critical coalescence concentration appeared to be close  to 5 ppm for the present conditions. The bubble surface area flux Sb increased  approximately linearly with impeller speed up to ca. 40s-1. Using forced air the bubble size behaved as expected: it  decreased with increasing impeller speed (due to higher shear) and decreasing Jg .  The Sb ranged up to ca. 80s-1, higher than values quoted for a laboratory machine.  To correspond more closely to industrial cells, operation with forced air is  recommended. The use of higher impeller speeds than are commonly used in laboratory  testwork will give more closely fit superficial gas velocity found in industrial  plant practice.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Finch, J. A.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Gomez, C. O.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qc776.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f6485</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418n887"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Novel mesh quality improvement systems for enhanced accuracy and efficiency of adaptive finite element electromagnetics with tetrahedra</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dorica, Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Finite element accuracy and efficiency can be directly affected  by mesh quality. When employing h-adaptive solution strategies, a mesh improvement  stage is required in order to ensure high quality tetrahedra. However, mesh  improvement techniques and quality indicators are often based on purely geometrical  considerations. Recent work has focused on theoretically linking mesh quality  criteria to interpolation and discretization errors. The potential benefits and  related costs of a family of new mesh quality improvement systems are investigated  using a set of electromagnetic benchmarks and mesh quality measures directly  associated with finite element accuracy and efficiency. The new techniques are shown  to outperform the existing mesh smoothing techniques in both mesh quality  improvement and computational cost. The significant gains in finite element accuracy  and efficiency are highlighted through theoretical and experimental  results.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Giannacopoulos, Dennis</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qq17r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418n887</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cw92w"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experimental validation of a model predicting the evaporation rate of zinc in a transferred arc</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aguilera, Luis, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A mathematical model has been developed to allow optimization  and scale up of a metal evaporator as a function of plasma operating parameters such  as composition and flow rate of the plasma gas, arc current, arc length as well as  wall and crucible temperatures. The system argon-zinc has been chosen to validate  and calibrate the output of the model simulations with experimental measurements.  The plasma gas used in the system was argon, and the metal to be evaporated was  zinc. The relatively low boiling point of zinc allowed more precise measurements of  the boundary and operation conditions being examined. Experimental measurements of  the evaporation rate of zinc at atmospheric pressure and steady state were compared  with the predictions of the computational model over a broad range of plasma  operating conditions and temperature boundary conditions. Measurements of  temperature at different locations in the crucible were taken to obtain the crucible  temperature profile; the range of current used was between 100 and 275 A; the plasma  gas flow rate covered a range from 10.7 to 27.9 slpm while the arc length was varied  from 3.0 to 5.2 cm.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Berk, D.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Munz, R. J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kg99h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cw92w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fh75t"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of fibres and headed bars on the response of concrete corbels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alameer, Mohammed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Six full-scale reinforced concrete corbel specimens were tested  to study the influence of steel and polypropylene fibres, headed bars, and  horizontal loading on their responses. The experimentally determined capacities were  compared with predictions using simplified and refined strut-and-tie models, with  the refined models providing better predictions of the capacities. The experimental study demonstrated the beneficial use of fibres  in reinforced concrete corbels, that is a reduction in the number and the width of  cracks at service loads. Headed bars provided excellent anchorage of the main  tension tie reinforcement and eliminated the need to weld bearing plates to the  reinforcement, as traditionally done in practice. Refined strut-and-tie models  provide better predications to the ultimate load capacities. The improved crack control, using fibre reinforced concrete, and  the excellent end anchorage provided by the headed bars provides more durable  corbels, suitable for use in parking garage structures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mitchell, Denis</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx60g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh75t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53ww39w"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Plotinus, the term and the way : theory of art and beauty</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Seniw, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ammonius Saccas instructs Plotinus towards a synthesis of  ancient Greek philosophy. A brief introduction to the historical Plotinus is  offered. The Hypostases: The One or Supreme Reality, the Divine Mind, Nous, and the  Universal Soul, Logos, are discussed in the context of Plato's eternal ideas,  Beauty, Truth and Good. An examination of the dialogue Plotinus has with art and beauty  is offered. The relationship between Plato's divine intelligibles and art is  discussed in context of the treatise On Beauty. The intelligible beauty of ideas,  cosmos, nature and art are examined in context of the treatise On Intellectual  Beauty. Plotinian theory of art is summarized. Plotinus advances an "iconic" dialectic that serves  his theological theory of art. The more important critical issues that arise from  his description of the realm of art are addressed. Plotinian mysticism, and the  subject of matter and form, identity and difference, is discussed. The opposing ways  of the "picture" and the "word" are briefly  summarized. The appearance of theos is an event of hierophany . The meaning  of art points towards the object of our ultimate concern. A Plotinian studio program  for the painter concludes the thesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McLelland, J. C.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687j038.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53ww39w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Art and religion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Art -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plotinus</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67jr80r"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Là-bas, suivi de, Espaces et temps du silence durassien</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tanguay, Johanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Part one of the thesis. She's leaving. She's running away.  Everything goes too fast. If she doesn't, the emptiness in her life will destroy  her. There, in Africa, nothing happens. Nothing but sight, silence, space and time.  There, she finds another way of living. There, everything happens. Everything that  has anything to do with essence. Only then can Gisella, 30, come  back. Part two. How can one tell of silence with words? How can  silence be what makes not only the style and themes of a fiction, but the whole  fiction, resonate, vibrate? In the fiction of Marguerite Duras, more specifically in  Aurelia Steiner (Melbourne) and L'amour, the obsession of silence is what modulates  the representation of time and space, be it corporal, geographical or domestic, and  what transforms reality in an attempt to open the heart of things, beings and time  on the infinite, the invisible, the sacred.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rivard, Yvon</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fr907.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jr80r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Duras, Marguerite -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Silence in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Space and time in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap2676w188"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>ger</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of German Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Der Liebescode : zur poetischen Korrespondenz Bertolt Brechts und Margarete Steffins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Karir, Simran</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the present study, the sonnets Margarete Steffin and Bertolt  Brecht wrote each other will be examined both in regard to the form of the sonnet as  well as the tradition with which this form is associated. A second point of  consideration, which stands to a certain extent in conflict with the first, is the  dialogue which these sonnets constitute. This dialogue provided Steffin and Brecht  the forum and opportunity to be equal partners, contrary to their real-life  situations, where equality between the two did not exist. This forum allowed them to  witness and experience each other simultaneously both as subjects and objects both  in terms of longing and desire, as in poetic discourse, enabling them to mutually  influence each other. And as the sonnets show, this influence did in fact occur  regarding their different ideas, attitudes and needs in their relationship to each  other.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peters, Paul</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mj68z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676w188</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Steffin, Margarete -- Correspondence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Brecht, Bertolt, 1898-1956 -- Correspondence</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>