<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83m203f"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ultra-high-speed bandpass interconnects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shahidzadeh Mahani, Mohammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La demande incessante pour des systèmes de communication de donnés de vitesse de plus en plus haute et d'efficacité énergétique de plus en plus amelioree pousse les limites de la conception du circuit et du système pour de telles applications. Ces exigences difficiles nécessitent des solutions innovantes pour les interconnexions. Cette thèse concentre sur Substrate Integrated Waveguide (SIW) dans le contexte de la communication de données à grande vitesse. L'étude des caracteristiques de SIW donne une image compléte de ses atouts, et de ses faiblesses et leur solutions possibles. Un obstacle principal à l'utilisation de SIW pour interconnexion à haute vitesse est sa grande empreinte. Un SIW hybride souple qui tente de circonvenir la grande empreinte SIW grâce à une utilisation plus efficace de l'espace est proposé. Le substrat souple ouvre la possibilité de former des canaux dédiés à Communication rapide. De tels canaux n'ont pas besoin de passer par différents connecteurs ou couches de substrat. Un système de communication de données incorporant une interconnexion SIW hybride est démontré expérimentalement. Les résultats de mesure sont présentés est analysés. Létude de l'effet de flexion du substrat sur les caractéristiques de cette interconnexion ainsi que la performance du système est présentée. Les progrés de la technologie CMOS ont rendu les transistors CMOS capables de générer des signaux de fréquences allant jusqu'à des centaines de Giga Hertz. Le prochain défi après la génération du signal consiste à le transférer efficacement entre différents points. Comme SIW est une interconnexion à faible perte et qualité élevée, principalement pour la bande d'onde millimétrique, la deuxieme partie de cette thèse est dediée à l'implementation CMOS de SIW dans un IBM processus CMOS de 130nm. Une étude complète des paramètres SIW dans un environnement CMOS est élaborée. Une comparaison entre SIW et d'autres interconnexions planaires est faite concernant les parametres suivant: perte, zone, et facteur de qualité. Les limitations de DRC et leurs solutions sont discutées. Une nouvelle structure de transition entre SIW et les sondes GSG est realisée. Cette structure de transition est très efficace par ce qu'elle fait partie du SIW. La technique de pliage réduit la surface de l'interconnexion par 30%. Notre structure de transition est 75% moins longue que des implémentations précédentes. Les formules de conception de l'interconnexion SIW pliée sont dérivées, et un modèle pour la structure de transition est introduit. L'interconnexion SIW pliée est fabriquée, measurée, et ses results comparés avec l'etat d'art. Enfin, un récepteur CMOS est implémenté dans le processus IBM 130nm CMOS pour une interconnexion SIW qui fonctionne dans la gamme de fréquences de 22 GHz-32GHz. Le récepteur a une architecture de codage ON-OFF avec un filtre passe bas. Le processus de conception et les résultats de la simulation du récepteur et ses composants sont présentés. Comparaison des mesures de laboratoire avec les publications précédent prouve l'efficacité de cette implémentation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The ever increasing demand for higher speed in data communication systems as well asthe energy efficiency of such systems are pushing the boundaries of circuit and systemdesign for such applications. Such challenging requirements necessitate innovativesolutions for interconnects which are the back-bone of the communication systems.This thesis focuses on Substrate Integrated Waveguide (SIW) as a promising solutionfor high speed data communication systems. Characteristics of SIW in the contextof high speed data communication are studied in this thesis which gives a completepicture of SIW and its strengths and shortcomings and possible solutions for thechallenges it faces.One main obstacle in the path of SIW to become the interconnect of choice forhigh speed data communication application is its large footprint. A flexible hybridSIW is presented that, addresses the issue of SIW large footprint by a more efficientusage of its space. Also, the flexible substrate opens the possibility of forming dedicatedchannels to high speed communication that do not need to go through differentsubstrate layers and connectors. The flexible interconnect is then implemented ina data communication system and the results of the measurement and discussionsare presented. The effect of bending the interconnect on the characteristics of theinterconnect as well the system performance is studied which shows minimal effecton the performance of the interconnect.Given the advancements of CMOS technology which have made the CMOS transistorscapable of generating signals in the frequency ranges of up to hundreds ofGiga Hertz on one hand and the capabilities of SIW as a low loss and high qualityfactor interconnect on the other, the second part of this thesis focuses on the CMOSimplementation of SIW in an IBM 130nm CMOS process. A folding technique isutilized to reduce the area of the CMOS SIW which leads to a 30% reduction inthe area of the interconnect. Multiple comparisons between SIW and other planarinterconnects are done on the different aspects of their performance including loss,area and quality factor. The DRC limitations and their solutions are discussed. Also,a novel transition structure with minimal area overhead that is used to connect theSIW to the GSG probing pads is proposed which is only 25% the length of the previousimplementations. Formulas for designing a Folded SIW interconnect are drivenin this chapter and a model for the transition structure is introduced. Measurementresults and comparison with the state of the art are presented.Finally, a CMOS receiver is implemented in IBM 130nm CMOS process for anSIW interconnect that operates in the frequency range of 22GHz-32GHz. The receiveris an ON-OFF Keying architecture that is implemented together with a low-passfilter. Design process is described and simulation results for both the receiver and itscomponents are presented. The measurement results and comparison with previouslypublished data show the effectiveness of the solution.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gordon W. Roberts</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r912.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m203f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zw99h"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Environmental regulation of hippocampal function: distinct effects and mechanisms in the dorsal and ventral hippocampus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nguyen, Huy-Binh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les parents exercent un rôle essentiel dans le développement de leurs enfants, transmettant des traits et comportements héritables et acquis afin d'assurer leurs succès en faisant face à leurs environnement. Pour la plupart des espèces, l'expérience des enfants pendant les phases de vie les plus précoces est dominées par les interactions parentales, qui représentent la source d'information sur l'environnement la plus importante. Les systèmes neuraux, qui sont fondamentalement plastique et surtout pendant l'enfance, sont élaborés en réponse aux signaux parentaux. Ainsi, le support  ou la négligence parentale pendant la vie précoce programme le développement neural afin d'influencer la cognition à l'âge adulte. L'hippocampe est une région du cerveau qui régule l'apprentissage, l'émotivité, et la réponse neuroendocrine au stress. Cette structure est une cible majeure des signaux parentaux durant la vie précoce, programmant un grand nombre de fonctions physiologiques qui produisent plusieurs traits cognitifs/émotionnelles. Récemment, la découverte des régions anatomiquement séparé dans cette structure aide à expliquer ses contributions à ces diverses fonctions. La région dorsale participe au traitement d'information comme l'apprentissage et la mémoire spatiale. Cependant, la région ventrale traite l'information, émotionnel, relié au stress et la peur. En utilisant un modèle de variations naturelles du soin  maternel chez le rat, nous explorons l'influence de l'élevage maternel sur la physiologie hippocampique. Les rejetons  adultes des mères qui démontrent une fréquence basse de léchage envers sa portée  pendant la période précoce (rejetons des mères  « low LG ») ont une réduction en LTP dans l'hippocampe dorsal comparé aux rejetons des mères « high LG ». Cette différence est reliée aux changements dans l'expression et la fonction des récepteurs N-méthyle-D-aspartate (récepteurs NMDA). Inversement, dans l'hippocampe ventral, on retrouve l'effet opposé : la magnitude de LTP formé est augmentée chez les rejetons des mères  « low LG ». Dans cette région, cet effet s'associe plutôt avec la programmation de l'hippocampe ventrale au niveau de la fonction synaptique et cellulaire. La transformation « input-output » synaptique, l'excitation au niveau cellulaire et des réseaux, et l'expression des canaux sodiques sont augmentée chez les rejetons des mères  « low LG » en comparaison aux rejetons des mères  « high LG ». Suite au conditionnement de la peur auditive, les rejetons des mères « low LG » démontrent une réduction en gel de mouvement relié à la peur quand ils font face à un ton neutre et non-conditionné. En comparaison, les rejetons des mères « high LG » démontrent un gel de mouvement généralisé en réponse à un ton neutre. Le blocage de LTP dans l'hippocampe ventral durant l'apprentissage en utilisant un peptide-appeau abolit la capacité des rejetons des mères  « low LG » de discriminer entre le ton conditionné et neutre pendant la période de rappel. Nous décrivons un effet par lequel une réduction dans la quantité de soin maternel forme la fonction hippocampique dans une manière particulière dans chaque sous-région, afin de générer un phénotype cognitif qui est accordé au traitement d'informations reliés à la peur et l'émotion. Cependant, une augmentation dans le niveau de soin maternel supporte plutôt la fonction de l'hippocampe dorsal afin de supporter l'apprentissage et la mémoire spatiale. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Parents exert a pivotal role in the development of their offspring, passing on both heritable and learned traits and behaviours to ensure their offspring's success in facing their environment and its associated challenges. For many species the experience of the offspring during the earliest phases of life is dominated by parental interactions, which represents the primary source of environmental information during development. Neural systems, which are fundamentally plastic and exceptionally so during childhood, elaborate networks and pathways in response to parental signalling. Thus, parental warmth or neglect in early life thus programs neural development, effectively shaping cognition in adulthood. The hippocampus is a central cognitive hub that regulates learning, emotionality, and the neuroendocrine stress response. Parental signals in early life target this structure, programming myriad physiological functions that cascade to produce an array of cognitive/emotional traits. In recent years, the discovery of anatomically segregate regions within this structure has explained some of the seemingly disparate functions it serves. The dorsal region participates in the processing of "cold" information devoid of emotional content, such as spatial awareness, whereas the ventral hippocampus handles "hot", stress- and fear-related emotionally salient information. Using a rat model of naturally-occurring variations in maternal care, we explore the influence of maternal rearing on hippocampal physiology. Adult rat offspring of dams that display lower frequency of pup licking and grooming (LG) during the early post-natal period (offspring of low LG dams) show reduced synaptic long term potentiation (LTP) in the dorsal hippocampus when compared to offspring of high LG dams, mediated through differences in expression and function of N-methyl-D-aspartate (NMDA) receptors. Conversely, in the ventral hippocampus, the opposite effect is found such that the magnitude of LTP formed is instead increased, where the effect instead associates with maternal care programming of ventral hippocampal physiology at the level of synaptic and cellular function. Synaptic input-output transformation, single-cell and network-level excitability, and voltage-gated sodium channel expression is increased in offspring of low compared to high LG dams. Following auditory cued fear conditioning, offspring of low LG dams display reduced freezing in response to a neutral, unconditioned tone when compared to offspring of high LG dams, who display generalized fear-associated freezing. Inhibition of LTP in the ventral hippocampus using a decoy peptide prior to learning abolishes the capacity of offspring of low LG dams to discriminate between conditioned and neutral tones during recall.We describe an effect whereby reduced levels of maternal care shapes hippocampal function in a region-specific manner to generate a cognitive phenotype that is tuned towards the processing of fear-related emotionally salient information through increased function of the ventral hippocampus, while increased levels of maternal care instead emphasizes spatial cognition through amplified dorsal hippocampal function. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael Meaney</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Tak Pan Wong</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pt10t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw99h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603r1080"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Visuo-spatial grouping abilities in Autism spectrum disorder: assessing perceptual and cognitive contributions across development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Doobay, Victoria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La présente thèse a deux objectifs principaux. Le premier objectif (étude no.1) fut d'évaluer le lien entre la perception et la cognition chez les individus atteints d'un TSA en comparant leur performance sur une tâche informatisée de blocs inverse à un groupe de neurotypiques. Le second objectif (étude no 2) fut d'évaluer le lien fonctionnel entre la perception et la cognition au cours du développement en comparant la trajectoire des enfants et adolescents autistes et neurotypiques. Afin d'atteindre les deux objectifs, nous administrâmes aux participants des deux études la même tâche informatisée de blocs inverse, construise par nous. Les attributs physiques des surfaces des blocs furent manipulés et présentés dans trois conditions : attributs traditionnels (surfaces rouges/blanches), attributs définis par luminance (surfaces noires/blanches) et attributs définis par texture, sur trois dimensions de matrice (4, 9 et 16 blocs). La cohérence perceptuelle a été manipulée dans deux conditions : condition de faible cohérence perceptuelle (exigeant une analyse locale), et condition d'haute cohérence perceptuelle (exigeant une analyse globale). Dans l'étude no 1, tous les participants (autistes et neurotypiques) enregistrèrent des temps de réaction plus lents dans les conditions de faible cohérence perceptuelle, ainsi que dans les conditions définies par la texture pour tous les trois dimensions de matrice. Par contre, le groupe TSA enregistra des temps de réaction plus rapides que le groupe neurotypique dans les conditions de faible et d'haute cohérence perceptuelle pour les matrices de 4 et 9 blocs, indépendamment des attributs physiques des blocs. Il est alors possible que les habiletés perceptuelles des individus autistes varient avec le niveau de fonctionnement requis par la tâche. Plus précisément, il est possible que l'influence perceptuelle diminue lorsque le niveau d'analyse requis augmente (c.-à-d., les stimuli définis par la texture semblent avoir moins d'influence sur les tâches visuo-spatiales d'haut niveau que de bas niveau). Le traitement local n'est probablement pas l'approche par défaut des individus autistes. Il est plus probable que leur usage de stratégies (traitement local ou global) dépende des exigences de la tâche. Dans l'étude no 2, tous les participants (autistes et neurotypiques) enregistrèrent des temps de réaction plus rapides en fonction de leur âge pour toutes les dimensions de matrice. Le groupe TSA s'améliora (temps de réaction plus rapide) à un taux plus rapide en fonction d'âge pour les matrices de 4 blocs comparé aux neurotypiques. De plus, lorsque les exigences de la tâche furent plus simples (c.-à-d., dans les matrices de 4 blocs), tous les participants enregistrèrent des temps de réaction plus rapides dans les conditions de faible cohérence au cours du développement. Par contre, pour le groupe TSA dans les matrices de 16 blocs, il y eut une diminution de performance particulière pour les modèles textuels de faible cohérence en fonction d'âge comparé aux neurotypiques. Ceci suggère que l'information perceptuelle de bas niveau influence la performance cognitive en fonction d'âge chez les autistes. Spécifiquement, il est possible qu'une sensibilité réduite pour l'information définie par la texture puisse interrompre le traitement local lorsque les exigences de la tâche augmentent (c.-à-d., dans les matrices de 16 blocs). Les connaissances tirées de cette étude permettront une meilleure compréhension, à la fois théorique et clinique, des besoins cognitifs et perceptuels des individus autistes au cours de leur développement. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The present dissertation had two main objectives. The first objective (Study 1) was to evaluate the relationship between perception and cognition in individuals with ASD compared to typically developing individuals (TD) using a computerized reverse BDT paradigm. The second objective (Study 2) was to evaluate the functional relationship between perception and cognition across development with children and adolescents with ASD compared to TD children and adolescents. Common methodology using a computerized reverse BDT paradigm was used to assess both objectives to isolate and test the role of cognitive and perceptual processes. The physical attributes of block surfaces comprising the BDT were manipulated in three conditions: Traditional (red/white), luminance-defined (black/white), and texture-defined across three block matrix sizes (4, 9, 16 blocks). Pattern cohesiveness was varied in two conditions: low pattern cohesiveness (necessitating increased local analysis) and high pattern cohesiveness (necessitating increased global analysis).  Results in Study 1 demonstrated that all participants (irrespective of group) had significantly longer reaction times (RT) for low-cohesiveness conditions, as well as texture-defined conditions across all block matrix sizes. However, the ASD group had significantly faster RTs compared to the TD group for both low and high cohesiveness conditions in the 4 and 9 block matrix size patterns, irrespective of perceptual block attribute condition. These results do not support an argument for a global processing impairment for complex visuo-spatial information in ASD, regardless of the perceptual nature of local, low-level component parts. In addition, given the perceptual nature of the reverse BDT, it can be suggested that superior ASD performance in the traditional BDT may be mediated to a greater extent by perceptual, rather than visuo-motor processes.The results of Study 2 demonstrated that all participants displayed faster RTs as age increased in all matrix sizes (irrespective of group). In the 4 block matrix, TD individuals improved across age (faster RTs) at a significantly faster rate compared to the ASD group, suggesting stronger overall performance on the task as age increased. Furthermore, when task demands were low (4 block matrix size), all participants displayed faster RTs in the texture-defined condition across development for low cohesiveness patterns. However, the ASD group displayed a selective decrease in performance on low cohesiveness texture-defined patterns, in the 16 block condition, compared to the TD group as participants ages increased, suggesting that decreased sensitivity to texture-information may interrupt enhanced local processing when task demands are increased (i.e., 16 block matrix size). The knowledge gained from this research will impart a better understanding of both perceptual and cognitive influences on visuo-spatial abilities in ASD, as measured by a task that is often used to define cognition in individuals with ASD. Furthermore, results help to elucidate the role of non-motor, perceptual and cognitive influences on BDT performance in ASD. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Armando Bertone</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p2863.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r1080</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4t64gq80n"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Traffic estimation and detection methods utilizing automatic vehicle identification systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lawlor, Sean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les méthodes d'estimation et de détection du trafic ont été utilisées pendant des décennies pour étudier les routes en milieu urbain. Ces réseaux routiers et les modes de circulation qui y sont présents ont été traditionnellement étudiés avec des systèmes de capteurs ponctuels tels que des boucles inductives qui enregistrent le nombre de véhicules sur un segment de route. Toutefois, ces derniers temps, les progrès réalisés dans les capteurs d'identification automatique des véhicules (AVI) ont permis un déploiement de capteurs plus avancé sur ces routes urbaines. Ces capteurs enregistrent un identifiant unique pour un véhicule à chaque emplacement de capteur permettant aux véhicules d'être suivis au fil du temps.Cette thèse présente trois thèmes utilisant des données de données AVI pour effectuer une série de tâches allant de la détection de convoi à l'estimation du flux de trafic sur un réseau routier urbain à l'estimation des profils origine-destination des voyageurs sur un réseau routier. Dans le premier article, nous présentons une méthode pour identifier des véhicules qui semblent se déplacer en motifs dépendants à travers un réseau de capteurs déployé dans un environnement routier urbain. L'article suivant se penche sur l'expansion du modèle pour le trafic nominal afin de permettre des changements dans le temps du trafic à mesure que le jour progresse. Enfin, nous présentons une méthode dans le dernier article qui recrée et la matrice OD d'un flux de données AVI dans un modèle de mélange variant dans le temps des matrices OD présentes dans le réseau routier.Les méthodes présentées ont des applications allant de l'application de la loi (pour la détection de convoi), à la gestion d'évacuation d'urgence (estimation de la tendance du trafic variable dans le temps), à l'urbanisme (estimation des matrices OD variables dans le temps). La collection de méthodes présentées dans cette thèse enrichit le domaine de l'ingénierie du trafic en permettant des modèles qui dépendent uniquement des données au lieu des informations de polarisation préalable ainsi que des applications en temps réel. Dans les trois manuscrits présentés, nous présentons les méthodes analytiques de détection et d'estimation. Nous analysons ensuite la performance des algorithmes sur des données réelles et simulées tout au long de ce travail.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Traffic estimation and detection methods have been used for decades to study the roads in urban environments. These road networks and the traffic patterns present on them have traditionally been studied with point-sensor systems such as inductive loops, which record the number of vehicles on a road segment. However in recent time, advances in automatic vehicle identification (AVI) sensors have allowed for a more advanced sensor deployement on these urban roads. These sensors record a unique identifier for a vehicle at each sensor location allowing the vehicles to be \textit{tracked} over time. This thesis presents three topics utilizing data from AVI data to perform a series of tasks ranging from convoy detection to estimation of the traffic flow on an urban road network to estimation of the origin-destination (OD) patterns of travellers on a road network. In the first article, we present a method for identifying vehicles which appear to be traveling in dependent patterns through a sensor network deployed in an urban road environment. The next article looks at expanding the model for nominal traffic to allow for time-varying changes in the traffic as the day progresses. Finally we present a method in the last article which recreates an OD matrix from a stream of AVI data into a time-varying mixture model of the OD matrices present in the road network. The presented methods have applications ranging from law enforcement (for convoy detection), to emergency evacuation management (time-varying traffic pattern estimation), to city planning (estimation of time-varying OD matrices). The collection of methods which are presented in this thesis enrich the field of traffic engineering by allowing models which are only dependent on the data instead of prior biasing information as well as having applications in real-time environments. In the three manuscripts presented, we lay out the analytical methods for detection as well as estimation. We then analyze the algorithms' performance on real and simulated data throughout this work.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael Rabbat</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h4311.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gq80n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kq684"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modeling coherence effects on cavity-based spectroscopy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Najih, Mohamed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Optical cavities are powerful instruments with which to perform sensing experiments. Through spectroscopic techniques, the presence of a target biological analyte or chemical species can be inferred by detecting the changes they produce in the spectral properties of a cavity. Conventional cavity-based spectroscopy relies on very narrow linewidth laser sources in order to mitigate the effects of optical coherence on the measurements they yield. The growing demand for fully-integrated and miniaturized sensing platforms for purposes such as point-of-care testing, disaster management, and environmental monitoring places stringent constraints on the design of sensing instruments. As a result, the use of optical sources with larger linewidths is unavoidable for these applications. Given this context, the aim of this work is the derivation of closed-form analytic models of cavity-based sensing that quantify the impact of source bandwidth (i.e., coherence) on spectroscopic measurements. Three cavity-based sensing paradigms are investigated in detail: cavity-enhanced absorption spectroscopy (CEAS), cavity ring-down spectroscopy (CRDS), and phase-shift cavity ring-down spectroscopy (PS-CRDS). Furthermore, examples based on a microtoroidal cavity are presented for each paradigm, where predicted measurements obtained from systems using tunable laser (narrow linewidth) or laser diode (large bandwidth) sources are compared. The models developed in this work demonstrate that microtoroid systems employing tunable lasers can detect changes in cavity transmission coefficient and refractive index. Laser diodes also yield measurements that are comparably sensitive to changes in cavity transmission coefficient, but they are insensitive to the microtoroid's refractive index.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les cavités optiques sont des instruments exceptionnels pour les expériences de détection. À l'aide de techniques spectroscopiques, la présence d'une entité biologique ou d'une espèce chimique peut être déduite en mesurant les modifications qu'elles produisent sur le spectre d'une cavité. Conventionnellement, cette méthode est effectuée avec un laser dont la largeur spectrale très étroite minimise les effets de la cohérence optique sur les résultats obtenus. La demande croissante pour des systèmes de diagnostics miniaturisés dans les domaines de la santé et de l'environnement impose de fortes contraintes sur la conception de ces instruments. Il devient donc nécessaire d'utiliser des lasers à plus grande largeur spectrale pour ces applications. De ce fait, ce document élabore le développement de modèles mathématiques qui prédisent l'impact de la largeur spectrale d'une source lumineuse (c'est-à-dire la cohérence optique de celle-ci) sur les résultats de la spectroscopie à base de cavité. Trois techniques de détection sont investiguées en détail:  «cavity-enhanced absorption spectroscopy» (CEAS), «cavity ring-down spectroscopy» (CRDS) et «phase-shift cavity ring-down spectroscopy» (PS-CRDS). De plus, des exemples basés sur un microtoroïde sont présentés pour chaque méthodologie afin de comparer la performance d'un laser accordable (largeur spectrale très étroite) et d'une diode laser conventionnelle (largeur spectrale très large). Les modèles démontrent qu'un instrument à base de microtoroïde qui utilise un laser accordable peut détecter des changements du coefficient de transmission et de l'indice de réfraction de la cavité. Les diodes lasers donnent des résultats comparables pour le coefficient de transmission, mais ne détectent pas des changements de l'indice de réfraction.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Andrew G. Kirk</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rn70q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kq684</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bx05q"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An electron microscope study of organelle autonomy in Ochromonas danica using inhibitors of protein synthesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith-Johannsen, Heidi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Both chloroplasts and mitochondria are known to contain DNA and RNA and to have all the components required for the synthesis of nucleic acids and proteins (Roodyn and Wilkie, 1968; Smil1ie and Scott, 1969). Although these organel1es are thus potentially autonomous, current evidence favours the view that both organel1es synthesize only some of their proteins while the rest are synthesized on cytoplasmic ribosomes and subsequently transported into the organelle. In the case of mitochondria, the large majority of their proteins, including cytochrome £, malic dehydrogenase and ATPase, are synthesized on cytoplasmic ribosomes, whereas only a small number of mitochondrial proteins, all apparently insoluble inner membrane proteins, are believed to be synthesized on mitochondrial ribosomes [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>S. P. Gibbs</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395wb01v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx05q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ribosomes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mitochondria</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ochromonas danica</dc:subject><dc:subject>Proteins -- Synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chloroplasts</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aff365769q"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les problèmes de la culture québécoise dans la seconde moitie du dix-neuvième siècle tels que vus par Arthur Buies dans La lanterne et Lettres sur le Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Simard, Sylvain</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La societe quebecoise au dix-neuvteme siade fait l'unanimite autour de l'idéologie de conservation incamee .. par le clerRe. Apres l'echec de la rebellion de 1837-38, les idees liberales representees par la bourgeoisie professionnelle trouvent de mains en mains d'echos dans la population. C'est presque seu! qu'Artbur Buies, dans des pamphlets violents, tente de denoncer la mediocrite culturelle de ses compatriotes. A tous les niveaux du systeme d'education, on retrouve la presence du clerge et de l'ideologie qutU soutient [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ethler-Blais, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741v21q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365769q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French-Canadians -- Intellectual life</dc:subject><dc:subject>Buies, Arthur, 1840-1901. Lanterne</dc:subject><dc:subject>Buies, Arthur, 1840-1901. Lettres sur le Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870z584"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The isolation, purification and properties of a nuclease from neurospora crassa conidia specific for single-stranded DNA</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rabin, E. Z.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The 92Mo (d,«) 90Nb reaction has been studied at a bombarding energy of 12 MeV using the University of Montreal tandem accelerator. Data were accumulated over an angular range of 150 to 1600 in the laboratory frame. The angular distributions of emitted particles corresponding to nine low-lying states in 90Nb were" determined. A DV/BA calculation has been performed and the results are discussed with reference to particle-hole states in 90Nb and the usefulness of the {d,oQ reaction as a spectroscopic tool for the study of nuclei in the A = 90 region.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Murray J. Fraser,</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440w26q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870z584</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>DNA</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>spectroscopic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dj150"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effectiveness of monetary policy in dealing with regional disparities in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Somers, Bertram A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In their efforts to deal with the high unemployment and low per capita income which is characteristic of certain regions of Canada, federal and provincial governments have devised a number of schemes such as incentives to industry, the building up of infra-structure, and even the establishment of a new federal Department of Regional Economic Expansion. Indeed, all levels of government have expressed a growing concern over Canada's regional problems. However, no attempt has been made to see how monetary policy may be effectively used for regional purposes [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gibbs, S. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pd10r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dj150</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Monitary Policy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Monetary policy -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rk73c"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functionalism and foreign policy : an analysis of Canadian voting behaviour in the General Assembly of the United Nations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Miller, Anthony John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines the theory of functionalism and its influence as a public philosophy on Canadian po1icymakers. Functionalism is a theory of international economic and social co-operation, through international organization. A proposition is put forward that Canadian policy, as expressed through its voting behaviour in the General Assembly of the United Nations, reflected the functionalist orientation to international relations. This proposition was not substantiated. Instead, Canada was found to have no consistent policy in respect of international functionalist co-operation butt it is suggested, was most responsive to developments occurring in the political environment in Which voting behaviour was expressed. The implications of the pattern of Canadian voting for the process of international integration are explored.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steinberg, Blema</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c521n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rk73c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Foreign affairs</dc:subject><dc:subject>United Nations -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Foreign relations -- 1945-</dc:subject><dc:subject>Voting</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f860v"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Race and industrial legislation in South Africa, 1910-1926</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mulhal, David Bernard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines the theory of functionalism and its influence as a public philosophy on Canadian po1icymakers. Functionalism is a theory of international economic and social co-operation, through international organization. A proposition is put forward that Canadian policy, as expressed through its voting behaviour in the General Assembly of the United Nations, reflected the functionalist orientation to international relations. This proposition was not substantiated. Instead, Canada was found to have no consistent policy in respect of international functionalist co-operation butt it is suggested, was most responsive to developments occurring in the political environment in Which voting behaviour was expressed. The implications of the pattern of Canadian voting for the process of international integration are explored.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steinberg, Blema</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jb47w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f860v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Foreign affairs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Voting</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515r017"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le crédit dans le gouvernment de Quebec : 1696-1720</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laviolette, Diane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>De 1696 a 1720, les habitants du gouvernement de Quebeo empruntent aupr~s des marchands de la oapitale. Ceux-ci leur pretent peu a la fois, a tres court terme et autant a des fins fami1ieles que commerciales; la quasi totalite de leurs ressources se composent de credits en nature plutOt qu'en espeoes et la majorite prefere le rOle d'un detaillant A oelui drun entrepreneur. Peu d'habitants, d'un autre cOte, empruntent (1.5% de la population adulte); malgre une conjoncture economique difficile, ils se suffisent A e ...mtlmes et oompa.raissent rarement en cour A titre de defendeur, la majorite d'entre eux paraissant solvables [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zoltvany, Y.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm74x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515r017</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Credit -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>French</dc:subject><dc:subject>Quebec</dc:subject><dc:subject>History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q879q"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Meteorology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Two-dimensional infrared heating rates in the atmosphere</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Myers, Richard Allen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Equations which consider the effect of non-horizontal surfaces on the infrared radiative fluxes and temperature tendencies in the atmosphere are derived by extension of the usual one-dimensional approach. A computer program is designed to solve the two-dimensional transfer equations by employing a practical approximation for the two-dimensional transmission functions. The slopes, heights, and temperature regimes of all non-horizontal surfaces in the model are unrestricted [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Orvig, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9676274.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q879q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atmospheric temperature -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Atmosphere</dc:subject><dc:subject>Terrestrial radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Meterology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Radiative transfer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gw464"><ual:graduationDate>2016</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comorbidities in a TMD patient population</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dahan, Haissam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction: There are numerous reports of overlap between temporomandibular disorder (TMD)  and painful comorbidities, including migraines and chronic fatigue syndrome. There is evidence that this overlap is more prevalent in people with TMD with myofascial pain, compared to TMD without myofascial pain.  In addition, classification systems group people with TMD based on physical and mental variables.  However, there has been a call to look at other variables, such as presence of comorbidities, in trying to group TMD patients based on their functional capacity.  In this thesis we had three main aims: Firstly, to compare the prevalence and number of five comorbidities in people with and without myofascial pain; we then explored the relationship between increasing number and specific comorbidities and TMD pain intensity and duration.  Finally, we used cluster analysis to investigate the possible clustering of people with TMD into exclusive diagnostic groups using the presence of their comorbidities. Methods: We collected data from a total of 180 participants from two hospital clinics using a cross-sectional study design.  We assessed the prevalence of five comorbidities: migraine, chronic fatigue syndrome, irritable bowel syndrome, interstitial cystitis and restless leg syndrome, using individual patient-filled diagnostic questionnaires.  TMD pain intensity was assessed using the numerical rating scale and TMD pain duration was assessed by a questionnaire.  We also collected information about participants' demographic and psychosocial variables.  Data analyses were done using logistic regression to compare comorbidity prevalence, based on the presence of myofascial pain, linear regression to observe associations between specific and number of comorbidities and levels of TMD pain intensity and duration and by exploring clustering patterns of comorbid pain in people with TMD by using two cluster methods: Ward's minimum variance and K-means. Results: Our results demonstrated that in people with TMD, the prevalence of migraine, irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), restless leg syndrome (RLS), chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS), and interstitial cystitis (IC) is 46%, 28%, 17%, 14% and 12%, respectively.  Migraine (Odds Ratio (OR) = 3.00, 95% Confidence Interval (CI): 1.41 – 6.40), CFS (OR=3.25, 95% CI: 0.86 – 12.26), and number of comorbidities (OR=1.53, 95% CI: 1.13 – 2.08) were higher in people with myofascial TMD than in people with non-myofascial TMD.  We also observed a positive association between the number of comorbidities and TMD pain intensity (B=0.46, 95% CI 0.15-0.78) and between the number of comorbidities and TMD pain duration (B=1.56, 95% CI 0.59-2.53). The presence of migraine was positively associated with TMD pain intensity (B=1.08, 95% CI 0.30-1.87). The presence of CFS was positively associated with TMD pain intensity (B=1.12, 95% CI 0.03-2.22) and with TMD pain duration (B=5.84, 95% CI 2.38-9.30).  Finally, the clustering analysis revealed four clusters of TMD patients: simple, moderate, severe and dysfunctional.  These clusters appear to divide the sample based on TMD pain duration, TMD pain intensity and number of comorbidities.  The presence of three comorbidities in particular, migraine, IBS, and CFS, appear to differentiate people with simple TMD from those with severe and dysfunctional TMD.  Conclusion: This study showed that the prevalence of migraine and chronic fatigue is higher in people with myofascial TMD than those with non-myofascial TMD.   Also, the presence of migraine, chronic fatigue syndrome is associated with increased TMD pain intensity and duration, and an increasing number of comorbidities is associated with increased TMD pain intensity and duration.   Finally, the clustering analysis revealed four clusters of TMD patients: simple, moderate, severe and dysfunctional.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introduction: Il y a de nombreux rapports de chevauchement entre le désordre temporo-mandibulaire (TMD) et les comorbidités douloureuses, y compris les migraines et le syndrome de fatigue chronique. Il existe des preuves qui montrent que ce chevauchement est plus répandu chez les personnes atteintes TMD avec la douleur myofasciale, par rapport à la DGT, sans douleur myofasciale.  Dans cette thèse, nous avons trois objectifs: d'abord, pour comparer la prévalence et le nombre de cinq comorbidités chez les personnes avec et sans douleur myofasciale; nous pourrions alors explorer la relation entre l'augmentation du nombre de cas et de comorbidités spécifiques et l'intensité de la douleur TMD et la durée. Enfin, nous allons utiliser l'analyse de cluster pour enquêter sur les éventuelles personnes affectées par TMD en groupes diagnostiques exclusifs en utilisant la présence de leurs comorbidités.  Méthodes: Nous avons recueilli des données auprès des participants à partir de deux cliniques de l'hôpital en utilisant une conception d'étude transversale. Nous avons évalué la prévalence de cinq comorbidités: migraine, le syndrome de fatigue chronique, le syndrome du côlon irritable, la cystite interstitielle et syndrome des jambes sans repos, en utilisant des questionnaires de diagnostic de chaque patient- rempli. L'intensité de la douleur a été évaluée à l'aide de TMD à l'échelle de notation numérique et de la durée de la douleur TMD qui a été évaluée par un questionnaire. Nous avons également recueilli des informations sur les variables démographiques et psychosociales des participants. L'analyse des données a été réalisée par régression logistique pour comparer la prévalence de la comorbidité, basée sur la présence de la douleur myofasciale, la régression linéaire pour observer les associations entre le nombre de comorbidités et les niveaux d'intensité de la douleur TMD et la durée et en explorant les modèles de clustering de douleur comorbidité chez les personnes atteintes par TMD en utilisant deux méthodes de cluster: variance minimale de Ward et K-means. Résultats: Les résultats ont démontré que chez les personnes atteintes par TMD, la prévalence de la migraine, le syndrome du côlon irritable, le syndrome des jambes sans repos, le syndrome de fatigue chronique, et la cystite interstitielle est de 46%, 28%, 17%, 14% et 12%, respectivement. Migraine (OR = 3,00, IC 95%: 1,41 à 6,40), le syndrome de fatigue chronique (OR = 3,25, IC 95%: 0,86 à 12,26), et le nombre de comorbidités (OR = 1,53, IC à 95%: 01.13 à 02.08) étaient plus élevé chez les personnes atteintes myofascial TMD que chez les personnes avec des non- myofascial TMD. Il existe une association positive entre le nombre de comorbidités et TMD intensité de la douleur (B = 0,46, IC 95% 0,15 à 0,78) et entre le nombre de comorbidités et la durée de la douleur TMD (B = 1,56, IC 95% 0,59 à 2,53). La présence de la migraine a été positivement associée à l'intensité de la douleur TMD (B = 1,08, IC 95% 0,30 à 1,87). La présence du syndrome de fatigue chronique a été positivement associée à l'intensité de la douleur TMD (B = 1,12, IC 0,03 à 2,22 95%) et à la durée de la douleur TMD (B = 5,84, IC 95% 2,38 à 9,30). Enfin, l'analyse de la concentration a révélé quatre groupes sur la base des niveaux de dysfonctionnement: aiguë, légère, modérée et sévère. Conclusion: Cette étude montre que les personnes atteintes de myofascial TMD ont une prévalence plus élevée de la migraine et de la fatigue chronique comparativement aux personnes non atteintes de myofascial TMD. En outre, la présence de la migraine, le syndrome de fatigue chronique et le nombre de comorbidités est positivement associée à l'intensité de la douleur TMD et la durée. Enfin, l'analyse de la concentration des sous-groupes a révélé quatre TMD basé sur des différents niveaux de dysfonctionnement.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul J. Allison</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Yoram Shir</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zr324.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gw464</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f871c"><ual:graduationDate>2016</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interleukin 33, an inflammatory mediator in cystic fibrosis lung disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Farías, Raquel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cystic Fibrosis (CF), is a systemic disease where chronic infection with Pseudomonas aeruginosa leads to a sustained increase in pro-inflammatory mediators. These mediators attract neutrophils to the lung with the objective of clearing the infection. However, this response is excessive and results in irreversible tissue damage. This tissue damage is further potentiated through the release of alarmins, also known as damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs). During physiological conditions, these mediators are inside the cell, where they play roles as regulators of different processes. However, following necrotic cell death, these mediators are released to the extracellular space where they act upon pattern recognition receptors (PRRs) on immune cells. IL-33, a member of the IL-1 family of cytokines, is a recently discovered DAMP. Intracellularly, IL-33 binds heterochromatin and acts as a transcriptional regulator. Extracellularly, IL-33 is a very potent neutrophil chemoattractant and a key amplifier of innate immunity. My central hypothesis is that decreasing IL-33 levels will reduce inflammation in CF.My first aim is to study the expression profile of IL-33 in CF and non CF airway epithelial cells in the context both, chronic and acute infections with P. aeruginosa. Secondly, I will study the signaling pathways regulating IL-33 expression in CF airway epithelial cells following infection. Finally, I will characterize the role of IL-33 as a mediator of inflammation in our model. My data show an increase of IL-33 mRNA in CF cells in an in vitro model of chronic infection as well as during an acute infection with P. aeruginosa. Signaling through toll-like receptors (TLRs) regulates IL-33 expression since neutralization of both TLR2 and TLR5 prevented IL-33 mRNA upregulation in response to infection. Furthermore, experiments using inhibitors of specific kinases downstream TLRs show that TAK1, IKKβ, Tpl2, MEK1/2, ERK1/2 and p38 MAPK modulate IL-33 expression in response to P. aeruginosa. The increase in IL-33 mRNA is followed by an increase in intracellular protein, as assessed by immunoblotting. Interestingly, P. aeruginosa increases IL-33 in the cytoplasm of both, CF and non CF airway epithelial cells. However, IL-33 is not released in our model of acute infection. Finally, to assess the role of intracellular IL-33, airway epithelial cells stably expressing an NFκB luciferase reporter were transfected with wild-type, full-length IL-33 (FL IL-33) and with IL-33 R48, a construct with a mutation in the chromatin-binding motif (CBM). FL IL-33 is expressed in the nucleus and R48 IL-33 localizes in the cytoplasm of cells. Transfection with both, FL IL-33 and R48 IL-33 attenuated NFκB transactivation in response to TLR5 activation by flagellin. In line with the latter result, transfection of both IL-33 constructs significantly decreased IL-8 mRNA.In conclusion, P. aeruginosa increases IL-33 expression in CF airway epithelial cells. The TAK1-IKKβ-Tpl2-MEK1/2 and TAK1-MKK3/6- p38 MAPK signaling pathways modulate IL-33 expression in response to bacterial infection. This is followed by an increase in intracytoplasmic IL-33. Intracellular IL-33 dampens NFᴋB transactivation in response to TLR5 signaling, resulting in a decreased expression of pro-inflammatory cytokine genes. Future experiments will aim to identify specific intracellular IL-33 binding partners and potential postranslational modifications occuring in airway epithelium. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La fibrose kystique (FK) est une maladie systémique ou les infections pulmonaires chroniques par Pseudomonas aeruginosa mènent à une réponse inflammatoire soutenue. Les médiateurs inflammatoires attirent des neutrophiles dans le poumon avec le but d'éliminer l'infection. Cependant, cette réponse est excessive et a comme conséquence des dommages tissulaires progressifs et irréversibles. Les dommages tissulaires peuvent potentialiser cette réponse inflammatoire à travers la libération d'alarmines, aussi connues comme DAMPs (Damage Associated Molecular Patterns). Durant des conditions physiologiques, ces médiateurs se retrouvent à l'intérieur des cellules ou ils jouent des rôles comme régulateurs de différents processus cellulaires. Cependant, suite à une mort cellulaire par nécrose, ces médiateurs sont libérés dans le milieu extracellulaire favorisant l'activation et le recrutement de cellules immunitaires. IL-33, une membre de la famille de cytokines IL-1, a récemment été découverte et classifiée comme alarmine. À l'intérieur de la cellule, IL-33 lie l'hétérochromatine et agit comme régulateur transcriptionnel. Dans le milieu extracellulaire, IL-33 est un puissant chemoattractant de neutrophiles et un amplificateur de la réponse immunitaire. Mon hypothèse est qu'une diminution des niveaux d'IL-33 reduira l'inflammation dans la FK. Mon premier objectif est de caractériser l'expression d'IL-33 chez les cellules épithélilales FK et non FK lors d'une infection chronique, ainsi que durant une infection aigüe par P. aeruginosa. Ensuite, j'étudierai les voies de signalisation qui régulent l'expression d'IL-33 en réponse à cette infection. Finalement, je déterminerai le rôle d'IL-33 comme médiateur de l'inflammation dans notre modèle.Mes résultats montrent une augmentation de l'ARNm d'IL-33 chez les cellules FK dans un modèle in vitro d'infection chronique, ainsi que durant une infection aigüe par P. aeruginosa.  La signalisation à travers les récepteurs TLR (Toll-like receptors) régule l'expression d'IL-33 car l'inhibition de TLR2 et TLR5 empêche l'augmentation de l'ARNm d'IL-33 durant une infection. De plus, à l'aide de différents inhibiteurs de kinases en aval TLR, j'ai démontré que les kinases TAK1, IKKβ, Tpl2, MEK1/2, ERK1/2 et p38 modulent l'expression d'IL-33 dans le contexte d'une infection aigüe par P. aeruginosa. Cette régulation à la hausse d'IL-33 est suivie par une augmentation d'IL-33 dans le cytoplasme des cellules. Pourtant, IL-33 n'est pas relarguée dans notre modèle d'infection aigüe. Finalement, pour étudier le rôle d'IL-33 intracellulaire, des cellules épithéliales pulmonaires exprimant un rapporteur luciférase de  NFκB ont été transfectées avec IL-33 sauvage (FL IL-33) ou avec IL-33 R48, un mutant ne liant pas la chromatine. FL IL-33 est exprimée dans le noyau tandis qu'IL-33 R48 est localisée dans le cytoplasme. La surexpression de FL IL-33 ainsi que d'IL-33 R48 diminue l'activité de NFκB en réponse à une activation de TLR5 par flagelline. En accord avec ce dernier résultat, la surexpression des deux constructions d'IL-33 diminue l'ARNm d'IL-8.En conclusion, P. aeruginosa augmente l'expression d'IL-33 dans les cellules épithéliales pulmonaires. Les voies de signalisation TAK1-IKKβ-Tpl2-MEK1/2 et TAK1-MKK3/6-p38 régulent l'expression d'IL-33 lors d'une infection par bactérienne. Cette augmentation est suivie d'une augmentation d'IL-33 dans le cytoplasme. À l'intérieur de la cellule, IL-33 diminue la transactivation de gènes pro-inflammatoires par NFκB suite à une activation de TLR5. Des futures expériences viseront à identifier les partenaires intracellulaires d'IL-33 ainsi que ses modifications post-traductionelles dans l'épithélium pulmonaire.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Simon Rousseau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445ch09b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f871c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10wt22k"><ual:graduationDate>2016</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Assessing the interactions of plant-made influenza virus-like particles (VLPs) with the mammalian immune system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Young, Katie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It has long been recognized that egg-based manufacturing is an important limitation of current influenza vaccine production. In particular, this platform cannot meet the surge requirements in the event of an emerging virus. There is therefore a strong impetus to develop updated technologies that do not rely on traditional manufacturing processes. Medicago Inc. has developed a highly efficient platform to produce influenza virus-like particles (VLPs) in plants that can produce a candidate vaccine in three weeks, once sequence information is released. Although the company has both seasonal and pandemic vaccines based on the hemagglutinin (HA) protein in advanced clinical trials, the mechanisms that underlie the powerful immunogenicity of the plant-made VLPs are still not fully understood. Our first goal was to generate a ‘trackable', plant-made influenza VLP that would allow us to study VLP interactions with the mammalian immune system. To this end, we engineered a chimeric protein composed of enhanced green fluorescent protein (eGFP) fused to the C terminus of HA from influenza A/Indonesia/05/2005 (H5N1). When expressed in Nicotiana benthamiana, the H5-eGFP construct assembled into brightly fluorescent particles that resembled non-fluorescent H5 VLPs while maintaining full HA function. In Balb/c mice, H5-eGFP VLPs elicited comparable anti-H5 serologic responses to those generated by H5 VLPs and elicited a greater anti-GFP IgG response than that generated by soluble GFP. Furthermore, initial proof-of-concept experiments demonstrated that the H5-eGFP protein/VLPs could be used to monitor both VLP assembly in planta and immune trafficking in the mammalian immune system. A more in-depth characterization of VLP immune trafficking revealed that the VLPs rapidly localized to distinct compartments of the draining lymph node (LN) after administration into the mouse footpad, where they interacted with antigen presenting cells and induced increased LN cellularity. Furthermore, the H5-eGFP VLPs were retained at the injection site longer than non-particulate GFP. Finally, we characterized both the ex vivo splenocyte and in vivo systemic responses to VLP exposure in terms of cytokine and chemokine production profiles in influenza-naïve mice. These studies demonstrated that VLPs create an early pro-inflammatory and chemoattractant immune environment. In summary, we generated a dual-purpose, fluorescently-labeled H5 VLP, and used the mouse model and multiple VLP tools to gain insight into the mechanisms by which these plant-made influenza VLPs exert their powerful immunologic effects.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Depuis longtemps, il a été reconnu que la fabrication de vaccin à base d'œuf est un facteur limitant important de la production du vaccin de la grippe. En particulier, cette plateforme ne peut satisfaire aux contraintes liées à l'émergence d'un virus pandémique. Il y a donc une forte impulsion pour développer des nouvelles technologies  qui ne reposent pas sur des procédés de fabrication traditionnelle. Medicago Inc. a développé une plateforme hautement efficace pour produire dans des plantes des particules pseudo-virales de type influenza (VLP) pouvant produire un vaccin candidat endéans trois semaines, une fois la séquence génétique connue. Bien que plusieurs vaccins saisonniers et pandémiques produits par Medicago et basés sur la protéine de l'hémagglutinine (HA) soient en phase d'essais cliniques, les mécanismes détaillés qui sous-tendent l'immunogénicité puissante de VLP produit à partir des plantes ne sont pas encore totalement compris. Notre premier objectif était de générer des VLP d'influenza d'origine végétale retraçable qui nous permettrait d'étudier les interactions avec les cellules du système immunitaire des mammifères. À cette fin, nous avons conçu une protéine chimérique composée d'une protéine fluorescente verte améliorée  (eGFP) fusionnée à l'extrémité C terminale de l'HA de la grippe A/Indonésie/05/2005 (H5N1). Lorsqu'elle est exprimée dans le N. benthamiana, la construction de H5-eGFP produit des particules brillamment fluorescentes qui ressemblent au H5VLP non fluorescent tout en conservant la fonctionnalité de HA. Chez la souris Balb/c, H5-eGFP VLP a suscité des réponses sérologiques anti-H5 comparables à celles générées par les H5VLP et a suscité une réponse d'IgG anti-GFP supérieure que celle générée par la GFP soluble. En outre, les premières expériences de validation ont démontré que la protéine H5-eGFP/VLP pourrait être utilisée pour le suivi de l'assemblage de VLP dans les plantes, ainsi que servir à surveiller le trafic des cellules immunitaires qui interagissent avec le VLP. Grâce à cet outil, nous avons révélé que les VLP se retrouvent rapidement localisées dans différents compartiment du ganglion lymphatique (GL) drainant après l'administration dans le coussinet plantaire de souris, où elles interagissent avec les cellules présentatrices et induisent l'augmentation de la cellularité du GL. En outre, les H5-eGFP/VLP ont été retenus au site d'injection plus longtemps que la GFP. Enfin, nous avons caractérisé la synthèse de cytokines et chimiokines suite à l'exposition ex-vivo de splénocytes de souris naïves ainsi qu'après  l'injection de VLP dans les souris naïves. Ces études ont montré que les VLP créent rapidement un environnement immunitaire pro-inflammatoire et chimiotactique. En résumé, nous avons généré H5-eGFP/VLP qui nous a permis de mieux comprendre les mécanismes par lesquels ces particules pseudo-virales de type influenza produites dans des plantes exercent leurs puissants effets immunologiques.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brian Ward</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sz680.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wt22k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77fv273"><ual:graduationDate>2016</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ācāryābhimāna: Agency, ontology, and salvation in Pillai Lokācārya's Śrīvacana Bhūsanam</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McCann, Erin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation explores the emergence of ācāryābhimāna ("love of the ācārya") as a key theological doctrine in the development of the Śrīvaiṣṇava tradition of South India in the post-Rāmānuja period. In the late thirteenth to early fourteenth century, Piḷḷai Lokācārya articulated a point of view on a number of the theological tensions evident in the works of his predecessors. This culminates in his conception of the ācārya and his love as an independent means (upāya) of salvation. His longest and most detailed defense of this position is found in the Śrīvacana Bhūṣaṇam. Thus, this study focuses on the theological problems presented therein, as they pertain to Piḷḷai Lokācārya's conception of the ācārya. There are three major issues: (1) the conflict between the soul's agency (kartṛtva) and subservience (śeṣatva) vis-à-vis the Lord's absolute autonomy (svātantrya); (2) the apparent paradox of mediation (puruṣakāra) in the soul's relationship to the Lord; and (3) the seeming ambiguity of the ācārya's ontological status. As I will show, all three of these tensions are present in the works of his predecessors. More importantly, however, it is through his discussion of these points that he leads his reader to his own ultimate conclusion: the love of one's ācārya alone is the true means of salvation.In addition to the descriptive analysis offered in the body of this dissertation, I have prepared an English translation and a new edition with variant readings of the Śrīvacana Bhūṣaṇam based on three palm-leaf manuscripts from the collection of the École française d'Extrȇme-Orient in Pondicherry, India.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'objet de cette thèse est d'explorer l'émergence de l'ācāryābhimāna ("l'amour de l'ācārya") comme  doctrine théologique clef dans le développement de la tradition Śrīvaiṣṇava de l'Inde du Sud, au cours de la période postérieure à Rāmānuja. De la fin du XIIIe siècle au début du XIVe siècle, Piḷḷai Lokācārya élabora une réflexion sur un certain nombre de tensions déjà visibles dans les œuvres de ses prédécesseurs. Sa position a pour point culminant sa conception de l'ācārya et de l'amour de ce dernier comme un mode (upāya) indépendant de salvation. Sa défense la plus longue et la plus détaillée de cette idée se trouve dans le Śrīvacana Bhūṣaṇam. Pour cette raison, cette étude se concentre sur les problèmes théologiques qui y sont discutés, concernant la conception que Piḷḷai Lokācārya avait de l'ācārya. Il y trois thèmes majeurs : (1) le conflit, à l'intérieur de l'âme, entre agentivité (kartṛtva) et subservience (śeṣatva) face à l'autonomie absolue du Seigneur (svātantrya) ; (2) le paradoxe apparent de la médiation (puruṣakāra) dans la relation de l'âme avec le Seigneur ; (3) l'ambiguité apparente du statut ontologique de l'ācārya. Comme je le montre, ces trois tensions sont déjà présentes dans les œuvres de ses prédécesseurs. L'élément crucial, cependant, est le fait que c'est en discutant ces thèmes que Piḷḷai Lokācārya conduit son lecteur vers sa conclusion personnelle : seul l'amour de l'ācārya est un véritable mode de salvation.Comme supplément à la description analytique contenue dans le corps de cette thèse, j'ai également  préparé une traduction anglaise et une nouvelle édition, avec indication des variantes, du Śrīvacana Bhūṣaṇam, sur la base de trois manuscrits appartenant à la collection de l'École Française d'Extrême-Orient à Pondichéry (Inde).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Katherine K. Young</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Davesh Soneji</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289m753.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fv273</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religious Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tx851"><ual:graduationDate>2016</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Patient and clinician assessments on symptomatology and recovery changes on older adults following a psycho -educational program for depression and anxiety</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Potes Holguin, Angela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Geriatric psychiatry populations present high prevalence and re-admission rates of depression and anxiety disorders, report subjective cognitive complaints that often precedes the onset of cognitive decline and are in gross need of service assessment. Evaluation of Mental Health services places important attention to the assessment of patient's perspectives, especially as treatment outcome studies typically assess clinician ratings rather than patient ratings. Pre-post measures of changes in depression (GDS), anxiety (BAI), well-being (GWBS) and self-assessments of recovery (RAS) were collected in a sample of 34 older adults (age = 71.32±6.46 years) participating on an ongoing psycho-educational program. Post -testing data included perceived improvement (PIQ) rated by patients and clinicians, and clinician assessment on depressive symptoms (CS-GDS). The first study examined the association between patient's perceived improvement and patient and clinician ratings on symptomatology. First, relationships between patient's perceived improvement and symptomatic change were studied. Second, patient's perceived improvement and post-measures of depression measured by patients and clinicians were also examined. Results indicate that while pre-post patient assessments on depressive symptomatology are associated to patient's perception of improvement, assessments on changes of anxiety and well-being are not. Moreover, patient and clinician ratings on depression symptoms post-treatment were associated to perceived improvement. In this context, patients report stronger associations. Interestingly, components of perceived improvement that assess aspects of social relations are associated to patient assessments of depression symptoms but not to clinician assessments. It appears that differences between patient and clinician ratings emerge as they place attention to different aspects of treatment outcome. In light with this, the second study explored associations between patient changes in recovery and patient and clinician assessments on perceived improvement, as aspects other than symptomatology change are considered relevant to the assessment of treatment outcome.  Despite recovery improvements are observed, patient assessments are not associated while examining recovery change and perceived improvement. Clinician assessments implied that patient improvement declines as recovery changes increase. Results from both studies imply patient and clinician differences on what they consider important within the assessment of treatment outcome. First, patient results on symptomatology change may be subject to their representation of illness, whereas longitudinal effects of treatment duration and service settings may have hindered recovery changes. Second, clinician assessments on symptomatology change may have been influenced by their tendency to focus on the assessment of depression symptomatology, whereas in the context of recovery, clinicians may differ in their perceptions of patient's improvement due to their own expectations. Future studies may integrate simultaneous assessments of instruments exploring symptoms and aspects other than depression (i.e. recovery), especially those examining representations of illness in older adults. In the same line, as the PIQ identifies patients who benefit more (or less) from treatment, assessments of non-completers and differences between patients diagnosed with mixed depression and anxiety versus those diagnosed with depression or anxiety alone may also be considered. In regards to examining influences on treatment retention, aspects including duration of treatment and type of setting may also be studied. Finally, in order to avoid rating biases, the use of double-clinician assessment may be influential in future directions of research. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les personnes traitées en psychiatrie gériatrique présentent une forte prévalence t de dépression et des troubles anxieux  et un taux de réadmission élevé. Il importe alors d'évaluer les services de santé qu'elles requièrent. Une attention particulière mérite d'être portée à la perspective des patients, spécialement en ce qui se rapporte aux résultats des traitements puisqu'ils sont généralement évalués par les cliniciens plutôt que les patient eux-mêmes. L'étude a été effectuée auprès d'un échantillon de 34 adultes âgés (en moyenne de 71.32±6.46 ans) participant à un programme psychoéducatif. Parmi les données recueillies au terme du programme figure aussi deux échelles complétées par leurs cliniciens ; une échelle d'amélioration perçue (PIQ) et une autre  sur l'évaluation de leurs symptômes dépressifs (CS-GDS). La première étude a examiné la relation entre l'amélioration perçue par les patients et leur évaluation ainsi que celle de leur clinicien de leurs symptômes. Les résultats impliquent que les évaluations des symptômes de dépression sont associées à l'amélioration perçue par les patients. Par contre, aucune corrélation significative n'a été trouvée entre les changements de symptomatologie pour l'évaluation de l'anxiété et du bien-être. En outre, les évaluations des patients et des cliniciens en rapport avec les symptômes de dépression à la fin du traitement sont associées à l'amélioration perçue des patients. Toutefois, la dimension de l'amélioration perçue (relations sociales)  est associées avec des symptômes de dépression par les patients seulement.Compte tenu  ces différences, les aspects autres que le changement symptomatologique ont été jugés pertinents d'être étudiés. Dans ce contexte, la seconde étude a porté sur l'association entre le rétablissement des patients et l'amélioration perçue jugée par les patients et cliniciens. Les résultats indiquent que même si le rétablissement des patients s'est amélioré après l'intervention, leur  évaluation n'indique pas d'association avec l'amélioration perçue. Les évaluations des cliniciens, quant à elles,  suggèrent une diminution dans l'amélioration des patients lorsque le rétablissement s'accroit. Les résultats des deux études indiquent des différences entre les patients et les cliniciens sur ce qu'ils considèrent  important quant à l'évaluation des résultats du traitement. À cet égard, les résultats des patients quant au changement symptomatologique en relation à leur amélioration perçue peuvent être conditionnés par leur perception de la maladie. Cependant, la durée du traitement et les caractéristiques des services peuvent avoir influencé leur perception de rétablissement. Deuxièmement, les évaluations de leurs cliniciens à propos du changement symptomatologique peuvent résulter de préconceptions quand ils tentent de se concentrer sur les évaluations de la symptomatologie de la dépression. De plus, dans le contexte du rétablissement, les perceptions des cliniciens sur l'amélioration des patients peuvent être modifiées par leurs propres attentes. Des études futures pourraient intégrer des évaluations simultanées d'instruments mesurant des symptômes et d'autres aspects en dehors de la dépression, spécialement ceux qui examinent les représentations de la maladie chez les personnes âgées. Dans cette perspective, comme l'échelle du PIQ, servant à identifier les patients qui bénéficient plus (ou moins) d'un traitement, l'évaluation des abandons ainsi que les différences entre les diagnostics des patients incluant la dépression et l'anxiété mixte versus les diagnostics de dépression ou d'anxiété uniquement, pourraient aussi être examinées. En ce qui concerne l'examen des influences sur la rétention de traitement, les aspects de la durée du traitement et le lieu de service peuvent être considéré. Enfin, afin d'éviter les biais des évaluateurs, l'utilisation des évaluations doubles par des cliniciens peut avoir une influence sur les directions  futures. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michel Perreault</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77ss667.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tx851</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychiatry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343v713"><ual:graduationDate>2016</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bayesian adjustment for confounding in Bayesian propensity score estimation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gonzalez Ginestet, Pablo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le problème de sélection de variable pour les modèles de score de pretension(SP) est un enjeu central auquel font face les chercheurs. Des méthodes jointes bayésiennes pour le SP ont récemment été proposées par Zigler et Dominici (2014, Journal of the American Statistical Association, 109, 95-107). Or, ces méthodes ne sont pas étrangères au problème connu dont les stratégies de sélection de facteurs confondants soufrent; elles ont tendance à inclure les variables qui sont associées avec la variable d'exposition, même si elles ne sont pas associées au résultat. En se basant sur les résultats ci-haut et sur ceux de Wang et al. (2012, Biometrics, 68, 661-671), nous proposons une nouvelle approche, que nous nommons Ajustement bayésien pour facteurs confondants en SP bayésien. L'objectif de cette approche est d'estimer l'effet causal moyen à l'aide d'une moyenne pondérée, indexée par différents modèles de SP de manière à diminuer l'impact de la limitation dont souffre les méthodes de sélection de variables, tel que mentionne ci-haut. Notre approche est une procédure en deux étapes, basée sur trois modèles : (1) le résultat comme fonction des facteurs confondants potentiels (le modèle de score prognostique); (2) la variable d'exposition comme fonction des facteurs confondants potentiels (le modèle de SP), et (3) le résultat comme fonction de la variable d'exposition, les facteurs confondants potentiels et le SP (le modèle résultat). La clé de notre approche est l'introduction à la deuxième  étape d'une prieure informative pour le modèle de SP qui relit ce modèle et le modèle de score prognostique. La prieure informative permet d'éliminer les variables instrumentales (VIs) du modèle de SP, donnant une probabilité a priori moindre aux modèles qui contiennent des VIs et favorisant ceux contenant les facteurs confondants et les prédicteurs du résultat. Nous illustrons certaines propriétés de notre approche à  l'aide d'une étude de simulation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The problem of variable selection for propensity score (PS) models is a central issue that researchers face. Joint Bayesian PS methods for variable selection on the PS models have been recently proposed by Zigler and Dominici (2014, Journal of the American Statistical Association, 109, 95-107). However, these methods are not exempt from the known limitation that a confounder selection strategy for the PS models suffers; they tend to include variables that are associated with the exposure even if they are not associated with the outcome. Building upon this work and the work of Wang et al. (2012,  Biometrics, 68, 661-671), we propose a new approach, which we call Bayesian Adjustment for Confounding (BAC) in Bayesian PS. The objective of this work is to estimate the average causal effect as a weighted average over different PS models using this new approach in order to mitigate the limitation on the variable selection that the previous methods exhibit. Our approach is a two stage procedure based on three models: (1) the outcome as a function of the potential confounders (the prognostic score model); (2) the exposure as a function of the potential confounders (the PS model), and (3) the outcome as a function of the exposure, the potential confounders and PS (the outcome model). The key to our approach is the incorporation in the second stage of an informative prior distribution on the PS models that links the prognostic score model with the PS model. The informative prior provides a chance to rule out instrumental variables (IVs) from the PS model, assigning less prior probability to those models that include IVs and favoring those containing the set of confounders and predictors of outcome. We illustrate features of our proposed approach through a simulation study.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robert William Platt</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m082.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343v713</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nd899"><ual:graduationDate>2016</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An accelerated algorithm for delayed distributed convex optimization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bakagiannis, Ioannis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans de nombreux problèmes d'optimisation à grande échelle qui se posent dans le cadre de la machine l'apprentissage , la variable de décision est de haute dimension et la fonction objectif se décompose en une somme sur un grand nombre de termes (une pour chaque instance dans l'ensemble de données d'apprentissage). Dans ce cadre , les méthodes d'optimisation de second ordre tels en tant que méthode de Newton ou quasi- Newton , ne sont pas traitables par la complexité de et l'évaluation de l'inversion de la Hessian ou une approximation de celui-ci. Par conséquent , nous nous concentrons sur les méthodes du premier ordre qui sont évolutives dans un cadre décentralisé.Dans cette thèse, nous fournissons un système cadre pour des méthodes d'optimisation distribués retardés convexes pour les réseaux multi-agents dans un cadre serveur-maître. Notre objectif est d' optimiser une fonction objectif globale qui est la somme des fonctions objectifs locales des agents dans le réseau. Nous introduisons l'idée d' accélérer l'algorithme de Nesterov pour l'optimisation centralisée dans le cadre serveur maître décentralisée puisqu'il est l'algorithme optimal pour le classe de fonctions qui nous intéressent. Il est naturel que dans un cadre asynchrone, la valeur actuelle du noeud de serveur est une valeur passée du noeud maître communiquée depuis quelques mesures de temps et ainsi donner lieu à des retards dans l'analyse. Nous ont prouvé que d'une méthode accélérée retardé maintient l'optimalité de l'algorithme avec des taux de convergence de O(1/t²). Nous avons également effectué des simulations et nous avons vérifié qu'un algorithme accéléré surpasse d'autres algorithmes disponible pour optimisation décentralisé dans un cadre de serveur maître.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In many large-scale optimization problems arising in the context of machine learning the decision variable is of high-dimension and the objective function decomposes into a sum over a large number of terms (one for each instance in the training data set).In this setting, second-order optimization methods such as Newton or quasi-Newton methods, are not tractable due to the complexity of evaluating and inverting the Hessian, or an approximation thereof. Also, the vast amount of data available is spread around multiple servers making a centralized optimization solution sub optimal or impossible. Therefore we concentrate on first order methods that are scalable in a decentralized setting.In this thesis we provide a framework for distributed delayed convex optimization methods for networks in a master-server setting. Our goal is to optimize a global objective function which is the sum of the local objective functions of the agents in the network.We review Nesterov's accelerated algorithm for centralized optimization since it is the optimal algorithm for the class of convex, and strongly convex functions and to modify it accordingly for decentralized optimization in the master-server setting.It is natural that in an asynchronous setting the current value of the server node is a past value of the master node communicated some time steps ago, and thus gives rise to delays in the analysis. We have proven that a delayed accelerated method maintains the optimality of the algorithm with a convergence rate of O(1/t²). We have also performed simulations and we have verified that the accelerated algorithm performs better that the alternative algorithms for decentralized optimization in a master server setting.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael Rabbat</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580q460.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nd899</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870z81x"><ual:graduationDate>2016</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Has the war powers resolution made a difference?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Conley, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines whether or not the 1973 War Powers Resolution (Resolution) has made a difference. I examine the Resolution from a theoretical and an empirical standpoint. Theoretically, I apply two competing approaches, one from the Analytical Liberal perspective, and the other from the Neoclassical Realist. These two approaches generate different expectations concerning the Resolution. Although these two approaches are widely used, they have rarely been compared in a direct fashion. By applying both to one question, I hope to shed light on their relative strengths and weaknesses. Empirically, I evaluate the Resolution's impact through historical military interventions, before and after the passing, to prove that the Resolution has not altered the intervention decision-making within the U.S. government. By examining interventions, this paper not only demonstrates that the Resolution has had little impact, but that the results support the Neoclassical Realists' argument. The Neoclassical Realist depiction of American foreign policy as a top-down endeavor is more accurate, when focusing on decisions to use military force. This paper intends to prove that the 1973 War Powers Resolution has been an ineffective piece of American legislation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine si la Loi sur les pouvoirs de guerre de 1973 (la Loi) vraiment fait une différence. J'examine la Loi des points de vue théorique et empirique. Je fais appel à deux approches théoriques opposées, une de la perspective Analytical Liberal, et l'autre de la perspective Neoclassical Realist. Ces deux approches généreront des attentes différentes concernant la Loi. Bien que ces deux approches soient largement utilisées, elles ont rarement été comparées d'une façon directe. En appliquant les deux à la même question, j'espère pouvoir clarifier sur leurs points forts et faibles relatifs. J'évalue l'impact de la Loi par le biais des interventions militaires tant avant et après l'adoption de la Loi, pour prouver que la Loi n'a pas modifié la décision du gouvernement américain d'intervenir. En examinant des interventions, ce document ne démontre non seulement que la Loi a eu peu d'impact, mais aussi que les résultats appuient l'argument des Neoclassical Realists. La représentation Neoclassical Realist de la politique étrangère américaine comme processus descendant explique le mieux les décisions d'utiliser la force militaire. Ce document pour objectif de prouver que la Loi sur les pouvoirs de guerre de 1973 ont été un projet de loi américaine inefficace.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mark R. Brawley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nk887.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870z81x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak35697136"><ual:graduationDate>1928</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Latin</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Supernatural influences in classical tragedy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Banford, Jean E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>So sang Prouertius in age when men had forgotten the untroubled simple aoceptance of the supernatural that Homer's heroes knew, and the nobler steadfast faith in the final vindication of right against wrong, that Aeschylus sang; in an age when only his own great passionate heart insistently demanded an after life for his beloved dead, that it might still adore her memory when herself had left him. Whether he really believed that Cynthia awaited him among the shadows, or whether his tired troubled mind only endeavoured to comfort itself with vain fond-memories of' his lost love, will never now be known: at all events, it was not long afterwards that he too bade farewell to the world, and joined th "wan shadows" of whom he had sung. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Latham, G.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Carruthers, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xx78c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k35697136</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Latin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Supernatural in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qp94w"><ual:graduationDate>1928</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A petrographic study of a zinc prospect in Bouchette Township, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Burton, Frederick Randall</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The area here described is situated 70 miles north of Ottawa, on the Gatineau branch of the C.P.R. near the town of Burb1dge, Quebec. It lies within the Laurentlan upland and in that part containing the famous Grenv111e Series of metamorphosed sediments. The field-work was performed in the latter part of the season of 1927, for the Bureau of Mines, Quebeo, in co-operation with the C.P.R. The work was made possible through the kindness of the Consolidated Mining and Smelt1ng Co., who held an option on the area. The object of the work was to make a study of the zinc prospect and a small area surrounding it, with a view to determining something as to its geological relations. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>O'Neill, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qs442.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qp94w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gw48p"><ual:graduationDate>1927</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Consequences of a matrix mechanics and a radiating harmonic oscillator without the quantum postulate</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Press, Abraham</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to avoid postulating quantum conditions from the start, as done in the Heisenberg-Born-Jordan-Dirac Matrix Mechanics, the writer conceived the idea of giving concrete visualization to the elements of the pq-qp matrix by relating them to a classical formula leading to an action. (See paper published in the Phil. Mag. for Sept., 1924). This required a slightly modified way of defining the unit matrix. If we consider a portion of a radiating gas capable of sending out a series of wave-lengths according to an observed law, then we may attribute to each periodicity a sine element of the p and q matrices. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eve, A.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Gillson, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2688011.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gw48p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795b46r"><ual:graduationDate>1927</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Relation of the parathyroids to fracture healing as controlled by X-rays</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ross, Dudley E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the time of Sandstrom's discovery of the external parathyroids in 1880 the parathyroid glands have been the subject of muoh controversy. Sandstrom, who credited both Remak (1851) and Virchow (1864) with having seen these bodies, believed that they probably represent undeveloped portions of thyroid tissue. Under the name of "undeveloped portions of the thyroid gland" Baber (1881), in a oommunication on the thyroid, described what we now recognize as the internal and external parathyroids. He found no evidenoe of their later development into thyroid tissue. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tait, J.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Archibald, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311s145.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795b46r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>