<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn1072730"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Neu tyrosine autophosphorylation site mutants exhibit similar and distinct mammary tumour phenotypes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lam, Sonya Hoan Linh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>ErbB2/Neu overexpression is observed in 20--30% of human mammary carcinomas and correlates with poor prognosis. We have demonstrated that four ErbB2/Neu tyrosine autophosphorylation sites (YB, YC, YD and YE) are sufficient to mediate transforming signals in vitro and bind distinct adapter proteins, suggesting that transformation functions through distinct pathways. To study the role of each individual tyrosine autophosphorylation site in mammary tumourigenesis, we derived transgenic mice expressing mutant ErbB2/Neu receptors in the mammary gland. Recently, we showed that YB and YD female transgenic mice developed mammary tumours with differences in tumour latency, morphology, and metastatic potential. To further understand the role of the autophosphorylation sites, I characterized the YC and YE transgenic mouse models and showed that although, they exhibit similar phenotypes, they also differ in their latency, morphology and metastatic rate compared to the YB and YD transgenic mouse models. This suggests that recruitment of specific adaptor proteins has distinct biological effects on ErbB2/Neu-mediated mammary tumourigenesis.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999b305.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1072730</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Phosphorylation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Receptor, erbB-2 -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mammary Neoplasms, Experimental -- metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f726k"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nrg1p and Rfg1p in Candida albicans yeast-to-hyphae transition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lacroix, Céline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The ability of Candida albicans to change morphology plays several roles in its virulence and as a human commensal. The yeast-to-hyphae transition is tightly regulated by several sets of activating and repressing pathways. The DNA-binding proteins Rfg1p, Nrg1p and the global repressor Tup1p are part of the repressors found to regulate this morphogenesis. Knowledge of these repressors is based on extrapolations from homology to S. cerevisiae and from expression studies of mutants in inducing conditions, all of which are indirect means of determining a protein's function. We proposed a genome-wide location study of the Nrg1 and Rfg1 transcription factors to obtain direct data to identify their in vivo targets. Our results suggest different avenues for Nrg1p function and a regulation behaviour diverging from the previously suggested model: Nrg1p acts not only as a repressor but also as a transcription activator. Furthermore it regulates its target genes through binding in their coding regions instead binding to the expected regulatory elements on promoters.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290f234.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f726k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Morphogenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fungal Proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Candida albicans -- growth &amp; development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Repressor Proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oligonucleotide Array Sequence Analysis -- methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hyphae -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae Proteins</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988p61j"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exploiting the use of mesenchymal stromal cells genetically engineered to overexpress insulin-like growth factor-1 in gene therapy of chronic renal failure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kucic, Terrence</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mesenchymal stromal cells (MSC) are bone marrow-derived, non-hematopoietic progenitors that are amenable to genetic engineering, making them attractive delivery vehicles for therapeutic proteins. However, limited transplanted cell survival compromises the efficacy of MSC-based gene therapy. We hypothesized that co-implantation of insulin-like growth factor-1 (IGF-I)-overexpressing MSC (MSC-IGF) would improve MSC-based therapy of anemia by providing paracrine support to erythropoietin (EPO)-secreting MSC (MSC-EPO). Murine MSC were found to express the IGF-I receptor and be responsive to IGF-I stimulation. IGF-I also improved MSC survival in vitro. MSC were admixed in a bovine collagen matrix and implanted by subcutaneous injection in a murine model of chronic renal failure. Mice receiving MSC-EPO co-implanted with MSC-IGF experienced a greater and significantly sustained elevation in hematocrit compared to controls; heart function was also improved. Co-implantation of MSC-IGF therefore represents a promising new strategy for enhancing implanted cell survival, and improving cell-based gene therapy of renal anemia.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t108.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988p61j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mesenchymal Stem Cells -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gene Therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Insulin-Like Growth Factor I -- therapeutic use</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kidney Failure, Chronic -- therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stromal Cells -- metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am039k881z"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the meteorological conditions associated with anomalously early and anomalously late openings of a Northwest Territories winter road</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Knowland, Katherine Emma</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the Canadian arctic, winter roads are engineered across the frozen land, rivers, and lakes. The strength and longevity of these roads depends on particular weather conditions. Our research focuses on the winter road between Tulita and Norman Wells, Northwest Territories, open since 1982. The opening dates for the winter road are statistically analyzed. Five extreme early-opening years and five extreme late-opening years are determined and subsequently compared to both surface weather observations and large-scale synoptic structures prior to the opening dates for these years. Results show extreme late years are strong El Nino seasons, and extreme early years are colder and have more precipitation during November, than the 1971--2000 climatology. The analysis of meteorological conditions near Norman Wells, associated with the extreme opening dates for this winter road, provides planners with more precise information germane to this road construction.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk93q.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k881z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Roads -- Northwest Territories -- Norman Wells Region -- Design and construction -- Cold weather conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Roads -- Design and construction -- Cold weather conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Norman Wells (N.W.T.) -- Climate</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A37720h583"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A search for the decays B⁺ [arrow] l⁺[nu] and B⁰ [arrow] l⁺ [tau]⁻ (l = e, [mu]) using hadronic tag reconstruction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Klemetti, Miika A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We present searches for the leptonic decays B + → ℓ+nu and the lepton flavor violating decays B0 → ℓ+/-tau &amp;mnplus;, where ℓ = e, mu, with data collected by the BABAR experiment at SLAC. These searches utilize a technique in which we fully reconstruct the accompanying B¯ in Upsilon(4S) → BB¯ events, and look for a monoenergetic lepton in the signal B frame. The signal yield in the data is extracted from a fit to the signal lepton candidate momentum distribution in the signal B rest frame. Using a data sample of approximately 378 million BB¯ pairs (342 fb-1), we find no evidence of signal in any of the decay modes. Branching fraction upper limits of B (B+ → e +nu) &lt; 5.2 x 10-6, B (B+ → mu+nu) &lt; 5.6 x 10-6, B (B0 → e +tau-) &lt; 2.8 x 10-5 and B (B0 → mu+tau -) &lt; 2.2 x 10-5, are obtained at the 90% confidence level.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94ht33g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720h583</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Leptons (Nuclear physics) -- Decay</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8p58ph52k"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dietary assessment and self-perceived impact of food in persons with multiple sclerosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kilborn, Sally J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a neurodegenerative disease of uncertain etiology and pathology, affected by genetic and environmental factors. Nutrition may be one of these factors. This study used one validated 80-item food frequency questionnaire and one 24-hour recall to assess dietary intake, anthropometric and lifestyle practices, and self-perceived impacts of food in 36 adults with MS. Although only 3 persons followed special diets for MS, 28 indicated food influenced the way they felt, and 17 thought food directly impacted their MS. Over 50% of participants were identified as potential underreporters of energy. Low intakes in grains, dairy, and fruits and vegetables were commonly observed. The FFQ and 24-hour recalls estimated different mean sample intakes of all nutrients; these differences were significant for carbohydrates, water, iron, magnesium, riboflavin, niacin, and omega-3. Both tools identified mean intakes below suggested AI levels for fibre, calcium, vitamin D, omega-3 and omega-6, and above the UL for sodium. Supplements were used by 72% of participants, and increased estimated nutrient intakes above the EAR or the UL for some nutrients in some individuals.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk940.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58ph52k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Multiple sclerosis -- Patients</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multiple sclerosis -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A41687m880"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of the effect of trastuzumab (Herceptin) on the development and progression of breast cancer associated skeletal metastasis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khalili Boroojeni, Parisa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Breast cancer is the most commonly diagnosed cancer in women. Despite recent advances in screening and early detection, breast cancer continues to result in a high incidence of morbidity and mortality. In its late stage the majority of patients exhibit signs of destructive skeletal metastasis. This complication is promoted by the production of growth factors by tumor cells which can induce tumor cell proliferation via their interaction with their respective receptors to initiate the vicious cycle of bone resorption. Inhibition of growth factors signaling through their receptors can therefore serve as a useful therapeutic approach to block bone metastasis. The biological characteristics of cancer cells along with the targeting properties of immune system offer a novel approach in the treatment of breast cancer. Directed against HER-2/nue oncogene, the recombinant humanized monoclonal antibody, Trastuzumab (Herceptin), has shown significant clinical benefits for the treatment of HER-2 positive metastatic breast cancer. In the present study, the effects of Herceptin and its molecular mechanism of action in abrogating the development and progression of osteolytic bone metastasis is investigated in an experimental mouse model of skeletal metastasis using human breast cancer cells BT-474 which are known to express high levels of HER-2. Treatment of BT-474 cells with Herceptin caused a dose dependent decrease in cell proliferation. In in vivo studies BT-474 cells were injected by into the left ventricle of female BALB/c nu/nu mice. Intraperitoneal infusion of Herceptin from the day of tumor cell inoculation or at the time of radiologically detectable skeletal metastasis either slowed the development or prevented the progression of skeletal metastasis as compared to control groups of animals receiving non-specific IgG. Bone histological analysis of long bones showed the ability of Herceptin to reduce the ratio of tumor volume to bone volume as well as mitotic index when Herceptin treatment was initiated from the day of tumor cell inoculation. Immunohistochemical analysis of long bones showed a significantly lower level of activated (phosphorylated) MAPK in bones of Herceptin treated animals. These studies demonstrate the ability of Herceptin to inhibit the development and abrogate the progression of skeletal metastasis associated with breast cancer by blocking the HER-2 mediated signaling pathways.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tk11j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687m880</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bone Neoplasms -- drug therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antineoplastic Agents -- therapeutic use</dc:subject><dc:subject>Breast Neoplasms -- pathology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antibodies, Monoclonal -- therapeutic use</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bone Neoplasms -- secondary</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gp66x"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anatomical mapping of dopamine receptor supersensitivity in the rat extended striatum</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaur, Navneet, 1979-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The extended striatum is a large, dopamine-innervated forebrain structure comprising the caudate-putamen, nucleus accumbens and olfactory tubercle (OT). The OT remains largely unexplored, despite its potentially important role in behaviour and dopamine (DA)-mediated reward. One method of studying function is examining "supersensitive" behavioural responses to DA agonists in animals after striatal DA loss. We examined whether D1 or D2 receptor supersensitivity occurs in the OT and neighbouring islands of Calleja (ICj), after unilateral 6-hydroxydopamine lesions of the medial forebrain bundle and medial OT (mOT). We also asked if the resulting DA receptor supersensitivity is anatomically heterogeneous. Our results showed D1-like receptor supersensitivity occurring in the OT with several DA agonists, and heterogeneously across the extended striatum. There is evidence of D2-like receptor supersensitivity in the ICj. Our focal mOT lesion failed to show DA receptor supersensitivity. Finally, there is little evidence for D2 supersensitivity as measured by [ 35S]GTPgammaS binding.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445ch898.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gp66x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Quinpirole -- pharmacology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Receptors, Dopamine -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Olfactory Pathways -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islands of Calleja -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dopamine Agonists -- pharmacology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corpus Striatum -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rats</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623h17m"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Early growth factor response 1 (Egr-1) negatively regulates expression of calsequestrin (CSQ) on cardiomyocytes in vitro</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kasneci, Amanda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Heart failure represents an important cause of death in Western Countries. The pathophysiology of heart failure is mainly associated with abnormalities in intracellular calcium control. We previously showed that Egr-1 negatively regulates expression of sodium-calcium exchanger (NCX) in vivo and in vitro. Here we tested the hypothesis that Egr-1 regulates expression of calcium storage proteins in the sarco-endoplasmic reticulum (SER), calsequestrin (CSQ) and/or ER, calreticulin (CRT) directly or indirectly via Egr-1:NFAT (nuclear factor of activated T-cells) formation. Secondarily, we hypothesized that this will reduce calcium mobilization. We found that undifferentiated 1293F cells, overexpressing Egr-1, have reduced CSQ compared to control H9c2 cells. We demonstrated that Egr-1 negatively regulates CSQ but not CRT expression. The Egr-1 mediated decrease in CSQ is linked to decreased calcium availability. Repression is by a novel NAB-independent (NGFI-A binding protein) activity localized to a.a. region 1-307. We conclude that Egr-1-mediated reductions in calcium storage protein expression alter calcium availability for cardiac contraction/relaxation.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v217m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623h17m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Early Growth Response Protein 1 -- genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Myocytes, Cardiac -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sarcoplasmic Reticulum -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Calcium Signaling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Calsequestrin -- metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3t945v521"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Basal-like breast cancers : characterization and therapeutic approaches</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khalil, Tayma</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background. Both basal-like subtype and BRCA1-related breast cancers tend to have a poor overall prognosis and lack of effective treatments. Given that the lung cancer drug gefitinib and the leukemia drug dasatinib inhibit proteins also belonging to the molecular signature of this subtype, we and others hypothesized that they might be useful therapies for those two breast cancer subgroups. Methods. Eight breast cancer cell lines were characterized by immunohistochemistry and western blotting and were treated with both drugs. Response was measured by using the sulphorhodamine B (SRB) assay. Results. Two out of six basal-like cell lines were sensitive to gefitinib and five of six to dasatinib. BRCA1-related breast cancers were also responsive to dasatinib (three out of four). Moreover, EGFR and caveolin-1 act as markers for dasatinib sensitivity, but do not appear to be the primary targets of this drug. The presence of SRC but not ABL is necessary to achieve a response to dasatinib. Conclusion. Dasatinib is more effective in the treatment of basal-like breast cancers than gefitinib and acts by inhibiting SRC and other molecules that are yet to be determined.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j260x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945v521</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Breast Neoplasms -- genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pyrimidines -- therapeutic use</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genes, BRCA1</dc:subject><dc:subject>Breast Neoplasms -- drug therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carcinoma, Basal Cell -- drug therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thiazoles -- therapeutic use</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carcinoma, Basal Cell -- genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Quinazolines -- therapeutic use</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rz24m"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Education as a healing process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Taieb, Belkacem</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This master's thesis is written by an indigenous person who sees education as a healing process. In the tradition of narrative inquiry (Clandinin and Connelly, 2000) I interweave autobiographical texts with reflections on colonialism, indigeneity and multiculturalism. I am Amazigh (Kabyle) from the country now called Algeria, where my people have lived for some 5,000 years. I was raised in France, where I experienced a racism which I became conscious of when I arrived in Canada. I draw on the Medicine Wheel teachings given by First Nations Elders in Canada as the philosophical framework of my text, a framework based on the balance of spiritual/emotional/physical and mental dimensions of experience. I provide the context for my story, explain my methodology, and offer narratives that I then reflect on as part of my life-journey through societies, cultures, belief systems and educational contexts.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q792k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rz24m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Indigenous peoples -- Education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multicultural education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Critical pedagogy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Decolonization</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acf95jf84c"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mémoire contumace : suivi de, Le palimpseste à l'œuvre</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>St-Amour, Sylvain</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The first part of my master's thesis in creative writing explores the way the leading character's identity is structured as a function of memory. The protagonist, limited to a confined space, does not have access to his existence other than through the senses which are drawn from different episodes of his past. These reminiscences, that open the way to experience, forge his becoming, and allow him to superimpose his own individual path to memories that he has of those persons who have shaped his experience of the world. The critical part of my work concerns the genesis and the elaboration of the last draft of Hubert Aquin's novel entitled "Obombre" in which the fragmented identity of the protagonist is defined through the destiny of other characters with whom he shares a common experience. The genetic studies approach in literature sheds light on the creative mechanisms and, in this particular case, the construction of a literary work by the superimposition of different narrative threads in a unique discourse.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b237w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jf84c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aquin, Hubert, 1929-1977 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Identity (Philosophical concept) in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89db10f"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Me Llamo Lenika</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith, Karina Yarwood</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Educating language minority children in Canada is becoming increasingly challenging as our population becomes more and more diverse. Determining the best educational policy to help immigrant children learn English or French, while furthering their knowledge of core subject material has long been a difficult task for educators in the public system. This novel is a fictional account of an immigrant girl's first year in an Ontario elementary school. Through her experience, I describe a language policy whereby children have access to bilingual primary education no matter what their first language is. Two-way immersion is offered for language minority groups with significant numbers of students within a district. And, in collaboration with the community, first language support in school is given to students of all language backgrounds. I propose a teacher training programme that better prepares teachers for the linguistic diversity in their classrooms and promotes foreign language learning in teachers themselves. Children under this system are able to acquire the dominant language of society, learn the subject material, and continue to develop literacy skills in their first language. With such policies in place, I argue, Canada could be a world leader in bilingual education for diverse populations.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h3223.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89db10f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Canada -- Foreign speakers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Languages, Modern -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d5701185"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Implementation of an elementary school-based action team for active and healthy living</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smeltzer, Krista</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to describe and evaluate the process of implementing an elementary school-based action team dedicated to increasing physical activity and healthy living opportunities for students. To facilitate this intervention, Epstein and colleagues' (2002) partnership framework, coupled with action research principles, was used to create partnerships between the school, home, and community. The results suggest that an action team based on Epstein and colleagues' guidelines may be suitable for creating opportunities for healthy and active living in an elementary school setting. In particular, families, students, teachers, and administration believed that the action team initiatives added to the school environment, school spirit, and value of the family as an essential component in the school. Likewise, the action team members felt that the health and wellness committee they represented was a valued component in the school culture that could be further developed and improved on in future years.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881q71x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d5701185</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical education and training</dc:subject><dc:subject>Home and school</dc:subject><dc:subject>Community and school</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abr86b706b"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gertrude Bell : an Orientalist in context</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schnell, Andréa Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is about the life and work of Gertrude Bell, a British woman born in the late nineteenth century, whose extensive knowledge of Middle East cultures and people won her a job as the Oriental Secretary in Iraq after World War One. Modern historians, including Toby Dodge and Edward Said, consider Bell to be an irredeemable orientalist, one whose work is only ethnocentric and essentialist. Using the work of Billie Melman and Mohja Kahf, my aim is to contextualize Bell's work, and to see if, given the various circumstances in which she worked, a more sympathetic reading is not possible, and if perhaps Said and Dodge are not sometimes guilty of essentialism. I will also examine Said's theories in Orientalism, and though this thesis is in no way an attempt to discredit Said's work, I wish to pose a question; if one can take a small piece of the Orientalist puzzle (Bell's work) and shows that it differs from Said's description, does this undermine the idea of orientalism as a cohesive body of ideas?</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr69m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b706b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Asianists</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bell, Gertrude Lowthian, 1868-1926</dc:subject><dc:subject>Orientalism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahq37vs191"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sak pase (what's going on)? : reading and spelling skills of bilingual Haitian children in French Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sauvé, Lisa-Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Linguists and psychologists alike have long overlooked the study of creole languages. We know very little about language and reading acquisition in young creole speakers. The aim of the present study was to examine the development of reading-related skills in native speakers of Haitian Creole (HC), a French-based creole, educated in French. In order to isolate the effects of speaking two highly similar languages, we compared Haitian children in 1st and 2nd grade to Spanish-French bilingual children and French monolingual children from European descent. Children from our sample were from five different schools in Montreal and had similar socioeconomic status. Participants were tested individually over three sessions on French standardized and experimental tasks assessing metalinguistic awareness, reading, comprehension, vocabulary and mathematical skills. Bilingual children were also tested on reading and spelling tasks in HC and Spanish. Results showed that HC and Spanish bilinguals performed as well as French native speakers on metalinguistic and reading tasks. However, Spanish-speaking children received lower scores than children in the two other groups on a receptive vocabulary measure. In an experimental task comparing the spelling of words of varying phonological similarity in HC and French, Haitian children had more difficulty spelling words that are cognates in HC and French than homophones or noncognate translations. Findings from this study were interpreted in light of the Bilingual Interactive Activation model (Dijsktra &amp; Van Heuven, 1998).</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sh288.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vs191</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Haitians -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bilingualism -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Creole dialects, French -- Haiti</dc:subject><dc:subject>Creole dialects, French -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9w032658h"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Québec Education Program in praxis : an investigation of the philosophical and practical elements of the curriculum reform in Québec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saltarelli, Nancy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The recently reformed Quebec Education Program has been implemented since the fall of 2000 and has drawn our attention to many questions regarding the philosophical and practical elements of education in Quebec. This thesis critically examines the implementation of this reform. It investigates the philosophical underpinnings of this new program, its approaches and implementation objectives. It provides an overview of the design of this new program and outlines some of the dominant themes emerging from its approach. It critiques the implementation of this reform by presenting some of the factors that make it difficult to effectively sustain change in school. Finally, it will conclude that we need an education that encompasses the authenticity of teaching and learning and which creates an atmosphere that will actively engage students in their learning.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nz280.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032658h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Educational change -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89db11q"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sacrifice in Genesis 22 : literal polemic or literary construct</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rosini, Amanda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this thesis is to examine the role of human sacrifice within the narrative of Genesis 22:1--19. For several decades, biblical scholarship has interpreted the role of human sacrifice within this particular narrative as an established and accepted practice, which was, only later abolished and replaced by the Law of Redemption (Ex 22:29--30). This thesis will study the archaeological data surrounding the practice of ritual human sacrifice in the expectation that it will provide added insight into the meaning of the ritual act within the narrative of Genesis 22. The study will also investigate the use of ritual offerings as a symbolic code and as a literary construct to transmit the interests and concerns of the author. These concerns were generated by specific political, social and religious realities brought about by the events surrounding the Babylonian and Persian invasions of the Syria-Palestine region.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j465d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89db11q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sacrifice in the Bible</dc:subject><dc:subject>Human sacrifice</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1z40kx47s"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Needling the spirit : an investigation of the perceptions and uses of the term Qi by acupuncturists in Québec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Reid, Erin M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The intent of this thesis is to explore the various ways in which acupuncturists trained in Quebec interpret and use the term qi in their practice as healers. It argues that these choices are influenced by the implicit connection between complementary and alternative medicine (CAM) and New Age spirituality. As Asian medical systems such as Chinese medicine carve out a niche within the dominant biomedical health-care system, there is a simultaneous desire to present its medical system as scientifically coherent within the biomedical context and a desire to cater to the New Age orientalist fascination with "traditional" Asian medicine and what is perceived as its inherent spiritual qualities. This study concludes that although Quebecois acupuncturists are well-versed in the historical interpretations of the term qi, as well as its medical applications, there is nevertheless a tendency for these practitioners to understand qi as a part of the framework of their own personal spirituality and the relation of that spirituality to their work as healers. Moreover, it is shown that this tendency is strongly informed by the interface of New Age notions concerning healing and the CAM movement. By situating the study within the cultural milieu of Quebec, the specific religio-historical background of this locale and its effects on these practitioners is also taken into consideration.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r9034.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kx47s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Alternative medicine -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>New Age movement -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acupuncture -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8336h532h"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>ita</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Italian</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dalla compassione alla masserizia : una 'conversione' del messaggio di Lotario in quello di Bono</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Papagni, Erika</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The De miseria humane conditionis (1191--1195) by Lotario di Segni (Pope Innocent III) was a greatly influential text in medieval culture, and was translated and reworked in many European languages. Early translations of the work, however, have been usually overlooked by scholars. This is true in particular of Della miseria dell'uomo, composed in the second half of the 13th century by the Florentine judge Bono Giamboni. My thesis consists in an extensive comparison of Bono's Della miseria dell'uomo with Lotario's De miseria humane conditionis. My purpose is twofold: to detect the differences between the two texts; and to understand how the two texts correspond to two completely different historical contexts. How the spirit of Lotario's text was transformed a century later into Bono's work? Bono's Della miseria reveals some crucial dimensions of the mentality and sensitivity of the communal age. It transforms Lotario's discouraging analysis of earthly life into a moral treaty conceived according to a more realistic and serene mentality. Bono feels compelled to console those who are burdened by the tribulations of life; to encourage sinners to humble themselves and repent; and to give hope to men of good will in order that they become better persons. He thus conveys a positive vision of life. It is not by chance that the last part of Bono's treaty deals with paradise.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zs088.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h532h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Innocent III, Pope, 1160 or 61-1216. De contemptu mundi</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dz95q"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Trying the Court : an assessment of the challenges facing the ICC in Uganda and Darfur</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nerland, Krista</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The ICC, which came into force in 2002, was held up by human rights activists as a force that would transform a culture of impunity into a culture of accountability. However, after five years of activity, the evidence suggests that the Court's effect has been mixed. Its ability to achieve retributive justice, broader reconciliation and restorative justice, as well as to deter future offences and promote peace has been variable, at best. Despite the Court's claim that politics are not its job, political missteps and support are adversely affecting the work of a judicious Court. Using the cases of Uganda and Darfur, this paper argues that the most significant factors impacting the Court's ability to achieve the four aims outlined are its lack of enforcement capacity, lack of international political will, the result of geo-political interests and concerns over the norm of state sovereignty, and lack of attention to political context by the Court itself.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j91d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dz95q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>International criminal courts -- Sudan</dc:subject><dc:subject>International criminal courts -- Political aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>International criminal courts -- Uganda</dc:subject><dc:subject>International Criminal Court</dc:subject><dc:subject>Criminal justice, Administration of -- International cooperation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1v53k177f"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The land wants me around : power, authority and their negations in traditional hunting knowledge at Wemindji (James Bay, Québec)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nasr, Wren</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigates the importance of traditional hunting knowledge to Cree identity and experience. My fieldwork was conducted in Wemindji, James Bay, Quebec, with Cree trappers and on the interactions of scientific researchers and Cree trappers. I explore the connections between these interactions and wider relationships of the Crees with histories of extractive development and the State. The misrecognition or negation of Cree authority in development discourse and outcomes has contributed to subsistence practices and traditional hunting knowledge becoming politically and emotionally charged signifiers. I argue that subsistence practices and traditional hunting knowledge have come to encode cultural difference and the assertion of authority in relation to struggles for recognition of Cree authority over their traditional territories.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72pc00j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k177f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cree Indians -- Québec (Province) -- Wemindji</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cree Indians -- Hunting</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cree Indians -- Québec (Province) -- Government relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asf268890x"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Porcupine's Quill and the Gaspereau Press : studies in the history, philosophy, and production values of two English-Canadian printer-publishers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Murphy, Tara Kathleen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the histories, publishing philosophies, and printing practices of two English-Canadian small-press publishers (The Porcupine's Quill of Erin, Ontario, and the Gaspereau Press of Kentville, Nova Scotia). By researching their publishing influences as well as the social and political climates in which each press operated, it is possible to analyze the decisions they made about why and how to publish certain kinds of texts. From there the thesis summarizes their publishing philosophies, and conducts extended analyses of the production of two specific literary texts: Endeared by Dark: The Collected Poems of George Johnston (PQL 1990), and Execution Poems (George Elliott Clarke, Gaspereau 2001). The historical research relies partly on secondary sources, and more generally the methodology was supplied by contemporary work in book history and textual criticism; however, the majority of the research, in chapters two and three particularly, has been culled from primary texts, press releases, newspaper features, web pages, and archival materials (letters, financial records, and so on). Overall, this thesis concludes that both the Porcupine's Quill and the Gaspereau Press emphasize an holistic approach to bookmaking, wherein each component part is capable of contextualizing, augmenting, celebrating, interpreting, historicizing, or socializing a literary text.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vv561.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268890x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gaspereau Press</dc:subject><dc:subject>Porcupine's Quill, Inc</dc:subject><dc:subject>Printers -- Canada -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Publishers and publishing -- Canada -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qq829"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A consort of gestural musical controllers : design, construction, and performance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Malloch, Joseph W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis project presents the T-Sticks, a new family of digital musical instruments (DMIs). Most DMIs are either entirely unique interfaces, or exist as design iterations in which each incarnation is intended to improve on the last. The T-Sticks are instead intended to form a complementary group or consort which may be performed ensemble and also performed individually in solo pieces or works for mixed instrumentation. Each of the T-Sticks is based on the same general structure and sensing platform, but each also differs from its siblings in size, weight, timbre and register. This document explores some of the issues challenging and motivating the field of DMI design and performance, and describes the motivations behind the T-Stick project in this context. Several existing DMIs are examined for similarities to the T-Stick and compared in terms of design intention, implementation, and usage. The hardware and software designed and built for this project is presented, along with insights gained through collaboration with performers and composers in the context of McGill University's Digital Orchestra project. The performers in question have collectively practiced and performed with the T-Stick for hundreds of hours in the lab, practice room, and on the concert stage. The consort of T-Sticks will be featured as an ensemble in a piece to be performed during the 2008 MusiMarch festival in Montreal.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fw30m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qq829</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electronic musical instruments -- Evaluation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Music and technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g865t"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The enjoyment factor : examining the relationship between enjoying and understanding science</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Malde, Millie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The investigation conducted for this thesis endeavoured to determine to what extent a relationship exists between pre-service elementary school teacher enjoyment of participating in science laboratory activities in a university-level background science course and their understanding of the science involved in those activities. A student enjoyment score for two science laboratory activities was generated from survey data. A student understanding score was generated from responses to relevant questions on the final exam of the course. A step-wise logistic regression was then conducted on the student enjoyment and understanding scores. Within the scope of the investigation described in this thesis, the findings lead to the conclusion that enjoyment appears to be unrelated to understanding.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945v539.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g865t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Science -- Study and teaching (Elementary) -- Activity programs</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>