<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax346d7350"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exchange reactions of sodium iodide with aromatic iodides</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kristjanson, Arnthor Marino</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An exchange reaction is a reaction in which an atom in a molecule interchanges with a chemically identical atom in some other state of chemical combination. The reaction may be represented by the equation AB + B*C = AB* + BC where B and B* represent atoms which are chemically identical but physically distinguishable. To follow the course of the reaction there must be some means of completely separating AB and BC after allowing them to mix and react for a given time. In addition, for quantitative calculations of the exchange, the physical property which distinguishes the atom must be a function of the concentration of the labelled atoms. The discovery of isotopes of the elements provided the necessary condition of chemically identical atoms which are physically distinguishable. If B represents the natural mixture of isotopes of an element and B* represents a mixture containing an excess of one particular isotope the difference in mass will serve to distinguish B and B*. If B* is a radioactive isotope of the element represented by B, this also will serve as a means of distinguishing B and B*. The use of stable isotopes generally requires more elaborate equipment and procedures for quantitative analyses than does the use of radioactive isotopes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mt10p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d7350</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72pb566"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Bacteriology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bacterial studies of egg shells in relation to the keeping quality of eggs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lachance, Robert Andre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The first consideration in the storage of eggs is the combatting of microbial spoilage. It is a well known fact that a high proportion of the eggs of the domestic hen (Gallus domesticus) are sterile internally in the bacterial sense at the time of laying, and for some time afterwards, though a microbial flora soon accumulates on the shell. However, there are instances in the literature of infection of the ovary by bacteria which can be transmitted to the egg. This is especially true with organisms of the Salmonella group responsible for bacillary white diarrhoea of the hen. This work was undertaken in order to obtain data which would provide a better understanding of the various factors which influence the microbial spoilage of eggs. The specific studies carried out have included (1) nutritional investigation to determine any possible relationship between the microbial penetration of the egg shell to the nutrition of the hen and to physical properties of the egg shell. (2) to test the feasibility of reducing bacterial penetration of the shell by impregnating the shell with (a) water repellants, (b) bactericidal agents and (c) by subjecting the egg to heat treatment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thatcher, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395wb72t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72pb566</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Bacteriology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301460t"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of racial preferences and self-consciousness as a member of a race</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lambek, Hanna Weiss</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper constitutes the writer’s first trial in experimental work in the field of Social Psychology. It stresses the present experimental study rather than a theoretical exposition of the problems and psychological implications of attitudes in general or feelings toward the Negro in particular.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Blackburn, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311s65n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301460t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>SOCIAL PSYCHOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ETHNOPSYCHOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEGROES IN CANADA</dc:subject><dc:subject>CANADA -- SOCIAL HISTORY AND LIFE</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8p58ph188"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of heat on the nutritive value of some vegetable oils</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Langerman, Helen Louise</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Linseed, corn, peanut, soybean and rape-seed oils, heated at 275 C were incorporated in the basal diets of rats at levels of 10, 20 or 36% by weight. Linseed oil was rendered toxic to young rats by treatment for 12 hours, but 30 hours heating was required to reduce the nutritive value of the other oils. Toxicity symptoms were non-specific but in severe cases included darkened adrenals, weight losses, diarrhea and death within 14 days. Acetone segregation partially concentrated the toxic factor in the soluble fraction of the oil, suggesting a specific polymer might be responsible. Of the various supplements tested, only rat feces and liver extract were effective in preventing toxicosis, therefore it was concluded that heated oils caused a deficiency of some essential nutrient. It is not clear how the toxic factor exerted its effect, but evidence suggests that bacterial synthesis might in some way be involved.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crampton, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vx22b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58ph188</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591c36c"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Threshold : a novel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leavitt, Helen Ruth Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><ual:supervisor>Files, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dq44w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c36c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x700t"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>ger</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of German</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Das Faust-Mephisto Verhältnis im Urfaust, Fragment und Faust I.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leppmann, Wolfgang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Schon im Eingangsmonolog tritt uns Eaust als Übermensch entgegen, als Einzelgänger in dem ein dämonischer Erkenntnisdrang soeben die intellektuellen (I) und moralischen (2) Schranken durchbrochen hat, die den Durchschnittsmenschen als ungeteiltes ‘Individuum’ umfassen und ihn - wenigstens auf dem moralischen Boden dem die Faustsage entsprang - zu seinem eigenen Heil begrenzen. Am Anfang der Dichtung bricht Faust auseinander; er hat sich der Magie ergeben und wünscht sich von ihr Befriedigung seiner beiden Übermacht igen Triebe: der Forderung nach unbedingter, restloser Erkenntnis dessen, “was die Welt im Innersten zusammenhält”, und der Sehnsucht nach einem völligen Aufgehen in der Natur (3).[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Graff, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vf64x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x700t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832. Faust</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q7502"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ezra Pound and the sense of the past</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Levine, Norman, 1923-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>[...] The study of Ezra Pound is a complex study. He,treats many themes in a highly individualistic manner but one thread does permeate through all of his poetry — the sense of the past. It is not a limited past restricted to one culture. Pound jumps from Provencal, Chinese, Roman, Italian to the London of the 1890fs with ease. In order to understand the necessity of this retreat, and the development of his writing within so loose a framework, it is necessary for the reader to examine, in chronological order, Ezra Pound as a personality together with Ezra Pound as a poet.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anderson, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j859v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q7502</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5138jh706"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of social and emotional factors in treatment of tuberculosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Levy, Deborah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tuberculosis is an old and well-known disease that may affect different organs of the human body. The specific etiologic agent is a microscopic bacterium, called the tubercle bacillus which was originally described by Koch in 1870. Since then, many steps have been taken towards improving the treatment of this disease, but as its microbe is so easily spread by coughing or sneezing and in many other ways, it still constitutes a very great problem in public health. We are aiming towards the goal where the preventive measures will reduce the task considerably. But as in the case of many other diseases, this will take time. When preventive programmes take the leading role, we may still be faced with problems, although much smaller in number and scope.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Younge, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kx058.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jh706</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440w97p"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The electrolytic oxidation of glycol, glucose and lignosulphonic acids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Logan, Kenneth Calvin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There are tremendous quantities of waste from the wood pulping industry. In Canada alone 2,027,532 tons (1) of sulphite pulp were produced in 1947 from which there was approximately 2,500,000 tons of unused solids in the sulphite waste liquor. Although a number of means of utilizing this material have been suggested, the only promising outlet for large quantities at present is as fuel and the economics of even this procedure are not yet proven for conditions as they exist on this continent. Most of the liquor is at present discharged into streams. The absence of a practical use for the great bulk of these spent liquors, and the absence of a recovery cycle for the chemicals therein, have been major reasons why the sulphite pulp industry has lost its position relative to competitive processes. Similarly, this handicap has prevented the development of the neutral sulphite pulping process which otherwise has many virtues. Apart from the absolute waste of half the wood used, there is the additional disadvantage that the sugars and other carbohydrates in the waste liquor, with their high biological oxygen demand, constitute a serious pollution of waterways with an attendant adverse effect upon fish life, upon further industrial development and upon the beauty of the country.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Purves, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gp22v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440w97p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859j77g"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The oxidation of hydroxybenzaldehydes with chlorine dioxide and sodium chlorite</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Logan, Charles Donald</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>[...]Realizing the great deficiency of knowledge in this field, the Wood Chemistry Committee of the Technical Section, Canadian Pulp and Paper Association, recommended a thorough investigation of the effects of halogen-containing oxidants on wood and its constituents. This research was very capably initiated by Dr. R.M. Husband, who undertook a carefully controlled study of the actions of sodium chlorite and chlorine dioxide on such model substances of lignin as pyrogallol, vanillin and syringealdehyde. It was hoped that these model studies would provide valuable information which would be helpful in the later studies of the oxidation of the more complex lignin molecule. However innumerable difficulties were encountered as a result of the complex behaviour of the oxidants and the labile nature of the quinoidal organic products. The object of this Thesis was to extend the earlier work: carried out by Dr. Husband. In order to avoid the sensitive products formed by the oxidation of phenols activated by a free hydroxyl group, ethers such as acetylvanillin and veratraldehyde were also oxidized. With such less active ethers, it was possible to make a sharper distinction between the action of chlorite and of chlorine dioxide under various conditions. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Purves, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676z937.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859j77g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60d078v"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The value of the digestibility trial as an adjunct to growth trial data in indicating the efficiency of hog rations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lucas, Ian Albert M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Digestibility experiments were conducted with swine using the rations fed during two growth trials. The calculated gross energies of the feeds were lower than the determined values and the digestible energy of a ground, balanced hog ration could be determined from a formula based upon its crude fibre content. The metabolizable energy was not found to be a more suitable evaluation of the diets than the digestible energy. Thus the latter figures were used when the effects of caloric intake upon carcass quality were studied. In that section the percentages of the variations in the carcass measurements attributable to the lengths of the fattening periods together with the total intakes of digestible therms during those periods, were determined. It was suggested that bacon quality might be controlled in practice by regulating the growth rates, and the applicability of a formula which estimates feed requirements for growth was discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ashton, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712mb05k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d078v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692t960x"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Economic and monetary aspects of national debt retirement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacIntosh, Robert Mallory</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study concerns itself with an aspect of public finance which is as old as the existence of national governments. But the approach differs somewhat from the treatment found elsewhere, inasmuch as it is not concerned with the desirability of debt retirement per se, but with the monetary effects which such retirement will tend to produce. The conclusions drawn from the analysis will, however, inevitably suggest certain attitudes towards the question of debt management policy. This thesis grew out of a vague sense of dissatisfaction on the part of the writer and his colleagues in the Graduate School with the monetary theory of debt retirement as it is found subsumed in the body of Keynesian doctrine relating to countercyclical fiscal policy. It is frequently suggested that debt retirement during inflationary periods will serve as a potent weapon in the reduction of purchasing power. Proper debt management is thought to serve the twin objectives of raising spending capacity in depressed periods and limiting it in more prosperous times, while at the same time the total national debt may be stabilized over the long run. It will be the object of this study to bring into question this view on the efficacy of deflationary monetary operations through debt redemption. It is not denied that government hoarding of tax revenues, or some such scheme could achieve deflationary results [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>James, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676z94h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t960x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Finance -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Finance -- England</dc:subject><dc:subject>Finance -- United States</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A44558h381"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A microbiological study of the amino acid composition of the horsebean (vicia faba L.)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mahon, John Harold</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Canadian crops capable of yielding a suitable supply of vegetable protein for use in chick rations are relatively few in number. Investigations were, therefore, undertaken by the Poultry Department of this College to explore the comparative feeding value of some lesser used, but climatically adapted sources of vegetable protein. Since the horsebean thrives in certain regions of Eastern Canada it was selected for study with a view to the possible extension of its use as a source of vegetable protein in poultry and other rations. The horsebean is a member of the Leguminoseae and has been cultivated for hundreds of years in the Mediterranean region (Winton)(l). Belzile (2) believes that the horsebean was introduced into Canada from France by the early settlers. The horsebean requires a cool, humid climate. For this reason it is grown as a Winter crop in Europe and the United States. The plant does not thrive under conditions of intense Summer heat which often prevails in the Montreal area. It grows satisfactorilly, however, in the lower St. Lawrence area and the Lake St. John district of Quebec Province. Under conditions of sufficient moisture the horsebean produces very heavy yields of seed. A well drained loam or clay loam appears to be most suitable for growth of this plant.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Common, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246w19t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558h381</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ang451m88r"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The psychological components of morale in an industrial situation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mahoney, Gerald Maurice</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The problem of morale has been receiving increasing attention from social scientists since World War I. Gradually, over the intervening period between wars, it has become an important aspect of the broader problem of discovering the principles of managing and organizing human activity. The literature on human relations in industry contains many references to morale and many large scale research projects in this field include attempts to estimate the morale levels of individuals and groups. During the recent war, of course, interest in this problem was heightened. Apart from a concern about morale in the more restricted social groupings of industry and the military services, general civilian morale commanded widespread attention. In spite of the quite general use of the term, the recognition of a problem of morale and numerous attempts to study it, there remains a singular lack of agreement as to what morale is and within which discipline or disciplines its investigation belongs. Accordingly, the research reported in this paper was designed to attack certain problems which, stated in general terms, are as follows: (a) To define morale within the limits of a psychological approach, (b) To develop a systematic, psychological theory of morale, (c) To devise an instrument or instruments for more accurate and meaningful measurement within this area.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webster, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d977m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451m88r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>SOCIAL PSYCHOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PSYCHOLOGY, EXPERIMENTAL</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515r65s"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A derivation of cross section formulae for resonance scattering and reactions in nuclear processes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Margolis, B. (Bernard)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the literature of the topic investigated below are two types of derivations, those using the spatial part of the wave function of the system, incident particle and target nucleus, and those using the time dependence mainly. The latter type of derivation has been open to question because of the attack, based on the time dependent perturbation theory of Dirac. It is the intention here, among other things, to separate the use of the time dependence of the wave function from this conventional perturbation theory. A successful derivation of cross section formulae follows from a modified version. The method used was decided upon after a careful study of the 1946 paper by Flugge.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wallace, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848t765.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515r65s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67jv39n"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The design of multi-conductor unbalanced transmission lines for broadcast frequencies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marshall, James L., 1913-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present day necessity of installing multi-tower antenna arrays for many transmitters in the broadcast band (540 kc. to 1600 kc.) in order to prescribe the pattern of their radiated fields, brings with it the need for longer transmission lines. The transmission efficiency of a line should, of course, be a maximum compatible with economical installation and good engineering practice, since this portion of the system carries the most expensive energy of a transmitter plant. Furthermore, in Canada and the U.S. at least, government regulations limit the amount of power that can be lost in the external circuits i.e. power-dividing network, transmission line, and antenna-matching networks. Therefore, where two or more antennas are used requiring an equal number of antenna-matching circuits and a considerable length of transmission line, the losses in both of these components must be kept small in order to satisfy the regulations. These conditions draw attention to the relative merits of the two common types of line, the concentric tube and the open-wire. The characteristics, performance, and cost of concentric lines are well known, since they have been used for many years, and their various sizes have been standardized. In recent years, however, multi-conductor open-wire lines have been gaining favour. There are two factors which make it possible to approach the transmission efficiency of a concentric line, with an open-wire type.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Howes, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q66d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jv39n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236550f"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Uses made of a mental hygiene clinic by a boys’ training school : how the Boys’ Farm and Training School at Shawbridge, Quebec makes referrals to and uses the treatment recommendations of the Mental Hygiene Institute on Pine Avenue, Montreal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mayotte, A. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Boys’ Farm and Training School, Shawbridge, Quebec, is operated for the re-education of boys who have delinquent and other behaviour problems. Most of the boys at the Training School are committed by the Juvenile Court in Montreal and by other law-enforcing agencies [...]. During the years of World War II, the Juvenile Court had many boys examined at the Mental Hygiene Institute on Pine Avenue in Montreal, before committing them to the Boys’ Farm and Training School. The School found it helpful to return some of these boys [...] for further psychiatric help. When wartime shortages of staff eased off, the School began to make increasing use of the Institute’s services. This latter development was noticeable during the Winter of 1947-1948 [...]. The writer was interested in social case work with boys. He was also interested in the Training School [...] he was asked by the Institute to carry some cases co-operatively with the School. While the writer was working on these cases, it was discovered that both agencies encountered several problems in connection with referrals from the School to the Institute. These referral problems have been selected as basic topics for investigation in this present study. Both agencies agreed to co-operate so as to make such an exploratory study possible. The aim of this study, therefore, is to discover how these two agencies can work together more effectively than they have done in furthering the treatment of boys at the School.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Younge, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xg053.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236550f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859j78r"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of infants with congenital abnormalities : Hospital, home and placement problems of parents whose infants are born with congenital abnormalities, the emphasis being on the emotional problems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mayotte, Eileen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study was first undertaken with the purpose of finding, in the Province of Quebec, the public and private institutions that accepted responsibility for the care of the congenitally abnormal child. The writer soon became aware of the limited resources in this province. During the course of this exploration this problem seemed to be overshadowed by other greater problems. Where were these children going upon hospital discharge? Who was giving them the care needed? Did the parents care for the child in the home? How did this placement in the home affect the parents and siblings? Parents, particularly, are affected by the birth of such a child, as the following quotation indicates. “How parents feel about their children is an emotional affair. What happens to them emotionally when their child is born with or acquires a physical impairment cannot be controlled either by intellect or good manners.” These questions and the concern with the parents’ emotional problems became the main interest in the study. The change in emphasis does not mean that the original problem of the need for placement facilities has been abandoned. Rather the focus of the study has been shifted to the emotional problems of the parents of these infants. How did the parents react to the birth of such a child? How was the child cared for? Therefore, we find that the locating of suitable placement facilities, while still important, is not the central issue of this study.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Younge, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059cb603.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859j78r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajd4730628"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of addition agents in electrodeposition of copper</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McConnell, Wallace Beverly</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The presence of an addition agent during the electrodeposition of a metal introduces further complications into a system in which the processes that occur are but poorly understood at the present time. The relations between the variables, even in a simple electrodeposition of a metal from a solution of one of its salts, have for the most part not proven amenable to any general mathematical formulation and individual investigations have usually been restricted to the study of one or two variables over a comparatively narrow range of experimental conditions. Explanation of results has frequently involved the formation of a new hypothesis, electrochemistry is one of the youngest branches of physical science as shown by the fact that its literature has increased tremendously in the last forty years and it is perhaps not surprising that published papers in this field are restricted in scope and frequently contain hypotheses which appear to be conflicting. The task of unifying this mass of electrochemical data and theory into an acceptable whole appears impossible as yet, since many aspects of the field have yet to be investigated while many others are in a confused state because of the conflict of both experimental data and theory.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sn54w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd4730628</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0p096b31q"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Radioactive minerals at Otter Rapids, Ontario</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McDougall, David J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Otter Rapids are located on the Abitibi River in the west-central portion of Pitt Township, District of Cochrane, Province of Ontario, at about Latitude 51°10’ North and Longitude 81°30’ West. They are approximately 79 miles west of north from the town of Cochrane and 87 miles southwest of Moosonee, which lies 12 miles south of James Bay. These towns serve respectively as the south and north terminals of the northern branch of the Ontario Northland Railway. The railway permits easy access to the area, since it closely parallels the west bank of the river for several miles to the north and south of Otter Rapids. Normally, there are two northbound and two southbound trains per week with the nearest regular stop at Coral Rapids Station at Mileage 96.3. Otter Rapids are most easily reached from the railway by detraining at Mileage 91.7 and going east to the head of the rapids, a distance of about 1500 feet along a good trail. The area examined in the field consists of 97 claims lying to the east, south and west of the lower end of Otter Rapids. These make up an irregular block about 4.7 miles in a north-south direction and 3.2 miles east-west. [...] In addition to the examination of the claims, several exploratory traverses were made to the north, south and west. In considering the regional features, a much larger area has been referred to, based mainly on previous reports on the area, or on information obtained from maps and aerial photographs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jolliffe, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xm81x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096b31q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahh63t012h"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bacteriology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies in the nutrition of Corynebacterium sepidonicum</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacLachlan, Donald Stuart</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A study of the nutrition of Corynebacteiium sepedonicum was carried out using both plate culture methods and the Warburg Respiration Apparatus. Fresh potato extract was found to contain a factor or factors essential for the growth of C. sepedonicum. A temperature of 23° C. and a pH of 7.0 were found to be optimum for growth. A relatively high oxidation - reduction potential (Eh) stimulated the growth of the organism. Pantothenic acid, inositol, thiamine and para-ami nobenzoic acid, added respectively in concentrations of 600, 3000, 200 and 3000 u grams per litre of medium, caused a significant increase in the growth of C. sepedonicum. The amino acids, glutamic acid, asparagine, leucine and lysine, added respectively in concentrations of 0.001, 1.0, 0.03 and 0.03 grams per litre of medium, caused a marked stimulation of growth either individually or in combination. A new medium was prepared for the isolation and maintenance of C. sepedonicum.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thatcher, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr172137j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63t012h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bacteriology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amc87pt81s"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The metabolism of acetylcholine in brain tissue preparations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McLennan, Hugh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The function of the central nervous system in the body is to control its response to physiological needs, and for the most part these needs are communicated to the central nervous system by messages sent through the afferent nerves. It responds by sending out impulses, which travel through the efferent nerves to the effector organs, it has been known since the days of Galvani that the stimulation of a nerve, whether by natural or artificial means, produces an excitation in the effector organ, and that this excitation is propagated in the nerve, and is accompanied by an electrical wave. It was generally believed that the electrical wave travelled to the effector, and there elicited the specific response. The action of a nerve may be subdivided into three distinct phases: a stimulus reaching a neuron must initiate an impulse; the impulse, once initiated, must be propagated along the axon; and finally, it must be transmitted either to a second neuron or to an effector cell. The supposition that electrical phenomena can account for this chain of events has been widely held, but there are certain parts of this purely electrical theory as originally stated which are very difficult of proof, and some modifications appeared necessary.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elliott, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tv733.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pt81s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n2042363"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intraparty democracy in the Co-operative Commonwealth Federation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Metcalf, John Franklin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Among the consequences of modern democratic government has been the emergence of political parties as agencies through which economic and social tensions are aired, and ultimately settled insofar as settlement is possible. Behind the institutions formalized in law and tradition, issues of state tend to be decided within the ranks of the political party which can, at any given moment, command the confidence of a majority of the electorate. This is especially true of the nations of the Commonwealth, and such other states in which the institutions of parliamentary government, and possibly national characteristics of the citizenry, make for a two or three-party system and normally for an outward show of unanimity on the part of members on whatever policies the organization may from time to time attempt to translate into public law. Investigation of how the policies of political parties are made, and by whom, is necessary for a proper understanding of the workings of contemporary democracy.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mallory, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w298d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n2042363</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Socialism -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Co-operative Commonwealth Federation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rm508"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of fostering on the growth pattern of the house mouse</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Metrakos, Julius Demetrius</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The development of an organism may be considered as the most outstanding of all its physiological properties. It is generally understood however, that this property of living natter embodies the corelative properties of growth and differentiation (Wetzel, 1944). In the strictest usage, growth is that fundamental property of living matter responsible only for increases or decreases in the size or the number of the organisms concerned. Thus it is possible to speak of both positive and negative growth. Differentiation, on the other hand, results in specific structural changes of the parts of the organism. In this thesis whenever the term “growth” is used, the dual sense of the word will be implied, and will be a substitute for the words “positive growth and differentiation”.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fraser, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jf345.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rm508</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mice -- Growth</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50tv74c"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Diencephalic function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Meyer, John S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Detailed study of highest level epileptic seizures (petit mal epilepsy) by Dr. Penfield and his co-workers has yielded considerable evidence of a localizing nature in this disorder. The characteristic feature of a highest level seizure is initial loss of consciousness. There may be little or no bodily manifestation of change. If there is any outward evidence, it may only be a staring expression of the eyes, or the eyes may turn upward, or blinking of the eyes may occur rhythmically. Movement of the extremities may be momentarily retarded or arrested, jerking movements of the arms may occur, or the patient may fall to the ground due to a sudden loss of postural control. The patient does not have any memory of the attack. Such clinical evidence indicates a primary loss of consciousness with somatic symptoms which are not characteristic of cortical excitation but which are more readily associated with a subcortical discharge. Changes of consciousness are also seen following lesions of the mesial wall of the diencephalon without clinical evidence of paralysis of corticospinal or other cortical mechanisms. Such patients may be unconscious for long periods, although ail extremities move in readjustments of posture or when they receive nociceptive stimulation (Penfield and Jasper, 1947).[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Penfield, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pd87c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tv74c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neurology &amp; Neurosurgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>