<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418r363"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dimorphism and pathogenicity of Mucor alternans (Van Tieghem)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leyritz, Michele</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A filamentous fungus, Mucor alternans (Van Tieghem), was found to grow in the yeast-like form in yeast extract-peptone-glucose broth (pH 4.5 and 6.8, at 25 and 37°) under carbon dioxide, and in tissue culture medium 199 (pH 7.2, 37°) under 5% carbon dioxide, 95% nitrogen gas mixture. The amount of growth was proportional to the glucose concentration. The pathogenicity of the yeast-like cells was studied in diabetic mice (strain C57 BL/KsJ-db/db) injected intraperitoneally with pre-incubated sporangiospores. A non-fatal disease developed from which the mice recovered. Cultures of M. alternans were obtained from visceral organs, lungs, brain and nodules of 37.7% of the diabetic mice. Normal controls were negative in culture. Upon microscopic examination of livers and nodules, hyphae, arthrospores and budding cells were found. It is postulated that single cells, e.g., broken off arthrospores disseminate the disease to distant foci where germination occurs accounting for the presence of hyphae observed in o histopathological sections.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kapica, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rx722.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r363</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Microbiology and Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>