<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aht24wk458"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ibn Miskawayh's concept of the intellect (ʻAql)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marcotte, Roxanne D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Miskawayh's theory of intellect is the subject of this thesis; in addition, the historical and conceptual sources--Greek and Islamic--that were to shape Miskawayh's noetic are examined. The first part of this thesis examines the Greek tradition and its first most complete work dealing with the intellect, Aristotle's De Anima. Then, Alexander of Aphrodisias' noetic, as it is found in his Risalah fi/ 'Aql, Plotinus' conception of Intelligence, as it occurs in his Theologia Aristotelis and Proclus' conception of Intelligence, as it occurs in his Liber de Causis and finally, Themistius' noetic which is elaborated in his commentary of Aristotle's De Anima will be examined and evaluated in relation to Miskawayh's noetic. The second part of this thesis examines the Islamic tradition. The noetics of al-Kindiand of al-Farabi elaborated in their respective Risalah fi al-'Aql, are examined. In spite of Miskawayh's apparent shunning of his Islamic tradition, he is greatly influenced by it. The last part of this thesis examines Miskawayh's noetic as it can be reconstructed from his works: the Risalah fi al-Nafs wa al-'Aql, the al-Fawz al-Asghar and the Tahdhib al-Akhlaq. However, the use of the Risalah fial- 'Aql wa al-Ma'qul, a text attributed to Miskawayh, for the reconstruction of Miskawayh's noetic is more problematic. At he end of this study, it will appear that Miskawayh's noetic is indebted to both Greek and Islamic traditions. In spite of Miskawayh's explicit emphasis on Aristotelian aspects, he implicitly adheres to cosmological and anthropological speculations belonging to his Islamic tradition, which in turn, are greatly influenced by Neoplatonism. Thus Miskawayh, in an attempt to revive and utilize the Greek heritage, operated a rearticulation of the noeticsphere.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ormsby, Eric</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cr58k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wk458</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ibn Miskawayh, Aḥmad ibn Muḥammad, d. 1030 -- Views on intellect</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag732db13r"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of two point mutations in the androgen receptor gene of patients with complete androgen resistance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bordet, Sylvie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two previously identified sequence alterations in the androgen receptor gene of patients with complete androgen resistance are studied to prove their pathogenicity. Family studies confirm that the mutation segregates with the phenotype and that the mothers are heterozygous carriers. In one family a sibling of the patient is identified as a heterozygous carrier. Mutant cDNAs encoding the mutant receptors are constructed and expressed in COS-1 cells. The resulting mutant receptors show a decreased apparent equilibrium constant for androgens, faster dissociation rates and impaired transactivation. Further studies reveal that both mutant receptors were either inactivated or destroyed in the presence of hormone, while the normal receptor is stabilized and up-regulated by incubation with ligand. These results prove that the sequence alterations thus identified are pathogenic and illustrate a dual mechanism of pathogenicity: an affinity defect combined with a loss of binding activity in the presence of hormone, resulting in receptors incapable of supporting normal male sexual development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pinsky, Leonard</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w360f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732db13r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sex differentiation disorders</dc:subject><dc:subject>X chromosome -- Abnormalities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Androgens -- Receptors</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azp38wd99c"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Matthew Arnold's five long poems : a dialectical reading</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Keshavjee, Nashira</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Matthew Arnold's five long poems were published between 1852 and 1867. In these poems (Empedocles on Etna, Tristram and Iseult, Sohrab and Rustum, Balder Dead and Merope) Arnold tries to analyze a number of themes, like nature, moral values, poetics, and the place of authority in society. His analysis is dialectical, and one notices great distress and an inability to resolve these issues. This thesis examines Arnold's confusion, as well as his eventual calm acceptance of life in all its contradictions. It concludes subsequently that Arnold has a genuine desire to find personal dialectical syntheses where possible.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McSweeney, K.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r429s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wd99c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Arnold, Matthew, 1822-1888 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd375x54r"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of dietary protein source on plasma parameters related to stress and behaviour in pigs varying in their susceptibility to stress</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roberts, Susan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study was performed to determine if pigs varying in their susceptibility to stress, adapted to a casein-based diet, experience an improvement in biochemical parameters related to stress and behaviour compared to pigs adapted to the traditional western canadian cereal-based swine diet. Experiment 1 involved separating fifty-eight, 8-week old pigs according to genotype with respect to the halothane gene. Within each genotype pigs were divided into 2 groups and assigned to either a control diet or to a diet where most of the protein source was substituted for casein. All animals were adapted to diet for 6 weeks and experienced a weekly blood sampling stressor. Day 1, 14 and 35 of the plasma samples were analyzed for glucose, cortisol, ACTH, insulin, pyridoxal 5$ sp prime$-phosphate (PLP), amino acid concentrations and dopamine-$ beta$-hydroxylase (DBH) activity; metabolic indices known to be responsive to stress. Experiment 2 involved separating fifty-seven, 14-week old pigs in the same manner, then adapting the pigs to their respective diets for a period of 4 weeks. Afterwards, pigs were transferred from their pen to a novel pen-maze situation where they had their behaviour monitored for a period of one hour. Results of these experiments have revealed that (1) the stress susceptible and carrier pigs experienced reduced day 35 plasma glucose, PLP concentrations and DBH activity compared to normal pigs; (2) dietary adaptation to the casein diet resulted in greater day 14 and 35 PLP levels and day 35 essential amino acid lysine, threonine, methionine, tryptophan and arginine concentrations compared to control-adapted pigs; (3) the carrier pigs investigated their surroundings more frequently than the stress susceptible pigs, and the normal pigs engaged in the through-maze behaviour more often than the stress susceptible pigs; and (4) adaptation to the casein diet, compared to the control diet, resulted in fewer displacement-type behaviours such as drinking</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thibault, Louise</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322f437.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375x54r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Proteins in animal nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Malignant hyperthermia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Swine -- Effect of stress on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stress (Physiology) -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77sr31x"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Association of endogenous viral genes and myb-gene polymorphisms with disease resistance in white leghorns</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Urbani, Nicola</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The incidences of endogenous viral genes (ev-genes) and myb-gene polymorphisms were determined in substrains of strains R, M and G which had been divergently selected or susceptibility to tumour formation induced by Rous Sarcoma virus (RSV) of type A and B. Frequencies of myb gene polymorphisms were also determined in two replicates of strains selected for high and low multiple immune response to challenge with Pasteurella multocida and Mycoplasma gallisepticum. Strains R, M and G were found to contain different sets of ev-genes reflecting their distinct genetic origins. Among eleven ev-genes identified, two showed a significantly increased frequency in the susceptible substrains. One was ev-6, which expresses the viral envelope protein of the endogenous avian leucosis, while the other was a new endogenous viral gene New-E, whose phenotype is unknown. A significant increased incidence of ev-4, reported to be a silent ev-gene, was observed in resistant rather than susceptible substrain. Myb gene polymorphisms were assessed using a cDNA probe and a genomic probe yielding 2 and 3 restriction fragment length polymorphisms (RFLPs) respectively. In strains M and G, only one polymorphism (PM5$ sp+$) observed at an Msp I site located downstream of the last of the c-myb exons was found to be significantly co-selected for susceptibility. Analysis of RFLPs of myb-gene in strains selected for high or low multiple immune response did not reveal any significant response to selection. Rather, polymorphisms seemed to reflect a founder effect as revealed by opposite frequencies obtained in the two replicates. DNA methylation, a possible epigenetic mechanism regulating gene expression, was also investigated in the myb-gene. DNA from semen, blood, spleen, liver and thymus was extracted from organs obtained from chickens at different ages.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kijhnlein, Urs</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r229n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sr31x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Leghorn chicken -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Natural immunity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw6634501b"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genome relationships among Lotus species based on random amplified polymorphic DNA (RAPD)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Campos, Lázara Pereira</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The usefulness of RAPDs (Random Amplified Polymorphic DNA) to distinguish among different taxa of Lotus was evaluated. The following species were included: L. corniculatus, L. tenuis, L. alpinus, L. japonicus, and L. uliginosus. Several accessions for each species were studied. Following DNA extraction, amplification reactions were performed in a Hybaid DNA Thermal Cycler, and the product visualized according to a standard procedure. Twenty primers were used for each species/accession. Clear bands and several polymorphisms were obtained for all primers. A phenogram was drawn based on the genetic distance among the species. L. alpinus appears as the most distant species from L. corniculatus, followed by L. uliginosus, L. tenuis, and L. japonicus. With the exception of L. alpinus, these findings are in agreement with previous experimental studies in the L. corniculatus group. The use of a greater number of primers and increased number of species may provide a greater resolution of the systematics of these taxa.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grant, William F.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm83t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634501b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lotus -- Classification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plants -- Classification -- Molecular aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lotus corniculatus</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3j3333444"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Trucking air cargo : the application of the Warsaw system to bimodal transport</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Croes, Philip</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The recent expansion of air trucking operations in Europe has put a strain on the traditional concept of air carrier's liability. Short-haul pick-up and delivery services have gradually given way to a more complex pattern of hubbing and substitute transport by road, possibly undertaken without consent of the consignor of the goods. In the absence of a set of international rules for multimodal transport, each segment is subject to a separate legal regime. An evolutive interpretation of the original Warsaw Convention, though, fits the newly developed bimodal operations prima facie into the sphere of air carrier's liability. Problems of delay are dealt with using an elaborate model on the concept of time in the several branches of transport law. The spectrum is completed by a discussion on the plurality of the parties involved in the entire process.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505176f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3333444</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3f4626722"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modeling, simulation and control of rotary blasthole drills</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aboujaoude, Claude E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Few rotary blasthole drills presently used in open pit mines are equipped with automatic control systems. Those drilling control systems which do exist are based mainly on ladder programming techniques. This thesis is an investigation into a closed loop feedback control approach for drilling control. A model for the plant consisting of the machine's actuators and the drilling process at the bit-rock interface is described based on physical assumptions and past research in this area. The model equations are further refined by experimental (field) testing. The instrumentation of a TAMROCK-DRILTECH D75K drill rig and the subsequent drilling tests aimed at refining the model equations are described, with an in-depth discussion of the field tests results. The analysis is based on regression techniques applied to empirical data, showing the dependencies between the cutting variables and ground conditions during actual drilling. The transfer functions of the mechanical actuators of the machine are also identified. A strategy for automatic feed pressure control is proposed and developed as a software source code. The controller is tested and tuned by interfacing it to a software simulator of the plant which implements the relationships identified from field testing. The simulation results are discussed. They show that the proposed strategy is viable: however, it is subject to some limitations. The thesis concludes with suggestions for future research and improvement of the proposed control approach.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw02p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f4626722</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hq94k"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study on the relaxation phenomena and pattern formation of nematic polymers after cessation of shear flow</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chan, Philip Kwok-Kiou</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The first part of this thesis studies numerically the effects that the surface conditions, defects and backflow have on the relaxation phenomena after cessation of simple shear flow for a typical rigid rod nematic polymer. The Leslie-Ericksen continuum theory and the Euler-Lagrange equations for surface motion are derived and used for this purpose. Predictions are found to be physically consistent. Nematic polymers, under certain conditions, develop a transient banded texture after cessation of shear flow when observing the sheared sample between crossed polars. The second part of this thesis presents a viscoelastic model that describes the formation mechanism of this well characterized but yet unexplained phenomenon for a typical rigid rod nematic polymer. This model is composed of the Ericksen and Landau-de Gennes continuum theories, and predicts that the relaxation of periodic spatial variations of the scalar order parameter produces spatially periodic torques on the director. Consequently, a transient banded texture is seen when viewing the sample between crossed polars. The numerical results and digitized optical patterns are in good agreement with reported experimental observations, and are used to explain these observations.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tw39q.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hq94k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dw720"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Deterministic and risk-based design of rotating biological contactors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Buchanan, Ian, 1953-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A method of minimizing the total active disc area, required for the removal of soluble biochemical oxygen demand (SBOD), by a multi-stage rotating biological contactor (RBC) operating steady-state is proposed. Both deterministic and stochastic inputs are considered. Total active disc area and the number of RBC stages are optimized for the deterministic case, and are then incorporated into a risk-based method of assigning per-stage active disc areas. The risk of the final stage SBOD exceeding a fixed effluent standard is evaluated by taking into account the variable nature of the influent flowrate and SBOD concentration. Bivariate normal, lognormal and shifted lognormal distributions are considered as models for the input random variables. The effluent SBOD probability density function is obtained according to the method of transformation of random variables. Illustrative examples are presented.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602205x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dw720</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290b70w"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The heat pipe injection lance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Botos, Peter A. (Peter Alex)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The work performed can be divided into three stages. The first stage involved the development and study of a transparent heat pipe which served to illustrate the principles of heat pipes, specifically, thermosyphons or wickless heat pipes. The second stage dealt with the conception, construction and study of a laboratory scale heat pipe injection lance. The knowledge gained in the laboratory was used to build two pilot scale heat pipe injection lances, Mark I and Mark II, in the third stage of this work. These lances were tested in the copper converting furnace at the Kidd Creek smelter. Through the development of pilot scale heat pipe injection lances, it is shown that a self-cooled heat pipe lance has a furnace life orders of magnitude greater than a conventional stainless steel lance, with its exact location relative to the molten copper bath surface known.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c172j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290b70w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, General</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag732db141"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'identité perdue : Georges Perec et l'autobiographie</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Molkou, Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Autobiography. Present in Georges Perec's writings but only in a profoundly revisionary way. In order to get a genuine understanding of his works, we must begin by recognizing the centrality of the Jewish genocide, the Shoah, in the writer's existence as well as in his activity. Unprovided with a story of his own, the writer surely felt the imbalance between what the autobiographical tradition offered him and his need to fashion the ephemeral recollections of his past. Hence, he had to destabilize the very idea of autobiographical narrative by writing out his story in a singular and distinct manner. While reversing the traditional pattern of autobiography, Georges Perec tries to find the most appropriate literary form to record the enormity of the human loss caused by the event. Despite the fact that he is neither a victim nor a survivor, the writer has succeeded in replying to the Holocaust threat to impose silence, by writing a text that occupies a legitimate place in this literature.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q757g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732db141</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Autobiography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Perec, Georges, 1936-1982</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sb42c"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Meteorology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A diagnostic study of the early phases of sixteen North-Pacific cyclones</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kelly, Robert W. P. (Robert William Patterson)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines the large-scale fields of eight stronger and eight weaker cyclones prior to rapid cyclogenesis to help explain their subsequent deepening rate. The cyclones all commenced their rapid development within the same small geographical region over the Kuroshio and are compared using composites, ensembles and individual case studies. Colder air and stronger anticyclogenesis over East Asia track the stronger cases along the Kuroshio, while the weaker cases tend to track across Japan. Anticylogenesis is also present to the east of the stronger cases which hence have warm advection ahead of them. The weaker cases generally form as transitory features in the northerly flow to the west of large cyclones and so have cold advection ahead of them. This affects a deep layer, producing a ridge-trough couplet at 500 mb for the stronger cases and a more zonal flow above the weaker cases.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407z51r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sb42c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343t440"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Radiative mass generation from new Physics in the Quark sector</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Punch, Sean M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A model is presented which consists of a dynamical scheme for reproducing the mass hierarchies observed in the quark sector. This is accomplished through new physics beyond the Standard Model, and does not rely upon the Higgs mechanism. By introducing a heavy fermion which couples to the quarks via the emission and reabsorption of a new boson, initially massless quarks are given their masses in a purely radiative fashion. The differences between up and down sector masses appear naturally as a result of generating the down mass matrix from corrections to the up mass matrix: accomplished via an anomalous flavour-changing coupling to the weak sector. Multipole type form-factors are inserted at each coupling, and introduce parameters which are varied to produce numerical fits to the quark masses, mixing angles and CP-violation parameter. Several extensions to the model are proposed and discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hd36x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343t440</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603qz73q"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mathematical programming with LFS functions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sharifi Mokhtarian, Faranak</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Differentiable functions with a locally flat surface (LFS) have been recently introduced and studied in convex optimization. Here we extend this motion in two directions: to non-smooth convex and smooth generalized convex functions. An important feature of these functions is that the Karush-Kuhn-Tucker condition is both necessary and sufficient for optimality. Then we use the properties of linear LFS functions and basic point-to-set topology to study the "inverse" programming problem. In this problem, a feasible, but nonoptimal, point is made optimal by stable perturbations of the parameters. The results are applied to a case study in optimal production planning.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d547c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qz73q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aht24wk46j"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Na2O-ZrO2-SiO2 and CaO-ZrO2-SiO2 systems : theoretical petrogenetic grids and synthesis experiments</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marr, Robert A. (Robert Allen), 1965-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Fixed-slope P$ rm sb{s}$-$ mu sb{ rm H2O}$ diagrams have been generated for the pseudoternary systems $ rm SiO sb2$-$ rm Na sb2 ZrO sb3$-$ rm H sb2O$ and $ rm SiO sb2$-$ rm CaZrO sb3$-$ rm H sb2O$ as first approximations to P-T phase relations for the Na- and Ca-zirconosilicates, respectively. Two possible topologies were determined for each pseudoternary based on an interchange of stable and metastable invariant points. Although for the $ rm SiO sb2$-$ rm Na sb2 ZrO sb3$-$ rm H sb2O$ system the correct topology cannot yet be resolved, owing to a lack of constraints from experimental and field observations, chemographic analysis reveals that the critical observation would be either the coexistence or incompatibility of the divariant mineral assemblage: elpidite + parakeldyshite. The observed replacement of armstrongite by gittinsite + quartz in the Strange Lake peralkaline complex, Canada, suggests that the preferred topology for the $ rm SiO sb2$-$ rm CaZrO sb3$-$ rm H sb2O$ system may be the one in which the calcium catapleiite-, quartz- and calciohilairite-absent invariant points are stable. Synthesis experiments in the $ rm SiO sb2$-$ rm CaZrO sb3$-$ rm H sb2O$ system resulted in the formation of the compound $ rm{Ca sb2 ZrSi sb4 O sb{12}}$ as well as zircon, baddeleyite, xonotlite and wollastonite under various conditions, but synthesis of naturally-occurring Ca-zirconosilicates remained elusive.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v13m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wk46j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hq95v"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Entomology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of intercropping sweet potato on the population density of sweet potato weevil, Cylas formicarius (F.) (Coleoptera:Curculionidae)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yaku, Alexander</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Field experiments were conducted during the 1989 dry season (July to December) at the Manggoapi Farm of the Faculty of Agriculture, Cenderawasih University in Manokwari, Irian Jaya, Indonesia. The objectives of the experiments were to determine the effects of four sweet potato cropping systems on the population density of sweet potato weevils (SPW) and on the diversity of other insects within these agroecosystems. Fewer SPW were found in intercropped sweet potato + corn (2 weevils per kg infected tubers), sweet potato + soybean (21 weevils), sweet potato + corn + soybean (8 weevils) than in monoculture sweet potato (37 weevils); percentage of damaged tubers followed the same trend, ranging from 2.6% to 14.0% in intercropped sweet potato, to 21.9% in the sweet potato monoculture. However, the higher number of SPW and damaged tubers in the monoculture did not reduce yield below that in the intercropped plots. Insect and spider populations were more diverse in the intercropped sweet potato systems than in monoculture. Number of arthropods increased throughout the growing season. Intercropping may reduce the population density of other insect pests associated with sweet potato and may increase the population density of natural enemies.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20st90z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hq95v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sweet potatoes -- Diseases and pests -- Cultural control -- Indonesia -- Papua</dc:subject><dc:subject>Companion planting -- Indonesia -- Papua</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cylas formicarius</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gt887"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Crack development and acoustic emission studies in potash rock loaded under uniaxial compression</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mlakar, Vincent William</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Acoustic Emission (AE) techniques under laboratory testing conditions are used in order to understand the mechanical behavior and deformational processes of uniaxially compressed potash rock. Results obtained from the acoustic emission measurements are compared to crack development at preselected stress levels up to specimen failure. It is observed that the fracture processes, mechanical behavior and acoustic emission response are dependent on the physical properties of potash rock. The mechanical behavior of potash rock displays two stress-strain trends under the same load conditions. Based on the acoustic emission rate, it was possible to delineate an approximate yield point of potash rock. However, a more detailed study of the acoustic emission amplitude and energy distributions showed that high amplitude events with long event durations are initially observed to occur near the yield point of the stress strain curves. These events are present prior to the yield point in specimens containing a high proportion of sylvite and after the yield point for monomineralic, halitic specimens. Finally, a classification scheme of crack morphology and systematic charts displaying the history of progressive crack development for all potash rock types has been developed.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579t42p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gt887</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geophysics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623d84v"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Performance effects of strategic groups and task environments in food manufacturing industries : augmenting the Bain-Mason paradigm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Banik, Milon Marc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The concentration-profits relationship of the Bain-Mason paradigm is tested and an alternative "augmented model" is proposed which includes dimensions of task environments of food industries and industry strategy variables. The environment is characterized in terms of Dess and Beard's (1984) dimensions: munificence, dynamism and complexity. The augmented model was found to be a better descriptor of factors affecting the performance of the food industries than the Bain-Mason model. Profitability was found to be positively related to industrial concentration, and negatively related to munificence and complexity. No significant relationship between dynamism and profitability was found. Further studies on the performance of the food manufacturing industries should include the use of strategic group typologies based on strategic behaviour specific to the food industries. It is also recommended that investigations of industry environments be conducted using multivariate measures of munificence, dynamism and complexity.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n460h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623d84v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food industry and trade</dc:subject><dc:subject>Industrial organization (Economic theory) -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q758r"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The EM algorithm : an overview with applications to medical data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Coupal, Louis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Owing to their complex design and use of live subjects as experimental units, missing or incomplete data is common place in medical experiments. The great increase in difficulty of maximum likelihood based analysis of incomplete data experiments compared to a similar complete data analysis encourages many medical researchers to ignore cases with missing data in favour of performing a "complete" cases analysis. The expectation maximization algorithm (EM for short) is often an easily implemented algorithm that provides estimates of parameters in models with missing data. The EM algorithm unifies the theory of maximum likelihood estimation in the context of "missing" data. The general problem of missing data also includes structurally unobservable quantities such as parameters, hyperparameters and latent variables. The nature of its defining steps, the expectation or E-step and the maximization or M-step, gives the user intuitive understanding of the maximization process. In this Thesis, the EM algorithm is first illustrated through an example borrowed from the field of genetics. The theory of the EM algorithm is formally developed and the special case of exponential families is considered. Issues concerning convergence and inference are discussed. Many examples taken from the medical literature serve to highlight the method's broad spectrum of application in both missing data and unobservable parameter problems.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634502m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q758r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Statistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50ts846"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Myths of the body : performing identity in Genet</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pietrobruno, Sheenagh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The issue of sexual and racial identity unfolds in a paradoxical light in Genet's works. Identity as a fixed essence is both deconstructed and maintained. His enigmatic portrayal of identity is addressed from a theoretical perspective which combines seemingly contradictory positions, namely essentialism and deconstruction. Such a theoretical stand claims that although identity categories are not fixed essences and consequently can be deconstructed, they must be maintained as political categories in order to deal with oppressive systems which construct essentialist-based identities. Through Genet's presentation of identity as a body performance, race and sex are deconstructed. At the same time, he illustrates how male dominance and racism maintain identities as fixed categories.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v669c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50ts846</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gender identity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Race</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genet, Jean, 1910-1986 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bj430"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Religion and Philosophy in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Caring as a moral concept and its inclusion in nursing education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Polacsik, Annice Samskin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores the psychological foundation of caring relationships, and analyzes the moral perspective of care as described by feminist and nursing theorists. Literature pertaining to a theory of nursing ethics will be discussed. Although such a theory is still in the development stage, there is considerable agreement in recent nursing literature that the concept of care is central to the practice of nursing, and an ethic of care should be an integral part of the teaching of ethics in nursing education. The final chapter of this thesis proposes a pedagogical paradigm shift in nursing education that incorporates a caring curriculum capable of enhancing the ethical ideal of caring.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs19g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bj430</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nursing -- Study and teaching</dc:subject><dc:subject>Caring</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tw40g"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A survey of a class of nonparametric two-sample tests for right censored failure time data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Colomay, Harold K. (Harold Kenney)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis takes an in-depth focus at a specific class of nonparametric two-sample procedures for right censored failure time data-standardized weighted log-rank (SWL) statistics. This family of tests comprises the very famous Gehan, Efron, and log-rank procedures. The first two of these reduce to the Wilcoxon test with censoring absent, while the third one is a censored data generalization of the Savage test. Two particular topics of interest to us are (1) the generation of SWL statistics as score tests within the context of some popular regression models, and (2) asymptotic and small-sample behavior.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f474m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tw40g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Statistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q7591"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gavarni and the Opéra Masked Ball</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bronfman, Beverly</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le thème des bals masqués de l'Opéra est intimement lié au peintre et graveur français du XIXe siècle Guillaume Sulpice Chevalier, dit Gavarni (1804-1866). Entre 1830 et 1853, celui-ci a produit plus de deux cents lithographies sur ce sujet, dont la majorité ont été publiées dans la presse populaire de l'époque. Ces scènes et les légendes qui les accompagnent--bribes de conversations réelles-évoquent l'esprit des bals. Chronique visuelle irrésistible, ces gravures dépeignent les moeurs et les manières de la société parisienne de l'époque. La présente thèse propose une analyse visuelle rigoureux du traitement de ce phénomène par Gavarni qui s'appuyer sur des témoignages littéraires contemporains pour élucider le sens de ses gravures. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The theme of the parisian Carnival masked balls at the Opéra became synonymous with the nineteenth-century French graphic artist Guillaume Sulpice Chevalier, known as Gavarni (1804-1866). Between 1830 and 1853, he produced more than two hundred lithographs of the subject, which usually appeared in the contemporary popular press. These depictions and their telling captions--snippets of actual conversations--evoke the essential esprit of the occasion. A compelling visual chronicle emerges from Gavarni's imagery of the Opéra masked halls, which uniquely captures the contemporary manners and mores of Parisian society. This dissertation is a close visual analysis of Gavarni's treatment of the phenomenon, which draws upon contemporary literary accounts to substantiate and elucidate the meanings of his prints.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Solomon Kiefer, Carol</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j38608223.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q7591</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Masquerades -- France -- Paris -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Balls (Parties) -- France -- Paris -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Paris (France) -- Social life and customs -- 19th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gavarni, Paul, 1804-1866 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kp39g"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Seismic response of steel beams coupling concrete walls</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harries, Kent A. (Kent Alexander)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ductile coupled flexural walls are critical lateral load resisting systems of many structures. The coupling beams of these structures must exhibit excellent ductility and energy absorption ability. To achieve better ductility and energy absorption than previously possible, the use of steel link beams with their ends embedded in the reinforced concrete walls is proposed. Preliminary experimental results are reported for two full-scale reversed cyclic loading tests of portions of ductile flexural walls coupled with steel link beams. The excellent performance, together with the ease of construction, demonstrate the feasibility of this alternative form of construction. In order to ensure ductile response, design and detailing guidelines for both the clear span and embedded portions of the link beams and the reinforced concrete embedment region are presented. An assessment, based on comparisons with other structural systems, of this novel type of construction is presented.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cc06z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp39g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>