<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xq06q"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Consumption of added sugars and development of metabolic syndrome components among a sample of youth at risk of obesity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Jiawei</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Previous evidence showed controversial links between added sugar intake, diet quality and increasing prevalence of metabolic syndrome (MetS) components (abdominal adiposity, dysglycemia, elevated blood pressure, reduced high–density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL–C) and hypertriglyceridemia) in youth, and most studied only its liquid source of sugar–sweetened beverages (SSB). To better understand the extent of the detrimental effects of added sugars from both liquid and solid sources to diets in terms of nutrient and food intake and metabolic consequences in children, three studies were undertaken to (i) quantify the associations of added sugar intake with overall diet quality and adiposity indicators; (ii) assess whether excess weight and glucose tolerance status modifies the associations between consumption of added sugars and MetS components; and (iii) evaluate whether consumption of added sugars predicts the development of MetS components over time.Data for these studies were obtained from the QUébec Adiposity and Lifestyle InvesTigation in Youth (QUALITY) cohort. Caucasian children (8 to 10 years at baseline, n = 630) with at least one obese biological parent were recruited from 1,040 Québec primary schools and followed–up 2 years later (n = 564). Dietary intake, including added sugars (liquid vs. solid) and Canadian Healthy Eating Index (HEI-C) was assessed in three 24–hour recalls at baseline. Adiposity indicators included measured height and weight for body mass index (BMI), BMI Z–score, waist circumference (WC), and fat mass (by dual–energy X–ray absorptiometry). Plasma glucose and insulin were measured at fasting and by oral glucose tolerance tests to calculate the homeostasis model assessment of insulin resistance (HOMA–IR) and the Matsuda IS index (Matsuda–ISI). Systolic blood pressure (SBP), concentration of triglycerides and HDL–C were measured by standard instruments. Multivariate linear regression models were used, adjusting for age, sex, pubertal status (by Tanner stage), energy intake, fat mass and physical activity (by 7–day accelerometer). The main findings include: (i) higher consumption of added sugars from SSB or solid sources was associated with lower nutrient density and lower HEI-C. Positive associations with adiposity indicators were observed with consumption of added sugars from liquid sources only; (ii) higher SSB consumption was associated with higher HOMA–IR and higher SBP among overweight children (≥ 85th BMI percentile), as well as higher SBP and higher WC among children with impaired glucose tolerance. These associations with metabolic indicators were not observed among children whose BMI was below 85th percentile; (iii) no association with added sugar intake was observed for 2–year changes in adiposity, but higher consumption of added sugars from liquid sources was associated with higher fasting glucose, higher fasting insulin, higher HOMA–IR and lower Matsuda–ISI. In conclusion, this thesis suggested that consumption of added sugars from both solid and liquid sources was associated with a lower overall diet quality, but only added sugars from liquid sources was associated with adiposity indicators. Cross–sectional links with higher levels of SSB intake and MetS components were more evident among overweight/obese and glucose–intolerant children. Consumption of added sugars from liquid sources was not associated with changes in adiposity over 2 years, but was clearly associated with development of impaired glucose homeostasis and insulin resistance. This thesis presents further evidence on the nutritional and metabolic consequences of consuming added sugar from liquid and solid sources.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les preuves antérieures ont montré des liens controversés entre la consommation de sucre ajouté, la qualité du régime alimentaire et l'augmentation de la prévalence du syndrome métabolique (SM) composants (adiposité abdominale, dysglycémie, pression artérielle élevée, cholestérol des lipoprotéines de haute densité réduite (HDL-C) et l'hypertriglycéridémie) chez les jeunes, et plus étudié que sa source liquide de boissons sucrées. Afin de mieux comprendre l'impact de la consommation de sucres ajoutés sur l'alimentation des enfants tant en termes des apports alimentaires que des apports nutritionnels, ainsi que les conséquences métaboliques de cette consommation, une série d'études ont été réalisées. Les objectifs de ces études visaient tout d'abord à quantifier les associations entre la consommation de sucres ajoutés (sources liquides et solides) et la qualité du régime alimentaire global de même que les indicateurs d'adiposité, ensuite à déterminer si l'excès de poids et l'état de la tolérance au glucose modifient les associations entre la consommation de sucres ajoutés et les composantes du SM, et finalement, à déterminer si la consommation de sucres ajoutés prédit l'apparition des composantes du SM.Les données utilisées dans les présentes études proviennent de l'étude de cohorte QUébec Adiposity and Lifestyle InvesTigation in Youth (QUALITY). Dans le cadre de cette étude QUALITY, des enfants de race blanche, âgés de 8 à 10 ans (n = 630) et ayant au moins un parent biologique obèses ont été recrutés (n = 564). Les données ont été colligées à l'entrée à l'étude et au suivi de deux ans.  L'apport alimentaire, y compris les sucres ajoutés (liquide ou solide) et l'indice canadien de la saine alimentation (HEI-C) a été évaluée dans trois rappels de 24 heures au départ.Les indicateurs d'obésité incluaient la hauteur et le poids mesurés pour le calcul de l'indice de masse corporelle (IMC), l'IMC Z–score, le tour de taille (TT) et la masse grasse (absorptiométrie bi–énergique à rayons X). Les taux de glucose plasmatique et d'insuline à jeun ont été mesurés ainsi que des tests de tolérance au glucose par voie orale pour le calcul de l'évaluation du modèle d'homéostasie de résistance à l'insuline (HOMA–IR) et de l'indice de Matsuda (Matsuda–ISI). En outre, la pression artérielle systolique, la concentration plasmatique de triglycérides et les taux des HDL–C ont été mesurés à l'aide de méthodes standardisées. Des modèles de régression linéaires multivariés ont été utilisés, ajustement pour l'âge, le sexe, le stade pubertaire (stade de Tanner), la consommation d'énergie, la masse grasse et l'activité physique (accéléromètre 7 jours).Les principales conclusions sont les suivantes augmentation de la consommation de sucres ajoutés provenant de sources boissons sucrées ou solide a été associée à la densité nutritionnelle plus en plus bas HEI-C. Les indicateurs d'adiposité ont été positivement associés à la consommation de sucres ajoutés liquides. Une plus grande consommation de boissons sucrés a été associé à plus HOMA–IR et plus la pression artérielle systolique chez les enfants en surpoids, ainsi que plus la pression artérielle systolique et plus TT chez les enfants présentant une intolérance au glucose. Ces associations avec des indicateurs métaboliques n'ont pas été observés chez les enfants de poids normal. Aucune association avec la consommation de sucre ajouté a été observé des changements dans l'adiposité, mais la consommation élevée de sucres ajoutés provenant de sources liquides a été associé à une glycémie à jeun supérieure, l'insuline à jeun élevée, supérieur HOMA–IR et inférieur Matsuda–ISI. En conclusion, cette thèse présente une preuve supplémentaire sur les conséquences nutritionnelles et métaboliques de sucre ajouté consommation provenant de sources liquides et solides. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Katherine Gray-Donald</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204247m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xq06q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A44558h488"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Multiscale mechanics and multiobjective optimization of cellular hip implants with variable stiffness</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Arabnejad, Sajad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bone resorption and bone-implant interface instability are two bottlenecks of current orthopaedic hip implant designs. Bone resorption is often triggered by mechanical bio-incompatibility of the implant with the surrounding bone. It has serious clinical consequences in both primary and revision surgery of hip replacements. After primary surgery, bone resorption can cause periprosthetic fractures, leading to implant loosening. For the revision surgery, the loss of bone stock compromises the ability of bone to adequately fix the implant. Interface instability, on the other hand, occurs as a result of excessive micromotion and stress at the bone-implant interface, which prevents implant fixation. As a result, the implant fails, and revision surgery is required.Many studies have been performed to design an implant minimizing both bone resorption and interface instability. However, the results have not been effective since minimizing one objective would penalize the other. As a result, among all designs available in the market, there is no implant that can concurrently minimize these two conflicting objectives. The goal of this thesis is to design an orthopaedic hip replacement implant that can simultaneously minimize bone resorption and implant instability. We propose a novel concept of a variable stiffness implant that is implemented through the use of graded lattice materials. A design methodology based on multiscale mechanics and multiobjective optimization is developed for the analysis and design of a fully porous implant with a lattice microstructure. The mechanical properties of the implant are locally optimized to minimize bone resorption and interface instability. Asymptotic homogenization (AH) theory is used to capture stress distribution for failure analysis throughout the implant and its lattice microstructure. For the implant lattice microstructure, a library of 2D cell topologies is developed, and their effective mechanical properties, including elastic moduli and yield strength, are computed using AH. Since orthopaedic hip implants are generally expected to support dynamic forces generated by human activities, they should be also designed against fatigue fracture to avoid progressive damage. A methodology for fatigue design of cellular materials is proposed and applied to a two dimensional implant, with Kagome and square cell topologies. A lattice implant with an optimum distribution of material properties is proved to considerably reduce the amount of bone resorption and interface shear stress compared to a fully dense titanium implant. The manufacturability of the lattice implants is demonstrated by fabricating a set of 2D proof-of-concept prototypes using Electron Beam Melting (EBM) with Ti6Al4V powder. Optical microscopy is used to measure the morphological parameters of the cellular microstructure. The numerical analysis and the manufacturability tests performed in this preliminary study suggest that the developed methodology can be used for the design and manufacturing of novel orthopaedic implants that can significantly contribute to reducing some clinical consequences of current implants.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La résorption osseuse et l'instabilité de l'interface os-implant sont deux goulots d'étranglement de modèles actuels d'implants orthopédiques de hanche. La résorption osseuse est souvent déclenchée par une bio-incompatibilité mécanique de l'implant avec l'os environnant. Il en résulte de graves conséquences cliniques à la fois en chirurgie primaire et en chirurgie de révision des arthroplasties de la hanche. Après la chirurgie primaire, la résorption osseuse peut entraîner des fractures périprothétiques, conduisant au descellement de l'implant. Pour la chirurgie de révision, la perte de substance osseuse compromet la capacité de l'os à bien fixer l'implant. L'instabilité de l'interface, d'autre part, se produit à la suite d'un stress excessif et de micromouvements à l'interface os-implant, ce qui empêche la fixation des implants. De ce fait, l'implant échoue, et la chirurgie de révision est nécessaire.De nombreuses études ont été réalisées pour concevoir un implant qui minimise la résorption osseuse et l'instabilité de l'interface. Cependant, les résultats n'ont pas été efficaces, car minimiser un objectif pénaliserait l'autre. En conséquence, parmi tous les modèles disponibles sur le marché, il n'y a pas d'implant qui puisse en même temps réduire ces deux objectifs contradictoires. L'objectif de cette thèse est de concevoir une prothèse orthopédique de la hanche qui puisse simultanément réduire la résorption osseuse et l'instabilité de l'implant. Nous proposons un nouveau concept d'implant à raideur variable qui est mis en œuvre grâce à l'utilisation de matériaux assemblés en treillis.Une méthodologie de conception basée sur la mécanique multi-échelle et l'optimisation multiobjectif est développé pour l'analyse et la conception d'un implant totalement poreux avec une microstructure en treillis. Les propriétés mécaniques de l'implant sont localement optimisés pour minimiser la résorption osseuse et l'instabilité d'interface. La théorie de l'homogénéisation asymptotique (HA) est utilisée pour capturer la distribution des contraintes pour l'analyse des défaillances  tout le long de l'implant et de sa microstructure en treillis. Concernant cette microstructure en treillis, une bibliothèque de topologies de cellules 2D est développée, et leurs propriétés mécaniques efficaces, y compris les modules d'élasticité et la limite d'élasticité, sont calculées en utilisant le théorie HA. Puisque les prothèses orthopédiques de hanche sont généralement censées soutenir les forces dynamiques générées par les activités humaines, elles doivent être également conçues contre les fractures de fatigue pour éviter des dommages progressifs. Une méthodologie pour la conception en fatigue des matériaux cellulaires est proposée et appliquée à un implant en deux dimensions, et aux topologies de cellules carrées et de Kagome. Il est prouvé qu'un implant en treillis avec une répartition optimale des propriétés des matériaux réduit considérablement la quantité de la résorption osseuse et la contrainte de cisaillement de l'interface par rapport à un implant en titane totalement dense. La fabricabilité des implants en treillis est démontrée par la fabrication d'un ensemble de concepts de prototypes utilisant la fusion par faisceau d'électronsde poudre Ti6Al4V. La microscopie optique est utilisée pour mesurer les paramètres morphologiques de la microstructure cellulaire. L'analyse numérique et les tests de fabricabilité effectués dans cette étude préliminaire suggèrent que la méthodologie développée peut être utilisée pour la conception et la fabrication d'implants orthopédiques innovants qui peuvent contribuer de manière significative à la réduction des conséquences cliniques des implants actuels.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Damiano Pasini</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vm34n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558h488</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2r36v177v"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Solute transport in articular cartilage: toward applications of diffusion, partitioning and adsorption for tissue functional assessment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moeini, Mohammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine les aspects de la partitionnement et de la diffusion des solutés dans le cartilage articulaire ainsi que l'adsorption des solutés sur ses surfaces et discute leurs applications potentielles dans l'évaluation fonctionnelle du cartilage. Étude de la dépendance de la température de transport de soluté dans le cartilage a montré une tendance générale de l'augmentation du coefficient de partage et de la diffusivité à température croissante pour une gamme de solutés fluorescents y compris l'isothiocyanate de fluorescéine, 4 et 40 kDa dextranes, la myoglobine, l'insuline et du sulfate de chondroïtine. Comportements inattendus de certains solutés et des variations faibles mais significatives du contenu de l'eau et des glycosaminoglycanes dans les explants ont souligné l'importance des interactions soluté-matrice. L'examen de l'adsorption du soluté sur les surfaces de cartilage a révélé qu'ignorer les effets d'adsorption donne lieu à des mesures de coefficients de partage apparent (Ka) significativement plus grandes que celles réelles (K).   Les différences entre Ka et K ont augmenté en augmentant le ratio de la surface sur volume des explants. Solutés étudiés comprenaient 3 ou 4 kDa et 40 kDa dextranes, sulfate de chondroïtine, l'insuline et la myoglobine conjugués avec trois fluorophores différents et des fluorophores seuls. Un modèle théorique a également été développé pour prédire les erreurs dans les mesures de K et d'estimer le K à partir des données de Ka. Enfin, l'adsorption de soluté à les fissures du cartilage blessé mécaniquement et tranché a été observée d'être significativement moins que les surfaces intactes. De plus, il a été trouvé que l'adsorption sur les surfaces intactes des explants blessés et tranchés était moins réversible que sur les surfaces des explants indemnes. Ces résultats suggèrent que l'adsorption de soluté sur les surfaces de cartilage peut être exploitée comme un mécanisme potentiel pour la détection des lésions de surface et aussi des changements structurels ou biochimiques au niveau des surfaces qui ressemblent visuellement sain. Les solutés étudiés ont été dextrane natif, dextranes modifiés par l'aldéhyde ou par un peptide de liaison de sulfate de chondroïtine (CS) et le peptide seul, tout conjugué avec les fluorophores. Modification de dextranes avec l'aldéhyde ou le peptide a amélioré l'adsorption avec le même niveau d'adsorption différentielle sur des surfaces fissurées et intactes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis examines aspects of solute partitioning and diffusion in articular cartilage and solute adsorption to its surfaces, and discusses their potential applications in functional assessment of cartilage. Investigation of temperature dependence of solute transport in cartilage showed general trends of increased partition coefficient and diffusivity with increasing temperature for a range of fluorescent solutes including fluorescein isothiocyanate, 4 and 40 kDa dextrans, myoglobin, insulin and chondroitin sulfate. Unexpected behaviours of some solutes and small but significant changes in water and glycosaminoglycan contents of explants underscored the importance of solute–matrix interactions. Examining solute adsorption onto cartilage surfaces revealed that ignoring adsorption effects results in measurements of apparent partition coefficients (Ka) significantly greater than actual ones (K). The differences between Ka and K increased with increasing explant surface-to-volume ratio. Solutes studied included 3 or 4 kDa and 40 kDa dextrans, chondroitin sulfate, insulin and myoglobin labeled with three different fluorophores and fluorophores alone. A theoretical model was also developed to predict the resulting errors in K measurements and to estimate K based on Ka data. Finally, solute adsorption onto cracked surfaces of mechanically injured and sliced cartilage explants was observed to be significantly lower than intact surfaces. Studied solutes included fluorescently labeled native dextran, dextrans modified with aldehyde groups or a chondroitin sulfate (CS)-binding peptide and the peptide alone. Adsorption at intact surfaces of injured and sliced explants was found to be less reversible than at surfaces of uninjured explants. Modification of dextrans with aldehyde groups or the peptide enhanced the adsorption with the same level of differential adsorption to cracked and intact surfaces. These findings indicate that solute adsorption to cartilage is sensitive to structural or biochemical changes at otherwise healthy-looking tissue surfaces which may be exploited as a potential mechanism for detection of focal injuries.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thomas Quinn</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vx37z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v177v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gk79w"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bargaining practice and negotiation failure in Russia-Ukraine gas relations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tingle, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Quelles sont les causes des conflits gaziers russo-ukrainiens? Cet article soutient que, pour répondre à cette question, il faut synthétiser deux grandes théories des relations internationales (RI) : le modèle de négociation de guerre et la théorie de l'action. L'article applique ces cadres théoriques à la crise du gaz de 2008-2009 entre l'Ukraine et la Russie, en se basant sur des études de cas qualitatives. Les relations gazières bilatérales peuvent être modélisées comme des interactions de négociation de crise - jusqu'à un certain point. La Russie et l'Ukraine ont tous deux recours à des pratiques de négociation de crise pour assurer leur approvisionnement en gaz naturel et pour obtenir des contrats l'un avec l'autre. Cependant, ces pratiques n'ont pas comme objectif principal la révélation de signaux crédibles de détermination, comme laisseraient à croire les modèles de négociation habituels. Au contraire, la Russie et l'Ukraine utilisent ces pratiques pour maintenir un contrôle politique sur le processus de négociation et pour préserver leur flexibilité par rapport à une gamme de résultats possibles. Cette entente tacite pose des difficultés lorsque les préférences changent et que la signalisation de la détermination devient plus importante que le maintien du contrôle politique et de la flexibilité. Dans de telles situations, comme le démontrent les événements de l'automne 2008, les deux parties continuent à utiliser des pratiques de négociation de crise qui seraient rationnelles si l'objectif principal était la négociation, mais qui ne correspondent plus à leurs objectifs stratégiques pour le processus. Les moyens habituels de faire de la politique gazière ne correspondent plus aux buts stratégiques visés. Le résultat est un conflit gazier coûteux, malgré les incitations fortes qui existent des deux côtés de la table à trouver une solution autre que le conflit.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>What causes 'gas wars' between Russia and Ukraine? Answering this question, this paper argues, requires that we synthesize two prominent theories of international relations (IR), the bargaining model of war and practice theory. It applies these theoretical frameworks to the 2008-2009 Russia-Ukraine gas crisis using qualitative case study methods. Bilateral gas relations can be usefully modeled as crisis bargaining interactions — up to a point. Both Russia and Ukraine deploy crisis bargaining practices to secure natural gas supply and pricing contracts with each other. These practices are not, however, primarily aimed at revealing credible signals of resolve, as standard bargaining models would suggest. Rather, Russia and Ukraine use them to maintain political control over the negotiation process and flexibility over a range of potential outcomes. This tacit understanding poses difficulties when preferences shift such that signaling resolve becomes more important than maintaining political control and flexibility. In these situations, such as late fall 2008, both parties continue to deploy crisis bargaining practices that 'make sense' as ways to engage in negotiation but no longer fit their strategic goals for the process. The taken-for-granted means of practicing gas politics don't fit with the strategic ends sought; the result is a costly gas war despite strong incentives on both sides of the table to locate a compromise short of conflict.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vincent Pouliot</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c392f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk79w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science - International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053k57q"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of the network in distributed optimization algorithms: convergence rates, scalability, communication/ computation tradeoffs and communication delays</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tsianos, Konstantinos</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Many questions of interest in various fields ranging from machine learning to computational biology and finance require the solution of an optimization problem. Frequently such problems are classified as large scale in the sense that they involve complex computations over very large datasets. The increasing interest in distributed optimization algorithms is motivated by two main reasons. First, the problem complexity pushes today's processors to their limits and the need for distributed algorithms arises quite naturally. A second and more practical reason is that sometimes the data is collected in a distributed manner and transmitting it to a single location is either too costly or violates privacy. The starting point of this thesis is the simple realization that the main difference between a serial and a distributed algorithm is that in the latter, a processor needs to exchange messages over a network to access another processor's information. Network communication is in general less reliable and orders of magnitude slower than local disk accesses. Furthermore, in an arbitrary network topology to achieve global performance messages might need to travel over multiple hops. Finally, the hardware's capabilities also limit the ways in which a  distributed algorithm may be implemented. All these factors highlight the important role of the network in distributed optimization algorithms. To understand that role we focus on the class of consensus-based distributed optimization algorithms. Those algorithms admit an elegant theoretical analysis while remaining easy to implement. In addition they tend to be scalable and robust to communication delays. The contributions of this work can be grouped into four important areas: 1) understanding the communication/computation tradeoff and its effect on scalability with the network size, 2) understanding the limitations of the network and the necessary features that distributed algorithms need to possess to be practical, 3) understanding the effects on convergence of network-induced communication delays and 4) understanding the theoretically achievable convergence rates of distributed algorithms. These areas impact the design and deployment of any consensus-based distributed optimization algorithm. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Il y a une grande variété de domaines d'apprentissage automatique, de la biologie à la finance, où l'on doit résoudre des problèmes d'optimisation. Souvent ces problèmes impliquent des calculs complexes sur de vastes ensembles de données. Pour résoudre ces problèmes le développement d'algorithmes distribués est devenu très populaire pour deux raisons. Premièrement, la complexité des problèmes pousse les processeurs actuels à leurs limites. Naturellement, il devient essentiel d'utiliser des systèmes distribués. La deuxième raison est que la collecte des données est parfois distribuée, et il est difficile, coûteux ou en violation d'accords de confidentialité de transférer toutes les données au même endroit.  La fondation de cette thèse est la réalisation simple que la grande différence entre un algorithme centralisé et un algorithme distribué est que ce dernier utilise un réseau pour permettre l'échange d'information d'un processeur à un autre. Généralement, la communication sur un réseau est moins fiable et beaucoup plus lente que l'accès d'information sur un disque local. De plus, pour une topologie de réseau arbitraire, la communication de messages nécessite plusieurs sauts. Finalement, les capacités matérielles aussi limitent les façons par lequelles les algorithmes distribués théoriques peuvent être mis en oeuvre.  Tous ces facteurs, rappellent l'importance du réseau. Pour comprendre cette importance, nous nous concentrons, sur la classe des algorithmes de consensus pour optimisation distribuée. Ces algorithmes aussi possèdent des analyses théoriques très élégantes tout en restant faciles a mettre en oeuvre. Aussi, ils sont robustes aux délais de communication et extensibles. Les contributions de cette thèse peuvent être classifiées selon les quatres catégories suivantes: 1) comprendre le compromis entre communication et calculs locaux, et l'extensibilité avec la taille du réseau, 2) comprendre les limites posées par le réseau aux fonctionnalités nécessaires que chaque algorithme distribué doit possèder en pratique, 3) comprendre les effets de délais de communication et les propriétés de convergence de ces algorithmes en présence de délais, 4) comprendre les taux théoriques de convergence des algorithmes d'optimisation distribués. Tous ces domaines affectent la conception et le déploiement de chaque algorithme de consensus d'optimisation distribué.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael Rabbat</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558h49j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053k57q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4x51hn68t"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanical stimulation of orthopaedic tissues: regulation of bone resorption and solute transport through articular cartilage</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shafieyan, Yousef</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Orthopaedic tissues such as bone, cartilage, ligament, tendon and muscle serve primarily mechanical roles in support of controlled movement. These tissues must continually adapt to changes in their physical environments, in a lifelong process termed remodelling. Interactions between cells in orthopaedic tissues and their physical surroundings underlie tissue functions, remodelling, responses to injury, diseases and repair. Osteoclasts are a type of bone cell responsible for bone resorption. Effects of mechanical stimulation on osteoclast differentiation and subsequent bone resorption activity are of interest for understanding bone physiology within a mechanically active environment. As a preliminary step toward osteoclast mechanotransduction experiments, we optimized conditions for osteoclast differentiation and adhesion to a highly extendable substrate made of poly(dimethylsiloxane) (PDMS). Results showed that a covalently-bound collagen coating can be used to promote osteoclast differentiation on extendable PDMS substrates which enables studies of osteoclast mechanostimulation. Differentiated osteoclasts maintained their functionality as evidenced by actin ring formation, gene expression and bone resorbing ability as specific features of active osteoclasts. To then study osteoclast behaviour in the context of mechanical stimulation, we applied relatively low frequency stimuli to osteoclast precursors and examined osteoclast differentiation and functionality. It was shown that low frequency mechanical stimulation can enhance osteoclastogenesis, in contrast with higher frequency stimulation which is known to be inhibitory during differentiation. Conditioned medium collected from mechanically stimulated cells contained factors that support differentiation of osteoclast precursors to mature osteoclasts. Results also indicated that the ERK 1/2 signaling pathway participates actively in the differentiation of bone marrow cells to osteoclasts under low frequency mechanical stimulation. Mechanotransduction is also a ubiquitous regulator of cell behaviour in articular cartilage. In particular, fluid and solute transport in compressed cartilage regulate cell metabolism and may provide means for minimally invasive detection of tissue degeneration. We studied effects of static compression on diffusion of different contrast agents applicable in magnetic resonance (MR) or X-ray computed tomography (CT) through articular cartilage. Static compression occurs physiologically and results in changes in extracellular matrix (ECM) density, and here provided a means for nondestructive modification of tissue structure. Consistent with previous reports, diffusivity of contrast agents tended to decrease with increasing static compression. Alterations in fluid and GAG contents of cartilage ECM were consistent with this behaviour. Findings suggest that measurement of contrast agent diffusivities during CT or MR imaging could be used to assess focal changes in matrix properties in articular cartilage.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les tissus orthopédiques tels que les os, les cartilages, les ligaments, les tendons et les muscles jouent des rôles essentiellement mécaniques en support au mouvement contrôlé. Ces tissus doivent continuellement s'adapter aux changements dans leur environnement, dans un processus continu appelé remodelage. Les interactions entre cellules dans les tissus orthopédiques et leur environnement physique sont à la base des fonctions des tissus, les réponses aux blessures, les maladies, le remodelage, et la réparation.Les ostéoclastes sont une categorie de cellule osseuse responsable de la résorption osseuse. Les effets de la stimulation mécanique sur la différenciation des ostéoclastes et l'activité subséquente de résorption osseuse sont intéressants pour la compréhension de la physiologie osseuse dans un environnement mécaniquement active. Dans un premier temps vers des expériences de mécanotransduction des ostéoclastes, nous avons optimisé les conditions de la différenciation des ostéoclastes et de l'adhérence à un substrat hautement extensible en poly (diméthyl) (PDMS). Les résultats démontre qu'un revêtement de collagène lié de façon covalente peut être utilisé pour promouvoir la différenciation des ostéoclastes sur des substrats PDMS extensible qui permet des études de mechanostimulation des ostéoclastes. Les ostéoclastes différenciés ont maintenu leur fonctionnalité comme en témoigne la formation d'anneau d'actin, l'expression des gènes et la capacité de résorption osseuse en tant que caractéristiques spécifiques des ostéoclastes actifs. Pour ensuite étudier le comportement des ostéoclastes dans le cadre de la stimulation mécanique, nous avons appliqué des stimuli à relativement basse fréquence à des précurseurs des ostéoclastes et examiné la différenciation et fonctionnalité des ostéoclastes. Il a été montré que la stimulation mécanique à basse fréquence peut améliorer ostéoclastogenèse, en contraste avec la stimulation haute fréquence qui est connu pour être l'inhibiteur de la différenciation. Des milieux conditiotrned recueillies à partir de cellules stimulées mécaniquement contenait des facteurs qui soutiennent la différenciation des précurseurs des ostéoclastes en ostéoclastes matures. Les résultats ont également indiqué que la 1/2 voie de signalisation ERK participe activement à la différenciation des cellules de la moelle osseuse à ostéoclastes sous stimulation mécanique à basse fréquence. Mécanotransduction est également un régulateur ubiquitaire du comportement des cellules dans le cartilage articulaire. En particulier, le transport des fluides et de solutés dans le cartilage comprimé régule le métabolisme des cellules et peut prévoir des moyens de détection minimalement invasif de la dégénérescence des tissus. Nous avons étudié les effets de la compression statique sur la diffusion des différents agents de contraste applicables à la résonance magnétique (IRM) ou le x-ray tomodensitométrie (TDM) à travers le cartilage articulaire. La compression statique survient physiologiquement et entraîne des changements dans la matrice extracellulaire (ECM) de densité, et ici a fourni un moyen de modification non destructive de la structure des tissus. En accord avec les rapports précédents, la diffusivité d'agents de contraste à tendance à se diminuer avec l'augmentation de la compression statique. Les modifications dans le liquide et dans le contenu de gag du cartilage ECM étaient compatibles avec ce comportement. Les résultats suggèrent que la mesure de contraste de diffusivités des agents durant l'imagerie CT ou IRM pourrait être utilisée pour évaluer les changements correspondants dans les propriétés matrice du cartilage articulaire.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thomas Quinn</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k8496.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hn68t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb397c63s"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamical and thermodynamical aspects of second- order relativistic hydrodynamics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sohrabi Anaraki, Kiyoumars</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis we study second-order relativistic hydrodynamics particularly in the context of quantum field theory and AdS/CFT. The theory of hydrodynamics can be thought of as an effective theory in derivative expansion. At first order in derivatives, the result is the equations of motion generally known as the Navier-Stokes equations. But the relativistic Navier-Stokes equations are acausal and numerically unstable. The solution was to extend the derivative expansion to second order. With this generalization we can have more terms with independent coefficients. The main method to obtain information and formally define these viscosities is to derive a set of Kubo formulae for each of these parameters. Kubo formulae are defined in terms of the limit of zero frequency and momentum of the correlation functions of currents or energy-momentum tensors. At first-order hydrodynamics, they are written in terms of two-point functions. We showed that at second order they are defined by generalized three-point Green's functions. Along the way in this thesis, we show that in general, properties of hydrodynamic systems can be classified as thermodynamical and dynamical. Based on the recent and ongoing experiments from RHIC (Relativistic Heavy Ion Collider) and the LHC (Large Hadron Collider), the relevance of these effects are shown. A through examination of the thermodynamical parameters is given in perturbative quantum field theory, non-perturbative lattice field theory and also in the AdS/CFT context. We give a complete calculation of thermodynamical parameters for a generic free field theory and study the coupling power of different orders of perturbation. Using the AdS/CFT correspondence, we calculate them again in the limit of infinite t'Hooft coupling; furthermore the effect of next-to-leading-order terms will be addressed. Since they haven't been computed using lattice field theory techniques, we develop a general picture for the calculation of these Euclidean transport parameters. Next, we show that one of the primary dynamical features of viscosities are the presence of long-time tails. These tails in 3 + 1 dimensions exhibit certain diffusional effects on momentum density and they will give corrections to viscosities. We also clarify the non-linear nature of the outcome. We hope that this thesis sheds light on nature of the matter produced in RHIC and the LHC.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse, nous étudions l'hydrodynamique relativiste de second ordre en mettant un accent particulier sur sa relation avec la théorie des champs quantiques et l'AdS/CFT.  La théorie de l'hydrodynamique peut etre vue comme la théorie efficace d'une expansion en gradients d'une autre théorie. Au premier ordre de cette expansion en gradients, les équations du mouvement de cette théorie efficace correspondent aux équations de Navier-Stokes. Il est cependent connu que la version relativiste des équations de Navier-Stokes n'est ni causale, ni stable numériquement. L'approche utilisée pour corriger ce problème est d'aller à l'ordre supérieur, le second ordre, de l'expansion en gradients. Cette généralisation introduit de nouveaux degrées de libertées, et donc de nouveaux paramètres de transport. La principale méthode pour obtenir de l'information sur ces paramètres est de dériver un ensemble de formules de Kubo pour chacun de ces paramètres. Ces formules sont définies en fonction de la limite zéro fréquence et impulsion de fonctions de corrélations de courants ou de tenseurs d'energie-impulsion. Pour la théorie hydrodynamique au premier ordre, leur expressions prennent la forme de fonctions à deux points. Nous montrons qu'au second ordre, ces formules sont définies comme comme des fonctions de Green généralisées à trois points. Plus spécifiquement, nous montrons dans cette thèse qu'en général, les propriétés de systèmes hydrodynamiques peuvent etre classifiées en propriétés soient dynamiques, soient thermodynamiques. À l'aide des expériences ayant présentement lieu au RHIC (Relativistic Heavy Ion Collider) et au LHC (Large Hadron Collider), l'importance de ces effets est démontrée. Un examen approfondi des paramètres thermodynamiques est donné en théorie des champs perturbatives, en théorie des champs sur réseaux, ainsi qu'en AdS/CFT. Nous donnons un calcul complet des paramètres thermodynamiques pour le cas générique d'un champ libre, et discutons des effets des corrections perturbatives d'ordres supérieurs. En utilisant la correspondance AdS/CFT, nous calculons à nouveau ces coefficients dans la limite d'un couplage de t'Hooft infini, en commentant sur l'effet de l'ordre supérieur sur le calcul. Une approche générale pour le calcul de ces paramètres de transport euclidiens est d'eveloppée pour pallier l'absence de tels résultats dans l'approche des champs sur réseaux. Ensuite, nous démontrons que l'une des principales caractéristiques dynamiques des viscosités est la présence de longues queues temporelles. En 3+1 dimensions, ces queues montrent certains effets de diffusions sur la densité d'impulsion, et elles apportent des corrections aux coefficients. Nous clarifions la nature non-linéaire du résultat. Nous espèrons que cette thèse contribuera à élucider la nature de la matière produite au RHIC et au LHC.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Guy Moore</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cp32b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397c63s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537432w"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La pastorale nordique dans «La Petite Poule d'Eau» et «Alexandre Chenevert» de Gabrielle Roy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roussel, Renaud</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis aims to show how the North in Gabrielle Roy's work is a liminal figurative space that, far from freeing individuals from society's constraints, allows them to reconnect with it in a simplified way. It argues that the characters' "northern" experiences and the mode of their actions, in La Petite Poule d'Eau (The Water Hen) and Alexandre Chenevert (The Cashier), are best defined as pastoral, because they result from an unresolved conflict – a contradiction – between their moral ideals and their passions. Torn between living a solitary life and a communal one, Roy's characters are unable to choose and forced to seek a form of compromise between these two desires. Their ontological uncertainty also sheds light on the tension between the idyllic and romance in Roy's novels, a tension that the liminal location of the northern space illustrates and allows to explore. By bringing together two seemingly antagonistic ideas – the North and the pastoral – and by examining how such an interaction unfolds in the writer's first two "northern" novels, this thesis wishes to underline the dual nature of Roy's characters, novels, and North.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le but de ce mémoire est de montrer que le Nord est un espace figuratif intermédiaire qui permet, non pas de rompre avec le monde, mais de refonder un lien, simplifié, avec la communauté. L'hypothèse qui sous-tend cette étude est que l'expérience nordique des personnages dans La Petite Poule d'Eau et Alexandre Chenevert de Gabrielle Roy renvoie au mode de la pastorale, car elle met en scène une tension irrésolue – une contradiction – entre leurs idéaux moraux et la réalité de leurs passions. Tiraillés entre le désir de vivre en solitaire et celui de vivre en communauté, les personnages royens ne peuvent choisir entre ces deux tentations et sont en quête d'une forme de compromis. Cette hésitation fondamentale des protagonistes de Gabrielle Roy met également en lumière la forte tension entre l'idylle et le romanesque dans les romans de l'auteure, tension que la position intermédiaire du Nord permet d'illustrer et d'explorer. À travers une problématisation des rapports entre le Nord et la pastorale et une étude des deux premiers romans « nordiques » de la romancière, ce mémoire se propose de souligner la nature duelle du Nord, des personnages et du roman royens.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michel Biron</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd376102s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537432w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Canadian (French)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207ts46c"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Radio resource allocation for wireless heterogeneous networks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ngo, Duy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>En déployant de petites cellules (dénommées les femtocells) au sein de la même zone de service que les cellules de tailles régulières (dénommées cellules macro), une efficacité spectrale zone beaucoup plus élevé, une meilleure couverture à l'intérieur, et d'importantes données mobiles de déchargement entre les deux cellules peuvent être réalisé tout en gardant faible coût. Vu que les femtocells réutilisent le spectre de fréquence déjà consacré à la cellule macro, auxquelles ils sont assignés, d'une manière non-coordonnée, de nouvelles limites de cellules sont créées et l'interférence devient beaucoup plus imprévisible que dans les réseaux traditionnels. Dans ce contexte réseau hétérogène, une allocation adaptative de puissance et des méthodes d'accès dynamiques au spectre sont nécessaires pour assurer une coexistence harmonisée des entités du réseau avec les nouvelles spécifications imposées par les femtocells. Depuis que les femtocells sont déployées par les terminaux sans aucune planification au préalable du réseau, des solutions qui s'adaptent automatiquement sont toujours désirable pour contrôler efficacement les sévères interférences entre les différents niveaux du réseau sans fil hétérogène.Dans cette étude, nous développons et évaluons des algorithmes distribués pour l'allocation de ressources radio dans les réseaux sans fil hétérogènes employant l accès multiple par répartition en code (CDMA) et Accès multiple par répartition en fréquence (OFDMA). En évitant une coordination centralisée, les solutions proposées protègent le fonctionnement de tous les utilisateurs de la cellule macro existantes, tout en exploitant de manière optimale la capacité résiduelle du réseau pour les utilisateurs du femtocells. Dans les réseaux CDMA, nous proposons un schéma de tarification dynamique associé à un contrôle d'admission des utilisateurs de la femtocell nous permettant de gérer indirectement l'interférence inter-niveaux (entre cellule macro et femtocell). Le contrôle simultané de la puissance et les algorithmes de contrôle d'admission proposés peut être exécuté localement sur chaque lien pour offrir un maximum d'utilité pour les utilisateurs individuels. Pour maximiser l'utilité totale du réseau, nous développons un algorithme de contrôle simultané de puissance basant sur l'optimalité de Pareto et le rapport signal sur interférence plus bruit (SINR) qui peut partager équitablement les ressources radio entre les utilisateurs. En appliquant d'une méthode d'optimisation, les SINR minimaux prescrits par les utilisateurs des cellules macro sont garantis, alors que le maximal global la somme de l'utilité du réseau est trouvé.Dans les réseaux OFDMA, afin de résoudre le problème non convexe et combinatoire de l'allocation conjointe de la puissance et des sous-porteuses, nous proposons un schéma alternatif de gestion dynamique du spectre qui optimise la distribution de puissance et des sous-porteuses. Avec l'approche par approximations successives convexe adoptée, le débit total de tous les femtocells est maximisé alors que la capacité du réseau de la cellule macro est toujours protégée. En femtocells cognitives où les utilisateurs du femtocell accèdent au spectre autorisé à la cellule macro d'une manière opportuniste, nous appliquons la dualité lagrangienne pour optimiser la distribution de la puissance et des sous-porteuses. Nous prouvons que les solutions distribuées proposées atteignent leur optimal global avec une faible complexité.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>By deploying small cells (i.e., femtocells) within the same service area of regular macrocells, a much higher area spectral efficiency, better indoor coverage, and significant mobile data offloading can be achieved at low cost. Because femtocells reuse the radio spectrum already assigned to macrocells in an uncoordinated fashion, new cell boundaries are created and the signal interference situation becomes far more unpredictable than in conventional networks. In this heterogeneous network setting, adaptive power allocation and dynamic spectrum access are needed to ensure a harmonized coexistence of network entities with diverse design specifications. Since femtocells are deployed by end users without any network planning, autonomous solutions are desirable to effectively control the severe intra-tier and cross-tier interferences. In this study, we develop and evaluate distributed radio resource allocation algorithms for wireless heterogeneous networks employing code-division multiple access (CDMA) and orthogonal frequency division multiple access (OFDMA). Requiring no central coordination, the devised solutions robustly protect the ongoing operation of all existing macrocell users, while optimally exploiting the residual network capacity for femtocells. In CDMA-based networks, we propose a dynamic pricing scheme combined with femtocell user admission control to indirectly manage the cross-tier interference. The proposed joint power and admission control algorithms can be locally executed at each link to offer a maximum utility to individual users. For the total network utility maximization, we develop joint Pareto-optimal power control and signal-to-interference-plus-noise ratio (SINR) assignment algorithms that can fairly share radio resources among users. Upon applying convex optimization methods, the minimum SINRs prescribed by macrocell users are effectively enforced, whereas the sum network utility is globally maximized. In OFDMA-based networks, to resolve the highly nonconvex and combinatorial problem of joint power and subchannel allocation, we propose a dynamic spectrum management scheme that alternatively optimizes the powers and assigns the subchannels. With the adopted successive convex approximation approach, the total throughput of all femtocells is maximized whilst the macrocell network capacity is always protected. In cognitive femtocells where femtocell users opportunistically access the spectrum licensed to macrocells, we apply Lagrangian duality to devise jointly optimal power and subchannel allocation algorithms. The distributed solutions are shown to achieve their global optimality with low complexity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tho Le-Ngoc</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343w42v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207ts46c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p3673"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of heterogeneity in adaptation and speciation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haller, Benjamin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Heterogeneity is at the heart of Darwin's "mystery of mysteries", the origin of species, as both cause and consequence. Heterogeneity within and between environments can lead to genetic and phenotypic heterogeneity within and between populations. This can lead, in turn, to heterogeneity in patterns of mating and reproduction, often called "non-random" or "assortative" mating. Ultimately, this process can lead to speciation – in essence, the development of stable, persistent heterogeneity at the phylogenetic level. A "chain of causation" thus exists along which heterogeneity propagates, from differences among environments to differences among individuals, populations, and ultimately species (Chapter 1). In this thesis I present three models, focused upon three different links in this chain of causation, to study the causes and consequences of heterogeneity in the evolutionary process. The first model (Chapter 2) examines the earliest link in this chain of causation: the process of adaptation within a single population in an environment containing a single resource type. This model demonstrates that stochasticity generates genetic and phenotypic heterogeneity even in a simple environment such as this. Furthermore, that heterogeneity can be maintained and promoted by simple ecological processes such as intraspecific competition that decrease the fitness of common phenotypes. The results of this model help to resolve a long-standing puzzle in evolutionary biology, the "paradox of stasis", by providing a mechanistic explanation for the pattern of selection observed in natural populations. The second model (Chapter 3) explores an intermediate link in the chain of causation: the effects of spatial environmental heterogeneity on divergent adaptation and biodiversification. This model incorporates complex, realistic patterns of environmental heterogeneity not previously studied, and demonstrates a novel "refugium effect" through which such complex environmental heterogeneity can promote biodiversification. In essence, "refugia" generated by patchy environmental heterogeneity can provide stepping-stones through which adaptation to hostile environments can proceed incrementally. Other effects of complex heterogeneity are also demonstrated, and these results are connected to empirical speciation research. The last model presented (Chapter 4) investigates the final links in the chain of causation: the development of reproductive isolation and progress toward speciation. It has previously been hypothesized that a floral syndrome called heterostyly might cause partial reproductive isolation among populations of flowering plants, promoting speciation. This chapter's model is used to test that hypothesis. Results support this hypothesis in some scenarios, because divergent ecological selection on traits involved in heterostyly can pleiotropically produce reproductive isolation. However, this model does not always lead to reproductive isolation. An alternative outcome in which heterostyly leads to asymmetric gene flow points toward a novel mechanism underlying the progression from heterostyly to dioecy, offering a possible resolution of an enduring mystery in plant mating system research. In Chapter 5, the chain of causation discussed above is visualized with a flowchart that depicts the mechanisms that generate and promote heterogeneity at different stages in the process of adaptation and speciation. This flowchart illustrates the unifying idea at the heart of this thesis: that the process of biodiversification involves the propagation of heterogeneity from the environment to individuals, populations, and ultimately new species. The models presented in the preceding chapters are shown at their respective positions along the chain of causation, illustrating which parts of this conceptual framework have been explored in this thesis.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'hétérogénéité est au coeur du «mystère des mystères» de Darwin : l'origine des espèces, comme cause et comme conséquence. L'hétérogénéité à l'intérieur et entre les environnements peut produire de l'hétérogénéité génétique et phénotypique dans une population et entre des populations. Ceci peut produire, à son tour, de l'hétérogénéité dans les patrons d'accouplement et de reproduction, souvent appelé «croisement assortatif». Ultimement, ce processus peut mener à la spéciation – en fait, le développement d'une hétérogénéité stable et persistante au niveau phylogénique.  Une «chaîne de causalité» existe au cours duquel l'hétérogénéité se propage, de différences environmentales à des différences entre les individus, les populations, et ultimement aux espèces (premier chapitre). Dans cette thèse, je présente trois modèles, qui portent chacun sur un lien différent de la chaîne de causalité pour étudier les causes et les conséquences de l'hétérogénéité dans les processus évolutifs. Le premier modèle (deuxième chapitre) examine le premier lien de la chaîne de causalité : le processus d'adaptation avec une seule population et un seul environnement ne contenant qu'un seul type de ressource. Ce modèle montre que la stochasticité génère de l'hétérogénéité génétique et phénotypique, même dans un environnement simple. En plus, l'hétérogénéité peut être maintenue et amplifiée par des processus écologiques simples comme la compétition intra-spécifique qui réduit la valeur d'adaptation des phénotypes communs. Ces résultats aident à résoudre une vieille question en biologie de l'évolution, «le paradoxe de la stase», en fournissant une explication pour les mécanismes de sélection que l'on observe dans la nature. Le deuxième modèle (troisième chapitre) explore un lien intermédiaire dans la chaîne de causalité : les effets de l'hétérogénéité environnementale sur l'adaptation divergente et les processus de biodiversification. Ce modèle intègre des patrons complexes d'hétérogénéité qui n'ont pas été étudiés précédemment et montre un nouvel «effet refuge» qui amplifie les processus de biodiversification dans des environnements hétérogènes complexes. En effet, les «refuges» générés par la fragmentation spatiale peuvent devenir des tremplins par lesquels l'adaptation aux environnements hostiles peut procéder séquentiellement. D'autres effets de l'hétérogénéité complexe sont aussi montrés et ces résultats sont liés à la recherche empirique sur la spéciation. Le dernier modèle (quatrième chapitre) étudie le dernier lien de la chaîne de causalité : le développement de l'isolation reproductive et l'évolution vers la spéciation. Il a été suggéré qu'un syndrome floral appelé hétérostylie peut causer une isolation reproductive partielle entre les fleurs, entraînant la spéciation. Le modèle de ce chapitre est utilisé pour tester cette hypothèse. Les résultats appuient cette hypothèse dans certains scénarios, car la sélection écologique divergente sur les traits impliqués dans l'hétérostylie peuvent produire de l'isolement reproductif à cause d'effects pléiotropes. Cependant, ce modèle ne génère pas toujours de l'isolement reproductif. Un autre résultat possible du modèle est que l'hétérostylie produit un flux génique asymmétrique. Ce résultat pointe vers un nouveau mécanisme sous-jacent à la progression de l'hétérostylie vers la diécie, offrant la possibilité de résoudre un mystère persistant à propos du système reproductif des plantes. Dans le cinquième chapitre, la chaîne de causalité est représentée par un organigramme qui présente les mécanismes qui génèrent et amplifient l'hétérogénéité à différents stades du processus d'adaptation et de spéciation. Les modèles présentés dans les chapitres précédents sont positionnés sur la chaîne de causalité, illustrant quelles sont les parties de cet organigramme qui ont été explorées dans cette thèse.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Andrew Hendry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q046k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p3673</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nm55w"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structural studies of P5 and its interactions with BiP and DNAj-containing proteins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vinaik, Roohi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les protéines disulfure isomérases (PDI) constituent une famille de thio-oxydoréductases qui catalysent l'oxydation, la réduction et l'isomérisation des ponts disulfures dans le réticulum endoplasmique (RE). La protéine P5 humaine (PDIA6) est un membre de la famille des PDI qui affecte le pronostic de maladies telles que le glioblastome multiforme et le carcinome hépatocellulaire (CHC). P5 est une protéine qui contient trois domaines fonctionnels. Les domaines catalytiques 1 et 2 qui sont thio-actifs et reliés par une région flexible sont suivis par un troisième domaine non-réactif. Dans ce travail, nous avons déterminé les structures cristallines à haute résolution des trois domaines de la protéine P5. Ils  possèdent tous une structure semblable à celle de la thiorédoxine et le site actif de chacun des deux domaines catalytiques contient un motif CGHC. La structure du domaine non catalytique montre une grande poche hydrophobe qui pourrait potentiellement servir de site de liaison pour le substrat, comme dans le cas de PDIA1. Il est intéressant de noter que ce site est bloqué par l'extrémité C-terminale qui s'enroule autour du domaine non-catalytique. Cela pourrait constituer un mécanisme d'auto-régulation de l'activité P5. Alors que sa fonction précise est encore inconnue, il a été montré que P5 pouvait interagir avec BiP, un homologue de la protéine Hsp70 du réticulum endoplasmique (RE). La chaperonne BiP empêche l'agrégation des protéines et a un rôle de contrôle de la qualité dans le RE. Nous avons utilisé des assais d'immunoprécipitation, de resonnance magnétique nucléaire (RMN) et de cristallographie aux rayons X pour caractériser l'interaction entre les protéines P5 et BiP. Les essais d'immunoprécipitation ont montré que la protéine P5 se liait spécifiquement au domaine de de liaison nucléotidique (NBD) de BiP. L'affinité diminue en présence d'ATP alors que la liaison n'est pas affectée par l'addition d'un agent réducteur. Nous avons déterminé la structure cristalline du domaine de liaison nucléotidique de BiP en complexe avec l'ADP qui révèle un changement de conformation qui n'avait pas été observé dans les structures antérieures. Ce changement de conformation pourrait imiter les changements structurels qui se produisent lorsque le NBD s'associe avec d'autres protéines. Il est intéressant de noter que cette région est adjacente au R197, un acide aminé critique pour la liaison aux protéines qui contiennent un domaine DNAj. Les expériences de titrage RMN suggèrent que la protéine P5 et ainsi que celles qui contiennent un domaine DNAj n'entrent pas en concurrence les uns avec les autres pour BiP, mais qu'elles pourraient former un complexe ternaire. Une autre protéine moins étudiée de la famille des PDI, PDIR (PDIA5), est un membre spécialisé qui participe au repliement des protéines α1-antitrypsine et des glycoprotéines N-linked. Durant cette thèse, la structure cristalline du domaine non catalytique de PDIR a été déterminée à une résolution de 1,5 Å. Sa structure adopte un repliement semblable à celui de la thiorédoxine stabilisé par un pont disulfure structurel et une surface de liaison chargée positivement pour les interactions avec les chaperones de l'ER calréticuline et ERp72. Les contacts entre les molécules au sein du cristal imitent potentiellement les interactions de la protéine PDIR avec un substrat mal replié. Les résultats suggèrent que le domaine non catalytique du PDIR joue un rôle clé dans la reconnaissance des protéines partenaires et des substrats.Comme le repliement anormal des protéines est impliqué dans une variété de maladies, la compréhension des mécanismes moléculaires de leur repliement facilitera le développement de stratégies thérapeutiques. Une caractérisation plus poussée de P5 et de PDIR permettra de mieux comprendre les voies de repliement dans lesquelles sont impliquées les protéines BiP et calnexine/calréticuline qui sont responsables du maintien de l'intégrité du réticulum endoplasmique.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Protein disulfide isomerases (PDIs) constitute a family of thiol oxidoreductases that catalyze oxidation, reduction, and isomerization of disulfide bonds in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER). Human P5 (PDIA6) is a PDI family member that affects the prognosis of diseases such as glioblastoma multiforme and hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). P5 is a protein which contains three domains, catalytically active domains 1 and 2 joined by a flexible linker and a non thiol-reactive domain 3. Here, we determined high-resolution crystal structures of all three P5 domains. The domains all possess a thioredoxin-like structural fold, and the active site of both catalytic domains contains a CGHC motif. The structure of the non-catalytic domain shows a large hydrophobic pocket that could serve as a potential substrate-binding site, similar to PDIA1. Interestingly, this site is blocked by a C-terminal tail that wraps around the non-catalytic domain. This may provide a mechanism of auto-regulation of P5 activity. While its precise function is still unknown, P5 has been shown to interact with BiP, an Hsp70 homolog found in the ER. BiP chaperone prevents protein aggregation and functions in ER quality control. We used pull-down assays, NMR and X-ray crystallography in order to characterize the interaction between P5 and BiP. Pull-downs showed that full-length P5 binds specifically to the nucleotide-binding domain (NBD) of BiP. The affinity is decreased in the presence of ATP, while the binding is not affected by addition of reducing agent. We obtained the crystal structure of the nucleotide-binding domain of BiP in complex with ADP that reveals a conformational switch not observed in previous structures. This switch could mimic structural changes that occur when NBD associates with partner proteins. Interestingly, this region is adjacent to R197, a residue critical for binding to DNAj-type proteins. NMR titrations suggest that P5 and DNAj-type proteins do not compete with each other for BiP binding, but could potentially form a ternary complex. Another less-studied PDI, protein disulfide isomerase-related (PDIR) protein (PDIA5), is a specialized member that participates in the folding of α1-antitrypsin and N-linked glycoproteins. In this thesis, the crystal structure of the non-catalytic domain of PDIR was determined to 1.5 Å resolution. The structure adopts a thioredoxin-like fold stabilized by a structural disulfide bridge with a positively charged binding surface for interactions with the ER chaperones, calreticulin and ERp72. Crystal contacts between molecules potentially mimic the interactions of PDIR with misfolded substrate proteins. The results suggest that the non-catalytic domain of PDIR plays a key role in the recognition of protein partners and substrates. Understanding the molecular mechanisms of folding will facilitate the development of therapeutic strategies because aberrant protein folding has a role in a variety of diseases. Further characterization of P5 and PDIR will provide a greater understanding of the BiP and calnexin/calreticulin folding pathways that are responsible for maintaining ER integrity. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kalle Burgess Gehring</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333575j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nm55w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn999b038"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The media players: Shakespeare, Middleton, Jonson, and the idea of news</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wittek, Stephen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>I argue that the early modern theatre made a significant contribution to the development of a new, more complex, idea of news that began to take root in the early seventeenth century. Unlike other means of representing current events, theatrical discourse did not present itself as true—it depended for effect on a knowing disengagement from reality, an implicit awareness that Burbage was not really Richard III and the Globe theatre was not really Bosworth Field. Compounding this formal barrier to reality, dramatists of the period typically approached topical concerns from an oblique angle, or from behind the guise of a sophisticated conceit, thus making the connection to news a matter of imaginative interpretation, or play. Paradoxically, however, such techniques did not fence the theatre off from news culture but in fact made it a unique space where formative thinking about the news could flourish, a space where the concept of news could become manifest from an elucidating distance and could accrue value in an emotionally and intellectually resonant register. Chapter One offers a parallel history of theatre and news and then moves to a discussion of how both forms contributed to a shift in early modern publicity. In the three chapters that follow, this historical and theoretical framework is applied to readings of The Winter's Tale (Shakespeare), A Game at Chess (Middleton), and The Staple of News (Jonson). Overall, the analysis shows how the theatre of Shakespeare, Middleton, and Jonson enriched news culture by providing a forum where a rigorous, but playful, re-thinking of news could develop—thereby opening up new opportunities for participation in public life. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse, j'avance que théâtre moderne a permis un progrès significatif dans le développement d'une conception nouvelle et plus complexe de l'information, telle qu'elle commença à prendre forme au début du 17ème siècle. Contrairement à d'autres sources de diffusion de l'information, le discours théâtral ne se prétendait pas comme vrai – il reposait plutôt sur un désengagement voulu de la réalité, sur un savoir implicite que Burbage n'était pas vraiment Richard III et que le théâtre du Globe n'était pas Bosworth Field. En amplifiant cet écart formel avec réalité, les dramaturges de la période abordaient des sujets d'actualité de manière oblique, ou sous le déguisement d'une métaphore sophistiquée, faisant ainsi du lien avec l'actualité matière au jeu interprétatif ou imaginatif. Cependant, de façon paradoxale, le retrait de la réalité opéré par le théâtre n'a pas mis ce dernier à l'écart de la culture de l'information, mais en a fait un espace unique où une réflexion formatrice sur l'information a pu se développer, un espace où les idées et les questions fondamentales au concept d'information ont pu prendre forme grâce à une distance éclairante, et acquérir une valeur d'un registre aussi bien émotionnel qu'intellectuel. Le premier chapitre relate en parallèle l'histoire du théâtre et celle de l'information, puis explore la manière dont tous deux ont contribué à opérer un tournant dans la médiatisation à l'ère moderne. Dans les trois chapitres suivants, ce cadre historique et théorique est appliqué à la lecture de The Winter's Tale (Shakespeare), A Game at Chess (Middleton), et The Staple of News (Jonson). Notre analyse montre finalement comment le théâtre de Shakespeare, Middleton et Johnson a enrichi la culture de l'information en offrant un forum où réflexion aussi rigoureuse que ludique sur l'information a pu se développer, créant ainsi de nouvelles occasions de participer à la vie publique. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul Edward Yachnin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x2556.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999b038</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dj95x"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of microstructure on static and dynamic mechanical properties of third generation advanced high strength steels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aydin, Huseyin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les études récentes sur les aciers se sont surtout concentrées sur le développement avancé de nouvelles feuilles d'acier à haute résistance (AHSS, advanced high strength sheet steels, en anglais), particulièrement pour les applications automobiles. Les "AHSS de première génération" sont des aciers qui possèdent principalement des microstructures à base de ferrite ayant une résistance à la traction (à l'état brut de laminage) de l'ordre de 450 à 700 MPa tandis que les "AHSS de seconde génération" sont des aciers austénitiques à haute teneur en manganèse ayant une résistance à la traction de l'ordre de 900 à 1100 MPa. Récemment, un intérêt s'est manifesté pour le développement "d'AHSS de troisième génération" qui sont des aciers ayant une résistance et une ductilité combinées supérieures aux AHSS de Première Génération de l'ordre de 20 000 MPa x ε%, mais à un coût nettement moindre que celui requis pour les AHSS de seconde génération, réduisant ainsi le recours à des éléments d'alliage coûteux. Conséquemment, l'approche actuelle pour le développement d'AHSS de Troisième Génération est d'unir tous les aspects de la première et de la seconde génération d'aciers en des combinaisons uniques d'alliages et de microstructures qui permettront d'atteindre les propriétés désirées. Ainsi, les microstructures d'AHSS de troisième génération sont constituées d'une phase à haute résistance (e.g. Martensite ou bainite) et d'austénite dont la ductilité et l'écrouissage sont  importants et qui possède une plasticité induite par déformation suite à une transformation ou un maclage. Dans cette thèse, quatre compositions d'aciers différents, centrés sur le Mn comme principal élément d'alliage, sont désignés comme candidats pour les grades d'AHSS de Troisième Génération. La conception de ces aciers est basée sur le contrôle du comportement à la déformation de l'austénite résiduelle. Par conséquent, les paramètres du procédé de traitement thermique sont déterminés de façon à obtenir différentes quantités et morphologies d'austénite résiduelle. L'évolution de la microstructure, au cours du traitement et de la déformation, est caractérisée par microscopie optique et électronique et des tests mécaniques. L'effet de la composition de l'alliage et des paramètres de traitement sur les mécanismes de déformation des aciers est discuté.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The recent studies on steels have largely focused on the development of new advanced high strength sheet steels (AHSS), particularly for automotive applications. "First generation AHSS" are steels that primarily possess ferrite-based microstructures with tensile strength (in the as-rolled condition) in the range of 450 to 700 MPa, and "second generation AHSS" are austenitic steels with high manganese content in the range of 900 MPa to 1100 MPa tensile strength. Recently, there has been interest in the development of a "third generation" of AHSS, which are steels with strength-ductility combinations better than the first generation AHSS with a range of 20 000 MPa x %ε but at a cost significantly less than that of the second generation AHSS as a result of reducing expensive alloying elements.  Therefore, the current approach to the development of third generation AHSS is to combine all the aspects of first and second generation steels in unique alloy/microstructure combinations to achieve the desired properties. Thus, the third generation of AHSS microstructures consists of a high strength phase (e.g., martensite or bainite) and a significant amount of ductility and work hardening from an austenite that exhibits deformation induced plasticity through transformation or twinning. In this thesis, four different steel compositions, centered on Mn as the main alloying element, are designated as candidates for third generation AHSS grades.  The design of these steels is based on controlling the deformation behavior of the retained austenite.  Thus, heat treatment process parameters are determined in order to obtain different amounts and morphologies of retained austenite.  The evolution of the microstructure, during processing as well as deformation, is characterized by using optical and electron microscopy techniques and mechanical tests. The effect of alloy composition and processing parameters on the deformation mechanisms of these steels is discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stephen Yue</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t9730.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dj95x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82kb65d"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spatial modeling of soil heterogeneities and their impacts on runoff, sediment and total phosphorus loss</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boluwade, Alaba</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Located in southern Quebec, at the northeastern extremity of Lake Champlain, the Missisquoi Bay is subject to eutrophication arising from excess nutrients, predominantly phosphorus (P), contributed by agricultural runoff. Land use patterns, agronomic practices, soil properties, and geomorphology have an impact on soil P. Studies have used hydrologic models [e.g., the Soil and Water Assessment Tool (SWAT)] to characterize P loadings from the region's agricultural watersheds. The lack of a proper understanding of the impact of spatial variability and heterogeneity of soil properties on the prediction of runoff, sediment and nutrient movement has proven a major challenge. In order to overcome this, field surveys, spatial variability characterization of P through geostatistics, heterogeneity quantification and hydrologic modeling using SWAT were undertaken. An extensive geostatistic study of soil properties was followed by the use of SWAT to predict runoff, sediment and total phosphorus (TP).  Soil surveys carried out in the summers of 2011 and 2012 measured soils physical and chemical properties.  Variogram analysis characterized the spatial variability of soil test phosphorus (STP). Ordinary kriging (OK) was used to estimate STP values at unsampled locations. Due to OK's smoothing effect, some high value areas were underestimated, while some low areas were overestimated. Compared to OK, sequential Gaussian simulation (SGS) helped characterize the uncertainty and provides better estimates at non-sampled locations.  Areas above the STP threshold at which P has the potential to move to freshwater after precipitation events, combined with topographic factors, were identified. The uncertainty in variogram parameters (sill, nugget and range) was characterized using a Bayesian Hierarchical framework, aiding in understanding the complexity and heterogeneity in the STP dataset attributable to land use patterns.  The Posterior mean and 95% credible confidence intervals of the variogram parameters and STP values were developed. An Independent Component Analysis (ICA) technique, which overcame the problem of matrix inversion in co-simulation, served in the decomposition of spatially-correlated geochemical variables. This implementation was tested on three correlated variables: magnesium, calcium and iron. The measured soil properties required by SWAT were regionalized and clustered using a Regionalization with Constrained Clustering and Partitioning (REDCAP) algorithm.  Five maps were created based on 5, 10, 15, 20 and 24 part partitioning. Each of these maps had different measures of heterogeneity and each was used as inputs for five different configurations of SWAT.  Mean monthly flow, sediment and total P load from April 2001 to December 2002 were used to assess model performance before and after calibration. Overall, there was no significant difference in runoff simulation between any of the five map configurations, which might be due to the impacts of the SCS-CN (soil conservation service-curve number) method in simulating runoff. In the study watershed, using a higher resolution (number of regions) of soil data did not improve predictions of monthly streamflow, sediment or TP.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Situé dans le sud du Québec, à l'extrémité nord-est du Lac Champlain, la Baie Missisquoi est sujette à une eutrophisation attribuable à un excès d'éléments nutritifs, principalement le phosphore (P), provenant du ruissellement agricole. L'utilisation des terres, les pratiques agronomiques,  les propriétés du sol et la géomorphologie influencent la teneur en P du sol. Employant des modèles hydrologiques tel le Soil and Water Assessment Tool (SWAT), une série d'études ont déjà servi à caractériser les charges en P provenant des bassins versants agricoles de la région. Une compréhension inadéquate de l'impact de la variabilité spatiale et de l'hétérogénéité des propriétés du sol sur la prédiction du ruissellement et du déplacement des sédiments et éléments nutritifs, rend la tâche difficile. Afin de surmonter cette difficulté, des relevés sur le terrain, une caractérisation de la variabilité spatiale du P par géostatistique, une quantification de son hétérogénéité, et une modélisation hydrologique avec SWAT furent entrepris. Une étude géostatistique approfondie des propriétés du sol fut suivie par l'utilisation de SWAT pour prédire le ruissellement, et les charges en sédiment et phosphore total (TP).  Des relevés pédologiques entrepris durant les étés de 2011 et 2012 permirent de mesurer les propriétés physiques et chimiques des sols. Une analyse par variogramme caractérisa la variabilité spatiale de la teneur en P du sol (TSP). Le krigeage ordinaire (OK) servit à l'estimation de la TSP à des sites non-échantillonnés. Etant donné l'effet de lissage de l'OK, certaines valeurs élevées furent sous-estimées, tandis que certaines petites valeurs furent surestimées. Comparé au OK, la simulation séquentielle gaussienne (SSS) permit d'évaluer l'incertitude et fournit de meilleures estimations pour les sites non-échantillonnées. Les régions en deçà du seuil auquel le P a le potentiel de se déplacer jusqu'au cours d'eau après une pluie, et les facteurs topographiques qui y sont liés furent identifiés. L'incertitude des paramètres de variogramme (palier, pépite et portée) fut évaluée dans un cadre hiérarchique bayésien, permettant une analyse plus approfondie de la complexité et de l'hétérogénéité des données de TSP pouvant être attribués à l'utilisation des terres. Des moyennes a posteriori, avec intervalle de crédibilité de 95%, furent générées pour les paramètres de variogramme et les valeurs de TSP. Une technique d'analyse en composantes indépendantes (ICA), surmonta le problème d'inverser une matrice lors de la co-simulation, et servit à la décomposition de variables géochimiques corrélées dans l'espace. Cette méthode fut éprouvée pour trois variables corrélées, soit le magnésium, le calcium et le fer. Les propriétés du sol mesurées et requises par SWAT furent régionalisées et groupe en utilisant un algorithme de régionalisation avec groupement et partitionnement sous contraintes (REDCAP). Cinq cartes furent crées selon que le territoire fut partitionné en 5, 10, 15, 20 ou 24 parties. Chacune de ces cartes différa en son hétérogénéité, et chacune servit comme donnée d'entrée à une configuration particulière de SWAT.  Les débits moyens mensuels et les charges en sédiment et phosphore totales mesurés entre avril 2001 et décembre 2002 servirent à évaluer la performance du modèle avant et après son étalonnage. Le fait qu'aucune des cinq configurations (partitions de la carte d'entrée) du modèle ne se démarqua, s'explique par le fait que la méthode des numéros de courbe du Soil Conservation Service, servant à simuler le ruissellement, ne permet pas de retenir de petites mais importantes différences des propriétés physiques des sols. Dans le bassin versant étudié, l'utilisation d'une résolution (nombre de régions) plus élevée avec le modèle SWAT n'améliora ni la prédiction des débits moyens mensuels, ni celle des charges en sédiment et phosphore total. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chandra A. Madramootoo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h2855.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82kb65d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Hydrology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bp91x"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Economic disparities and intensifying burden of neglected tropical diseases</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Silva, Guilherme</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the interaction between economic disparities and the burden of neglected tropical diseases through a multi-layered study of international agreements, mostly the Trade Related Aspects of Intellectual Property (TRIPS), the health structure in developing countries and the manner in which intellectual property rights relate to the right to health in poor countries. By shedding light to this interaction, it will be demonstrated that small attention and resources is attributed to neglected tropical diseases. The predominance of the interests of affluent economic stakeholders over the reality of a substantial part of population of the world (either infected or at risk) is determined by virtue of limited access to drugs in developing countries, elevated out-of-pocket health expenditures by the poorest of the poor and inefficient/insufficient management of public funds for healthcare. This thesis challenges the current allocation of material and immaterial resources to attenuate the burden of neglected tropical diseases, as part of the right to health, as a way of bringing about more development and well-being to these populations.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire analyse l'interaction entre les disparités économiques et le fardeau des maladies tropicales négligées à travers une étude multi-niveaux d'accords internationaux, principalement les Aspects des Droits de Propriété Intellectuelle Qui Touchent Au Commerce (ADPIC), la structure de santé dans les pays en développement et la manière dont les droits de propriété intellectuelle se rapportent au droit à la santé dans les pays pauvres. En mettant en lumière cette interaction, il sera démontré que peu d'attention et de ressources est attribué aux maladies tropicales négligées. La prédominance des intérêts des acteurs économiques prospères sur la réalité d'une partie importante de la population mondiale (soit celle qui est infectée ou celle qui est à risque) est déterminée en vertu de l'accès limité aux médicaments dans les pays en développement, des coûts élevés de dépenses de santé par les plus pauvres et la mauvaise gestion et l'inefficacité / l'insuffisance des fonds publics pour la santé. Ce mémoire remet en cause la répartition actuelle des ressources matérielles et immatérielles pour atténuer le fardeau des maladies tropicales négligées, dans le cadre du droit à la santé, comme un moyen d'amener plus de développement et de bien-être à ces populations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Richard Gold</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000335q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bp91x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab27740014"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Force development during and after muscle length changes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Minozzo, Fabio</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Muscles are the motors of human movement. The most commonly accepted theory of muscle contraction, the "crossbridge theory", was postulated by A.F Huxley in 1957, and since then it has been widely accepted to model and explain how a muscle contracts. However, some phenomena are still not fully understood in the framework of the crossbridge theory, including the effects of muscle stretching and shortening on force production. More specifically, there is still controversy in the literature about the mechanisms responsible for the increase in force observed during and after stretch, and the decrease in force observed during and after shortening. The goal of the studies presented in this thesis was to investigate the mechanisms responsible for changes in force during and after length changes to test the following hypotheses: (i) force development during stretch is caused by crossbridges in a pre-powerstroke state, (ii) force development during shortening is affected by biasing crossbridges into pre-powerstroke, (iii) force enhancement after stretch is due to an increase in the number of attached crossbridges, (iv) force enhancement after stretch is caused by half-sarcomere non-uniformities, (v)  force enhancement after stretch is caused by stiffening of non-contractile proteins induced by Ca2+, and (vi) force depression after shortening is caused by a decrease in the number of attached crossbridges.   In order to achieve this goal, we developed four studies.  First we investigated the mechanisms of force development (i) during stretch, and (ii) during shortening separately. We then investigated the link between the changes in force during length changes with the changes observed after length changes (iii). These three studies were performed with skinned muscle fibres from the rabbit psoas muscle. Finally, we investigated in details a potential mechanism for the residual force enhancement observed after stretch using a new preparation that we developed in our laboratory – isolated half-sarcomeres (iv). Our results suggest that (i) the force increase during stretch is largely caused by crossbridges in a pre-powerstroke state, (ii) the force decrease during shortening is related to the engagement of pre-powerstrokes only at the initial, rapid phase of force change, (iii) force enhancement after stretch is caused by an increase in the number of crossbridges attached to actin, half-sarcomere non-uniformities, and titin stiffening upon Ca2+ activation, and (iv) force depression after shortening is caused by myosin crossbridge deactivation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les muscles sont les moteurs du mouvement humain. La théorie la plus communément reconnue de la contraction musculaire, "théorie des pontages croisés", mis en avant par AF Huxley en 1957, est depuis largement utilisée comme model d'explication afin de démontrer comment un muscle se contracte. Toutefois, certains phénomènes ne sont pas encore entièrement compris dans la structure de cette théorie, notamment les effets d'étirement et de raccourcissement du muscle sur la production de la force. D'ailleurs, il existe toujours une controverse dans la littérature sur les mécanismes responsables de l'augmentation de la force observée pendant et après l'étirement, et la diminution de la force observée pendant et après le raccourcissement. L'objectif des travaux présentés dans cette thèse est d'étudier les mécanismes responsables des changements au niveau de la force pendant et après une modification de la longueur du muscle afin de tester les hypothèses suivantes: (i) le développement de la force au cours de l'étirement est causé par les pontages croisés en pré-course de puissance, (ii) le développement de la force au cours du raccourcissement est affecté par la polarisation des pontages croisés en pré-course de puissance, (iii) l'augmentation de la force après étirement est due à une augmentation du nombre de pontages croisés attachés, (iv) l'augmentation de la force après étirement est causée par les  non-uniformités du demi-sarcomère, (v) l'augmentation de la force après étirement est causée par le raidissement des protéines non contractiles induites par le Ca2+, et (vi) la diminution de la force après raccourcissement est provoquée par une diminution du nombre de pontages croisés attachés. Dans le but d'atteindre cet objectif, nous avons élaboré quatre études. D'abord, nous avons étudié séparément les mécanismes de développement de la force (i) au cours de l'étirement, et (ii) au cours du raccourcissement. Ensuite, nous avons étudié le lien entre les changements de la force observés pendant et après une modification de la longueur du muscle. (iii). Ces trois études ont été réalisées à l'aide de fibres musculaires provenant du psoas du lapin. Enfin, nous avons étudié en détail un mécanisme potentiel pour l'augmentation de la force résiduelle observée après étirement en utilisant une nouvelle préparation développée en laboratoire - demi-sarcomères isolés (iv). Nos résultats nous amènent à penser que (i) l'augmentation de la force durant l'étirement est en grande partie causée par les pontages croisés dans un état de pré-course de puissance, (ii) la diminution de la force au cours du raccourcissement du muscle est lié à l'engagement de la pré-course de puissance,  seulement au moment de la phase initiale rapide du changement de la force, (iii) l'augmentation de la force après étirement est provoquée par une augmentation du nombre de ponts fixés à l'actine, des non-uniformités du demi-sarcomère et du durcissement de la titine sur l'activation du Ca2+, et (iv) la diminution de force après raccourcissement est causée par la désactivation du pontage croisé de myosine.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dilson Rassier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053k580.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b27740014</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r441b"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Precoding designs in multiuser multicell wireless systems: competition and coordination</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nguyen, Huu Ngoc Duy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans un système multicellulaire, la réutilisation universelle des fréquences peut être utilisée dans un réseau de cellules voisines pour une efficacité spectrale supérieure. Cependant, la réutilisation universelle des fréquences provoque de l'interférence intercellulaire (ICI) sévère, qui peuvent nuire à la performance globale du système, en particulier dans les stations mobiles (MS) qui se trouvent dans la périphérie de la cellule. Pour contrer activement l'ICI, la norme de communication sans fil émergente préconise le concept de coordination multicellulaire informée d'interférence. Connu comme coordonnée de transmission/réception multipoint (CoMP), ce nouveau paradigme permet au système multicellulaire de contrôler activement et même de profiter de l'ICI. L'objectif de cette recherche est d'étudier les méthodes de précodage dans le système multicellulaire multiutilisateur avec CoMP. Plus précisément, cette étude examine les diverses techniques de précodage et développe des algorithmes peu complexes et distribués afin de concevoir des précodeurs optimaux qui minimisent soit la puissance d'émission ou maximisent le débit cumulé des systèmes CoMP. De plus, cette recherche apporte des perspectives et des connaissances nouvelles pour le système CoMP où les interactions entre les stations de base coordonnées sont caractérisées en deux modes de fonctionnement: le mode informé d'interférence (IA) et le mode coordination d'interférence (IC).Dans le mode IA, le système multicellulaire est en état de compétition puisque chaque BS adapte égoïstement ses stratégies de précodage en conséquence de l'ICI. Naturellement,le mode IA représente un jeu non coopératif stratégique (SNG) dans lequel les stations de base sont les acteurs rationnels, qui tentent de maximiser une certaine utilité pour leurs MSs connectées. Ce mémoire caractérise le SNG disputé entre les stations de base en examinant l'existence et l'unicité d'un point de fonctionnement stable du système, qui correspond à un équilibre de Nash (NE) du jeu multicellulaire. La convergence vers le NE et son efficacité sont ensuite soigneusement analyées.Dans le mode IC, les systèmes multicellulaires sont censés être en coordination puisque les transmissions de la BS sont coordonnées afin de maximiser conjointement le gain de performance de CoMP. L'optimalité et la mise en oeuvre décentralisée sont des considérations fondamentales pour la conception de précodages sous le mode IC. Dans ce mémoire, nous proposons des conceptions de précodage multicellulaires qui maximisent conjointement la somme pondérée du débit (WSR) du système multicellulaire coordonné. En raison de la non-convexité des problèmes d'optimisation WSR, nous nous concentrons sur le développement de techniques d'approximation convexes à faible complexité pour les décomposer en une série de problèmes convexes simples, qui peuvent être résolus de façon distributive avec la transformation locale au niveau de chaque cellule coordonnce. Les résultats de simulation montrent une amélioration significative des performances en termes de puissance d'émission et de somme des débits réalisables par le mode IC sur le mode IA.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In a multicell system, universal frequency reuse can be employed in a network of neighboring cells for higher spectral efficiency. However, universal frequency reuse comes at the price of severe inter-cell interference (ICI), especially at cell- edge mobile stations (MS), which may effectively impair the overall system performance. To actively deal with the ICI, the emerging wireless communication standard advocates the concept of interference-aware multicell coordination. Known as coordinated multipoint transmission/reception (CoMP), the new paradigm allows the multicell system to actively control and even take advantage of the ICI. The objective of this research is to study the precoding perspectives in the multiuser multicell system with CoMP. Specifically, this research examines various precoding techniques and develops low-complexity and distributed algorithms in designing optimal precoders that either minimize the transmit power or maximize  the sum-rate of the CoMP systems. In addition, this research brings new perspectives and understanding to the CoMP system where the interactions among the coordinated BSs are characterized under two operating modes: interference aware (IA) and interference coordination (IC).Under the IA mode, the multicell system is said to be in competition where each BS selfishly adapts its precoding strategies accordingly to the ICI. Naturally, the IA mode represents a strategic noncooperative game (SNG) with the BSs being the rational players, who try to maximize a certain utility for their connected MSs. This work characterizes the SNG played among the BSs by examining the existence and uniqueness of a stable operating point of the system, which is corresponding to a Nash equilibrium (NE) of the multicell game. The convergence to the NE and its efficiency are then thoroughly analyzed.Under the IC mode, the multicell systems are said to be in coordination where the transmissions from the BSs are coordinated to jointly maximize the performance gain of CoMP. Optimality and distributed implementation are key considerations for the precoding designs under the IC mode. In this work, we propose multicell precoding designs that jointly maximize the weighted sum-rate (WSR) of the coordinated multicell system. Due to the nonconvexity of the WSR optimization problems, we focus on the development of low-complexity convex approximation techniques to decompose them into a sequence of simpler convex problems, which can be solved distributively with local processing at each coordinated cell. Simulation results show significant performance improvements in terms of transmit power and achievable sum-rate by the IC mode over the IA mode.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tho Le-Ngoc</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838389c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r441b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mn18c"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Computational models of human and animal larynx and vocal folds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bakhshaee, Hani</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Voice production is the result of the fluid-structure-interaction (FSI) of airflow through glottis and the vocal folds. The physics of the voice production consists of the geometry of the vocal folds and larynx, the aerodynamics of the airflow within larynx, and mechanical properties of the vocal folds. Through these physical aspects of voice production, engineering analyses can contribute to voice research. Creation of patient-specific computer models of the vocal folds and larynx may be considered as one of the main contributions of engineering studies in voice research.  Person-to-person differences in voice parameters are considered in patient-specific models and as a result, they have high potential for clinical applications. In this dissertation, the aforementioned physical aspects of voice production were studied through the creation of patient-specific geometries, numerical analyses on glottal airflow, and investigation of the vocal folds' strain-stress field during oscillation. To address the geometry parameters, the patient-specific three-dimensional (3D) geometries of the vocal folds, larynx, and laryngeal cartilages (i.e., thyroid, cricoid and arytenoid) were built. Morphometric measurements were performed and the obtained results were compared to the existing cadaver data. Low discrepancies between these measurements indicate the feasibility of using Computed Tomography (CT) scan data for creation of 3D models. General laryngeal cartilage models were created while preserving all the biomechanically important morphometric features. A methodology to create accurate geometries of the vocal folds with desired glottal angles was introduced based on mapping high-speed digital imaging (HSDI) data with that from Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI).   To address the fluid dynamics of voice production, the quasi-steady approximation in glottal airflow simulations was investigated in a two dimensional (2D) driven model. The surface area of the model was kept constant to avoid volume variations. Two-dimensional dynamic simulations of airflow through an idealized glottal orifice with moving walls were performed. A series of steady flow simulations was then performed using vocal fold configurations and boundary conditions that instantaneously coincide with data from the dynamic simulations. Aerodynamic parameters such as fluid flow rate, normal pressure on the vocal folds, shear stress on the glottal walls, and orifice discharge coefficients were compared between the dynamic and static simulations and similarities and differences were discussed. Three-dimensional simulations of the glottal airflow within patient-specific geometries were performed. One of the models was for a healthy subject and the second model was a postsurgical geometry from a patient with cancer. The effects of the geometry differences on the aerodynamic parameters such as orifice discharge coefficient and flow resistance were shown and discussed. To investigate the 3D nature of the glottal airflow, a 2D simulation was conducted in a computational domain made from a frontal CT scan image. The 2D results were compared to the corresponding slice in the 3D simulation. Significant differences between 2D and 3D simulations were observed in orifice discharge coefficients, jet flow deflection, and secondary flow, highlighting the importance of using realistic 3D models for glottal airflow simulations.To address the mechanical properties of the vocal folds, the deformation field on the superior visible surface of the vocal folds was captured in the excised larynx experiments using Digital Image Correlation (DIC). The initial pre-phonatory strain was measured using a dissection protocol and added to the relative strain obtained during the vocal folds' vibration to calculate the net strain. Kinematics of the vocal folds' oscillation was compared to that of synthetic models and similarities and differences were discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La production de la voix résulte de l'interaction fluide-structure entre l'écoulement d'air dans la glotte et les cordes vocales. La physique de la production de la voix comporte trois aspects principaux que sont respectivement la géométrie des cordes vocales et du larynx, l'aérodynamique de l'écoulement d'air et les propriétés mécaniques des cordes vocales. Ces trois aspects de la production vocale se situent dans le cadre de l'ingénierie. La création de modèles numériques de cordes vocales et de larynx spécifiques à l'individu peut être vue comme une contribution majeure pour l'analyse technique dans la recherche sur la voix. Ces modèles ont beaucoup d'intérêt pour les applications médicales et thérapeutiques parce qu'ils prennent en compte la variation des propriétés des tissus et de la géométrie entre chaque individu. Dans cette thèse, trois aspects de la production vocale ont été pris en compte : la création de modèles géométriques propres à chaque individu, l'analyse numérique de l'écoulement glottique et la recherche des relations entre les déformations et les contraintes au sein des cordes vocales au cours de la vibration.Afin d'obtenir des paramètres géométriques, des modèles numériques de cordes vocales, du larynx et des cartilages laryngés ont été conçus en trois dimensions et pour chaque patient. Des mesures morphométriques ont été réalisées et comparées à des données ex-vivo. La faible divergence entre ces mesures a permis de valider l'utilisation de la tomographie par rayons X pour la création de modèles 3D. Des modèles standards de cartilages laryngés furent créés tout en conservant les caractéristiques biomécaniques importantes. Une méthode basée sur la mise en correspondance de données d'imageries haute vitesse (HSDI) et d'Imageries par Résonnance Magnétique (IRM), a été introduite pour créer des géométries précises des cordes vocales avec le contour glottique souhaité. La dynamique des fluides lors de la production vocale a été étudiée en utilisant une approximation quasi-statique de l'écoulement glottique dans un modèle 2D. La surface du modèle était fixée constante afin d'éviter des variations de volume et éliminer ainsi la création de sources monopôles parasites. Les simulations dynamiques à deux dimensions de l'écoulement de l'air ont alors été réalisées à travers une glotte idéale aux parois mobiles. Une série de simulations d'écoulement statique étaient alors réalisées en utilisant les configurations de cordes vocales ainsi que les conditions aux limites qui coïncidaient avec les données provenant des simulations dynamiques au même instant. Les paramètres aérodynamiques tels que le débit du fluide, la pression normale aux cordes vocales, la contrainte de cisaillement sur les parois glottiques, le coefficient de perte de charge ont été comparés et discutés pour les simulations dynamiques et statiques.Des simulations 3D de l'écoulement glottique ont été réalisées pour chaque modèle individuel. Une des géométries étaient considérée comme saine et la seconde correspondait à la géométrie post-chirurgicale pour un patient atteint d'un cancer. Les effets des différences géométriques sur les paramètres aérodynamiques tels que le coefficient de perte de charge dû à un changement de section et la résistance à l'écoulement ont été mis en valeur et discutés.Afin de caractériser les propriétés mécaniques des cordes vocales, le champ de déformation de la surface supérieure et visible des cordes vocales d'un larynx excisé a été mesuré à l'aide d'une technique de corrélation d'image numérique (DIC). La déformation initiale de pré-phonation a été mesurée à l'aide d'un récent protocole de dissection et ajoutée à la mesure de déformation relative obtenue pendant la vibration des cordes vocales afin de calculer la contrainte totale. La cinématique de l'oscillation de ces cordes vocales a alors été comparée à celle de modèles synthétiques afin d'observer les similitudes et les différences.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rosaire Mongrain</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Luc Mongeau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vb973.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mn18c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bj285"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History and Classical Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The transformative power of Paideia or Paideia transformed? Paideutic culture during the Second Sophistic</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hunter, Darren</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'étude présentée ici discute la marchandisation et la décadence de l'Hellénisme et de la paideia durant la Seconde Sophistique. L'essence de l'Hellénisme a dû changer d'une ethnique ésotérique à une éthique universelle et inclusive. La compétition pour une audience obligea les sophistes à adopter un style de cours davantage théâtral, dans lequel les apparences et le divertissement étaient plus importants que l'enseignement. Le contexte socio-politique romain encouragea également la dissimulation en marchandant activement le rôle du sophiste et du philosophe. À la fin, les plaisirs superflus du spectacle permirent à un nouveau code moral d'adopter et d'adapter une éducation philosophique grecque, annonçant un lent déclin de l'Hellénisme ancien. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The present study contends with the commodification and decadence of Hellenism and paideia (intellectual and cultural sophistication) during the Second Sophistic. It charts the path that Hellenism took from an esoteric ethnic essence to a universal and inclusive ethic. Given this inclusiveness, anyone in the empire who adopted a paideutic character had the chance of becoming a "Hellene," especially sophists. Upon establishing an ecumenical Hellenism, competition for audiences with other forms of entertainment compelled sophists to adopt a more theatrical lecture style, where the aesthetics of performance were more important than edification, and laid the foundation for commodification. The socio-political Roman context encouraged dissembling, actively commodifying the role of the sophist and philosopher. In the end, the empty pleasures of spectacle allowed for a new moral code to adopt and adapt Greek philosophic education, heralding a slow decay of ancient Hellenism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anastassios Anastassiadis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225f49n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bj285</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History - Ancient</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698c03x"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Applications of second and third harmonic generation microscopy for tissue imaging and malaria detection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ghattamaneni, Nageswara Rao</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le développement de la nouvelle technologie vise à faible coût des soins de santé avec un traitement dirigé. Dans cet effort, nous avons couplé deux technologies microfluidiques et optiques pour détecter l'infection du paludisme. Nous avons conçu et construit une plate-forme de diagnostic compact pour le paludisme. Très petite quantité (pour des micro litre) de sang a été utilisé comme il est analysé dans la puce microfluidique. Hémozoïne cristal, un sous-produit de pigment malarique produite troisième signal harmonique et notre système est très sensible à compter le nombre de particules lors de leur passage à travers le point du microscope. Le signal de spectacle du sang infecté bien définis variation de son contrôle. L'étude démontre détection rapide et sensible du paludisme. La force de la microscopie harmonique supérieur a également été appliquée pour étudier la structure de deux protéines d'élastine et de collagène dans cicatrices cordes vocales. Saine et marquée rat cordes vocales un mois et deux mois après la blessure ont été examinés dans diverses régions. Les résultats en corrélation avec l'infiltration de collagène au niveau du tissu cicatriciel. À partir des résultats de l'élasticité du tissu peut être déduite de la teneur en collagène dans le tissu.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The development of newer technology is aimed at low cost health care with directed therapy. In this effort we have coupled two technologies microfluidics and optics to detect the malaria infection. We have designed and built a compact diagnosis platform for malaria. Very small quantity (order of micro liter) of blood was used as it is analyzed in microfluidic chip. Hemozoin crystal, a byproduct of malaria pigment produced third harmonic signal and our system was very sensitive to count the number of particles as they pass through the focus of microscope. The signal from infected blood show well-defined variation from its control. The study demonstrates rapid and sensitive detection of malaria. The strength of higher harmonic microscopy was also applied to study the structure of two proteins elastin and collagen in scarred vocal folds. Healthy and scarred rat vocal fold one month and two month post injury were examined at various regions. The results correlate with the infiltration of collagen at scarred tissue. From the results elasticity of tissue can be deduced from collagen content in the tissue. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul Wiseman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712mb227.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698c03x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Optics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A41687m570"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spatial and temporal effects on molecular signaling networks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Naqib, Faisal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Il est connu que le moment de présentation des stimuli a un effet important sur la force de la mémoire formée. Un excellent modèle pour étudier ce phénomène est la synapse sensori-motrice des neurones de l'aplysie. Dans ce système, une stimulation séparée par des périodes de repos (applications espacées) conduit à des changements persistants au niveau de la force synaptique qui dépend de voies biochimiques différentes de celles qui se produisent lors d'une stimulation sans périodes de repos (applications continues). Récemment, il a été montré que dans les neurones sensoriels isolés, l'application de la sérotonine, qui est le neurotransmetteur impliqué dans l'induction de ces changements synaptiques, entraîne une désensibilisation de la réponse PKC Apl II d'une manière qui dépend du moment précis de la stimulation par la sérotonine. Nous avons développé un modèle mathématique de cette réponse afin de mieux comprendre comment les neurones traitent-ils la différence temporelle entre stimuli. Le modèle représente le trafic du récepteur de la sérotonine responsable de l'activation de PKC. Chaque composante du modèle a été développée progressivement et a été validé expérimentalement. Basée sur ce modèle, nous avons découvert deux éléments majeurs de la voie de signalisation médiatrice de désensibilisation de la PKC. Premièrement, nous avons découvert l'activité PKA conduit également à une augmentation du processus réversible de désensibilisation. Deuxièmement, nous proposons que le mécanisme permettant à la voie de signalisation de différencier l'effet de la sérotonine, dépendamment d'une application espacée ou une application continue, est largement déterminée par les taux de synthèse et de dégradation d'une paire de protéines hypothétiques, que nous nommerons AD et D qui régulent l'activité des récepteurs. Nous avons élargi le travail des neurones sensoriels isolés en observant la désensibilisation de la translocation PKC Apl II dans des co-cultures de neurones sensoriels et moteurs, où le neurone sensoriel forme une connexion synaptique avec le motoneurone. Nous avons constaté que la formation d'une synapse résulte d'un changement de la désensibilisation de la translocation PKC: les applications espacées de 5HT ne sont plus capables de causer une désensibilisation plus importante que celles des applications continues. Ceci peut signifier que, le neurone sensoriel a subi un changement durant la formation de synapses dans le réseau de signalisation régulant l'activation de la PKC. Pour expliquer ces changements, nous avons créé deux nouveaux modèles: l'un dédié aux corps cellulaires des neurones sensoriels co-cultivés avec des neurones moteurs et l'autre aux synapses de ces neurones. Ces nouveaux modèles ont été en mesure d'expliquer le changement dans la désensibilisation de la translocation de la PKC en pratiquant des changements dans les taux de synthèse et de dégradation des proteines AD et D.Le modèle de la translocation PKC Apl II a pu décrire les dynamiques biologiques sans prendre en considération la structure spatiale du système. Néanmoins, la géométrie d'un système peut avoir un impact significatif sur la résultante d'une des voies de signalisation. Ainsi, nous considérons le cas général d'une voie de signalisation ayant deux molécules de signalisation: une espèce activatrice et une espèce inhibitrice avec une rétroactivité négative, qui sont synthétisés dans des sites uniques et qui interagissent les uns avec les autres à travers un processus de diffusion. Les comportements dynamiques de ces systèmes dépendent des localisations spatiales des sites de synthèse. Dans un système de rétroactivité négative à deux sites, on trouve une dynamique à deux modes: point fixe et oscillations stables dont la fréquence peut être ajustée en faisant varier la distance entre les deux sites. Quand il y'a plusieurs sites de synthèse, nous avons constaté une dynamique plutôt diverse, incluant chaos, quasi-périodicité et instabilité.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Two areas that are particularly suited to mathematical modeling analysis are how molecular signaling pathways process the timing of stimuli and how spatial structure can influence a signaling pathway's dynamics. These topics are explored through specific examples. The timing of stimuli is known to affect the strength of memory formation. This phenomenon has been studied in the sensory-motor neuron synapse of Aplysia. In this system, training that is separated by rest periods (spaced training) leads to persistent changes in synaptic strength that depend on biochemical pathways that are distinct from those that are engaged when the training lacks rest periods (massed training). Applications of serotonin (5HT), the neurotransmitter implicated in inducing these synaptic changes, causes desensitization of PKC Apl II, in a manner that depends on the timing of 5HT stimulation; spaced applications of 5HT cause more desensitization than massed applications of 5HT. We developed a mathematical model of this response to gain insight into how neurons process the timing difference in stimuli. The model represents the trafficking of the 5HT receptor responsible for activating PKC Apl II. Each component of the model was developed incrementally and was experimentally validated. We discovered two major elements of the signaling pathway mediating PKC Apl II desensitization. First, we discovered that PKA activity leads to an increase in the reversal from desensitization. Second, we propose that the mechanism allowing the signaling pathway to differentiate spaced from massed applications of 5HT is largely driven by the rates of synthesis and degradation of a pair of hypothetical proteins, named AD and D, that regulate receptor activity. We further developed the isolated sensory neuron work by experimentally observing the desensitization of PKC Apl II translocation in co-cultured sensory and motor neurons. We found that the formation of a synapse results in a change in the desensitization of PKC Apl II translocation: spaced applications of 5HT no longer caused greater desensitization than massed applications. This finding implies that the sensory neuron has undergone a change during synapse formation in the signaling network regulating the desensitization of PKC Apl II. To explain these changes, we created two new models: one of the cell body of sensory neurons co-cultured with motor neurons and one of the synapses of these neurons. These new models were able to explain the change in desensitization of PKC translocation by making changes to the expression and activity of regulatory proteins. These models provide a signaling pathway mechanism for neurons to encode the timing of stimuli. The model of PKC Apl II desensitization was able to describe these signaling dynamics without taking into consideration the spatial structure of the system. However, the geometry of a system may have a significant impact on a signaling pathway's output. To examine this issue in more detail, we modeled the general case of a signaling pathway with two signaling molecules, an activating species and an inhibiting species forming a negative feedback, which are synthesized at unique sites and interact with each other through diffusion. The dynamical behaviors in these systems depend on the spatial locations of the synthetic sites. In a negative feedback system with two sites, we find two dynamical modes: fixed point and stable oscillations whose frequency can be tuned by varying the distance between the sites. When there are multiple synthetic sites, we find more diverse dynamics, including chaos, quasiperiodicity, and bistability. These studies propose a mechanism for signaling pathways to encode the timing of stimuli, and demonstrate the effects spatial structure can have on signaling output. Furthermore, they provide examples of the use of mathematical modeling in furthering our understanding of molecular signaling networks.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Edward Ruthazer</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Christopher Pack</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x716q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687m570</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zh794"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A longitudinal view of emotional vitality in caregivers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Edwards, Skye</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The management of post-stroke recovery has changed considerably in recent decades, with approximately 80% of individuals returning home and rehabilitating in the community made possible because of the support of family members to provide care to meet their daily needs.  Stroke caregivers are required to quickly learn rehabilitation and medical management techniques, while adjusting to changes in their relationships with the person who experienced the stroke. Unsurprisingly, stroke caregivers report high levels of stress and burden related to the deterioration of their own health status, social relationships, quality of life, and poor rehabilitation outcomes for the stroke survivor. Emotional vitality is an emerging concept characterized by a sense of positive energy and effective emotional regulation in order to remain interested, engaged and productive in life. While emotional vitality may serve as a critical buffer against caregiver strain, very little is known about what enables some caregivers to thrive and be emotionally vital in this role, and others to burnout.   This thesis was designed to contribute to the understanding of the caregiving experience by taking a longitudinal view of emotional vitality.The first three studies contributed to the development of a conceptual and measurement framework for caregiver emotional vitality that included five domains: i) physical health and well-being; ii) support and recognition from others; iii) engagement in meaningful activity; iv) mood regulation; and v) a sense of control/mastery of new skills. The fourth study contributed evidence towards the measurement properties of a set of 19 items that reflect the emotional vitality construct as it pertains to caregivers of stroke survivors.A final study was aimed at providing preliminary evidence for how this measure of emotional vitality behaved longitudinally. Specifically, the objectives were to (i) estimate the extent to which caregiver emotional vitality changes in the first caregiving year; and (ii) estimate the extent to which caregiver characteristics and the functional profile of the care recipient impacts a caregiver's emotional vitality in the first year. From a sample of 409 caregivers (mean age 59 years, SD 15), five trajectories of emotional vitality were identified. Most caregivers (4 trajectories representing 78% of participants) displayed low levels of emotional vitality that remained persistently low over time. The concordance between caregiver baseline levels of mastery and emotional vitality was fair (kappa=0.45). In summary, emotional vitality in caregivers was on average very low in the first caregiving year. Mastery may be a component cause of emotional vitality, lending support to the importance of the need for health professionals to incorporate assessment of caregiver emotional vitality and mastery throughout the caregiving experience. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Depuis les dernières décennies,  la gestion de la guérison suite à un accident vasculaire cérébral (AVC) a considérablement évolué. Approximativement, 80% des gens retournent à la maison et font leur réhabilitation dans la communauté. Ceci est rendu possible grâce au soutient des membres de la famille qui leur procurent des soins pour rencontrer leurs besoins quotidiens.  Les aidants naturels des personnes ayant eu un AVC doivent apprendre rapidement des techniques de réadaptation et de gestion des médicaments, tout en s'adaptant à des changements dans leur relation avec la personne ayant eu un AVC. Il n'est donc pas surprenant de voir chez ces aidants naturels un niveau de stress plus élevé. De plus, le fardeau lié à la détérioration de leur propre état de santé, de leurs relations sociales et de leur qualité de vie résulte souvent en de mauvais résultats de réhabilitation chez les survivants d'un AVC.La vitalité émotionnelle est un concept émergent caractérisé par un sentiment d'énergie positive et une régulation des émotions efficace afin de rester intéressé,  engagé et productif dans la vie. Alors que la vitalité émotionnelle peut servir de tampon contre la pression ressentie chez les aidants naturels, on en connait très peut sur ce qui permet à certains aidants naturels de réussir et être émotionnellement vital dans ce rôle et d'autres seront complètement épuisés. Le but de cette thèse est de contribuer à la compréhension de l'expérience des aidants naturels en prenant une vue longitudinale de la vitalité émotionnelle.  Les trois premières études ont contribué à l'élaboration d'un cadre conceptuel et de mesure pour la vitalité émotionnelle chez les aidants naturels. Ce cadre inclus cinq domaines : i) la santé et le bien-être physique ; ii) l'appui et la reconnaissance d'autrui ; iii) l'engagement dans des activités significatives ; iv) la régulation de l'humeur ; et v) le sentiment de contrôle/maîtrise de nouvelles compétences. La quatrième étude a contribué aux évidences des propriétés de mesure d'un ensemble de 19 items illustrant le concept de la vitalité émotionnelle en ce qui a trait aux aidants naturels des survivants d'un AVC.Une dernière étude a utilisé cette mesure afin (i) d'estimer la mesure dans laquelle  la vitalité émotionnelle chez les aidants naturels change dans la première année de soins; et (ii) d'estimer la mesure à laquelle les caractéristiques des aidants naturels ainsi que le profil fonctionnel du bénéficiaire des soins influencent la vitalité émotionnelle des aidants naturels dans la première année. À partir d'un échantillon de 409 aidants naturels (moyenne d'âge de 59 ans, SD=15), cinq trajectoires de vitalité émotionnelle ont été identifiées. La majorité des aidants naturels (quatre trajectoires représentant 78% des participants) a démontré un faible niveau de vitalité émotionnelle qui est demeuré bas au fil du temps. La concordance de départ entre le niveau de maîtrise et de vitalité émotionnelle chez les aidants naturels était bonne (kappa=0.45).En résumé, la vitalité émotionnelle chez les aidants naturels était en moyenne très faible dans la première année de soins. La maîtrise peut être une partie constituante de la vitalité émotionnelle. Ceci démontre l'importance et la nécessité que les professionnels de la santé intègrent dans leur évaluation la vitalité émotionnelle et la maîtrise des aidants naturels, et ce, tout au long de l'expérience de soins. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Susan Bartlett</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Nancy Mayo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mj791.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zh794</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Occupational Health and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pd97m"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of angiogenesis, breast cancer and inflammation by angiopoietin-1</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Echavarria, Raquel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Angiogenesis and inflammation are hallmarks of several pathologies including breast cancer. The angiopoietins and Tie receptors have emerge as alternative targets for therapeutical intervention due to their function as essential regulators of angiogenesis, vascular homeostasis and inflammation. Angiopoietin-1 (Ang-1), the main agonist of Tie-2 receptors, promotes vessel growth, inhibits inflammation and maintains vessel stability. Although important advances have been made in understanding the functions of Ang-1 in the vasculature the intracellular signaling pathways activated by Ang-1, as well as its role in breast cancer and inflammation, remain largely unexplored. Using human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs), we identified dual-specificity phosphatases (DUSPs) that negatively regulate mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK) signaling pathways activated by Ang-1. Specifically we found that Ang-1 increased the expression (mRNA and Protein), as well as the activity of DUSP1, DUSP4 and DUSP5. Knocking down these phosphatases using siRNA revealed that DUSP1 mainly inactivates p38, DUSP4 dephosphorylates ERK1/2, p38 and SAPK/JNK, and DUSP5 is ERK-specific. Furthermore DUSP1, DUSP4 and DUSP5 had distinct functions in Ang-1-dependent survival and migration of endothelial cells (ECs).Because of the importance of angiogenesis in tumor progression, we then investigated the influence of estradiol (E2) on the expression of angiopoietins in breast cancer cell lines. We found Ang-1 mRNA and protein expressions to be lower in estrogen receptor (ERα) positive cells than in ERα negative cells. Additionally, we observed that both tumor size and Ang-1 production were reduced in ERα+ cell-derived xenografts in mouse mammary pads when compared to those derived from ERα- cells; and this effect was inhibited when the mice were ovariectomized. Since a large portion of the genome is under the regulation of microRNAs (miRNAs), we hypothesized that Ang-1 induces the expression of miRNAs to protect the endothelium against E. Coli lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced inflammation. We found that treating HUVECs for 24h with Ang-1 reduced LPS-induced phosphorylation of p38 and SAPK/JNK, and the activation of nuclear factor kappa b (NF-B). Ang-1 also decreased the expression of pro-inflammatory cytokines, adhesion molecules and leukocyte adhesion in vitro. Our findings suggest that miR-146b-5p is induced by Ang-1 as a mechanism to control Toll-like receptor (TLR) 4 signaling and the expression of pro-inflammatory mediators by targeting the signaling proteins interleukin-1 receptor-associated kinase 1 (IRAK1) and TNF receptor-associated factor 6 (TRAF6). We conclude that Ang-1 induces the expression of DUSP1, DUSP4 and DUSP5 to coordinate its anti-apoptotic and migratory response. Ang-1 is also an important modulator of growth and progression of ERα- breast cancers. Finally, Ang-1 treatment antagonizes pro-inflammatory pathways activated by LPS through the induction of miR-146b-5p which targets the TLR signaling proteins IRAK1 and TRAF6.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'angiogenèse et l'inflammation sont caractéristiques de plusieurs pathologies, dont le cancer du sein. Les angiopoiétines et les récepteurs Tie ont émergé comme cibles d'intervention thérapeutique alternatives en raison de leur fonction de régulateurs essentiels de l'angiogenèse, de l'homéostasie vasculaire et de l'inflammation. L'angiopoiétine-1 (Ang-1), l'agoniste principal du récepteur Tie-2, favorise la croissance des vaisseaux, inhibe l'inflammation et maintient la stabilité vasculaire. Bien que des progrès importants aient été réalisés dans la compréhension des fonctions d'Ang-1 dans le système vasculaire, les voies de signalisation intracellulaires activées par Ang-1 ainsi que son rôle dans le cancer du sein et l'inflammation sont largement inexplorées.Utilisant des cellules endothéliales de veine ombilicale (CEVOH), nous avons identifié des phosphatases à double spécificité (DSPs) qui régulent négativement les voies de signalisation des protéines kinase activée par mitogènes (MAPKs) activées par Ang-1. Plus précisément nous avons trouvé que l'Ang-1 a induit l'ARNm, l'expression des protéines et l'activité de DSP1, DSP4 et DSP5. Réduire l'expression de ces phosphatases à  l'aide de ARNi a révélé que DSP1 inactive principalement p38, DSP4 déphosphoryle ERK1/2, p38 et SAPK/JNK et DSP5 est spécifique pour ERK. En outre DSP1, DSP4 et DSP5 possèdent des fonctions distinctes pour la régulation de la migration, la survie, la formation de tube capillaire et la perméabilité vasculaire dépendante d'Ang-1.En raison de l'importance de l'angiogenèse dans la progression tumorale, nous avons ensuite étudié l'influence de l'estradiol (E2) sur l'expression des angiopoiétines dans des lignées cellulaires du cancer du sein. Nous avons trouvé que le niveau de transcrits d'ARNm ainsi que l'expression protéique d'Ang-1 étaient réduits  dans cellules positives pour les récepteurs des œstrogènes (ER) par comparison aux cellules négatives pour ER. En outre, nous avons observé que la taille de la tumeur et la production d'Ang-1 étaient réduits dans de xénogreffes de tissu mammaire chez la souris dérivés de cellules ER+, par rapport à ceux issus de cellules ER. De plus cet effet est inhibé lorsque les souris sont ovariectomisées.Comme une grande partie du génome est sous le contrôle des microARNs (miARN), nous avons émis l'hypothèse que l'Ang-1 induit l'expression des miARNs pour protéger l'endothélium contre l'inflammation induite par le lipopolysaccharide (LPS) d'E. Coli. Nous avons constaté que le traitement de CEVOH pendant 24 heures avec Ang-1 réduit la phosphorylation de p38 et SAPK/JNK, ainsi que l'activation du facteur nucléaire kappa B (NF-B) induite par le LPS. Ang-1 a également diminué l'expression de cytokines pro-inflammatoires, des molécules d'adhésion et l'adhérence des leucocytes in vitro. Nos résultats suggèrent que miR-146b-5p est induit par l'Ang-1 comme un mécanisme pour le contrôle de la signalisation des récepteurs de type toll (TLR) et l'expression de médiateurs pro-inflammatoires, en ciblant les protéines de signalisation IRAK1 et TRAF6.Nous concluons que l'Ang-1 induit l'expression de DSP1, DSP4 et DSP5 à fin de coordonner son action anti-apoptotique et sa réponse migratoire et angiogénique. Ang-1 est également un modulateur important de la croissance et de la progression des cancers du sein ER-. Enfin, le traitement avec Ang-1 antagonise les voies de signalisation pro-inflammatoires par l'induction de l'expression de miR-146-5p, qui cible des protéines de la voie de signalisation TLR: IRAK1 et TRAF6.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sabah N. A. Hussain</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j225b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pd97m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4j03d3299"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Subgroup theorems in relatively hyperbolic groups and small- cancellation theory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bigdely, Hadi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the first part, we study amalgams of relatively hyperbolic groups and also therelatively quasiconvex subgroups of such amalgams. We prove relative hyperbolicityfor a group that splits as a finite graph of relatively hyperbolic groups with parabolicedge groups; this generalizes a result proved independently by Dahmani, Osin andAlibegovic. More generally, we prove a combination theorem for a group that splitsas a finite graph of relatively hyperbolic groups with total, almost malnormal andrelative quasiconvex edge groups. Moreover, we provide a criterion for detectingquasiconvexity of subgroups in relatively hyperbolic groups that split as above. As anapplication, we show local relative quasiconvexity of any f.g. group that is hyperbolicrelative to Noetherian subgroups and has a small-hierarchy. Studying free subgroupsof relatively hyperbolic groups, we reprove the existence of a malnormal, relativelyquasiconvex, rank 2 free subgroup F in a non-elementary relatively hyperbolic groupG. Using this result and with the aid of a variation on a result of Arzhantseva, weshow that if G is also torsion-free then "generically" any subgroup of F is aparabolic,malnormal in G and quasiconvex relative to P and therefore hyperbolically embedded.As an application, generalizing a result of I. Kapovich, we prove that for any f.g.,non-elementary, torsion-free group G that is hyperbolic relative to P, there exists agroup G∗ containing G such that G∗ is hyperbolic relative to P and G is not relativelyquasiconvex in G∗ .In the second part, we investigate the existence of F2 × F2 in the non-metric small-cancellation groups. We show that a C(6)-T(3) small-cancellation group cannotcontain a subgroup isomorphic to F2 × F2 . The analogous result is also proven in theC(3)-T(6) case.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans la premiere partie, nous etudions les amalgames de groupes relativement                          hyperboliques et egalement les sous-groupes relativement quasiconvexes de ces amalgames. Nous prouvons l'hyperbolicie relative pour un groupe qui se separe comme un graphe fini de groupes relativement hyperboliques avec des groupes d'aretes paraboliques, ce qui generalise un resultat prouve independamment par Dahmani,Osin et Alibegovic. Nous l'etendons au cas ou les groupes d'aretes sont totalaux, malnormal et relativement quasiconvexes. En outre, nous fournissons un critere de detection de quasiconvexite relative des sous-groupes dans les groupes hyperboliques qui divisent. Comme application, nous montrons la quasiconvexite locale relative d'un groupe qui est relativement hyperbolique a certains sous-groupes noetheriens et qui a une petite hierarchie. Nous etudions egalement les sous-groupes libres de groupes relativement hyperboliques, et reprouvons l'existence d'un sous-groupe libre, malnormal, relativement quasiconvexe F2 dans un groupe non- elementaire relativement hyperbolique G. En combinant ce resultat avec une variation sur un theoremede Arzhantseva, nous montrons que si G est aussi sans-torsion, "generiquement" tout sous-groupe de F2 est aparabolique, malnormal dans G et quasiconvexe par rapport a P. Comme application, nous montrons que pour tout groupe G non-elementaire, sans-torsion, qui est hyperbolique par rapport a P, il existe un groupe G∗ contenant G tel que G∗ est hyperbolique par rapport a P et G n'est pas quasiconvexe dans G∗. Dans la deuxieme partie, nous  etudions l'existence de sous-groupe F2 × F2 dans desgroupes a petite simplification. Nous montrons que les groupes C(6) ne peuvent pas contenir un sous-groupe isomorphe a F2 × F2 . Le resultat analogue est egalement prouve dans le dossier C(3)-T(6) affaire.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daniel Wise</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397c642.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d3299</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az316q4864"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Poly (ADP-ribose) glycohydrolase (PARG) is a new therapeutic target for breast cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lovato, Amanda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Breast cancer is a heterogeneous disease, but is invariably associated with genome wide deregulation of transcription. The silencing of tumor suppressor genes (TSGs) in particular is thought to be an early, initiating event in many cancers. While re-expressing these genes is a clinically relevant goal, the development of therapeutics targeting the reactivation of TSGs has been hampered by a lack of understanding of the mechanisms responsible for TSG silencing. Recently, however, we have described a novel means through which several TSGs become silenced in cancer, which may highlight new therapeutic targets. This involves the epigenetic regulatory factor Ctcf which is critical for maintaining transcriptional activation and organizing chromatin at several TSG loci. In cells where these TSGs are silenced, the DNA binding of Ctcf to these TSGs is lost. This lack of DNA binding is associated with a loss of the post-translational modification by poly(ADP)ribosylation (known as PARylation). Aberrant dePARylation of Ctcf is associated with breast cancer progression, underscoring the importance of this Ctcf post-translational modification. We have novel data indicating that the dePARylating enzyme Parg is overexpressed in cancer. We hypothesize that inhibition of Ctcf PARylation by Parg disrupts normal epigenetic patterns at TSGs leading to subsequent gene silencing. We propose to examine the impact of Parg overexpression on the epigenetic programming and expression of Ctcf target genes, as well as the proliferation of breast epithelial cells. To determine the relevance of Parg in breast cancer, we have accumulated evidence from bioinformatics sources and through our own experimentation revealing an enrichment of Parg in a significant proportion of breast cancers. For instance, we have evidence from the Oncomine database and the UCSC Cancer Genome Browser that Parg is overexpressed at the mRNA level in 30-50% of breast cancers. Likewise, at the protein level, higher Parg expression is found in breast cancer cell lines compared to untransformed cell lines and is found to be enriched in more aggressive stages of a mouse tumor model. This is complemented with clinical breast tissue samples showing overexpression of Parg protein in breast cancer.In support of clinical data, we have generated Parg-overexpressing Mcf10a cells to assess the role of this protein in mediating cellular transformation. Interestingly, Parg overexpression induced cells to shift from an epithelial morphology to a mesenchymal one. This was met with a decrease in the rate of proliferation in vitro. The expression of the Parg transgene, however, was quickly lost and alludes to a significant role for Parg in cellular biology.   Overexpression studies were complemented with drug and knockdown studies. This work illustrated that a shRNA knockdown of Parg was met with a significant decrease in cell growth. Similar results were obtained for cells treated with the Parg inhibitor, tannic acid. Use of this drug caused a decrease in the repressive histone mark H3K27me3 which we believe may restore the expression of silenced TSGs. Likewise, tannic acid induced DNA damage foci over the course of long treatments with the drug, suggesting that DNA damage, too, may contribute to the decrease in cellular proliferation observed. Ultimately, this work provides evidence for a therapeutic benefit of targeting Parg in breast cancer.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le cancer du sein est une maladie hétérogène, invariablement associée à une perturbation de l'expression génique. Le silençage des gènes suppresseurs de tumeurs (GST) est l'un des phénomènes jouant un rôle lors de l'initiation du cancer. Si la réactivation de l'expression de ces gènes est une stratégie attractive sur le plan clinique, la mise au point de traitements efficaces a été entravée par la compréhension insuffisante des mécanismes responsables du silençage des GST. Récemment, de nouveaux mécanismes régulant le silençage des GST dans le contexte du cancer ont été décrit, ce qui pourrait conduire à l'identification de nouvelles cibles thérapeutiques. Un des exemples concerne la protéine CTCF, un facteur essentiel au maintien de l'organisation de la chromatine et de l'activité transcriptionnelle à de nombreux loci du génome. Dans des cellules où des GST sont « silencés », la capacité de liaison de CTCF proche de ces gènes est perdue. La perte de cette liaison est due à l'abrogation d'une modification post-traductionnelle sur CTCF : la poly-(ADP)-ribosylation (aussi appelée PARylation). Selon notre hypothèse, l'inhibition de la PARylation de CTCF par l'enzyme PARG, responsable de la déPARylation, perturbe les patrons de modification épigénétiques normaux des GST, ce qui aboutit au silençage de ces gènes. Nous nous proposons d'analyser l'impact de la surexpression de PARG dans le cadre du cancer du sein sur la programmation des modifications épigénétiques et l'expression de gènes cibles de CTCF, ainsi que sur la prolifération des cellules épithéliales mammaires.Dans un premier temps, nous avons recueilli des données de sources bio-informatiques et de nos propres expériences, et nous avons pu observer une surexpression de l'ARNm de PARG dans 30 à 50% des cas de cancer du sein (UCSC Cancer Genome Browser et Oncomine). De plus, les niveaux protéiques de PARG sont plus importants dans les lignées cellulaires de cancer du sein par rapport aux lignées cellulaires non transformées. Dans un deuxième temps, nous avons utilisé la lignée MCF10A (immortalisée mais non transformé) pour générer une lignée cellulaire surexprimant PARG afin d'évaluer le rôle de cette protéine dans la transformation cellulaire.  Nous avons pu observer que les cellules surexprimant PARG étaient passées d'une morphologie épithéliale à une morphologie mésenchymateuse, et  que leurs vitesses de prolifération avaient diminué. L'expression du transgène PARG a toutefois été rapidement perdue, ce qui laisse entrevoir le rôle significatif de PARG en biologie cellulaire.Dans un troisième temps, nous avons voulu observer les effets de la perte de PARG sur des lignées de cancer du sein en utilisant soit une drogue (acide tannique : TA) soit la technique des shARNs.  Par ces deux méthodes, nous avons montré que la déplétion de PARG (ou inactivation) ralentie significativement la prolifération des cellules cancéreuses. De plus, le traitement avec l'acide tannique conduit d'une part à la formation de nombreux foyers de dommages à l'ADN, et d'autre part à la diminution de la marque répressive H3K27me3, ce qui pourrait conduire à la réexpression de GST. Enfin, ce travail permet de mettre en avant le potentiel de PARG comme cible thérapeutique  dans le traitement du cancer du sein.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael Witcher</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p8090.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q4864</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>