<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p963d"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Subject of her knowledge : landscape of story/layers of word</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Goudreau, Estelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The CUSO-WID project has been providing credit and training to rural women's groups which perform economic activities in Northern Ghana. Based on the theory of empowerment elaborated by Paulo Freire (and Henry Giroux), this research evaluates the knowledge acquired, and the behavior adopted by women participating in this project. It also identifies the possible internal and external factors which have had an impact upon knowledge acquisition. The analysis is qualitative in approach. However, we have also used a quantitative approach when answers provided by participants were compared with other women's groups. The research results demonstrate that participants of the CUSO-WID project have acquired more knowledge than the non-participants with regard to the use of agricultural technologies. These changes in behavior are related to the capital invested in that activity. Significant changing behavior has been observed in savings, diversification of activities and group organization. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>CUSO-WID est un projet qui accorde du crédit sous forme de prêts, et qui dispense de la formation a des groupes de femmes de milieux ruraux du Nord-Ghana pratiquant une activité génératrice de revenus.La présente étude traite des connaissances acquises par ces femmes et des changements de comportement reliés à la formation reçue. Nous avons aussi relevé les facteurs internes et externes susceptibles d'avoir influence l'acquisition de connaissances. Notre analyse s'appuie sur la théorie du pouvoir telle qu'élaborée par Paulo Freire et reprise par Henry Giroux. Notre approche méthodologique est essentiellement qualitative. Cependant, nous avons utilisé des données quantitatives lorsque les réponses fournies par les participantes pouvaient être comparées a celles d'autres groupes de femmes (étrangères au projet). Les résultats de notre recherche démontrent que les participantes ont acquis plus de connaissances que les autres en ce qui a trait a l'utilisation de technologie agricoles. Les changements de comportement relevés alors le sont dans la mesure ou un apport de capital extérieur est insuffle dans le travail. […] Les changements de comportement les plus significatifs ont été note aux plans de l'épargne, de la diversification des activités entreprises, et de l'organisation du groupe.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ghosh, Ratna</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h59z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p963d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ghana -- Economic conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rural women -- Ghana</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cd200"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Subject of her knowledge : landscape of story/layers of word</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Goodman, Gayle E. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thesis draws on knowledge in the fields of psychology, literary criticism, semiotics, philosophy, women's studies and education to study the semantic landscape of the word. This semantic landscape, and some of its layers, are revealed in the stories we write, hear and speak. Since the stories in our lives and the development of semantic knowledge about the word interweave both dialectically and dialogically, -the thesis foregrounds the growth of semantic knowledge in the socio- cultural contexts of the narratives of ordinary persons. The argument will centre on the primary experience of narrative in the process of making meaning of the word, a process which transforms both self and culture.Since the word can be seen as a phenomena that is socio- cultural and ideological, both the living subjects in the thesis and the subjectivity of the ways in which they construct meanings in the landscape of story and word are presented as an ethnography of speech. The ethnographic paradigm used in these chapters will frame the word in its day- to- day life, showing it to be central to constructions of Self and Other. It is these constructs, or concepts of self- in- world, which frame what we come to know about language, story and pedagogy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jackson, Nancy</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Dillon, David</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Beer, Anne</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mitchell, Claudia</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p054p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cd200</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Semantics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Word (Linguistics)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1z40kw16k"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Franz Rosenzweig’s notes to poems by Jehuda Halevi : speech-thinking applied</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Galli, Barbara E</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans "Das neue Denken", l'essai complémentaire à l'étoile de Rédemption, Franz Rosenzweig dit que ses Notes à la poesie de Jehuda Halevi donnent un exemple de !'application pratique de sa méthode philosophique: la pensée du langage. La question que nous posons ici est toute simple: comment les Notes illustrent-elles la pensée du langage? Le présent ouvrage commence par une traduction des Notes vers l'anglais, suivie d'une analyse de la pensée du langage. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In "Das neue Denken," the supplementary essay to The Star of Redemption, Franz Rosenzweig states that his Notes to the poetry of Jehuda Halevi provide anexample of the practical application of his philosophic method, simply: speech-thinking. The question posed here is How do the Notes exemplify speech-thinking? Following a translation of the Notes into English, an analysis of speech-thinking is undertaken. In this analysis we examine Rosenzweig's philosophy of translation, his concept of a universal language, and finally, since speech-thinking involves belief in God, we enquire into religious experience. Based upon this analysis, an attempt is then made to answer the question and to consider speech-thinking as a possible genre for doing philosophy. The concluding chapter tries to locate Rosenzweig in the various contexts ranging from his lifetime to the present.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McLelland, Joseph</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r734.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kw16k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Translating and interpreting</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rosenzweig, Franz, 1886-1929</dc:subject><dc:subject>Prayer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gw01s"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intellectual property and competition law : a comparative approach EEC and USA</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lobelson, William J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les monopoles octroyés par les droits de propriété intellectuelle sont-ils en conflit avec les politiques de concurrence qui visent, sinon à éliminer, tout au moins à limiter les monopoles? Cette question a fait l'objet d'un grand nombre de polémiques et de commentaires. Le débat est en vérité empreint d'une grave confusion: les monopoles découlant des droits de propriété intellectuelle sont des monopoles légaux, et non économiques, qui ne menacent donc pas la liberté de concurrence sur les marches. De plus, si l'on raisonne à long terme, on ne peut éviter de constater que les droits de propriété intellectuelle visent en fait les mêmes objectifs que les politiques de concurrence, à savoir la protection des marches contre les actes de concurrence déloyale et le bien-être des consommateurs. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Are the monopolies afforded by intellectual property rights in conflict with competition policies that aim at eliminating, or at least limiting monopolies ? That question has generated much controversy and commentary. Indeed, the debate neglects an important distinction: the monopolies resulting from intellectual property rights are legal ones, not economic monopolies, and therefore they do not jeopardize free market competition. Besides, from a long term view, intellectual property rights tend to achieve the same objectives as those of competition policies, namely the protection of markets against unfair competition and consumers' welfare. […]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4307072.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gw01s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Intellectual property -- European Economic Community countries</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intellectual property -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antitrust law -- European Economic Community countries</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahh63sz32m"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis and properties of poly (2,6-diarylphenylene ether)s</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yang, Hu, 1961-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des modifications sont apportées au poly(diphényl-2.6-phénylène éther) (P30) afin d'atteindre des températures de fusion réduites et pour accéder des thermoplastiques moulables au point de fusion.Pour la préparation des polymères dérivés du P3O avec les structures variées systématiquement, on a synthétisé une serie de monomères qui possedent divers fonctionnalités apportées au diphényl-2,6-phénol. Plusieurs procédures de synthèse des monomères sont examinées et varient selon les groupes fonctionnels désires. De ces monomères on a préparé les homopolymères et copolymères correspondant et on a fait l'étude de leur propriétés. La réduction du point de fusion et la rétention de cristallinité ont été réalisées comme l'indiquent certaines propriétés de ces polymères. Les relations entre structure et propriétés sont décrites. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Modifications of poly(2,6-diphenylphenylene ether) (P30), to attain reduced melting temperatures and melt processible thermoplastics, are described. In order to prepare a series of P30 polymers with systematically varied structures, a series of substituted 2,6-diphenylphenol monomers with corresponding structural variations are synthesized. Several possible procedures for monomer synthesis are examined depending on the substituents to be introduced. The corresponding homopolymers and copolymers are prepared from these monomers and their properties are examined. The desired reduction in melting points and retention of crystallinity in some of the resulting polymers have been realized. The structure-property relationships are discussed. It is found that fluoro substitution on the polymers significantly depresses the crystallinity and melting temperatures in the P30 polymer derivatives. These effects have been further studied by synthesizing a series of systematically fluoro-substituted P30 polymers and determining their properties. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hay, Allan S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r0822.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sz32m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n5717"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Nursing</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of communication style and empathy on self-disclosure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Woo, Nancy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examined the relationship between nurses' communication style (person-centeredness vs. position-centeredness), patients' perception of nurses' empathy and patients' self-disclosure. Based on symbolic interaction theory, it was hypothesized: 1. patients' self-disclosure would be directly related to person-centeredness and perceived nurse empathy; 2. patients' perception of nurse empathy would be more important in predicting patient self-disclosure than communication style. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette étude examine la relation entre le type de communication des infirmières (centrée sur la personne versus centrée sur la position), perception de l'empathie des infirmières par les clients et auto-révélation des clients. Basé sur la théorie de l'interaction symbolique, il est présenté l'hypothèse suivante: 1. l'auto-révélation des clients est directement relié a l'approache centrée sur la personne et la perception de l'empathie des infirmières; 2. la perception de l'empathie des infirmières par les clients serait d'autant plus importante par la prédiction de l'auto-révélation du client que le type de communication. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pepler, Carolyn</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fk383.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n5717</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Self-disclosure</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw37639311"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Patterns of retinal ganglion cell loss after interruption of the adult rat optic nerve at different distances from the eye</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Villegas-Perez, Maria Paz</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Using the fluorescent marker dil (1, 1 '-dioctadecyl-3,3,3' ,3'- tetramethylindocarbocyanine perchlorate) as a retrogradely transported persistent label for retinal ganglion cells (RGCs), I have studied RGC survival between 15 days and 12 or 20 months after interruption of the optic nerve (ON) at each of four different distances between the eye and the optic chiasm in adult rats. The patterns of decreases in RGC densities varied with the different levels of axotomy; there was an early rapid loss of cells whose severity increased the closer the lesion was to the eye, and a later more protracted loss of cells that occurred at a similar rate for all distances of ON interruption and continued for the period of the study.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>En utilisant le dil (1, 1 '-dioctadecyl-3,3,3',3'-tetramethylindocarbocyanine perchlorate) comme marqueur fluorescent persistent transporte de façon rétrograde dans les cellules ganglionnaires de la rétine (GCR) de rats adultes, j'ai étudié la survie des CGR de 15 jours à 20 mois après l'interruption du nerf optique a quatre niveaux différents entre l'œil et le chiasma optique. Le profil de la diminution de la densité des CGR a varié en fonction du niveau auquel l'axotomie a été effectuée. On observe d'abord une diminution rapide et précoce des densités des CGR dont le degré de sévérité est d'autant plus important que la lésion est proche de l'œil. On observe ensuite une diminution plus lente des densités des CGR qui est indépendante du niveau auquel on effectue la lésion et se poursuit pour toute la durée de la période étudiée.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Aguayo, Albert J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w9809.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w37639311</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Optic nerve</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dr942"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Transcriptional regulation of the vibrio harveyi lux operon</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Swartzman, Elana Esther</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The molecular mechanisms involved in transcriptional regulation of the Vibrio harveyi lux operon were examined. The 5 ' and 3 ' ends were mapped and two new lux genes, luxG and luxH, were discovered upstream of the termination site. A transcription terminator that was able to function bidirectionally was located downstream of only one new lux gene, luxG, in the lux operon of Vibrio fischeri. Differences in transcriptional start sites were detected when the V. harveyi lux mRNA was mapped in vivo and in vitro. Studies using recombinant Escherichia coli containing the V. harveyi lux operon demonstrated that the promoter in E. coli mapped to the same site as found in vitro. The in vivo start site mapped to 26 base  pairs (bp) and the in vitro start site mapped to 123 bp upstream of the initiation codon of the luxC gene. The expression of luxR in recombinant E. coli shifted the start site from position -123 to position -26, demonstrating that LuxR is required for transcriptional activation of the -26 lux promoter. […]  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The molecular mechanisms involved in transcriptional regulation of the Vibrio harveyi lux operon were examined. The 5 ' and 3 ' ends were mapped and two new lux genes, luxG and luxH, were discovered upstream of the termination site. A transcription terminator that was able to function bidirectionally was located downstream of only one new lux gene, luxG, in the lux operon of Vibrio fischeri. Differences in transcriptional start sites were detected when the V. harveyi lux mRNA was mapped in vivo and in vitro. Studies using recombinant Escherichia coli containing the V. harveyi lux operon demonstrated that the promoter in E. coli mapped to the same site as found in vitro. The in vivo start site mapped to 26 basepairs (bp) and the in vitro start site mapped to 123 bp upstream of the initiation codon of the luxC gene. The expression of luxR in recombinant E. coli shifted the start site from position -123 to position -26, demonstrating that LuxR is required for transcriptional activation of the -26 lux promoter. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Meighen, Edward</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jt59x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr942</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lux operon</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78tf40q"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanism of elimination of trypanosoma musculi : characterization of protectgive antigen(s) and of effector cells mediating cure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shaw, Karen Ting-Ying</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'élimination immunitaire de Trypanosoma musculi est stimulée par un mécanisme cellulaire anticorps-médiateur cytotoxique incluant l'anticorps IgG2a, la composante complément C3, ainsi qu'une cellule effective inconnue. Dans la détermination de la population de cellules effectives responsables de l'élimination par médiateur, une réduction sélective des cellules de Kupffer, leucocytes et des plaquettes n'a pas augmenté l'habilite à éliminer les trypanosomes in vivo. La présence d'une cellule radioresistante responsable de l'élimination des parasites, fut démontrée tors d'expérimentations in vitro sur l'activité trypanocide du sang complet obtenu de souris irradiées. L'activité de la cellule radioresistante était perdue in vitro alors que cette même activité était maintenue in vivo. Pour démontrer l'habilite potentielle d'une variété de cellules du système vasculaire (macrophages, neutrophiles, plaquettes et cellules endothéliales) à démontrer leur activité trypanocide, ces cellules furent incubées avec du plasma immunise et des parasites. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Immune clearance of Trypanosoma musculi occurs by an antibody-mediated cellular cytotoxic mechanism involving IgG2a antibody, complement component C3 and an unidentified effector cell. To determine the identity of the effector cell responsible for mediating clearance of the parasite, mice were selectively depleted of Kupffer cells, leukocytes and platelets. In each case, the ability to clear trypanosomes in vivo was unaffected. Although trypanosome clearance remained intact in irradiated mice, whole blood from these animals was unable to kill the parasite in vitro in the presence of immune plasma and C3. The trypanocidal activity of various cells of the vascular system (macrophages, neutrophils, platelets and endothelial cells) was examined in vitro and all the cell types were found to have the ability to kill the parasite. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kongshavn, P. A. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc94k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tf40q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Antigens</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dj00c"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>New algorithms for classification and identification of the vestibulo-ocular reflex</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rey, Claudio Gustavo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>New models for the vestibule-ocular reflex (VOR) are presented. The VOR is a reflex whose goal is to stabilize the visual line of sight. The VOR is characterized by constantly switching between two response modes: one mode (called slow phase) is compensatory to head movements (stabilization) while the other (called fast phase) is used to quickly reposition the eye in its orbit. The study of the function of the VOR is the study of its behaviour during the slow phase response. Current models of the VOR isolate the slow phase response to study its properties. lt has, however, become apparent that the fast phase response affects the slow phase dynamics and that it is therefore incorrect to consider the slow phase response as a separate isolated dynamic system. New models are presented that account for a fast phase mediated component in the slow phase dynamics.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>De nouveaux modèles du reflexe vestibulo-oculaire (VOR) sont présentés. Le VOR est un réflexe dont l'objectif est de stabiliser la ligne visuelle de la vue. La charactéristique du VOR est d'avoir deux modes de réponse entre lesquels il change constamment: le premier (appelé la phase lente) qui est une compensation aux movements de la tête (stabilisation) tandis que le deuxième (appelé la phase rapide) a pour objéctif de vite repositionner l'oeil dans son orbite. L'étude de la fonction du VOR est l'étude de son comportement pendant la phase de réponse lente. Les modèles utilisés jusqu'à l'heure actuel isolent la réponse de la phase lente afin d'étudier ses propriétés. Cependant, il est clair maintenant que la phase de réponse rapide affecte la phase lente et il est, des lors, incorrect de considérer la phase lente comme un système dynamique isole. De nouveaux modèles sont présentés pour la dynamique de la phase lente qui tiennent compte de la présence de la réponse de la phase rapide. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Galiana, H. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw92m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dj00c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Vestibulo-ocular reflex</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67jt60p"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The efficacy of mental practice as a function of task complexity in an ecologically valid setting</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Phillips, Geoffrey Douglas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude vise à comparer les effets de l'exercice mental sur la maitrise d'une tache de motricité grossière A trois niveaux de complexité. Soixante étudiants en éducation physique ont été répartis au hasard entre trois niveaux de complexité d'une tâche de motricité grossière de gymnastique exécutée soit mentalement, soit dans des conditions contrôlées, (groupe témoin). L'analyse de variance 2 X 3 (conditions X complexité) des notes de rendement moyennes des sujets n’a révélé aucune interaction significative à l'appui de l'hypothèse. Toutefois, on a constaté des effets importants et significatifs tant pour ce qui est du niveau de complexité que pour les conditions témoins, ainsi que des tendances conformes aux hypothèses. Même si les notes de rendement moyennes des groupes affectés à l'exercice mental étaient toujours plus élevés que les notes du groupe témoin, les écarts n’étaient significatifs qu'aux niveaux les plus élevés de complexité. Cela semble indiquer que l'efficacité de l'exercice mental augmente avec le degré complexité de la tâche.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The purpose of the study was to compare the effects of mental practice on the acquisition of a gross motor skill at three different levels of complexity. Sixty physical education students were randomly assigned to one of three levels of task complexity in either a mental practice or a control condition for the acquisition of a gross motor gymnastics task. The results of the 2 X 3 (condition X complexity) analysis of variance for subjects’ mean performance scores failed to produce a significant interaction to substantiate the hypothesis. However, there were significant main effects found for both complexity and condition, as well as trends in the hypothesized direction. Although the mean performance scores for mental practice always appeared greater than for the control, the difference was only significant at the highest level of complexity. This would seem to indicate that as the task became more complex, the efficacy of mental practice increased. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Neil, Graham I.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pq36m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt60p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sports -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s255v"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Louisiana Tuition Assistance Plan : the effects and implications of a state tuition waiver</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Painter, Thornton S., Jr.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse a pour but d'examiner le Louisiana Tuition Assistance Plan (LTAP), un programme d'exemption de frais de scolarité post-secondaire offert aux étudiants de revenus faibles ou moyens dans l'état de la Louisianne. Les aspects suivants de ce programme sont examinés: le contexte danslequel le programme fût introduit, les caractéristiques du LTAP ainsi que les forces qui l'ont façonné, et les effets du LTAP sur le système d'éducation en Louisianne. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the Louisiana Tuition Assistance Plan (LTAP) , a college tuition waiver program offered to low and middle income students in the state of Louisiana. A program evaluation methodology was used to examine the following aspects: the context into which the LTAP was introduced, the LTAP's characteristics and the forces that shaped them, and the effects the LTAP has had on education in Louisiana. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burgess, Donald</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xh18t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s255v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>College costs -- Louisiana</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anz806230k"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Performance evaluation of error control methods with noisy feedback : the generalized type-II hybrid ARQ scheme and the selective repeat ARQ scheme on Markov and Gilbert Channels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oduol, Vitalice K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le bruit affecte tous Ies canaux de communication, ce qui se traduit par des erreurs dans les messages transmis. Il y a donc un besoin pour les techniques de correction d'erreurs. À quelques exceptions, près toutes les techniques de correction d'erreurs qui utilisent la rétroaction dans le canal font l'hypothèse que celui ci est sans erreurs pour en faire l'analyse. Cette thèse étudie l'effet de la rétroaction dans le canal sur deux techniques de correction d'erreurs, la méthode hybride ARQ type II généralisé et la méthode du ARQ sélectif. On y présente des expressions pour l'efficacite du debit, la probabilité des erreurs non-détectées, des méssages reçues correctement et des paquets perdues. On y montre que le bruit dans la boucle de contre-réaction réduit l'efficacité du debit, cause des pertes de paquets et augmente le nombre d'erreurs non-détectées. Des moyens sont présentés pour réduire la dégradation causée par les erreurs dans le canal avec rétroaction. Des résultats obtenues par simulation sont présentés. À partir des résultats, et de l'analyse de ceux-ci, on conclut que le canal avec rétroaction a un effet important sur la performance des méthodes de type ARQ et que ceci doit être pri en compte afin d'évaluer de façon réaliste leurs performance. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Noise affects all channels used for communication, causing errors in the transmitted messages, thereby creating the need for error control. With a few exceptions, the methods of error control that use a feedback channel have assumed this channel to be error-free in their analysis. This thesis considers the effect of feedback channel errors in two methods of error control, the Generalized Type-ll Hybrid ARQ Scheme and the Selective ARQ Scheme. Expressions are derived for the throughput efficiency, the probabilities of undetected error, correct delivery, and packet loss. It is found that noise in the feedback channel lowers the throughput efficiency, causes the loss of packets, and increases the number of undetected errors. Methods are suggested for reducing the degradations caused by feedback channel errors. Simulation results are also provided. From the results and the analysis, the conclusion drawn is that feedback channel noise has an important effect on the performance of ARQ schemes, and should be taken into account to provide a more realistic assessment of their performance. </dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d662p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806230k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>School children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Classroom environment</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adf65v999f"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of age, gender, and socio-economic status on the ability of children to adapt to classroom situations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nathan, Oded</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigated the effects of age, gender, and socio-economic status (SES) on the ability of children to adapt to classroom situations. Forty-eight children from three elementary schools, ages 8.0 to 11.11 years, and equally distributed between gender and SES served as subjects. The Vineland Adaptive Behavior Scale- Classroom Edition (Sparrow, Balla, &amp; Cicchetti, 1985) was administered to all subjects. The results of a factorial analysis of variance revealed significance. Similarly, F-tests measuring the relationships of age, gender, and SES to domain and subdomain Q scores yielded significance. On the basis of the results reported, the differences found due to the contribution of age to domain and subdomain scores can be accounted for as differences in maturity and motivation. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette recherche a eu pour but d'étudier selon l’âge, le genre et le statut économique, les facultés d'adaptation des enfants en milieu scolaire. Quarante-huit enfants de 8.0 à 11.11 ans ont été selectionnés dans trois écoles élémentaires. Ils ont été repartis selon leur genre et statut économique. Chaque enfant a rempli le questionnaire Vineland Adaptive Behavior Scale, édition de classe (Sparrow et al., 1985). Après analyse a Analyse Factorielle de Variance ont donné des résultats significatifs. Également, des testes F mesurant la relation entre l’âge, le genre, et le statut économique ont rélevé des effets significatifs. Les effets dus à l’âge sont attribués à la maturité et la motivation des enfants. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Talley, William M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945t291.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v999f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>School children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Classroom environment</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9306t161d"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Luminescence spectrosopy of Ei(III) in lanthanum magnesium aluminate, a solid state laser host</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nafi, Madjid Michael W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Laser induced luminescence of Eu(lll) in La 1-x Eu x MgAl11O19 (LMA) was studied for three different concentrations (x-0.1, 0.01 and &lt;0.01) at various temperatures between SK and 300K. The polarization of this luminescence was investigated in the highest concentration sample. Results show that Eu(lll) occupies three distinct substitutional sites associated respectively with: the Beevers-Ross position (BR, D3h), the mid-Oxygen position (mO, C2v) and a third "intermediate energy" position. The BR site was identified for the first time in these samples. Luminescence peaks of the 50~7F0,1 were assigned for the first time and the orientation of the principal axis of the three sites with rasped to c was determined. Excitation spectra recorded at low temperature for the three concentrations show that Eu(lll) is forced into the BR site as its concentration increases. An analysis of the phenomenological crystal-field parameters suggests that the "intermediate energy site" is mid-way between the BR and the mO sites.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Laser induced luminescence of Eu(lll) in La 1-x Eu x MgAl11O19 (LMA) was studied for three different concentrations (x-0.1, 0.01 and &lt;0.01) at various temperatures between SK and 300K. The polarization of this luminescence was investigated in the highest concentration sample. Results show that Eu(lll) occupies three distinct substitutional sites associated respectively with: the Beevers-Ross position (BR, D3h), the mid-Oxygen position (mO, C2v) and a third "intermediate energy" position. The BR site was identified for the first time in these samples. Luminescence peaks of the 50~7F0,1 were assigned for the first time and the orientation of the principal axis of the three sites with rasped to c was determined. Excitation spectra recorded at low temperature for the three concentrations show that Eu(lll) is forced into the BR site as its concentration increases. An analysis of the phenomenological crystal-field parameters suggests that the "intermediate energy site" is mid-way between the BR and the mO sites.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Simkin, D. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t445b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t161d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Magnesium</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axp68kj68x"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A biomechanical comparison between novice and elite ice hockey skaters</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mullen, Andrew J. </ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to document and compare the kinematics of the centre of gravity and the lower limbs in both the frontal and sagittal planes over the course of a maximal velocity skating step. Four elite and three novice skaters were filmed in orthogonal planes, at 80 frames per second over the course of a maximal velocity skating step. The results demonstrated a significantly different (p ~ 0.05) kinetic planar energy ratio between the subject groups. This suggests that the relationship of the frontal to sagittal plane energies over the course of the skating step may differ between the skill levels. In addition to this the frontal plane hip joint kinematics (angular velocity and displacement) were significantly greater (p ~ 0.05) for the elite skaters when compared with the novices. The sagittal hip joint kinematics demonstrated no significant differences between subject groups. Skating is a unique form of locomotion in which the only effective component of the push-off force is that which is occurring laterally. Both the planar kinetic energy ratios and the frontal plane hip joint kinematics suggest that elites ice skaters employ a different pattern of force application which has not been sufficiently elucidated in the coaching and training literature. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'objet de cette étude était de comparer les paramètres cinématique du centre corporal de masse et de I' articulation de la hanche propulsif sur le plan saggitale et frontale chez les patineurs des niveaux novice et élite. Huit sujets ont été assignes à un niveau d'habileté selon le niveau de compétition atteint. Les résultats d'une analyse préliminaire des temps d'exécution du coup de patin ont confirmé les classifications. Les résultats de l'analyse cinématographique révèlent un ratio entre l'énergie cinétique du plan saggitale et le plan frontale plus bas chez les patineurs du niveau élite. Ce phénomène indique une proportion plus basse d'énergie cinétique du plan sagittal, possiblement une indication d'une poussée dirige plus sur le plan frontale. Les résultats des analyses sur les paramètres de la hanche propulsif, démontrent que les patineurs élites, ont franchi une amplitude de mouvement plus élevé au niveau de la hanche et que se mouvement s'effectuait à une vélocité plus élevé. Les parametres de la hanche propulsif sur le plan saggitale n'ont démontré aucune différence. Les résultats de cette étude ont démontré que le coup de patin est une forme de locomotion humaine peu commun. En vertu des résultats obtenus, les patineurs du niveau élite ont une méthode d'exécution distingue qui pourrait s'appliquer à l'entrainement et l'enseignement, de ce mouvement.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236452s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj68x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Skating -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hockey players</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hockey -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698984q"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Secondary metabolite production using self-cycling fermentation (SCF)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McCaffrey, William Chessleigh, 1964-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Self-cycling fermentation (SCF) is a new method to cultivate synchronous populations of cells. The process has been successfully extended to encompass the fermentation of an eukaryotic microorganism, Candida bombicola. Metabolic events, which occurred during the resting phase of the microorganism, were incorporated into the control scheme. With this change, the new control scheme enabled the production of a biphasic secondary metabolite and was proven to be effective for the production of sophorolipid, an extracellular glycolipid produced by Candida bombicola. The effect of substrate on the production of the glycolipid was also investigated. An important discovery was that the self-cycling fermentation can be operated with a cycle time which is significantly longer than the doubling time. With relatively long periods of nutrient starvation added to each cycle, which are required for sophorolipid production, it is possible to maintain a constant doubling time and synchronous growth.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La fermentation auto-cyclique (F AC) est une nouvelle méthode pour cultiver des populations synchronisées de cellules. Le procédé a été étendu avec succès pour contenir la fermentation du micro-organisme eucaryotique, Candida bombicola. Les évènements métaboliques, qui surviennent pendent la phase repos du micro-organisme, ont été incorpores dans le système de contrôle. Avec cette modification, le nouveau système a permit la production d'un métaboliste secondaire et il fut prouvé effectif pour la production de sophorolipide, un glycolipide extracellulaire produit par Candida bombicola. L'effet du substrat sur la production du glycolipide a aussi été étude. Une découverte importante a été que la fermentation auto-cyclique peut être opéré avec un temps de cycle qui est, d'une manière significative, plus long que le temps de doublage. Avec des longues périodes de manque d'éléments nutritifs, requises pour la production de sophorolipide, il est possible de maintenir un temps de doublage constant et une croissance synchronisée. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cooper, D. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks777.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698984q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fermentation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acv43p055z"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Metaphor interpretation : the complementary contributions of pragmatics and the grammar</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Matthews, John S. (John Scott)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans ce mémoire de maitrise, on critique la spécificité~ qui est fréquentement attribuée a la métaphore en tant qu'objet de recherche linguistique. En particulier, on soutient que l'interprétation du langage métaphorique n'a besoin d'aucune machinerie cognitive que ne nécessite également l'interprétation du langage littéral. Après une revue sélective des littératures philosophique, linguistique et pragmatique, le Modèle de la Sélection des Traits pour l'interprétation du langage en général, et du langage métaphorique en particulier, est développé pour illustrer les mécanismes communs qui sous-tendent l'interprétation des deux types d'énonces. La conventionalité et la transparence sont proposés comme les variables importantes qui caractérisent l'interopérabilité des énonces métaphoriques individuels. On évalue le modèle et son mécanisme d'intégration du contexte a la lumière des études expérimentales qui examinent le traitement de la métaphore, de l'idiome et de l’ambigüité lexicale. On revoit la littérature peu abondante qui rapporte des troubles réflectifs du langage non-littéral après lésions cérébrales droites. Quelques explications sont alors offertes dans le cadre de notre modèle.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In this thesis the "special, status frequently assigned to metaphor as a focus of linguistic research is challenged. Specifically, I will argue that the interpretation of metaphorical language requires no cognitive machinery not also needed for the interpretation of literal language. Therefore, the Feature Selection Model for the interpretation of language in general, including metaphorical language in particular, will be developed in order to illustrate the common mechanisms underlying the interpretation of both utterance types. Conventionality and transparency are introduced as important variables in characterizing the interpretability of individual metaphorical utterances. The Feature Selection Model and its mechanism of context integration are evaluated against experimental studies examining the processing of metaphor, idiom and lexical ambiguity. The sparse literature that exists. Which reports the selective impairment of non-literal language following right hemisphere brain damage is reviewed and some speculative explanations are given in terms of the Feature Selection Model. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paradis, Michel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870z37c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p055z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Metaphor</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kd06d"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Perceptions of preservice education : a study of specialists in adapted physical education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Madden, John Brendan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to investigate the link between university preservice education in adapted physical education and job requirements when teaching in special schools. The relationship was tested through the use of a questionnaire. This instrument recorded the degree to which teachers felt specific teaching competencies were important in their teaching and also the degree to which competencies were perceived to have been covered, during university preservice education. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'objet de cette étude est d'enquêter le lieu entre la formation universitaire obtenue dans le domaine de l'éducation physique spécialisée, et les exigences de travail dans les écoles spécialisées. Un questionnaire fut utilisé pour examiner cette relation. Le questionnaire a mesure le niveau d'importance que les professeurs ont attribué à certaines compétences d'enseignement 1 ainsi que leur perception de l'emphase que chaque compétence a reçu à l'universités. […] </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, Greg</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05ff25g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kd06d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical education for children with disabilities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physical education and training -- Study and teaching (Higher)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343v30v"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"[[The]] Popes on sport"</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kardas, Raymond Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La réalité socioculturelle du sport exerce une influence énorme dans le monde actuel. Le sport subit grandement l'enquête et l'analyse de diverses sections de la société. La thèse présenté examine les enseignements des Papas sur le sport dans le cadre de l'époque moderne. Afin d'analyser et d'évaluer d'une manière efficace les réflexions papales sur le sport, le Chapitre Un examine la littérature qui traite du sport, en révélant ainsi les caractéristiques d'une approche conservatrice, libérale et radicale envers le sport. Ayant établi la grande porte de la typologie idéologique des communiques official des Papes sur le sport, le Chapitre Deux de l'étude fait la revue de l'histoire du sport dans la civilisation occidentale. Cette revue prétend que le sport au vingtaine siècle est un phénomène social sui generis, sépare des forme antérieures de sport en reflétant par ailleurs le caractère de modernité. Le sport mérite donc une nouvelle réflexion évaluative. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The socio-cultural reality of sport exerts a tremendous influence in the modern world. Sport is subject to a great deal of investigation and analysis by various segments of society. The thesis examines the teaching of the popes on sport against the background of the modern age. In order to effectively analyze and evaluate the papal reflections on sport Chapter One examines the critical literature dealing with sport thus revealing the characteristics of a conservative, liberal, and radical approach to sport. After establishing the significance of the ideological typology for the papal statements on sport Chapter Two of the study offers a review of the history of sport in Western civilization. This review argues that sport in the twentieth century is a social phenomenon sui generis, distinct from previous forms of sport while additionally reflecting the character of modernity. Therefore sport deserves new evaluative reflection. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baum, Gregory</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m644z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343v30v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sports -- Papal documents -- Bibliography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sports -- Religious aspects -- Catholic Church</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anp193c226"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"La passion mariale" dans le theatre français du XVe siècle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hitchin, Anna L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>On n'a pas encore étudié le personnage de "Notre Dame" dans les Passions du XVe siècle. Cette thèse vise à combler cette lacune. Nous espérons révéler le personnage de Marie tel qu’il aurait été compris par les spectateurs du moyen âge. L’image de la Vierge qui domine dans ces pièces est celle d'une femme souffrante, d'où le sujet de notre travail: la "passion" de Marie. Après avoir réfléchi aux rapports entre le péché et la "passion mariale", nous allons considérer le deuil de Marie dans le contexte des rôles différents qu'elle joue dans les pièces: la mariée, la mère, et la co-rédemptrice. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>So far, there has been no study devoted expressly to the Virgin Mary character in the French Passion Plays. This thesis aims to provide such a study, and through it, hopefully to reveal the Virgin character as a medieval audience would have appreciated it. The dominant image of Mary in these plays is that of a suffering woman. Therefore, accordingly, this thesis is an exploration of what we are calling Mary's "Passion". After some reflection on the place of sin in relation to her suffering, we consider Mary's grief in the context of her various roles within the plays: "bride", "mother" and "co-redemptrice". […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Di Stefano, Giuseppe</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kn08k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193c226</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mary, Blessed Virgin, Saint</dc:subject><dc:subject>French drama -- To 1500</dc:subject><dc:subject>Passion-plays</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atm70mx88m"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Climates of criticism : a dialectical conception of language in the Stevensian solar system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Heintzman, Andrew, 1967-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La poésie de Wallace Stevens est devenue centrale au développement de la théorie littéraire nord américaine. Depuis sa mort, son œuvre a commandé l'attention et informe les conceptions de plusieurs théoriciens importants. Cependant, malgré le degré d'attention critique portée à Stevens, on y remarque l'absence marquée de consensus sur quelque aspect de son œuvre. La critique littéraire de Stevens fait preuve de la même diversité et est aussi contradictoire que I' ensemble de la théorie littéraire elle-même. L'attention tellement variée qu'on a porté à l'œuvre de Stevens semble refléter les importantes divergences théoriques entre les diverses méthodologies employées pour expliquer, comprendre, et maitriser sa poésie. Ma thèse tente d'expliquer ses divergences dans le but d'illuminer, et la poésie de Stevens, et la théorie littéraire contemporaine. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The poetry of Wallace Stevens has become central to the development of North American literary theory. Since the time of his death his writing has commanded the attention, and informed the conceptions, of many important theorists. Despite the vast amount of critical attention paid to Stevens, however, there has been a striking lack of consensus about any aspect of his poetry. Stevensian criticism is as diverse and contradictory as the discipline of literary theory itself. The enormous variety of critical writing that Stevens has engendered seems to reflect important theoretical divergences between the methodologies that have been put to work in trying to explain, understand, and master his poetry. My thesis is an attempt to make sense of these divergences with the aim of shedding light on both Stevens' poetry and contemporary literary theory. </dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft84h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx88m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Stevens, Wallace, 1879-1955 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870z38n"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Subrogation and space insurance : a U.S. legal perspective</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guo, Liping</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The issue of subrogation in space insurance is one of the hotly debated topics in the space community. Some underwriters have tried hard to pursue the right of subrogation in order to get compensation from third-parties, in most cases the space products manufacturers. In this thesis, the doctrine of subrogation is examined and the possibility of applying this doctrine to space insurance is explored. Various legal bases in the jurisdictions of the United States, which might be used for compensation under subrogation, are discussed. The thesis also tries to trace the U.S. courts’ attitude towards subrogation and related issues in recent cases. After examining the present legal liability regime for space venture and U. S. policy of commercialization of space activities, a conclusion is made. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La question de la subrogation dans l'assurance spatiale est l'un des sujets les plus chaudement discute au sein de la communauté spatiale. Certains assureurs essayèrent énergiquement de poursuivre le droit de subrogation afin d'obtenir compensation de la part des tierces parties, pour la plupart les manufacturiers de produits spatiaux. Dans le cadre de cette thèse, la doctrine de la subrogation est examinée et la possibilité d'appliquer cette doctrine dans le domaine de l'assurance spatiale est explorée. Diverses bases légales dans les juridictions des États-Unis qui puissent être utilisées pour compensation sous la rubrique de subrogation sont discutées. La thèse tente aussi de tracer l'attitude des tribunes américaines envers la subrogation et des questions connexes pendant les années récentes. Après l'examen du régime actuel de responsabilité légale pour les entreprises spatiale et la politique américaine de commercialisation des activités spatiale, une conclusion est tirée. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bunker, Donald H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vk13p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870z38n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Satellite insurance -- Law and legislation -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Subrogation -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Satellite insurance -- United States</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795b03z"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Self-concept and second language acquisition in adult immigrant Latin American women : a model of intervention</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guanipa-Ho, Carmen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ce projet de recherche est une tentative pour : (a) explorer le concept de soi des femmes immigrantes latino américaines, (b) évaluer l'efficacité de l'atelier "Amélioration du concept de soi" qui a pour but d'améliorer le concept de soi des femmes immigrantes latino américaines au Québec et (c) établir l'influence du concept de soi sur les aptitudes à acquérir une seconde langue, chez les femmes immigrantes adultes. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The purpose of this research was an attempt to: a) explore the self-concept of Latin American women taking a second-language course, b) measure the effectiveness of an "Enhancing Self-Concept" workshop on developing a better self-concept, and c) establish the influence of self-concept on second-language acquisition in immigrant Latin American women. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Talley, William</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c973z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795b03z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Second language acquisition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Self-perception</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1j92g972v"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A minipig model for evaluation of the lower urinary tract</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guan, Zhichen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An animal model, using mini-pigs has been developed to study the pressure/flow relationships in normal, partially obstructed and de-obstructed animals, while awake and in the normal upright posture. This has been achieved by the use of subcutaneously implanted portacatheters into the bladder and peritoneal cavity to measure bladder (Pves) and abdominal pressure (Pabd) respectively and the use of a sling within a restraining cage to immobilise the animal. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Un modèle animal a été développé pour étudier les relations qui existent entre la pression et le debit urinaire chez des "mini-couchons" partiellement obstrues et désobstrués. L'étude a été faite lorsque ces animaux normaux étais réveillés et en position debout grâce à l'utilisation d’un « sling » à l’intérieur des cages pour immobiliser et soutenir les animaux. Un "portacath" a été implante sous-cutané avec des tubes en silastic dans la vessie et la cavité peritoneale pour mesurer la pression vesicale (Pves) et abdominale (Pabd). […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kiruluta, George</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Elhilali, Mostafa</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw83w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g972v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Urinary tract</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>