<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afb494c207"><ual:graduationDate>1932</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Botany</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cytological studies in the genus Hordeum</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Johnson, Robert Edward</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Barley is one of the most ancient of cultivated plants. Even in the accounts of the earliest historians barley is mentioned. Little is known of the ancient species, however, as the whole group is so much alike that they were classed as one, namely, "barley". As an example of this de Candolle (1882) says, the mention of the occurrence of "wild and cultivated barley" by Berosus, Moses, Chorene, Pansanias, Marco Polo, and more raecently Olivier, in a given country, proves nothing because they made no reference to the species to which they referred. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Huskins, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451m52c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494c207</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Grain</dc:subject><dc:subject>Botany</dc:subject><dc:subject>Botany, Economic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anv9355823"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Family Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Risk of hepatitis C virus transmission among people who inject prescription opioids: examining the contribution of patterns and contexts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Puzhko, Svetlana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction: Dans les pays développés, le virus de l’hépatite C (VHC) est principalement transmis par l’injection de drogues illicites. Durant la dernière décennie, une nouvelle population des personnes utilisatrices de drogues par injection (UDIs) – les injecteurs de médicaments opioïdes (MO) – a émergé au Canada et dans le monde. Or, les caractéristiques de ce nouveau groupe d’UDIs ont été peu étudiées. Décrire les injecteurs de MO et définir le lien entre l’injection de MO et le risque de séroconversion au VHC peut être utile pour développer des programmes spécifiques de prévention et de traitement. Objectifs: Les buts de l’étude étaient: 1)d’examiner les caractéristiques sociodémographiques, les patterns d’injection et les contextes de vie associés à l’injection de MO dans une cohorte d’UDIs à Montréal, 2)de comparer les taux d’incidence de VHC entre les injecteurs de MO et les IDUs qui ne s’injectent pas de MO, et 3)d’analyser le lien entre l’injection de MO, avec ou sans le co-usage d’autres drogues, et la séro-incidence au VHC. Méthodologie: Les données recueillies auprès d’UDIs participant à une étude prospective de cohorte (HEPCO, Montréal) ont été examinées. Les critères d’éligibilité incluent être âgé de 18 ans et plus, l’injection de drogues durant les 6 derniers mois et la résidence à Montréal. Les données ont été collectées entre 2004-2013 par le biais d’un questionnaire (administré par un intervieweur) et d’un prélèvement sanguin pour tester le VHC. Les données d’entrée ont fait l’objet d’une analyse transversale à l’aide des tests Chi-carré et T de Student. Un modèle de régression logistique a été appliqué pour identifier les facteurs en lien avec l’injection de MO. Les UDIs qui étaient séronégatifs au VHC à leur entrée dans l’étude ont été incluses dans l’analyse longitudinale. Des analyses de survie Kaplan-Meir et de régression Cox ont été menées pour examiner la relation entre l’injection de MO et l’intervalle de temps observé avant la séroconversion au VHC. Résultats: Analyses transversales. Parmi les 1243 UDIs qui ont participé à la Cohorte entre 2004-2011 (83.8% hommes; âge moyen: 38.2 ans), 380 (30.6%) se sont injecté des MO dans le dernier mois. Dans une analyse de régression multivariée, les caractéristiques et comportements suivants ont été indépendamment associés avec l’injection de MO: âge (Rapports de cote ajustés (RCA) par tranche de 5 ans: 0.79; 95% intervalle de confiance [95%IC]:0.7,0.9), co-usage d’héroïne injectée (RCA:3.03, [95%IC:2.2,4.2]) ou d’amphétamines non-injectées (RCA:1.84; [95%IC:1.2,2.9]) ou de tranquillisants (RCA:2.38; [95%IC:1.8,3.2]), conditions de logement instables (RCA:1.78, [95%IC:1.3,2.4]), injection dans un endroit public (RCA:2.03, [95%IC:1.5,2.8]) et séropositivité au VHC (RCA:1.56; [95IC:1.1,2.2]). Analyses longitudinales. Parmi les 356 (81.5% hommes; âge moyen: 34.7 ans) participants (séronégatifs au VHC à l’entrée dans l’étude, suivis entre 2004-2013), 123 (34,6%) ont rapporté l’injection de MO et 115 (32%) ont séroconverti. Les dyades de co-usage qui ont été associées au VHC comprennent: l’injection de MO avec l’injection de cocaïne (Rapport des risques instantanés (RRI):10.86,[95%IC:5.8,20.3] comparé à la consommation d’aucune de ces drogues) ou avec l’usage de crack/cocaïne fumée (RRI:4.08,[95%IC:2.5,6.7]) ou avec la prise de tranquillisants (RRI:4.09,[95%IC:2.5,6.6]). Dans une analyse multivariée, l’injection de MO a été indépendamment associée à l’infection au VHC. Les UDIs qui ont fait co-usage de ces trois drogues avec l’injection de MO ont présenté le risque le plus élevé de contracter le VHC. Discussion: Les stratégies de prévention et de réduction des méfaits pour les injecteurs de MO à Montréal devraient être adaptées pour les jeunes UDIs et aborder le co-usage de cocaïne injectée, de crack/cocaïne fumée et de tranquillisants non injectés. Les injecteurs de MO qui font co-usage de ces trois drogues devraient être des cibles prioritaires d’interventions.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introduction: In developed countries, Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) is mainly transmitted through illicit drug injection. Within the last decade, a new population of People Who Inject Drugs (PWID), namely Prescription Opioids (PO) injectors, has emerged both in Canada and worldwide. However, this new group of PWID has not been sufficiently studied. Characterizing PO injectors, and defining the association between PO injection and the risk for HCV seroconversion may be useful for developing specific HCV prevention and treatment programmes. Objectives: The study objectives were: 1) to examine sociodemographic characteristics, drug use patterns, injecting behaviors, and living contexts associated with PO injection in a cohort of PWID in Montreal, 2) to compare HCV incidence rates between PO injectors and non-PO injectors, 3) to examine the association between PO injection, with or without co-use of other drugs, and HCV seroincidence.Methods: Data collected from PWID, who participated in a prospective cohort study (HEPCO Cohort of Montreal), were examined. Eligibility criteria were age of 18 years old or over, drug injection in the previous 6 months, and current residence in Montreal. Data were procured in 2004-2013 by means of a validated, interviewer-administered questionnaire and blood testing for HCV and HIV antibody. Baseline data were assessed in a cross-sectional analysis by Chi-square and Student’s t tests. Logistic regression modeling was applied to identify the correlates of PO injection. HCV negative at baseline PWID were included in the longitudinal analysis. Kaplan-Meier survival and time-varying Cox regression analyses were conducted to calculate the relative rates of HCV seroincidence and examine the association between PO injection and time-to-HCV seroconversion. Results: Cross-sectional analysis. Of 1243 PWID who participated between 2004 and 2011 (83.8% males; mean age: 38.2 years), 380 (30.6%) reported PO injection in the past month. In a multivariate regression analysis, characteristics and behaviors independently associated with PO injection were age (adjusted odds ratio (aOR) by 5-year increment: 0.79; 95% confidence interval [95%CI]: 0.7,0.9), co-use of heroin injection (aOR:3.03, [95%CI: 2.2,4.2]) or non-injection amphetamines (aOR: 1.84; [95%CI: 1.2,2.9]) or non-injection tranquilizers (aOR:2.38, [95%CI: 1.8,3.2]), unstable housing conditions (aOR: 1.78, [95% CI: 1.3,2.4]), injecting in a public place (aOR:2.03, [95%CI: 1.5,2.8]), and HCV seropositivity (aOR: 1.56, [95%CI:1.1,2.2]). Longitudinal analysis. Of 356 participants (81.5% males; mean age: 34.7 years) who were HCV-negative at baseline and were followed up between 2004 and 2013, 123 (34.6%) reported PO injection, and 115 (32%) seroconverted to HCV. Co-use dyads associated with HCV were: PO injection with cocaine injection (crude hazard ratio (cHR): 10.86, [95%CI: 5.8,20.3] vs. use of neither drug), PO injection with crack/cocaine smoking (cHR:4.08, [95%CI: 2.5,6.7]), and PO injection with non-injection tranquilizers (cHR: 4.09, [95%CI: 2.5,6.6]). In a multivariate analysis, PO injection was independently associated with HCV infection. PWID who co-used all three drugs with PO injection had the highest risk of HCV acquisition. Interpretation: Comprehensive harm reduction and HCV prevention strategies for PO injectors in Montreal should address young PWID. In addition, addressing co-use of PO injection with cocaine injection, crack/cocaine smoking, or non-injection use of tranquilizers may also be beneficial. PO injectors who co-use all three drugs should be identified as high priority targets for interventions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gillian Bartlett-Esquilant</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Julie Bruneau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117r85f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv9355823</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Family Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac247dw09t"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of protein-based hydrogels as encapsulation matrices for Lactobacillus casei ATCC 393</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xu, Meng</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bio-based polymers have been a topic of high interest in the past decades due to their biocompatibility, biodegradability and their relative low toxicity. Proteins, polysaccharides and lipids are the main biological materials utilized for their synthesis. The diversity of the functional groups of proteins allows for a wide variety of chemical and physical linkages and structures. The subject of this thesis focuses on the synthesis and characterization of physically crosslinked protein-based hydrogels. These hydrogels have been utilized in the biomedical and food industry as they generally exhibit excellent biocompatibility and therefore can be used for applications such as tissue engineering and drug delivery. Moreover due to their high nutritional value and ability to form gels, protein-based hydrogels are highly used in the food industry.As a part of this thesis, the synthesis and characterization of physically crosslinked pea protein isolates-alginate (PPI-alginate) and canola protein isolates-alginate (CPI-alginate) hydrogels microspheres for encapsulation applications were performed.  In addition, the effect of extra polyelectrolyte complexation (PEC) with another biopolymer, chitosan, was also studied. The thermogravimetric analysis and the differential scanning calorimetry results showed that CPI microspheres have a similar thermal stability as PPI microspheres. The swelling tests showed that in general, CPI microspheres have a higher swelling capacity than PPI microspheres in all swelling media (distilled water, simulated gastric fluid (SGF) and simulated intestinal fluid (SIF)). Furthermore, degradation test were performed in simulated gastric fluid and simulated intestinal fluid media with enzymes to explore the effect of PEC on the stability of hydrogels. The results indicated that PEC had no influence on the stability of hydrogels in SGF but significantly delayed the degradation of hydrogels under SIF conditions. These findings suggest that PEC could be utilized to modify protein-alginate hydrogels to create matrices for prolonged release applications.The PPI-alginate hydrogel matrices were utilized in a subsequent study to encapsulate Lactobacillus casei ATCC 393, an acid sensitive probiotic strain. The goal of this study was to target applications related to the delivery of probiotics to the human gut. The PPI-alginate hydrogels were selected not only because the high nutritional value of PPI but also the due to the compatibility of PPI with the specific probiotic strain. A high encapsulation yield (85.69% ± 4.82) was achieved by using this matrix. Moreover, the L. casei loaded PPI-alginate hydrogel microspheres were freeze dried and tested for long term storage. A robust number (59.9 % ± 17.4) of viable cells was detected after 84 days of storage at -15 °C. Both the fresh microspheres and stored hydrogel microspheres have been tested in simulated gastrointestinal to verify the probiotics’ survival rate as well as their release rate. The L.casei in stored hydrogel microspheres were more sensitive to the acidic gastric conditions. However, both types of microspheres displayed significant protective effects. The release tests showed a rapid release of bacteria in the first 20 min of digestion. The complete release of L. casei from the matrices was observed 60 min after their contact with the SIF media.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les polymères bio-sourcés ont été un sujet de grand intérêt au cours des dernières décennies en raison de leur biocompatibilité, biodégradabilité et de leur faible toxicité. Les protéines, les polysaccharides ainsi que les lipides sont les principaux matériaux biologiques utilisés pour leur synthèse. La diversité des groupes fonctionnels des protéines permet une grande variété de liens physiques et chimiques permettant la formation d’une vaste gamme de structure. L'objet de cette thèse implique l’utilisation d’isolats de protéines dans la synthèse d’hydrogels réticulés physiquement. Les hydrogels dont la composante principale constitue les protéines sont utilisés dans l'industrie biomédicale puisqu’ils présentent généralement une excellente biocompatibilité et peuvent donc être utilisés pour des applications telles que l’ingénierie tissulaire ainsi qu’agent de libération contrôlé. De plus, en raison de leur haute valeur nutritive et de leur capacité à former des gels, ils sont abondamment utilisés dans l'industrie alimentaire.Dans le cadre de cette étude, des hydrogels micro-sphériques réticulés physiquement à base d’isolats de protéines de pois et d’alginate (IPP-alginate) ainsi que d’isolats de protéines de canola et d’alginate (IPC-alginate) furent synthétisés dans le but de les utiliser afin d’encapsuler des bactéries probiotiques. De plus, l'effet de la complexation polyélectrolyte (CPE) avec un autre biopolymère, la chitosane, a également été étudié. Les résultats obtenus par l'analyse thermogravimétrique ainsi que l’analyse calorimétrique différentielle à balayage ont montrés que les hydrogels synthétisés à partir de protéines de pois ont une stabilité thermique similaire à ceux ayant été synthétisés avec des protéines de canola. Par contre, les hydrogels synthétisés à partir de protéines de canola ont une capacité de gonflement à l’équilibre plus élevée que les hydrogels synthétisés à partir de protéines de pois et ce, dans tous les média testés (eau distillée, liquide gastrique simulé (LGS) et liquide intestinal simulé (LIS)). De plus, des enzymes furent ajoutés au LGS ainsi qu’au LIS afin d’effectuer des tests de dégradation. Lors de ces tests, il fut démontré que l’effet de la CPE est nul lors des essais dans le LIS mais retarde la dégradation dans le LGS. Ces résultats suggèrent que la CPE peut être utilisée afin de modifier les hydrogels à base de protéines et d’alginates afin de créer des matrices pour des applications nécessitant de la libération contrôlée.Des hydrogels à base de protéines et d’alginate ont été utilisées afin d’encapsuler des probiotiques (Lactobacillus casei ATCC 393). Les hydrogels IPP-alginate ont été choisis dus à la valeur nutritive des protéines de pois ainsi qu’à leur compatibilité élevée avec L.casei. Un rendement élevé d'encapsulation (85,69 % ± 4.82) a été réalisé à l'aide de ces matrices.  Après l’étape d’encapsulation, les matrices furent lyophilisées et entreposées afin de vérifier leur stabilité lors de l’entreposage à long terme. Un bon nombre de cellules viables (59,9 % ± 17,4) a été détecté après 84 jours de stockage à -15 °C.Les hydrogels non-lyophilisés ainsi que les hydrogels lyophilisés contenant des probiotiques ont été testés dans le liquide gastro-intestinal simulé pour vérifier le taux de survie des probiotiques ainsi que leur vitesse de libération. Les résultats ont montrés que le taux de survie de L.casei encapsulé dans les matrices lyophilisées est moindre dans le liquide gastrique simulé que lorsqu’encapsulé dans les matrices non-lyophilisées. Toutefois, les deux types d’hydrogels ont des effets protecteurs significatifs par rapport aux probiotiques non encapsulés. Les tests de libération contrôlés ont montré une libération rapide des bactéries dans les 20 premières minutes de digestion. La libération complète de L. casei par les matrices a été observée après 60 minutes après  leur contact initial avec le LIF.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marie-Josee Dumont</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd376046n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dw09t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bioresource Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62fc13h"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of fruit based products using extrusion-drying process for need applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chahal, Bavneet</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les préoccupations diététiques des consommateurs changent rapidement de l’emphase sur les aliments qui préviennent les déficiences nutritionnelles et autres maladies liées à l’alimentation vers des aliments qui préviennent les maladies chroniques à plus long terme. Le fait de consommer des aliments malsains cause deux problèmes très différents, d’un côté le manque d’éléments nutritifs et de l’autre, l’apparition de problèmes d’obésité et de maladies chroniques. Une solution possible à ce dilemme est la création d’aliments sains et pratiques. Le traitement par extrusion peut aider l’industrie alimentaire en créant des produits alimentaires qui sont pratiques et nutritifs en offrant la possibilité d’enrichir les aliments avec des fibres, protéines, antioxydants et vitamines. Cette thèse vise à développer des produits à base de fruits qui sont équilibrés sur le plan nutritif en utilisant le traitement par extrusion dans le but potentiel d’offrir des régimes ayant des demandes spéciales particuliers tels que les enfants souffrant de malnutrition et les patients atteints d'insuffisance rénale chronique.Des études sur la transformation par extrusion ont été réalisées afin de développer deux produits, la réglisse aux fruits et le gruau instantané, en utilisant la mangue et l’ananas comme ingrédients de base. Le modéle expérimental D-optimal mixture design a été choisi pour cette étude afin d’étudier l’effet des différents ingrédients fonctionnels sur les caractéristiques sensorielles et nutritionnelles du produit final. Le modéle expérimental a généré 16 combinaisons expérimentales, de plus, un mélange additionnel de contrôle a été formulé pour chacun des deux produits. La vitesse d’extrusion était réglée à 100 tr/min et la température était de 120OC, 100OC, 80OC et 60OC pour la réglisse et de 140OC, 120OC, 100OC et 80OC pour le gruau dans chacune des quatre zones respectives en gardant la température la plus haute proche de la fillère. Les extrudats ont été séchés afin de baisser le taux d’humidité à 8-10% pour de plus amples analyses. Les caractéristiques du produit telles que la masse volumique, la couleur, la texture, etc ont été analysées pour chacun des deux produits. Les niveaux d’antioxydants et les attributs texturaux augmentaient si la teneur en fruit augmentait pour les deux produits. Toutefois, la farine de banane a créé qui a été ajoutée dans la bouillie instantanée une texture plus dure et a donné une couleur plus foncée au gruau. Une masse volumique des ratios de réhydratation plus élevés étaient associés à de plus hautes teneurs en ananas et farine de banane. Les produits développés ont également été analysés pour leur contenu en protéine afin de convenir aux besoins d’un régime spécial ex : plus haute teneur en protéines pour un supplément nutritionnel pour enfants malnourris et teneur en protéines plus faible pour patients ayant des problèmes de reins. Les produits développés ont été comparés à des échantillons sur le marché et ont été jugés similaires en texture et saveur tout en ayant de meilleurs profils nutritifs.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The dietary concerns of consumers are moving rapidly from foods that prevent nutritional deficiency and associated diseases to foods that offer longer-term prevention of chronic diseases. Consuming unhealthy foods is leading to different extremities, lack of nutrition on one hand and aggravation of chronic diseases and obesity on the other. A possible solution to these problems is the creation of healthy and convenient foods. Extrusion processing can serve the food industry with food products which are convenient as well as nutritious by providing a platform for enrichment of food products with fiber, protein, antioxidants and vitamins. This thesis aims at developing nutritionally balanced fruit products using an extrusion process to serve as a potential diet for special need applications such as malnourished children and chronic kidney disease patients.Extrusion cooking studies were carried out in order to develop two products: fruit licorice and instant porridge using mango and pineapple as base ingredients. D-optimal mixture design was selected for this study to investigate the effect of different functional ingredients on the sensory and nutritional characteristics of the final product. The design generated 16 experimental combinations and an additional control formulation was made for both products. The extrusion screw speed was set to 100 rpm and temperature was set to 120OC, 100OC, 80OC and 60OC for licorice and 140OC, 120OC, 100OC and 80OC for porridge in the four barrel zones, respectively, keeping the highest temperature near the die. The extrudates were finish dried to reduce the moisture content to 8-10% for further analysis. The product characteristics such as bulk density, color, texture etc. were analyzed for both products. Antioxidant level and textural attributes were found to increase with an increase in fruit content in both the products. However, banana flour which was added in instant porridge led to an increase in the hardness and darkness of the porridge. Higher bulk density and rehydration ratios were associated with higher content of pineapple and banana flour. The developed products were also analyzed for protein content to conform to the needs of specific diets, i.e. higher protein level for nutrient supplement (undernourished children) and lower protein level for kidney patients. The products thus developed were compared to some market samples and were found to be similar in texture and flavor, but with better nutritional profiles.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hosahalli Ramaswamy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vf33x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fc13h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515r31z"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The neural correlates of the emergence of sleep and waking in chickens</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chan, Aimee</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Chez les rongeurs adultes, l'éveil est soutenu par l'activité dans un ensemble interconnecté de populations neuronales (le "système d'éveil"), qui comprend les Hypocrétines, le Noradrénergique Locus Coeruleus (NA-LC), le Raphé Dorsal Sérotoninergique (5HT-DR) et les Neurones Cholinergiques Pontique (ChAT-LDT/PPT).Le sommeil est soutenu par l'activité dans diverses populations de neurones GABAergiques, et par un manque d'activité dans les systèmes d'éveil. Les mouvements oculaires rapides (MPL) du sommeil sont pris en charge par l'activation du ChAT-LDT/PPT et des neurones contrôlant les hormones de concentration de la mélanine (MCH).Les oiseaux et les mammifères montrent des états de sommeil et d’éveil similaires (Lesku et Rattenborg 2014). Les poulets sont précoces; ils développent des motifs électroencéphalographiques (EEG) de sommeil avant l'éclosion, et un état stable d’éveil quelques heures après l'éclosion (Mellor et Diesch 2007; Martinez-Gonzalez et autres 2012).Afin de comprendre le moment propice où l'activité, dans les populations neuronales régissant le sommeil et l'éveil, devient coordonnée et en mesure de soutenir les états stables, j’ai enquêté sur l'activation des systèmes 5HT-DR et ChAT-LDT/PPT dans des embryons de poulet non perturbés. L'Orexine, NA-LC, et les systèmes de MCH ont déjà été étudiés en laboratoire. J’ai prolongé ce travail dans la période néonatale, les poussins au premier jour après la naissance (P1), séparés dans les périodes du sommeil naturel, de privation de sommeil, et de conditions de récupération de sommeil. cFos a été utilisé comme un marqueur de l'activation neuronale dans les études d'immunofluorescence avec étiquetage double.L’activation des neurones 5HT-DR et ChAT- LDT/PPT a suivi la tendance observée pour les autres systèmes d'éveil, comme les résultats déjà connus dans le laboratoire : il était faible au 12ième jour embryonnaire (E) et a augmenté un peu à E16 et E20. L’activité de tous les systèmes d'excitation a atteint leurs plus hauts niveaux d'activation chez les poussins P1 éveillés, et était faible dans les deux conditions naturelles et de récupération de sommeil.Dans le système favorisant le sommeil, le travail déjà effectué dans le laboratoire avait démontré que l'activation des neurones MCH avait également progressivement augmentée dans les embryons et avait atteint ses valeurs les plus élevées au E20. Ici une faible activation du système MCH a été observée dans toutes les conditions de P1. Parmi les populations neuronales, une corrélation significative de l’activité a été vue seulement entre NA-LC et d'expression 5HT-DR cFos dans les embryons, et chez la plupart des systèmes de l'éveil à P1.Je conclus que les systèmes d'éveil deviennent progressivement recrutés dans les embryons et deviennent coordonnés seulement après l'éclosion. Les neurones MCH peuvent être impliquées dans l'émergence du sommeil paradoxal comme dans des embryons de poulet. L’absence de l'activation du ChAT-LDT/PPT et des systèmes de MCH dans les poussins postnataux, peut être dûe à la durée relativement courte des épisodes de sommeil étudiées ici.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In adult rodents, wakefulness is sustained by activation in an interconnected set of neuronal populations (the "arousal system"), which includes the orexin, noradrenergic Locus Coeruleus (NA-LC), serotonergic dorsal raphe (5HT-DR) and pontine cholinergic (ChAT-LDT/PPT) neurons. Sleep is supported by activation in various GABAergic neuronal populations, and a lack of activation in the arousal systems. Rapid eye movement (REM) sleep is supported by activation of ChAT-LDT/PPT and melanin-concentrating hormone (MCH) neurons.Birds and mammals show similar sleep and waking states (Lesku and Rattenborg 2014). Chickens are precocial; they develop sleep-like electroencephalographic (EEG) patterns before hatching, and a stable waking state within a few hours after hatching (Mellor and Diesch 2007; Martinez-Gonzalez et al 2012). In order to understand when activation in neuronal populations that regulate sleep and waking becomes coordinated and able to support stable states, I investigated activation of the 5HT-DR and ChAT-LDT/PPT systems in undisturbed chick embryos. The orexin, NA-LC, and MCH systems were previously investigated in the lab. I extended this work into neonatal, posthatched day (P) 1 chicks separated into natural sleep, sleep deprivation, and sleep recovery conditions. cFos was used as a marker of neuronal activation in double-labelling immunofluorescent studies.  Activation of 5HT-DR and ChAT-LDT/PPT neurons followed the pattern seen for the other arousal systems and previously studied in the lab: it was low at embryonic day (E) 12 and slowly increased at E16 and E20. Activity of all arousal systems reached their highest activation levels in awake P1 chicks, and were low in both natural and sleep recovery conditions. In the sleep-promoting system, previous work done in the lab had shown that activation of MCH neurons also progressively increased in embryos and reached its highest values at E20. Here, low activation of the MCH system was seen in all P1 conditions. Among neuronal populations, significantly correlated activation was seen only between NA-LC and 5HT-DR cFos expression in embryos, and among most arousal systems at P1.I conclude that the arousal systems become progressively recruited in embryos and become coordinated only after hatching. MCH neurons may be involved in the emergence of REM sleep-like in chick embryos. Absence of activation of the ChAT-LDT/PPT and MCH systems in the sleeping postnatal chicks may be due to the relatively short duration of the sleep episodes studied here.    </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maria Pompeiano</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jr74x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515r31z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816q387"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis and biological evaluation of novel triazole-containing pantothenate analogues as potential antibacterial and antiplasmodial agents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tran, Elisa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The rapid spread of antibiotic resistance has created an unmet demand for novel antibacterial agents. Pantothenamides are a class of compounds that exhibit antimicrobial activity, encompassing antibacterial, antifungal and antiplasmodial growth inhibition. The currently accepted mechanism of action for these antimicrobial agents primarily involves activation by the coenzyme A (CoA) biosynthetic enzymes to their corresponding CoA analogues, which then affects downstream pathways including fatty acid biosynthesis.Pantothenate kinase (PanK) is the rate-limiting enzyme in CoA biosynthesis. Various forms of PanK exist among bacteria; Type I, type II and type III, all of which phosphorylate pantothenate at the terminal alcohol. Type I PanK, most studied from Escherichia coli, is highly regulated through negative feedback inhibition and readily accepts pantothenamides as substrates. Type II PanK found in Staphylococci bacterial strains, do not exhibit this form of regulation, and their inhibition correlates well with antibacterial activity. Many pathogenic bacteria, including difficult-to-treat Gram-negative bacteria, contain type III PanK (Pseudomonas aeruginosa), which are neither inhibited, nor transform pantothenamides.One challenge associated with pantothenamides as antimicrobial agents is the presence of pantetheinase enzymes in human blood serum. Pantetheinases act to cleave pantothenamides at the amide bond that connects the N-substituents, rendering pantothenamides inactive. Thus, it was envisioned that a novel series of pantothenamides with a triazole moiety replacing this amide bond could prevent degradation and increase in vivo stability. The design and synthesis of the novel pantothenamides is described in Chapter 2, followed by the biological activity in Chapter 3. Fortunately, a few pantothenamides presented in this thesis show good antimicrobial activity, signifying the potential for these compounds. Contributions and experimental methods comprise the final chapters of this thesis.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La propagation rapide de la résistance bactérienne aux antibiotiques a créé une demande sans précédent pour de nouveaux agents antibactériens. Les panthothénamides sont une classe de composés qui montrent diverses activités antimicrobiennes telles que de l’activité antibactérienne, de l’activité antifongique ainsi que de l’activité d’inhibition croissance antiplasmodiale. Actuellement, pour ces agents antimicrobiens, le mécanisme d’action accepté implique principalement l’activation d’enzymes biosynthétiques de la coenzyme A (CoA) en leurs analogues correspondants, ce qui affecte les voies biosynthétiques en aval, incluant la biosynthèse des acides gras.La panthothénate kinase (PanK) est l’enzyme impliquée dans l’étape limitante de la biosynthèse de la CoA. Chez les bactéries, il existe différentes formes de PanK: type I, type II and type III qui phosphorylent toutes la PanK sur l’alcool primaire terminal. La PanK de type I, surtout étudiée à partir de Escherichia coli, est hautement régulée par rétroaction négative et accepte facilement les pantothénamides comme substrat. La PanK de type II, présente chez les souches de bactéries staphylocoques, ne montre pas ce genre de régulation et son inhibition correspond assez bien à son activité antibactérienne. Plusieurs bactéries pathogènes, incluant les bactéries Gram négatives qui sont difficiles à traiter, possèdent la PanK de type III (Pseudomonas aeruginosa), chez lesquelles aucune inhibition ou transformation des pantothénamides ne sont observés.Un problème lié à l’utilisation de pantothénamides en tant qu’agents antimicrobiens est la présence d’enzymes pantéthéinase dans le sérum sanguin humain. Les pantéthéinases agissent en clivant les pantothénamides sur le lien amide qui connecte différents substituants sur l’azote, ce qui désactive les pantothénamides. Par conséquent, il a été imaginé qu’une nouvelle série de molécules contenant un groupement triazole remplaçant ce lien amide pourrait empêcher leur dégradation et ainsi augmenter leur stabilité in vivo. La conceptualisation et la synthèse de nouvelles pantothénamides sont décrites au Chapitre 2, dont l’évaluation biologique a été effectuée au Chapitre 3. Par chance, certaines pantothénamides décrites dans ce mémoire possèdent une bonne activité antimicrobienne, démontrant aussi par conséquent le potentiel de ces composés. Les contributions et la partie expérimentale sont présentées dans le chapitre final de ce mémoire.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Karine Auclair</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nf02n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816q387</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aht24wn256"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of calcineurin inhibitor therapy in treatment of primary focal segmental glomerulosclerosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laurin, Louis-Philippe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>BACKGROUND: Primary focal segmental glomerulosclerosis (FSGS) is the most common cause of nephrotic syndrome in adults. Glucocorticoids have been studied as treatment of primary FSGS in retrospective studies. Although some studies evaluated the role of calcineurin inhibitors (CNIs) in a steroid-resistant primary FSGS population, their role as early therapy remains poorly established. OBJECTIVES: To evaluate the efficacy of CNIs in treatment of primary FSGS.METHODS: Two studies were performed. The first was a systematic review to describe the efficacy of CNIs compared to placebo, supportive therapy and other immunosuppressive agents. The second study used registry data and time-dependent Cox models to compare time to end-stage kidney disease (ESKD) between different immunosuppressive therapies while controlling for potential confounders, including those influencing choice of therapy and renal survival.RESULTS: Study 1: Six randomized controlled trials and 2 cohort studies were reviewed. All but one suggested CNIs may be beneficial in steroid-resistant primary FSGS compared to placebo or supportive therapy. No prospective trial studied the efficacy of calcineurin inhibitors in first-line treatment of FSGS. Study 2: In adjusted Cox regression, immunosuppressive therapy with glucocorticoids and/or CNIs was associated with a better renal survival [hazard ratio 0.49 (95% confidence interval 0.28, 0.86)] than no therapy. Although not statistically significant, CNIs ± glucocorticoids were associated with a lower likelihood of ESKD [hazard ratio 0.42 (95% confidence interval 0.15, 1.18)] than glucocorticoids alone.CONCLUSIONS: Our results suggest that immunosuppressive therapy with CNIs and/or glucocorticoids is associated with better renal survival compared with supportive therapy alone in patients with FSGS. Whether early use of CNIs alone or in combination with glucocorticoids are superior to glucocorticoids alone in attaining remission and preventing ESKD, remains to be established.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>CONTEXTE : L’hyalinose focale et segmentaire (HFS) primaire est la cause la plus commune de syndrome néphrotique chez l’adulte. Les glucocorticoïdes ont été étudiés comme traitement de première ligne dans l’HFS primaire dans des études rétrospectives. Malgré le fait que des études ont évalué le rôle des inhibiteurs de la calcineurine (ICN) dans une population d’HFS primaire résistante aux stéroïdes, leur rôle comme thérapie au début de l’évolution de la maladie reste mal établi.OBJECTIFS : Évaluer l’efficacité des ICN dans le traitement de l’HFS.MÉTHODE : Deux études ont été conduites. La première était une revue systématique pour décrire l’efficacité des ICN par rapport à un agent placebo, à un traitement non-immunologique, ainsi qu’à d’autres agents immunosuppresseurs. Dans la deuxième étude, nous avons utilisé les données d’un registre et des modèles de régression de Cox afin de comparer le temps à l’insuffisance rénale terminale (IRT) entre différents traitements immunosuppresseurs et ce, en ajustant pour des facteurs confondants potentiels, incluant ceux connus pour influencer le choix du traitement et l’issue rénale.RÉSULTATS : Étude 1 : Six essais cliniques randomisés et 2 études de cohorte ont été revus. Tous les articles sauf un suggèrent un effet bénéfique des ICN dans l’HFS primaire résistante à la corticothérapie. Aucune étude prospective n’a évalué l’efficacité des ICN dans le traitement de première intention de l’HFS. Étude 2 : Dans la régression de Cox ajustée, l’immunosuppression avec des glucocorticoïdes avec ou sans ICN est associée à une meilleure survie rénale [rapport risque 0.49 (intervalle de confiance à 95% 0.28, 0.86)] qu’une absence d’immunothérapie. Quoique qu’il ne soit pas statistiquement significatif, les ICN ± glucocorticoïdes sont associés à un risque moindre d’IRT [rapport risque 0.42 (intervalle de confiance à 95% 0.15, 1.18)] que les glucocorticoïdes seuls.CONCLUSIONS : Nos résultats suggèrent qu’un traitement immunosuppresseur composé d’un ICN avec glucocorticoïdes, ou de glucocorticoïdes seuls est associé à une meilleure survie rénale qu’une thérapie de support seule chez les patients atteints d’HFS. La supériorité des ICN avec ou sans glucocorticoïdes vis-à-vis les glucocorticoïdes seuls pour induire une rémission ou prévenir l’IRT reste indéterminée.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bethany Joy Foster</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Patrick H. Nachman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920g058k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wn256</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924f580"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Digital Hadron Calorimeter: Analysis of the November 2011 Fermilab data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Freund, Benjamin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The future electron-positron International Linear Collider (ILC) is a high precision machine requiring high resolution detectors. It has a broad physics program covering topics such as precision measurements of the Higgs Boson and possible detection of Dark Matter or supersymmetric particles. New detector concepts have to be developed to meet the very stringent requirements. For optimised event reconstruction innovative Particle Flow algorithms will have to be applied to all detector systems. The international CALICE collaboration is developing highly granular calorimeter detectors for that purpose. Within this collaboration, several physical prototypes have been constructed, including a Digital Hadron Calorimeter (DHCAL) physical 1m^3 prototype, using the Resistive Plate Chamber technology, which is developed at Argonne National Laboratory. It is a high granularity sampling calorimeter with 1x1 cm^2 digital read-out, making it the first digital imaging calorimeter ever. The DHCAL prototype was tested with different absorber materials, such as steel and tungsten, at different test beam facilities (Fermilab and CERN).  Additionally in November 2011, data was taken without the additional absorber structures. Data collected with minimal absorber material provides unprecedented insight into the inner structure of both electromagnetic and hadronic showers. The data set is ideal for detailed comparisons with GEANT4 based simulations. This thesis presents a full detector analysis of electromagnetic and hadronic showers in the DHCAL without additional absorber plates. It includes calibration, event selection and particle identification. The single particle energy resolution and other parameters are compared to GEANT4 simulations and different hadronic models implemented in GEANT4 are validated against the data.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le futur collisionneur linéaire international électron-positron (ILC) est un accélérateur de grande précision nécessitant des détecteurs de haute résolution. Son vaste programme de physique inclut par exemple des mesures précises des propriétés du boson de Higgs et d'éventuelles particules supersymmétriques. Ainsi de nouveaux concepts de détection doivent être développés. Pour optimiser la reconstruction des événements, une approche basée sur le suivi de particules ("Particle Flow") doit être appliquée dans toutes les parties du détecteur. La collaboration internationale CALICE développe ces calorimètres à haute segmentation qui satisfont aux exigences de la resolution. Dans ce cadre, plusieurs prototypes ont été développés et construits, y compris un calorimère hadronique digital (DHCAL) développé à Argonne National Laboratory, dont le volume est d'un mètre cube, utilisant des chambres à plaques résistives de verre en tant qu'élément sensible. C'est un calorimètre à échantillonnage de segmentation latérale d'un centimètre carré. Le DHCAL a été testé à plusieurs reprises dans des lignes de faisceaux de particules (Fermilab et CERN) avec différents matériaux d'absorption (acier et tungstène). En novembre 2011 des données ont été prises sans matériaux d'absorption supplémentaires. Ces données fournissent des détails sans précédent sur des cascades électromagnétiques et hadroniques et forment ainsi qu'une base idéale pour des comparaisons avec des simulations basées sur GEANT4. Dans ce mémoire une analyse complète de ces données est effectuée, incluant la calibration, la sélection d'événements et l'identification des particules. La résolution en energie des particules ainsi que d'autres mesures sont comparées à des simulations. Pour conclure des modèles hadroniques implémentés dans GEANT4 ont été validés.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Francois Corriveau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289m906.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924f580</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A37720g748"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Doors that lead to doors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boneh, Oren</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Doors That Lead to Doors est une œuvre musicale écrite pour grand orchestre à vent. La pièce se concerne avec la fonctionnalité hiérarchique qui résulte de l’interaction entre éléments musicaux dans un contexte donné. L’orchestre se divise en quatre groupes différents, dont chacun est assigné sa propre musique unique. La cohérence de l’instrumentation aide à établir des liens entre le timbre et le geste musicale pour faire en sorte que chaque geste n’apparaisse que dans le cadre d’un timbre spécifique. Par l’utilisation de telles contraintes structurelles, la pièce sert à enquêter les processus cognitifs de l’écoute et de l’apprentissage à court terme, et leurs potentiels en tant qu’outils pour l’écriture de la musique originale et dynamique.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Doors That Lead to Doors is a musical work for large wind ensemble. The piece is concerned with hierarchical functionality arising from interaction between musical elements in a given context. The ensemble is split into four different groups that are each assigned their own distinctive music. Consistency in orchestration helps to create ties between timbre and musical gesture such that each gesture is connected to a particular set of timbres. Through the use of such formal constraints, the piece serves as a vehicle to investigate the cognitive processes of listening and short-term learning, and their potential as tools for composing original and dynamic music.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brian Cherney</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2688143.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720g748</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr172100w"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Trace metal content in Panamanian marine turtles, its potential to differentiate populations, and implications for human consumption</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ross, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Anthropogenic input of chemical pollutants into the marine environment has led to substantial increases in the concentrations of naturally occurring trace metals, often with detrimental effects on the health of exposed marine animals and humans. Although they are a common food source in many tropical countries, quantitative toxicological assessments of marine turtles are generally limited in number of species investigated, number of data per species, and geographical distribution of samples. Chapter 1 presents a comprehensive review of sea turtle toxicology, and sea turtle eggs in particular given their widespread human consumption. From 70 collated studies reporting As, Cd, Hg, and/or Pb concentrations in edible sea turtle tissues, Loggerheads (Caretta caretta) and Green turtles (Chelonia mydas) were most frequently reported, with over half the data from liver, kidney, or muscle tissues. Eggs made up less than 10% of the data. Globally, no species was distinct for any metal; Cd and Hg showed tissue-specificity to kidney and liver, respectively; and Cd was significantly highest in the Pacific Ocean. Using a standard adult body weight (62.0 kg) and serving size (75 g), Cd was the most toxic metal. On average, eating ≤75 g week-1 would induce Cd poisoning from either Green or Loggerhead kidney and liver, and Hg poisoning from only Loggerhead liver. Chapter 2 presents measurements of 12 trace metals in Green turtle and Olive Ridley (Lepidochelys olivacea) eggs from Pacific Panama. Qualitatively, the metal profiles measured were similar to previous reports, with 8 of 12 falling in their previously reported ranges. In my samples, interspecific differences were found on a per-site basis, and geographic differences for each species, but the interaction of these patterns prevented overall significant differentiation. Cd was, again, the most toxic metal; however, consumption of these eggs at the reported average rates is unlikely to induce metal poisoning in adult consumers. However, males and females aged 16-30 and children up to ~3.4 yrs (~16.5 kg), consuming eggs at their maximum reported rates of 15 eggs day-1, 30 eggs day-1, and 5 eggs day-1, respectively, may be putting themselves at risk of developing symptoms of long-term heavy-metal poisoning. The research presented here supports previous findings that Cd is highest in Green turtles, but that other toxic metals (Hg and Pb) are typically higher in more carnivorous species; we also show that, given the data available, patterns frequently observed in local comparisons are not always globally robust. Furthermore, we show that Cd is on average the most toxic metal in marine turtles concerning human health, but that additional analyses are needed to fully understand the health-risks of global sea turtle consumption.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L’introduction anthropique de polluants chimiques dans l'environnement marin a conduit à une augmentation substantielle de concentrations naturelles de métaux traces, souvent avec des effets néfastes sur la santé des animaux marins exposés, et des humains. Les tortues marines sont une source de nourriture importante dans plusieurs pays tropicaux, mais leurs évaluations toxicologiques quantitatives ont peu d'espèces étudiées, peu de données par espèce, et la distribution géographique des échantillons demeure limitée. Le premier chapitre présente une revue compréhensive de la toxicologie des tortues marines - particulièrement sur leurs œufs - compte tenu de leur consommation humaine très répandue. Parmi 70 études qui ont inclue des concentrations de As, Cd, Hg et/ou Pb dans les tissus comestibles de tortues marines, la caouanne (Caretta caretta) et la tortue verte (Chelonia mydas) ont été le plus souvent documentées. Plus de 50% des données provenaient du foie, des reins ou de tissus musculaires, et moins de 10% des données provenaient des œufs. Globalement, aucune espèce n’était distincte pour n’importe quel métal. Le Cd était retrouvé spécifiquement dans le foie et le Hg, dans les reins; le niveau de Cd était significativement plus élevé dans l’océan Pacifique. Pour un poids standard d’adulte (62,0 kg) et une portion standard (75,0 g), le métal le plus toxique était le Cd. En moyenne, consommer ≤75 g sem-1 induit un empoisonnement de Cd par le foie et les reins de la caouanne et de la tortue verte, et un empoisonnement de Hg par le foie de la caouanne. Le deuxième chapitre présente des mesures de 12 métaux traces retrouvées dans les œufs de la tortue verte et la tortue olivâtre (Lepidochelys olivacea) dans la côte pacifique du Panama. Qualitativement, les profils des métaux mesurés étaient similaires aux rapports précédents - 8 des 12 métaux démontraient des gammes similaires à celles reportées auparavant. Dans mon échantillonnage, des différences interspécifiques ont été trouvées par site, et des différences géographiques pour chaque espèce, mais l'interaction de ces patrons ont empêché une différenciation globale significative. Le Cd était encore une fois le métal le plus toxique, mais il est peu probable que la consommation moyenne de ces œufs puisse entraîner des intoxications aux métaux chez les consommateurs adultes. Cependant, chez les hommes de 16 à 30 ans, les femmes de 16 à 30 ans, et les enfants jusqu'à ~3,4 ans (~16,5 kg), où les taux de consommation d’œufs peuvent atteindre 15 œufs jour-1, 30 œufs jour-1 et 5 œufs jour-1 respectivement, ils risquent de développer des symptômes à long termes d’intoxication aux métaux lourds. La recherche présentée ici confirme les résultats précédents que le Cd est le plus élevé chez les tortues vertes, mais que d'autres métaux toxiques tels que le Hg et le Pb sont généralement plus élevés chez les espèces plus carnivores. Nous montrons aussi que compte tenu des données disponibles, les modèles fréquemment observées dans les comparaisons locales ne sont pas toujours robustes à l'échelle mondiale. De plus, nous montrons que le Cd est en moyenne le métal le plus toxique dans les tortues marines en ce qui concerne la santé humaine, mais des analyses supplémentaires sont nécessaires pour bien comprendre les risques de la consommation mondiale des tortues marines pour la santé.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hector Guzman</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Catherine Potvin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935584n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172100w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719q12v"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The beast within: Gothic vampirism in the nineteenth century</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yeh, Shen-Chih</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This MA thesis studies the significance of the nineteenth-century British literary tradition of Gothic vampirism. The first half of the thesis surveys the modern image of Gothic vampires developed by Lord Byron in The Giaour (1813) and "Fragment of a Novel" (1819), by John William Polidori in his novella The Vampyre (1819), and by Abraham "Bram" Stoker in Dracula (1897). At the beginning of the nineteenth century Byron and Polidori reinvented the Gothic vampire as a callous, cunning, but always charismatic predator, and at the end of the century Stoker reinforced the same image by portraying his vampire-protagonist Count Dracula as an intellectually brilliant, well-educated, and refined master parasite. Together these three authors reimagined the abominable undead entity in folklore as a monster that donned the mask of a gentleman—a remarkable creature occupying an enduring role in modern literature. The second half of the thesis traces the allusions to Gothic vampirism in Mary Shelley’s Frankenstein (1818) and Robert Louis Stevenson’s The Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde (1886). I analyze how Mary Shelley and Stevenson model their human and monster protagonists on the alluring images of Gothic vampires to shock, to seduce, to psychologize, and above all to investigate the dangerous proximity of man to beast, of a drawing-room dandy to a monster. These vampiric tales of the makings of a monster are thus about what defines a human. Through the juxtaposition of monsters and their humanized counterparts these stories of Gothic vampires destabilize the distinction between humanity and animality and challenge our conventional understanding of the relationship between man and beast.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La présente thèse de maîtrise est une réflexion sur l’importance de la littérature anglaise dans le développement et l’évolution du vampirisme gothique. La première moitié de la thèse passe en revue l’image moderne des vampires développée par Lord Byron dans The Giaour (1813) puis dans «Fragment of a Novel» (1819), par John William Polidori dans The Vampyre (1819) et enfin par Abraham «Bram» Stoker dans Dracula (1897). Au début du 19e siècle, Byron et Polidori ont réinventé le vampire gothique pour en faire un prédateur à la fois insensible et rusé mais toujours charismatique. À la fin du siècle, Stoker est venu ajouter à ce portrait en représentant son personnage principal, le comte Dracula, comme un maître parasite intellectuellement brillant, éduqué et raffiné. Ensemble, ces trois auteurs ont réinventé l’abominable entité de mort-vivant du folklore pour en faire un monstre portant un masque de gentleman—une créature formidable qui occupe une place durable dans la littérature moderne. La deuxième partie de cette thèse trace les allusions au vampirisme gothique dans le roman de Mary Shelley, Frankenstein (1818), et dans la courte nouvelle de Robert Louis Stevenson, The Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde (1886). Nous nous penchons sur la manière dont ces auteurs ont modélisé leurs personnages humains et leurs monstres sur l’image de gentleman du vampire gothique pour choquer, séduire, psychanalyser et par-dessus tout, examiner la dangereuse proximité entre l’homme et la bête, entre le gentleman et le monstre. Ces contes de vampires nous instruisent sur ce qui définit l’être humain. Par la juxtaposition des monstres et de leurs contreparties humaines, ces histoires de vampires gothiques déstabilisent la distinction entre l’humanité et l’animalité.  Elles mettent en question la compréhension traditionnelle de la relation entre l’homme et la bête.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David C. Hensley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451m53n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719q12v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35tc16h"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Economic and environmental impacts of biofuel policy in Canada: An application of input-output modelling</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Xi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>RÉSUMÉLe gouvernement canadien s’est engagé à réduite de 17 pourcent par rapport au niveau de 2005 l'émission de gaz à effet de serre pour l’an 2020.  Pour atteindre cet objectif, le gouvernement canadien a annoncé sa stratégie d’énergie renouvelable qui a introduit des exigences supplémentaires pour l'usage d'éthanol et de biodiésel dans les carburants fossiles. Ainsi, le gouvernement fédéral introduit des initiatives comme la mise au point de nouveaux standards d'émission pour les véhicules lourds et, depuis 2005, introduit de nouveaux  règlements entourant la génération d'électricité à partir du charbon. Ces règlements exigent que le diesel et l'huile de chauffage contienne 2 pour cent de biocarburants, créant ainsi une demande en biodiésel d’environ 600 millions de litres par an.   De plus, les standards de contenu de biocarburants dans l'essence ont été ciblés à 5% à partir de 2010, ce qui représente environ 2.1 milliards de litres d'éthanol par année selon l'Association Canadienne de Carburants Renouvelables (ACCR).  Dans ce contexte, cette étude estime les impacts macroéconomiques des secteurs de l'éthanol et du biodiésel au Canada en utilisant un modèle d’entrées-sorties. Les secteurs bio-carburants a été intégrés au modèle entrées-sorties à partir de l’an 2008.  Les exercices de simulation ont également utilisé un modèle Leontief modifié afin d’atteindre les objectifs.  Les résultats démontrent que l'impact macroéconomique du secteur des biocarburants fait augmenter la production industrielle, le PIB et l'emploi. De plus, le secteur agricole est affecté de par l'usage du secteur des biocarburants de grain initialement utilisé pour l’alimentation animale.  Les industries minières et manufacturières sont également touchées par ces nouvelles politiques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>ABSTRACTThe government of Canada has committed that Canada’s total GHG emissions be reduced by 17 percent of 2005 levels by 2020.  To achieve this, the federal government of Canada announced its renewable fuels strategy in 2007, which introduced mandated requirements for the use of ethanol and biodiesel.  The Federal government has also introduced several initiatives by setting new emissions standards for heavy-duty vehicles, and phase in regulations for the generation of electricity from coal by 2015.  These regulations required 2% renewable content in diesel fuel and heating distillate oil by 2012, for a total production of approximately 600 million litres of biodiesel per year.  In addition, renewable content standards for gasoline were targeted at 5% by 2010.  This represents approximately 2.1 billion litres of ethanol being required per year according to the Canadian Renewable Fuels Association. With this backdrop, the study aims at estimating the macroeconomic impacts of the ethanol and biodiesel sectors in Canada using an Input-Output model.  Biofuel sectors including ethanol, biodiesel and corresponding by-products have been incorporated into the 2008 Input-Output Model of Canada.  Simulation exercises have also been attempted to reach the mandates using a modified Leontief model.  Results show that the macroeconomic impact of the ethanol sector leads to an increase in industrial output, GDP and employment.  Further, the agriculture sector is affected because of feedstock use in the biofuel sector. Mining and manufacturing industries also show a considerable impact.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kakali Mukhopadhyay</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Paul Thomassin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913s71x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tc16h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abg257h84j"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>High-order time-domain steady-state simulation for radio frequency applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abou Ziki, Nassir</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La simulation en régime permanent est une étape cruciale de la conception de circuits à radio-fréquences. Parmi les méthodes couramment utilisées pour la simulation en régime permanent, on retrouve notamment la méthode d'équilibre harmonique dans le domaine fréquentiel et les méthodes de shooting dans le domaine temporel. Chacune de ces méthodes comporte des lacunes. La méthode d'équilibre harmonique peut demander une forte puissance de calcul à cause du grand nombre d'inconnus dans le système, tandis que les méthodes de shooting sont également complexes dû à la nécessité de calculer la matrice de sensitivité. Ce mémoire porte sur la réduction du coût de calcul des méthodes de shooting, et présente une méthode Shooting-Newton d'ordre supérieur pour la simulation en régime permanent de circuits radio-fréquences. La méthode proposée est fondée sur des formules "A-stable" et "L-stable" d'Obreshkov d'ordre supérieur. L'ordre de la méthode de shooting peut être arbitrairement grand sans perte de stabilité. Le recours à des méthodes d'ordre supérieur permet d'utiliser des pas plus grands lors de l'intégration numérique, et la stabilité de la méthode garantie la précision de la solution. Conséquemment, la méthode proposée permet une amélioration considérable du coût de calcul par rapport aux approches fondées sur la méthode d'Euler implicite. Les résultats présentés démontrent une amélioration du temps de calcul de plus de 8 fois.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Steady-state simulation is a crucial step in the design of Radio Frequency (RF) circuits. The most popular steady-state simulation methods include Harmonic Balance (HB) in the frequency domain and Shooting methods in the time domain. Both of these methods have their drawbacks; while HB can be computationally expensive due to the large number of unknowns that are required to be found, Shooting methods suffer computationally due to the necessity of computing the sensitivity matrix.  This work focuses on alleviating the computational costs of Shooting methods. A high order Shooting-Newton method for steady-state simulation of Radio Frequency (RF) circuits is presented. The method is based on high order A- and L-stable Obreshkov formula (ObF). The proposed Shooting method can have arbitrarily high-order without losing the stability property. The high-order methods allow using bigger step sizes in numerical integration; the stability property guarantees that the accuracy of the numerical solution is not compromised. Consequently, the presented method allows for a considerable improvement in CPU cost when compared to the Backward Euler based approach. Speedups of more than 8 are reported.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roni Khazaka</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wn26g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257h84j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqz20sw669"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Towards individualized assessment of patient benefit from treatment and prognosis in breast cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paquet, Éric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Technologies to measure gene expression in a massively parallel fashion have facilitated a more complete molecular understanding of breast cancer and a deeper appreciation for the heterogeneity of this disease. Although the subtypes defined by Estrogen Receptor (ER) and Human Epidermal growth factor Receptor 2 (Her2) status have long been recognized as distinct forms of the disease, early genomic studies emphasized the magnitude of the differences between and within these subtypes at the molecular level. Unbiased bioinformatic analyses of expression profiles provided the so-called intrinsic molecular subtyping scheme, consisting of the Luminal A, Luminal B and Normal-like subtypes enriched for ER+ tumors, the Her2-enriched subtype containing many Her2+ tumors and the Basal-like subtype enriched for ER-/Her2- tumors. The subtypes have differing clinicopathological attributes, prognostic characteristics, and treatment options, providing sufficient clinical utility as to support their inclusion within international guidelines for treatment. In fact, the ProsignaTM PAM50-based risk of recurrence score generated from assignments of the intrinsic subtypes has recently been FDA approved for clinical use. Several alternative omics-based subtyping schemes have been proposed that promise similar molecular and clinical utility.We have shown that variations in the ratio of ER+ to ER- samples and variations in the frequency of each subtype within datasets drastically influence subtype assignments. It remains unknown as to the degree of imbalance necessary in datasets that can cause such "subtype instability". We developed a bioinformatics approach, entitled Absolute Intrinsic Molecular Subtyping (AIMS), for estimating patient subtype that circumvents many of the above listed "relativistic" shortcomings. Firstly, the method does not require a panel of gene expression samples. As such, it is the first method that can accurately assign subtype to a single patient in a manner that is insensitive to changes in normalization procedures or the relative frequencies of specific subtype or clinicopathological patient attributes. The stability and accuracy of AIMS is explored for the intrinsic subtyping scheme across several datasets and technologies including microarrays and RNA­Seq. We extended this analysis by comparing AIMS to other subtyping schemes and to study absolute subtypes in breast cancer models including cell lines.In a manner analogous to the situation for subtyping, so-called "pathway analysis tools" that assess the activity of a specific pathway in a patient (eg. the EGFR pathway) are all currently based on relativistic approaches (ssGSEA, GSVA, BreSAT, etc) and consequently need a large "complete" dataset of patients. This hinders their ability to be used in a clinical setting where such information is largely not available, and individual samples must be considered in isolation. We have developed a new bioinformatics approach (AIPS) for stable absolute pathway activation assessment from raw gene expression data that, although conceptually similar to AIMS above, requires significant technical adjustment and development.Finally, within the Q-CROC project, we identified a signature of response to treatment using a panel of colon cancer cell lines. We developed a 12-gene signature that was validated in two independent cohorts of colon cancer patients (Almac and PETACC-3). The 12-gene signature is able to predict which patients will benefit from FOLFIRI (5­FU + irinotecan) instead of 5-FU alone (logrank test P = 0.039). This is the first study identifying a group of colon cancer patients that benefit from FOLFIRI treatment.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>De récentes avancées nous permettent maintenant d’obtenir un portrait global des processus biologiques impliqués dans l’apparition des cancers du sein. L’information émanant de ces analyses nous indique bien tout l’étendu de la diversité moléculaire de ce cancer. Bien que la diversité intrinsèque du cancer du sein est reconnue depuis plusieurs années grâce à l’utilisation, notamment, des marqueurs des récepteurs de l’estrogène (ER) et des seconds récepteurs des facteurs de croissance de l’épiderme (Her2), ces nouvelles technologies nous démontrent à quel point le cancer du sein se présente comme une pathologi hétérogène au niveau moléculaire. Les premières analyses bioinformatiques ont permis l’identification de cinq sous-types bien distincts incluant les sous-types Luminal A, Luminal B et Normal-like qui sont pour la plupart ER+, un sous-type Her2-enriched majoritairement Her2+ et finalement le sous-type Basal-like qui correspond aux cancer double négatifs (ER-/Her2-). Tous ces groupes ont une importance capitale dans la prise en charge clinique des patientes, car ils permettent un meilleur diagnostique, mais surtout permettent un traitement adapté au type de cancer. Récemment, l’agence Américaine des produits pharmaceutiques et alimentaires (FDA) a approuvé l’utilisation clinique du test ProsignaMD, un test basé sur la définition des différents sous-types de cancer du sein. Lors de l’étude des différentes méthodes de classification des sous-types de cancer du sein, nous avons démontré qu’une légère perturbation dans la fréquence des échantillons ER+ d’un jeu de données cliniques avait des répercutions sur l'attribution des sous-types. Conséquemment, nous avons élaboré une méthode bioinformatique permettant l’attribution absolue des sous-types moléculaires intrinsèques de cancer du sein (AIMS) qui corrige la plupart des problèmes reliés aux approches courantes. Une des caractéristiques d’AIMS est son application sur des échantillons uniques de cancer du sein et, de ce fait, la composition ou la perturbation d’un jeu de données n’a plus aucune emprise sur l'attribution des sous-types. Nous avons testé AIMS sur plusieurs plateformes technologiques incluant les biopuces et séquenceurs à ADN et avons étendu l’application d’AIMS à d’autres systêmes de classification et aussi aux modèles de lignées cellulaires du cancer du sein pour la validation des sous-types observés dans ces modèles.Nous avons aussi étendu nos analyses de stabilités aux outils bioinformatiques permettant d’établir le niveau d’activité d’un processus biologique chez un patient qui pourrait correspondre, par exemple, au niveau d’activation de la voie de signalisation EGFR en utilisant des outils comme ssGSEA, BreSAT, GSVA, etc. Nous avons observé un niveau d’instabilité analogue à celui observé pour l’attribution des sous-type de cancer du sein. Aussi, tout comme les sous-types, ces approches requièrent l’accès à un large jeu de données et malheureusement ce type de données n’est la plupart du temps pas disponible en clinique. Pour toutes ces raisons, nous avons étendu l’application de notre méthode AIMS à l’attribution des niveaux d’activation des différents processus biologiques et il est donc possible maintenant, grâce à un seul échantillon de patient, d’avoir accès à toute cette information. Pour terminer, dans le cadre du projet Q-CROC nous avons identifié une signature de 12 gènes à partir de lignées cellulaires du cancer du colon que nous avons ensuite validée dans deux jeux de données indépendants (Almac et PETACC-3). Nous avons démontré que notre signatures de 12 gènes identifie les patients devant être traités avec une combinaison de 5-FU + irinotecan (FOLFIRI) au lieu d’un traitement unique au 5-FU (logrank test P = 0.039). Cette étude démontre, pour la première fois, qu’il existe un groupe de patients souffrant du cancer du colon bénéficiant d’un traitement au FOLFIRI.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael Trevor Hallett</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021j00g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sw669</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88ck55j"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Non-Suicidal Self-Injury, Online Activity and Emotional Health Among Adolescents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>De Riggi, Melissa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Non-suicidal self-injury, the deliberate destruction of one’s body tissue (e.g., self-cutting, burning) without suicidal intent, consistently ranges from 15% to 20% among adolescents. Recently, more youth are accessing NSSI-related material online despite the potential associated risks (e.g., triggering through explicit content). Importantly, preliminary research suggests that adolescents who engage in NSSI may use the Internet more often and for different reasons than their non-self-injuring peers. Additionally, while getting health information and obtaining emotional support may underlie NSSI online activity, the motivations and needs of adolescents who go online for emotional health-related issues, particularly among adolescents who self-injure is not known. This study is the first to directly examine 1) the frequency of general Internet use, 2) the frequency of Internet use for emotional health reasons, and 3) the online activities related to emotional health among adolescents who engage in NSSI. Participants were 58 adolescents who reported current engagement of NSSI (Mage = 14.36 58; SD = .55; 79% female); 28 who reported past engagement of NSSI (Mage = 14.39; SD = .50); 50% female); 56 who reported never engaging NSSI (Mage = 14.51; SD = .51; 55% female).  Participants completed the How I Deal With Stress questionnaire (HIDS; Heath &amp; Ross, 2007) and the Beck Depression Inventory for Youth (BDI-Y; Beck, Beck, &amp;  Jolly, 2001) in groups during class time to screen for NSSI, risk-taking (RT) and elevated depressive symptomology. Those at-risk completed follow-up individual interviews that included the Emotional Health Online Behvaviour Assessment (EHOBA; Lewis &amp; Heath, 2012) to examine online interactions. Results from a one-way ANOVA indicated that adolescents who currently engage in NSSI use specific websites more frequently than those who have stopped engaging in NSSI (i.e., YouTube) and those with no history of NSSI (i.e., YouTube and Tumblr). Further, results from a MANOVA indicated that adolescents who currently engage in NSSI use the social media sites more frequently for emotional health reasons, regardless of gender. Chi-square tests revealed significant group differences, such that those with a history of self-injury online more often to give/receive support, read information, look at pictures/videos and blog, and are more interested in emotional health topics of depression, self-injury, sadness and eating disorders compared to their non-self-injuring peers. In conclusion, this study demonstrates that adolescents who currently engage in NSSI have a different profile of Internet use, indicative of connecting online, whereas adolescents with a past history of NSSI are most often comparable to individuals who have never engaged in NSSI.  Findings highlight the importance of the Internet as a form of support for adolescents engaging in NSSI.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L’automutilation non-suicidaire (AMNS) est définie comme étant une altération consciente, intentionnelle, et directe des tissus de l’organisme sans intention suicidaire et exclut tous comportements socialement acceptés. Récemment, plus de jeunes accèdent matériau AMNS liée en ligne malgré les risques potentiels associés (p.ex., le déclenchement grâce à un contenu explicite). La recherche préliminaire suggère que les adolescents qui se livrent à AMNS peuvent utiliser l’Internet plus souvent et pour des raisons différentes que leurs pairs non-automutilation. En outre, même si l'information sur la santé et le soutien affectif peuvent sous-tendre l'activité en ligne AMNS, les motivations et les besoins des adolescents qui vont en ligne pour les questions liées à la santé émotionnelle, en particulier chez les adolescents qui se mutilent est inconnue. Cette étude est la première à examiner directement 1) la fréquence de l'utilisation générale d'Internet, 2) la fréquence de l'utilisation d'Internet pour des raisons de santé émotionnelle, et 3) les activités en ligne liées à la santé émotionnelle chez les adolescents qui s’automutilent. Les participants étaient 58 adolescents qui ont déclaré l'engagement actuel de l’AMNS (Mâge = 14.36 58; SD = 0,55; 79% de femmes); 28 qui a signalé l'engagement passé de NSSI (Mâge = 14.39; SD = 0,50); 50% de femmes); 56 qui ont déclaré ne jamais engager AMNS (Mâge = 14,51; SD = 0,51; 55% de femmes). Les participants ont rempli The How I Deal With Stess Questionnaire (HIDS; Heath &amp; Ross, 2007) et le Beck Depression Inventory for Youth (BDI-Y; Beck, Beck, et Jolly, 2001) en groupe pendant les heures de classe pour dépister la présence d’AMNS, la prise de risqué (RT) et la symptomatologie dépressive élevée. Ceux terminé à risque ont fait des entretiens individuel et on complies le Emotional Health Online Behaviour Assessment (EHOBA; Lewis &amp; Heath, 2012) pour évaluer les interactions en ligne. Les résultats indiquent que les adolescents qui s’automutilent utilisent des sites Web spécifiques plus souvent que ceux qui ont arrêté l'automutilation (p.ex., YouTube) et les personnes sans antécédents de NSSI (p.ex., YouTube et Tumblr). De plus, les résultats révèle que les adolescents qui s’automutilent actuellement utilisent les sites de médias sociaux le plus souvent pour des raisons de santé émotionnelle, sans distinction de sexe. De plus, il existe des différences significatives entre les groupes, tels que ceux ayant des antécédents d'automutilation vont en ligne plus souvent pour donner / recevoir un soutien, lire des informations, regardez des photos / vidéos et blog, et sont plus intéressés par des sujets de santé émotionnels de la dépression, automutilation, la tristesse et les troubles alimentaires par rapport à leurs pairs non-automutilation. En conclusion, cette étude montre que les adolescents qui s’automutilent actuellement ont un profil différent de l'utilisation d'Internet, l'indicatif de connexion en ligne, alors que les adolescents ayant des antécédents d'automutilation non suicidaire sont le plus souvent comparables à des personnes qui ne sont jamais engagés dans l’AMNS. Les résultats soulignent l'importance de l'Internet comme une forme de soutien pour les adolescents qui s’engage a l'AMNS.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nancy Lee Heath</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw62f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ck55j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avd66w265v"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Attention filtering of visual information by prefrontal cortex neural ensembles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tremblay, Sebastien</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L’attention sélective est le processus cognitif par lequel le cerveau attribue ses ressources de manière préférentielle aux stimulations sensorielles qui sont importantes pour la survie de l’organisme. Les techniques d’enregistrement unicellulaire appliquées au cerveau du singe macaque ont révélé certains corrélats neuronaux de ce processus de sélection attentionnel. Toutefois, les dynamiques de populations neuronales qui régissent ce processus cognitif sont largement inconnues. Dans cette thèse doctorale, j’ai investigué les dynamiques de population neuronales qui sous-tendent l’attention visuelle dans le cortex préfrontal latéral du singe macaque en utilisant des techniques d’enregistrement multicellulaire.Premièrement, j’ai emprunté des outils computationnels au champ d’apprentissage par machine afin d’extraire l’information attentionnelle contenue dans les patterns de potentiels d’action générés par les populations neuronales préfrontales. À partir de cette activité, j’ai été en mesure de prédire le focus attentionnel des singes de manière presque instantanée, ce qui suggère que cette région cérébrale pourrait être la source des signaux attentionnels qui régissent le traitement cognitif normal.Deuxièmement, j’ai comparé l’activité des potentiels d’action à l’activité des potentiels de champ local qui est composée d’oscillations électriques de basse fréquence dans l’espace extracellulaire. J’ai découvert que le focus attentionnel pouvait être décodé à partir de ces signaux, mais seulement pour certaines fréquences élevées. D’autant plus, j’ai trouvé que ces fréquences élevées reflétaient principalement l’activité des potentiels d’action des neurones.Finalement, en combinant les techniques d’investigation précédentes avec une intervention pharmacologique, j’ai été en mesure de démontrer que le méthylphénidate, le médicament le plus prescrit pour traiter le déficit d’attention chez l’enfant, réduit un certain type d’interaction inter-neuronale délétère au traitement de l’information. J’ai aussi démontré que cet effet du méthylphénidate sur les propriétés des réseaux neuronaux provoquait une augmentation de la qualité du codage des signaux attentionnels par les populations de neurones préfrontaux.En résumé, ces résultats devraient améliorer notre compréhension des mécanismes neuronaux par lesquels le cortex préfrontal supporte les fonctions attentionnelles. D’autant plus, ces découvertes devraient ouvrir de nouvelles avenues de recherche clinique visant à développer de meilleurs traitements pour les enfants et adultes souffrant d’un déficit d’attention.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Selective attention is the cognitive process by which processing resources are preferentially attributed to behaviourally relevant sensory stimulations. Single electrode studies in the macaque monkey brain have identified the single neuron correlates of this selection process within both sensory and higher-order associative areas. However, the neural ensemble correlates of this cognitive process remain poorly documented. In this doctoral thesis, I have studied the neural ensemble correlates of visual attention within the primate lateral prefrontal cortex using multielectrode recording techniques.First, I have employed computational tools borrowed from the field of machine learning to extract the attentional information contained in the spiking activity of prefrontal neural ensembles. I was able to predict the focus of attention from this activity on a single-trial basis, indicating that this region could drive the attentional selection process within behaviourally relevant timeframes. Second, I have compared the spiking activity of the neural ensembles to the local field potential activity, which is composed of low frequency voltage oscillations within the extracellular space. I found that attention could be decoded in a frequency-dependent manner from these signals. Moreover, I found evidence that high-frequency gamma oscillations are mostly reflecting spiking activity.Finally, by combining the previous approach with a pharmacological intervention, I have found that methylphenidate, the most widely prescribed drug to treat attention deficit disorders, reduces inter-neuronal interactions that are detrimental to information coding. I have also shown that this network effect of the drug leads to improved coding of attentional signals by prefrontal cortex neural ensembles.Overall, these results will help further our basic understanding of the neural mechanisms by which the prefrontal cortex supports attentional functions in the primate brain. In addition, it should illuminate new clinical research avenues aimed at designing better treatments for children and adults with attention deficit disorders.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michalakis Petrides</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Julio Martinez Trujillo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059cb31n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w265v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d570047d"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of PKA signaling in dendritic cells that regulates Treg homeostasis and its applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lao, Qicheng</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le rôle physiologique des voies de signalisation de la protéine kinase A (PKA) a été largement étudié, mais leur rôle dans le système immunitaire reste largement obscur. Dans cette étude, nous démontrons que les voies de signalisation de la PKA jouent un rôle important dans la régulation des fonctions suppressives des cellules dendritiques, en régulant l’homéostasie des cellules T régulatrices Foxp3+ (Tregs). Nous avons découvert que l’activation conditionnelle de la PKA dans les cellules dendritiques entraine une expansion globale des cellules Treg CD4+Foxp3+ périphériques. L’altération de l’homéostasie des Tregs n’est pas causée par une augmentation de la production thymique des Treg mais par une augmentation de la prolifération et de la survie des cellules Treg matures en périphérie. Les cellules dendritiques dont la PKA est activée produisent significativement plus d’interleukine 2 et favorisent la survie et la prolifération des Tregs. En conséquence, les tumeurs grossissent beaucoup plus rapidement lorsqu’elles sont inoculées dans des souris dont la PKA est conditionnellement activée dans les cellules dendritiques, ce qui indique que le système immunitaire de ces souris est inhibé. Nos découvertes pourraient ouvrir la voie à de nouvelles stratégies thérapeutiques pour des maladies reliées au système immunitaire impliquant une homéostasie perturbée des Treg, comme par exemple les maladies auto-immunes et les tumeurs.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The protein kinase A (PKA) signaling pathway has been extensively studied for its role in physiology; however, its role in the immune system remains largely unclear. In this study, we demonstrate that the PKA signaling pathway plays an important role in the regulation of dendritic cell suppressive function by regulating the homeostasis of FoxP3+ regulatory T cells (Tregs). We find that conditional activation of PKA in DCs results in a global expansion of peripheral Foxp3+CD4+ Treg cells. The altered Treg homeostasis is not caused by an increased thymic output but rather the increased proliferation and survival of peripheral mature Treg cells. The PKA activated DCs produced significantly more IL-2 and supported the survival and proliferation of Treg cells. As a consequence, inoculated tumor grew much faster in DC-specific PKA knockout mice than in wildtype controls, indicating that immune suppression was enhanced in vivo. Our findings may provide a new strategy for clinical therapies of immune system related diseases involving disturbed Treg homeostasis, including autoimmune diseases and tumor.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hua Gu</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j8294.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d570047d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78tg03s"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Network-based RF localization in adverse propagation environments</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yousefi, Siamak</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Network-based radio frequency (RF) localization has gained considerable attention in the past decade due to the tremendous number of applications where location information is required while conventional localization systems, such as the global positioning system (GPS), cannot be employed. Positioning in harsh propagation environments such as dense urban areas, indoor places and underground areas, where the GPS satellites are not visible to the receiver are among such applications. Network-based RF localization, where instead of satellites, a set of fixed reference nodes transmit and/or receive signal to/from a wireless device (target) can overcome the limitations of the GPS. Nevertheless, localization in harsh propagation environments is challenging and can lead to large errors due to the non-line of sight (NLOS) propagation. In this case, the direct path cannot be detected, thus the time of arrival (TOA) and hence range measurements become positively biased.In this thesis, we study different localization scenarios in a wireless sensor network (WSN) with positively biased range measurements. As the first contribution of this thesis, we develop a constrained square-root unscented Kalman filter (CSRUKF) for TOA-based mobile target tracking in NLOS and then extend it to a cooperative scenario for multiple target tracking. As the second contribution, we propose a robust distributed technique for cooperative localization of sensors in a WSN without prior identification of NLOS links. As the third contribution, we study a geometric problem in WSNs, where due to NLOS every target is restricted to lie inside the intersection of several disks, forming a convex hull. To quantify the size of these convex hulls, an iterative distributed technique based on the idea of belief propagation has been employed, where a crucial step in each iteration is to find a tighter ellipsoidal outer approximation (OA) of the intersection of multiple ellipses. We develop a novel technique in 2-dimensions to obtain tighter OA compared to other techniques and consequently more accurate location estimates can be obtained efficiently.The new localization algorithms developed in this thesis are well suited to the next generation of cellular and WSN positioning systems, where efficient distributed techniques that are robust against NLOS propagation will be needed to support various applications.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La localisation par fréquence radio (RF) dans les réseaux sans fil a attiré une attention considérable dans la dernière décennie en raison de grand nombre d’applications qui ont besoin d’information de localisation, tandis que les systèmes de localisation classiques tells que le système mondial de localisation (GPS) ne peuvent pas être utilisés. Parmi ces applications, nous notons le positionnement dans les environnements avec conditions de propagation radio d’afordables, tels que les zones urbaines denses ainsi que les lieux intérieurs et souterrains où les satellites GPS ne sont pas visibles au récepteur et où le signal GPS est considérablement atténué. La localisation RF basée sur les réseau terrestriels, qui au lieu de stellites, utilise un ensemble de points de référence radio fixes pour transmettre et/ou recevoir des signaux vers/à partir d’un appareil sans fil (cible) peut surmonter les limitations du GPS. Les points de référence pouvent être des stations de base dans un réseau cellulaire, ou des ancres dans un réseau de capteurs sans fil (WSN). Néanmoins, la localisation dans des environnements avec propagation difficile est problématique et peut mener à des erreurs importantes en raison de propagation multi-trajet et sans ligne de vue (NLOS). Le problème de locailsation NLOS, dans lequel les mesures de la distance deviennent positivement biasées, reste toujours le défi principal.La première contribution de cette thèse met l’accent sur la localisation mobile NLOS en utilisant des mesures TOA, où un nouveau filtre de Kalman, de type racine-carrè sans parfum (unscented) avec contrainte (CSRUKF) est développé. Le filtre proposé est ensuite utilisé dans un scénario de localisation coopérative où un CSRUKF centralisé est utilisé pour le suivi multi-cibles dans les scénarios NLOS. Les résultats des simulations démontrent que le filter proposé peut donner une bonne précision de localisation dans les situations NLOS sévères et est également robuste contre les fausses alarmes aux identifications NLOS.Les techniques centralisées souffrent de la complexité calculs et ne sont pas extensibles en proportion à la taille du réseau. Par conséquent, les techniques de localisation distribuées sont préférables dans de nombreuses applications, et elle constituent la deuxième contribution de cette thèse. Plus particulièrement, un algorithme robuste distribué en deux étapes est proposé pour la localisation coopérative avec réseau de capteurs en utilisant les données TOA sans identification préalable NLOS. Par des simulations et l’analyse de données réelle, il est démontré que l’algorithme proposé peut atteindre une racine de l’erreur quadratique moyenne plus faible que celle des algorithms existants, et ainsi atteindre une performance se rapprochant du cas idéal dans lequel la connaissance a priori des liens NLOS est disponible.La troisième contribution de cette thèse porte sur l’analyse d’un problème géométrique dans les réseaux de capteurs où les mesures de TOA sont biaisées positivement en raison d’une condition NLOS. Ainsi, la position de chacune des cibles est contrainte de se trouver à l’intérieur de l’intersection de plusieurs disques, formant une coque convexe. Pour quantifier la taille de ces enveloppes convexes, deux nouvelles techniques sont développées et étudiées pour trouver des OAs plus serrées dans lespace à deux dimensions. Les simulations démontrent que l’algorithme qui utilise ces nouvelles techniques OA ellipsoïdales converge rapidement vers une limite et offer une estimation plus serrée des enveloppes convexes par rapport au cas où OA ellipsoïdale classique est utilisée. Les nouveaux algorithmes de localisation développés dans cette thèse sont bien adaptés à la prochaine génération de systèmes de positionnement cellulaires et WSN, où des techniques distribuées efficaces qui sont robustes contre la propagation NLOS seront nécessaires afin de soutenir diverses applications.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Xiao-Wen Chang</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Benoit Champagne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mj34p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tg03s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rh36d"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Preferred locations of convective storms over Southern Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kovacs, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The occurrence of deep convection over southern Québec exhibits strong mesoscale variability.  According to the 9-year radar climatology of deep convection by Bellon and Zawadzki (2003, or BZ03), a meridional axis of low convective activity extends from the Adirondack mountains of New York north through Montreal and into the Laurentian mountains.  To the east, convection hotspots within the Champlain Valley of New York extend northeastward through the eastern suburbs of Montreal, most notably near Trois Rivières.  While these findings suggest strong topographic controls on the regional convection signature, BZ03’s 9-year data analysis may have been insufficient to obtain a robust climatological signature.  Moreover, they did not physically explain the mechanisms that might give rise to the observed deep-convection signature.  Herein we build on BZ03 by extending the radar climatology to the 1993-2014 period and performing a suite of quasi-idealized, convection-permitting numerical simulations of convection events over the region.  The extended climatology confirms that BZ03’s results are robust, and that the regional convection patterns strongly depend on the low-to-mid level geostrophic wind directions.  To physically interpret these findings, we conduct quasi-idealized simulations that use the real terrain and land use of the region but are initialized horizontally homogeneously using composite soundings based on the climatology.  This model set-up is designed to directly test our hypothesis that topographic variations play a key role in the regional convection climatology.  The simulations and sensitivity tests reveal that pockets of orographic-induced moisture and mass convergence to the lee of larger terrain features explains most of the observed regional variability in convection occurrence along with positive anomalies of mixing ratio (qv) and convective available potential energy (CAPE).  However, the relationship between simulated convective-storm occurrence and convective inhibition (CIN) is more complicated.  While low CIN generally favors more storm activity, some areas of larger CIN are collocated with convection hotspots.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L’apparition de convection profonde au sud du Québec démontre une forte variabilité méso-échelle.  Selon l’étude du radar climatologique de 9 ans de la convection profonde établie par Bellon et Zawadzki (2003 ou BZ03), un axe méridien de faible activité convective s’étend à partir des montagnes Adirondack de New York, au nord à travers Montréal et dans les Laurentides.  À l'est, les maxima de convection régionale de la vallée du lac Champlain de New York prolongent vers le nord au travers des banlieues de l'est de Montréal, notamment à proximité de Trois-Rivières.  Bien que ces résultats suggèrent de forts contrôles topographiques sur la signature de convection régionale, l'analyse des données de 9 ans de BZ03 risque d'être insuffisant pour obtenir une signature climatologique robuste.  En outre, ils n’expliquent pas, de façon concrete, les mécanismes qui pourraient donner lieu à la signature convection profonde observée.  Ici, nous ajoutons aux résultats de l’étude de BZ03 en prolongeant le radar climatologique à la période de 1993-2014 et en effectuant une série de simulations numériques de convection quasi-idéalisées sur la région.  La climatologie prolongée confirme que les résultats de BZ03 sont robustes, et que les modèles de convection régionales dépendent fortement des vents géostrophique directionnels de bas à mi-niveau.  Afin d’interpréter physiquement ces résultats, nous effectuons des simulations quasi-idéalisées en utilisant le terrain réel ainsi que l'utilisation des terres de la région, avec des sondages composites à base de la climatologie qui sont initialisées horizontalement et de façon homogène.  L’objectif de la conception de ce modèle est de permettre de tester directement notre hypothèse que les variations topographiques jouent un rôle clé dans la climatologie de la convection régionale.  Les simulations et les épreuves de sensibilité révèlent que les poches d'humidité orographiquement induites et la convergence de masse à l'abri de grandes caractéristiques du terrain expliquent la majorité de la variabilité régionale observée en l’occurrence convective, ainsi que les anomalies positives de rapport de mélange (r) et de l’énergie potentielle de convection disponible (EPCD).  Cependant, la relation entre l’occurrence de tempête-convective simulée et l'énergie d’inhibition de la convection (EIC) est plus complexe. Bien qu’une faible EIC favorise généralement plus d'activité de tempête, certaines zones de EIC plus élevée sont colloqées avec les maxima de convection.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daniel Kirshbaum</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m702n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rh36d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956j801"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Moments of Eisenstein series on convex co-compact hyperbolic manifolds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Munroe, Patrick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We investigate the high-energy limits of the moments of Eisenstein series, when these functions are considered as real random variables over a compact subset of a convex co-compact hyperbolic manifold. In the first part, under a restriction on the Hausdorff dimension of the limit set of the fundamental group of the manifold, we prove a general formula describing all the moments of the Eisenstein series at high-energy. In particular, we show that all the odd-order moments vanish. In the second part, we study the rate of convergence of the moments in the high-energy limit. In the case of the odd-order moments, we prove that the rate of convergence is at least polynomial. As for the even-order moments, following an approach based on the work of Guillarmou and Naud concerning the equidistribution of Eisenstein series, we find a polynomial error term for the fourth moment under the additional hypothesis that the manifold in question is a surface.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Nous étudions les moments des séries d'Eisenstein dans la limite des hautes énergies, lorsque ces fonctions sont considérées en tant que variables aléatoires sur un sous-ensemble compact d'une variété hyperbolique convexe co-compacte. Dans un premier temps, en imposant une condition sur la dimension de Hausdorff de l'ensemble limite du groupe fondamental de la variété, nous obtenons une formule générale décrivant tous les moments des séries d'Eisenstein à hautes énergies. Dans un second temps, nous étudions la vitesse de convergence des moments dans la limite des hautes énergies. Dans le cas des moments d'ordre impair, nous démontrons que la vitesse de convergence est au moins polynomiale. En ce qui concerne les moments d'ordre pair, en suivant une approche basée sur les travaux de Guillarmou et Naud concernant l'équidistribution des séries d'Eisenstein, nous trouvons un terme d'erreur d'ordre polynomial pour le quatrième moment en ajoutant l'hypothèse que la variété en question est une surface.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dmitry Jakobson</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vb549.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956j801</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics and Statistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343v909"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of drug resistance mechanisms in intact Plasmodium falciparum-infected red blood cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Reiling, Sarah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Avec la moitié de la population mondiale à risque d’infection, le paludisme est un problème important de santé mondiale. Parmi les espèces de Plasmodium qui infectent les humains, P. falciparum provoque la majorité des décès. Pendant des décennies, la chloroquine (CQ) a été le médicament privilégié. Le mécanisme exact de la résistance à la CQ n'est pas encore connu. Il a été proposé que la CQ s'accumulait dans la vacuole digestive du parasite, où elle déploie son action antipaludique.Plusieurs transporteurs sont impliqués dans la distribution intracellulaire des médicaments antipaludiques dont le P. falciparum chloroquine resistance transporter (PfCRT) et le P. falciparum multidrug resistance 1 transporter (PfMDR1). Tous les deux sont situés dans la membrane de la vacuole digestive, mais ils transportent des substrats dans des directions opposées. Alors que la variante PfCRT porteuse de la mutation de la chloroquine K76T transporte la CQ hors de la vacuole digestive (VD), PfMDR1 transporte des substrats dans la VD. PfMDR1 contient cinq polymorphismes proposés comme étant impliqués dans le transport altéré de la drogue. Le rôle exact de chaque mutation dans ces acides aminés reste inconnu. Les variantes polymorphiques composées des divers types de mutations ont été analysées en utilisant le substrat fluorescent Fluo-4 pour identifier les fonctions de transport de PfMDR1. Nous avons trouvé un rôle primordial de transport de Fluo-4 au niveau de l'asparagine (N) localisée au résidu 1042, alors que la substitution de cet acide aminé par un acide aspartique (D) abolissait tous les transports. Nous avons aussi montré une association de la mutation PfMDR1 N1042D avec une sensibilité accrue pour la méfloquine. De plus, des études de compétition de Fluo-4 avec les antipaludiques tels que la chloroquine, méfloquine et quinine ont montré des profils d'inhibition de transport distincts pour les parasites d'origines génétiques différentes.Ensuite, nous avons étudié le mécanisme de la résistance à la chloroquine plus en détail. Nous avons montré que la survie des parasites était plus élevée chez les parasites CQ-résistants (CQR) par rapport aux parasites CQ-sensibles (CQS) après exposition à des concentrations de CQ également létales. Par ailleurs, des structures cytosoliques sombres ont été observées dans les parasites CQS. Des compartiments contenant de l’hémozoïne entouré d'une membrane bicouche ont été ensuite confirmés. L’hypothèse de perforations de la VD entraînant la fuite ultérieure des cristaux des hémozoïnes n’a pas été retenue car lyse de la membrane vacuolaire digestive n'a pas eu lieu au cours de ce laps de temps. Ces données suggèrent que la résistance à la CQ n'est pas seulement liée à des concentrations de médicament réduites dans la VD.Par ailleurs, un analogue fluorescent de la chloroquine disponible dans le commerce LynxTag™-CQ-GREEN (CQ-GREEN) a été examiné étant approprié pour l’étudie du transport de la CQ et de l'accumulation intracellulaire du médicament. La CQ-GREEN était à moitié efficace pour tuer les parasites CQS que la CQ non modifiée, mais nous n’avons pas observé de changement significatif dans la destruction des parasites CQR. De plus, l'imagerie des cellules vivantes a permis de montrer que la CQ-GREEN s’accumulait dans le cytosol des parasites et non dans la VD. Ces résultats montrent pour la première fois une cible potentielle d’un analogue à la CQ hors de la VD. Les quantités d'accumulation intracellulaire de CQ-GREEN ont été réduites chez les parasites CQR par rapport aux parasites CQS et ainsi suggère que les parasites CQR semblent avoir développés un mécanisme régulateur pour diminuer l'accumulation de CQ intracellulaire.Les résultats présentés dans cette thèse élargissent notre compréhension du transport de substrat de PfMDR1. En plus, ces données suggèrent que des mécanismes de régulation modifiés, probablement situés dans le cytosol des parasites, jouent un rôle dans la résistance à la CQ.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Malaria is a major global health concern, with half of the world’s population being at risk of infection. Among the Plasmodium species that infect humans, P. falciparum causes most fatalities. Chloroquine (CQ) was the drug of choice for decades and considered safe, affordable and easy-to-use until resistance emerged. However, the exact mechanism of CQ resistance is not known. CQ is suggested to accumulate in the parasite’s digestive vacuole due to its weak base properties, where it exerts its antimalarial action. Several transporters are involved in intracellular distribution of antimalarial drugs. Among them are the P. falciparum chloroquine resistance transporter (PfCRT) and the P. falciparum multidrug resistance 1 transporter (PfMDR1). Both are located in the digestive vacuolar membrane but transport substrates in opposing directions. While PfCRT transports substrates out of the digestive vacuole (DV), PfMDR1 transports substrates into the DV. PfMDR1 contains five polymorphisms that are suggested to be involved in altered drug transport, although the exact role of each amino acid mutation remains unknown. To gain more insight into the transport functions of PfMDR1, variants with different mutation patterns were analyzed using the fluorescent substrate Fluo-4. We found a crucial role for asparagine (N) at residue 1042 in Fluo-4 transport, while substitution with aspartic acid (D) abolished all transport. In addition, we showed an association of the PfMDR1 N1042D mutation with increased mefloquine but decreased quinine sensitivity. Furthermore, competition studies of Fluo-4 with the antimalarial drugs chloroquine, mefloquine and quinine showed distinct transport inhibition patterns for parasites of different genetic background. This can be used as a tool to evaluate parasite susceptibility to antimalarial drugs.Next, we investigated the mechanism of resistance to CQ in more detail. We showed that parasite survival is higher in CQ-resistant strains compared to CQ-sensitive strains in the initial 10 hours after exposure to equally lethal CQ concentrations. Moreover, dark cytosolic structures appeared in CQ-sensitive strains that were later confirmed as hemozoin-containing compartments surrounded by a membrane bilayer. Leakage of hemozoin crystals out of the DV was ruled out since lysis of the digestive vacuolar membrane did not occur during that time frame. These data suggest that CQ resistance is not linked to reduced drug concentrations in the DV alone, and additional regulatory mechanisms in the parasite must play a crucial role during CQ exposure.To pursue these findings, a commercially available fluorescent tagged CQ analogue, LynxTag™-CQ-GREEN (CQ-GREEN), was examined for its suitability in studying CQ transport and intracellular drug accumulation. While CQ-GREEN was half as effective in parasite killing of CQ-sensitive strains compared to unmodified CQ, no significant changes in parasite killing were observed in CQ-resistant strains. However, live cell imaging showed that CQ-GREEN accumulated in the parasite cytosol and not the DV. These results show for the first time a potential target for a CQ analogue outside the digestive vacuole. Moreover, intracellular CQGREEN uptake rates were reduced in CQ-resistant strains compared to CQ-sensitive strains. This, too, suggests that CQ-resistant strains must have evolved a regulatory mechanism to decrease intracellular CQ accumulation.The results presented in this thesis expand our understanding of substrate transport by PfMDR1. Furthermore, a novel phenotype was described for CQ-sensitive strains upon drug exposure that was not seen in CQ-resistant strains. These data suggest that altered regulatory mechanisms play a role in CQ resistance and are likely located in the parasite cytosol.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Petra Rohrbach</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pt47g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343v909</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Parasitology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn107198n"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of metabolic reprogramming in breast cancer progression and metastasis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dupuy, Fanny</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract> Breast cancer is the most commonly diagnosed cancer in woman and the emergence of metastasis is the most deadly aspect of the disease. Major bioenergetic and biosynthetic demands are associated with proliferation in order to sustain the exponential growth of a primary tumor and metabolic pathways must be reprogrammed to meet these demands. However, the metabolic challenges of cells during tumor initiation will differ from those that occur during tumor progression and dissemination. Despite progress in understanding the underlying mechanisms of how altered metabolism fuels the growth of primary tumors, the role that metabolic reprogramming plays in the metastatic process remains poorly characterized. This work focused on identifying the regulators of metabolic reprogramming and defining their roles in mediating breast cancer growth and metastasis. Using transgenic mouse models, we showed that loss of LKB1 cooperates with ErbB2 to promote breast cancer initiation and progression at early stages. Loss of LKB1 resulted in the activation of mTOR signaling, conferring a pro-growth metabolic advantage to the tumors. However, LKB1-deficient tumor cells displayed greater sensitivity to glucose limitation compared to their LKB1-proficient counterparts, suggesting a lack of metabolic flexibility that was rescued by rapamycin-mediated suppression of mTOR signaling.To investigate the metabolic reprogramming associated with breast cancer progression we compared the metabolic profiles of breast cancer cells that originated from a single primary tumor; however, which display different abilities to metastasize. Our results reveal an overall increase in metabolic activity (glycolysis and OXPHOS) that correlates with an increase in metastatic potential. However, we demonstrated that upon dissemination, metastatic breast cancer cells engage distinct metabolic programs depending on the site of metastasis. Using breast cancer explants isolated from bone, lung or liver metastases, we demonstrate a bifurcation in the way these cells utilize available carbon sources. Mitochondrial metabolism is elevated in bone- and lung-metastatic cells while liver-metastatic breast cancer cells preferentially engage glycolysis. We next determined the molecular mechanisms responsible for the glycolytic switch observed in the liver-metastatic breast cancer cells. The transcription factor HIF-1α is activated in liver-metastatic breast cancer cells under normoxic conditions and partially responsible for the observed metabolic reprogramming. Downstream of HIF-1α, PDK1 (pyruvate dehydrogenase kinase 1) was identified as an important driver of metabolic adaptation to energetic stress and was required for efficient liver metastasis. Our work demonstrates that, while loss of metabolic regulators may be advantageous for cancer initiation and early progression, retaining these key checkpoints is critical for metabolic adaptation to stress and successful metastatic dissemination.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le cancer du sein est le cancer le plus fréquemment diagnostiqué chez la femme et l’apparition de métastases est l’aspect le plus meurtrier de la maladie. Si d’important besoins énergétique et biosynthétique sont associés à la prolifération de la tumeur primaire et ceci afin de maintenir une croissance exponentielle, les défis métaboliques rencontrés par une cellule tumorale au cours de la phase d’initiation de la tumeur sont très différents de ceux rencontrés pendant la phase de progression et la phase métastatique. Malgré une meilleure compréhension des mécanismes selon lesquels un métabolisme altéré promeut la croissance de tumeurs primaires, le rôle de la reprogrammation métabolique dans le processus métastatique demeure peu caractérisé. Le travail présenté ici se concentre sur l’identification des régulateurs de la reprogrammation métabolique ainsi que sur la définition de leur rôle dans l’évolution du cancer du sein et de ses métastases. A l’aide de modèles de souris transgéniques, j’ai montré que la perte de LKB1 coopère avec ErbB2 afin de promouvoir l’initiation du cancer du sein et sa progression durant les stades précoces. La perte de LKB1 abouti à l’inactivation de la voie de signalisation mTOR, conférant un avantage métabolique à la croissance des tumeurs. Toutefois, les cellules cancéreuses qui sont dépourvues de LKB1 affichent une sensibilité accrue aux restrictions en glucose par rapport à leurs homologues qui possèdent LKB1. Ce résultat suggère un manque de flexibilité métabolique qui peut être restauré par une suppression de la signalisation médiée par mTOR suite à un traitement avec la rapamycin. Afin d’étudier la reprogrammation métabolique associée à la progression du cancer du sein, j’ai comparé les profiles métaboliques de lignées du cancer du sein issues d’une même tumeur primaire mais présentant des capacités différentes à métastaser. Mes résultats révèlent une augmentation globale de l’activité métabolique (glycolyse et OXPHOS) qui corrèle avec une augmentation du potentiel métastatique. J’ai démontré par ailleurs que suite à cette dissémination, les cellules métastatiques du cancer du sein engagent des programmes métaboliques différents selon leur site de métastase. A l’aide d’explants isolés de métastases du cancer du sein présentes dans l’os, le poumon ou le foie, j’ai démontré un différentiel dans la façon dont ces cellules utilisent les sources de carbone disponibles. Le métabolisme mitochondrial est élevé dans les lignées métastatiques de l’os et du poumon tandis que les lignées du cancer du sein provenant des métastases hépatiques utilisent préférentiellement la glycolyse. J’ai alors déterminé les mécanismes moléculaires responsables de la conversion glycolytique observée dans les lignées de métastases hépatiques du cancer du sein. Le facteur de transcription HIF-1α, activé dans des conditions normoxiques dans ces cellules, est partiellement responsable de cette reprogrammation métabolique. J’ai identifié PDK1 (pyruvate déshydrogénase kinase 1), en aval de HIF-1α, comme un moteur important de l’adaptation métabolique aux conditions de stress énergétique et montré que sa présence est requise pour la formation pérenne de métastases hépatiques. Mon travail démontre que la perte de régulateurs métaboliques peut s’avérer avantageux dans la formation des tumeurs et leur progression initiale, cependant, conserver la capacité d’activer ces points de contrôle est critique pour l’adaptation métabolique aux conditions de stress qu’implique le processus tumoral et métastatique.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Russell Jones</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Peter Siegel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hg106.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107198n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c555g"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sustained release of milrinone using microparticles: new strategy for future therapy in heart failure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al Kindi, Hamood</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>       Purpose: The aim of this study is to construct a new drug delivery system for milrinone (Mil) using microparticles. This novel technology enhances drug bioavailability, decreases cytotoxicity and dosage frequency with future implication in the treatment of patients with end-stage heart failure.       Methods: Polylactic-co-glycolic acid microparticles (PLGA-MPs) loaded with Mil were prepared by double emulsion-solvent evaporation technique. In-vitro release kinetics was estimated at T: 37C° and PH: 7.4. Twenty-four female Lewis rats were randomized into one of the three groups (n=8 per group), one week after left anterior descending artery ligation: Group I received intravenous (IV) injection of PLGA-MPs (250 µL); Group II received bolus IV Mil (50µg/kg/min prepared in 250 µL); and Group III received bolus IV Mil-PLGA-MPs with the same dose as Group II. All injections were given intravenously via tail vein over 10 mines. Transthoracic echocardiography and non-invasive heart rate and blood pressure measurements were performed at different pre-determined time intervals for 24hrs after the injection. After that, all rats were sacrificed and plasma was taken for cytokine assays and Mil level using HPLC.         Results: In-vitro Mil-release kinetic studies showed a slow release of Mil over a 24-hour [Figure1]. Rats in Group III had significantly higher left-ventricular ejection fraction at 90mins, 3hrs, 6hrs and 12hrs post-treatment compared to other groups [Table1]. Plasma level of Mil at 24 hrs. post-injection was significantly higher in Group III compared to other groups (Group I= 0, Group II= 1.7 ±2.4, Group III=9.1±2.2 ng/ml, P&lt; 0.05). The levels of ICAM and CINC-1 were lower in Group III compared to other groups (P&lt;0.05).         Conclusions: Inotropic drug encapsulation using microparticles can prolong the clinical effects of milrinone. The current study may provide a new strategy for future drug delivery in patients with end-stage heart failure.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Objectif:Le but de cette étude est de construire un nouveau système d’administration de médicaments pour milrinone (Mil ) utilisant des microparticules. Cette nouvelle technologie améliore la biodisponibilité du médicament, diminue la cytotoxicité et la fréquence de dosage avec implication future dans le traitement des patients atteints d'insuffisance cardiaque au stade terminal. Méthodes: Microparticules d'acide polylactique -co- glycolique (PLGA- PM) chargés de Mil ont été préparés par la technique de double émulsion évaporation de solvant. In vitro cinétique de libération a été estimé à T : 37C ° et PH : 7.4. Vingt-quatre rats Lewis femelles ont été randomisés dans l'un des trois groupes (n = 8 par groupe), une semaine après ligature de l'artère descendante antérieure gauche: Le groupe I a reçu par voie intraveineuse (IV) l'injection de PLGA- PM (250 ul ), le Groupe II reçu un bolus IV Mil (50μg/kg/min préparé dans 250 pi ) et le Groupe III a reçu un bolus IV Mil- PLGA - députés avec la même dose dans le groupe II. Toutes les injections ont été administrées par voie intraveineuse via la veine caudale sur une période de 10 minutes. L'échocardiographie transthoracique,  la fréquence cardiaque non-invasive et la pression artérielle ont été mesurés à différentes intervalles de temps prédéterminés pendant les 24 heures suivant l'injection. Après cela, tous les rats ont été sacrifiés et le plasma a été pris pour mesurer les dosages de cytokines et le niveau du Mil par HPLC. Résultats:Les étude de In vitro Mil libération études cinétiques ont montré une libération lente de Mil sur une période de  24  heures [ Figure 1 ]. Les rats du groupe III avaient une fraction d'éjection ventriculaire gauche significativement plus élevée à 90mins, 3h, 6h et 12h post- traitement par rapport  aux autres groupes [ Table1 ]. Le niveau de plasma de Mil à 24 heures  post- injection était significativement plus élevé dans le groupe III par rapport aux autres groupes (Groupe I = 0, le groupe II = 1,7 ± 2,4, le Groupe III = 9,1 ± 2,2 ng / ml, P &lt; 0,05 ). Les niveaux d' ICAM -1 et CINC étaient plus faibles dans le groupe III par rapport aux autres groupes (p &lt; 0,05 ). Conclusions :L’encapsulation de médicaments inotropes utilisant des microparticules peut prolonger les effets cliniques de milrinone. L'étude actuelle peut offrir une nouvelle stratégie pour l’administration future des médicaments chez les patients atteints d'insuffisance cardiaque au stade terminal.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dominique Shum-Tim</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sn25f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c555g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gg771"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Theory and simulation of defect dynamics in confined liquid crystals</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shams, Alireza</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les cristaux liquides sont des matériaux viscoélastiques auto-organisés avec longue portée ordre d'orientation partielle. Imperfection dans cet ordre donnent lieu à des défauts points, lignes, et les murs dont la dynamique et de géométrie reflète leur élasticité anisotrope et la viscosité. Pour les défauts de ligne confinement agit comme un champ externe qui affecte la dynamique de défauts et géométrique courbure de ligne. Cette thèse utilise la renormalisation de la dynamique de défauts de ligne et de la géométrie en raison du confinement pour extraire des propriétés viscoélastiques, évitant ainsi la mesure rhéologique complexe. Les géométries choisies sont cylindriques et coniques capillaires, où ce dernier affiche confinement gradients commun biologique cristaux liquides auto-assemblage. Le travail commence par la théorie classique de cristal liquide qui élasticité dans 1dimension est montré pour la première fois que la carte dans le modèle de elastica Euler pour cordes élastiques avec la tension et rigidité à la flexion. La tension et des coefficients de flexion dans le cristal liquide élastique sont dérivés en termes de modules d'élasticité de la phase brute.Utilisation trempes thermiques, les transformations de texture impliquant lignes de disinclinaison sont trouvés et décrits en utilisant des modèles géométriques-elastica. Les différentes étapes dans les transformations ont des caractéristiques uniques telles que la ramification, les collisions de la boucle, la croissance de la boucle, qui sont comparés pour capillaires cylindriques à des expériences réelles de notre équipe de collaborateurs expérimentaux. Les données viscoélastique extrait se avère en bon accord avec les données disponibles viscoélastiques. La théorie et la modélisation a été étendu à capillaires coniques et de nouvelles prévisions en raison de gradients conduit confinement sont-analysés. La théorie et les simulations développées fournit une nouvelle méthode efficace d'utiliser défaut physique quantitatif prédire les propriétés viscoélastiques de la matière molle anisotrope.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Liquid crystals are self-organized viscoelastic materials with long range partial orientational order.  Imperfection in this order gives rise to point, line, and wall defects whose dynamics and geometry reflects their anisotropic elasticity and viscosity.  For line defects confinement acts as an external field that affects defect dynamics and geometric line curvature.  The present thesis uses the renormalization of line defect dynamics and geometry due to confinement to extract viscoelastic properties, thus avoiding complex rheological measurement.  The chosen geometries are cylindrical and conical capillaries, where the latter displays confinement gradients common in biological liquid crystal self-assembly. The work starts with the classical theory of liquid crystal elasticity which in 1dimension is shown for the first time to map into the Euler elastica model for elastic strings with tension and bending stiffness.  The tension and bending coefficients in the liquid crystal elastic are derived in terms of elastic moduli of the bulk phase.Using thermal quenches, textural transformations involving disclination lines are found and described using geometric-elastica models.  The different stages in the transformations have unique features such as branching, loop collisions, loop growth,  that are compared for cylindrical capillaries to actual experiments from our team experimental collaborators. The extracted viscoelastic data are shown to be in good agreement with available viscoelastic data.  The theory and modelling was extended to conical capillaries and new predictions due to confinement-driven gradients are analyzed. The developed theory and simulations provides an efficient new methodology to use defect physics for quantitative predict viscoelastic properties in anisotropic soft matter.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alejandro D. Rey</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c556r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg771</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9z9032691"><ual:graduationDate>2015</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Accounting for time-varying exposure in prospective safety monitoring for pharmacovigilance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>van Gaalen, Rolina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La pharmacovigilance consiste à surveiller l’innocuité des médicaments après leur approbation et leur commercialisation. Il est essentiel de détecter rapidement les effets indésirables d’un médicament pour en limiter les préjudices à ses utilisateurs. Dans les études post-commercialisation basées sur la population, l’exposition éventuelle au médicament de l’individuel et la dose changent au fil du temps, ce qui constitue un défi méthodologique de taille. En ce qui concerne l’évaluation des risques, les études de pharmacovigilance actuelles s’appuient pour la plupart sur des indicateurs choisis arbitrairement pour répondre de l’exposition, qui peuvent ne tiennent pas compte de l’information sur la dose, la durée et le moment de l’exposition. Une sélection de modèle arbitraire et imprécise, qui ne tient compte ni de la dose-réponse, ni des possibles effets retardés ou cumulatifs de l’exposition, peut retarder considérablement la détection d’une association par rapport à des modèles plus appropriés. Toutefois, avant le début de la pharmacovigilance, il n’y a généralement pas de preuves suffisantes sur la relation véritable entre une exposition au médicament variant avec le temps et le risque d’effets indésirables. Par conséquent, il est a priori peu probable de choisir le modèle d’exposition «étiologiquement correct». Cette thèse est basée sur simulations pour évaluer, dans une première étude, l’impact d’une mauvaise spécification du modèle d’exposition sur la rapidité de la détection du signal en pharmacovigilance prospective, en supposant des relations véritables différentes entre l’usage de drogues variant avec le temps et le risque d’effets indésirables. Les données simulées ont été analysées avec des modèles alternatifs d’estimations plus complexes à base de spline à de multiples temps d’essai attendus. Dans une deuxième étude, j’ai examiné la possibilité d’accélérer la détection en utilisant les résultats obtenus par un ensemble de modèles alternatifs de pharmacovigilance appliqués simultanément aux données d’exposition variant avec le temps. Dans les deux études, le Ç signal È a été généré d’après la valeur-p corrigée spécifique au modèle. D’après les résultats de ces deux études de simulation, le temps de détection du signal en pharmacovigilance prospective peut varier considérablement selon le modèle utilisé pour représenter les expositions passées. Aucun modèle d’estimation unique choisi a priori pour la pharmacovigilance n’a fonctionné de manière optimale dans différents scénarios simulés. Toutefois, il est possible de détecter une association opportune en se basant sur les indications d’un ensemble de modèles d’expositions. Enfin, dans une troisième étude, j’ai utilisé des données réelles pour illustrer la pertinence et les avantages pratiques des résultats des études antérieures. J’ai réévalué le risque d’infection grave causée par la prise de glucocorticoïdes dans une cohorte représentative de la population de patients atteints de polyarthrite rhumatoïde. La période entière de suivi, d’environ 20 ans, a été divisée en 20 intervalles d’essai, ce qui a permis l’analyse «prospective» de ces données et a reproduit une étude de pharmacovigilance. Les résultats ont confirmé que le temps de détection du signal dans la pharmacovigilance prospective réelle dépend du modèle d’exposition. Il est nécessaire d’effectuer une surveillance prospective des grandes bases de données pour assurer la détection rapide de problèmes d’innocuité liés aux produits pharmaceutiques. Cependant, le recours à des modèles d’exposition inappropriés peut retarder considérablement la détection des effets indésirables. Cette thèse démontre que la pharmacovigilance devrait se baser sur un ensemble de modèles alternatifs appliqués simultanément afin de réduire les problèmes liés à une sélection de modèle a priori et pour atténuer les effets d’un mauvais choix. Elle propose une méthode simple aux chercheurs qui effectuent la pharmacovigilance.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Pharmacovigilance monitors the safety of drugs after their approval and marketing. The timely detection of the adverse effects of a drug is critical to limit harm to its users. An important methodological challenge is related to the fact that in population-based post-marketing studies, the individual user’s drug exposure status and dose change over time. In assessing risk, most current pharmacovigilance studies rely on arbitrarily chosen metrics to account for exposure, such as current exposure or use in the past three months. Yet, such simple exposure models ignore information on dose, duration, and timing of exposure, all of which tend to affect the risk of an adverse event. Moreover, an arbitrary and inaccurate model selection, without suitable consideration for the dose-response and the possible lagged or cumulative effects of exposure, may substantially increase the time to detect an association compared to more appropriate models. However, appropriate model selection poses a considerable challenge for pharmacovigilance studies. Prior to the start of pharmacovigilance, there is generally insufficient evidence regarding the true relationship between a time-varying drug exposure and the risk of adverse events. Therefore, selecting the "etiologically correct" exposure model a priori is unlikely. In this thesis, I relied on extensive simulations to first assess the impact of exposure model misspecification on the timeliness of signal detection in prospective pharmacovigilance, assuming different true relationships between time-varying drug use and the adverse event hazard. Simulated data were analyzed by fitting alternative estimation models at multiple, pre-specified testing times. In a second study, I investigated whether time to detection could be reduced by relying on evidence from a set of alternative pharmacovigilance models, applied simultaneously to time-varying exposure data. I used five approaches for combining the results of alternative estimation models. In both studies, the "signal" was generated based on the corrected model-specific p-value. Results of these two simulation studies suggested that the time of signal detection depended on the model used to represent past exposures. No single estimation model selected a priori for pharmacovigilance performed optimally across different simulated scenarios. However, an association could be detected in a timely manner by relying on evidence from a set of exposure models applied simultaneously to exposure and time to event data. The approach that relied on a set of multiple exposure models may be simple, where a signal is generated when the p-value of the exposure model falls below a certain predetermined threshold. Finally, in a third study, I used real data to illustrate the relevance and practical advantages of the findings of the earlier studies. Specifically, I re-assessed the risk of serious infection from glucocorticoids in a population-based cohort of rheumatoid arthritis patients. The entire period of about 20 years of follow-up was divided into 20 testing intervals, enabling the "prospective" analysis of these data and thereby mimicking a pharmacovigilance study. Results confirmed that the time of signal detection in real-life prospective pharmacovigilance depended on the exposure model.Prospective monitoring of large databases is necessary to ensure the timely detection of safety concerns related to pharmaceuticals. However, this thesis shows that relying on inappropriate exposure models may significantly prolong the time to adverse event detection. To alleviate the challenges of a priori model selection, and to reduce the impact of a poor choice, this thesis demonstrates that pharmacovigilance should rely on a set of alternative models simultaneously, and provides a simple method for investigators to consider when conducting pharmacovigilance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David Buckeridge</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Michal Abrahamowicz</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128d96k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9032691</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>