<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axw42nb37d"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exploring 'father involvement' among caregiving fathers of children and youth with neurodisabilities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bogossian, Aline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les connaissances sur les expériences des parents d'enfants atteints de troubles neurodéveloppementaux se sont développées rapidement au cours des trente dernières années. Pourtant, malgré des études plus approfondies, la recherche sur les «parents» et la «parentalité» est souvent neutre sur le plan du genre et reconnait moins les expériences parentales des pères. Cette thèse, issue du domaine du travail social, se compose de trois articles. Elle a été conçue pour explorer la façon dont les pères des enfants atteints de troubles neurodéveloppementaux conçoivent leur engagement auprès de leur enfant, avec le but d'approfondir les connaissances sur l'engagement des pères pour orienter la pratique clinique et la recherche future. Le premier article représente une revue exploratoire de la littérature empirique sur la parentalité des enfants ayants des troubles neurodéveloppementaux et décrit les dimensions affectives, comportementales et cognitives de l'engagement du père dans la littérature. Il révèle le caractère limité de la recherche sur les perspectives des pères, et, par une exploration systématique, identifie les aspects de l'engagement du père qui mériteraient d'être approfondis dans les recherches futures. Les deuxième et troisième articles rapportent les résultats d'une étude d'analyse phénoménologique interprétative d'entretiens réalisés avec onze pères biologiques d'enfants atteints de troubles neurodéveloppementaux. L'article 2 introduit l'approche de la recherche qualitative. Cet article décrit comment l'analyse phénoménologique interprétative (API, Smith et al.,2009) a été utilisée pour développer une compréhension des expériences parentales des pères d'enfants atteints de troubles neurodéveloppementaux. L'API permet une exploration approfondie des mondes uniques des participants et reconnait le rôle des chercheurs dans la co-construction de ces expériences. Ces principes ressemblent au point de départ de toute intervention de travail social avec des individus. L'article discute donc des parallèles entre l'API et le travail social. L'article 3 s'appuie sur les récits des pères pour approfondir et élargir la compréhension de la notion d'engagement du père. Les pères ont concentré leur énergie parentale à mieux comprendre leurs enfants afin de comprendre comment les aider. Trois thèmes principaux ont émergé du récit des pères. «Former les connexions - des perturbations aux nouvelles compréhensions» décrit les luttes et les joies des pères dans la paternité. Ce thème décrit aussi l'influence des contacts réciproques avec leurs enfants sur leur compréhension de leur rôle de père. «Prendre notre place dans le monde» décrit les expériences et les négociations des pères avec le monde à l'intérieur et à l'extérieur de leur famille. «Anticiper, émerger et grandir» décrit comment les pères sont venus à se comprendre et se développer différemment selon leur relation avec leur enfant. Les pères ont accordé une grande importance à l'établissement de liens physiques et émotionnels étroits avec leur enfant, bien que ce soit parfois un processus lent et frustrant. En l'absence d'un lien émotionnel ou d'information sur la façon de soutenir leur enfant, la parentalité était une traversée difficile et solitaire. Les implications pratiques de cette étude comprennent l'importance de la reconnaissance et du renforcement du lien émotionnel des pères avec leurs enfants, de discuter des expériences parentales avec les pères, de reconnaitre les pères comme ressources dans l'unité familiale et de prioriser les besoins d'information des pères. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The scholarship on 'parenting' children with neurodisabilities has developed rapidly over the past thirty years; yet, on closer examination, this scholarship on 'parents' and "parenting" is often gender neutral and less is known about the parenting experiences of fathers.  This dissertation, originating in the field of social work, is comprised of three related manuscripts.  It was designed to explore the meanings fathers of children with neurodisabilities draw from their engagement with their child in order to deepen theoretical understandings of fathers' involvement and to ultimately inform clinical practice with families.  The first article represents a scoping review of empirical literature on parenting in the context of childhood neurodisability and maps the affective, behavioural and cognitive dimensions of father involvement found within this scholarship.  It reveals the limited nature of research on fathers' perspectives and through a systematic exploration, identifies aspects of father involvement that may be more fully explored in future research.  The second and third articles represent an Interpretive Phenomenological Analysis study based on multiple conversations with eleven biological fathers of children with neurodisabilities.   Article 2 introduces Interpretive Phenomenological Analysis (IPA), qualitative research approach.  This article describes how Interpretive Phenomenological Analysis (IPA; Smith et al., 2009) was employed to develop an understanding of the parenting experiences of fathers of children with neurodisabilities. IPA allows for in-depth exploration of participants' unique worlds and acknowledges the researchers' role in co-constructing those experiences.  These tenets resemble the starting point of any social work intervention with individuals.   In this article, the congruence of IPA with social work is discussed. Article 3 draws on fathers' narratives to build depth and enhance understandings of the concept of "father involvement".  Fathers focused their parenting energy on understanding their child and understanding how to help their child with a neurodisability.  Three master themes emerged from fathers' narrative.  "Forming connections – from disruptions to new understandings" describes fathers' early struggles and joys in fatherhood and the influence of children's reciprocal contacts on fathers' understandings of their role. "Taking our place in the world" describes fathers' experiences and negotiations with the world inside and outside of their family.  "Anticipating, emerging and growing" describes how fathers came to understand themselves and grow in new ways as a function of their relationship with their child.  Fathers placed great importance on forging close physical and emotional connections with their child, though this was at times a slow and frustrating process.  In the absence of an emotional connection or of information about how to support their child, parenting was a difficult and solitary journey.  Practice implications of this study include the importance of noticing and reinforcing fathers' emotional connection with their children, discussing parenting experiences with fathers, acknowledging fathers as resources in the family unit, and prioritizing fathers' information needs. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lucyna Maria Lach</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t460f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nb37d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bx04f"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Information Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Constructing an effective electronic records management programme: policies, practices, and systems in an international legal context</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Sunghoon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude vise à comprendre comment les documents électroniques sont gérés par les tribunaux internationaux - en particulier à la Cour Pénale Internationale (CPI), qui est la première cour internationale électronique - et d'identifier divers facteurs qui soutiennent un programme de gestion des documents électroniques qui assure leur authenticité, fiabilité, intégrité et facilité d'utilisation.Cette étude a adopté une méthodologie de recherche mixte basée sur l'étude de cas. Les données ont été recueillies à l'aide de trois méthodes: (1) une enquête en ligne auprès des professionnels de l'information à la CPI ; (2) des entrevues semi-structurées en profondeur avec des professionnels de l'information sélectionnés en fonction de leurs rôles et responsabilités dans les processus de gestion des documents électroniques à la CPI ; (3) et les documents justificatifs.Les résultats de l'étude montrent que la gestion des documents électroniques est essentielle pour de la CPI et que le personnel est bien conscient de l'importance de la gestion des documents électroniques. Des politiques de gestion des documents ont été élaborées et mises en œuvre au niveau aussi bien de l'institution que des sections et unités en fonction de la politique organisationnelle de la cour. Les membres du personnel gérent les documents électroniques et les métadonnées tout au long du cycle de vie des documents en appliquant les politiques afférentes et en utilisant adéquatement les systèmes de gestion des documents électroniques. Un processus opérationnel collaboratif est nécessaire entre les organes et les sections pour assurer l'authenticité, la fiabilité et l'intégrité des dossiers. Une analyse des besoins fonctionnels des systèmes définit la sécurité des documents comme la fonction prioritaire en raison de la sensitivité des documents judiciaires. En outre, les résultats montrent que la gestion des documents électroniques doit s'adapter au contexte organisationnel pour être plus efficace et pratique. L'étude développe les composantes d'un programme de gestion des documents électroniques dans les organisations internationales. Elle définit ces composantes et explique les relations qui existent entre elles. Les quatre composantes sont: (1) les politiques et le cadre règlementaire; (2) les pratiques et procédures; (3) les systèmes  et  technologies; (4) et le contexte organisationnel. Un modèle de programme de gestion des documents fondé sur les quatre composantes peut être adapté à toute organisation internationale ainsi qu'aux différents types d'organismes judiciaires lorsqu'ils entreprennent ou révisent leur programme de gestion électronique des documents. En outre, cette étude suggère une liste des prérequis des systèmes pour les tribunaux internationaux qui peuvent être utilisées pour l'évaluation des systèmes existants ou pour la sélection d'un nouveau.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The objectives of this study are to understand how electronic records are managed in international courts--in particular, at the International Criminal Court (ICC), whichis the first international e-Court -- and to identify various factors that support an electronic records management programme that ensures the authenticity, reliability, integrity and usability of records. This study was designed to adopt the mixed research methods applying a case study strategy. Data was collected using three methods: (1) a web-based survey with information professionals at the ICC; (2) semi-structured in-depth interviews with selected information professionals based on their roles and responsibilities in the electronic records management processes at the ICC; and (3) supporting documentation.   The results of the study indicated that electronic records management is critical within the ICC, and the staff at the ICC is well aware of the importance of electronic records management. Records management policies have been developed and implemented at the organizational level as well as in the section/unit level because of the policy oriented organizational character at the ICC. Staff members have managed electronic records and metadata in the records' lifecycles by applying the related policies and using the electronic records management systems appropriately. A collaborative business process is required across organs and sections to ensure the authenticity, reliability and integrity of records. Throughout a functional requirements analysis for electronic records management systems, the security of records is defined as the critical function in the systems due to the sensitivity of legal records. In addition, the results show that electronic records management should adapt to an organizational context to be more effective and practical. This study develops the components of an electronic records management programme in international organizations and explains the definitions and relationship of each component. The four components include: (1) policy/regulation; (2) practice/procedure; (3) system/technology; and (4) organizational context. A model for a records management programme based on the four components can be adapted to any international organization as well as to different types of legal organizations when they initiate or review their electronic records management programme within an organization. Furthermore, this study suggests a list of system requirements for international courts that can be used for reviewing existing systems or selecting a new system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eun Gyung Park</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dg120.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx04f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Information Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn107160q"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A qualitative investigation into the educational experience of young adults with learning disabilities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Reinsma, Alyssa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'étude suivante est une étude qualitative des expériences académiques de quatre jeunes adultes ayant des troubles d'apprentissage et des déficiences associées. L'étude examine les modèles et les variations trouvés parmi les participants afin de mieux comprendre leurs expériences de l'école primaire jusqu'aux études postsecondaires. Au moment du recrutement, les quatre participants impliqués dans cette étude étaient inscrits ou récemment diplômés de programmes postsecondaires à Montréal. Ils ont partagé leurs expériences avec des chercheurs en entrevues semi-structurées individuelles. Les données ont été extraites par analyse thématique. Les conséquences des expériences éducatives des participants ont été classées en trois catégories: environnement social, milieu académique et environnement de soutien. Bien que beaucoup de diversité ait été trouvée chez les participants, d'importantes parallèles ont été découvertes.  Les participants ont relevé une hausse de difficulté à mesure qu'ils atteignaient des niveaux supérieurs d'éducation en raison d'une plus grande demande académique et d'une augmentation des charges de parcours.  Des expériences positives et négatives ont été signalées concernant les éducateurs et les services de soutien. Les éducateurs et le personnel de soutien qui ont prêté attention aux besoins des élèves et qui comprenaient leur handicap ont eu le plus grand impact parmi les étudiants.  Enfin, les étudiants ont bénéficié d'une compréhension de leurs propres handicaps, de leurs forces et de leurs besoins, ce qui était très utiles dans les milieux académiques et pour l'autonomie sociale. Cette étude renforci la littérature actuelle en apportant une nouvelle perspective, celle des étudiants eux-mêmes, en plus d'accroître la recherche relative au contexte canadien.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The following study is a qualitative investigation of the academic experiences of four young adults with learning and associated disabilities. The study explores patterns and variation found among participants in order to better understand their experiences from primary school through post-secondary education. The four participants involved in this study were enrolled in or recently graduated from post-secondary programs in Montreal at the time of recruitment. They shared their experiences with researchers in one-on-one semi-structured interviews.  Data were analysed with thematic analysis. Impacts on the participants educational experiences were categorized into three areas: social environment, academic environment and supportive environment. While much diversity was found among participants, several important parallels were uncovered. Participants recounted increased difficulty as they moved into higher levels of education as a result of greater academic demands and increased course loads. Both positive and negative experiences with educators and support services were reported. Educators and service providers who paid attention to students' needs and understood their disabilities had the greatest impact on students. Lastly, students benefited from an understanding of their own disabilities, strengths and needs, which was valuable in academics and self-advocacy. This study adds support to the current body of literature by contributing a new perspective, that of the students themselves, in addition to expanding the research pertaining to the Canadian context.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elin Thordardottir</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd724.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107160q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications Sciences &amp; Disorders</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xh33x"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Managing the tensions facing indigenous social change organizations that combine service and advocacy: The case of the Arab Jewish centre for equality, empowerment and cooperation in the Negev, Israel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>El-Sana, Amal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La tension entre la fourniture de services aux groupes marginalisés et l'organisation desrevendications afin de défier les structures de pouvoir est un dilemme fondamental pour lesOrganisations de Services de Changement Social. Ce dilemme existe dans de nombreusesorganisations de sociétés civiles, en particulier parmi les organisations qui travaillent avec descommunautés marginalisées et subjuguées telles que la minorité indigène Bédouine qui demeureen Israël, où la prestation de services immédiats et la promotion de changements politiques sonttout aussi prépondérantes. Il existe une littérature riche concernant les tensions qui proviennentdu groupement des services de disposition et revendication, car ces approches nécessitentchacune leur propre structure organisationnelle et leurs ressources. Cependant, il existe très peud'études exposant la façon dont ces organisations gèrent et surmontent ces tensions. Cette étude aemployé une étude de cas exploratoire utilisant Le Centre Judéo-Arabe pour l'Égalité, l'Emploiet la Coopération (AJEEC) dans le Naqab-Negev en tant que cas unique instrumental. Cetteétude explore les tensions et les approches / stratégies utilisées pour gérer les tensions entre ladisposition de service et de revendication et la façon dont AJEEC a pu survivre et prospérer àlong terme. Les résultats de cette étude ont mis en évidence les contextes sociaux et politiques entant que facteurs principaux qui façonnent les tensions et les stratégies développées parl'organisation afin de les gérer. Le cas a permis une compréhension approfondie de la dynamiquequi est provoqué par ces tensions et révèle l'approche unique, les stratégies et les solutions à longterme mises en oeuvre par AJEEC pour gérer ces tensions de manière efficace et durable dans lecontexte social, politique et culturel dans lequel AJEEC opère. L'étude présente des implicationspour la recherche, la politique et la gestion futures, ainsi que des recommandations pour lapratique du travail social.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The tension between providing services to marginalized groups and organizing them foradvocacy to challenge the power structure is a fundamental dilemma for Social Change ServiceOrganizations. This dilemma exists in many civil society organizations, especially amongorganizations that work with marginalized and oppressed communities such as the Bedouinindigenous minority in Israel where providing immediate services and advocating for policychange are equally crucial. There is abundant literature on the tensions that arise from combiningservice provision and advocacy, as these approaches each require their own organizationalstructure and resources. There are very few studies, however, showing how these organizationsmanage and overcome these tensions. This study applied an exploratory case study using TheArab Jewish Center for Equality, Empowerment, and Cooperation (AJEEC) in the Naqab-Negevas an instrumental single case. This study explores the tensions and approaches/strategies used tomanage the tensions between providing service and advocacy and how AJEEC was able tosurvive and thrive in the long run. The findings of this study pointed to the social and politicalcontexts as the main factors that shaped the tensions and the strategies the organizationdeveloped to manage them. The case provided an in-depth understanding of the dynamics ofthese tensions and revealed AJEEC's unique approach of Advocacy Based Alternative, strategies, and long-term solutionsimplemented to manage these tensions effectively and sustainably within the social, political, andcultural context in which AJEEC operates. The study presents implications for future research,policy, and management, along with recommendations for social work practice.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>James Torczyner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33s009m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh33x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612r163"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Our stories: Language stories and experiences of young adult Mi'gmaq</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Metallic, Janine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette recherche, dont les sujets sont de jeunes adultes Micmacs (Mi'gmaq) désirant se familiariser avec l'héritage linguistique de leurs ancêtres et faire l'étude du micmac comme langue seconde, vise à explorer leur expérience ainsi que la perception qu'ils en ont. Pour ce faire, elle tente de répondre à la question suivante : Comment les jeunes adultes Micmacs apprennent-ils la langue de leurs ancêtres dans leur communauté? Les sous-questions abordées dans l'étude sont : 1) Comment les jeunes adultes Micmacs décrivent-ils leur expérience d'apprentissage de la langue? 2) Comment est-ce que la langue micmac s'enseigne-t-elle dans ce contexte? Cette recherche utilise autant une méthodologie qualitative qu'autochtone afin d'explorer et de comprendre l'expérience d'apprentissage des jeunes Micmacs. Les participants de l'étude sont sept jeunes diplômés du secondaire qui ont participé à un programme d'étude du micmac à Listuguj durant l'été 2012. En utilisant ces méthodes autochtones et qualitatives, trois thèmes généraux ont émergé de l'analyse des entrevues des participants : 1) leur réflexion sur les expériences qu'ils ont vécues; 2) l'endroit où ils prennent place dans la classe; 3) le maintien de la continuité culturelle. L'analyse des données sur l'observation du terrain a fourni des indices sur les pratiques pédagogiques utilisées pour enseigner le micmac qui incluaient ces éléments suivants : 1) la création d'un environnement de classe agréable; 2) le respect et l'entrée en relation avec les autres; et 3) la priorité accordée à la collaboration dans la communauté d'apprenants. Mis en commun, ces résultats donnent des indices importants sur l'expérience de l'apprentissage du micmac et sur les pratiques pédagogiques choisies. Ils contribuent également à la prise de décisions concernant la planification scolaire et communautaire en ce qui concerne le mouvement de renaissance des communautés autochtones et la revitalisation de leur langue. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to explore the experiences and perspectives of young adult Mi'gmaw language learners who were learning their Indigenous heritage language as a second language. I believed that a better understanding of the contextual factors that shape language learning experiences would inform decision-making for language planning by community members, teachers, and education administrators. Therefore, this study aimed to answer the following overarching research question: How do young adult Mi'gmaq learn their Indigenous heritage language in their home community? The study also aimed to address the following sub-questions: 1) How do young adult Mi'gmaq describe their language learning experiences? 2) How is the Mi'gmaw language taught in this context? This research employed a blend of qualitative research and Indigenous research methodologies to explore and understand the language learning experiences of young adult Mi'gmaq. The participants of this study included seven young adult Mi'gmaq postsecondary students who participated in a Mi'gmaw language class in Listuguj during the summer of 2012. Three broad themes emerged from the analysis of the participant interviews: 1) reflecting on past language learning experiences; 2) finding a place in the classroom; and 3) maintaining cultural continuity. The analysis of observational data provided insights into the pedagogical practice used to teach Mi'gmaw language, which involved: 1) creating a comfortable classroom; 2) relating to others; and 3) fostering a collaborative learning community. Taken together, these findings provide important insights into the experience of Mi'gmaw language learning and how the language is taught. These insights will help inform local decision-making about school and community planning for language revitalization. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lynn Butler Kisber</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354h852.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612r163</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Integrated Studies in Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As1784p218"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Developmental toxicity of glyceryl trinitrate</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bardai, Ghalib Karim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Glyceryl trinitrate (GTN) is a therapeutic compound that has been shown to be embryotoxic. However, the paucity of current knowledge, with respect to both its activity as a developmental toxicant and the extent of its use during pregnancy, suggests that a detailed evaluation of GTN teratogenicity is warranted. Therefore, the central aim of the research in this thesis was to: (1) investigate the developmental toxicity of GTN in a biological model that is representative of mammalian development, the Japanese quail embryo (Cotournix cotournix japonica); (2) determine the ability of the embryo to biotransform the drug; and 3) elucidate the effects of GTN on global gene expression. Both in-ovo and ex-ovo quail embryo exposure models were used.GTN exposure was embryotoxic to quail embryos, inducing developmental pathologies that included microphthalmia and cranio-facial, heart, and neural tube defects. Furthermore, GTN exposure induced an increase in nitrated proteins in these embryos; nitrated proteins may be involved in mediating developmental pathologies in quail embryos during organogenesis. The increase in nitrated proteins after GTN exposure suggested that the embryo has the ability to metabolize this drug. GTN treatment of quail embryos resulted in an increase in nitrite, a decrease in total glutathione, and an increase in the ratio of NADP+/NADPH, indicating that redox balance may be compromised in exposed embryos. Indeed, alpha- and mu-type glutathione S-transferases (GSTs), purified from the whole embryo and the embryonic eye, had GTN-metabolizing activity. Co-treatment with N-acetyl cysteine, a glutathione precursor, partially protected against the effects of GTN exposure. Thus, GTN denitration by quail embryo GSTs may represent a key initial step in the developmental toxicity of GTN.Because the maintenance of redox homeostasis is critical in regulating proper and timely gene expression during embryo development, it was important to determine what perturbations in gene expression were occurring following GTN exposure. Ingenuity pathway analysis suggested that the EIF2, mTOR and WNT/β-CATENIN signaling pathways are most affected by GTN exposure. In conclusion, GTN is a teratogen in quail embryos. One explanation as to the mechanism by which GTN induces these malformations is that the metabolism of GTN in the quail embryo results in a change in the redox status, which subsequently affects global gene expression. Thus, changes in redox status may dysregulate the expression of genes that are critical in pattern formation during embryo development. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le trinitrate de glycéryle (GTN) est un composé thérapeutique pour lequel des effets embryotoxiques ont été observé. Cependant, il y a très peu de connaissances en ce qui concerne son activité toxique sur le développement embryonnaire. Étant donné son utilisation pendant la grossesse, une évaluation détaillée des effets tératogènes du GTN est necessaire. Par conséquent, l'objectif central de ce projet de recherche était de: (1) caractériser la toxicité du GTN sur le développement dans un modèle biologique représentatif du développement de mammifères : l'embryon de caille japonais (Cotournix cotournix japonica); (2) déterminer la capacité de biotransformation du GTN par l'embryon; et 3) élucider les effets de GTN sur l'expression des gènes de l'embryon. Des modèles d'exposition aux embryons de caille ont été utilisés à l'intérieur de l'œuf mais aussi ex-ovo.Nous avons observé dque lexposition au GTN était toxique pour les embryons de cailles, induisant des pathologies de développement incluant des microphtalmies et des défauts cranio-faciaux, cardiaques et neurologiques. En outre, l'exposition au GTN a induit une augmentation des protéines nitrées dans ces embryons. Ces protéines nitrées pourraient être impliquées dans la médiation des pathologies du développement dans les embryons de cailles pendant l'organogenèse. D'autre part, l'augmentation des protéines nitrées après l'exposition au GTN suggère que l'embryon a la capacité de métaboliser ce médicament. Nous avons mesuré que le traitement au GTN a entraîné une augmentation du nitrite, une diminution du glutathion total et une augmentation du rapport NADP + / NADPH dans les embryons de caille. Ceci indique que l'équilibre redox peut être compromis dans les embryons exposés. De plus, nous avons montré que les S-transferases (GST) de glutathion de type alpha- et mu, purifiées à partir de l'embryon entier et de l'œil embryonnaire, ont une activité métabolisant GTN. Finalement, le co-traitement avec du N-acétyl cystéine, un précurseur de glutathion, a partiellement protégé l'embryon contre les effets de l'exposition au GTN. Nos résultats suggèrent donc que la dénitration de GTN par les GST des embryons de cailles représente une première étape clé dans la toxicité pour le développement de GTN. Étant donné que le maintien de l'homéostasie redox est essentiel pour réguler l'expression temporelle des gènes pendant des phasses clés du développement embryonnaire, nous avons chercher à déterminer les effets d'une exposition au GTN sur l'expression des gènes. L'analyse de la voie d'ingénierie a suggéré que les voies de signalisation EIF2, mTOR et WNT / β-CATENIN sont les plus affectées par l'exposition GTN. En conclusion, le GTN est un tératogène dans les embryons de cailles. Une explication sur le mécanisme par lequel le GTN induit ces malformations est que le métabolisme du GTN dans l'embryon de caille donne lieu à une modification de l'état redox affectant par la suite l'expression globale des gènes. Ainsi, les changements dans l'état redox peuvent déréguler l'expression de gènes qui sont essentiels à la formation de motifs lors du développement embryonnaire.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barbara F. Hales</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Geoffrey I. Sunahara</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zt096.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784p218</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adn39x3996"><ual:graduationDate>2016</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dissolving ornament: A study of bavarian rocaille</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Recktenwald, Olaf Lewis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette recherche considère les gravures ornementales de type rocaille dans l'architecture du dix-huitième siècle d'Augsbourg.  Nous y examinons l'importance de la rocaille et interprétons les raisonnements qui sous-tendent le choix du mélange entre architecture, ornementation et nature, ainsi que l'importance de la théâtralisation de ces gravures.  Les représentations de l'artiste bavarois Johann Esaias Nilson se prêtent particulièrement bien à une telle analyse.  Des questions clés influencent cette enquête.  Si dans ces oeuvres d'art, architecture et ornement se mélangent, dans quelle mesure l'ornement peut-il continuer de communiquer avec éloquence?  Comment peut-on comprendre une architecture qui tente de se rapprocher de la nature et ses attributs?  Quelle relation le public peut-il avoir avec le spectacle théâtral représenté?  Les gravures de type rocaille représentent les premiers exemples notables de la séparation entre l'ornementation et l'architecture dans la tradition occidentale.  Ces gravures ont mis en doute la dépendance sur la rhétorique que les ornements ont manifestée pendant des siècles.  De plus, il n'y avait pas de traité d'architecture pour aider à verbaliser les intentions de la rocaille.  Ainsi, l'interprétation de ce phénomène fut confiée au siècle des Lumières, qui, sans hésitation, condamna scrupuleusement l'époque passée.  Toutefois, malgré son absence de mots, la rocaille était loin d'être dénué de sens.  En effet, elle s'inspirait de traditions de longue date et faisait écho aux discours théoriques de son époque.  Ses composantes naturelles étaient remplies de symboles, et ses scènes théâtrales s'inspiraient de théories de mise en scène de l'époque.  Ses cadres ornementaux ont permis de connecter le spectateur avec l'image de manière innovante.  En entremêlant des éléments architecturaux, naturels et théâtraux, la rocaille a fait montre d'un désir profond de raconter sa propre histoire.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This research centers on the architecture of eighteenth-century Augsburg rocaille ornamental engravings.  The dissertation investigates the significance of rocaille and interprets the meaning of that ornament's fusion with architecture, the reasoning behind the architecture's blending with nature, and the importance of the engravings' theatricality.  The analysis focuses on the Bavarian artist Johann Esaias Nilson, whose depictions speak effectively to these concerns.  Key overall questions govern the inquiry.  If architecture merges with ornament in these artworks, to what extent can that ornament still speak eloquently?  How is one to understand an architecture that attempts to take on nature's attributes?  What relation does one have with the theatrical spectacles represented?Rocaille engravings demonstrate the first substantial instance in the western tradition of the dissolution of ornament's integral connection with architecture.  The dependence upon rhetoric that ornament had treasured for centuries received its most comprehensive challenge in these works.  Compounding this situation was the lack of any architectural treatise to assist in verbalizing rocaille's intentions.  As a result, the interpretation of this phenomenon was left to the ensuing Enlightenment which unhesitatingly and meticulously condemned the prior era.  Despite the absence of words, however, rocaille was far from meaningless.  It drew from long-standing traditions and paralleled theoretical discourses and writings of the time.  Its natural components were awash with symbolic meanings, and its theatrical scenes engaged current theories of stage design.  Its ornamental frames allowed for unprecedented interactions between the viewer and the picture.  Through its repeated intermingling with elements of architecture, of nature, and of theater, rocaille evinced a continual desire to narrate its own story.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alberto Perez-Gomez</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hm78v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x3996</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Architecture</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04ds16w"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Postoperative infectious complications accelerate tumor reoccurence and mestastasis as a result of circulating tumor cell interactions with neutrophil extracellular traps</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cools-Lartigue, Jonathan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les interventions chirurgicales demeurent aujourd'hui le pilier fondamental/central du traitement curatif des patients souffrants de cancer. Cependant, une proportion importante de ces patients souffrira de complications infectieuses postopératoires, qui sont elles-mêmes associées à une élévation du risque de récidive et de décès reliés aux métastases. Tenter de réduire les aboutissements/ résultats oncologiques défavorables reliés aux complications postopératoires infectieuses n'est pas envisageable du point de vue clinique, en partie due au fait que les mécanismes sous-jacents de ce phénomène sont peu compris/ ne sont pas encore élucidés. De nouvelles études ont récemment suggéré que les neutrophiles pourraient faciliter la propagation du cancer. Les pièges neutrophiliques extracellulaires (PNEs) sont des filaments d'ADN extracellulaires d'origine neutrophillique, activement libérés/ relâchés fâce a des signaux/stimulus inflammatoires pour piéger et tuer les envahisseurs microbiaux. Le rôle exact de ces pièges neutrophiliques extracellulaires (PNEs) dans la propagation du cancer est inconnu/ peu compris. Cependant, nous suggérons l'hypothèse que les cellules cancéreuses circulantes pourraient devenir piégées au sein de ces PNEs et pourraient ainsi encourager le développement de métastases. Dans la thèse présentée ci-dessous, nous démontrons  que les PNEs peuvent attraper les cellules tumorales in vitro sous conditions statiques autant que dynamiques. De plus, nous montrons que ces interactions sont facilitées par les intégrines β1 provenant des tumeurs ainsi que des PNEs. En utilisant un modèle physiologique d'infections postopératoires in vivo pertinent, la ligature et ponction du coecum, nous montrons un dépôt généralisé de PNEs au sein de la microcirculation des organes. Nous confirmons par la suite les observations in vitro de la rétention/arrêt des cellules tumorales par les PNEs et démontrons l'importance des intégrines β1 dans ce phénomène. Par ailleurs, la perturbation/destruction des PNEs par l'administration/l'addition exogène d'un inhibiteur de l' élastase neutrophilique (NEi) ou de DNAse élimine/annule l'effet adhésif des PNEs. Enfin, nous montrons que l'attachement des PNEs entraine une augmentation du développement des métastases, qui est empêché par la dégradation des PNEs par la DNAse ou le NEi. En tout, ces résultats sont les premiers à impliquer directement les PNEs en tant que facilitateurs de métastases dans le contexte d'infections postopératoires sévères. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Surgery remains the cornerstone of curative intent therapy for cancer patients. However, a significant proportion of patients will suffer postoperative infectious complications, which are associated with an increased risk of tumor recurrence and death from metastasis. Mitigating the adverse oncologic outcomes associated with postoperative infectious complications is not a reality in clinical practice, in part because the mechanisms underlying this phenomenon are poorly understood. Emerging evidence suggests that neutrophils can facilitate cancer progression. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NET's) are extracellular neutrophil-derived DNA webs actively released in response inflammatory cues to trap and kill invading pathogens. The role of NETs in cancer progression is unknown. However, we hypothesized that circulating tumor cells (CTC) could become trapped within NET's favoring the development of metastasis. In the present work, we demonstrate that NETs are able to trap neoplastic cells in vitro under both static and dynamic conditions. Furthermore, we demonstrate that these interactions are mediated by both tumor and NET derived β1 integrins.  Using a physiologically relevant model of postoperative sepsis in vivo, cecal ligation and puncture, we demonstrate widespread deposition of NETs within end organ microvasculature. Furthermore, we confirm the in vitro observations of NET mediated CTC arrest and demonstrate the importance of β1 integrins in this process. More importantly disruption of NETs via exogenous administration of a neutrophil elastase inhibitor (NEi) or DNAse abrogates their adhesive effect. Finally, we demonstrate that NET trapping results in the increased development of gross metastasis, which is inhibited by NET disruption with DNAse or NEi. Taken together, these results are the first to directly implicate NETs as facilitators of metastasis in the context of severe postoperative infection.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lorenzo Edwin Ferri</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f8593.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04ds16w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924f29j"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stress-induced permeability evolution in limestone rocks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Glowacki, Adrian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ce travail de thèse s'intéresse à l'évolution de la perméabilité sous contrainte de roches poreuses (le Calcaire de l'Indiana) et peu poreuses (le Calcaire de Cobourg) en laboratoire. Les apports d'un tel travail sont multiples et concernent aussi bien la science fondamentale (structure des roches, comportement de la lithosphère) que le domaine appliqué (stockage en couche géologique profonde de déchets radioactifs à moyenne et longue durée de vie, séquestration du dioxyde de carbonate en conditions subcritique, gestion des géoressources en eau et des énergies fossiles).De nouvelles configurations expérimentales innovatrices ont été développées autour de deux approches complémentaires pour l'étude de la perméabilité: des mesures à charge constante et des mesures par pulsations hydraulique. Selon la roche considérée, les résultats montrent deux comportement différents de l'évolution de la perméabilité sous contrainte en configuration triaxiale classique: (1) La perméabilité diminue avec l'augmentation de contrainte dans le calcaire de l'Indiana, au cours de la compaction et dans le domaine inélastique de post-rupture; et (2) la perméabilité augmente de manière continue avec l'augmentation de contrainte dans le calcaire de Cobourg, que ce soit dans le domaine élastique ou dans le domaine inélastique de post-rupture. Des modèles d'évolution simples de la perméabilité avec les contraintes et basés sur les résultats expérimentaux sont proposés, ainsi que des modélisations numériques plus abouties. Ces derniers consistent à modéliser un écoulement laminaire dans des environnements similaires à des tubes circulaires, en les comparants à des situations où la perméabilité reste constante au cours de la déformation. Enfin, plusieurs configurations expérimentales ont été mises en œuvre afin d'examiner les facteurs pouvant influencer la perméabilité (hétérogénéité de la roche, taux de saturation, température, régime diphasique air-eau, composition chimique du fluide saturant) ainsi que leur sensibilité respective. De plus, une étude approfondie des deux phases hétérogènes présentes dans le calcaire de Cobourg montre que la phase argilo-calcaire (gris foncé), ou marneuse, est plus perméable (d'environ un ordre de grandeur) que la phase calcaire (gris pâle).</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates the stress-state dependent evolution of permeability of rocks in a laboratory setting. The focus was primarily on Indiana Limestone and Cobourg Limestone. The selected topics for this thesis have a direct impact on current geotechnical endeavours such as the deep geologic disposal of heat-emitting nuclear fuel wastes, the extraction of geothermal energy, oil and gas recovery, as well as the geologic sequestration of carbon dioxide in supercritical form.The laboratory methods for testing permeability were limited to steady state and hydraulic pulse tests. This thesis outlines specific innovative experimental configurations that were developed to test large rock samples. The investigations on the evolution of permeability in Indiana Limestone with stress state show that as the compressive stresses increased, including post-failure, the permeability decreased. In contrast, for the low porosity Cobourg Limestone the permeability increased with increasing triaxial stress states until failure, after which the permeability increased further. The results obtained from both rocks were used to develop empirical relationships for the variation of permeability with principal stress states. The empirical results were also used in a computational model to analyse seepage into a circular tunnel and the results were compared with situations where the permeability experienced no change. Additionally, the experiments on permeability in rocks were extended to examine factors that influence the results, including the degree of saturation, temperature, trapped air in the experimental configuration, etc. Special diffusing disks were developed to allow permeability testing of rocks subjected to triaxial stresses. The specific permeability studies of the heterogeneous phases found in the Cobourg Limestone was investigated in detail. It was determined that the dark grey argillaceous phase was more permeable (by one order of magnitude) than the light gray carbonate phase.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Patrick A. P. S. Selvadurai</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bs00t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924f29j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mq01b"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nonlinear finite element analysis of flexure-dominant reinforced concrete structures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kheyroddin, Ali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse démontre l'efficacité d'un nouveau modèle d'éléments finis non-linéaires pour la prédiction du comportement enflexion des structures en béton armé. Le modèle d'éléments fiis NONLACS2 ideélise les composantes par le biais de couches multiples pour le béton et l'armature. Le modèle inclue une procédure pour éliminer la dépendance sur le degre de la discrétisation, des courbes contraintes-déformations pour le béton normal et le béton hautes performances en compression, de nouveaux modèles pour le béton en tension et l'augmentation de la résistance en tension, et pour les déformations ultimes en tension et en compression du béton.[...]  Les logiciels NONLACS et NAFS peuvent etre utilisés pour l'analyse des structures en béton arme avec une précision acceptable. Finalement, cette recherche illustre l'utilité des éléments finis non-linéaires pour l'analyse de différents types d'éléments structuraux soumis a des charges monotoniques jusqu'a la rupture.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis demonstrates the capabilities of the nonlinear fmite element method as a tool for predicting the flexural response of reinforced concrete (R C) structures. The layered fmite element program, NONLACS2, developed in the present study, includes the different modelling options including the proposed model for eliminating mesh size dependency, the compressive stress-strain  curves of normal and high-strength concrete, new models for concrete in tension and tensionstiffening, and the concrete ultimate compressive and tensile strains. [...] The proposed flexural rigidity equations are utilized to develop a nonlinear fmite element program, NAFS, based on the modified stiffuess approach. The NAFS program provides a more efficient, speedy, and economical method, for a complete analysis of large frame structures. The NONLACS2 and NAFS programs and the proposed methods can be used for nonlinear analysis of R C structures with sufficient accuracy. Finally, this research study indicates the usefulness of the nonlinear fmite element analysis as a powerful tool to study the behaviour of different types of structural elements subjected to loads increasing monotonically until failure.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mirza, M. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418q80f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mq01b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t461q"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bubble formation at an orifice in fluidized beds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hsiung, Theodore Patrick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bubble size distributions play an important role in heat and mass transfer operations and reactions in fluidized beds. Knowledge of bubble formation is necessary to provide a boundary condition for the bubble interaction model developed in this department. In the present experiments, the frequency of bubble formation at a single orifice in fluidized beds and in aqueous sugar solution has been measured by a low pressure transducer and by analysis of cine-films. The regularity of bubble formation has been studied by recording frequency spectra with a wave analyzer. Four different orifice sizes have been used (0.16 cm -0.63 cm) with orifice flow rates varying,  3 from 20 -110 cm Is. The volume of the chamber feeding the orifice has also been varied between 50 cm -4800 cm [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grace, John R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xc05r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t461q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemical Engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bubbles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fluidization</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axk81jp07w"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ethnicity versus elite interest and behaviour as sources of conflict and instability in the Nigerian political system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nwakwesi, Maduka Lawrence</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study attempts to assess the extent to which instability in the Nigerian political system is the result of ethnic antagonism or of divergent elite politico-economic interests. Most scholarly treatments of African politics have explained political conflict in terms of ethnic antagonism, and in regard to Nigeria, political analysts have more often than not attributed the instability of the political system to tribalism or the cultural pluralism of Nigerian society. Our study questions this approach to the analysis of Nigerian politics, and suggests that tribalism is not the instinctive behaviour of groups in multi-ethnic Nigerian society, but rather an instrument of mass political mobilization used by elites who seek political power and the material rewards it brings. In the study we show how political leaders manipulate ethnicity to acquire political power which in turn is used for the embourgeoisement of politicians and some government and party functionaries.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Aronson, Dan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053j71b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jp07w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ethnic attitudes -- Case studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Elite (Social sciences)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nigeria -- Politics and government</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n5920"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Philosophy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Transcendent freedom as the basis of Kant's philosophy of history : a criticism of Emil Fackenheim's and George Armstrong Kelly's interpretation of Kant</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sharkey, Robert John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Récemment, certains commentateurs ont maintenu que les écrits kantiens sur l'histoire impliquent que tout acte humain est libre seulement s'il  échappe au principe de causalité. Le but de cette thèse est de raffirmer à l'encontre de ces commentateurs, l’importance de la liberté transcendantale pour la philosophie de Kant. C’est en mettant en relation la conception kantienne de la liberté avec la raison, la morale et le principe de causalité qu'est clarifiée la notion de "transcendance". Et c'est en montrant comment une liberté  transcendantale est compatible avec une causalité mécanique que sont surmontés les difficultés initiales impliqu6es dans la conception d’une liberté comme transcendantale et, pourtant, historiquement significative. En niant que la liberté' est de fait transcendantale, ces mêmes commentateurs font violence l’ensemble de la théorie morale de Kant. Ils finissent par faire de la téléologie un fait objectif et ils ne peuvent expliquer comment, pour Kant, l’histoire se développe selon un modèle moral nécessaire. Ces difficultés peuvent évitées, toutefois, en réaffirmant la transcendance de la liberté et en concentrant son attention sur la relation de celle-ci avec l’histoire. Le lien entre les deux doit être cherché dans une providence dont la tâche est de conduire l'homme  créer une situation ou la vertu suffit pour le bonheur.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Some commentators have recently claimed that in his writings on history Kant implies that human acts are free only when they escape the principle of causality_ The aim of this thesis is to reassert against such commentators the importance of transcendent freedom for Kant's philosophy. The notion of "transcendence" is clarified by relating Kant's conception of freedom to reason, morality, and the principle of causality; and the initial difficulties involved in conceiving a freedom which is transcendent and yet relevant to history are overcome by showing how transcendent freedom is consistent with the presence of mechanical causality. By denying that freedom is de facto transcendent, the same commentators do violence to the whole of Kant's moral theory. They end up making teleology objective; and fail to give a rationale for Kant's belief that history develops according to a necessary moral pattern. The difficulties they incur can be avoided, however, by reasserting the transcendence of freedom; and by focusing one's attention on how such freedom is connected to histor [...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096976v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n5920</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kelly, George Armstrong, 1932-1987. Idealism, politics and history: sources of Hegelian thought</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kant, Immanuel, 1724-1804</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fackenheim, Emil L. Kant’s concept of history</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cw649"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Surface treatment of polyethylene in electrical discharges</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stradal, Milos</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le traitement par corona dans l'oxygène, l'azote, l'hélium et l'argon ont augmenté d'une manière substantielle l'autoadhésion du polyéthylène de faible densité. Il a été démontre que la puissance consommée plutôt que la nature dugaz dans la décharge est le facteur important qui contrôle l'augmentation d'autoadhésion. L'oxydation du polyéthylène induite par corona avait un effet nuisible sur la liaison. L'augmentation de densité du polymère et de la rugosité de la surface ont diminué l'autoadhésion. La dépendance de la liaison a la température pour des surfaces rugueuses et lisses, traitées ou non-traitées, allait de pair avec la dépendance de la température du flux visqueux du polyéthylène. Les vitesses de décroissance de la charge de surface et de la capacité après vieillissement pour l'autoadhésion du polyéthylène traite par corona ont montré des tendances similaires, augmentant avec l'augmentation de température de stockage. Néanmoins, Il a été prouvé que l'autoadhésion induite par corona n'était pas due à la présence de la charge de surface. L'oxydation du polyéthylène induite par corona n'était pas nécessaire a la bonne liaison de l'encre d'imprimerie a la surface du plastique.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Corona treatment in oxygen, nitrogen, helium and argon substantially enhanced the autohesion of low density polyethylene. The power consumed rather than the nature of the gas in the discharge proved to be the important variable controlling the increase in the autohesion. Corona-induced oxidation of polyethylene had a detrimental effect upon bonding. Increase in polymer density and surface roughness lowered the autohesion. The temperature dependence of bonding for both rough and smooth surfaces, either untreated or treated, was similar to the temperature dependence of viscous flow of polyethylene. The rates of decay on aging of surface charge and capacity for autohesion of corona treated polyethylene followed similar trends, increasing with increase in the temperature of storage. However it was shown that the corona-induced autohesion was not due to the presence of surface charge. Corona-induced oxidation of polyethylene was not a prerequisite for the good bonding of printing ink to the surface of the plastic.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Goring, D. A. I.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x638j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cw649</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Corona (Electricity)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polyethylene</dc:subject><dc:subject>Adhesion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electric discharges through gases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Surfaces</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89d911h"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship between visual perception and lexical marking</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Doan, Brian D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An asymmetry was found in subjects responses to triplets of visually-presented items which varied along one (simple) or two (complex) physical dimensions. These results were obtained in an experiment where subjects made similarity-difference judgements in one of three conditions. lVhen verbal cues were provided, performance was symmetrical. When no cues were provided, and when language was suppressed, responses to cards containing two "unmarkedtl items were fastest for complex relations and slowest for simple relations. The asymmetry is discussed in terms of different characteristics of the items which determine how they are processed and compared. The results are seen as supporting the notion of a common, abstract, representational system for language and visual perception.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Une asymetrie est evidente dans les temps de repondre a des triplets d'objets presentes visuellement, qui varient en une (simple) ou deux (complexe) dimensions physiques. Cette decouverte sort d'une experience dans laquelle trois groupes de sujets ont juge de la similarite et de la difference des objets. Dans le groupe ou l'information verbale a ete fournie, les reponses etaient symetriques. Dans le groupe ou l'information n'a pas ete fournie, et dans celle ou la vocalization a ete empechee, les reponses aux cartes contenant deux objets "marquesll etaient plus lentes pour les relations complexes et plus rapides pour les relations simples. Evidemment, les differentes caracteristiques des objets determinent la maniere dont ils sont interpretes et compares. Les resultats soutiennent la notion d'un systeme de representation abstrait et commun pour le langage et la perception visuelle.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Macnamara, John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77ss403.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d911h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Vision</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atd96k5150"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of crude oil on terrestrial vegetation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brown, Si</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Vers la fin du printemps, on a applique de l'huile brute sur trois communautes vegetales terrestres a predominance herbeuse. Le taux d'application etait de 1.25 litres par metre carre. Au cours d'une saison de croissance, les especes ont reagi differemment a la contamination, tant dans leur deperissement initial que dans leur regeneration. La vegetation des sols argileux peu draines a regenere plus vite que celle des terrains sablonneux bien assainis. Les graminees et les roseaux ont regenere plus lentement que les herbes et les especes ligneuses. La plupart des especes rhizomateuses profondement enracinees ont pu survivre en regenerant des souches non-contamineesj les especes ligneuses ont ete les moins endommagees. Lee epanchements d'huile ont reduit le taux de capacite d'echange des sols affectes, et particulierement, le niveau de potassium echangeable. La saturation de base a legerement diminue tandis que le pH et le contenu en substances organiques sont restes inalteres.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Crude petroleum oil was sprayed on three terrestrial, herb -dominated plant communities in late spring. The application rate was 1.25 litres per square meter. In the course of one growing season, species responded differently to oil contamination, both in their initial decay and later regeneration. The vegetation associated with a poorly drained clay soil regenerated at a faster rate than that associated with a well drained sandy soil. Grasses and sedges regenerated at a slower rate than herbaceous and woody species. Deep rooting rhizomatous species were able to survive oil contamination by regenerating from uncontaminated rootstocks. Woody species were least subject to oil -caused injury. The oil spills substantially lowered the cation exchange capacity in general, and the exchangeable potassium in particular. The base saturation tended to decline slightly, while the pH and organic matter content remained unchanged.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Moore, T. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jt82q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k5150</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vegetation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plants -- Effect of petroleum on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Crude oil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483m731"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of lesions in the nigrostriatal dopamine system on the development of alcohol preference by hypothalamic stimulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Arnold, Penny Susan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette expérience a examiné l'action d'une lésion nigrostriatal sur le développement de la préférence pour l'alcool par la stimulation électrique du hypothalamus. Les 24 animaux étaient assignés à un sur quatre conditions I une lésion nigrostriatal suivie par 30 jours de la stimulation électrique du hypothalamus latéral; seulement une lésion nigrostriatal; seulement la stimulation hypothalamique; ni la lésion ni la stimulation hypothalamique. Tous les animaux avaient le choix de l'eau et de l'alcool pendent les 60 jours. La stimulation électrique du hypothalamus lateral n'est pas produit une préférence pour l'alcool. La lésion nigrostriatal a empêché l'élévation de l'ingestion de l'alcool qui se rencontre au cours des 60 jours (p &lt; .01) • Ces résultats suggèrent que la système nigrostriatal aide à la régulation de la consomption d'alcool. Les hypothèses étaient présentées pour expliquer l'insuccès de la stimulation hypothalamique d'obtenir l'ingestion de l'alcool.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The present study examined the effects of nigrostriatal lesions on the development of alcohol preference by hypothalamic stimulation. The 24 animals were assigned to 1 of 4 conditions: A nigrostriatal lesion followed by 30 days of stimulation in the lateral hypothalamus; a nigrostriatal lesion alone; hypothalamic stimulation alone; or neither hypothalamic stimulation nor a lesion. All animals had free access to both water and alcohol for 60 days. Electrical stimulation of the lateral hypothalamus failed to induce a preference for alcohol. The lesion in the nigrostriatal dopamine system significantly inhibited the normal elevation of alcohol intake which occurrs over time (p&lt;.01).These results indicate that the nigrostriatal system contributes to the regulation of alcohol consumption. Hypotheses were put forward to explain the failure of the stimulation to elicit alcohol preference.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stern, Muriel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05ff41v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483m731</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rats -- Behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>development</dc:subject><dc:subject>alcohol</dc:subject><dc:subject>nigrostriatal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avt150m55m"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Malbay : a sociolinguistic community-study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mougeon, Raymond</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thesis is the fruit of eight months of field research in Malbay, a bilingual village of the Gaspe (Province of Quebec). The study is divided in three parts. The first one deals with the three related questions of bilingualism, language maintenance and language use in Gaspe and in Malbay. The study of Malbay involves a detailed comparison of all the households of the community at two different points in time (1925 and 1970). It provides a clearer understanding of bilingualism and language maintenance. The two phenomena are shown to be primarily conditioned by a combination of demographic, economic and attitudinal factors. In the second part, the language attitudes of the community are described in detail. Malbay anglophones and francophones hold a number of fairly homogeneous and stereotyped attitudes to the local language varieties, to standard English and standard French, to the local language use and to the various aspects of bilingualism. In the third part of the thesis one will find a description of the pronunciation, vocabulary and syntax of Malbay English. Malbay English exhibits a number of features which have already been found to characterize other varieties of Canadian English. Interestingly it also contains a substantial proportion of linguistic items which have probably been borrowed from the French language.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse est le résultat de huit mois de recherche sur le terrain dans le village bilingue de Malbay en Gaspesie (Province de Quebec). L'ouvrage se divise en trois parties. La première partie traite des trois questions connexes du bilinguisme, de l'assimilation linguistique et de l'usage linguistique en Gaspesie et dans Malbay. L'étude de Malbay consiste en une comparaison détaillée de tous les foyers du village a deux époques différentes (1925 et 1970). Grâce à cette comparaison on aboutit à une meilleure compréhension du bilinguisme et de l'assimilation linguistique. Ces deux phénomènes sont en grande partie conditionnes par un ensemble de facteurs d'ordre démographique, économique et psychologique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Macnamara, John</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Weber, Rose-Marie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mq02m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m55m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bilingualism -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sociolinguistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Malbay (Québec)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avt150m56w"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Setting and sensibility : a study of two novels by Frances Brooke</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hildebrand, George H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the literary and cultural context of Frances Brooke's The History of Emily Montague (1169) in order to establish a basis for the evaluation of its Canadian content. The introduction shows that Canadian criticism, on the whole, has ignore~ such a context when discussing the novel's "Canadianism. 1I Chapter I focuses on the literary and cultural dimensions of the age of sensibility and Mrs. Brooke's relationship to this cultural phenomenon [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Messrs, Y.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m937n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m56w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Brooke, Frances, 1724?-1789. History of Lady Julia Mandeville</dc:subject><dc:subject>English</dc:subject><dc:subject>Brooke, Frances, 1724?-1789. History of Emily Montague</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290d10v"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some aspects of a floc barrier module for turbidity removal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bourque, J. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Turbidity is one of the typical characteristics of surface water sources, and may be caused by inorganic and organic matter in coarse, fine and colloidal suspensions. While it may not be dangerous to health, turbidity is objected to from the standpoint of appearance. The coarser matter is kept in suspension by flow velocity of surface waters, and this type of turbidity is easily removed by reducing the flow velocities and thus removing the particles by gravity subsidence. Colloidal particles, however, cannot be conveniently removed in this manner, and represent the true cause of the milky and opaque appearance of raw water to be treated.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kd26w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290d10v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Turbidity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sedimentation and deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sewage -- Purification -- Flocculation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rx07r"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'émigration canadienne-française aux Etats-Unis : 1920-1930</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boulanger, Rolande</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette these a pour sujet l'histoire soeiale de l'emigration eanadienne-fran~aise aux Etats-Unis de 1920 A 1930. Nous presentons le cheminement de cette emigration, vue dans son ensemble, e'est-a-dire les causes, le depart, l'etablissement ou l'integration de ees emigrants dans leur nouveau milieu et le rapatriement de certains. Le Quebec d'alors etait sensibilise a l'exode desCanadiens fran~ais vers les Etats-Unis. C'est en fait la deuxieme fois qu'on peut parler d'exode a propos de leur migration. Les emigrants sont des gens de elasse moyenne en quete d'une situation meilleure et non l'elite eanadienne-fran~aise. Une fois rendus aux Etats-Unis, ils s'etablissent dans les villes et organisent une societe franco-americaine semblable a celle du Quebec par sa langue et ses institutions, mais differente par la nationalite pour laquelle i1s optent.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cd421.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rx07r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>United States -- Emigration and immigration</dc:subject><dc:subject>French-Canadians -- United States</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax346d6868"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Piece for four track tape recorder Canada unlimited number two</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Austin, Kevin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper is submitted as an accompaniment to my thesis presentation of April 25, 1973 at McGill University, Montreal. A tape recording of the concert, along with this paper will be deposited in the McGill University Archives. Herewithin are notes relating to l} production, 2} performance conditions, 3} a general description of the tape part of the work, and 4) the participation of the group METAMUSIC, in my piece, Piece for Four Track Tape Recorder Canada Unlimited Number Two -subtitled Sam McGee, abbreviated as PFFTTRCUNTsSMc. Preceding the body of the paper are 1) a table of abbreviations and 2} explanation of some fundamental terms as they are used within. At the end will be found three appendices on 1) acoustic regeneration, 2) technical description of some of the equipment, and 3) the words 'meta' and 'METAMUSIC'. I would like to extend my thanks to Istvan Anhalt for having helped me to learn how to work, and to Professor Bengt Hambraeus for help in how to put this knowledge to a concise practical task.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xm26v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d6868</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Service, Robert W. (Robert William), 1874-1958 -- Musical settings</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electronic music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n204167w"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A contrastive study of the structure of rhetoric in English and Spanish composition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Strei, Gerald John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cultural thought patterns are reflected in the forms of written composition, an idea suggested by Robert Kaplan in a study of compositions written by students from different language groups. This thesis attempts to test this theory by describing the composition forms typical of English and of Spanish, then examining compositions written in English by native Spanish speakers and in Spanish by native English speakers to see if a transference of form has occurred. Thirty compositions written in each language by students from two universities were used in the study. Comparisons with the models established by reference to the cultural and historical development of the (!omposition in both languages revealed that all but four Spanish speakers and five English speakers transferred the composition form of their mother tongue to the composition written in the second language. This study has particular implications for the teachers of composition to students whose second languages are Spanish or English. There are also implications for further study on different levels of composition comparison [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Weber, Rose-Marie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj82r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204167w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English rhetoric</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spanish language -- Rhetoric</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9w032559k"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lecture d'Hubert Aquin : Prochain épisode</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tremblay, Christiane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'univers romanesque de Prochain episode rejoint cette definition que donne Lucien Goldmann de la structure romanesque classique: Une recherche degradee, demoniaque, de valeurs authentiques dans un monde degrade mais a un niveau plus avance et sur un mode different. 1 Le drame de l'identite, dans la recherche de l'amour et des significations, regit cet univers de la degradation, chez Hubert Aquin. La nature des mediations qui interviennent entre la conscience alienee du heros et son desir de se depasser dans l'amour revolutionnaire, revele la vanite de la recherche et l'accroissement du mal ontologique. Mais le procede de l'enquete et de la poursuite permet d'atteindre un tel degre d'intensite et de lucidite dramatiques que le heros-auteurnarrateur, s'abimant jusque dans l'univers du mythe, est conduit a se projeter a l'encontre d'une litterature-refuge, par la remise en question de l'acte d'ecrire.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vigneault, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz8062588.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032559k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aquin, Hubert, 1929-1977. Prochain épisode</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rh07z"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Archibald Lampman : Canadian nature poet</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jobin, Madeline Graddon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lampman's function as nature poet emerges as oonsisting in the manifestation of a national phenomenon whioh marked the beginn:ing of a traly Canadian literature. Lampman owed his naturalism ani his early poetio style to the English Romantios. I.n increase in social oonsoiouaJ1eSS later in his life attraoted him to Matthew Arnold. From j;mold, he learned to value the poetio objeotivity of his olusioal traimng, ani to search for an escape from the oonfusion of later Romanticism [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mallory, J. R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010s67m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rh07z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lampman, Archibald, 1861-1899</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nature in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>