<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw6634745t"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The input impedance of a full-wave dipole</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chess, Gordon. F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Before the developement of radar, television, and frequency modulated communications equipment, stations were operated at relatively low frequencies. The long wavelengths employed dictated the use of long wire or tower antennas with the inherent problems due to the proximity of the earth. Although these problems can be greatly reduced by using a dipole antenna mounted several wavelengths above the earth, all physical dimensions are too large except at high frequencies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Howes, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795c79h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634745t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zm90g"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of chemical fertilizer treatment on culm diameter, crown development and plant height of three varieties of oats as related lodging</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Casserly, Leo. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the most important cereal crops in Eastern Canada is oats. Lodging is one of the most serious hazards which limit the amount of chemical fertilizers that may be applied to this crop. There are more than one kinds of lodging. However the type of lodging which occurs prior to maturity is the most common. It involves a leaning or bending of the culms at ground level and often an uprooting of the immature oat plant. It is most frequently encountered after heavy rain or wind storms.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lods, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w621c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zm90g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tq93k"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Dunham dolomite near St. Armand, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carter, George. F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Location of Area: The area investigated lies two miles southeast of Frelighsburg in the County of Missisquoi. It is bounded on the south by the international boundary and the State of Vermont. Its approximate western boundary is the road leading south from St. Armand Center. Size of Area: The area extends two miles north from the international boundary and varies from one to one and a half miles in width.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stearn, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wv57w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tq93k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb397d26v"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Inter-relations of growth hormone and thyroxine on metabolism and tissue morphology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carriere, Rita. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The processes which result in the growth and differentiation of animal organisms are regulated by factors of a widely varied nature. Among these, the hormones are of prime importance. These regulators do not act independently, but in harmony. The growth hormone of the anterior pituitary, and the thyroid hormone, chiefly thyroxine have been shown to be greatly concerned with growth. It has become evident that the release of growth hormone from the pituitary is dependent upon stimulation by the thyroid.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leblond, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xd580.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397d26v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zj54g"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The geology of the Suffield Mine, Sherbrooke, Que</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carriere, Gilles. E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Suffield mine is in the Eastern Townships of the Province of Quebec and is situated five miles southwest of the city of Sherbrooke. The mine is the property of the Suffield Metals Corporation Limited, a wholy owned subsidiary of Ascot Metals Corporation Limited, and is a producer of zinc, copper, lead, silver and gold. A range of hills known as the Stoke Mountain range and locally called the Ascot ridge extends southwest from the mine to lake Memphremagog, and northeast, through the city of Sherbrooke, to Lake St. Francis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Riddell, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712mb91n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zj54g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8623j307m"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Flange and stiffener stress in an all-welded plate girder</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Campbell, Hugh. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It will be readily agreed upon by almost any engineer associated with the structural steel fabricating industry, that one of the most convenient and economical types of structural components in use today is the plate girder. Almost every structure built, which has long spans or has heavy loads to be carried, whether it be a building or a bridge, will have one or several of these most practical members. Until recently, specifications gave sufficiently wide scope to the designer to make these girders applicable in almost any case.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>De Stein, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2677063w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j307m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78th14h"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An experimental study of the internal mammary artery implanted in the left ventricular myocardium, with special reference to variations in the operative procedure as it affects the implant, and to blood flow characteristics through the implant</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Buller, William. K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>At the present time, with coronary disease in such prominence, it is interesting to glance back briefly over the development of our knowledge from the time Heberden first described angina pectoris in England, in 1768, (120). Many well known men have been active in the development of this knowledge. Such names as Fothergill, Hunter, Hammer, Osler, and many others will be familiar to most readers. Hammer, in 1878, was probably the first to diagnose coronary occlusion clinically, and to confirm this diagnosis at autopsy, (117).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webster, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bj951.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78th14h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xq665"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cholinergic transmission in a sympathetic ganglion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Birks, Richard. I.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The strikng similarity that Elliot (1904) discovered between the effects of adrenaline and sympathetic stimulation led him to suggest that the sympathetic nervous system might act by releasing small quantities of adrenaline from its post-ganglionic terminations. This was the first formulation of the idea of chemical transmission: two years later W. E. Dixon proposed that parasympathetic nerves similarly might liberate a chemical transmitter of their effects, and he suggested muscarine to be the substance involved (Dixon, 1906).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacIntosh, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702qb34s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xq665</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591d15t"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Morphology of the face in the hymenoptera</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bigelow, Robert. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This is a study in comparative animal morphology. The method used is entirely descriptive, and most of the conclusions cannot be tested experimentally. The validity of these conclusions for any particular reader must, therefore, depend upon the degree to which the evidence and reasoning impress him as adequate and logical. To assist the reader in thus assessing the conclusions and suggestions that are presented, l will attempt to outline, as briefly as possible, the point of view from which the study was carried out.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tt25t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591d15t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j923p"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Histology and histophysiology of the alveolar lung tissue</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bertalanffy, Felix. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The physiological role of the lung was not realized before the middle of the sixteenth century. In 1553 Michael SERVETUS stated that there occurred in the long "the generation of the vital spirit, a compound of the inspired air with the most subtle portion of the b1ood. 1) The first investigations on the intimate structure of the lung were those by MALPIGHI (1697) who demonstrated that the two systems in the lung, the air conducting and vascular systems, were independent and that no communication existed between them.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leblond, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b7426.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j923p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar781wm258"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some experimental investigations of magnetic probes for measurement purposes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beaulieu, Jacques. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The response of magnetic probes to an electromagnetic wave incident upon them bas been investigated experimentaIIy first at a wavelength of 50 cms., using probes of various design and size as compared to the wavelength. Their measured receiving patterns were found to compare favourably with simple theoretical predictions provided that an external circuit was used for the purpose of eliminating those undesirable excitations which are not directly caused by the incident magnetic field. A type of probe developed earlier in the practice of direction finding was used in these experiments to measure magnetic fields with greater efficiency and greater ease of construction than the loop probes usually employed for such measurements. The above studies were made with the ultimate view of adapting these probes for work at microwave frequencies in the region of 3 cm. wavelengths. The experiments indicate that the type of probe investigated can be adapted for measurements at microwave frequencies where probes without the external compensating circuit had failed so far.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bekefi, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2366305.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wm258</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692tb32z"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The nematodes of Egyptian birds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baer, Harold. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is concerned with a collection of nematode parasites collected from Egyptian birds which was sent to the Institute of Parasitology, Macdonald College, by United States Navy Medical Unit 3, Cairo, Egypt. Recently, this unit was carrying on research in the distribution of schistosomiasis and other parasitic diseases infectious to man in the Middle Eastern countries of Yemen, Egypt and the Sudan. It was decided that it would be of considerable value to Science to make a study of the ecto- and endoparasites of these areas, and ultimately to publish a host-parasite list of the findings.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cameron, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sh708.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692tb32z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Parasitology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An009w622n"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Occupational stratification and evaluation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Badgley, Robin. F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Man being born sentient is able to perceive the normative patterns which surround him in society. It is the contention of this thesis that individuals receive many common thought patterns in the process of socialization, but that their evaluation of these norms differ according to their dissimilar backgrounds. More specifically, the problem revolves around the ideas which a sample of high school pupils have about the occupational hierarchy and their evaluations of the occupations representing this hierarchy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elkin, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021k04s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w622n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acf95jg23v"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A 180° focussing beta ray spectrometer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Badior, Mark. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A large number of technical issues are now available for the study of radioactive decay schemes. The complete investigation of decay schemes involves getting all information on nuclei and their states, such as spin, parity, and line widths. From this, conclusions as to regularities of nuclear structures can sometimes be drawn. To provide data for such investigations, two methods are widely used. One involves measurements of energy spectra of beta and gamma rays; the other consists of coincidence measurements from which the sequence of emissions from a nucleus can be determined.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Foster, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612s64z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jg23v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75rc950"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of iodine deficiency in the production of goiter and thyroid tumors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Axelrad, Arthur. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Endemic goiter is such a conspicuous disease, so definitely limited to certain geographic areas, and human beings are so much more comfortable when they have an "explanation" for a phenomenon (even a wrong one) than when they have none that it is not surprising that there have been so many hypotheses to account for this condition. St. Lager in 1867 (R-7) collected 40 causes of goiter, of which 4 had to do with the diet. Coindet, the man who first showed that iodine could cure goiter, himself believed that one of the reasons for the high incidence of this disease in women was the fact that they carried heavy loads upon their heads.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leblond, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35698213.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rc950</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rj41g"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A Study of the Internal Fractures Caused by the Deformation of Scale Models of Geological Structures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Avison, A.T.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since geologists first observed deformed rocks, they have attempted to reproduce the structures they saw by using models. The purpose of the models was to achieve an understanding of the cause of the structures, of the way in which they were produced and the stages through which they passed during their formation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gill, J. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gh88r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rj41g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sf56b"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Music as a means of investigating perception of emotion and social attribution in typical development and in autism spectrum disorders</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bhatara, Anjali K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract> This thesis uses music as a means of investigating both typical and atypical perception of emotion and attribution of social intent. The primary aim of this thesis is to investigate this perception and attribution in indviduals with autism spectrum disorders (ASD) and compare this with typical adults and children. Chapter 1 comprises a literature review of music and emotion, and of music cognition in individuals with ASD. The first manuscript (Chapter 2) describes the development of a new method for investigating perception of emotion from musical performance. Using this method, we found that typical adults can reliably rate the emotional content of musical performances which vary in expressive parameters. In the second manuscript (Chapter 3), we used this method to examine the ability of adolescents with ASD to rate the emotional content of musical performance. We compared the group with ASD to a group of typically developing adolescents as well as a group of individuals with Williams syndrome (WS). The results of this study showed that adolescents with ASD are impaired in this kind of emotional recognition relative to both comparison groups. Emotional recognition is an important aspect of everyday social interactions, both in understanding and predicting others' actions. Thus, in the third manuscript (Chapter 4), we examined the effect of musical soundtracks on attribution of social action and intent in ASD by adding music to an established visual task. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans cette these, la musique est utili see pour investiguer la perceptiontypique et atypique des emotions ainsi que l' attribution d'intentions sociales.L' objectif premier est d' evaluer la perception des emotions et des intentionssociales chez des individus presentant un trouble du spectre autistique (TSA) enles comparant a des .adultes et des enfants dont le developpement est typique. Lepremier chapitre est consacre a une revue de la litterature portant sur la musiqueet les emotions ainsi que sur la cognition de la musique chez des individuspresentant un TSA. Le premier manuscrit (chapitre 2) porte sur le developpement d'une nouvelle methode permettant d'evaluer la perception desemotions associees a des performances musicales. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daniel J. Levitin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666883b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sf56b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Autism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Musical perception</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cognition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A028711077"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A variational approach to the equations of stellar structure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aron, Ivan. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The fact that a star can only be studied through its light may seem, at first, to impose severe limitations on the knowledge to be acquired concerning the nature of these bright pinpoints on the night sky. When Mother Goose said "Twinkle, twinkle little star, How l wonder what you are"she expressed not only the astronomer's interest in his subject, but also his continuaI battle with the atmosphere that introduces such uncertainty into his observations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Morris, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333638m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/028711077</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50h140w"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sub-audible noise spectra measurement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Armstrong, Robert. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An apparatus has been constructed to extend measurements of electrical noise spectra to sub-audible frequencies. The system of measurement incorporates a process of recording the noise magnetically and later playing the noise back for analysis at a much higher speed. The process makes low frequency noise measurable by conventional apparatus in the audio frequency range. The apparatus has been tested and found to be linear and independent of frequency in its range of use. The noise power spectra of a 6SJ7 pentode has been measured. Above 10 kc/s shot noise predominated, at lower frequencies flicker noise became important. The l/f-spectrum flicker noise was observed to exist down to 0.02 c/s, the lower frequency limit of the apparatus.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Woonton, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cj34w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h140w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77sv023"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the Witwatersrand system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Antrobus, Edmund. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In March, 1886, many years of prospecting culminated in a rich gold strike on the farm Langlaagte, in that part of the Transvaal now known as the Witwatersrand. This farm is now part of the city of Johannesburg (see Plate 1). The gold was discovered in a conglomerate bed, later to be known as the Main Reef. As this conglomerate was traced along its outcrop, it was quickly realised that a new and important goldfield had been discovered. That this view was justified is evident from Plate l, which shows all the areas held under mining lease today in the Transvaal and Orange Free State, totalling some 700 sq. miles.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clark, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579x38q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sv023</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j924z"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Supercritical flow in curved channels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anand, Tilakraj. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The importance of study of super-critical flow in open channels is recognized by present day hydraulic engineers. The subject is so vast and the mechanics of such flow is so complex that in spite of considerable work having been done in this field during the past twenty years, the final word has still to be said, especially regarding the beat remedial measures available. The writer found an article "Model Study Aids Designers of Spillway for Lyman Run Dam" in September 1951 issue of "Civil Engineering".</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Craig, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r7216.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j924z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77fw59k"><ual:graduationDate>1954</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of electrogastrographic recordings</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Allen, Lloyd. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Various electrical methods for the diagnosis and study of human physiology and pathology are now in general use. The most important of these are the electrocardiogram, electroencephalogram and electromyogram. All are a measure of the electrical activity within the tissues of the organ under study. Pathological changes within the tissue cells are reflected by a change in electrical recordings from the normal. Clinical progress has been considerable with these electrical devices.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webster, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nc89c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fw59k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52jc783"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The iron bearing formations of the Michipicoten area Ontario</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Young, William. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ever since the discovery of iron and gold in the Michipicoten area, a large amount of investigation has been done in an effort to explain the geology and its many interesting problems. This writer spent the summers of 1950, 1951, and 1952 in the area, while in the employ of Jalore Mining Company, Limited. During this time he examined the regional setting and the detailed geology of the iron formations and other rock formations, and wrote a Master of Science thesis on the Lucy Orebody. In the course of these investigations he became aware that much could still be added to the geologic picture, especially concerning the problems of the genesis of the iron formation, and the structure of the area.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gill, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nz54m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jc783</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A73666884m"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Shapes of coexistence curves in the critical region</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Whiteway, Stirling. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The concept of a critical temperature, above which a substance exists only in the gaseous state regardless of the pressure, and below which may exist in the liquid and/or gaseous state, was first (1869) postulated by Andrews (3). His classical study of the pressure-volume isotherms of carbon dioxide indicated that the liquid-vapour region was defined by a roughly parabolic boundary, the coexistence curve. The isotherm passing through the apex of such a parabola would therefore represent the critical temperature, the apex itself being designated as the critical point.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maass, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c226z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666884m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rq284"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bacterial response to ultraviolet radiation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Whitehead, Howard. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Biological effects are produced whenever radiations are absorbed by the living organism. The reaction that occurs as a result of the irradiation may be insignificant in that no recognizable injury is apparent during the life of the recipient; the effects may be insidious and appear only after a lapse of many generations; or the results may be ruinous with death resulting within a short time. The biological response to radiations might thus represent a number of manifestations all of which might be expected to have a common etiology.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Murray, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558j15x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rq284</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bacteriology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>