<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860970z"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cyclic adenosine monophosphate and rho guanine triphosphatase signaling in the guidance of axons to netrin-1</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moore, Simon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The adult nervous system is a network of neurons connected to each other by thin processes, called axons. During development, axons are guided to their targets by patterned chemical cues. The leading tip of an axon, called the growth cone, pulls the axon to its target with cell surface receptors that sense these cues and trigger biochemical cascades which extend, retract or turn the axon.  This thesis examines mechanisms involved in the guidance of axons to the cue netrin-1. I test the hypothesis that netrin-1 may function as an adhesive ligand. As well, I examine the role of two signaling pathways, the cyclic adenosine monophosphate (cAMP) and the rho guanine triphosphatase (Rho GTPase), in the guidance of axons to netrin-1.  I report that neurons efficiently attach to netrin-1 and that their growth cones display morphological changes consistent with its function as an adhesive ligand. Inhibition of the RhoA subfamily of Rho GTPases or elevation of cAMP levels increases the plasma membrane presentation of netrin-1's receptor DCC and promotes axon outgrowth and turning to netrin-1.  This observation is consistent with the possibility that these two biochemical pathways are linked. However, an important difference exists in how these pathways are regulated by netrin-1; while netrin-1 inhibits RhoA activation, it does not affect cAMP levels. Studies by others have reported that inhibiting RhoA activity or elevating cAMP concentration promotes axon regeneration following injury. These studies did not, however, examine the axon's guidance decisions past the injury site; while overcoming an inhibitory injury site likely involves ignoring or switching the response to inhibitory cues, guidance to their appropriate targets requires axons to sense and respond appropriately to the cues in their environment. Results presented here indicate that inhibiting RhoA or augmenting cAMP levels promote axonal attraction to the netrin-1 guidance cue.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le système nerveux adulte comprend un réseau de neurones connectés les uns aux autres par des prolongements minces que l'on nomme des axones. Pendant le développement, les axones sont guidés vers leurs cibles par des signaux moléculaires. L'extrémité d'un axone, appelé cône de croissance, tire celui-ci vers sa cible grâce à des récepteurs de surface qui détectent les signaux moléculaires environnementaux et déclenchent des cascades biochimiques qui font s'allonger, se rétracter ou tourner l'axone. Cette thèse examine les mécanismes impliqués dans le guidage des axones vers le signal moléculaire nétrine-1. J'ai investigué l'hypothèse voulant que nétrine-1 puisse fonctionner comme ligand adhésif. De plus, j'ai examiné le rôle de deux cascades biochimiques : l'adénosine monophosphate cyclique (cAMP) et la rho guanine triphosphatase (Rho GTPase), dans le guidage de l'axone vers nétrine-1. Le présent travail démontre que les neurones s'attachent efficacement à nétrine-1 et que leurs cônes de croissance axonaux affichent des changements morphologiques conformes à une fonction de ligand adhésif pour nétrine-1. L'inhibition de RhoA, une sous-famille de Rho GTPases, ou l'élévation des niveaux de cAMP augmente la présentation du récepteur de nétrine, DCC, à la surface de la cellule, promeut la croissance axonale et fait tourner l'axone vers nétrine-1. Ces observations suggèrent la possibilité que ces deux voies biochimiques soient inter-reliées. Cependant, une différence importante existe dans la façon dont ces voies biochimiques sont régulées par nétrine-1 : nétrine-1 diminue l'activation de RhoA, mais n'affecte pas les niveaux de cAMP. Des études précédentes avaient rapporté que le fait de diminuer l'activité de RhoA ou d'élever la concentration de cAMP promeut la régénération des axones après une lésion. Cependant, ces études n'ont pas examiné les décisions de l'axone, une fois passé le site de lésion</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Timothy E. Kennedy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924f52b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860970z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816q24w"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors involved in DNA demethylation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>D'Alessio, Ana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'épigénome est constitué de la chromatine, de protéines associées et de groupement méthyles liés de façon covalente à l'ADN qui en somment, régulent et maintiennent l'expression génique. Une particularité du génome des mammifères est la compartimentalisation de l'ADN en deux formes ; l'une dont la chromatine est compacte et inactive, qui est hyperméthylée, et l'autre dont la chromatine est ouverte et active, qui est hypométhylée. On a cru à l'origine que la méthylation de l'ADN était le facteur dominant qui déterminait la structure de la chromatine. Cependant, des données récentes suggèrent que cette structure puisse affecter l'ADN en déclenchant la méthylation ou la déméthylation de novo de l'ADN, impliquant l'existence d'un rapport bilatéral entre la structure de la chromatine et la méthylation de l'ADN.La présente thèse, étudie les mécanismes qui commandent l'interface entre l'activation de la chromatine et la déméthylation de l'ADN. Au deuxième chapitre, j'apporte en effet la preuve que le valproate, inhibiteur de l'histone déacétylase, induit la déméthylation de trois endogènes indépendants chez les cellules HEK 293 (un antigène du cancer et des testicules, un gène suppresseur de tumeur, et une metalloprotéinase de matrice.) Ces événements de déméthylation se produisent au même moment où nous avons aperçu une déméthylation active de l'ADN de la sonde non-répliquable pCMV-GFP. Ainsi, le chapitre deux prouve que les médicaments, qui fonctionnent de façon transitoire et réversible sur la chromatine, pourraient également changer la méthylation de l'ADN et causer une déméthylation disséminée des gènes. Cette question soulève des inquiétudes concernant la sûreté de ce médicament, le valproate, pour traiter les maladies chez l'homme.Le fait que les inhibiteurs d'histone déacétylase causent la déméthylation de l'ADN mène à un modèle où l'accès des déméthylases d'ADN à certains CpGs$</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The epigenome, which is comprised of chromatin, associated proteins, and the pattern of covalent modification of DNA by methylation, sets up and maintains gene expression programs. A hallmark of mammalian genomes is the compartmentalization of the DNA into dense inactive chromatin, which is hypermethylated, and active open chromatin, which is hypomethylated. It was originally believed that DNA methylation was the dominant factor determining chromatin structure. However, emerging data suggest that chromatin structure can affect DNA methylation triggering either de novo DNA methylation or demethylation, implying the existence of a bidirectional relationship between chromatin structure and DNA methylation.This thesis studies the mechanisms that control crosstalk between chromatin activation and DNA demethylation. In Chapter 2, I show that the histone deacetylase inhibitor, valproate, induces demethylation of three unrelated, endogenous genes in HEK293 cells (a cancer-testis antigen, a tumor suppressor gene, and a matrix metalloproteinase); these demethylation events occurred in the same time frame where we mapped active DNA demethylation of a non-replicating pCMV-GFP probe. Thus, Chapter 2 shows that drugs that function transiently and reversibly on chromatin, could also alter DNA methylation and cause widespread gene demethylation. This issue raises concerns about the safety of valproate for treating disease in humans.The fact that histone deacetylase inhibitors cause DNA demethylation leads to a model where the access of DNA demethylases to methylated CpGs is determined by the state of acetylation of the histones. In Chapter 3, I analyze the validity of this model by characterizing the time course of events leading from histone acetylation to DNA demethylation using a non-replicating pCMV-GFP probe, which measures active DNA demethylation. I found that histone acetylation precedes DNA demethylation. H3 trimethyl lysine 4 methylation, a marker of actively transcrib</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Moshe Szyf</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r383n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816q24w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301417j"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Failure to protect: explaining the response of the United States to the crisis in Darfur</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Newman, Jennifer</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire analyse l'échec du gouvernement américain pour résoudre de façon significative la crise de Darfour, à Soudan. Notamment, il constate que la réponse américaine est extrêmement disproportionnée par rapport à l'engagement rhétorique quant à l'intervention humanitaire. Faisant usage des arguments constructivistes, ce mémoire suggère que cet engagement reflète une norme émergente de l'intervention humanitaire. En revanche, étant donné les limitations du constructivisme, la seule présence de cette norme ne peut pas prédire son impact sur la création des politiques. C'est pourquoi ce mémoire considère les mécanismes de causalité exigés par le réalisme et le libéralisme. Du point de vue réaliste cette analyse suggère que, selon les hommes politiques américains, davantage de participation à Darfour compromettrait l'intérêt national américain. D'autre part, la perspective libérale souligne un manque des préférences domestiques soutenant l'intervention. Finalement, en combinant les connaissances réalistes et libérales avec le potentiel modificateur constructiviste, une route vers une réponse plus effective à des crises humanitaires est suggérée.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This paper examines the failure of the United States to meaningfully respond to the humanitarian crisis in Darfur, Sudan. Specifically it asserts that the U.S. response is markedly incongruent with the expected outcome of its rhetorical commitment to humanitarian intervention. Drawing on constructivist arguments, this paper suggests that this commitment is reflective of an emergent norm of humanitarian intervention. Given constructivism's limitations, however, the presence of this norm alone cannot predict its impact on policy formation. Therefore, this thesis considers the causal mechanisms posited by realism and liberalism. Through the realist lens this analysis suggests that U.S. policy makers perceive increased involvement in Darfur as compromising the American national interest. Alternatively, the liberal perspective emphasizes a lack of domestic preferences supporting intervention. Combining these realist and liberal findings with the constructivist potential for change ultimately suggests a route toward a more effective response to humanitarian crises.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rex J. Brynen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795b51m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301417j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science - International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rm002"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The suitability of French immersion education for students with reading disabilities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sauvé, Deanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study reported outcomes for students with reading disabilities (RDs) in early total French immersion (n = 17) relative to students with RDs in the regular English program (n = 17) on measures of academic achievement, English reading, behaviour, and perceived social acceptance. French immersion is a widespread, alternative education program where majority language speakers are taught the regular curriculum through a second language. Early program evaluations revealed that students suffered no cognitive, linguistic, or academic delay as a result of learning through French. However, these findings were largely limited to normally-achieving, non-disabled students. The few studies of at-risk students in French immersion have been inconclusive. Although some studies have found evidence that at-risk students did more poorly in immersion than core English, and argued that they should be transferred out of the immersion program immediately, other studies have found no differences between at-risk students in immersion and core English programs and argued that they should be permitted to remain in immersion. Consequently, parents and teachers have been left to make placement decisions without empirical support. In this study, students with RDs were compared to each other and to a matched sample of non-disabled control students (n = 34). Groups were matched on age, gender, socioeconomic status, and IQ. Participants attended Grades 4, 5 and 6 and were tested in English. Students with RDs in French immersion performed equivalently to students with RDs in core English on all measures. They showed comparable achievement in spelling, arithmetic, phonological awareness, and reading comprehension. They were not rated by parents or teachers as having more behaviour problems, and reported similar self-perceptions of social acceptance. Comparisons were also made between students with RDs in immersion and students with RDs who transferred out of the immersion program. These explor</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette recherche rapporta les résultats pour les étudiants avec des disabilités en lecture qui sont dans le programme d'immersion total française tôt (n = 17) relatif aux étudiants avec des disabilités en lecture dans le programme anglais régulier (n = 17) d'après les mesures de réussite académique, lecture anglaise, conduite et acceptation sociale perçu. Le programme d'immersion française est un programme d'éducation alternatif très répandu où la majorité des personnes parlent la même langue est éduquée dans le curriculum régulier dans une langue secondaire. A ses débuts, l'évaluation du programme démontre que les étudiants instruits en français ne souffre d'aucun délai soit cognitif, linguistique ou académique. Par contre, ces résultats sont très grandement limités aux étudiants qui réussissent normalement et non handicapé. Les quelques recherche relié aux étudiants à risques dans le programme d'immersion française sont peu concluant. Quoique, quelques études démontrent que les étudiants à risques ont eu moins de succès dans l'immersion que le programme régulier anglais et dispute qu'ils devraient être transférer immédiatement hors du programme d'immersion. D'autres études n'ont trouvé aucune différences entre les étudiants à risques dans les programmes d'immersion et le programme régulier anglais et dispute qu'ils devraient être permit de rester dans l'immersion. Donc, les parents et les professeurs sont seuls, sans support concret, pour prendre les décisions de placement. Dans cet étude, les étudiants avec des disabilités en lecture sont comparés l'un à l'autre et à un exemplaire de groupe-contrôle d'étudiants normaux (n = 34). Les groupes étaient assortis par age, gendre, milieu socioéconomique et quotient intellectuel. Les participants faisaient partie de la quatrième, cinquième et sixième année et ils ont été évalués en anglais. Les étudiants dans le programme d'immersion française$</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael L. Hoover</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j391t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rm002</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010s89n"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Breaking the shell of whiteness: naming whiteness in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Waddell, Amelie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La littérature académique abonde d'écrits portant sur les objets du racisme, ainsi que sur ses effets en tant que système de domination pour les populations racisées. Par contre,  on retrouve peu de textes qui traitent des populations  qui maintiennent le racisme et qui en  profitent. Au Québec, les écrits sur la « blancheur » sont très rares en anglais et inexistants en français. Historiquement, la blancheur a été construite comme étant supérieure à travers un processus de racialisation, où l'autre racisé était exclu de toute humanité. Cette exclusion était justificative de l'exploitation de son labeur, de ses ressources et de sa terre. Dans sa construction constante de l'autre, la « blancheur » restait –et reste- invisible.    Ce mémoire cherche à comprendre comment la « blancheur » s'est installée en tant que système de domination. Il tente de découvrir comment l'identité blanche est comprise au Québec et quelle est sa relation avec les populations racisées.  Afin de répondre à ces questions, des cégépiens blancs ont été questionnés sur leur interprétation de la blancheur ainsi que sur leur participation au système du racisme. Leurs interprétations sont ensuite analysées à la lumière des études critiques de la « blancheur », de la pédagogie critique et des auteurs postcoloniaux.  Cette étude révèle que non seulement la « blancheur » est restée invisible au sein de la société québécoise, mais qu'elle façonne la vision que nous avons des groupes racisés et du racisme. Cette étude démontre également que le racisme et les privilèges blancs sont au centre de la société québécoise/canadienne.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Academic literature abounds with work on the objects of racism, and on the effects this system of domination has on racialized populations. Yet, this literature is limited when it comes to those who maintain and profit from racism. In Québec, literature about whiteness is almost absent in English, and inexistent in French. Historically, whiteness has been constructed as superior through the process of racialization, where racialized others are excluded from humanity. This exclusion becomes the justification for the exploitation of their labour, their resources, their land. Through the constant construction of otherness, whiteness remained -and remains- invisible.   This thesis seeks to understand how whiteness was deployed in Québec as a system of domination. How do white Québécois understand the white identity, along with their relationship with racialized groups? White Québécois college students were interviewed about their interpretation of whiteness, of otherness, of racism and of their participation in the system of racism. Their interpretations were analysed in light of critical white studies, critical pedagogy, and post-colonial writers. This study reveals that not only whiteness has remained invisible in Québec, but that it shapes the vision whites have of racialized populations and of racism. Furthermore, this study illustrates how racism and white privilege are maintained at the core of Québecois/Canadian society.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peter Leonard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rp007.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010s89n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8336h451h"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>RNA interference during HIV-1 infection: role of TRBP and viral suppressors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Melendez Pena, Carlos</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Un grand nombre d'observations indiquent que l'interférence à ARN (RNAi) peut  être utilisée comme une réponse naturelle innée dans des cellules de mammifère pour contrer l'infection virale.  La protéine liant l'ARN TAR du virus d'immunodéficience humaine (VIH) (TRBP) est une composante du complexe de mise en silence induit par l'ARN (RISC), tel que démontré par son interaction avec Dicer. Bien que Dicer seul puisse cliver les ARNs double brin (db) et les pre-micro (mi)RNAs efficacement, le recrutement de « short interfering » (si)RNA/miRNAs à Ago2 a besoin de TRBP.  TRBP, une protéine capable de lier l'ARN db, peut accroître la traduction du VIH contenant des ARNs TAR en se liant directement aux ARNs TAR structurés et en inhibant la protéine kinase PKR.  La relation entre l'activité sur l'expression des gènes du VIH et la RNAi n'a pas encore été étudiée.   En utilisant la méthode du double-hybride, nous avons identifié les régions spécifiques d'interaction dans la partie C-terminale de TRBP et dans la partie N-terminale de Dicer.  On a confirmé l'interaction entre les deux protéines endogènes par immunoprecipitation et colocalisation dans des cellules humaines.  On a montré que la voie de RNAi a besoin de TRBP, par un essai fonctionnel dans des cellules HeLa, des Astrocytes et des cellules de souris Tarbp2 -/- en utilisant des plasmides codant pour la fluorescence verte (GFP) et des short hairpin (sh)- ou miRNAs contre la GFP. La RNAi diminue  dans des cellules de souris Tarbp2 -/-.  Un essai de double luciférase démontre que le VIH supprime le mécanisme de RNAi dans des cellules humaines ainsi par l'intermédiaire de sa protéine Tat et de ses ARNs TAR et RRE.  De plus, on démontre que l'infection par le VIH n'a pas d'effet sur l'interaction entre TRBP, Dicer et Ago2 dans les cellules humaines.  Donc, même si la voie de RNAi est fonctionnelle chez l'humain, le VIH a trouvé des moyens pour supprimer ce mécanisme.  Que le VI</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Increasing number of observations indicate that RNA interference (RNAi) may be used by mammalian cells to counteract virus infection as a natural innate immunity.  The human immunodeficiency virus (HIV-1) TAR RNA binding protein (TRBP) interacts with Dicer and is a component of the RNA-induced silencing complex (RISC). In humans, while Dicer alone can process double-stranded (ds) RNAs and pre-micro (mi)RNAs efficiently, the recruitment of the short interfering (si)RNA/miRNAs to Ago2 requires TRBP. TRBP is a dsRNA binding protein that increases translation from HIV TAR containing RNAs by a direct binding to the structured TAR RNAs and by inhibiting the protein kinase PKR. The relationship between its activity on HIV gene expression and on RNAi has not been studied.  Using the two-hybrid method we identified the specific region of interaction in the C-terminal part of TRBP and in the N-terminal part of Dicer.  This interaction between both endogenous proteins was further confirmed by immunoprecipitation and colocalization in human cells.  TRBP's requirement in the RNAi pathway was shown by an assay in HeLa, Astrocytes and Tarbp2 -/- cells using a green fluorescent protein-expressing plasmid and either short hairpin (sh)- or mi-RNAs against GFP.  RNAi is decreased in Tarbp2 -/- mouse cells and Astrocytes.  Results using a dual luciferase assay show that HIV-1 disrupts the RNAi mechanism in mammalian cells and that HIV-1 products Tat protein, TAR and RRE RNAs mediate this suppression.  In addition, we show that HIV infection has no effect on the interaction between TRBP, Dicer and Ago2 in human cells. Even though the RNAi pathway is functional in human cells, HIV has found the way to repress this mechanism.  Whether HIV-1 is able to disrupt the function of RISC to avoid an innate immunity response or whether it co-opts the RNAi pathway for its benefit remains to be elucidated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anne Gatignol</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m11c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h451h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913s58c"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microwave-assisted extraction (MAE) of Secoisolariciresinol Diglucoside (SDG) from flaxseed</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nemes, Simona</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le secoisolariciresinol diglucoside (SDG) est le lignane le plus important provenant de la graine de lin, et il est le plus important précuseur exogène des lignanes mammifères entérolactone et entérodiol. Le SDG est un ingrédient alimentaire fonctionnel reconnu pouvant offrir plusieurs bénéfices santé; il possède une importante activité antioxydante, des effets cardio-protecteurs, il peut réduire le niveau sanguin de cholestérol à lipoprotéines à basse densité, et réduire le risque de cancers hormonaux. Le SDG est présent dans la graine de lin sous une forme polymérique complexe qui lie son ester au 3-hydroxy-3-methyl-glutaryl (HMG). Le SDG peut être libéré de la structure polymérique par une hydrolyse alkaline de ses liens estériques.   Une nouvelle méthode d'analyse a été développée pour la quantification rapide et fiable du SDG de la graine de lin. La méthode utilise l'énergie micro-onde afin de favoriser le processus de diffusion lors de l'extraction du SDG de la graine de lin.  Un plan de criblage statistique a été utilisé pour déterminer le domaine expérimental et pour identifier les facteurs qui gouvernent l'extraction micro-onde du SDG de la graine de lin.  Le processus d'extraction micro-onde a été optimisé par l'entremise de la méthodologie de surface de réponse.  Les résultats indiquent que le rendement de l'extraction de SDG est optimal pour les conditions suivantes : 1 mg de graines de lin dégraissées, hydrolysées avec 50 ml NaOH 0.5M, pour 3 min, et sujet à 135 W de micro-onde intermittent (30 s marche/arrêt). L'efficacité de l'extraction micro-onde optimisée a été comparée avec la méthode traditionnelle d'hydrolyse et l'extraction témoin sans micro-onde.  L'extraction micro-onde a réalisé le meilleur rendement avec 21.45 mg SDG/g de lin dégraissé, comparé à 20.22 et 19.45 mg SDG/g lin dégraissé obtenus par hydrolyse conventionnelle et extraction témoin sans micro-onde respectivement. L</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Secoisolariciresinol diglucoside (SDG) is the main lignan from flaxseed, and it is the main exogenous precursor of the mammalian lignans enterolactone and enterodiol. SDG is a recognised nutraceutical which presents several health benefits; it has strong antioxidant activity, cardioprotective effects, reduces the blood levels of low-density lipoprotein cholesterol, and reduces the risk of hormone related cancer. SDG is present in flaxseed in a complex polymeric form, in which it is ester linked to 3-hydroxy-3-methyl-glutaryl (HMG). SDG can be released from the polymeric structure by alkaline hydrolysis of the ester bonds.  A new analytical method was developed for fast and reliable quantification of SDG in flaxseed. The method used microwave energy to enhance the extraction diffusion processes and to release the SDG from the flaxseed matrix. Statistical screening designs were used to determine the experimental domain, and to identify the factors that governed the MAE of SDG from flaxseed. The MAE method was optimised by use of a response surface methodology study. The results showed that the extraction yield of SDG was maximised for the following combinations: 1 mg defatted flaxseed hydrolysed with 50 ml NaOH 0.5M, for 3 min, at 135 W, with the microwave power applied intermittently (30 s on/off). The efficiency of the optimised MAE method was evaluated by comparing it with a conventional hydrolysis method and a microwave-less control method. The MAE method achieved the highest extraction yield, 21.45 mg SDG/g defatted meal, as opposed to 20.22 and 19.45 mg SDG/g defatted meal obtained with the conventional hydrolysis and microwave-less control methods respectively. The optimised MAE method is recommended for fast and reliable preparation of flaxseed lignan extracts for chromatography.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>G. S. Vijaya Raghavan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sg39k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913s58c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Food Science and Technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x6599"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Local knowledge of, and responses to, HIV-1/AIDS among the Turkana of Lodwar township</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Owiti, John Arianda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study used a broad theoretical framework encompassing an ecosystem approach to HIV-1/AIDS that investigated: local knowledge of HIV-1/AIDS and other sexually transmitted infections (STIs); local knowledge of the nexus between HIV-1/AIDS and tuberculosis on one hand, and other STIs on the other; the factors of the ecosystem that influence the contraction and transmission of HIV-1; and the local responses to HIV-1/AIDS among the Turkana of Lodwar Township.   The study found that, according to the Turkana's local knowledge of HIV-1/AIDS, other sexually transmitted infections, and tuberculosis, these infections are largely contagious, and are attributed to impersonal and natural causes.  In addition, in line with biomedical knowledge, the Turkana's local knowledge emphasises a conceptual link between tuberculosis and HIV-1/AIDS. The study also demonstrates a link between other STIs and HIV-1/AIDS. This has implications for the successful control and prevention of HIV-1, as well as that of all STIs, tuberculosis, and the management of AIDS.  In addition, the study demonstrates that factors of the ecosystem such as kaada, video and disco halls, unsafe medical practices, polygamy, banditry, urbanisation, migration and travel, poverty, long-distance truck drivers, military personnel, refugees, the low use of condoms, the gender-accentuated power imbalance, poverty-accentuated commercial sex work, poor sexual health and the prevalence of STIs, widow inheritance, and other socio-cultural practices play an influential role in the vulnerability of the Turkana to the contraction and transmission of HIV-1/AIDS.  The thesis posits an integrated approach to the prevention of HIV-1 and the management of AIDS that combines structural, public health, and biomedical approaches. In view of this integrated approach, various arenas of interventions are recommended. Some seem obvious, such as HIV-1 counselling and testing, and the development of a more durable healthcare infrastruc</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans un grand schéma théorique qui, entre autres, aborde le VIH-1 et le sida sous l'angle de l'écosystème, cette étude a examiné les points suivants : ce que l'on sait, à l'échelon local, du VIH-1/sida et d'autres infections sexuellement transmises (IST) ; ce que l'on sait, à l'échelon local, du lien entre le VIH-1/sida et la tuberculose, d'une part, et les autres IST d'autre part ; les facteurs de l'écosystème qui influent sur la contraction et la transmission du VIH-1; et la réaction locale au VIH-1/sida chez les Turkana du township de Lodwar.   L'étude a constaté que les Turkana de cette région pensent que le VIH-1/sida, les autres IST et la tuberculose sont généralement contagieux et les attribuent essentiellement à des causes impersonnelles et naturelles.  De plus, et ce qui correspond aux connaissances biomédicales, les Turkana font le lien conceptuel entre la tuberculose et le VIH-1/sida. L'étude démontre par ailleurs un lien entre les autres IST et le VIH-1/sida. Ces constatations ont des répercussions sur l'efficacité de la lutte contre le VIH-1, toutes les IST et la tuberculose et sur l'efficacité de leur prévention, ainsi que sur la prise en charge du sida.  L'étude examine aussi les divers facteurs de l'écosystème qui font beaucoup pour prédisposer les Turkana à contracter et transmettre le VIH-1/sida : le kaada (alcool de fabrication locale), les salles vidéo et les dancings, les pratiques médicales insalubres, la polygamie, le banditisme, l'urbanisation, les migrations et déplacements, la pauvreté, le camionnage long parcours, la présence de militaires et de réfugiés, le faible taux d'utilisation du préservatif, le déséquilibre des pouvoirs accentué par l'inégalité entre les sexes, la prostitution commerciale aggravée par la pauvreté, une santé-sexualité laissant à désirer, la prévalence des infections transmises sexuellement, les problèmes de succession des veuves et d'autres usages socio-culturel</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Galaty</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d2713.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x6599</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anthropology - Medical and Forensic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j3923"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A thermodynamic and dynamic Lagrangian model for icebergs: a data-model intercomparison for the Southern Ocean</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abrahamowicz, Maria Izabela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A Lagrangian dynamic and thermodynamic iceberg drift model was developed, coded and validated against observations. First, the model was used to create a climatology (1979-2000) of iceberg drift in the Southern Ocean. The simulation reproduced the main patterns of motion and the northernmost extent of Antarctic icebergs as inferred from satellite and ship observations. The model was then used to hindcast 29 giant iceberg drift tracks in what was the first study of an iceberg model ability to reproduce the motion of individual icebergs around the Antarctic continent on timescales of years. The shape and timing of twelve of the twenty-nine tracks was successfully modeled with a model error in the 0.9-50% range. In six cases, the shape of the observed drift track was reproduced but the timing was off, and in the remaining eleven simulation the icebergs moved in the wrong direction. The model error was found to be independent of simulation length suggesting that the error was due to inaccuracies in the forcing data rather than in the physics of the model. In particular, model performance deteriorated in coastal areas and in the southern portions of the Weddell and Ross sea, highlighting the need for higher resolution forcing data in these regions. The model accuracy would benefit from a better definition of the Antarctic coastline, a better representation of Katabatic winds off the continent and a forcing ocean model which would include a dynamic and thermodynamic sea-ice component.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Un modèle Lagrangien dynamique-thermodynamique pour la dérive d'icebergs a été développé, codé et validé à l'aide d'observations. Premièrement, nous avons produit,  à l'aide du modèle, une climatologie (1979-2000) de la dérive d'icebergs dans l'Océan du Sud. Les principales tendances du mouvement des icebergs simulés sont en accord avec les observations satellitaires et les mesures in-situ. Le modèle simule bien la limite septentrionale des icebergs d'Antarctique. Nous avons ensuite simulé vingt-neuf trajectoires individuelles d'icebergs géants. C'est la première fois qu'une telle étude est menée pour des icebergs observés autour de l'Antarctique et sur une échelle de plusieurs années. Dans douze cas, le tracé et le minutage de la trajectoire observée a été reproduit avec succès (erreur de 0.9-50%). Six simulations avaient des erreurs de temps mais non de trajet et dans les onze simulations restantes, l'iceberg a dérivé dans la mauvaise direction. Il a été établi que l'erreur du modèle était indépendante de la durée de la simulation, suggérant que l'erreur était due au champ de forçage plutôt qu'aux équations physiques du modèle. En particulier, une détérioration de la qualité des résultats a été observée dans les régions côtières et dans les parties sud des mers de Ross et de Weddell; soulignant ainsi le besoin d'améliorer le champ de forçage dans ces régions. D'autres moyens d'augmenter la précision du modèle seraient, entre autre, une meilleure définition de la géographie côtière de l'Antarctique, une meilleure représentation des vents catabatiques et un modèle océanique incluant une composante de glace dynamique et thermodynamique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bruno Tremblay</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s301r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j3923</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Physical Oceanography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10wt287"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structural behaviour of steel fibre reinforced concrete members</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aoude, Hassan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une série d'essais a été réalisée sur des poteaux de taille réelle soumis à des charges axiales. Les échantillons, qui avaient des quantités variables d'armature transversale, ont été construits en utilisant un béton auto-plaçant qui contenait une quantité variable de fibres métalliques. Les résultants de cette étude expérimentale démontrent que la présence des fibres influence positivement la capacité portante des poteaux. De plus, les résultats montrent que l'utilisation d'un béton renforcé de fibres métalliques (BFM) peut s'avérer une solution appropriée pour assurer une ductilité adéquate aux poteaux.  L'auteur propose des modèles analytiques pour prédire le comportement de poteaux chargés uniaxialement.  Le comportement sous tension d'éléments en BFM armés d'une seule barre a été étudié. Les résultats montrent que la présence de fibres améliore la résistance en tension. Une procédure pour la prédiction de la réponse des éléments soumis sous tension, prenant en compte la présence de fibres métalliques, est présentée.   Des recherches expérimentales furent entreprises afin d'étudier le comportement de poutres sans étriers. L'influence de la présence de fibres sur le développement de fissures ainsi que les mécanismes de ductilité et de rupture est discutée. Les résultats montrent que l'ajout de fibres améliore la capacité portante et la ductilité des poutres. Une procédure est suggérée afin de déterminer la capacité portante de poutres construits avec BFM.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A series of full-scale axial compression tests was conducted on RC and SFRC columns. The specimens, which were detailed with varying amounts of transverse reinforcement, were cast using a self-consolidating concrete (SCC) mix that contained various quantities of fibres. The results demonstrate that the addition of fibres leads to improvements in load carrying capacity and post-peak response. The results also show that the addition of steel fibres can partially substitute for the transverse reinforcement in RC columns, thereby improving constructability while achieving significant confinement. Analytical models for the prediction of the load-strain response of SFRC columns are presented and validated with the experimental results.  The tensile behaviour of SFRC members reinforced with a single reinforcing bar was also studied. The results indicate that the addition of fibres leads to improvements in tension stiffening and crack control. A procedure for predicting the response of tension members, accounting for the presence of fibres, is presented.  Experimental investigations were carried out on a series of RC and SFRC beams. The effects of steel fibres on shear capacity, failure mechanism and crack control are studied. The results show that the addition of steel fibres leads to improvements in load carrying capacity and can lead to a more ductile failure. A simple procedure that can be used to predict the ultimate shear capacity of SFRC beams is introduced and validated using results from other researchers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denis Mitchell</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mj19k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wt287</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arf55zb59f"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Alterations in responsiveness and mRNA expression of alpha-1 adrenergic receptors in neonatal ventral hippocampus lesioned rats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kamath, Aarthi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La lésion ventrale néonatale de l'hippocampe (nVH) chez les rats est largement admise comme modèle animal de la schizophrénie. Des études antérieures ont montré une augmentation de liaison aux récepteurs adrénergiques (AR) a-1 dans le cortex frontal des rats post-pubères ayant des lésions au niveau du nVH (nVHL) comparativement aux rats contrôles. De plus, l'hyperlocomotion normalement induite chez les rats contrôles par l'amphétamine est abolit par le prétraitement de ces rats avec le prazosin, un antagoniste du AR a-1, alors que ce dernier est sans effet sur les rats avec lésions.. Afin d'investiguer l'hypothèse que des lésions au niveau du nVH peuvent mener à l'hyperactivité du AR a-1, nous avons étudié les comportements locomoteurs et la «prepulse inhibition» (PPI) chez les rats contrôles (PD56-90) et les nVHL, en réponse à différentes doses de l'agoniste adrénergique a-1 cirazoline. Les résultats montrent qu'une dose de 0.6 mg/kg de cirazoline augmente significativement l'activité motrice dans les deux groupes d'animaux, sans effet différentiel chez les nVHL. Cependant, les nVHL présentent une diminution substantielle du PPI suite à l'administration de 0.45 mg/kg de cirazoline, laquelle dose ne réduit pas de manière significative la PPI chez les contrôles. Ce déficit a été bloqué par le prétraitement avec le prazosin, démontrant que les effets de la cirazoline sont médiés via l'activation du AR a-1. Ensemble, ces résultats suggèrent que les nVHL ont une hyperactivité du système adrénergique a-1, laquelle peut mener à certains comportements anormaux chez ces animaux. Nous avons utilisé des sondes marquées avec digoxigenin pour faire de l'hybridation in situ. Les sondes étaient spécifiques pour différents sous-types d'oligonucléotides d'ARNm de AR a-1. Les resultats ont indiqué un nombre sensiblement plus élevé de cellules marquées par l'ARNm a-1A, un nombre inférieur de cellules marquées par l'ARN</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Neonatal ventral hippocampus (nVH) lesion in rats is a widely accepted animal model of schizophrenia due to the exclusively post-pubertal emergence of many schizophrenia-like abnormalities. Previous studies have shown increased ligand binding of a-1 adrenergic receptors (AR) in the frontal cortex of post-pubertal nVH lesioned rats, compared to sham-operated control rats. Also, pretreatment with a-1 AR antagonist prazosin reversed amphetamine-induced hyperlocomotion in controls, but failed to do so in lesioned animals. In order to investigate the hypothesis that nVH lesions may lead to hyperactivity of a-1 AR, we studied locomotor behavior and prepulse inhibition (PPI) in post-pubertal (PD56-90) sham and lesioned animals in response to different doses of a-1 AR agonist cirazoline. Results showed that 0.6 mg/kg cirazoline significantly increased locomotor activity in both groups of animals, without any differential effect on nVH lesioned animals. However, lesioned animals showed a substantial decrease in PPI in response to an intermediate dose of 0.45 mg/kg cirazoline that did not significantly reduce PPI in control animals. This deficit was blocked by pretreatment with prazosin, demonstrating that the effect of cirazoline was through activation of a-1 ARs. Together, these results suggest that nVH lesioned animals show a hyperactive a-1 AR system that may regulate at least some behaviors that are abnormal in these animals. In situ hybridization using digoxigenin-labeled, subtype-specific oligonucleotide probes for a-1 AR mRNA revealed a significantly higher number of cells labeled for a-1A AR mRNA, a lower number of cells labeled for a-1D AR mRNA, and no difference in the number of cells labeled for a-1B AR mRNA in the medial prefrontal cortex of nVH lesioned rats. These results suggest that alterations at the level of transcription of genes encoding for some a-1 AR subtypes may be responsible for the abnormal adrenergic system in nVH lesioned animals.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lalit K. Srivastava</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720g659.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zb59f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78tf93r"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic markers of neurodegeneration: a role for 3-hydroxy -3-methylglutaryl-coenzyme A reductase in sporadic Alzheimer's disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Legault, Veronique</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Maintes preuves convergent aujourd'hui vers un métabolisme du cholestérol anormal dans la maladie d'Alzheimer (MA).  D'autres constats suggèrent que les statines, ou inhibiteurs de la 3-hydroxy-3-méthylglutaryl coenzyme A réductase (HMGR), l'enzyme limitante de la voie de synthèse du cholestérol,  protégeraient contre cette maladie.  À partir d'une large cohorte de Canadiens français, nous démontrons qu'un polymorphisme du gène codant pour HMGR diminue fortement le risque de développer la MA, alors qu'un second constitue un facteur de risque influençant l'âge de début de la maladie.  Ce dernier semble intervenir dans la formation d'enchevêtrements neurofibrillaires, l'une des marques neuropathologiques de la MA, ainsi que sur l'expression et les niveaux de protéines de HMGR dans le cortex frontal, l'une des régions gravement touchée par la maladie.  L'implication de ce gène, et la voie métabolique s'y rattachant, dans le développement, et possiblement la progression, de la MA semble donc plus que probable.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Mounting evidence now converges towards an altered cholesterol metabolism in Alzheimer's disease (AD).  Other recent reports suggest that statins, or 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl coenzyme A reductase (HMGR) inhibitors, the rate-limiting enzyme in the biosynthetic pathway of cholesterol, protect against AD.  Using a large French Canadian cohort, we demonstrate that a single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) within Hmgr gene greatly diminishes the risk of developing AD, while a second SNP appears as a risk factor, by influencing the age of onset of the disease.  This latter SNP may interfere in neurofibrillary tangles (NFT) formation, one of the neuropathological hallmarks of AD, as well as in HMGR expression and protein levels in the frontal cortex, a region severely affected by AD.  Thus, the involvement of Hmgr gene and its downstream metabolic pathway in AD onset, and perhaps also in its progression, seems more than likely.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Judes Poirier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vw819.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tf93r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd3760311"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Watershed modeling for regional water budget analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hellas, Neil</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les modèles de bassin d'eau peuvent jouer un rôle important dans la planification régionale. Leur capacité de considérer de grandes régions, diverses en espace et évaluer l'impact de scénarios d'utilisation de différentes terres sur des ressources en eau peut mener à des prises de décisions meilleures et plus informées. La récente législation en Ontario a mené à l'adoption de modèles de bassin d'eau faisant partie de processus de planification de protection de source d'eau potable. Dans cette étude, la capacité du modèle SWAT (Outil d'évaluation du sol et de l'eau) pour simuler l'hydrologie du bassin de la Rivière Raisin, un secteur de 556km2 situé à l'est de l'Ontario, est examiné. Le modèle a été calibré au cours de la période de 1985 à 1994 et validé au cours de la période de 1995 à 2004. Des débits hebdomadaires moyens ont été utilisés pour évaluer le modèle, produisant un coefficient Nash Sutcliffe de 0.798 pendant la période de calibrage et 0.788 pendant la période de validation.   L'erreur modèle est la plus significative pendant la période de fonte de neige annuelle, suggérant des manques dans la manière que la fonte de neige est modelée. Les prédictions du débit de base sont correctes sur une base annuelle, mais exposent plus de volatilité que le flux observé. Le coefficient Nash Sutcliffe est une mesure commune de performance du modèle hydrologique, mais souffre en étant fortement influencé par certains temps de l'année. Spécifiquement, il est insensible aux périodes de bas débit qui sont importantes pour la planification de la protection de source. La possibilité de transformer les débits observés et prévus pour indemniser est discutée. La méthodologie présentée profite de données standardisées aisément disponibles, permettant à un exercice de modélisation semblable d'être facilement entrepris pour une région différente. Les résultats et l'analyse tel que présentés pourraient$</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Watershed models can play an important role in regional planning.  Their ability to consider large, spatially diverse regions and assess the impact of different land use scenarios on water resources can lead to better, more informed decision making.   Recent legislation in Ontario has led to the adoption of watershed models as part of drinking water source protection planning processes. In this study, the ability of the SWAT model to simulate the hydrology of the Raisin River watershed, an area of 556km2 located in eastern Ontario, is examined.  The model was calibrated using data from 1985 to 1994 and validated using data from 1995 to 2004.  Weekly average flow rates were used to evaluate the model, producing a Nash Sutcliffe coefficient of 0.798 for the period of calibration and 0.788 for the validation period.   Model error is most significant during the annual snowmelt period, suggesting deficiencies in the way snowmelt is modeled.  Baseflow predictions are correct on an annual basis but exhibit more volatility than the observed flow.  The Nash Sutcliffe coefficient is a common measure of hydrologic model performance but suffers from being strongly biased to certain times of the year.  Specifically, it is insensitive to periods of low flow which are important for source protection planning.  The possibility of transforming the observed and predicted flow rates to compensate is discussed. The methodology presented takes advantage of readily available standardised data, permitting a similar modeling exercise to be easily undertaken for a different region.  Results and analysis as presented could be used directly in the development of source protection plans.  Spatial and temporal variation of water budget components (runoff, recharge and evapotranspiration) throughout the watershed is discussed.  The impact of land use and soil type on the water budget is also highlighted.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robert B. Bonnell</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qc51b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd3760311</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Hydrology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aff3657917"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship between substance use disorders and depression in adolescence: an examination of cognitive vulnerability factors to depression</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Skitch, Steven</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>          Adolescent substance use is a major public health concern with prevalence rates of substance use disorders increasing markedly during this developmental period. Substance use disorders frequently co-occur with depressive disorders and such comorbidity leads to a more chronic, severe course of illness. Self-medication models propose that substance use is employed as a strategy for coping with negative affective states such as depression, a pattern of consumption which increases vulnerability for the development of substance use problems.  Individuals who are susceptible to experiencing heightened, persistent emotional distress in response to stress are posited to be most likely to employ substance use as a coping strategy. As such, factors that predict vulnerability to the onset and maintenance of depressive symptoms may also predict vulnerability to substance use disorders. Cognitive theories of vulnerability to depression have generated considerable theoretical and empirical interest among both adult and adolescents populations. Despite this proliferation of research, there have been few studies seeking to examine cognitive vulnerability factors to depression as predictors of substance use disorder symptoms.            The purpose of this dissertation was to prospectively examine cognitive vulnerability factors to depression as predictors of substance use disorder symptoms among adolescents. Specifically, the research examined a depressogenic attributional style and a ruminative response style as predictors of substance use disorder symptoms. The research described in Chapter 2 examined the tendency to ruminate in response to stress as a vulnerability factor and found that adolescents who ruminate reported greater elevations in both depressive symptoms and substance use problems following elevations in negative life events than adolescent who do not tend to ruminate. Furthermore, elevations in negative affect symptoms of depression were found to mediat</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>          Le taux de prévalence d'utilisation de substances psychoactives augmente de façon marquée durant l'adolescence, en faisant un problème de santé d'intérêt public majeur.  Le trouble lié à l'utilisation d'une substance est fréquemment identifié chez des personnes atteintes de troubles dépressifs, et une telle comorbidité mène à une évolution de la maladie plus chronique et sévère. Selon les modèles d'automédication, l'utilisation de substances serait employée comme stratégie d'adaptation à des états affectifs négatifs tels que la dépression, une habitude de consommation qui augmenterait la vulnérabilité aux troubles de consommation. On assume que les individus susceptibles d'expérimenter une détresse émotionnelle élevée et persistante en réponse au stress sont  plus à risque d'avoir recours à l'utilisation de substance comme stratégie d'adaptation. Les facteurs prédisposants au développement et à la maintenance de symptômes dépressifs pourraient ainsi prédirent la vulnérabilité au trouble lié à l'utilisation d'une substance. Les théories cognitives avancées pour expliquer la vulnérabilité à la dépression ont généré un intérêt théorique et empirique considérable, autant chez les populations adulte qu'adolescente. Cependant, malgré la prolifération de la recherche à ce sujet, peu d'études ont examiné les facteurs de vulnérabilité à la dépression comme facteurs prédisposants aux symptômes de trouble lié à l'utilisation d'une substance.                Le but de cette dissertation était d'étudier de manière prospective les facteurs de vulnérabilité cognitifs de la dépression comme facteurs de prédisposition au trouble lié à l'utilisation d'une substance chez les adolescents. Plus spécifiquement, cette recherche a examiné un style d'attribution dépressogène et un style de réponse ruminatif comme facteurs prédisposants aux symptômes de trouble lié à l'utilisation d'une sub</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Robert Abela</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042w69p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff3657917</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Clinical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z368s"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Zeolite as natural feed additives to reduce environmental impacts of swine manure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tiwari, Jagannath</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>   Depuis 20ans, on observe l'intensification des entreprises porcines et la concentration régionale de la production de fumier.  Cette concentration a engendré des problèmes de qualité d'eau et de sol, ainsi que de contamination de l'air par les odeurs. Comme solution, la zéolite pourrait être ajoutée à la ration des porcs pour améliorer l'ingestion des nutriments et réduire l'effet de concentration des fumiers. Dans ce contexte, deux essais furent réalisés pour mesurer l'impact d'ajouter de la zéolite dans les rations pour porcs à l'engraissement : le premier visait les propriétés physico-chimiques des fumiers, et ; le second visait la productivité porcine. La zéolite expérimentale contenait plus de 90% de clinoptilolite et fut utilisée à un taux de 4%.     Les rations testées, R2, R3 and R4, contenaient 4% de zeolite (90%+ clinoptilolite) et soit 100%, 90% ou 90% de protéine brute et 100%, 90% or 85% d'énergie respectivement. Ces rations furent testées conjointement avec une ration témoin contenant 100% de protéine brute et d'énergie mais sans zéolite.    Pendant le premier essai, on alimentait chaque ration à trois porcs et on prélevait leurs fumiers pour analyser leurs propriétés physico-chimiques.  Aussi, 2% et 4% de zeolite était ajouté à du fumier frais pour mesurer la viscosité du fumier. L'alimentation de la zéolite a augmenté le taux de siccité des fumiers, sans toute fois avoir un impact sur leur viscosité. Les rations R3 et R4 ont produit des fumiers qui coulaient mieux et qui dégageaient moins d'odeur après 67 jours de stockage, comparativement à la ration témoin R1. La ration R2 a produit un fumier dégageant moins d'odeur que la ration R1, mais sans toute fois donner des résultats significatifs (P&gt;0.05). Donc, l'ajout de zéolite dans les rations pour porcs à l'engraissement peut avoir un impact positif sur les propriétés physico-chimiques des fumiers produits.   Le second essai consistait à ajoute</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>   The intensification of swine farming in recent year has resulted in excessive manure applications in some areas affecting both the terrestrial and aquatic ecosystems. The source reduction of manure nutrients by using zeolite (clinoptilolite) as a feed additive in the ration of hogs is envisaged as one of the possible solutions to reduce the excessive applications of manure nutrients in land. In this context, an experimental feed trial was performed to test the effect on the manure physico-chemical properties and the growth performance of hogs of supplementing grower hog rations with a 4% zeolite (90%+ clinoptilolite).     The zeolite ration tested, namely R2, R3 and R4, contained 4% zeolite (90%+ clinoptilolite) and either 100, 90 or 90% crude protein (CP) and 100, 90 or 85 % energy, respectively. These rations were tested against a control ration, R1, with no zeolite and 100% CP and energy.    The first experiment consisted in feeding each ration to three hogs and collecting their manure to analyze the physico-chemical characteristics. Also, 2% and 4% zeolite was added to fresh manure, to measure its viscosity. The zeolite rations did increase the total solids (TS) content of the manure. Rations R3 and R4 produced manures which flowed better and emitted less odours after aging for 67 days, as compared to the control ration R1. Ration R2 produced less odours than the control ration R1, although the results were not significantly different (P&gt;0.05). Thus, supplementing hog rations with zeolite can have some positive impact on the physico-chemical properties of the manure.  The second experiment consisted in testing the effect on hog performance of adding 4% zeolite (90%+ clinoptilolite) to their ration, while also lowering the ration crude protein and energy content. A batch of 192 hogs were split into two groups, one housed in a room and fed the control ration R1, and the second in another identical room and fed two of the zeolite rations, namely rations R2 an</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Suzelle Barrington</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nh55v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z368s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mq28r"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Distribution, density, and refuge use by squirrelfishes and soldierfishes (Holocentridae) in Barbados, West Indies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ménard, Alexandre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les poissons écureuils et poissons soldats, de la famille des Holocentridae, sont fidèles à leurs refuges diurnes sur les récifs coralliens. Il est suggéré que les espèces qui se nourrissent la nuit de crustacés benthiques se partagent la nourriture et la niche alimentaire. Cependant, il subsiste peu d'information sur comment les poissons Holocentridae se partagent les habitats de repos diurnes et les sites de refuges. Nous ignorons également comment la densité et la taille de ces poissons peuvent varier en fonction de l'habitat et des caractéristiques des refuges. J'ai examiné la distribution diurne, la densité et la taille des poissons Holocentridae sur deux récifs frangeants et une section d'un banc de coraux bordant la côte ouest de la Barbade, Inde Occidentale, afin de déterminer comment la distribution, la densité et la taille des poissons Holocentridae sont influencés par l'habitat à trois échelles spatiales. À l'échelle intermédiaire des sites, j'ai recensé les poissons Holocentridae dans 42 transects distribués sur sept sites situés dans cinq zones différentes sur trois récifs différents. J'ai observé six espèces de poissons Holocentridae dont les densités variaient entre les sites et étaient fortement associées avec les caractéristiques de l'habitat, même si les sites à eux seuls expliquaient la majorité de la variation du système. À plus petite échelle, j'ai recensé la présence d'espèces de poissons Holocentridae dans 5 quadrats (4 x 4 m) à l'intérieur de chaque transect et j'ai caractérisé la composition du substrat et la topographie. À cette échelle, même après avoir contrôlé l'effet des sites et des transects, seulement une très petite portion de la variation dans la composition de la communauté des poissons Holocentridae était expliquée par l'habitat. À une échelle encore plus petite, celle des refuges occupés par les poissons Holocentridae, quatre espèces étaient suffisamment abondante</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The squirrelfishes and soldierfishes, family Holocentridae, show site fidelity to their diurnal refuges on coral reefs. Species feeding at night on benthic crustaceans partition food and foraging habitats. However, it is not known whether holocentrids also partition diurnal resting habitats and refuge sites or how their density and size vary with habitat and refuge characteristics. I examined the diurnal distribution, density and size of holocentrids on the west coast of Barbados, West Indies, to determine how they are influenced by the habitat at three spatial scales. At the meso-scale, I surveyed 42 transects on seven sites located in five different zones of three different reefs. I recorded six holocentrid species that varied in density among sites and were strongly associated with habitat characteristics, although sites alone explained most of the variation. At the micro-scale, I recorded the presence of species and characterized substratum composition and topography of 5 quadrats (4 x 4 m) within each transect, but little of the variation in community composition was explained by habitat at this scale. At the refuge scale, four species common enough to analyze occupied 248 holes and spaces under ledges that varied in their volume, orientation, light intensity and presence of cleaner fish. Refuge volume was an important determinant of the biomass of the fishes it contained, due to positive relationships with both the number and size of the occupants, even though holocentrids were usually considerably smaller than the refuge they occupied.  Species differed in social organizations and different species and social organizations occupied refuges of different sizes. This thesis provides the first detailed examination of diurnal habitat use in the Holocentridae and shows that their density, biomass and social organization is related to habitat and differs among species at some scales but not others.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Donald L. Kramer</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301418t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mq28r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Ecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149s474"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamic purity analysis for Java programs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xu, HaiYing</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The pure methods in a program are those that exhibit functional or side effect free behaviour, a useful property of methods or code in the context of program optimization as well as program understanding. However, gathering purity data is not a trivial task, and existing purity investigations present primarily static results based on a compile-time analysis of program code.   We perform a detailed examination of dynamic method purity in Java programs using a Java Virtual Machine (JVM) based analysis.  We evaluate multiple purity definitions that range from strong to weak, consider purity forms specific to dynamic execution, and accommodate constraints imposed by an example consumer application of purity data, memoization.  We show that while dynamic method purity is actually fairly consistent between programs, examining pure invocation counts and the percentage of the bytecode instruction stream contained within some pure method reveals great variation.  We also show that while weakening purity definitions exposes considerable dynamic purity, consumer requirements can limit the actual utility of this information. A good understanding of which methods are "pure" and in what sense is an important contribution to understanding when, how, and what optimizations or properties a program may exhibit.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract> Les fonctions purs dans un programme sont ceux qui démontre un comportement sans fonctionnalité ou effet secondaire. Ceci s'avère une propriété utile pour une fonction ou du code dans le contexte d'optimisation et de compréhension du programme. Cependant, récolter de l'information de pureté n'est pas une tâche facile, et les techniques existantes pour les analyses de pureté ne fournissent que des résultats statiques basés sur une analyses de la compilation du programme. Nous avons exécuter une analyse détaillée de la pureté dynamique des fonctions dans des applications Java en utilisant une approche basés sur un Java Virtual Machine (JVM). Nous avons évalué multiples définitions de pureté, forte et faible, et considéré les formats de pureté spécifiques à l'exécution, tout en considérant les contraintes qui nous sont imposées par un application "consommateur" d'information de pureté et de mémorisation. Nous démontrons que malgré la consistance de la pureté dynamique des fonctions parmi certains applications, l'examen du nombre d'invocation pure et le pourcentage de chaîne d'instruction "bytecode" trouvé dans les fonctions purs nous dévoile l'existante de grande variation. Nous montrons aussi que malgré l'affaiblissement de la définition de la pureté expose considérablement la pureté dynamique, les pré-requis des consommateurs peuvent actuellement limiter l'utilité de cet information. Une bonne compréhension de ce qu'est une fonction "pure" et dans quel sens, est une important contribution à comprendre quand, où, et quelles optimisations ou propriétés une application peut dévoilée.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clark Verbrugge</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf617.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149s474</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zh25t"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Accelerating a medical 3D brain MRI analysis algorithm using a high-performance reconfigurable computer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Koo, Jahyun</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Plusieurs algorithmes ont été proposés pour l'analyse des données d'imagerie par résonance magnétique (IRM). Ceux-ci ont permis aux chercheurs cliniques d'analyser leurs données avec précision jusqu'à tout récemment. Mais avec l'augmentation des données quantitatives à analyser dans le domaine de l'imagerie du cerveau, il y a un besoin maintenant pour des méthodes pour accélérer ces algorithmes surtout que leur temps de calcul peut prendre plusieurs heures. Cette thèse présente le résultat d'une étude sur l'implémentation de ces algorithmes sur des ordinateurs reconfigurables à haute performance. L'estimation de volume partiel (PVE), un algorithme de classification du tissu de cerveau a été implémenté sur deux systémes SGI RASC RC100 qui utilisent le langage de haut niveau Mitrion-C. L'algorithme PVE sur processeur a été profilé pour identifier les fonctions intensives en temps de calcul et deux fonctions à virgule flottante estimant les densités de probabilité de tissus et l'information antérieure ont été implémenté sur des accélérateurs FPGA. Plusieurs images de cerveau humain simulées et réelles ont été utilisées pour vérifier la précision et l'amélioration en performance de l'algorithme PVE sur FPGA. Les coefficients de sensitivité et kappa ont été mesurés dans le but de vérifier la précision des images de l'implémentation sur FPGA. L'estimation des densités de probabilité sur FPGA et la fonction d'estimation d'information antérieure ont eu pour résultat des gains de performance de 2.5 et 9.4, respectivement. La performance globale de l'amélioration de l'algorithme PVE sur FPGA comparativement à l'algorithme établie sur processeur a été de 5.1 sur quatre processeurs.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Many automatic algorithms have been proposed for analyzing Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) data sets. These algorithms allow clinical researchers to analyze their quantitative data with consistently accurate results. With the increasingly large data sets being used in brain mapping, there has been a significant rise in the need for methods to accelerate these algorithms, as their computation can consume many hours. This thesis presents the results from a study on implementing such quantitative analysis algorithms on High-Performance Reconfigurable Computers (HPRCs). The Partial Volume Estimation (PVE), a brain tissue classification algorithm for MRI, was implemented on two SGI RASC RC100 systems using the Mitrion-C High-Level Language (HLL). The CPU-based PVE algorithm was profiled to identify the computationally intensive functions and two floating-point functions, estimating the probability densities (PDs) of tissues and the prior information, were implemented on FPGA-accelerators. Several simulated and real human brain MR images were used to evaluate the accuracy and performance improvement of the FPGA-based PVE algorithm. The Sensitivity and Kappa coefficients were calculated to verify the accuracy of the images resulting from the FPGA-based implementation. The FPGA-based PDs estimation and prior information estimation function achieved an average speedup of 2.5X and 9.4X, respectively. The overall performance improvement of the FPGA-accelerated PVE algorithm over the conventional CPU-based algorithm was 5.1X with four FPGAs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Warren Gross</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Alan C. Evans</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f8771.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zh25t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abg257h75k"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bayesian exploration in Markov decision processes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Castro Rivadeneira, Pablo Samuel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les processus de décision Markoviens sont des modèles mathématiques fréquemment utilisés pour résoudre des problèmes d'optimisation stochastique et de contrôle. L'apprentissage par renforcement est une branche de l'intelligence artificielle qui s'intéresse aux environnements stochastiques où la dynamique du système est inconnue. Un problème majeur des algorithmes d'apprentissage est de bien balancer l'exploration de l'environnement, pour acquérir de nouvelles connaissances, et l'exploitation des connaissances acquises. Nous présentons trois méthodes pour obtenir de bons compromis exploration-exploitation dans les processus de décision Markoviens. L'approche adoptée est Bayésienne, en ce sens où nous utilisons et maintenons une estimation du modèle. L'existence d'une politique optimale pour l'exploration Bayésienne a été démontrée, mais elle est impossible à calculer efficacement. Nous présentons trois approximations de la politique optimale qui utilise l'échantillonnage statistique. \\ La première approche utilise une combinaison de programmation linéaire et de l'algorithme "Q-Learning". Nous présentons des résultats empiriques qui démontrent sa performance. La deuxième approche est une extension de cette idée, et nous démontrons des garanties théoriques de son efficacité, confirmées par des résultats empiriques. Finalement, nous présentons un algorithme qui s'adapte efficacement au temps alloué pour le calcul de la politique. Cette idée est présentée comme une approximation d'un programme linéaire à dimension infini; nous garantissons sa convergence et démontrons une dualité forte.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Markov Decision Processes are a mathematical framework widely used for stochastic optimization and control problems. Reinforcement Learning is a branch of Artificial Intelligence that deals with stochastic environments where the  dynamics of the system are unknown. A major issue for learning algorithms is the need to balance the amount of  exploration of new experiences with the exploitation of existing knowledge. We present three methods for dealing with this exploration-exploitation tradeoff for Markov Decision Processes. The approach taken is Bayesian, in  that we use and maintain a model estimate. The existence of an optimal policy for Bayesian exploration has been shown, but its  computation is infeasible. We present three approximations to the optimal policy by the use of statistical sampling.\\ The first approach uses a combination of Linear Programming and Q-learning. We present empirical results demonstrating its  performance. The second approach is an extension of this idea, and we prove theoretical guarantees along with empirical evidence  of its performance. Finally, we present an algorithm that adapts itself efficiently to the amount of time granted for computation. This idea is presented as an approximation to an infinite dimensional linear program and we guarantee convergence as well as  prove strong duality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Doina Precup</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Prakash Panangaden</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913s60d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257h75k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67jv04j"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gene therapy for malignant gliomas</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lau, Cara Jean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gliomas are the most common primary brain tumours found in adults. The median survival of patients diagnosed with the most malignant form, glioblastoma multiforme (GBM), is 9-12 months and has changed little over the years despite advances in medical technology. Gene therapy may offer new solutions to treat this resistant disease. Hence, we tested three different gene therapy strategies.  In our first study, we tested the efficacy of targeted therapy to correct common aberrations found in gliomas including amplification/mutation of receptor tyrosine kinases (RTK) and loss of PTEN, which result in an overactive PI3K/Akt pathway. Without PTEN, FOXO transcription factors are inactivated, and the cell becomes resistant to apoptosis and cell cycle arrest. By using an adenoviral vector (AdV) expressing an activated FOXO1 mutant (AdFOXO1;AAA), we restored apoptosis and cell cycle arrest, reduced tumour volume and prolonged survival in an intracerebral xenograft model.  Secondly, we examined the therapeutic capacity of a novel replicating/non-disseminating AdV expressing the fusion protein of cytosine deaminase and uracil phosphoribosyltransferase (CU). CU can convert the non-toxic pro-drug, 5-fluorocytosine (5-FC) to the tissue diffusible chemotherapeutic drug, 5-fluorouracil (5-FU) to target dividing cells. In vitro, the replicating vectors were superior to the non-replicating vectors, but the fully replicating/disseminating vector did not perform considerably better than the replicating/non-disseminating vector suggesting that dissemination may not be advantageous. In vivo, the replicating/non-disseminating vector administered in conjunction with 5-FC prolonged survival in both an athymic and an immunocompetent mouse model. Moreover, an immune bystander effect in vivo was mediated by macrophages and T cells.  Lastly, we investigated a method to harness a tool of the immune system, IFN-ß; this cytokine is known to have anti-angiogenic, anti-proliferative, and immunomo</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les gliomes sont des tumeurs primaires de cerveau les plus communes retrouvées dans les adultes. La survie médiane des patients diagnostiqués avec la forme la plus maligne, le glioblastome multiforme (GBM), est de 9 à 12 mois et a peu changé au cours des années en dépit des avances en technologie médicale. La thérapie génique peut offrir de nouvelles solutions pour traiter cette maladie résistante. Durant nos travaux, nous avons examiné trois stratégies différentes de thérapie génique   Dans notre première étude, nous avons examiné l'efficacité de la thérapie visée à corriger des anomalies communes retrouvées dans les gliomes, comprenant l'amplification/mutation de récepteurs de type tyrosine kinase (RTK) et la perte de PTEN, qui mènent en conséquence à une voie activée de PI3K/Akt. Sans PTEN, les facteurs de transcription FOXO sont inactivés, et la cellule devient résistante à l'arrêt du cycle cellulaire et à l'apoptose. En utilisant un vecteur adénoviral (AdV) exprimant une protéine activée du mutant FOXO1 (AdFOXO1;AAA.), nous avons reconstitué les signaux pour l'arrêt du cycle cellulaire et l'apoptose in vitro ainsi que in vivo.  Deuxièmement, nous avons examiné la capacité thérapeutique d'un nouveau vecteur adénovirale qui a la capacité de se répliquer sans provoquer de lyse cellulaire et qui exprime en plus la protéine de fusion uracile phosphoribosyltransférase/cytosine déaminase (CU). La  protéine CU peut convertir le promédicament non-toxique, le 5-fluorocytosine (5-FC) à la drogue chimiothérapeutique diffusible, le 5-fluorouracile (5-FU) qui a comme cible des cellules en division cellulaire. In vitro, les vecteurs à capacité de répliquation étaient meilleurs que ceux qui ne pouvaient pas se répliquer. In vivo, le vecteur en présence du 5-FC a prolongé la survie de deux modès animaux (avec et sans sytèmes immunitaires).  Dans un dernier temps, nous avons étudié une méthode pour exprimer l'IF</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Josephine Nalbantoglu</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fr63n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jv04j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw6634649q"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Using image analysis and GIS for coffee mapping</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bolanos Arias, Sandra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Currently, the system that developing countries use to map coffee crops is expensive, tedious and inaccurate; therefore coffee maps cannot be updated frequently and production cannot be accurately estimated.  If such countries could map coffee crops in a cost-effective way, they would have an advantage in terms of setting the prices and getting a higher return for their product.   Here I hypothesize that coffee systems can be properly characterized and mapped using the spectral and spatial information derived from satellite images and topographic data.  I also believe that during the spatial analysis of the data, the additional information provided by an object-based approach (comprehensive information about the shape and context of a particular area) provides more information than a pixel-based one, traditionally used in the integration of Remote Sensing and Geographic Information Systems (GIS).  I statistically analyzed spatial and spectral characteristics of different coffee systems (monoculture, polyculture and agroforestry systems) in three study areas in Colombia of 70km2 each.  I integrated satellite images and topographic grids using both pixel-based and object-based approaches in a hierarchical approach and the results were compared.  Following this hierarchical approach, a preliminary classification was performed to reduce the number of classes spectrally similar to coffee systems.  Then in a second step, the classification was refined using decision rules from the statistical analysis of objects (composed of at least 3 pixels).  Finally, using the same objects, the classification was refined further, through linear spectral unmixing.    The results show that the rule-based classification combined with an object-based approach can improve the overall accuracy of the classification by 3% and by 17.47% for the coffee class when compared to the pixel-based analysis.  The linear spectral unmixing, however, does not contribute to improve the classification a</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Actuellement, le système que les pays en voie de développement emploient pour cartographier les récoltes de café est cher, pénible et imprécis. Ainsi, les cartes de café ne peuvent être mises à jour fréquemment et la production ne peut pas être estimée avec exactitude. Si ces pays pouvaient cartographier les récoltes de café d'une manière plus économique, ils auraient un avantage pour fixer les prix et obtenir des revenus plus élevés pour leur produit.   Je pose ici l'hypothèse que les zones de café peuvent être correctement caractérisés et cartographiés en utilisant l'information spectrale et spatiale dérivée des images satellites et des données topographiques. Je suppose également que pendant l'analyse spatiale des données, l'information additionnelle fournie par une approche 'object-basée' (informations complètes sur la forme et le contexte d'une zone particulière) fournit plus d'informations que qu'une approche 'pixel-basée', traditionnellement utilisée dans l'intégration de la télédétection et des systèmes d'information géographiques (GIS).   J'ai analysé (statistiquement) les caractéristiques spatiales et spectrales des systèmes de café dans trois secteurs d'étude en Colombie de 70km2 chacun. J'ai intégré des images satellites et des grilles topographiques en utilisant les 2 approches 'pixel-basée' et 'object-basée' dans une approche hiérarchique et les résultats ont été comparés. Des objets ont été formés sur la base de la similitude spectrale des bandes 2.3.4 5 et 7. Après l'approche hiérarchique, une classification préliminaire a été effectuée pour réduire le nombre de classes spectralement semblables aux systèmes de café. Alors, dans une deuxième étape, la classification est affinée en utilisant des règles de décision sur l'analyse statistique de plus petits objets (composés de 5 pixel ou moins). Finalement, en utilisant les mêmes objets, la classification a été de nouveau affin</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Raja Sengupta</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kb08s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634649q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Physical Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fr64x"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Simulating vortex ring collisions: extending the hybrid method</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eckbo, Ryan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les filaments de vortex sont des tubes de vorticité isolés, et il est important de comprendre leur comportement pour caractériser les fluides dans lesquels ils apparaissent. La reconnection de vortex, i.e. le changement de topologie qui survient lorsque des filaments entrent en collision, est un phénomène particulier qui ne peut être modelisé par la méthode traditionnelle des vortex, ce qui mène (Ghuneim, 2002, Ghuneim et al., 2002) à l'intégrer avec la méthode des ensembles de niveau. Cependant, la complexité de l'implémentation traditionnelle de la méthode des ensembles de niveau limite grandement le type de simulations qui sont possibles. Motivés par ceci, nous proposons une nouvelle implémentation qui organise les voxels dans une structure de données en arbre, ce qui permet des évolutions de filaments plus longues, plus étendues, plus précises et plus versatiles. Un méchanisme simplifié pour gérer les reconnections est aussi proposé. Nous démontrons les avantages de la méthode hybride étendue et de la nouvelle implémentation par ensembles de niveau par des simulations d'une variété d'évolutions de filaments avec des événements de reconnection.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Vortex filaments are isolated tubes of vorticity, the behaviour of which is important to the understanding of the fluid flows they are found in. Vortex reconnection, the change in filament topology when filaments collide, is a particular phenomenon that cannot be modelled by the traditional vortex method, which leads (Ghuneim, 2002) to integrate it with the level set method. However, the computational complexity of this method's traditional implementation severly limits the types of simulations possible. Motivated by this, we propose a new level set implementation that stores voxels in a tree data structure such that neighborhood relationships are recursively encoded. We then modify the hybrid method to use this data structure, allowing for longer, more expansive, accurate and versatile filament evolutions. A simpler mechanism for handling reconnections is also proposed. We demonstrate the advantages of the extended hybrid method and the new level set implementation with simulations of a variety of laboratory filament evolutions with reconnection events.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kaleem Siddiqi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wj87v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fr64x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gk206"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Non-suicidal self-injury, attachment, emotion regulation and childhood trauma in university students</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schaub, Kristin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude examinera les risques d'être auto-blessant en comparant un groupe d'étudiant universitaire qui exerce cette pratique contre un groupe contrôle sous les paramètres de l'attachement, du contrôle de ses émotions et le traumatisme d'enfance.  L'échantillon fut composé de 1400 étudiants universitaires (364 mâles, 1036 femelles; M = 19.76), qui ont rempli un questionnaire préliminaire dans le cadre d'un projet plus général qui vise les stratégies d'ajustement. Ceux qui furent identifiés en tant qu'auto-blessant et qui étaient intéressés à poursuivre cette étude (N = 55; 6 mâles, 49 femelles) ont reçu un suivi, avec un groupe contrôle, examinant les facteurs risques d'être auto-blessant. Trois MANOVA furent utilisés et plusieurs effets multivariables ont été trouvés pour l'attachement et le contrôle d'émotion mais aucune pour les traumatismes d'enfance. Des effets univariables furent examinés pour l'attachement et le contrôle d'émotion démontrant d'importantes différences d'un groupe à l'autre, avec l'exception des facteurs de sécurité pour l'attachement et des facteurs de consciences émotionnelles pour le contrôle d'émotion.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The current study examined risk factors associated with non-suicidal self-injury (NSSI), by comparing university students who self-injure with a control group on measures of attachment, emotion regulation, and childhood trauma. The sample consisted of 1400 university students (74% female; M = 19.76), who completed a screening questionnaire examining coping strategies. Those identified as self-injurers and who were willing to complete a follow-up (N = 55; 6 male, 49 female) along with a matched control group completed a follow-up study examining risk factors of NSSI. MANOVAs were employed and significant multivariate effects were found on attachment subscales (NSSI showing more negative attachment) and emotion regulation subscales (NSSI having fewer emotion regulation skills), but not for childhood trauma. Univariate effects were examined for attachment and emotion regulation revealing significant differences between groups on all subscales, with the exceptions of the "Secure" subscale for attachment and the "Emotional Awareness" subscale for emotion regulation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nancy Lee Heath</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795b52w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk206</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acv43p094n"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ab-initio simulation of spintronic devices</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Waldron, Derek</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse, nous présentons les détails mathématiques et d'implémentation d'une méthode \emph{ab initio} pour le calcul des propriétés de transport quantique polarisé en spin de dispositifs spintroniques de taille atomique sous un différence de potentiel appliquée. La méthode est basée sur la théorie des fonctionnelles de la densité (DFT) dans le cadre du formalisme des fonctions de Green hors équilibre (NEGF) de Keldysh pour calculer les densités de spin auto-consistantes. Cette technique de pointe étend les travaux précédents: i) en reformulant la théorie dans l'espace de spins de telle manière que la densité de charge hors équilibre peut être évaluée pour différents canaux à spin, et ii) en présentant l'échantillonnage de k-point pour traiter les dispositifs périodiques transversaux de telle façon que le magnétisme de surface et de volume peuvent être décrits correctement. Les détails informatiques, y compris l'échantillonnage de k-points pour la convergence de l'intégration sur la zone de Brillouin, la construction et l'optimisation de la base et des pseudo-potentiels, et un calcul efficace O(N) de la fonction de Green sont présentés.  Nous appliquons cette méthode pour étudier le transport polarisé en spin, non linéaire et hors équilibre, dans plusieurs jonctions tunnel magnétiques (MTJs), comme fonction du potentiel appliqué. Premièrement, nous constatons que pour une structure tri-couche de Fe/MgO/Fe, la magnétorésistance tunnel (TMR) à différence de potentiel nulle est de plusieurs milliers de pourcents, et se réduit environ à 1000% lorsque l'interface de Fe/MgO est oxydée. La TMR pour des dispositifs sans oxydation se réduit à zéro de façon monotone avec une différence de potentiel de l'ordre de 0.5-1V, conformément aux observations expérimentales. Nous interprétons nos résultats en étudiant les détails microscopiques d'états de diffusion et des bandes de Bloch dans les électrodes</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In this thesis, we present the mathematical and implementation details of an ab initio method for calculating spin-polarized quantum transport properties of atomic scale spintronic devices under external bias potential. The method is based on carrying out density functional theory (DFT) within the Keldysh non-equilibrium Green's function (NEGF) formalism to calculate the self-consistent spin-densities.  This state-of-the-art technique extends previous work by: i) reformulating the theory in spin-space such that the non-equilibrium charge density can be evaluated for different spin-channels, and ii) introducing k-point sampling to treat transverse periodic devices such that correct bulk as well as surface magnetism can be described.  Computational details including k-point sampling to converge the Brillouin zone integration, optimization of pseudopotentials and basis sets, and efficient O(N) calculation of the Green's function are presented.  We apply this method to investigate nonlinear and non-equilibrium spin-polarized transport in several magnetic tunnel junctions (MTJs) as a function of external bias voltage.  Firstly, we find that for an Fe/MgO/Fe trilayer structure, the zero-bias tunnel magnetoresistance (TMR) is several thousand percent, and it is reduced to about 1000% when the Fe/MgO interface is oxidized. The TMR for devices without oxidization reduces monotonically to zero with a voltage scale of about 0.5-1V, consistent with experimental observations. We present an understanding of the nonequilibrium transport by investigating microscopic details of the scattering states and the Bloch bands of the Fe leads. Secondly, we investigate a molecular MTJ composed of Ni leads sandwiching a benzenedithiol(BDT) molecule.  We find a TMR of ~27% which declines toward zero as bias voltage is increased. The spin currents are nonlinear functions of bias voltage, even changing sign at certain voltages due to specific features of the coupling between molecular states</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hong Guo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3335153.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p094n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Solid State</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655k339"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Three-dimensional orthogonal graph drawing with direction constrained edges</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kim, Dong Hyun</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le dessin de graphe étudie le problème de produire des plans de structures relationnelles pouvant être représentées par des graphes combinatoires. Un dessin orthogonal est un graphe dont les arêtes sont des lignes polygonales parallèles aux axes de coordonnées. Les dessins orthogonaux sont utiles dans plusieurs applications de divers champs comme la visualisation d'information et la fabrication de plan pour l'intégration de circuits à très grande échelle (very large scale integration - VLSI). Une des meilleures méthodes pour générer des plans orthogonaux bidimensionnels de graphes est l'approche dite de «Topology-Shape-Metrics» [Topologie-Forme-Métrique], où la tâche de définir les formes combinatoires du dessin est séparée de celle de déterminer les coordonnées géométriques des sommets dans le dessin final.  Par opposition à son équivalent bidimensionnel, la méthode de «Topology-Shape-Metric» mentionnée précédemment n'a pas encore été exploitée en trois dimensions. La première étape afin d'atteindre ce but est énoncée par Di Battista et autres [10, 11] lorsqu'il donne les caractéristiques combinatoires des chemins et cycles d'une forme donnée tels qu'ils admettent des dessins 3D simples, (c'est-à-dire: sans intersections). En particulier, [10] étudie le problème suivant: étant donné un cycle avec une étiquette associant chaque arête à son axe parallèle, peut-on obtenir un dessin orthogonal simple du cycle? La preuve de la condition nécessaire pour la caractérisation dans [10] s'est néanmoins révélée comme étant incomplète par les auteurs. Le but de ce mémoire est donc de compléter la preuve de la caractérisation donnée par Di Battista et autres et aussi de discuter les résultats futurs résultant des conséquences de la complétion de la caractérisation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Graph drawing studies the problem of producing layouts of relational structures that can be represented by combinatorial graphs. An orthogonal drawing is one whose edges are drawn as polygonal lines, with constituent segments drawn parallel to the coordinate axes. Orthogonal drawings arise in applications in diverse fields such as information visualization and VLSI circuit layout. One of the most successful methodologies for generating 2D orthogonal layouts of graphs is the so-called Topology-Shape-Metrics approach, where the task of defining the combinatorial shape of the drawing is separated from the task of determining the geometric coordinates of the vertices in the final drawing.  In contrast to its 2Dcounterpart, however, the aforementioned Topology-Shape-Metrics approach has not been exploited in 3D. The first step toward achieving this goal is due to Di Battista et al. [10, 11], who give combinatorial characterizations of paths and cycles with given shape such that they admit simple (i.e. nonself- intersecting) orthogonal 3D drawings. In particular, [10] studies the following problem: given a cycle with an axis-parallel direction label on each edge, can we compute a simple orthogonal drawing of the cycle? However, the necessity part of the proof for the characterization in [10] was later discovered by its authors to be incomplete. The aim of this thesis, therefore, is to complete the proof of the characterization given by Di Battista et al., and to discuss further results that arise as consequences of this now complete characterization.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sue Whitesides</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059cb21d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655k339</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>