<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anp193955b"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Opportunistic multicasting scheduling using erasure-correction coding over wireless channels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Le, Dang Quang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans les communications sans-fil, la diffusion se prête naturellement aux services efficaces de multidiffusion tandis que les variations des gains de canal, parmi les liens avec les différents utilisateurs, permettent de promouvoir la diversité multiutilisateur qui peut être utilisée pour améliorer la performance de multidiffusion. Ce mémoire propose une méthode d'ordonnancement multidiffusion opportuniste en utilisant un code correcteur d'effacement pour exploiter conjointement le gain de multidiffusion ainsi que les diversités temporelle, spectrale et multiutilisateurs disponibles dans les communications sans fil. La méthode proposée n'envoie qu'une seule copie, sur les créneaux temporels et spectraux, à un seuil de transmission sélectionné pour tous les utilisateurs appartenant au groupe de multidiffusion et en utilisant un code correcteur d'effacement pour récupérer les paquets effacés lorsque le rapport signal sur bruit (SNR) instantané du lien entre Station de Base et un utilisateur est insuffisant.   Sur un canal à évanouissement uniforme, un cadre analytique est développé pour établir la sélection optimale du seuil de transmission et le taux de codage à effacement pour atteindre le meilleur débit de multidiffusion sous l'effet de différentes conditions d'évanouissement. Les résultats numériques montrent que la méthode proposée surpasse en performance à la fois les méthodes Pire-Utilisateur et Meilleur-Utilisateur pour une ample plage de SNR. Les résultats montrent aussi que la diversité multiutilisateur est supérieure à bas SNR tandis que le gain multidiffusion est plus significatif à haut SNR. De plus, pour étudier le rôle de la connaissance du canal, la méthode proposée est considérée pour deux cas: (i) avec connaissance complète du canal et (ii) avec seulement une connaissance partielle du type d'évanouissement et SNR moyen. Notre étude indique que la connaissance complète du canal est avantageuse pour$</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In wireless communications, the broadcast nature can be explored to efficiently support multicast services while the difference in channel gains among the wireless links of users promotes multiuser diversity which can be used to improve multicast performance. This thesis proposes an opportunistic multicast scheduling scheme using erasure-correction coding to jointly exploit multicast gain, multiuser diversity, and time/frequency diversity in wireless communications. The proposed scheme sends only one copy to all users in the multicast group at a selected transmission threshold on time/frequency slots and using erasure-correction coding to recover erased packets when the instantaneous signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) of the link between the Base Station and a user is insufficient. On flat fading channel, an analytical framework is developed to establish the optimum selection of transmission threshold and erasure-correction code rate to achieve the best multicast throughput on different fading conditions. Numerical results show that the proposed scheme outperforms both the Worst-User and Best-User schemes for a wide range of SNR. The results also show that multiuser diversity is superior in the low SNR region while multicast gain is most significant at high SNR region. Moreover, to study the role of channel knowledge, the proposed scheme is considered in two cases: (i) with full channel gain knowledge and (ii) with only partial knowledge of fading type and average SNR. Our study indicates that full channel knowledge is beneficial for small multicast groups but at large group size it is sufficient to have partial channel knowledge as the difference in achievable throughput between the two cases is just marginal. The proposed scheme is further extended for applications to Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexing systems to take advantage of frequency diversity in a frequency-selective fading environment. Our study on the effect of frequency correlation on multicast thro</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tho Le-Ngoc</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96021035.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193955b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692t670j"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A metacognitive tool to support reading comprehension of historical narratives</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poitras, Eric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les étudiants ont fréquemment de la difficulté à comprendre des textes historiques narratifs incohérents; conséquemment, cette étude introduit une approche de bas en haut pour développer des outils métacognitifs qui supportent leur compréhension. L'utilisation d'ordinateurs comme outils métacognitifs visent à assister l'apprenant à atteindre le but de l'instruction au moyen d'initier, supporter et modeler des processus reliés à la métacognition et l'autorégulation de l'apprentissage (Azevedo, 2005a, 2005b). Cette étude suit un devis expérimental 2*2 avec condition expérimentale (lecture avec le bénéfice de l'outil métacognitif vs. sans le bénéfice de l'outil) et mesure (lecture silencieuse vs. verbalisations concomitantes). Les mesures pré-tests incluent l'habilité de compréhension de textes et le rappel de connaissances reliées au sujet du texte. Les mesures post tests incluent le rappel libre de l'information mentionné dans le texte et la précision de réponses aux questions ouvertes. Les étudiants qui utilisent l'outil métacognitif ont mieux performer que le groupe control quant au rappel puisqu'ils sont d`avantages conscient de leur compréhension et génèrent des explications.  Mots clés: outils métacognitifs, compréhension du langage, narratif historique</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Learners frequently have difficulty understanding incoherent historical narrative texts; therefore, this thesis project introduces a bottom-up approach to design metacognitive tools to assist learners reading comprehension. Metacognitive tools are defined as computer-based learning environments designed to assist learners to achieve an instructional goal through prompting, supporting, and modeling metacognitive and self-regulatory learning processes (Azevedo, 2005a, 2005b). The study follows a 2*2 design with experimental condition (reading with the benefit of the metacognitive tool vs. without the benefit of the tool) and process data (silent reading vs. think aloud). Pretest measures include reading comprehension skill and free recall measures. Posttest measures include amount of material recalled and accuracy of answers to open-ended questions. Learners who used the metacognitive tool outperformed the control group in their recall of information mentioned in the text because they monitored their comprehension and generated explanatory inferences more frequently.  Keywords:  metacognitive tools, reading comprehension, historical narratives</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Susanne P. Lajoie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zd89r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t670j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A44558d71f"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Planetary and synoptic-scale analysis of freezing rain events in Montreal, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ressler, Gina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La pluie verglaçante pose un risque majeur le long de la vallée du fleuve Saint-Laurent au Québec. Pour les grandes villes comme Montréal, des épisodes graves peuvent avoir un effet dévastateur sur la population, les biens et le commerce. Dans cette thèse, nous effectuons une analyse à l'échelle planétaire et synoptique des épisodes de pluie verglaçante à Montréal au Québec.  En utilisant les données de surface, 46 épisodes graves sont identifiés à Montréal pour la période 1979-2008. Ces épisodes graves sont ensuite divisés en trois types selon l'emplacement de l'axe du zone dépressionnaire de 500-hPa.   Des représentations composites sont produites pour chaque type, et les principales caractéristiques de la circulation d'échelle planétaire et synoptique sont identifiées. L'accumulation de précipitations et l'intensité sont examinées.  Enfin, l'épisode le plus extrême de chaque type est étudié.  Les résultats indiquent que bien que la pluie verglaçante est souvent associée avec le passage des cyclones extra-tropicaux, de nombreux épisodes sont soutenus principalement par la frontogenèse de bas niveau renforcée par la topographie de la vallée du fleuve Saint-Laurent.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Freezing rain poses a major risk to areas along Quebec's St. Lawrence River Valley.  For large cities such as Montreal, severe events can have a devastating effect on people, property, and commerce.  Therefore, we conduct a planetary and synoptic-scale analysis of freezing rain events in Montreal, Quebec.  Using surface data, we identify 46 severe events at Montreal for the period 1979-2008.  These events are further partitioned into three types based on the location of the 500-hPa trough axis.  Composite plots for each type are produced, and key planetary and synoptic-scale circulation features are identified.  Precipitation accumulation and intensity characteristics are examined.  Finally, the most extreme event from each type is studied.  Results indicate that while freezing rain is frequently associated with the passage of extratropical cyclones, many events are sustained primarily by low-level frontogenesis enhanced by the topography of the St. Lawrence River Valley.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Richard Gyakum</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d693c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558d71f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bp54h"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Non-suicidal self-injury and gender: patterns of prevalence, methods, and locations among female and male adolescents and young adults</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sornberger, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'automutilation non suicidaire (AMNS) est la destruction délibéré et immédiate du tissue corporel sans intention suicidaire, et pour des raisons non sanctionnée par la société. La recherche indique qu'entre 13 et 23% des adolescents et entre 4 et 47% des jeunes adultes ont pratiqué l'AMNS au moins une fois dans leur vie, mais le rôle du sexe dans ce comportement continue d'être incertain. Cette étude a évalué les différences dans la prévalence, les méthodes, et les lieux de mutilation entre les sexes dans deux échantillons: des adolescents et de jeunes adultes. Les résultats indiquent un schéma de différences entre les femelles et mâles qui n'est que partiellement constant entre les deux échantillons. Ceci pourrait suggérer des différences de développement. Des implications pour la recherche dans le domaine de l'AMNS, de même que pour les psychologues scolaires travaillant avec des clients à risque d'AMNS sont discutées.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Non-suicidal self-injury (NSSI) is the deliberate, self-inflicted destruction of body tissue without conscious suicidal intent, for purposes not socially sanctioned. Community-based research estimates that 13 to 23% of adolescents and 4 to 47% of young adults have engaged in NSSI at least once. Little is known about gender's role in this behaviour. The current study investigated gender differences in prevalence, method, and location of NSSI in two samples: adolescents and young adults. Results indicate a pattern of differences between females and males which was only  partially consistent across two age samples, which suggests possible developmental differences. Implications for researchers studying NSSI and school psychologists working with clients at risk for NSSI are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nancy Lee Heath</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w768m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bp54h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zh230"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Technology and civil aviation: How popular attitudes and government policies shaped civil aviation and the air cargo industry from the early years of aviation through the jet age</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lycos, Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Au fur et a mesure que les attitudes populaires entourant un certain type de technologie évoluent et que cette industrie croit and approbation et utilisation, elles provoquent des étincelles de progrès et d'innovation dans ce secteur. Ceci, à son tour, attire l'attention des intérêts du gouvernement.  Constatant l'utilité de cette technologie et de sa place légitime dans l'avancement du bien-être de la nation, les politiques et réglementations gouvernementales visent à stimuler sa croissance optimale et a réduire la perception négative de tout effet secondaire.  Ces forces externes influencent la direction que prend l'innovation technologique dans un espace donné.  Parallèlement, le sous-produit de telles forces est une technologie qui s'adapte et déploie son dû niveau d'influence dans la future vague d'attitudes populaires àvenir et les politiques gouvernementales le concernant.  La relation entre l'aviation civile, les opérations de fret aérien aux Etats-Unis et les attitudes populaires jointes aux politiques gouvernementales encadrant cet espace est un exemple d'un tel phénomène.  Plus précisément, que le niveau dominant la technologie de l'aviation civile de 1903 à 1955 a été une fonction : (1) des attitudes populaires dominantes et (2) des politiques gouvernementales (par exemple politiques nationales des États-Unis et politiques gouvernementales internationales) -elles mêmes influencées par les progrès technologiques dans ce domaine. Plutôt que d'offrir un compte rendu exhaustif des forces qui façonnent l'aviation civile, cette thèse propose une analyse approfondie du contexte dans lequel la technologie s'est développée dans l'aviation des États-Unis afin de mieux comprendre l'interaction entre ces forces et les avancées technologiques qu'elles ont inspiré.  Cet ouvrage retrace l'évolution des attitudes populaires à partir d'une variété de perspectives, les efforts de la législation américaine (p.e. Air Mail Act$</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>As popular attitudes surrounding the place of a particular type of technology evolve, they spark advances and innovation as the technology grows in acceptance and use. This, in turn, attracts the attention of government interests. Agreeing on the technology's usefulness and rightful place in advancing the nation's welfare, government policies and regulation seek to encourage its optimum growth and reduce any perceived negative knock-on effects. These external forces influence the direction that technological innovation takes in a given space. Concurrently, the byproduct of such external forces is an adapting technology which itself exerts its due level of influence in the next wave of popular attitudes and government policies concerning it. The relationship between civil aviation and air cargo operations in the United States and the popular attitudes and government policies surrounding this space is one example of such a phenomenon. More specifically, that the prevailing level of civil aviation technology from 1903 to 1955 was a function of: (1) prevailing popular attitudes and (2) government policies (e.g. domestic U.S. and foreign government policies)—themselves influenced by the technological advances in the field. Rather than offer an exhaustive account of the forces shaping civil aviation, this thesis offers a thoughtful analysis of the context in which aviation technology developed in the United States in order to better understand the interplay between these forces and the technological advances they inspired.  This work traces the development of popular attitudes from a variety of perspectives, U.S. legislative efforts (e.g. Air Mail Act of 1925, Air Commerce Act of 1926, Civil Aeronautics Act of 1938), and international law (e.g. Warsaw Convention of 1929, Hague Protocol of 1955) as they relate to the advances made in civil aviation and air cargo. This is buttressed by a survey of selected technological changes over this period. Finally, the thesis conc</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pierre-Emmanuel Moyse</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q674x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh230</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f621r"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of lesson characteristics on dialogue duration in classroom discourse and class content learning outcomes on multiple-choice tests</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lemay, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It has been proposed that forms of dialogue (Keegan, 1993) are differentially related to subject knowledge possessed by the student and the roles that teachers and students play within those dialogues. A reading of the socio-constructivist literature suggests that maximal learning occurs in instructional situations that are authentic, meaningful, and actively involve students in constructing their knowledge (Loyens &amp; Gijbels, 2008). It has been shown (Alexander, Kulikowich, &amp; Schulze, 1994) that interest and prior knowledge interact with subject mastery. Hence, it was hypothesized that different forms of dialogue would have different class content learning outcomes because interest and prior knowledge influence opportunities for elaborative encoding (Bradshaw &amp; Anderson, 1982). This study is based on a thirteen-week educational psychology course for pre-service teachers whose instructional design was grounded on socio-constructivist principles of learning. A mixed-methods exploratory study (Creswell, 2007) included a model of classroom discourse analysis (1998, 2002) to explore the effect of topic characteristics and dialogue forms on dialogue duration and class content learning outcomes. An overall effect for Dialogue Form and an interaction was found between Dialogue Form and Dialogue Duration. A qualitative analysis introduced two new variables, Curriculum Topic, and Dialogue Responsibility. Further quantitative analysis identified significant differences between curriculum topics and dialogue responsibility on class content learning outcomes. These findings suggest that an analysis of individual dialogues alone is insufficient to explain the variability in class content learning outcomes and that any proper account of the complexities of classroom dialogue must also take into account at least two other contextual elements, namely curriculum topic and dialogue responsibility.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Il a été proposé que les formes de dialogues (Keegan, 1993) correspondent différentiellement à la connaissance de la matière possédé par l'étudiant, et aux rôles assumés par l'enseignant et les étudiants dans ces dialogues. Une lecture de la littérature socio-constructiviste propose qu'un apprentissage maximal se produit dans des situations d'apprentissage qui sont authentiques, significatives, et qui impliquent activement les étudiants dans la construction de leurs savoirs (Loyens &amp; Gijbels, 2008). Il a été démontré (Alexander, et al., 1994) que l'intérêt et la connaissance antérieure interagissent avec la maîtrise d'une matière. Ainsi, l'hypothèse était que des formes différentes de dialogue produisent des résultats d'apprentissage variables pour la classe (comprise dans son ensemble) parce que l'intérêt et la connaissance antérieure influent sur les occasions pour l'approfondissement de l'encodage (Bradshaw &amp; Anderson, 1982). Cette étude est basée sur un cours d'introduction à la psychologie de l'éducation pour des étudiants en formation professionnelle d'enseignement. Le cours était basé sur des principes socio-constructivistes de l'apprentissage. Cette étude exploratoire et séquentielle de méthodologie mixte (Creswell, 2007) comptait un modèle de l'analyse du discours (1998, 2002) pour explorer les effets du topique et des formes de dialogue sur la durée des dialogues et les résultats d'apprentissage par topique. Un effet multivariable pour les formes de dialogue ainsi qu'une interaction fut identifiés entre les formes de dialogues et la durée des dialogues. L'analyse qualitative introduit deux nouveaux variables, le Topique curriculaire, et la Responsabilité pour le dialogue. La deuxième analyse quantitative identifia des différences significatives entre les topiques curriculaires et la responsabilité pour le dialogue sur les résultats d'apprentissage pour la classe. Ces résultats indiquent qu'une analyse i</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mark Wesley Aulls</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150j62m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f621r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj9602104f"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A vibrotactile floor for enabling interaction through walking in virtual spaces</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Law, Alvin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In existing virtual environments, conventional ground surfaces often impair a user's sense of immersion due to their static nature. This thesis presents a novel approach to enhance one's sense of presence through a floor interface platform that mimics a variety of ground terrains. The ambient system records the force profile of footsteps, synthesizes appropriate responses, and delivers these signals through vibrating floor tiles to imitate the feel and sound of walking on various surfaces. High-quality interactive graphics provided by overhead projectors complete the multimodal experience. Virtual snow and ice environments were developed that allow users to create footprints and crack a frozen ice sheet. Moreover, a perceptual experiment involving the recognition of eight vibration patterns, or haptic icons, delivered to the feet was performed to gauge its discrimination ability. It was found that the interaction afforded to  users by the augmented floor was both engaging and perceptually convincing.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A present, dans les milieux virtuels, les surfaces de planchers conventionnelles nuisent a la sensation d'immersion a cause de leur nature statique. Cette these de recherche propose une approche nouvelle pour ameliorer l'experience de l'utilisateur en utilisant un plancher interactif capable de reproduire plusieurs sortes de terrains. Le systeme ambiant capte le profile de force applique au plancher par les pas de l'utilisateur, synthese une reponse appropriee et transmet ces signaux a l'aide de tuiles vibrantes ce qui reproduit la sensation tactile et sonore de marcher sur divers types de surfaces. De plus, la surface du plancher est illuminee par des projecteurs suspendus au plafond, permettant la projection de graphiques interactifs et de hautes qualites pour completer l'experience multimodale. Par exemple, des environnements virtuels hivernaux permettant aux utilisateurs de laisser leurs traces dans la neige ou de craquer la glace d'un etang gele ont ete developpes pour d ́emontrer les capacites du systeme. De plus, une etude de perception sur la reconnaissance de huit modeles de vibration, ou d'icones tactiles, transmis par notre plancher pour elucider la capacite de discrimination du pied a permit de d ́ecouvrir que notre systeme est perceptivement convaincant et prenant.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jeremy Cooperstock</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579s59n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602104f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8p58pd30x"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>CM cycles on varieties fibered over Shimura curves, and «p»-adic «L»-functions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Masdeu Sabaté, Marc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Let f be a modular form of weight k ≥ 4 on a Shimura curve, let K be a quadratic imaginary field, and fix a rational prime p which is inert in K and di- vides the level of f. The goal of this thesis is to construct and study a collection of algebraic cycles on an appropriate Chow motive which encode data about the anticyclotomic p-adic L-function Lp(f,K,s) attached to f and K introduced by Bertolini-Darmon-Iovita-Spieß in [BDIS02]. In our setting, this function of a p-adic variable s vanishes in the critical range s = 1,...,k−1, and we study its derivative. After constructing this motive and the corresponding cycles, we compute their im- age under a p-adic analogue of the Griffiths-Weil Abel-Jacobi map, and show how this recovers the derivatives of the p-adic L-function at all the points in the critical range.  Our main result can be viewed as a generalization of the result obtained by Iovita-Spieß in [IS03], which gives a similar formula for the “central” value s = k/2. It can also be seen as an extension of the construction of Bertolini-Darmon-Prasanna appearing in [BDP09] to the Shimura curve setting.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Soit f une forme modulaire de poids k ≥ 4 sur une courbe de Shimura, soit K un corps quadratique imaginaire, et soit p un premier fixé qu'on suppose inerte dans K. Le but de cette thèse est de construire une collection de cycles algébriques sur un motif de Chow approprié, et de démontrer qu'ils sont liés à la fonction-L p-adique anti-cyclotomique Lp(f,K,s) attachée à f et K introduite par Bertolini-Darmon-Iovita-Spieß dans [BDIS02]. Cette fonction d'une variable p-adique s s'annule dans l'intervalle critique s = 1,...,k−1, et nous nous intéressons à sa dérivée. Après avoir construit le motif et les cycles correspondants, nous calculons leur image par un analogue p-adique de l'application d'Abel-Jacobi, et nous retrouvons la dérivée de Lp(f,K,s) dans l'intervalle critique.  Notre résultat principal est une généralisation du théorème obtenu par Iovita-Spieß dans [IS03], qui donne une formule du même genre pour la valeur centrale s = k/2. Cette thèse étend également les constructions introduites par Bertolini-Darmon-Prasanna dans [BDP09] au cadre des courbes de Shimura.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Henri Darmon</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Adrian Iovita</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sq495.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pd30x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w770n"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>RNAi applications: development of approaches for selection of siRNAs and characterization of miRNA function in cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Zhen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>RNA interference (RNAi) is an evolutionarily conserved me chanism for silencing gene expression mainly through small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) and microRNAs (miRNAs). SiRNAs have revolutionized experimental biology and gained recognition as a powerful tool for functional genomics studies. The sequence-specific selectivity and robust capacity of siRNA to inactivate genes in vivo has also led to the development of novel RNAi-based therapeutics. Recently, miRNA has attracted considerable attention due to its important roles in the regulation of various cellular processes, especially its link with cancer. Understanding of RNAi has advanced remarkably worldwide. In light of such progress, this project aimed to develop a high throughput approach for forward screening of the most effective siRNAs in mammalian cells, and to comprehensively analyze sequence variations in both miRNA targets and miRNA genes in human tumor tissues and characterize their roles in tumorigenesis.  To develop a genetic forward approach for screening of siRNAs as the first objective, siRNA expression libraries were directly delivered into mammalian cells via bacterial invasion. The target genes were fused with the suicide gene, cytosine deaminase, and stably expressed in mammalian cells. The most effective siRNAs were conveniently and robustly identified in surviving cells under drug selection without the prior assay of the RNAi potency of individual siRNAs in all wells that is required by other siRNA screening methods.  Significantly, the potent siRNAs isolated from the surviving cells proved to have noncellular toxicity. Hence, this approach can robustly enrich the most potent and nontoxic siRNAs in surviving cells, and thus has considerable potential to facilitate RNAi applications by minimizing the dose-dependent and sequence-nonspecific side effects of siRNAs.  To investigate whether single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) located at miRNA-binding sites affect the expression of miRNA targets</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>RNA interférence (RNAi) est un mécanisme conservé au cours de l'évolution,les gènes de silence sont exprimés principalement par les petits RNAs interférents (siRNAs) et les microRNAs (miRNAs). Les petits RNAs interférents ont expérimentalement révolutionné la biologie, et ont obtenu la reconnaisance comme un outil puissant sur les études utiles génomiques. La sélectivité de la séquence spécifique et la capicité robuste de siRNA à inactiver les gènes in vivo a aussi dirigé le développement de la nouvelle thérapeutique de RNAi-based. Récemment, miRNA a attiré une attention considérable grâce à ses rôles importants dans la régulation de divers processus cellulaires, surtout ses liens avec le cancer. La compréhension de RNAi a progressé remarquablement dans le monde entire. À la lumière de tel progrès, ce projet s'est efforcé de développer une approche de haut rendement pour filtrer les siRNAs les plus effecaces dans les cellules mammifères, analyser d'une manière globale les variations des séquences dans les miRNAs de cibles et de gènes dans les tissus des tumeurs humains, et caractériser leurs rôles dans la cancérogénèse.  Pour développer une approche génètique pour filtrer les siRNAs comme le premier objectif, les bibliothèques d'expression de siRNA ont été livrées directement aux cellules mammifères via les vecteurs bactériens. Les gènes de cibles ont été fondus avec le gène de suicide, et ont été exprimés avec stabilité dans les cellules mammifères. Les siRNAs les plus efficaces ont été identifiés commodément et puissamment dans la survie des cellules sous la sélection de médicament, sans l'essai préalable sur le pouvoir de RNAi de siRNAs individuel dans toutes les cellules qui sont demandées par les autres méthodes de filtrage de siRNA. Évidemment, les siRNAs puissants isolés de la survie des cellules prouvent qu'ils ont la toxicité non-cellulaire. De là, cette approche peut enrichir p</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shi-Hsiang Shen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d013s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w770n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3f4625866"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microstructure and corrosion and tribo-corrosion behaviors of Si-based and Ti-based aerospace coatings produced by PECVD</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Duanjie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Microstructure and corrosion and tribo-corrosion behaviors of Ti-based and Si-based coatings have been systematically investigated. A series of Ti-based and Si-based coatings with different silicon and/or carbon contents were prepared by plasma enhanced chemical vapor deposition (PECVD). Various experimental techniques were employed for the microstructural characterization of the coatings, e.g., X-ray diffraction (XRD), field emission scanning electron microscopy (FESEM), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and atomic force microscopy (AFM). The mechanical and tribological properties were assessed using nano-indentation, micro-scratch test and pin-on-disk wear test. Corrosion resistance was measured using potentiodynamic polarization test and analyzed using electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), while the tribo-corrosion behavior was characterized using reciprocating wear test in corrosion environment in tribo-corrosion apparatus. The grain size refinement took place as the Si and C incorporated into the TiN coating. At the same time, the microstructure of the coatings changed and a transition from TiN columnar structure into densely packed homogeneous nano-composite structure was observed for nc-TiN/a-SiNx and nc-TiCN/a-SiCN coatings. This gave rise to a further improvement of the corrosion resistance by a factor of ~20 compared to TiN.  Interface structure of the TiN coating system was designed in such a way that the hardness increased gradually with the distance from the substrate to the coating surface. This was done by applying a Cr interlayer in order to enhance the adhesion and simultaneously improve the load bearing capacity. In addition, the Cr interlayer further enhanced the corrosion resistance of the TiN-based nano-composite coatings.  The Ti-Si-C coatings mainly consisted of nanocrystalline TiC particles embedded in the a-SiCx:H and a-C:H matrix. The refinement of the TiC grains and the increase of the amorphous fraction simultaneously took</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La microstructure et le comportement en corrosion et en tribo-corrosion des revêtements à base de titane et de silicium ont été systématiquement étudiés. Une série de ces revêtements contenant différentes composition de silicium (Si) et/ou de carbone (C) ont été préparés par déposition chimique en phase vapeur assistée par plasma (PECVD). Différentes techniques expérimentales ont été utilisées pour la caractérisation de la microstructure des revêtements. Un raffinement de la taille des grains s'est produit lors de l'incorporation du Si ou du C dans la composition du revêtement TiN. Au même temps, la microstructure du revêtement a changé et une transition de la microstructure de colonnaire à celle nanocomposite, dense et homogène a été observée pour les revêtements nc-TiN/a-SiNx and nc-TiCN/a-SiCN. Cela a permit de rehausser la résistance à la corrosion d'un facteur de ~20 comparé au TiN. La structure de l'interface du système de revêtement TiN a été conçue de façon à ce que la dureté augmente graduellement avec la distance entre le substrat et la surface du revêtement. Cela a été réalisé en appliquant une couche intermédiaire de chrome (Cr) dans le but de rehausser l'adhésion et simultanément d'augmenter la capacité de chargement. En plus, la couche de Cr a permit l'augmentation de la résistance â la corrosion des revêtements nanocomposites à base de TiN. Les revêtements Ti-Si-C sont principalement constitués de particules nanocristallines de TiC incorporées dans une matrice  amorphe a-SiCx:H and a-C:H. Le raffinement de  la taille des grains de TiC et l'augmentation de la fraction de phase amorphe se produit lorsque plus de Si et/ou de C sont incorporés dans les revêtements Ti-Si-C. Cela a permit d'améliorer les propriétés électrochimiques du Ti-Si-C, lequel peut être attribué à la résistance à la corrosion supérieure et a la densité et l'homogénéité de la matrice -SiCx:H and a-C:H qui e</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Richard Chromik</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jolanta Klemberg-Sapieha</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jerzy A. Szpunar</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b1631.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f4625866</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqz20ss865"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Energetic, morphologic and physiologic responses during «Heligmosomoides bakeri» (Nematoda) infection and protein deficiency in pregnant and lactating mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Odiere, Maurice</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research investigated the concurrent effects of a gastrointestinal nematode infection Heligmosomoides bakeri, pregnancy, and protein deficiency (PD) during late pregnancy throughout lactation on energetic, morphologic and immunological responses in CD1 mice and their offspring. Our novel findings can be summarized broadly into three key themes: (i) energetics and resting metabolic rate, (ii) bone metabolism and (iii) immune development.  This work highlights the largely independent ways in which the mouse responds to competing demands of pregnancy, infection, and PD. Pregnancy increased RMR while PD lowered RMR; a trickle infection was not associated with any change. During pregnancy, these additional energetic demands were met by increased food intake and fat utilization. During infection mice lowered their body temperature. Finally, the reduction in RMR during PD was associated with higher serum corticosterone and leptin concentrations.  A second novel finding was that both infection and PD impacted on maternal and neonatal bone development. Infection lowered maternal femur bone area which was associated with elevated serum IFN-γ in heavily infected pregnant mice and reduced foetal crown-rump length consistent with higher amniotic fluid IL-1β. Lower bone mineralization in PD dams was associated with elevated serum corticosterone and leptin whereas it was associated with elevated serum IL-1β and IL-6 during infection. The elevated serum IL-1β, lower leptin and IGF-1 in pups of PD and infected dams were consistent with the shorter crown-rump length.   Finally, we explored for the first time the impact of maternal PD and infection on neonatal immune development. Both maternal infection and PD reduced lymphoid organ mass in pups whereas the percentage of T cells and T:B cell ratio in the spleen was increased only by maternal PD. These changes were associated with elevated corticosterone and IL-6 concentration in milk, and lower pup serum leptin and IGF-1 i</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'impact sur les réactions immunologiques, énergétiques et morphologiques a été étudié suite à une combinaison de facteurs tels une infection par Heligmosomoides bakeri, un nématode du système gastro-intestinal, la grossesse et la déficience protéique (DP) durant les derniers mois de grossesse et pendant la lactation chez les souris CD1 et leur descendance. Nos découvertes peuvent se résumer selon trois thèmes clés: (i) énergétique et métabolisme de base (MB), (ii) métabolisme osseux et (iii) développement immunitaire.    Ce travail met en évidence les diverses voies indépendantes utilisées par la souris pour répondre à trois évènements: la grossesse, l'infection et la DP. La grossesse a augmenté le MB tandis que la DP l'a diminué. Une infection peu sévère n'a été associée à aucun changement. Durant la grossesse, les besoins énergétiques supplémentaires ont été comblés en augmentant l'apport nutritionnel et l'utilisation des graisses. Pendant la période d'infection, la température corporelle des souris a diminué. Enfin, la réduction du MB lors de la DP a corrélé avec une plus grande concentration de corticostérone et de leptine.   Notre seconde découverte montre que l'infection et la DP ont un impact sur le développement osseux maternel et néonatal. L'infection a diminué l'os du fémur et a entraîné une forte concentration d'IFN-γ dans le sérum des souris gestantes fortement infectées. Elle a aussi diminué la distance vertex-coccyx tout en augmentant IL-1β dans le fluide amniotique. Une plus faible minéralisation osseuse chez les souris souffrant de DP coïncidait avec une forte concentration de corticostérone et de leptine dans le sérum bien qu'elle coïncidait avec une forte concentration d'IL-1β et d'IL-6 lors de l'infection. Une concentration élevée de IL-1β mais plus faible de leptine et de IGF-1 chez les souriceaux de mères infectées et souffrant de DP était compatible avec des distances$</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marilyn Scott</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Kristine G. Koski</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dm70w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20ss865</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Parasitology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9w0323438"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Remediation of mixed contaminants (polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons and heavy metals) in soil with the s,s- stereoisomer of ethylenediaminedisuccinic acid and Brij98`</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wen, Yuexiang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les efficacités d'extraction choisis avec le stéréoisomère [S,S] – de l'acide éthylènediaminedisuccinique ([S,S] - EDDS) sur des produits toxiques sélectionnées ont été étudiées. Un procédé de lavage a été optimisé et évalué pour solubiliser simultanément les composés aromatiques polycycliques de l'hydrocarbure (APH) et les métaux lourds du sol, dans une solution de mobilisation aqueuse contenant 0.1 M EDDS-6% (V/V) Brij98. Le procédé optimisé avec l'agent chélateur EDDS a mobilisé du sol un total de 101% de B [a] P  après neuf extractions successifs. Comparativement, quand les expériences ont été réalisée avec EDTA ou sans l'adition d'agent complexant (seulement agent tensio-actif Brij 98), l'EDDS augment la efficacité un 21% par rapport à EDTA et 28% à la solution traitante en absence de agente complexant. Cependant, l'extraction de chrysène n'a pas été sensiblement affectée par la présence du réactif chélateur EDDS. La modélisation du processus d'extraction pour des composés organiques, APH, qui restent dans le sol a indiqué que B [a] P a été extraite plus efficacement en présence d'EDDS, c.-à-d. le nombre de lavages requis pour réduire la concentration initiale de B [a] P à la moitié était moins que le nombre prévu de lavages en présence d'EDTA ou de Brij98 seulement, et les différences étaient significatives au niveau de 95% de la confiance. L'EDDS a également eu une influence appréciable sur l'efficacité d'extraction de métaux lourds. La plupart des métaux analysés, (Al, As, Cd, Cr, Cu, Fe, Ni, Pb et Zn,) ont été extraits plus efficacement en présence d'EDDS qu'en présence d'une quantité équivalente d'EDTA ou en l'absence du réactif complexant. Néanmoins, l'extraction du Ca, du magnésium, et du manganèse par EDDS ont été diminués en comparaison avec seuls l'EDTA et/ou l'agent tensio-actif. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The efficiencies of extraction with the [S,S]-stereoisomer of ethylenediaminedisuccinic acid ([S,S]-EDDS) on selected toxicants were investigated. A soil washing procedure to solubilize mixed contaminants, polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon (PAH) compounds and heavy metals from soil, into an aqueous mobilizing solution containing 0.1 M EDDS-6% (V/V) Brij98 was optimized and evaluated. The optimized procedure with EDDS had mobilized a total of 101% of B[a]P burden from the soil after nine successive equilibrations with the same charge of mobilization aids (complexing reagent plus surfactant), which was 21% higher than analogous extractions with the equivalent quantity of EDTA and 28% higher than extractions in the absence of complexing reagent (surfactant Brij98 alone). In contrast to B[a]P, chrysene recovery was not affected appreciably by the presence of the EDDS reagent. Modelling of the extraction process for PAH compounds remaining within the soil revealed that B[a]P was extracted more efficiently in the presence of EDDS, i.e. the number of washes needed to reduce the initial concentration of B[a]P by half was less than the predicted number of washes in the presence of  EDTA or Brij98, and the differences were significant at the 95% level of confidence. EDDS also had an appreciable influence on heavy metal exraction efficiency.  Most analyte metals, (Al, As, Cd, Cr, Cu, Fe, Ni, Pb and Zn,) were extracted more efficiently in the presence of EDDS than in the presence of an equivalent quantity of EDTA or in the absence of complexing reagent. By contrast, the mobilization of Ca, Mg, and Mn by EDDS was decreased when compared with EDTA and/or surfactant alone.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>William D. Marshall</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644r976.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w0323438</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fh48x"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanisms of demyelination and axonal damage in a CD8+ T cell-mediated model of spontaneous demyelinating disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Estrada Guadarrama, José</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les maladies autoimmunitaires de démyélinisation du système nerveux sont une cause majeure pour les déficiences neurologiques chez les humains. De récentes preuves indiquent que les lymphocytes T CD8+ peuvent contribuer significativement dans la pathogénèse de ces conditions mais les mécanismes par lesquelles ces cellules induisent des dommages reste à déterminer. Pour comprendre les mécanismes par lesquelles les cellules CD8+ T peuvent induire des lésions dans le tissue nerveux in vivo, on étudie un modèle animal (nommé L31) dont la démyélinisation et l'endommagement des neurones se développent de façon spontanée, dans le système nerveux central (SNC).  Dans ce projet, on a remarqué que les lymphocytes T CD8+ sont localisés en grappes aux emplacements spécifiques dans le SNC des souris L31 et ils sont associés avec des lésions de démyélinisation. On a observé que les oligodendrocytes, mais non les neurones, des souris L31 augmentent leur expression des molécules de complexe majeur d'histocompatibilité de classe I (CMH I), et ils ont le potentiel d'interagir avec les cellules T CD8+ infiltrant le SNC de manière dépendante du CMH I avant la manifestation clinique de la maladie. On a constaté que les lymphocytes T CD8+ infiltrant le SNC sont des cellules effectrices activées et on a montré que ces cellules dégranulent in situ; cependant, on a démontré que la démyélinisation ne se produise pas par des mécanismes dépendants de perforine ni de Fas/FasL. On a déterminé l'augmentation des chimiokines CCL5 et CXCL9 et le récepteur de chimiokines CXCR3 dans le SNC des souris L31 et on a établit que l'expression de CXCR3 est nécessaire pour l'activation des microglies, l'accumulation des cellules T CD8+ dans le SNC, la démyélinisation et le développement de la maladie dans les souris L31, bien que le déficit en CXCR3 n'altère pas le phénotype fonctionnelle des lymphocytes T CD8+ transgéniques. Finalement, on a confirm</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Autoimmune demyelinating diseases of the nervous system are a major cause for neurological impairment in humans. Recent evidence indicates that CD8+ T cells may contribute significantly to pathogenesis in these conditions but the mechanisms by which CD8+ T cells induce damage remain to be established. To understand the mechanisms by which CD8+ T cells may induce nervous tissue injury in vivo, we study an animal model (referred to as L31) that spontaneously develops CD8+ T cell-mediated demyelination and axonal damage in the central nervous system (CNS). In this project, we revealed that CD8+ T cells located in clusters at specific sites within the CNS of L31 mice and their location was associated with areas of demyelination. We showed that oligodendrocytes, but not neurons, from L31 mice up-regulated their expression of major histocompatibility complex class I (MHC I) molecules and had thus the potential to interact with CNS-infiltrating CD8+ T cells in a MHC I-dependent manner before clinical manifestations of disease. We reported that active caspase 3 was present in oligodendrocytes, suggesting that oligodendrocytes undergo apoptosis in L31 mice. We found that CNS-infiltrating CD8+ T cells from L31 mice were activated effector cells and we provided evidence showing that these cells degranulated in situ; nonetheless, we found that demyelination did not occur through either perforin- or Fas/FasL-dependent mechanisms. We also determined the upregulation of the chemokines CCL5 and CXCL9 and the chemokine receptor CXCR3 in the CNS of L31 mice and established that absence of CXCR3 expression was sufficient to inhibit CD8+ T cell accumulation in the CNS, microglial activation, demyelination and disease development in the L31 model, although CXCR3 deficiency did not alter the functional phenotype of transgenic CD8+ T cells. In addition, no compensatory effect for CCR5 could be detected in L31 mice. Finally, we established the presence of CD8+ T cells and tissue damage</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sylvie Fournier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fr73k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh48x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bt92f"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modulation of the host innate immune response by «Leishmania» parasites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Contreras Garcia, Irazú</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Leishmania parasites have evolved sophisticated mechanisms to subvert macrophage immune responses in order to survive inside the mammalian host. Among these mechanisms are the rapid activation of phosphatases that in turn will inactivate protein kinases and transcription factors, causing abrogation of nitric oxide (NO) production and induction of immunosuppressive molecules. This doctoral thesis discusses novel mechanisms of how the parasite modulates the immune response of macrophages and dendritic cells.  Herein, we describe the role of Myeloid Related Proteins (MRPs) 8 and 14 during Leishmania infection. MRPs 8/14 are produced by neutrophils and are able to induce microbicidal activity in macrophages. We present data that shows that priming macrophages with MRP 8/14 before infection induces their activation. However, infection with L. major prior to MRP stimulation significantly decreases their activation. In vivo studies showed that abrogation of MRPs resulted in an increased parasitic burden, whereas injection of recombinant MRPs (rMRPs) reduced the size of the lesion and the parasitic load.  One of the main mechanisms that Leishmania parasites utilize to subvert the innate immune response is the alteration of transcription factors (TFs). In this thesis, we have shown that upon Leishmania infection, AP-1 activity is abolished and this correlates with the nuclear degradation of AP-1 subunits. Of interest, c-Jun, the main AP-1 activator is degraded and cleaved by Leishmania inside the nucleus in a GP63 dependent manner.  Despite the fact that macrophages have been considered as preferred hosts for Leishmania parasites, other cells have been described as possible hosts. Finally, we discuss the effect of Leishmania infection in dendritic cells (DCs) and how this pathogen affects their maturation and capacity to present antigen. In addition, we found that Leishmania is able to activate phosphatases to inactivate signalling pathways in these cells. Collectively, o</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le parasite Leishmania a su développer des mécanismes sophistiqués lui permettant de déjouer les réponses immunitaires des macrophages dans le but de survivre à l'intérieur de son hôte mammifère. Parmi ces mécanismes, notons l'activation rapide de phosphatases, qui inactiveront des protéines kinases et des facteurs de transcription, causant ainsi l'abrogation de la production d'oxyde nitrique, de même que l'induction de molécules immunosuppressives. Cette thèse doctorale discute de nouveaux mécanismes utilisés par le parasite afin de moduler la réponse immunitaire des macrophages et des cellules dendritiques. Dans le présent rapport, nous décrirons le rôle des MRPs (Myeloid Related Proteins) 8 et 14 lors de l'infection par Leishmania. Produites par les neutrophiles, les MRPs 8/14 ont la capacité d'induire l'activité microbicide des macrophages. Nos résultats montrent qu'une sensibilisation active pré-infection des macrophages avec les MRPs 8/14 induit leur activation. Par contre, lorsque l'infection à L.major est antérieure à la stimulation avec les MRPs, l'activation des macrophages est significativement réduite. Les études in vivo démontrent quant à elles que l'abrogation des MRPs a entraîné une augmentation de la charge parasitaire, alors que l'injection de MRPs recombinantes réduit la taille de la lésion, de même que la charge parasitaire. Un des principaux mécanismes qu'utilisent les parasites Leishmania, afin de déjouer la réponse immunitaire innée, est l'altération de facteurs de transcription. À l'aide de nos résultats, nous démontrons que l'activité d'AP-1 est abolie suite à l'infection par Leishmania, ceci concordant avec la dégradation au noyau des protomères d'AP-1. Il est d'ailleurs à souligner que c-Jun, le principal activateur d'AP-1, est dégradé et clivé par Leishmania à l'intérieur du noyau, et ce de façon GP63 dépendante.  Malgré le fait que les macrophages sont considérés comme les cell</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Martin Olivier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hc58r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bt92f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nf146"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Economic integration of immigrants to Canada and foreign credential recognition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Girard, Magali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The lack of foreign credential recognition by Canadian employers and professional associations is often cited as one of the explanations for the increasing earnings gap between Canadian workers and immigrant workers. The main objective of my dissertation is to look at different aspects of economic integration of immigrants to Canada, and more specifically at issues related to credential recognition.  The objective of the first analysis is to examine the extent to which, after arrival, immigrants find jobs in the same occupations in which they were employed in their home countries. I also examine the effect on earnings of a match between the pre- and post-immigration occupations. Our results suggest that most recent immigrants move into a new occupation when they arrive in Canada and that those whose pre- and post-immigration occupations match tend to earn more. In the second analysis, I determine how many immigrants work in regulated and unregulated occupations and look at how education is associated with the likelihood of working in a regulated occupation. In aggregate, immigrants are slightly less likely to work in a regulated occupation. Immigrants educated in Asia, Latin America, and the Caribbean prove to be much less likely to secure access to a regulated occupation than either the native-born or other immigrants.  The objective of the third analysis is to understand the transition between immigrants' premigration education and their educational trajectories once in Canada, and the return on investment in postmigration education in terms of employment status and earnings. A third of new immigrants with postsecondary training pursue their education during their early years in Canada. Those who enrol do not see an immediate benefit in terms of their earnings and employment status. In the last chapter, I examine foreign credential recognition processes in Canada and recent public investments to address this issue. Gaining foreign credential recognition from a</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le manque de reconnaissance des titres de compétences acquis à l'étranger est l'une des causes souvent citées pour expliquer l'augmentation de la disparité salariale entre immigrants et non-immigrants au Canada. Le principal objectif de ma thèse est d'examiner différents aspects de l'intégration économique des immigrants au Canada, et plus particulièrement ceux liés à la reconnaissance des titres de compétences étrangers.  Le but de la première étude est d'analyser le lien entre le domaine de l'emploi principal occupé par les immigrants avant leur arrivée et les emplois qu'ils ont occupés en début d'établissement, ainsi que l'effet net d'une adéquation des emplois sur le revenu des immigrants récents. Les résultats suggèrent que la plupart de ces immigrants ne se trouvent pas un emploi dans leur domaine; par ailleurs, ceux qui y parviennent ont un salaire plus élevé. Dans la deuxième analyse, je détermine combien d'immigrants travaillent dans des professions réglementées et non réglementées. J'examine comment l'éducation est associée à la probabilité de travailler dans une profession réglementée et, dans l'ensemble, les immigrants sont un peu moins susceptibles de travailler dans de telles professions. Les immigrants formés en Asie, en Amérique latine et dans les Caraïbes ont beaucoup moins de chances d'occuper une profession réglementée que les autres immigrants et les non-immigrants.  L'objectif de la troisième analyse est de comprendre la transition entre l'éducation pre-migratoire et les trajectoires d'éducation au Canada, et les effets de l'investissement en éducation post-migratoire sur l'employabilité et le revenu. Un tiers des nouveaux immigrants ayant une formation postsecondaire poursuivent leurs études pendant leurs premières années au Canada. Ceux qui s'inscrivent à un programme de formation ne voient pas un bénéfice immédiat sur leur revenu et les chances d'être en emploi.  Dans le dernier chap</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael R. Smith</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mv51j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nf146</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology - Ethnic and Racial Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860735z"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pushing the boundaries of second language education: exploring the use of "sensitive" material for language learning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Walkty, Mélanie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans le but de favoriser une compréhension plus profonde des possibilités pédagogiques liées à l'utilisation d'histoires vécues pour aborder des sujets « délicats » lors de l'enseignement d'une langue seconde, l'auteure a effectué une étude exploratoire basée sur une réflexion personnelle, décrivant son processus de raisonnement et sa démarche pour trouver du matériel potentiel pour l'enseignement de l'ALS dans la banque de données et les archives du projet Histoires de vie Montréal. Les directives pratiques et pédagogiques suggérées dans la présente thèse pourraient aider les enseignants d'ALS à éviter certaines difficultés et certains dangers pouvant surgir au moment d'aborder des sujets comme le génocide et les droits de la personne. Il est à espérer que ce type de cadre théorique aidera les enseignants à organiser leurs pensées et à intégrer l'éducation en matière de droits de la personne au moyen de matériel sensible dans la classe d'ALS.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>For the purpose of developing a deeper understanding of the pedagogical possibilities of using life story material to teach “sensitive” issues in second language classroom, the author conducts an exploratory study based on personal reflective narrative, describing her reasoning process and the steps involved in locating potential ESL materials in the Montreal Life Stories project's database and archive. The practical instructional and pedagogical guidelines suggested in this thesis have the ability to help ESL teachers avoid certain difficulties and dangers that come with teaching about genocide and human rights education.  It is hoped that this type of framework will help second language educators organize their thinking and facilitate links to human rights education through the use of sensitive materials in the ESL classroom.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mekhala Sarkar</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xv37q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860735z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Language and Literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zt69c"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Transposon mutagenesis of «Mycobacterium avium» subsp. «paratuberculosis» to investigate potential pathogenicity islands</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moolji, Jalaluddin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Titre de la thèse : La Mutagénèse de Transposon de Mycobacterium avium sous-espèce paratuberculosis pour Investiguer des Zones de Pathogenicité Potentielles.  Résumé : Mycobacterium avium sous-espèce paratuberculosis (MAP) est l'agent causal de la maladie de Johne, une maladie chronique intestinale des bétails très répandue.  C'est aussi l'agent causal putatif de la maladie de Crohn, une maladie inflammatoire de l'intestin chronique chez l'humain.  Le génome de MAP contient six segments d'ADN appelés des grands polymorphismes de séquences (LSPP) qui ne sont pas présents chez les cousins évolutionnaires de cette bactérie et qui furent probablement obtenus par transfert génique horizontal.  Ensembles, ils constituent 125kb soit 2,5% du génome de MAP, et contiennent 96 cadres de lecture ouverts.  Une analyse approfondie de l'évolution de MAP nous a mené à supposer que les LSPP sont des zones de pathogenicité qui codent des gènes importants pour la survie et la réplication de MAP dans l'hôte.  Afin de tester cette hypothèse, nous avons produit une banque de mutants de transposon de MAP de 5 000 membres, et nous avons mis au point des conditions de réaction en chaîne par polymérase (PCR) pour identifier des mutants potentiels des gènes LSPP.  Nous avons réussi à isoler un mutant de MAP3776c, qui encode un sidérophore de zinc.  Ce dernier fait partie d'un opéron de cinq gènes pour un système de captation zinc qui prend presque la totalité de  la séquence d'insertion LSPP15.  Le mutant ne semble pas avoir de défauts de croissance in vitro, et il est capable de coloniser les foies et les rates des souris C57Bl/6 en une semaine à la suite d'une infection intrapéritonéalle.  Les données d'expériences en cours à long terme détermineront si le mutant a une capacité modifiée à persister dans les souris.  Le mutant de MAP3776c et la banque de mutants de transposon sont des outils avantageux pour la recherche sur la génomique e</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Mycobacterium avium subsp. paratuberculosis (MAP) is the causative agent of Johne's disease, a highly prevalent chronic intestinal disease of cattle.  It is also the putative cause of Crohn's disease, a chronic inflammatory bowel disease of humans.  The MAP genome contains six segments of DNA called large sequence polymorphisms (LSPP) that are not present in its closest evolutionary relatives and were probably acquired through horizontal gene transfer.  Together, they comprise 125kb, or 2.5% of the MAP genome, and contain 96 open reading frames.  A detailed analysis of MAP evolution led us to hypothesize that the LSPP are pathogenicity islands, encoding genes important for MAP survival or replication in the host.  To test this hypothesis, we generated a 5,000-member transposon-mutant library in MAP K-10 and developed a PCR screening method to identify potential mutants of LSPP genes.  We succeeded in isolating a mutant of MAP3776c, which encodes a putative zinc siderophore.  It is part of a putative five-gene zinc uptake operon that occupies almost the entirety of the insertion sequence, LSPP15.  The MAP3776c mutant does not appear to have in vitro growth defects, and it is able to colonize the livers and spleens of C57Bl/6 mice within one week of intraperitoneal infection.  Upcoming data from an ongoing, long-term experiment will determine whether the mutant has altered ability to persist in mice.  The mutant of MAP3776c and the transposon-mutant library are useful tools for research on MAP genomics and pathogenicity that might ultimately contribute to improvements in vaccines and immunodiagnostics for Johne's disease.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marcel A. Behr</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gk18n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zt69c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w5099"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Desautels Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Two essays on corporate governance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Yong</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse comprend deux essais sur la gouvernance corporative. La première vérifie l'hypothèse que la relation entre la valeur de la firme et le risque peut varier selon la rémunération des cadres. En appliquant un double triage sur l'échantillon selon cinq niveaux de risque et trois niveaux de rémunération de façon indépendante, nous arrivons à deux conclusions. La première est que le Tobin q s'intensifie suite à une croissance marginale des plans d'intéressement par actions, selon un niveau de risque particulier. Par conséquent, cela suggère que les rémunérations s'appuyant sur l'incitatif au risque déterminent l'harmonisation efficace de la paie des gestionnaires avec la performance de l'entreprise. La seconde conclusion est que le Tobin q a une tendance croissante à travers les niveaux de risque, selon un niveau spécifique de plans d'intéressement par actions. De ce fait, les firmes atteignent la maximisation de leur valeur lorsque les incitatifs et le risque se trouvent à leurs niveaux les plus élevés. Ce résultat suggère un mécanisme par lequel les plans d'intéressement par actions influencent la prise de risque de la part l'entreprise de sorte que la croissance marginale du risque engendre la création de valeur. Cela nous invite à investiguer davantage sur la manière dont l'aversion au risque affecte ce mécanisme. En effet, nous constatons que les différences de Tobin q entre les niveaux plus faibles et ceux plus forts en termes d'interactions entre le risque et les plans d'intéressement par actions se réduisent au fur et à mesure que l'aversion au risque diminue. Cette tendance confirme que les plans d'intéressement par actions qui encouragent la prise de risque engendrent effectivement les gestionnaires conservateurs à verser de l'argent dans des investissements risqués, mais qui génèrent de la valeur. Le second essai examine une simple intuition comprenant la détention d'argent liquide et le risque de défau</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis comprises two essays on corporate governance. The first essay (Chapter 2) examines whether or not the relationship between firm value and risk can be differently established according to executive compensations. By double-sorting the sample into five levels of risk and three levels of compensations independently, we make two findings. First, within a given level of risk, Tobin q increases with incremental equity incentives. This finding suggests that the risk-taking compensations drive the effective alignment of managers' pay to company performance. Second, within a given level of equity incentives, Tobin q has an upward trend over risk levels. As a result, firms achieve value maximization when both incentives and risk are at the highest levels. This result suggests a mechanism whereby equity incentives affect firm risk such that risk increment is associated with value creation. We further investigate how risk aversion affects the mechanism. Tobin q differences between the lowest and the highest interactions of risk and equity-incentives become larger as risk aversion decreases. This trend confirms that the risk-taking equity-based incentives effectively encourage risk-averse managers to undertake risky, yet value-creating investment.  The second essay (Chapter 3) examines a simple intuition about cash holding and default risk: A greater amount of cash better prepares firms for unexpected cash expenditures or contingent credit events. Hence, one may expect a negative correlation between large cash values and cost of risky debt. However, this intuition is not consistent with the data. We find instead a strong positive relationship between the two variables. From the perspective of corporate governance, we provide empirical explanations for the puzzling phenomenon. Building the samples differentiated by governance quality, we find that in poorly governed firms, as opposed to their well managed counterpart, agency problems drive the puzzle. The distinct</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Artyom Durnev</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290983r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w5099</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics - Finance</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75dc890"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Isolation and characterization of protein fractions from chickpea («Cicer arietinum» L.) and oat («Avena sativa» L.) seeds using proteomic techniques</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chang, Yu-Wei</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Chickpea (Cicer arietinum L.) and oat (Avena sativa L.) seeds are important sources of protein ingredients with potential nutritional, functional and bioactive properties. Protein fractions were prepared from chickpea and oat using sequential extractions with distilled water (albumins), NaCl solution (globulins) and NaOH solution (glutelins), respectively. Molecular characteristics of individual protein fractions were investigated using polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis (Native- and SDS-PAGE, and 2-DGE) in combination with reversed-phase high performance liquid chromatography (RP-HPLC). Tryptic peptide sequences were identified using proteomic techniques including 1D trypsin in-gel digestion, liquid chromatography electrospray ionization tandem mass spectrometry (LC-ESI-MS/MS) analysis and Mascot MS/MS ion search. Sequence similarity and potential bioactivity of proteins were examined using BLAST and BIOPEP analysis, respectively. Native-PAGE results showed chickpea and oat globulin fractions (C-Gb and O-Gb) contained proteins corresponding to legumin (11S) and avenalin (12S), respectively. SDS-PAGE revealed that chickpea albumin and globulin fractions (C-Ab and C-Gb) showed protein bands with MWs related to legumin (11S) and pea vicilin (7S) while chickpea glutelin fraction (C-Gt) showed protein bands with MWs related to rice glutelin; oat protein fractions (O-Ab, O-Gb and O-Gt) showed protein bands with MWs related to oat 12S globulin (avenalin). α- and β-subunits of globulin and glutelin fractions from chickpea and oat were identified with estimated MWs ranging from 31 to 45 kDa and from 21 to 31 kDa, respectively. In vitro chickpea albumin, globulin and glutelin hydrolysates showed DH of 22.8%, 28.6% and 28.8%, respectively; SDS-PAGE revealed that legumin α- and β-subunits from chickpea globulin fraction (C-Gb) were hydrolyzed. The identified tryptic peptides from chickpea and oat protein fractions showed sequence homology that corresponded to chickpea l</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les semences du pois chiche (Cicer arietinum L.) et de l'avoine (Avena sativa L.) sont d'importantes sources d'ingrédients protéiques dont les propriétés nutritionnelles, fonctionnelles et bioactives démontrent un grand potentiel. Les fractions protéiques ont été préparées à partir du pois chiche et de l'avoine par extraction séquentielle avec de l'eau distillée (albumine), une solution de NaCl (globuline) et une solution de NaOH (glutelines), respectivement. Les caractéristiques moléculaires des fractions de protéines individuelles ont été examinées par électrophorèse en gel de polyacrylamide (non dénaturante et SDS-PAGE, et 2-DGE) en combinaison avec la chromatographie en phase liquide à haute performance en phase inversée. Les séquences de peptides tryptiques ont été identifiées par des techniques protéomiques telles que la digestion de trypsine en gel unidimensionnelle, l'analyse chromatographique en phase liquide couplée à la spectrométrie de masse en tandem avec ionisation de type électrospray (LC-ESI-MS/MS), et la recherche d'ions MS/MS (Mascot). Les similarités séquentielles et la bioactivité potentielle des protéines ont été examinées sous analyse par BLAST et BIOPEP, respectivement.  Les résultats de l'électrophorèse non dénaturante en gel de polyacrylamide démontrent que les fractions de globulines du pois chiche et d'avoine (C-Gb et O-Gb) contiennent des protéines correspondant aux légumines (11S) et avenaline (12S), respectivement. La SDS-PAGE révèle que les fractions d'albumine et de globuline de pois chiche (C-Ab et C-Gb) montrent des bandes protéiques ayant des poids moléculaires reliés à la légumine (11S) et le viciline de pois (7S) alors que la fraction de glutéline de pois chiche (C-Gt) montre des bandes protéiques avec des poids moléculaires reliés à la glutéline de riz; les fractions  protéiques d'avoine (O-Ab, O-Gb et O-Gt) montrent de bandes protéiques avec des poids moléculaire</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Inteaz Alli</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b165k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dc890</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Food Science and Technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386j55f"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La Habana es La Habana: tourism, heritage and symbolic space in Havana, Cuba</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaiser, Natalie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Après plus de cinquante ans d'existence, le régime socialiste Cubain continue de survivre malgré d'innombrables obstacles. Cuba a dû faire face à plusieurs changements depuis la chute de l'URSS en 1989, et ceci a contribué à l'inauguration de plusieurs politiques qui ont grandement changé l'espace politique, social et économique du pays. Ma recherche porte sur la contradiction fondamentale qui existe à Cuba entre le système politique socialiste et le système économique qui est aujourd'hui axé sur des principes capitalistes. Me basant sur des techniques de recherche qualitatives, je démontre que l'état Cubain gère ces contradictions en créant des espaces discursifs et visuels. Ces espaces, notamment présents à travers des cartes touristiques et des politiques de restauration de la vielle Havane, sont des espaces symboliques hautement flexibles utilisés par l'état Cubain dans un effort de maintenir le statut quo face à un futur incertain.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>After more than fifty years, the Cuban socialist regime continues to survive against steep odds. The transition that Cuba has had to face since the fall of the Soviet Union in 1989 has led to the implementation of a number of policies that have drastically altered the social, cultural, political and economic landscape of the country. My research focuses on the fundamental contradiction that exists between Cuba's socialist political system and the market capitalism of the tourism industry in Havana, Cuba. I am especially interested in how the State attempts to resolve this contradiction. Drawing on qualitative research, I argue that the Cuban state creates visual and discursive narratives through which it manages these contradictions. I show how imaginaries created through tourist maps and through restoration policies in Old Havana consist of highly malleable symbolic landscapes that the Cuban state utilizes in order to maintain the status quo in the face of an uncertain future.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Benjamin Forest</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q187s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386j55f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s2842"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Embedded voices in-between empires: the cultural formation of Korean popular music in modern times</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, YongWoo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation examines the historical trajectory of colonial mentality and the genealogy of cultural modernity and Americanization in South Korea by recontextualizing popular music as a narrative of collective memories and mass trauma. By mapping out two continual colonial histories, those represented by the periods of the Japanese Empire and of the American military government, I develop a narrative of Korean popular music that echoes this submission experienced by Koreans, a movement empowered by modern western technology such as the gramophone, radio and phonograph records as well as by the appropriation of various foreign popular music genres.  This research primarily explores the ways in which consumption and production practices of Korean popular music were intertwined with structures of Korean cultural modernity. By examining socio-historical transformations such as urban development, commercialization and modernization, I examine the colonial experiences of Koreans as manifest in popular music narratives that gradually embraced collective sentiments and mass perceptions of everyday life under colonial circumstances, particularly as these were influenced by burgeoning concepts of western and American modernity and represented in song lyrics and musical performances from within the interior of Japanese colonial surveillance. As I shall argue, the submissive colonial narrative in Korean popular songs was enforced by the mobilization of Japanese militarism and imperial discourses concerned with “becoming an imperial subject” within the imperial national body, such that the colonial narrative was present continuously from the post-liberation era until the 1950s when the U.S. military controlled Korean society.  Thus, this research raises a set of questions concerning, first, the embedding of Japanese colonialism within Korean popular songs, and secondly, the means by which Americanization and modern life circulated within the colonial and postcolonial di</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>En replaçant la musique populaire dans le contexte d'une histoire de mémoire collective et de traumatisme de masse, cette thèse examine le parcours historique des mentalités coloniales et la généalogie de la modernité culturelle et de l'américanisation en Corée du Sud. En traçant les contours de deux histoires coloniales successives, de l'Empire japonais au contrôle du gouvernement militaire américain, les expériences modernes des Coréens font écho à la soumission implicite du récit colonial au sein du texte culturel, autorisée par le trope moderne des technologies occidentales – le gramophone, la radio et les enregistrements phonographiques – et la conciliation entre divers genres de musique populaire. Cette recherche explore comment les pratiques de consommation et de production de la musique populaire, s'enlacent intimement dans la formation de la modernité culturelle en examinant la commercialisation et la modernisation, avec le développement urbain. La représentation des expériences coloniales des Coréens dans le récit de la musique populaire a progressivement englobé les sentiments collectifs et les perceptions de masse des circonstances coloniales en insufflant le concept naissant de modernité occidentale/américaine dans les paroles et dans les performances, à travers plusieurs processus de modernisations macroscopiques dans la vie de tous les jours à l'intérieur de l'imaginaire colonial japonais. Par conséquent, le récit assujetti à l'empire japonais de l'expérience coloniale, dans les chants populaires, avait été renforcé par la mobilisation du militarisme japonais et des discours sur le « sujet impérial » à l'intérieur du corps impérial de la nation qui ont refait surface sous la forme de la soumission continuelle à l'intérieur des mentalités coréennes qui avaient repris les pleins pouvoirs après la libération du joug japonais durant les années 1950. Cette étude s'intéresse à la période de la guerr</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Straw, William O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161657c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s2842</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Mass Communications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cw64q"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development and organisational practice: ethnography at the Food and Agriculture Organisation of the United Nations (FAO)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dionne, Geneviève</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les anthropologues ont analysé le développement sous plusieurs angles : certains l'ont critiqué pour être un projet moderniste, alors que d'autres ont voulu mieux comprendre les relations entre les acteurs du monde du développement et   ont proposé des moyens alternatifs de faire du développement. Rarement les anthropologues ont étudié «vers le haut», à l'intérieur même des organisations de développement, afin d'analyser les pratiques et les cultures de cette «communauté d'experts». Ma recherche offre une perspective interne sur «l'expérience vécue» par les employés de l'Organisation pour l'alimentation et l'agriculture des Nations Unies (FAO), après avoir travaillé au sein du Livelihoods Support Programme. Ce programme avait pour but d'intégrer les «livelihoods approaches» dans les pratiques de la FAO, et peut être considéré comme une approche alternative de développement. Cette ethnographie déconstruit l'idée ‘d'une FAO', en révélant la présence de nombreuse «dis-jonctions» appartenant à la structure organisationnelle ainsi que la grande variété des professionnels employés au siège social et sur le terrain. Deux thèmes sont au cœur de l'étude : a) la complexité et la compartimentation inhérentes à l'organisation et b) le pouvoir d'agir (agency) des professionnels qui entreprennent des initiatives en plus de leur travail quotidien. L'ethnographie et l'expérience empirique ont permis de documenter l'hétérogénéité des interactions des employés avec la structure organisationnelle. Ainsi, la recherche démontre que les professionnels – charismatiques, au centre de réseaux sociaux et expérimentés – ne sont pas seulement des «experts» : en plus de leur savoir technique, ils ont également recours à leur expérience, à leurs réseaux, et à leur personnalité. Elle confirme que la ‘structure' elle-même n'est pas productive et que le pouvoir d'agir et les interactions quotidiennes des employés affecte</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Anthropologists have analysed development from several angles: some have critiqued development on the grounds that it is a modernising project, while others have sought to understand relationships between actors in development work and proposed alternative methods of pursuing development. Rarely however, have anthropologists “studied up” within organisations to analyse the practices and cultures of this ‘community of experts'. This research provides an insider's perspective on the ‘lived experienced' of employees of the Food and Agriculture Organisation of the United Nations (FAO), based on having worked as a consultant for FAO's Livelihoods Support Programme (LSP) with permission to conduct this research. The LSP aimed at ‘mainstreaming' livelihoods approaches in FAO, and may be considered as an exercise in alternative development. This ethnography deconstructs the idea of ‘one FAO', revealing the many “disjunctures” inherent to the organisational structure and the diversity of practitioners employed at HQ and in the field. This aim is achieved through focusing on two themes: a) the complexity and compartmentalisation of the organisation, depicting the organisational context within which employees work; and b) the agency of some professionals who undertake initiatives beyond their prescribed scope of work. Using ethnographic information and empirical observation, this research reports on the heterogeneity of the interactions of employees with FAO's organisational structure. With attention to charismatic, networking and experienced practitioners, the research highlights that professionals are not ‘only' experts: while achieving their tasks, development workers contribute not only their technical knowledge, but also their experience, networking skills and personalities. The research confirms that the ‘structure' itself does not produce work and that the agency and interactions of FAO personnel affect the organisation's work. The capacity of practitioners</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Galaty</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dc90r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cw64q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anthropology - Cultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1z40kt254"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of timing of umbilical cord clamping on newborn anemia: implications for clinical practice in the Peruvian Amazon</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blouin, Brittany</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Delayed umbilical cord clamping has been shown to decrease the risk of infant anemia.  A pre-post study design was used to determine the effectiveness of a two-component intervention (workshop and directive) in delaying cord clamping.  Women were recruited from the labour room of Hospital Iquitos in Iquitos Peru pre (N=112) and post intervention (N=112).  Maternal hemoglobin was assessed before delivery; time-to-cord clamping was recorded at delivery and infant hemoglobin was measured at four months of age.  Time-to-clamp increased significantly by 113 seconds following the intervention (βadjusted = 113.2 seconds, 95% CI: 96.6, 129.9).  Maternal anemia was identified as an effect modifier on the relationship between time-to-clamp and infant anemia.  In infants born to anemic women, the odds ratio of developing anemia is 0.59 for every one minute delay in cord clamping.  These findings add to the mounting support for delayed cord clamping as a means to decrease infant anemia.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Des études ont démontré que retarder la coupure du cordon ombilical pourrait réduire les risques d'anémie infantile. Un plan d'étude pré/post a été utilisé pour déterminer l'efficacité d'une intervention visant à retarder la coupure du cordon. Des femmes ont été recrutées à l'Hôpital Iquitos (Pérou) pré- (N=112) et post-intervention (N=112). Le statut hématologique des mères a été quantifié, le moment où le cordon est coupée a été chronométré et le niveau d'hémoglobine des enfants à été mesuré. La coupure du cordon a été retardée de manière significative de 113 secondes suite à l'intervention (βajusté=113.2 secondes; 95% IC =96.6-129.9). L'anémie maternelle a été identifiée comme un facteur modifiant. Chez les enfants nés d'une mère anémique, le rapport de cotes pour l'anémie est de 0.59 pour chaque minute où la coupure du cordon est retardée. Ces résultats supportent le retardement de la coupure du cordon comme mesure pouvant réduire l'anémie infantile.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Theresia Gyorkos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hj43b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kt254</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p757v"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The function of King David in the deuteronomistic history</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lemarquand, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the literary figure of King David in the narrative of Samuel-Kings. John Van Seters, in his book The Biblical Saga of King David, has identified two major blocks of tradition in the Samuel-Kings version of the narrative of David. Van Seters contends that the earlier Deu teronomistic narrative (DtrH) portrays David as the ideal king of a unified Israel, and that this narrative was overlaid by a later Persian period narrative (the David Saga,) which was written as a reaction to the Deuteronomistic narrative, and which sought to undercut its monarchical ideology. The aim of this thesis is to exact the socio-historical circumstances under which both of these narratives were composed. I will argue that DtrH reflects the hopes of the exiled elite of the Babylonian golah for the reestablishment of the Davidic line, and that the David Saga reflects the dissolution of these hopes under Persian imperial control.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine la figure littéraire du Roi David dans le récit de Samuel-Rois. John Van Seters, dans son livre « The Biblical Saga of King David », a identifié deux blocs principaux de tradition dans la version biblique de Samuel-Rois du récit de David. Van Seters affirme que le récit antérieur deutéronomiste (DtrH) dépeint David en tant que roi idéal de l'Israël unifiée, et que ce récit a été superposé par un récit postérieur de l'époque Perse (la saga de David,) qui a été écrit en réaction au récit deutéronomiste, et qui vise à nuire à son idéologie monarchique. Le but de cette thèse est d'établir les circonstances socio-historiques sous lesquelles ces deux récits on été composés. Je soutiendrai que DtrH reflète les espoirs d'élite exilée du Babylonien « golah » pour le rétablissement de la ligne de David, et que la saga de David reflète la dissolution de ces espoirs sous la commande impérial persane.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Patricia Kirkpatrick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tf740.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p757v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religion, Biblical Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149q145"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>&amp;quot;Dans la vie j'ai le vertige ... mais je sens que Dieu veut monter haut avec moi &amp;quot; : langages religieux et parcours identitaires de jeunes Haïtiens de la seconde génération à Montréal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jaimes, Annie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the role of Christian idioms and practices in the self-fashioning of second generation Haitians of Protestant faith in Montreal. These members of Baptist and Pentecostal Haitian Churches encounter the particular challenges of combining multiple affiliations as they face racism and pressures to assimilate to the mainstream Quebecois society. Taking this context into account, I examine how young Protestants use and subvert religious symbols and practices in constructing their identity, and how they negotiate their position in their world defending themselves against denigrating stereotypes. My research explores how they undertake their personal as well as collective salvation through the work of memory, a self-righteous lifestyle, an intimate relationship with God as well as through the elaboration of their Christian mission.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nb53h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149q145</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Haitians -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Ethnic identity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Haitians -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Religion</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>