<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386n69d"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the mechanism of protein release from the rat parotid gland</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harfield, Bruce</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mechanism of amylase secretion from the rat parotid gland was studied using an in vitro pulse labelling technique. Using this technique the kinetics of the appearance of the labelled protein in the various cell fractions as well as the characteristics of epinephrine-stimulated release were found to be similar to the results of other investigators. While the pattern of epinephrine-stimulated release vas different from that obtained with dibutyryl cyclic AMP, in both cases the release of labelled protein was similar to the release of amylase. The presence of EGTA did not affect epinephrine stimulated release but did decrease epinephrine-stimulated accumulation of cyclic AMP. These results indicate that the optimum calcium concentration for adenyl cyclase activity was between 0 and 2.5 mM. Cyclic AMP accumulates in the rat parotid gland in amounts in excess of that needed for protein secretion; it cannot be concluded therefore that cyclic AMP is not essential for the secret ion process.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tenenhouse, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tv63v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386n69d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>