<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn999819r"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Glucocorticoid receptors in the adrenal medulla : characterization, regulation and function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Betito, Katia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present thesis has examined in detail the dynamics of adrenomedullary glucocorticoid (GC) receptors at various concentrations of steroid, the regulation of levels of receptor following various treatments, and the regulation of phenylethanolamine N-methyltransferase (PNMT) activity following acute exposure to GCs and various time delays, providing evidence that GC regulation of adrenomedullary catecholamine biosynthesis is more dynamic than was classically thought. We report that adrenomedullary GC receptors are translocated, both in response to nM concentrations of GCs, and in response to higher concentrations of GCs encountered by the glands during stress. We show that long-term increases in cyclic nucleotide second messengers are able to decrease GC receptor binding in adrenal medullary cells, via a mechanism independent of released cortisol, and provide the first evidence that changes in adrenomedullary GC receptor levels are reflected in an alteration in a GC-mediated function, i.e. induction of PNMT. We also provide novel in vitro evidence for the regulation of adrenomedullary PNMT activity, following a necessary lag period, by acute changes in both cortisol and nicotine. In addition, our in vitro studies are supported by our in vivo findings which show increases in adrenal tyrosine hydroxylase and PNMT activity 18h following a single episode of mild acute stress (20 min restraint) in rats.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boksa, Patricia</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q5594.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999819r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dw959"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Foetal toxicity of methyl isocyanate metabolites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guest, Ian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The foetal toxicity of the methyl isocyanate metabolites trimethylamine (TMA) and S-(N-methylcarbamoyl)glutathione (SMG) was studied in mice. Administration of TMA but not SMG during pregnancy decreased foetal weight and selectively inhibited the postnatal growth of male offspring. Both TMA and SMG were teratogenic to mouse embryos in culture. TMA caused a dorsal-rostral split in the head and SMG produced distortion and separation of somites; both agents decreased the growth of embryos. The inhibition of embryonic growth by TMA could not be antagonized by antioxidants or growth factors. The embryotoxic effects of SMG could be antagonized by glutathione (GSH). TMA inhibited the incorporation of $ sp3$H-thymidine, $ sp3$H-uridine and $ sp3$H-leucine into their respective macromolecules; SMG inhibited the incorporation of $ sp3$H-thymidine. Uptake by the yolk sac placenta and incorporation into embryonic proteins of $ sp3$H-leucine-labelled proteins but not of free $ sp3$H-leucine was inhibited by TMA at concentrations which did not inhibit lysosomal degradation of proteins. SMG inhibited the uptake and incorporation of both free $ sp3$H-leucine and $ sp3$H-leucine-labelled proteins. The inhibition of receptor-mediated uptake by SMG could be antagonized by GSH. The data suggest that TMA, and SMG produce embryotoxicity mainly by an inhibition of uptake mechanisms of the yolk sac placenta.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Varma, D. R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741t364.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dw959</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Toxicology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612q19q"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some applications of Cartan's method of equivalence to the geometric study of ordinary and partial differential equations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fels, Mark Eric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cartan's method of equivalence is used to prove that there exists two fundamental tensorial invariants which determine the geometry of systems of n ($ ge$ 2) second order ordinary differential equations. These invariants allow us prove that there exist a unique equivalence class of second order equations which admit a Lie point symmetry group of maximal dimension, the dimension being $n sp2 + 4n + 3$. For third order systems of ordinary differential equations, we prove that the possible dimension of the point symmetry group is bounded by $n sp2 + 3n + 3$. As well we find that there is a unique third order system whose symmetry group has dimension n$ sp2$ + 3n + 3. We also characterize invariantly under point transformations some equivalence classes of parabolic quasi-linear second order partial differential equations, and examine their point symmetry groups. We are able to make our characterizations by proving a reduction theorem for principal fibre bundles.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kamran, Niki</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558f825.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612q19q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g1818"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Results in categorical proof theory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Čubrić, Djordje</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We prove a completeness result for the equivalence of proofs in the positive fragment (T, $ Lambda, rightarrow$) of intuitionistic propositional logic with respect to sets. We also show that proofs in the full intuitionistic propositional logic factor through interpolants--in this way we prove a stronger interpolation property than the usual one which gives only the existence of interpolants. Translating that to categorical terms, we give a representation theroem for free Cartesian closed categories (Theorem 3.16) in the category of sets and we show that pushouts of biCartesian closed categories have the interpolation property (Theorem 4.47).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Makkai, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xz95z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g1818</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajw827d23f"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Plagiorchis elegans from cercariae to infective metacercariae : factors affecting transmission, requirements for development, and behavioural responses of intermediate hosts to infection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lowenberger, Carl A. (Carl Arnold)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Plagiorchis elegans is a typical digenean parasite that cycles through aquatic molluscs and insects as intermediate hosts. During emergence of P. elegans cercariae, infected snails moved to the top of the water column where they remained immobile for 2-3h. Consequently, the cercariae formed a dense cloud which dispersed slowly. The infectivity of cercariae was $&lt;$20% upon emergence and peaked at 76% 4-6h later. This delay in reaching maximum infectivity may be an adaptation to prevent superinfection and the associated mortality of insect hosts. Cercariae transformed into metacercariae after penetrating Aedes aegypti larvae, the experimental insect host. Overall development of metacercariae, and excystment of infective metacercariae in vitro, was temperature dependent. However, there was an initial 8-hour period of obligatory host-parasite contact that was temperature independent. This may represent a period of major nutrient acquisition since young metacercariae were more active metabolically than older metacercariae, as measured by the in vitro uptake of $ sp3$H-glucosamine and $ sp3$H-leucine. Mosquitoes may have mechanisms to reduce losses of larvae to parasites. Oviposition by adult A. aegypti was reduced in waters that had previously contained P. elegans-infected larvae. We propose that this selective oviposition was due to the production of an oviposition deterrent compound produced by parasitized larvae that serves to reduce oviposition in sites detrimental to larval development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rau, Manfred E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67js710.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827d23f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plagiorchiidae</dc:subject><dc:subject>Metacercaria</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aedes aegypti -- Parasites</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35t9979"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Atmosphere-ocean interactions in the mid-latitude North Atlantic and the impact on river runoff over Siberia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Peng, Shiling</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The atmospheric fluctuations associated with sea surface temperature (SST) anomalies in the northern North Atlantic and their subsequent effects on river runoff variations over Siberia are studied in this thesis. A data analysis is performed in Part I of the thesis using 50 years (1930-79) of records of SST sea level pressure, precipitation and runoff. It is found from this analysis that the winter SST anomalies in the northern North Atlantic are significantly correlated with the winter and the following summer runoff fluctuations of the Ob and Yenisey rivers in western Siberia. A modelling study is conducted in Part II of the thesis to investigate the variability of winter atmospheric responses to the SST anomalies in the northwest Atlantic. Experiments are performed with an atmospheric global spectral model using both November and January conditions. The atmospheric responses to the prescribed positive SST anomalies obtained are found to be completely different in the November and January simulations. Over the Atlantic, a positive (negative) geopotential height anomaly center is observed downstream of the warm SST area in the November (January) case. A comprehensive diagnostic analysis of the heat advection in the experiments is carried out to obtain a deeper understanding of the physical maintenance of the two responses.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mysak, L. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d576t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35t9979</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr171z786"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Children's coping with marital disruption : a family systems perspective</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pagani, Linda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Adaptive processes were comparatively examined in elementary school children experiencing the postdivorce process and their peers from intact homes using a developmental conceptualization of coping with a family systems perspective. Children's psycho-social coping resources were assessed using the Self Perception Profile for Children, Coping Inventory, Children's Beliefs About Parental Divorce Scale, and Family Environment Scale. Children's global and specific coping efforts were measured using the Child Behavior Checklist and the Schoolagers' Coping Strategies Inventory, respectively. Parental coping efforts were examined using the Ways of Coping Questionnaire. Children from disrupted families were found to have diminished psycho-social coping resources (self-efficacy, self-esteem, coping styles, and social support). Between group differences were found in children's global coping efforts with the frequency and effectiveness of specific coping efforts being influenced by the time since marital disruption. Relationships between children's coping resources and efforts were also observed. In disrupted family systems, parental coping efforts characterized by escape-avoidant and social support seeking behaviors were found to be associated with children's global coping efforts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Derevensky, Jeffrey L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df06n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171z786</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Children of divorced parents</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000164r"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Keyword classification trees for speech understanding systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kuhn, Roland</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Speech understanding systems try to extract meaning from one or several word sequences hypotheses generated by a speech recognizer. Designers of these systems rely increasingly on robust matchers to perform this task; a robust matcher processes semantically important word islands rather than attempting to parse the entire word sequence. This thesis describes a robust matcher for speech understanding whose rules are learned automatically from training data. Learning is carried out by a new set of algorithms involving a new data structure, the Keyword Classification Tree (KCT). By eliminating the need to handcode and debug a large number of rules, this approach facilitates rapid construction of a speech understanding system. Furthermore, the rules learned by a KCT, which depend on a very small number of words in each utterance, are highly resistant to errors by the speaker or by the speech recognizer. The thesis discusses a speech understanding system built at the Centre de Recherche Informatique de Montreal that incorporates this robust matcher, using the DARPA-sponsored Air Travel Information System (ATIS) task as training corpus and testbed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mori, Renato De</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sx382.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000164r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g436t"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The electrical stimulation of sacral nerves and its effect on neurogenic bladder</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Jin-sheng</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Electric neurostimulation of the sacral roots have been demonstrated to be of benefit in the treatment of some patients with established neurogenic bladder. The present study addresses the feasibility of neurostimulation in order to control the bladder evacuation immediately following a suprasacral spinal cord lesion in the dog (spinal shock phase). In the first part of the study, 20 male dogs underwent supraspinal cord section and were assigned to different groups accordincg to the method of bladder evacuation namely neurostimulation of the sacral nerve roots and intermittent catheterization. It was found that neurostimulation early in the spinal shock phase has hastened the return of the detrusor activity. When the stimulation was delayed, the urinary bladder could still regain its activity soon after initiation of neurostimulation. The detrusor activity was found to decay gradually after turning off the stimulation and instituting intermittent catheterization. The neurostimulation was found to be effective in ensuring complete emptying of the urinary bladder provided that a selective sacral rhizotomy was performed in order to denervate the striated urethral sphincter. The return of the detrusor activity was shown to be associated with an increase in the acetylcholine tissue content in the detrusor musculature. The long term neurostimulation reduced significantly the urinary complications caused by intermittent catheterization and protected the renal functions. In the second part of the study, the possibility of using striated muscle fatigue instead of a sacral root rhizotomy was tested on the bladder outlet resistance during neurostimulation to obviate the need of sphincteric denervation. The pudendal nerve was stimulated at high frequency (100-500 Hz) till fatigue was achieved using the following parameters: 3 V, 100 $ mu$sec for 15-20 sec. The combined pressure-flow studies showed that fatiguing the sphincter was as effective as denervating the sphincter in reducing the bladder outlet resistance. The principle of sphincteric fatiguing was applied in long term animals and proved to be effective in achieving voiding without the need for denervation. In order to attain such a goal, a specially designed neurostimulator with 4 output channels was built with the collaboration of the Department of Electrical Engineering at the University of Sherbrooke. Such a neurostimulator was found to be more effective in achieving bladder evacuation when compared to the commercially available neurostimulators. The present work shows that neurostimulation of the urinary bladder is feasible early after spinal cord injury. This new technique utilizing the principle of sphincteric fatigue in order to reduce the bladder outlet resistance during neurostimulation of the detrusor, seems quite promising for future clinical application in human.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elhilali, M. M.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hassouna, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139357q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g436t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021g74v"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An electrophysiological investigation of monosialoganglioside in the mammalian central nervous system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Miu, Peter</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis focuses on the functional role of monosialoganglioside (GM1) in neuronal activity and synaptic transmission of rat hippocampal slices. The slices were placed in an interface recording chamber and constantly superfused with oxygenated saline at 33$ sp circ$. Both extracellular and intracellular (current- and voltage-clamp) recording techniques were used to measure the field potentials and postsynaptic responses respectively. Our findings indicated that GM1 induces a small inward current in CA1 pyramidal neurons, depresses their high voltage activated (HVA) Ca$ sp{2+}$ currents, and selectively facilitates the excitatory synaptic inputs while reducing the inhibitory ones. The most probable mechanism underlying the selective enhancement of excitatory inputs by GM1 is an increase in glutamate release, since the amplitudes and frequency of spontaneous miniature postsynaptic responses, recorded either in the presence or absence of presynaptic cell firing, were cosistently increased. When L-glutamate was applied iontophoretically in the dendritic region, GM1 transiently potentiated the postsynaptic glutamate currents, thus further indicating a GM1-induced enhancement of glutamatergic transmission. In contrast, both spontaneous and evoked inhibitory postsynaptic responses were suppressed by GM1. This effect is dependent on changes in excitatory inputs to inhibitory interneurons because in the presence of tetrodotoxin and/or kynurenic acid, GM1 did not alter the amplitude of the monosynaptic IPSPs or the frequency of spontaneous miniature IPSCs. Both the GM1-induced inward current and the reduction of postsynaptic HVA Ca$ sp{2+}$ currents were antagonised by kynurenic acid, suggesting that these effects might be caused by glutamate receptor activation. By raising intraneuronal Ca$ sp{2+}$ concentration, the potentiated glutamate release would trigger Ca$ sp{2+}$-dependent Ca$ sp{2+}$ inactivation, and thus explain the reduction in HVA Ca$ sp{2+}$ currents. In conclusion, most of the GM1 actions observed in this project can be explained on the basis of a GM1-induced facilitation of excitatory transmission, mediated especially via enhanced glutamate release.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Krnjevic, Kresimir I.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c429n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g74v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bw072"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Emergency communications preparedness in Canada : a study of the command-and-control model and the emergence of alternative approaches</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thomas, Brownlee</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In recognition of the fact that communications commonly are considered to be essential to effective disaster preparedness and response, the present study addresses several related themes concerning the role of communications infrastructures--i.e., equipment facilities on the one hand, and established patterns of interpersonal relationships among government decision-makers and industry representatives on the other--in peacetime emergency communications planning and response processes. Its investigative tasks include the choice to apply the implicit guiding model in North American emergency management, namely, the "command-and-control" theoretical model, to a specific single-country peacetime disaster context: the Canadian case. That choice rests upon a recognition of the methodological difficulties and challenges in dealing with an emerging and highly dynamic configuration of multiple institutional players, new technologies and residual government policies respecting the telecommunications sector. The study's findings suggest an appreciation of the complexity and nuanced context within which multiorganizational and especially multijurisdictional peacetime crisis management occurs, sometimes understood as the emergence of other frameworks. This investigation contributes to the disaster literature by providing the first exhaustive study of Canada's national emergency communications structure and capabilities. It therefore can perhaps best be seen as a prologue or preliminary discourse to a broader international comparative effort of addressing questions related to communications preparedness in regard to peacetime disasters.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crowley, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr43t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw072</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Emergency management -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Civil defense -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Emergency communication systems -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zc68b"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Attraction to sexual aggression and physical affection : an initial investigation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Benjamin, Mary Ellen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Research has demonstrated that for a significant minority of men, exposure to sexually violent media results in a series of changes. These men are more likely to be sexually aroused by sexually violent stimuli, and also believe in certain rape myths and admit a greater likelihood to sexual aggression. The construct Attraction to Sexual Aggression, which comprises the affective, cognitive and behavioral responses to sexually aggressive media, has been proposed by Malamuth (1989a, 1989b). The Attraction to Sexual Aggression Scale has been developed as a dependent measure of the construct. A study by Malamuth and Check (1983) proposed that lack of pleasurable physically affectionate experiences with women may contribute to sexual aggression. This proposal reflects the theory put forward by Prescott (1977), who hypothesized that lack of physical affection at critical stages of development results in a greater propensity towards aggressive behavior. The current study is an initial investigation into attraction to sexual aggression and physical affection experiences.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maroun, Theodore J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j33b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc68b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aggressiveness</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sexual excitement</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xg447"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cellular mechanisms in the induction and regulation of experimental allergic encephalomyelitis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zeine, Rana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Experimental Allergic Encephalomyelitis (EAE) is an autoimmune demyelinating disease of the central nervous system (CNS) with pathological and clinical features, including patterns of remission and relapse, reminiscent of the human disease Multiple Sclerosis (MS). EAE can be induced by immunization with myelin proteins in genetically susceptible rodents and can be adoptively transferred with CD4$ sp+$ T cells. In this thesis the mechanisms governing EAE induction in SJL/J mice were examined by flow cytometric analysis of the migration into the CNS of CD4$ sp+$ T cells labelled with a lipophilic fluorescent dye (PKH2). Selective retention was demonstrated within the CNS of myelin basic protein (MBP)-reactive CD4$ sp+$ T cell blasts, which were of a CD44$ sp{ rm high},$ CD45RB$ sp{ rm low},$ memory/effector phenotype and which expressed mRNA for IL-2 and IFN-$ gamma$ but not for IL-4. Mechanisms of immunoregulation were examined during remission and in mice preimmunized with irradiated T cells (T-cell-vaccination). A loss of CD4$ sp+$ T cells from the CNS was observed in animals that had remitted, but neither reversion of memory/effector phenotype nor increased numbers of regulatory CNS CD8$ sp+$ cells were observed. In vaccination experiments, evidence was obtained for rescue of background activation levels and enhanced proliferative responses to antigens within lymph nodes of vaccinated animals. The effector and regulatory mechanisms described in this thesis may further facilitate the development of effective T-cell-vaccination protocols for the control of cell-mediated autoimmune disease.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Owens, Trevor</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591988q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xg447</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar781wh57x"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of machine-ground interaction in surface mines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hadjigeorgiou, John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ground preparation design encompasses problems of ground characterization, equipment selection and performance. Ground characterization has in the past been the subject of empirical diggability classification schemes based on case studies. A new system is proposed for evaluating the ease of excavation of different ground conditions, is put forward. This has been applied successfully in different field studies. While such empirical schemes are useful to mining design, there still remains a basic lack of understanding of machine-ground interaction in the excavation process. This will be essential for long term machine and method advancement. This thesis reviews the approach and methodology adopted for the development of predictive digging models in mining. Past theoretical attempts to model soil-rock cutting processes are critically evaluated and an analytical digging model applicable to fragmented rock is proposed. Physical modelling studies, concentrating on the interaction between machine and spoil characteristics, are reported. These considered in particular the digging profile propagated by cable shovel operation, the impact of geotechnical parameters on the profile, and the efficiency of digging in fragmented rock. These were undertaken in a controlled laboratory environment based upon an instrumented scale model and photographic studies. The salient parameters influencing the efficiency of the digging processes are identified and a bucket filling model for cable shovels is proposed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Scoble, M. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nz727.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh57x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geotechnology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adr26xz967"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hierarchal vector finite elements for 3D electromagnetic resonance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liu, Paul Tak Shing</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The analysis of electromagnetic resonance is important in the design of many microwave and optical devices. The finite element method has been applied successfully to this type of problem. To avoid the occurrence of spurious, non-physical modes in the computed spectrum, a special brick element has been developed--the covariant projection element. The brick is curvilinear, allowing a good fit to curved boundaries, but of low order: it uses a mixture of first and second order polynomials. In this thesis, a set of higher order elements is described. The elements are curvilinear quadrilaterals and bricks. Within an element, each component of the vector field is interpolated by a polynomial order m in the direction of the component and order n in the orthogonal directions. Elements for which m is less than n seem to be spectrally correct. The most useful elements are those in the set (m,n) = (1,2),(2,3),(3,4),$ ...$ Since this set is hierarchal, different orders may be mixed within the same mesh. A number of 2D and 3D geometries are used to test the new elements: rectangular, circular and double ridge waveguides; cubic and cylindrical cavities; and a microstrip resonator. In all cases, spurious modes are absent from the computed spectrum, and the higher order elements provide greater accuracy, as expected.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webb, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fj67b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26xz967</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vd08c"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An evaluation of a self-instructional marital enrichment training programme</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lane, Terry</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study is an evaluation of a self-instructional version of the Couples Communication Programme (CCP) in terms of its effect on marital and parent-child communication. Twelve families completed self report measures of marital and family life (the Marital Communication Inventory and the Family Environment Survey). As well an audio tape of a family discussion was rated by observers using the Sequential Analysis of Verbal Interaction. The mothers and fathers in each family then completed the self-instructional CCP over a one month period, following which the same measures were repeated. Fourteen additional families served as a wait-list control group, completing the same measurements with CCP training. Analysis of variance indicated no differences between the groups for the selected variables. These results suggest that self-instructional methods for couples communication may have limited usefulness. It is possible that this type of training could be improved by designing programmes which take into consideration gender differences in attitudes and learning styles.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hum, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b5919890.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd08c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communication in marriage</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqb98mh183"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Strategic groups and technological change : a comparative analysis of the primary textile and steel industries</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sabourin, Vincent</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>How does technological change alter the position and the configuration of groups of producers in an industry? This dissertation examines the transformations in the strategic groups of two manufacturing industries that introduced radically new manufacturing processes. The primary textile market during the period 1958 to 1978 with the introduction of synthetic fibers, introduced a large-scale process production. In the steel industry during the period 1965 to 1985, small-scale process production was introduced with the technology of mini-mills. The impact of new manufacturing processes on the economic position of producers in the industry has been examined conventionally by the research in strategic management, which used with the set of business strategies developed by the positioning school (i.e., cost leadership, differentiation and focus). Where the cost structure is the determinant of the profitability of a manufacturer, strategic groups are expected to establish their position in terms of scale and scope (Porter 1980, Aaker, 1984, Day, 1990). Our findings lead us to introduce a different view of the topic by focusing on competition between strategic groups having different centers of gravity. A center of gravity has been defined by Galbraith (1983) as the primary location of a producer in the economic chain of transformation. We found that large-scale and small-scale manufacturing processes have radically different impacts since these processes are intimately associated with specific centers of gravity. Large-scale manufacturing processes create conditions for the formation of generalists with a strong center of gravity at the upstream primary manufacturing stage engaged in processes such as casting, cutting and forming. This strategic group of generalists establishes a dominant position in the industry in two stages: a cost leadership strategy followed by integrative strategies such as upstream and downstream vertical integration and ultimately, product diversification. Since manufacturers serve the same geographical market, we have a configuration of competing strategic groups. Small-scale manufacturing processes create conditions for the formation of mid-size producers that we have called semi-generalists and semi-specialists. These strategic groups have a strong center of gravity at the downstream manufacturing stage and are engaged in processes such as as assembling and finishing. They have smaller scale facilities, are not vertically integrated, and sell a narrower product range than generalists. Since they are located closer to industrial centers and dedicated to specific industries, they compete on factors other than price, such as geographic location, product differentiation, service, etc. These strategic groups of medium-size producers challenge the dominance of generalists by restructuring the market into a set of regional markets. The configuration of strategic groups is shaped by generic groups of manufacturers competing in different geographical markets. The set of business strategies proposed by the positioning school was adequate for large-scale processes. However, this set of strategies was largely inappropriate in a context where small-scale processes are introduced.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mintzberg, Henry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f36n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mh183</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Textile industry -- Technological innovations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Strategic planning</dc:subject><dc:subject>Steel industry and trade -- Technological innovations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pp47x"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structurefunction analysis of the rat prolactin receptor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rozakis-Adcock, Maria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to investigate the structure/function relationships of the prolactin (PRL) receptor family, two complementary approaches were employed: that of site-specific mutagenesis and chimeric receptor constructs with the homologous growth hormone (GH) receptor. We initiated our studies by first attempting to define structural features in the extracellular domain that were involved in ligand-receptor interactions. Binding studies of transiently expressed rat PRL receptor mutants established that the first four cysteine residues conserved among all members of the cytokine/GH/PRL receptor superfamily are crucial for ligand binding and contribute to the structural integrity of the receptor protein. Moreover, charged residues within the first disulfide-linked loop as well as a set of lactogen-specific sequences between the two pairs of cysteines were shown to be key determinants of PRL binding specificity. Conversely, the second disulfide loop did not appear to participate in ligand-binding interactions with either oPRL or hGH. A phenylalanine residue highly conserved among all members of the GH/PRL receptor subfamily and lying adjacent to the fourth cysteine was also shown to be indispensable for the binding activity in both somatogenic and lactogenic receptors and is thus postulated to confer the loss-of-function phenotype observed in certain patients with Laron-type dwarfism in which the phenylalanine residue in the GH receptor has been substituted to a serine. Finally, the WSXWS motif, another hallmark of the cytokine/GH/PRL class of receptors which lies proximal to the transmembrane domain, was shown to be necessary for high affinity binding of the PRL receptor to oPRL and hGH, perhaps by providing a contact site for the formation of a dimeric high affinity complex. Structure/function analysis of the cytoplasmic domain demonstrated that it not only influences hormone binding but also regulates the cellular distribution of the PRL receptor. A putative internalizat</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kelly, P. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z058.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp47x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2b88qd71r"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Morphology of block ionomers : a study by SAXS and SANS</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gouin, Jean-Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The solid state morphology of block copolymers containing short ionic terminal sequence(s) was investigated using small-angle X-ray and neutron scattering (SAXS and SANS) as a function of architecture (AB, ABA), chemical composition of the ionic block(s) (vinylpyridinium, cesium methacrylate), length of the ionic and nonionic (polystyrene) blocks, extent of neutralization, and method of preparation (compression molding, solvent casting). The ionic phase-separated microdomains were found to be spherical. The radius of those spheres depends only on the length of the ionic block and not on any other of the parameters studied. The only exceptions were the molded ABA vinylpyridinium materials which were thought not to be in their equilibrium morphology due to the method of preparation. The ionic blocks seem highly extended in their microdomains. This is explained by the fact that the system is producing the biggest possible spheres in order to minimize the total interfacial energy. It was also found that the AB architecture and the preparation by solvent casting favor ordering of the microdomains. The conformation of the polystyrene midblock in ABA vinylpyridinium materials in the solid phase was studied by SANS. The dimensions of this segment were clearly found to be identical to a homopolymer of the same molecular weight, indicating that no stretching occurs due to the presence of the two attached ionic blocks.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eisenberg, Adi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr443.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qd71r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, General</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xt268"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Formulation of Colletotrichum coccodes as a bioherbicide</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saad, Fadia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Colletotrichum coccodes (Wallr.) Hughes, a foliar pathogen of velvetleaf, is being developed as a bioherbicide. Formulation of living organisms for use as pest control products presents unique problems. This research has achieved the development of an adequate formulation of the pathogen by using kaolin clay or talcum powder (1:2.79 wt/wt) as the fillers to dry conidia. Formulated C. coccodes conidia stored at 4, 30C, or at room temperature in bags permeable to oxygen remained viable and able to infect velvetleaf plants at least six months in storage. Various reported germination stimulants increased germination of formulated conidia, although not significantly, whereas increasing concentrations of cutin resulted in subsequent decreases in germination and appressoria formation of fresh as well as formulated conidia. In controlled environment experiments, 14 day-old velvetleaf seedlings were severely diseased when stearic or oleic acids were added to conidia formulated in kaolin clay or talcum powder, respectively. Combinations of germination stimulants, cutinase and/or pectinase inducers did not significantly increase germination and appressoria formation of C. coccodes conidia. Germination of fresh and formulated conidia increased, although not significantly, with the addition of 1% sucrose.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Watson, A. K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x49z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt268</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Phytopathogenic fungi</dc:subject><dc:subject>Weeds -- Biological control</dc:subject><dc:subject>Colletotrichum coccodes</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354g839"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Post-punching response of flat plate slab-column connections</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Redl, Erin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La réponse après-poinçonnement  d’assemblages dalle-poteau de béton armé a été étudiée. Cette thèse constitue de deux parties dont la première discute les recherches précédentes sur l’effet des membranes en traction en plus de l’utilisation d’armature d’intégrité structurale de façon à éviter l’effondrement progressif après avoir subit un poinçonnement en cisaillement d’assemblage dalle-poteau. La deuxième partie décrit la conception d’un système formant d’une dalle plate qui sera la base des modèles d’assemblage dalle-poteau de cette recherche. Deux modèles ont été construits et testés à déterminer la résistance de poinçonnement en cisaillement et la résistance après-poinçonnement pour étudier le paramètre d’armature d’intégrité structurale.Les résultats expérimentaux obtenus ont contribués aux connaissances du mécanisme de résistance après-poinçonnement et trois modes de rupture ont été observés : le fluage de l’acier, la rupture du béton similaire aux brisures des ancrages, et l’échec du lien de retirement. Les résultats ont été comparés aux prédictions de la résistance d’armature intégrité structurale du CSA A23.3-04 (2004) et les modèles conçus ont obtenus 98% et 104% de la résistance prévue. De plus, ses résultats ont été utilisés pour évaluer l’équation proposée par Melo et Regan (1998) pour la rupture du béton similaire aux brisures des ancrages et cette équation a été déterminée à sous-estimer la résistance après-poinçonnement des assemblages dalle-poteau.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The post-punching failure response of reinforced concrete flat plate slab-column connections is investigated. The first part of this thesis discusses previous research on the tensile membrane action of reinforced concrete slabs and the use of structural integrity reinforcement to prevent progressive collapse after punching failure of slab-column connections. The second part of this thesis describes the design of a flat plate slab system that is the basis for slab-column connection test specimens. Two specimens were constructed and tested to determine punching failure resistance and post-punching failure resistance. The parameter investigated was the detailing of structural integrity reinforcement. Observations from testing contributed to the understanding of the post-punching resisting mechanism that developed. Three failure modes observed during testing were the yielding of reinforcing steel, concrete failure similar to the breakout of embedments, and pullout bond failure. The test results were compared to the predicted resistance of structural integrity reinforcement by CSA A23.3-04 (2004). The test specimens achieved 98% and 104% of the predicted resistance. Test results were also used to evaluate the equation proposed by Melo and Regan (1998) for concrete failure similar to the breakout of embedments, and the equation was found to underestimate the post-punching resistance of flat plate slab-column connections.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denis Mitchell</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763852k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354g839</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g6598"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Influence of detailing on response of dapped end beams</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Peng, Ting</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Influence of Detailing on Response of Dapped End Beams Abstract This research investigated the behaviour of disturbed regions in dapped end beams. In this experimental research programme, two dapped end beams with similar geometry were designed and tested. Each had a span of 3 m, but each of the four different dapped ends utilized a different reinforcing detail. The main parameters studied in this research were the anchorage of the hanger reinforcement and the flexural reinforcement. The dapped ends were detailed in accordance with the provisions of the 2004 CSA Standard A23.3, as well as the 1971 and 1999 PCI Design Handbooks. Strut-and-tie models were used for the design and strength predictions.  The results from the experimental programme are compared with strut-and-tie model predictions. It was concluded that: (1) proper anchorage is essential; (2) the anchorage and the details of hanger steel and longitudinal reinforcement have a great influence on shear capacity and ductility; (3) design using strut-and-tie models for dapped end beams provides a conservative approach; and (4) the early versions of the 1971 and 1999 PCI Design Handbooks gave poor design and detailing requirements.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Influence de la modélisation sur le comportement de poutres à extrémités emboutiesRésuméCette étude a porté sur le comportement de poutres à extrémités embouties sous contrainte. Dans le cadre de ce programme de recherche expérimentale, deux poutres à extrémités embouties ayant une géométrie similaire ont été conçues et mises à l’essai. Chaque poutre avait une portée de trois mètres, mais l’armature de chacune des quatre extrémités embouties était différente. Les principaux paramètres étudiés dans le cadre de cette recherche étaient l’ancrage principal l’armature de suspente et l’armature de flexion. Les extrémités embouties ont été modélisées conformément aux dispositions de la norme ACNOR A23.3 2004 ainsi que des manuels de conception du PCI. Le modèle de contrefiches et de tirants a servi aux prédictions de conception et de résistance.Les résultats du programme expérimental sont comparés aux prédictions du modèle de contrefiches et de tirants. Il est conclu que : 1. un ancrage adéquat est essentiel; 2. l’ancrage et les détails de l’acier de suspension et l’armature longitudinale ont une grande influence sur la résistance au cisaillement et la ductilité; 3. la conception utilisant des modèles de contrefiches et de tirants pour des poutres à extrémités embouties représente une approche conservatrice; et 4. les exigences en matière de conception et de modélisation enchâssées dans les versions antérieures (1971 et 1999) des manuels de conception du PCI étaient peu contraignantes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denis Mitchell</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj16n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g6598</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zj279"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Preventing progressive collapse of flat plate structures with an irregular layout of structural integrity reinforcement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Egberts, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To investigate the post-punching shear resisting mechanism of slab-column connections having an irregular layout of structural integrity steel, two test specimens were designed, constructed and tested.  The aim of the research program is to determine the appropriateness of the CSA A23.3-04 code provision which assume that the post-punching shear resistance is a function of the total area of bottom steel.  The first of two test specimens experienced significant tilting which may have reduced the post-punching resistance of the slab-column connection, however, the second test specimen was able to resist the expected post-punching load as required by the CSA code. The slabs were designed with 150% of the required structural integrity steel, a ratio of three to one for area of structural integrity steel provided in each span direction, detailing the minimum slab thickness required for the span length between columns, and provisions for high design live loads.   These factors likely reduce the post-punching resistance of slab-column connections, however, the details specified using the code were adequate.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Pour investiguer le mécanisme de résistance des raccordements dalle-poteau avec une disposition irrégulière d’armature pour l’intégrité structurale, deux spécimens ont été conçus, construits et puis testés. Le but du programme de recherche est de déterminer si les provisions inclues dans le code CSA A23.3-04 présentement sont appropriées. Celles-ci supposent que la résistance post-poinçonnement est déterminée en fonction de l’aire totale de l’armature placé dans le bas de la dalle. Le premier spécimen a subi un penchement significatif ce qui aurais pu réduire sa résistance. En revanche, le deuxième spécimen a réussi à résister la charge prévue par l’obligation indiquée dans le code CSA. Les dalles ont été conçues avec 150% de l’armature requise pour intégrité structurale, incluaient un rapport de trois a un pour l’aire d’acier pour l’intégrité structurale dans chaque direction, étaient détaillées avec l’épaisseur de dalle la plus petite pour la portée entre les colonnes et les provisions de conception pour les charges vives les plus élevées ont été utilisées. Tous ces éléments réduisent probablement la résistance des connections dalle-poteau. Cependant, le deuxième specimen était quand même capable d’atteindre la résistance de post-poinçonnement prévue.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denis Mitchell</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vj32p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj279</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n2040718"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Towards greater gender equality? An examination of gender equity policy in the European Union's labour market</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marry, Beatrice</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the late 1970s, the EU has attempted to alleviate gendered labour market inequality throughout its member states with the help of a set of gender equitable policies. While some progress was achieved, both the gender wage gap and the glass ceiling remain firmly in place. Subsequently, women throughout the EU are severely underpaid and under-represented in positions of leadership and power, suggesting that the problem is far from being solved. Why does such blatant gender inequality persist in spite of policies meant to alleviate it? Policies are only as effective as the degree to which they are implemented. This thesis will suggest that the implementation of equity policy is impeded due to a process that renders EU equitable policy less effective than it could be otherwise. Consequently, the policy process needs strengthening and policies need wider utilization by multiple stakeholders, as well as domestic employers to yield greater results.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Depuis la fin des années 1970, l'UE s'est efforcée de réduire les inégalités entre les hommes et les femmes dans le marché du travail des pays membres en établissant des politiques de traitement équitable entre les sexes. Bien qu'on ait fait certains progrès, la disparité salariale entre les sexes et le plafond de verre sont encore fermement en place. En conséquence, les femmes de l'UE sont remarquablement sous-payées et sous-représentées dans les postes de leadership et de pouvoir, ce qui semble démontrer que le problème est loin d'être résolu. Pourquoi une inégalité aussi criante persiste-t-elle malgré les politiques visant à redresser la situation? Les politiques ne sont efficaces que dans la mesure où elles sont mises en œuvre. Cette thèse suggère que la mise en œuvre de la politique d’équité de l’UE est entravée par un processus qui nuit à son efficacité. Par conséquent, si l’on veut atteindre les objectifs visés, il faut renforcer le processus de mise en œuvre de la politique et voir à ce que cette dernière soit plus généralement appliquée par les nombreuses parties intéressées et les employeurs des pays membres.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mark R. Brawley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz14b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n2040718</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science - International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603r005z"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aspect impact analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Dehua</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the major challenges in aspect-oriented programming is that aspects may have unintended impacts on a base program.   Thus, it is important to develop techniques and tools that can both summarize the impacts and provide information about the causes of the impacts.   This thesis presents impact analyses for AspectJ.  Our approach detects different ways advice and inter-type declarations interact and interfere with the base program and focuses on four kinds of impacts, \emph{state impacts} which cause changes of state in the base program, \emph{computation impacts} which cause changes in functionality by adding, removing or replacing computations of the base program, \emph{shadowing impacts} which cause changes of field reference in the base program, and \emph{lookup impacts} which cause changes of method lookup in the base program.  We provide a classification scheme for these kinds of impacts and then develop a set of static analyses to estimate these impacts.   A key feature of our approach is the use of points-to analysis to provide more accurate estimates.  Further, our analysis results allow us to trace back to find the causes of the impacts.  We have implemented our techniques in the AspectBench compiler.  By  implementing them in an AspectJ compiler, all kinds of pointcuts, advice and  inter-type declarations can be analyzed.   We also have integrated these  analyses into an AspectJ IDE and provided a two-way navigation between  impacts and program source code.   In addition, we have carried out experiments  on example programs and benchmarks to investigate the results of our analyses.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'un des principaux d\'efis de la programmation orient\'ee aspect est queles aspects peuvent avoir des effets non voulus sur le programme debase.  Il est donc important de d\'evelopper des techniques et des outilsqui peuvent mesurer les impacts et fournir des informations sur ce genrede ph\'enom\`ene.  Cette th\`ese pr\'esente des analyses d'impact pour AspectJ.Notre approche examines les diff\'erentes voies par lesquelles les aspectspeuvent interagir avec le programme de base et se concentre sur quatretypes d'impacts, \emph{les impacts d'\'etat} qui provoquent deschangements d'\'etat dans le programme de base, \emph{les impacts decalcul} qui provoquent des changements au niveau des fonctions parl'ajout, la suppression ou le remplacement de calculs le programme debase, \emph{les impacts d'ombres} qui provoquent des changements dedomaine r\'ef\'erences dans le programme de base et \emph{les impacts der\'ef\'erence} qui provoquent des changements au niveau des m\'ethodesr\'ef\'erenc\'ees.Nous offrons un syst\'eme de classification pour ces types d'impacts etd\'eveloppons une s\'erie d'analyses statiques pour \'evaluer ces impacts.  Un\'el\'ement cl\'e de notre approche est l'utilisation d'analyses de pointeursafin de fournir des estimations plus pr\'ecises.  En outre, nos r\'esultatsd'analyse nous permettent de remonter plus loin et de trouver les causesde ces impacts.Nous avons mis en place nos techniques dans le compilateur AspectBenchpour AspectJ.  En les appliquant dans un compilateur AspectJ, plusieurssortes de d\'eclarations peuvent \^etre analys\'ees.  Nous avons \'egalementint\'egr\'e ces des analyses dans un environnement de d\'eveloppement AspectJet avons fourni une navigation bidirectionnelle entre les impacts et lecode source.  En outre, nous avons proc\'ed\'e \`a des exp\'eriences sur desprogrammes de test pour d\'emontrer les r\'esultats d'analyses typiques.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Laurie Hendren</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd32k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r005z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>