<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q581n"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the characteristics and behaviour of composite backfill material</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Annor, A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The history of mine backfill shows that in the past, considerable improvements in backfill-reliant mining technology were made when new fill systems were introduced. The present trend in mine backfill technology is towards the use of high-density fill systems. Tight filling and void reduction have also become essential requirements in engineering design of mines to ensure global stability. High-density fills have a low moisture content and are more competent products requiring less binder and time for stabilization, compared to conventional hydraulic backfill. Cemented rockfill and tailings/sand paste fills are two familiar high-density backfill systems in current use. In future there could be a high demand for low porosity high-density fills, as mines go deeper and ground stresses increase. This study was an original attempt to investigate the characteristics and property of high-density composite fill systems. Composite fills are made up of derivatives of waste rock, tailings, sand and metallurgical by-products. Composite fills represent the future direction of backfill technology. As mines go deeper, the ore could be processed underground and the waste rock and tailings combined together to form a low-porosity competent fill product. The application of composite fill systems will also increase the material available for backfilling, provide more flexibility in backfill mix design and produce competent fill systems for ground support. It will also benefit the underground mine environment through effective utilization of mine wastes. The fundamental basis of the work required the study and understanding of the characteristics and properties of cemented rockfill and paste backfill. The effects of sand addition to fine tailings as a means of reducing porosity and improving the mechanical properties of the fill product were also investigated. Additionally, a new concept of backfill, namely, Composite-Aggregate Paste (CAP) that consists of a mixture of fine tailings and graded coarse aggregates was introduced and the material properties were investigated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hassani, F. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sb987.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q581n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053h79b"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Systematics of Niteobrachis, a new genus in the tribe Brachistini (Hymenoptera:Braconidae:Helconinae)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aranguren, Antonio M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Niteobrachis, a new genus in the tribe Brachistini (Hymenoptera: Braconidae: Helconinae), is described. The genus is endemic to the New World and contains 24 species, all of which are newly described: amazonicus, attonitus, candeo, carmenae, clarus, delicatus, elegans, fulgeo, gracilis, gustus, ictus, insignis (type species), luceo, lucidus, luisi, lumen, luminosus, luna, mico, nitidus, serenus, splendidus, subtilis and venustus. Keys to the species of Niteobrachis and to the genera of Brachistini are given. Niteobrachis is diagnosed by a combination of characters in the metasoma, including the absence of striations and/or sculpturing on the second and third median tergites with a glossy/smooth appearance; a shallow suture between the second and third median tergites; presence of a crease that separates the second median tergite from the second laterotergite; absence of a crease that separates the third median tergite from the third laterotergite; fused second and third laterotergites; the lateral longitudinal carinae of the first median tergite reaching the articulation between the first and second median tergites; and the first three median tergites covering most of the remainder of the metasoma. The monophyly of Niteobrachis is supported by two synapomorphies: a minute median longitudinal carina of the propodeum, and the lateral longitudinal carinae of the first median tergite reaching the articulation between the first and second median tergites. Recognition of this genus resulted from a phylogenetic analysis of six tribes of Helconinae, including most genera of Brachistini based on a data matrix of 49 characters and 18 terminal taxa. The phylogenetic affinities of the genus are examined, a sister group relationship with Foersteria Szepligeti is hypothesized, and the problematic placement of the subgenera of Eubazus Nees is considered.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wheeler, Terry A.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Lewis, David J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r07j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h79b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Braconidae -- Classification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Braconidae -- Identification</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bj90c"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Etude de l'ajustement hydrostatique suite à un forçage diabatique dans un modèle pleinement élastique</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thurre, Christian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this research is to further our understanding of the hydrostatic adjustment process due to diabatic heating. This is achieved by the use of an atmospheric model based on Euler's non-hydrostatic, fully elastic set of equations resolved by the semi-Lagrangian, semi-implicit marching scheme. Such a model thus allows a tri-dimensional, numerical approach of a problem which could, until now, only be addressed within a simplified context (one-dimensional and analytical; bi-dimensional and numerical). The hydrostatic adjustment is the mechanism by which the atmosphere tends to reach a new hydrostatic balance when this one has been upset. This can be the case through a diabatic forcing, such as the sudden latent heat release during the formation of a thunderstorm cell. This is actually the kind of forcing we chose for this study. The problem of the hydrostatic adjustment is tackled through two different contexts: an idealized and a real case. Both are simulated by three different model's versions: fully compressible (PE), quasi-hydrostatic (QH) and quasi-anelastic (QA). These versions differ from each other only by the formulation of the diabatic heating terms. The idealized case makes use of a prescribed heating source. A high resolution, in time and space, allows to show (PE version) how the mass, pressure and energy redistribution process is accomplished by the elastic, Lamb and gravity disturbances. The QH version, which consists in a spreading of the heating over the whole column above the source, inhibits vertically propagating elastic perturbations. The QA version, which considers the omission of the diabatic term in the pressure prognostic equation, shows that only the gravity mode is maintained. The real case simulates a highly convective summer situation. The choice of a long time step brings out only the gravity mode; the hydrostatic adjustment by the fast modes (elastic and Lamb) is taking place quasi instantaneously. Thus this large-scale case doesn't exhibit significant differences between the PE, QH and QA versions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Laprise, Rene</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m350s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bj90c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw6634556x"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of sequential context on the perception of brief tones</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Weaver, Lisa L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Eight experiments were performed to investigate factors affecting the discrimination of two characteristics of very brief tones. The subjects (adults with normal hearing) were asked to rate targets that differed either by amplitude envelope or by a change in frequency. For the majority of the trials, a target was followed (after a brief silent interval) by a pure tone referred to as a "mask". Two factors affecting discrimination within this simple paradigm were examined in detail; the frequency separation and the duration of the silent interval between the target and the mask. For most of the other conditions, a target and mask were embedded in a series of sounds that were presented with an isochronous rhythm. Several features of these "background" sounds were varied across the experiments, including their timbre, presentation rate and frequency relationships with the target and mask. Superior discrimination was obtained when targets were able to perceptually "emerge" from a background of tones or noises. Specifically, performance was strongest when a target was easily segregated from the other sounds in the series by timing factors or through having a unique frequency. Discrimination was also enhanced when the interfering effects of the mask were removed through association with other tones in the sequence. The data suggest that a simple "interruption" model of processing, in which the presence of a mask disrupts subjects' ability to process individual characteristics of a target, does not adequately explain the differences in discrimination observed across the conditions. A more comprehensive explanation could consider attentional factors that may influence subjects' ability to accurately identify which tone in a sequence is to be rated. However, a perspective based on auditory segregation seems to most consistently explain the data; individual characteristics of a target were most easily discriminated when the target was perceived as belonging outside of an auditory group formed by the background sounds. This was especially true when the mask was likely to have been perceived as belonging within the group due to frequency proximity and/or rhythmic regularity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bregman, Albert S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k681j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634556x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Auditory perception</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abg257g73t"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A functional analysis of the IDDM2 susceptibility locus in type 1 diabetes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vafiadis, Petros</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Type 1 diabetes is an autoimmune disease characterized by destruction of the insulin-producing pancreatic beta-cells. Genetic predisposition, encoded by a number of loci, plays a large role in the probability of disease development. The IDDM2 susceptibility locus maps to the insulin gene (INS) variable number of tandem repeats (VNTR) minisatellite, which has two main clusters of alleles. As a whole, alleles of the class III cluster reduce the probability of developing type 1 diabetes and those of the class I cluster predispose to type 1 diabetes. To determine the functional basis of this susceptibility and protection, we tested the hypothesis that the IDDM2 effect is mediated through INS VNTR effects on transcription levels of the nearby INS and insulin-like growth factor 2 (IGF2) genes, in tissues known to be of importance in the pathogenesis of the disease. We have found evidence to suggest that protective INS VNTR alleles are associated with different levels of INS expression in the thymus than predisposing alleles, and that these levels correlate with the level of protection conferred by the INS VNTR alleles in population studies. Thus, alleles associated with high expression are protective, while alleles associated with no expression are very predisposing. This suggests that IDDM2-encoded susceptibility is mediated, at least in part, through variable expression of thymic INS which may in turn affect the efficiency of central immune tolerance induction to INS-encoded antigenic epitopes and the probability of an autoimmune response against the beta-cells. Furthermore, we did not detect any significant difference in IGF2 mRNA levels associated with the protective INS VNTR class of alleles as compared to the predisposing class in thymus, pancreas and leukocytes. This argues against IGF2 as a target gene through which INS VNTR alleles mediate susceptibility to type 1 diabetes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Polychronakos, Constantin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qb582.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257g73t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25xb251"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of atmospheric turbulence using the wavelet transform</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Turner, Barry John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, methods based on the wavelet transform are used to extend spectral methods for studying turbulent mixing. These methods are then applied to momentum and heat flux for fast response measurements taken above and within a deciduous forest at Camp Borden, Ontario. Multiscale distributions of flux event intensities are derived, presented and interpreted. Results show intensification of mixing efficiency near the canopy top, dominated by turbulent structures near a dominant scale, as reported in previous studies. There is no indication of a distinct, clearly separable population of intense 'coherent structures', as is often assumed, but rather an overall increase in intermittency near a particular scale. The multiscale flux event distributions are simplified to provide component cospectra for down-gradient and counter-gradient fluxes. Dimensional arguments are used to explain observed scaling, and differences between upward and downward cospectra of momentum above and within the forest are used to understand the influence of different terms in the Reynolds stress budget. A multiscale parameterization of the Reynolds stress budget is developed using the wavelet results for momentum flux. The physical meaning of the scale-dependent parameters is examined. Empirical values derived from the Camp Borden observations show considerable consistency. Changes in parameter values within the canopy are consistent with the effect of neglected Reynolds stress budget terms which are known to become significant within the forest.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Warn, Tom</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn22s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb251</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25xb269"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Morphometry of the cortex in partial epilepsy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Jong Woo, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the changes in cerebral morphology studied with magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) in two common forms of partial epilepsy, temporal lobe epilepsy (TLE) and frontal lobe epilepsy (FLE). In addition, the contribution of structural abnormalities to the observed distribution of fluorodeoxyglucose (FDG) in positron emission tomography (PET) was examined in patients with TLE. In the first study, a quantitative morphological examination of the lateral temporal lobe in patients with mesial TLE is described. A significant reduction of white matter volume ipsilateral to the seizure focus and bilateral gray matter volume reduction were observed. In addition, abnormalities of the structure of the gray matter/CSF interface were found by surface curvature analysis. The results of the first study raised the possibility that the apparently reduced uptake of FDG observed in interictal PET studies in TLE may in part be due to partial volume effects (PVE). The second study examines the contribution of volume loss and PVE to the asymmetry in the uptake of FDG seen in interictal PET. The results indicated that PVE contributes significantly to the observed asymmetry but does not explain it entirely. This suggests that additional metabolic or physiological factors are responsible for the observed abnormalities. On the basis of the changes in white matter volume ipsilateral to the seizure focus, a loss of temporal lobe projection fibers resulting in local changes in the morphology of the corpus callosum at a site corresponding to the location of temporal crossover fibers was predicted. A method of detecting localized changes in the midsagittal corpus callosum was devised. Focal thinning in the corpus callosum was observed in patients with TLE compared to normal controls, supporting the biological significance of temporal lobe white matter changes in patients with TLE. The location of temporal lobe crossover fibers in the anterior to midbody of the corpus callosum was demonstrated. Progressive regional thinning of the anterior corpus callosum was demonstrated after temporal lobe resection in the same location as the thinning seen in TLE. In the final study, the quantitative techniques developed in the previous morphometric studies of the cortex in TLE were applied to patients with FLE with normal MR images. White matter volume asymmetries corresponding to the clinical and electrographic lateralization of the site of seizure onset were observed in patients with normal MRI scans on visual inspection. These findings indicate that in patients with FLE, subtle structural lesions may be present despite a normal appearance on visual inspection of MR images. In addition to their vital clinical role, neuroimaging techniques such as MRI and PET, are valuable research tools in the study of epilepsy. They yield a diverse range of biological information; in the studies describe, they have provided insight into aspects of the morphology of the normal brain and the structural changes of partial epilepsy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reutens, David C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qb59b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb269</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn9998418"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effectiveness and utilization of b-blocker therapy for secondary prevention of ischemic cardiac events and death among elderly survivors of myocardial infarction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Levy, Adrian R., 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Numerous placebo-controlled randomized clinical trials have shown that long-term secondary prophylaxis with beta-blockers can reduce the risk of death following myocardial infarction (MI). Despite consensus guidelines advocating their use, studies from many countries have shown that beta-blockers are underutilized among MI survivors, with advancing age and increasing comorbidity being associated with lower utilization. This thesis includes three studies relating to key issues regarding the effectiveness and utilization of beta-blocker after hospital discharge among elderly survivors of MI in Quebec between 1990 and 1993. The first study presents information on the validity on the diagnosis of MI and other medical conditions recorded on the Quebec hospital discharge database. An analysis of 234 medical charts of MI survivors over the age of 65 years from six Montreal hospitals revealed that, if a diagnosis of MI was made by the discharging physician, the diagnosis was reliably transmitted to the discharge database. However, comorbid medical conditions were undercoded. If comorbidity is of specific interest, hospital discharge data are probably not adequate for the purpose. If these conditions are being considered as confounding variables, undercoding does not alter the interpretation regarding the risk of rehospitalization after discharge. In the second study, the effectiveness of beta-blockers in reducing rehospitalization for ischemic cardiac events and all-cause mortality in the year after MI was estimated in a cohort of 14,547 elderly Quebecers. Due to concerns about residual confounding between users and non-users of beta-blockers, the main analysis included only subjects dispensed a beta-blocker and compared the risks during periods of use with the risks during periods of non-use using time-dependent exposures. It was found that use of beta-blockers was associated with reductions in rehospitalization and death greater than those observed in most randomized c These studies offer further confirmation of the effectiveness of beta-blockers for secondary prevention in MI, underline the low rates of utilization in Quebec between 1990 and 1993, and identify groups of physicians which could be targeted by an educational program designed to increase the utilization of beta-blockers among MI survivors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tamblyn, Robyn</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z711x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9998418</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gerontology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hh262"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Computer simulation of oxide texture and microstructure formation and their effects on oxidation kinetics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Hualong, 1967-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Computer models of oxide texture and microstructure development and oxidation kinetics have been developed. The first computer model enables the evaluation of the effects of various factors on oxide texture and microstructure development. The second computer model enables the evaluation of the effects of oxide texture and microstructure on oxidation kinetics. Two examples of Ni single crystal and polycrystalline, Zr-2.5%Nb are used to illustrate the proposed computer models. Simplified oxidation mechanisms on Ni and Zr have been proposed. In the first system, the simulation of oxide texture and oxidation kinetics on the {100} and {111} oriented single crystal Nickel substrate is analyzed. At the nucleation stage the oxide grain orientation is determined by lattice matching between the oxide and the metal substrate. At the stage of oxide grain growth, oxide surface free energy plays an important role. The simulated oxide textures are in good agreement with experimental results. The observed difference in the oxidation kinetics of the two samples is explained by difference in oxide textures formed on the two single crystal substrates. The high percentage of Sigma3 twin boundaries found in the oxide formed on the {111} substrate indicates that the presence of these boundaries significantly improves oxidation resistance. In the second system where oxidation on Zr-2.5%Nb is simulated and analyzed, lattice matching between the oxide and the metal substrate is used to determine the oxide orientation at the nucleation stage. At the stage of oxide grain growth, oxide orientation is determined by minimizing the compressive stress that is parallel to the metal/oxide interface. Four samples with different substrate orientations have been used in study. The simulated oxide textures and microstructures are in good agreement with experimental results. During the simulation of oxidation kinetics, it is found that oxygen transport through Zr oxide film takes place mainly through two diffusion paths. The first diffusion path is through oxide grain boundaries formed in the bulk alpha-Zr grain region and the second one is through oxide grain boundaries formed at the alpha-Zr grain boundaries and beta-Zr grain region.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Szpunar, J. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w1498.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh262</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Physical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A79407z920"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Data analysis through auditory display : applications in heart rate variability</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ballora, Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis draws from music technology to create novel sonifications of heart rate information that may be of clinical utility to physicians. Current visually-based methods of analysis involve filtering the data, so that by definition some aspects are illuminated at the expense of others, which are decimated. However, earlier research has demonstrated the suitability of the auditory system for following multiple streams of information. With this in mind, sonification may offer a means to display a potentially unlimited number of signal processing operations simultaneously, allowing correlations among various analytical techniques to be observed. This study proposes a flexible listening environment in which a cardiologist or researcher may adjust the rate of playback and relative levels of several parallel sonifications that represent different processing operations. Each sonification "track" is meant to remain perceptually segregated so that the listener may create an optimal audio mix. A distinction is made between parameters that are suited for illustrating information and parameters that carry less perceptual weight, which are employed as stream separators. The proposed sonification model is assessed with a perception test in which participants are asked to identify four different cardiological conditions by auditory and visual displays. The results show a higher degree of accuracy in the identification of obstructive sleep apnea by the auditory displays than by visual displays. The sonification model is then fine-tuned to reflect unambiguously the oscillatory characteristics of sleep apnea that may not be evident from a visual representation. Since the identification of sleep apnea through the heart rate is a current priority in cardiology, it is thus feasible that sonification could become a valuable component in apnea diagnosis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pennycook, Bruce</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Glass, Leon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s651r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407z920</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sound -- Recording and reproducing -- Digital techniques</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sleep apnea syndromes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heart rate monitoring</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s416b"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The structure and expression of a human Ly-6-related gene homologous to mouse TSA-1</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shan, Xiaochuan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mouse Ly-6 antigens belong to a family of structurally related GPI-anchored cell surface proteins encoded by tightly-linked, but independently regulated genes on chromosome 15. Functional data so far suggest roles in intercellular communication and trafficking of cells during hematopoiesis and immune responses. High sequence divergence between species has hampered homology cloning of human Ly-6 genes. The major part of this thesis reports the characterization of the first of two human Ly-6 homologues which have been discovered recently. Also reported is work on the generation of recombinant forms of Ly-6 proteins for use in Ly-6 ligand studies and in raising antibodies to the novel human Ly-6-related proteins. cDNA clone 9804, provided by collaborators at CytoMed (Cambridge Mass.), encoded a human Ly-6 sequence most like mouse TSA-1. It was used as a probe to isolate genomic fragments containing 9804 exons. Further cloning and characterization of overlapping fragments revealed that the 9804 gene consists of 4 exons, arranged like other Ly-6 genes, and spanning approximately 5 kb. Screening of human-hamster hybrid cell DNA by PCR associated the 9804 gene with chromosome 8. Fluorescence in situ hybridization, performed by collaborator D. Well, refined the mapping to 8q24.3, a region showing synteny with mouse chromosome 15 in the region containing Ly-6 genes. Northern blot analyses demonstrated a broad tissue distribution of 9804 expression, similar to that of TSA-1. While present in many different human tumor cell lines, 9804 mRNA was not detected in the B cell lines Raji and Daudi. 9804 mRNA levels were inducible in vitro by IFN-alpha and ATRA. The response to ATRA was restricted to myeloid leukemia cell lines and was a late event (36--48 hrs), whereas IFN-alpha produced a stronger and more rapid (8--12 hrs) enhancement in normal PBMC and a broad range of cell lines. The induction required protein synthesis, and was apparently at the level of transcription. Solub</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Palfree, G. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b785r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s416b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tn67j"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of soil organic matter on the fate of trichloroethylene in soil</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sheremata, Tamara W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Trichloroethylene (TCE) contamination of soil and groundwater is extensive in Canada and the U.S. Under saturated soil conditions, TCE partitions with the organic fraction of soil and under anaerobic conditions is subject to biodegradation to dichloroethylene (DCE) isomers and vinyl chloride (VC). However, biodegradation is slow, and TCE often persists with accumulation of the DCE isomers and VC. The objective of the present study was to determine the effect of soil organic matter (SOM) on the fate of TCE in a saturated soil environment under anaerobic conditions. In natural soil, the presence of inorganic minerals as well as indigenous microorganisms greatly complicates the study of the concurrent processes of sorption and anaerobic biodegradation. To overcome such difficulties, a surrogate soil organic matter (SSOM) was used in conjunction with the pure strain Desulfomonile tiedjei to determine the effects of sorption and desorption on the anaerobic biodegradation of TCE. Composted sphagnum moss, sterilized so as to eliminate indigenous microbial activity, was implemented as a SSOM since it is representative of natural SOM. Desulfomonile tiedjei was utilized as a model of anaerobic consortia that exist in soil since it is a well studied microorganism. Results of the present study indicate that as the initial contact time ( i.e. aging) between the TCE and SSOM increases, TCE becomes increasingly resistant to biodegradation. The extent of biodegradation declined by 75% when the SSOM was aged with TCE for 30 d. This decline was attributed to TCE partitioning with SSOM and possibly due to complexation with dissolved organic matter (DOM). Results of this study indicate that soils contaminated with TCE for prolonged time periods may be less amenable to bioremediation efforts. Resistance of TCE to biodegradation was not paralleled by resistance to desorption for the 30 d aging that was studied. Results of longer term biodegradation tests (i.e. incubation times of up t</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yong, R. N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b505n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tn67j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Environmental Sciences</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biogeochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d56zz29z"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The acquisition of natural language negation : a logical resources approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sharpe, Dean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The logic of natural language negation (e.g. no) is prima facie at odds with an exclusively CLASSICAL LOGIC based on SET THEORY. The negation of classical logic obeys the LAW OF NON-CONTRADICTION (according to which an element cannot be both in and not in a set) and the LAW OF EXCLUDED MIDDLE (according to which an element either is or is not in a set). In contrast, natural language negation tolerates APPARENT CONTRADICTIONS (as in, Do you like your supper?---Yes and no) and UNEXCLUDED MIDDLES (as in, Do you love your supper?--- No; Do you hate your supper?---No). These prima facie non-classical phenomena relate to non-set theoretic INTERPRETIVE STRUCTURES, particularly OBJECT STRUCTURE, i.e. that objects may possess properties in part but not in whole (e.g. one might love one part of a supper but hate another), and PREDICATE DIMENSIONALITY , i.e. that properties may have mid-range values (e.g. one might evaluate the supper as a whole as an average between the two extremes). I describe several experiments exploring adults' and children's grasp of object structure and predicate dimensionality and their relation to natural language negation, using two different reasoning tasks: the ability to resolve apparent contradictions and the ability to draw inferences about unexcluded middles. Results suggest that even the negation of children as young as age three is not exclusively classical and set theoretic, but rather reflects a principled grasp of object structure and predicate dimensionality. I argue that children's grasp of natural language negation is guided by sophisticated LOGICAL RESOURCES that relate to the NATURAL LOGIC of common objects and their properties, particularly object structure and predicate dimensionality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Genesee, Fred</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w6532.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz29z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Negatives</dc:subject><dc:subject>Negation (Logic)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language acquisition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dx149"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Religious pluralism and the theory of deep diversity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sinacore-Guinn, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>American Supreme Court jurisprudence in the area of religious freedom is, for the most part, predicated upon a form of liberal democratic theory commonly known as "procedural liberalism." A close analysis of this jurisprudence reveals that because of this theoretical basis, the Supreme Court has been unable to craft a consistent jurisprudence that adequately addresses the reality of religion as a pluralistic social institution. Based upon the detailed critiques of procedural liberalism by such thinkers as Charles Taylor and Iris Marion Young, and drawing upon a concept known as "deep diversity" suggested by Taylor, a new general political theory, identified as the theory of deep diversity, is developed to answer these critiques. This theory is then used to reconceptualize Supreme Court jurisprudence and to demonstrate how the theory can be applied in a practical way to resolve the many problems inherent in existing religious freedom jurisprudence so as to support and advance religious pluralism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Letsacqz, Karen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tw863.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx149</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>United States. Supreme Court</dc:subject><dc:subject>Group identity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Religion and politics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multiculturalism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Religion and politics -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Freedom of religion -- United States</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085n040"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Academic writing instruction in disciplines other than English : a sociocultural perspective</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gentil, Guillaume</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This classroom-based interpretive inquiry investigates how two academic writing instructors with disciplinary backgrounds in English Literature and English Education teach writing to graduate students with other disciplinary backgrounds. The instructors' teaching practices are conceptualized within a Vygotskian socio-cultural framework. Relevant educational issues are situated within two fields of education, Second Language Education and L1 writing instruction. This inquiry challenges the polarized views of writing instruction reflected in the second language literature. The research participants were two writing instructors and two focal students in one class. Data collected and analyzed include 70 hours of classroom-based observations in two classes over a semester, 12 hours of interviews with the research participants over 16 months, and documents such as course handouts, the focal students' portfolios, teacher audio-taped and written feedback to student drafts. Findings indicate that the writing instructors provided writing instruction and writing opportunities both in the specific disciplinary discourses of their students and other discourses. The instructors' goal-directed teaching practices were informed by their own generalist and discipline-sensitive evaluative orientations toward academic writing instruction at postsecondary levels. The instructors' evolving individual beliefs, perceptions, and practices were shown to be related to embedding sets of nested institutional contexts, such as developments in composition and education theory, and the changing theoretical orientations of the instructors' teaching units. Despite the instructors' different emphases on discipline-specific and general features of writing, findings suggest that both instructors mediated the students' appropriation of disciplinary discourses.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maguire, Mary</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343t857.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085n040</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Foreign speakers</dc:subject><dc:subject>English language -- Composition and exercises -- Study and teaching</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A736666294"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The assessment of adolescent life stress : the comparison of a newly developed interview-based measure to a self-report checklist</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kenny, Alisa A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present research compared a newly developed interview measure of adolescent life stress, the Life Events and Difficulties Schedule (Brown &amp; Harris, 1978), to a self-report checklist The Adolescent Perceived Events Scale (Compas, Davis, Forsythe, &amp; Wagner, 1997). Participants consisted of a community-based sample, of 58 adolescents in grades 9--11. The life strew interview and checklist were compared on a number of factors, namely accuracy and comprehensiveness of obtained stressor data and accuracy of stressor dating. Moreover, the relative performance of the two measures in predicting current depressive symptomatology was assessed. Results revealed differences in the stress profiles obtained by the two measures. Respondents reported stressors in a redundant manner on the checklist and reported a number of stressors on the checklist that did not qualify as stressors according to interview criteria. The checklist was found to lack in comprehensiveness, as many stressors elicited during the interview had no counterpart on the checklist. Respondents were unable to precisely date stressors on the self-report checklist. Results indicated that stressor data obtained by the interview was more associated and more, predictive of current levels of depressive symptomatology than stressor data obtained by the checklist. The implications of these results in reference to life stress assessment and research in the area of adolescent life stress and depression is discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Smith, Tim</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182m95g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736666294</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Stress in adolescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stress (Psychology) -- Testing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515q07p"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sex differences in responses to status differentials</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Waite, Angela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Past research has provided conflicting results concerning sex differences in the desire for status. The current study was designed to examine more explicitly sex differences in the desire to attain status. Eighty girls and 80 boys from kindergarten and grade four were placed in groups of four same-sex friends and were observed during a session in which they had to choose a leader, as well as during a drawing task. The children were also interviewed following the tasks using a questionnaire format. Results showed that there were no sex differences in the number of volunteers to be leader, in the length of time to negotiate who would be the leader, in the degree of positive affect expressed while choosing a leader, or in the degree of involvement in the negotiation of who would be the leader. Results suggest that based on this one study in which status was defined as leadership, no sex differences exist in the desire to attain status, although leadership styles may vary. Results are discussed in terms of the implications of the desire for status for the personality development of females and males.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Benenson, Joyce</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tr03c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q07p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social status</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sex differences (Psychology) in children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xn38k"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Blood lactate response and performance in a simulated ice hockey task in male varsity and recreational players</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Buffone, Michael A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose was to compare the blood lactate response and performance of varsity hockey players to recreational players, and to provide a shift by shift analysis of blood lactate accumulation in a simulated ice hockey task. Ten university, varsity players and ten recreational players performed a continuous aerobic treadmill test (VO2max), a 45 s Wingate test, and four trials of the Repeat Sprint Skate (RSS) test. Each RSS test consisted of four repetitions of a 91.4 m skate with repetitions initiated on 30 s intervals. To simulate game, competition, 5 min of recovery separated each RSS test. Results indicated: (1) performance of the varsity players was superior (p &lt; 0.01) to that of the recreational players in the RSS test; (2) four shifts of the RSS test elicited similar peak blood lactate concentrations for the varsity and recreational groups; (3) change in blood lactate following 15 min of passive recovery was similar in the two groups, and (4) there was a significant relationship (&amp;prop; = 0.05) between performance indices in the RSS test and corresponding variables measured in the 45 s Wingate test.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Montgomery, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z7126.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xn38k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Blood lactate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Skating -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hockey -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3j333409r"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of an alternative instrumental music program on elementary school children</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Walsh, Brenda, 1956-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Music education is an important element in the development of the whole child. The school is a place where children learn about and are directly influenced by things that make a lasting impression on their development. What better place for music to be taught? Music is a course of study that can have a direct influence on a child's lifetime tastes and values for the arts. This study investigates the effects of an Alternative Instrumental Music Program on grade three children, at an elementary school situated on the West Island of Montreal, Quebec. One of the two classes involved in the Study (Experimental Group) participated in an alternative instrumental music program and its applications; the other class (Control Group) followed a traditional music program. Each class consisted of twenty-eight students. Quantitative and qualitative data were collected from both groups of students, homeroom teachers, and parents over a period of ten consecutive weeks. The findings revealed that the children in the Experimental Group enjoyed learning music in school more than those in the Control Group. The Experimental Group also indicated a greater increase in the enjoyment of activities experienced during music class than those in the Control Group. Moreover, there was a higher increase of musical knowledge in the Experimental Group. The author suggests that further research on the effects of alternative music programs on elementary school children would be beneficial to the educational community.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Amoriggi, Helen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f525w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333409r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>School music -- Instruction and study</dc:subject><dc:subject>School music -- Instruction and study -- Québec (Province) -- Case studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75df310"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Social class and differences in parental expectation and involvement in education : a study of two schools in urban Shanghai, China</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhao, Yu Ming</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Drawing from cultural and social reproduction theory, this research studied the relationship between social class and parental involvement in education in modern China. The study paid particular attention to parents' educational background, professional occupation and socio-economic status, and how these factors contribute to their expectation and involvement in education. The research was an attempt to explore the importance of cultural and social capital in Chinese families, which has a decisive impact on children's educational experience. It also examined how class status were maintained and perpetuated from one generation to the next through parents' role in schooling, and through China's dual track school system. A key school and a non-key school in Shanghai were chosen for the study. Forty eight families, including children and parents, participated in this research. Data collection was completed through interviews and observations. Interview protocols were prepared and used for parents and students respectively. The findings of the research indicate that parental expectation is closely related with parents' educational level, while parental involvement in education is determined by more than one factor, and parent's socio-economic status is the most important.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lin, Jing</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p2022.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df310</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education -- Parent participation -- China -- Shanghai</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social classes -- China -- Shanghai</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5712m838q"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cognitive pain coping strategies of rowers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sedgwick, Whitney A. (Whitney Ann)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigated rowers' cognitive pain coping strategies during a 2,000 metre ergometer race. The concepts of association and dissociation were expanded upon by devising five thought categories: performance dissociation (PerfD), pain association (PaA), pain dissociation (PaD), psychological performance association (PsyA), and technical performance association (TechA). Sixteen rowers, five males and eleven females, between the ages of 19 and 27 years, rowed at maximum intensity for four race segments of 500 m, 1,000 m, and 2,000 m on separate occasions. A forty-one item Thoughts During Rowing Questionnaire was administered upon completion of each distance. Subjects' average thought category scores were analyzed by a 4 x 5 (Distance x Thought category) MANOVA. Results indicated significant (p $&lt;$.005) effects for distance and thought category, and an interaction. Results suggest that while racing, rowers rarely dissociate from their performances. As pain awareness rises, rowers dissociate from pain and associate with the psychological or technical aspects of their performances.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Neil, Graham</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns632.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m838q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rowing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sports -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pain -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301302q"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Topographic mapping of the brain activity of perceived motion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zanni, Caroline A. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study compared electrical brain activity of subjects in five different conditions: eyes-closed at rest, eyes-open at rest, looking at a flashing object, looking at apparent movement, and looking at real movement. Absolute theta and alpha power in the frontal and occipital areas were analyzed. Significant differences were found in the frontal area. Results suggest that perceived movement requires higher order cognitive processes outside the occipital area. Implications for education and cognitive research are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cartwright, Glenn F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967535m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301302q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Brain mapping</dc:subject><dc:subject>Motion perception (Vision)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67js931"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The neural basis of human auditory rhythm perception and production</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Penhune, Virginia B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Music depends on the perception and production of complex temporal patterns, or rhythms, as a vital part of its power to communicate. These experiments investigated the neuroanatomical substrate of rhythm perception and production in patients with focal cerebral lesions, and in neuroimaging studies with normals. The hypotheses focused on the role of the primary and secondary auditory cortex, as well as the cerebellum and other motor-related areas. Experiment I. To estimate the extent of removals in the region of auditory cortex in neurosurgical patients, a 3D probabilistic map of Heschl's gyrus (HG) was developed from magnetic resonance imaging (NW scans of normals. The map was coregistered with patent MRIs, revealing that most removals involved only anterior secondary auditory cortical regions, with relatively little encroachment onto primary auditory cortex. Additionally, this experiment compared the volumes of HG between hemispheres and found a consistent L &gt; R asymmetry in the volume of cortical white matter, which could contribute directly to the preferential left-hemisphere processing of speech. Experiment II. Using a paradigm contrasting reproduction of auditory and visual rhythms, four groups of patients were tested: those with right or left anterior temporal-lobe removals (RT-a, LT-a) and those with similar removals which also included HG (RT-A, LT-A). RT-A patients were impaired on auditory but not visual rhythms, particularly when accurate reproduction of stimulus durations was required. In contrast, LT-a, RT-a and LT-a patients were not impaired. These results demonstrated a role for the right anterior secondary auditory cortical regions in the retention of auditory temporal information. Experiment III. The rhythm reproduction paradigm was adapted for a positron emission tomography (PET) activation study in normals. These data confirmed the participation of secondary auditory regions in the retention of auditory temporal information. They also demonstrated a supra-modal contribution of the lateral cerebellar cortices, vermis and basal ganglia to the task, pointing to a distributed system of neural structures involved in the production of a timed motor response from external stimuli. The results are discussed in relation to possible interhemispheric differences in auditory temporal processing as well as the role of the cerebellum in motor and perceptual timing.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Petrides, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053h81c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67js931</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rhythm -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Auditory cortex</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75r9507"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The application of RASS in urban boundary layer meteorology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Potvin, Guy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the application of a Radio-Acoustic Sounding System (RASS) at an urban site, and proposes a Rank-Order Signal Processing Algorithm (ROSPA) to overcome the problems associated with that type of application. The main problem is clutter of many kinds contaminating the clear-air profiler measurements. ROSPA uses primarily order statistics, and operates in two main stages. The first stage operates on the clear-air Doppler velocity spectra by using a threshold minimum filter on the successive spectral power values at a given Doppler velocity bin for several spectra at a given altitude. The threshold minimum filter is a variant of the minimum filter. The second stage operates on the time-height mean Doppler clear-air velocity data by imposing a median filter. It is shown using theoretical models that the minimum and median filters possess the properties required to eliminate intermittent clutter, namely their insensitivity with respect to outliers. A profiler/RASS at an urban site, another at a rural site, and an airplane flying over mainly rural terrain, are used to study the urban boundary layer on the clear and convective early afternoon of June 28, 1996. The rural profiler/RASS data are free of clutter and show an initially stable rural boundary layer becoming convective in the middle of the observation period, and attaining a depth of about 1 km at the end of the period. The urban profiler/RASS data are treated with ROSPA to eliminate the severe intermittent clutter contamination and show a convective urban boundary layer over the entire observation period, with a depth increasing from 1.5 to 1.8 km. The heat flux profile of the second half of the rural RASS data agrees well with the airplane profile up to about 0.6 km. The surface heat flux estimated by airplane measurements is 146 +/- 0.77 W/m2, while the urban RASS measurements yield 523 +/- 239 W/m2. This result, along with comparisons of the vertical velocity variance profiles, is consist</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rogers, R. R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db70c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r9507</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hh28m"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hydrogeologic and agroclimatic considerations for the development of a water management model for the Tlacolula subbasin, Oaxaca, Mexico</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Perraton, Etienne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The area investigated in this research is the groundwater basin of the valley of Tlacolula de Matamoros, of the central valleys of Oaxaca in Mexico. The objectives of this research were to consider together the causes and symptoms of the technical problems concerned with effective management of ground-water and related land resources in a semi-arid climate. The preparation of electronic basemaps and their field control is first investigated. A methodology for the preparation of multi-layer base maps is successfully established. The variability of climatic conditions and climatic trends that may affect the quantification of the design rainfall and the elaboration of long term water strategies are then investigated. Historical pumping test data are analyzed. Analytical techniques for the interpretation of single well test data are applied. A trial and adjustment procedure based on the reversibility of the test when the aquifer-well system has stabilized, is proposed for the data analysis of a single well test with declining step drawdown. In order to determine the suitability of water for irrigation and to obtain an early warning of groundwater salinization, the quality of groundwater is assessed over the area. Hydrometric are analyzed for accuracy and potential water availability.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Broughton, Robert S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333410h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh28m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Groundwater -- Mexico -- Oaxaca Valley -- Management</dc:subject><dc:subject>Groundwater -- Mexico -- Oaxaca Valley -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>