<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqz20sv816"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Conflicts of laws in private international air law : the contracts of carriage by air, aviation insurance, aircraft purchase, finance, the creation of security rights in aircraft and a common general part</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kadletz, Andreas, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis deals with the problems of conflicts of laws with respect to contractual private air law, focusing on those contracts which are of a practical importance. As compared to traditional studies of this legal area, this study applies a very innovative approach to the topic. Due to the vast amount of legal instruments, jurisprudence and legal writings to be handled, it does not appear appropriate to deal with the problems without pointing out common approaches, methods and solutions. In accordance with the economic legal working methods which have been developed by Middle European legal systems, and increasingly can also be observed in a number of common law systems, the aspects, which are common to all kinds of international contracts in private air law, are dealt with in a common General Part. Aspects such as the method of interpretation of international conventions, their "interrelations" with the conflicts of laws, and the general approach to "conflicts justice" (Kegel) as opposed to the modern American "Choice of Law Revolution" approaches are discussed. The Specific Part deals with the particulars of each kind of contract; significant aspects such as the effects of the new IATA Inter-Carrier Agreement (signed at Kuala Lumpur, 1995) are examined, as well as the problems which are encountered in international contracts of aviation insurance, cross-border finance of aircraft, and the creation of security rights, which, because of the sheer monetary sums involved, are of enormous practical significance. The conclusion at the end of the thesis provides two rules to resolve the conflicts of laws with respect to all contractual aspects of private international law: one single common rule as to contractual obligations, and another rule as to real rights in aircraft (iura in rem) which require a slightly different approach.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f54b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sv816</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290c51w"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Commercial transactions on the internet</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Joulie, Anne-Hortense</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study explores selected issues in the legal environment created by domestic and international electronic contracting practices on the Internet within the United States and international jurisdictions: questions regarding the formation of the contract through the Internet, the enforceability of such a contract (contractual writing requirements, legally binding signatures), the contents of the contract, the ways to prove the electronic contract, the applicable law and the competent court, and finally, the best ways to settle disputes arising from electronic contracts are considered. We examine to what extent contract law, and in particular article 2 of the Uniform Commercial Code (UCC), provides a satisfactory legal ground for the Internet, and how the various model trading partner agreements or the United Nations Commission on International Trade Law's Draft Model Statutory Provisions (UNCITRAL DMSP) deal with legal contract issues. We attempt to show that contracts in Cyberspace do not require any substantial reform but only some changes and adaptations to existing law, since when the policy considerations that underlie an existing rule still make sense as applied to Cyberspace, a completely new rule is not worth having. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Johnston, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km61w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c51w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ast74cs478"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dispute resolution in international civil aviation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jeremic, Zorica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aviation industry, by its very existence, has a tremendous impact on the global economy. As an integration of economic interests and international prestige, aviation triggers a large number of disputes and disagreements. This dissertation examines the regulatory aspects of international air transport disputes. Chapter one acknowledges the existence and nature of international aviation disputes in its scope and, more importantly, recognizes some of the many causes of conflicts arising from such disputes. The second chapter reviews chronologically dispute resolution attempts and analyses their effectiveness. Further, it examines the international bodies, governing treaties, and the available machinery for the resolution of aviation disputes. The third chapter distinguishes the most influential multilateral and bilateral treaties in the field of aeronautics and presents the solutions for settlement of disputes promoted by ICAO. Chapter four includes the variety of procedures found in international agreements on aviation and the examination of political, legal and economic means as the mechanisms for the settlement of disputes. Chapter five establishes the recent proposals for the improvement of the current procedures governing the settlement of aviation disputes. Hence, it includes an analysis of the legislative measures of the European Union, the regulations of the World Trade Organization and the norms of North American Free Trade Agreement; all in view of their competence in resolving air transport conflicts. The conclusion is a summary of the structure and the function of the existing aeronautical dispute settlement system and its future developments.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j742g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs478</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afq977x00k"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Legislating science and morality : statutory schemes for the regulation of reproductive technology in Australia, Canada and the United Kingdom</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haysom, Georgina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Reproductive and genetic technologies ("RGTs") raise many complex social, legal and ethical issues. Several jurisdictions have perceived a need for government intervention and regulation of the conduct of RGTs, and consequently have enacted legislation to this end. In three states in Australia (Western Australia, Victoria and South Australia) and in the United Kingdom, legislation has been introduced which imposes a regulatory scheme according to which RGTs must be practised in each jurisdiction. Legislation based on the recommendations of the Royal Commission on New Reproductive Technologies is currently before the Canadian parliament. This thesis examines from a comparative perspective the proposed legislation in Canada and legislation enacted in the United Kingdom and the Australian states to govern the conduct of RGTs. Particular emphasis is given to the manner in which the legislation seeks to deal with the rapid pace of scientific development and with moral pluralism. The focus of the thesis is on the effectiveness of the legislation in these jurisdictions in light of the relationships between law and science and law and morality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Healy, Patrick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354h275.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977x00k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, Public Administration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap2676x710"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Legal implications of Pan Am flight 103 disaster</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haney, Caroline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The tragedy of Pan Am Flight 103 explosion over Lockerbie, Scotland shocked the world for we never get used to such atrocities. However, the scope of the tragedy was more than just an aircraft explosion. It shook the very foundations upon which the United Nations system rests. It also served as a catalyst to the reevaluation of the established United Nations legal order. The Security Council as well as the International Court of Justice found themselves thrown in a direct collision course by the exercise of their respective powers. This thesis will analyze the events that lead to such a legal and political impasse and look into the legal issues involved. The first Chapter will retrace the events leading to the determination of the cause of accident as well as the identification of the suspects. Will also be examined the series of steps taken to bring the suspects to justice as well as obtain Libya's cooperation. We will finally look into the legal principles applicable to the situation such as those contained in the United Nations Charter, the Montreal Convention as well as those included in general international law. The second Chapter will be devoted to the legal study of the United Nations Charter, specifically the provisions concerning the Security Council's and the International Court of Justice's powers as well as the general obligations the Charter imposes on them. Finally, the last Chapter will focus on the complex issue of relationship between the Security Council and the International Court of Justice.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c525.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676x710</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nd07t"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The practical utility of international law in the negotiation and implementation of aboriginal self-government agreements</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gillon, Kirstin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of this thesis is to evaluate the practical utility of international norms to indigenous peoples. In recent decades, indigenous peoples have looked increasingly to international fora to secure what they see as their rights. It becomes important, then, to evaluate the potential utility of these efforts. Two conclusions dominate my assessment of the role of international law. Firstly, the lack of enforceability of the norms means that international law is unlikely to achieve change in the face of state resistance. Secondly, the vagueness of the norms, coupled with the complexity of self-government regimes, severely limit the principles' ability in achieving specific change. Instead, the utility of international law is seen to lie in changing attitudes amongst the general public and governments, by establishing common standards of treatment to which all indigenous peoples are entitled, creating new channels of communication and broadening the context of indigenous disputes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webber, Jeremy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w1722.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nd07t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cc84b"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La privatisation des entreprises en Fédération de Russie</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Froment-Meurice, Isabelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The privatization of an economy which has been socialized during seven decades may have seemed unachievable, particularly concerning such a great industrial power as former Soviet Russia. Nevertheless the work performed under Presidents Gorbatchev and Eltsine, who were prompted by a reformist political will, has led to the privatization of the great majority of enterprises. Since 1992, it has made necessary the build-up of a new governmental and administrative structure and of an impressive legislative and regulatory framework. Though the methods of privatization were often similar to those used in the West, Russia has distinguished itself by setting up a system of "mass privatization" through the distribution of vouchers to the entire population. After the launching of two Programs in 1992 and 1994, the privatization of small enterprises was largely completed. As far as middle and large enterprises are concerned, the transfer of ownership has mostly benefited employees, or not too transparent investors and banks, but rarely foreigners. Since 1995 the process of privatization has come under criticism and has slowed down. Future developments will depend upon the unfolding of politics in Russia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Janda, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq13j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc84b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, Public Administration</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9306t121f"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A critique of the powers and duties of the assembly of the International Civil Aviation Organization (ICAO)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fossungu, Peter Ateh-Afac</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is indeed strange that the Assembly of the International Civil Aviation Organization (ICAO), composed of all the present 183 member States, should have no powers in connection with the principal functions of the Organization (that is, the formulation of Standards and Recommended Practices); nor any over the appointment and creation of the Organization's principal officers and sub-organs. Stranger still is the fact that even the little and insignificant powers that this Assembly might possess can be easily and constitutionally/conventionally "usurped", or interfered with, by the limited 33-member Council of the Organization. Much more puzzling is the fact that this limited membership Council, which is normally supposed to be answerable to the Assembly, runs the Organization's entire business exclusively as it sees fit: Without the remaining 150 States having any means whatsoever of checking it. The result of this strange arrangement has been that the majority of States simply cannot contribute to the advancement of the international aviation cause as they might have: had the universal organ had the voice and say that it now lacks. The entire constitutional and political set-up of ICAO can hardly be justified in both the Schools of Democracy and of its corollary, the Supremacy of the Assemblies of international organizations. A serious and meaningful re-evaluation of the ICAO framework and working methods to remedy the anomaly is therefore called for in the present study.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s679f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t121f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adr26z0390"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Securities regulation in Canada : status, issues and prospects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Doyle, Kathleen M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Canada's fragmented, provincially-based securities regulatory system is facing domestic and international pressures to become more coherent and efficient. This paper outlines various factors and proposals, concluding that the system must become nationally-based, but only if the change is properly planned, implemented and administered. There should be uniform (or, at least, coordinated) legislation, with federal and provincial joint delegation to a single commission. Interprovincial coordination must improve before, during and after the change. While feasibility requires most provinces to participate, the scheme should not be rejected if unanimity is lacking. Although important, regional autonomy cannot be allowed to outweigh national authority. Market participants will be somewhat reassured if presented with a realistic transitional plan and definite time-table. A national system should proceed only if the federal and provincial governments can plan and implement it with common sense and without damaging compromises.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Johnston, D. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w95052344.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z0390</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canadian Studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economics, Finance</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s435j"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Foreign direct investment in Mexico and the 1994 crisis : a legal perspective</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Del Toro, Guillermo Emiliano</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the 1994 economic crisis, Mexico's inclusion in the globalization era has been questioned. To discover if Mexico is moving in the right direction, this study has as its objective the examination of the different regulations that, in Mexico, are related to Foreign Direct Investment. These regulations include the 1993 Foreign Investment Law ("Ley de Inversion Extranjera"); the Competition Act ("Ley Federal de Competencia Economica"); and the North American Free Trade Agreement. The aim of this study is to find out if these regulations are capable of attracting Foreign Direct Investment, which is the most convenient foreign capital flow needed, in order to assist Mexico in its search for economic growth. The importance of the rule of law as an effective instrument to attract FDI is also an element considered in this study. Finally, this thesis, after the above examination, concludes that Mexico has the potential to overcome its latest economic crisis by using its existing regulations. However, some improvements would benefit its place within the global competition to attract FDI. Most of these improvements are needed at the multilateral level, where Mexico should address the importance that FDI has as a counterbalance to the risks associated with short-term investments. As shown, short-term investments were one of the conditions that provoked the 1994 crisis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>de Mestral, Armand</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg53s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s435j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economics, Finance</dc:subject><dc:subject>History, Latin American</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zq53p"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The challenge of aircraft financing and its legal implications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cohen, Jérôme, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Following a long period of recession which affected the world's economy and a fortiori the aerospace industry the demand for new aircraft is now very high. Purchasing an aircraft is a very complex operation as several parties are involved, not only the final user of the airplane and the manufacturer. Banks or other institutional lenders, trustees, lessors, private investors, etc... may be involved in the elaboration of a purchase contract. This leads to the creation of very complex financial deals. Moreover, the various parties to such a contract often come from different countries and, therefore, are subject to different legal systems. This thesis begins with a review of the various methods of financing available to lenders i.e. the title based financing and the security based financing with an emphasis on the French and American legislations. Next an analysis of the international legislation and the rights in aircraft will be presented, including the UNIDROIT's as yet unenforced proposals. Then there will be an examination of conflicts of laws and conflicts of jurisdictions--conflicts that are particularly complicated in the field of aircraft financing. Lastly, the question of bankruptcy, with an emphasis on the American case, will conclude this paper.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b5318.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq53p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economics, Finance</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arj430665r"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La convention sur le marquage des explosifs plastiques et en feuilles aux fins de détection (Montréal, le 1er mars 1991), ou, Etude d'un des moyens de prévention du sabotage aérien</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bourgoin, Céline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of this thesis is to view the convention on the marking of plastic explosives for the purpose of detection as a preventive means against aerial sabotage. After having identified the terrorist phenomenon (Preliminary chapter), we have to know if the studied convention can fight against these well-organized groups who have already showed their violence with deadly success. A preventive and deterrent action seems to be the best legal way to improve the detection of the explosives these groups use (First chapter). The institution of an international criminal law can be envisaged as a means of intimidation but I.C.A.O. has developped other measures and the convention is one of them. To be effective, this convention and its annex have to have a universal and compulsory application but these are conditions that they don't fulfill. Such negative observation is also to presented with regard to the conventional actors in the fight against sabotage (Chapter II). Indeed the international commission created by the convention still doesn't have the necessary supranational jurisdiction. Thus the sovereign States are keen on keeping their influence on the control of the marking. Obviously these States and other actors like U.N.O. can act in many ways on the international scene to fight against the aerial terrorism but new actors should exist. An international inquiring authority and an international court could reinforce this struggle. Then this thesis has showed the gaps of the studied convention and consequently, the weakness of the detection systems in airports.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jt17d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430665r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445cg39v"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Commercialisation of remote sensing U.S. and International law : towards a liberalization of economic regulations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bourbonnière, Michel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis analyses the International and American laws and regulations structuring the commercialization of space based remote sensing images. Chapter one outlines the historical evolution influencing the present regulatory structure. Chapter two describes the technology of space based remote sensing systems. Chapter three analyses the international treaties and institutions along with their application to commercial remote sensing by satellites. Chapter four analyses the American legislative evolution and regulatory structure pertaining to commercial remote sensing. The argument of the thesis is that a contextual evolution of the global geopolitical climate is forcing a regulatory retooling for commercial space endeavors. The contextual evolution has created new paradigms based upon international economic market values. The initial international treaties and institutions must evolve to reflect these criteria.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Janda, Richard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zj71v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg39v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Remote Sensing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445cg40m"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vers un systeme européen de responsabilité des entreprises en matière de dommage à l'environnement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boiron, Hélène</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objective of this thesis is to contribute to the debate triggered by the Green Paper on Remedying Environmental Damage published by the Commission of the European Communities in March 1993. This Green Paper discussed the relevance and shortcomings of a recourse to the strict liability regime and to a joint compensation fund mechanism as means of remedying environmental damage which take place in the European Union.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brunnee, Jutta</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t45m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg40m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Environmental Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418q129"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Canadian International Trade Tribunal : Canada's emerging trade jurisprudence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alexander, Tamra A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Established in 1988, the Canadian International Trade Tribunal (the "CITT") replaced the Tariff Board, the Canadian Import Tribunal and the Textile and Clothing Board. Tasked with the responsibilities of advising the government on various trade related matters, conducting injury inquiries and reviewing certain decisions of the customs department, the CITT is an important source of Canadian trade policy and jurisprudence. This paper focuses on the role the CITT has played in the development of Canadian trade jurisprudence, with particular emphasis on the CITT's material injury inquiries and its appellate review of Canada Customs' classification and valuation determinations. Placing these decisions against the background of Canada's international trade commitments, the author gives a mixed review of the CITT's performance to date. That said, the author notes that a significant proportion of the CITT's failures in this area is more accurately attributable to the statutory limitations to its jurisdiction due to the incomplete manner in which Parliament has implemented Canada's international trade commitments into domestic law.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>de Mestral, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vj703.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418q129</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canadian Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50gz078"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Consideration with regard to global navigation satellite systems (G.N.S.S.) of the establishment of a legal framework</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Addison, Henry, 1955-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Global Navigation Satellite Systems (GNSS) are a key technology underpinning the International Civil Aviation Organization's (ICAO's) communications, navigation, surveillance/air traffic management concept. The fact the de facto GNSS, the Global Positioning System (GPS) is a military system owned, operated and controlled by the United States raises many legal and institutional issues for civil aviation. This thesis will discuss the nature of GPS/GNSS as a global utility, ICAO's evolutionary path toward a civil GNSS (ie one independent from GPS) and trace the development of the institutional debate within ICAO. Reliance on navigation by GNSS in terms of the principle of State sovereignty over territorial airspace and the Chicago Convention will be considered. The three major institutional issues in respect of a GPS based GNSS (ie charging, non-discriminatory access and liability) will be examined. This thesis will also examine past and present State practice in respect of radionavigation systems of an international character in considering whether a legal framework for GNSS is necessary, and if so what form it is likely to take. The conclusions reached on these issues will be summarised in the final chapter.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz531.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gz078</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128c864"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Myocardial repair with satellite cell implantation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zibaitis, Audrius</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Injured adult mammalian cardiac muscle does not respond with significant regeneration. Skeletal muscle, on the other hand, has an efficient regeneration mechanism attributable to myogenic stem (satellite) cells. This study investigated a hypothesis which states that skeletal muscle satellite cells (SCs), if grafted into an injured heart, can form muscle tissue and repair the damaged myocardium. In the first study SCs obtained from 28 dogs were isolated, purified and cultured. Percoll density gradient and preplating methods for the purification of SC culture were investigated. Beta-galactosidase ($ beta$-Gal) labelled SCs underwent autografting into acutely cryoinjured myocardium. Three control dogs received only sham implants into the cryoinjured heart. Two (n = 6), 4 (n = 16) and 6 (n = 6) weeks after SC implantation, hearts with SC graft sites were procured and processed for histrionical examination, as well as for detection of a $ beta$-Gal marker. Control specimens were obtained at 2 (n = l), 4 (n = l), and 6 (n = l) weeks after sham implantation and were processed as described above. In the second study on rats, SCs were obtained from donor animals (n = 30). An intramuscular bupivicaine method to increase SC yield was adopted. Purified, cultured, and $ beta$-Gal labelled SCs were implanted either into acutely cryoinjured myocardium (n = 15), or into the mature cardiac scar (n = 15) of isogenic donor animals. Myocardial specimens were obtained at 1 month after SC implantation. Techniques of rodent SC labelling in vitro with human alkaline phosphorate genes were also explored. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chiu, Ray C.-J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f551h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128c864</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aff3657187"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sequencing and functional studies on chromosome I of Saccharomyces cerevisiae</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhong, Wuwei</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis reports on some sequencing and functional studies on chromosome I of Saccharomyces cerevisiae. Eight open reading frames (ORFs) have been identified in S. cerevisiae which have similarity to the canine 24kD glycoprotein, gp25L (Wada et al., 1991). In chapter 2 of this thesis, I report the gene disruption and functional characterization of three of these ORFs: YAR002Ac, YAL007c and YGL002w. Disruption of YAR002Ac resulted in calcofluor white resistance, disruption of YGL002w increased sensitivity to this compound, while yal007c$ Delta$ mutants had no calcofluor white phenotype. The expression of Kre9p was partially increased in the ygl002w$ Delta$ mutant. All single, double and triple mutants grew, mated and sporulated normally. The sequence of each S. cerevisiae chromosome, released in GenBank database, lacked most of the telomere sequence. This was due to the fact that a telomeric fragment with one clonable end cannot be integrated into a vector by the classical cloning method. Recently, Louis and Borts cloned all telomeres of S. cerevisiae successfully using an alternative cloning method (Louis and Borts, 1995). In chapter 3 of this thesis, I report the DNA sequence of the right telomeric region of chromosome I. The sequence indicates that this region represents a typical yeast telomeric region and contains 98bp of TG$ sb{1-3}$ repeats and an X subtelomeric element. Another subtelomeric element, the Y$ sp prime$ element, is absent from the right telomeric region of chromosome I. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bessey, Howard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d195g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff3657187</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816p470"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The binding modes of maltose binding protein with different ligands studied by NMR</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Xiaochen, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Maltose Binding Protein (MBP) of Escherichia Coli, a kind of periplasmic protein, can bind its ligands interacting predominantly either with their anomeric end (end-on binding) or with the middle of the maltodextrin chain (middle binding). Using NMR spectroscopy, we have studied the modes by which maltose, linear maltodextrin and some derivatives like $ beta$-cyclodextrin bind to MBP. 1D proton difference spectra and 2D HSQC proton-nitrogen correlation spectra were acquired of MBP in the presence of different ligands. Spectra with linear maltodextrins showed many common features and were distinctly different from those of MBP with $ beta$-cyclodextrin. 2D HSQC spectra suggest further that MBP- $ beta$-cyclodextrin adopts an open form conformation similar to that of ligand free MBP because of the surprisingly similarity of their spectra. Ligands such as $ beta$-cyclodextrin, can not be transported into the cyto-plasm but have high affinity for MBP, multiple $ alpha$(1-4) linkages and no reducing end. These ligands bind to MBP mainly by the middle binding mode. This suggests that this mode determines high affinity binding of ligand to MBP, but doesn't produce a physiologically active complex.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gehring, Kalle</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k7112.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p470</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac247dv10c"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On languages in AC0 that have a neutral letter</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zamora Cura, Carlos Alberto</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A language L is said to have a neutral letter e, if for any word in L, the action of inserting or deleting this letter anywhere in the word does not affect membership in the language. In this thesis we study the set of languages having a neutral letter that can be expressed by a first order expression. The conjecture which we are studying is that this class is equal to the star-free languages which have a neutral letter. We give detailed and complete proofs of the following cases. We prove that it is true if the alphabet has only two letters. We also prove that if the arity of the numerical predicates is restricted to be one, then the conjecture is true. The case when the language is defined by a $ Sigma sb1$ sentence is also proved. The outlines of the last two cases are from (17). We note that for some languages in AC$ sp0$, the action of adding a neutral letter puts them outside of AC$ sp0$.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Therien, Denis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g9378.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dv10c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207tr287"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Computer simulation of reentrant spiral-wave activity in two-dimensional ventricular Myocardium</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xu, Aoxiang, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Acute myocardial ischemia is the main cause of ventricular tachycardia and ventricular fibrillation. Reentrant activity is the most common mechanism of these ventricular arrhythmias, and is often initiated from the border zone between the ischemic and normal tissue. Theoretical studies have suggested that spiral-wave activity may be one form of reentrant arrhythmia. Our study explores the possible relation between spiral-wave activity and ischemia-induced ventricular arrhythmias. We numerically simulate reentrant activity in a two-dimensional sheet of ventricular myocardium which contains an ischemic area. We construct this ischemic area by increasing the extracellular potassium concentration in that area. When pacing the sheet with a sequence of stimuli delivered at a sufficiently high frequency, different types of spiral waves are initiated either within the ischemic area itself or in the normal area close to the ischemic boundary, depending on the potassium concentration in the ischemic area. The formation of the spiral wave is influenced by several factors such as the frequency of stimulation, the geometry of the ischemic area, and the exact level of the extracellular potassium concentration in the ischemic area. Future work should model the ischemic area more realistically with a spatially-extended border zone.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Guerara, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gz08j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tr287</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3j3334343"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Passive microwave snow mapping in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xiao, Renmeng</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objective of this research is to map snow cover in the Quebec area using passive microwave and other remote sensing data. The areal snow extent and snow water equivalent are determined and a twelve year snow water equivalent map is produced for the purpose of analyzing interannual snow variability. The presence of vegetation cover will affect the data obtained with passive systems. For heavily vegetated areas such as Quebec, the vegetation effect should be predetermined and classified to reduce the error on snow water equivalence calculation. In dry snow conditions, forest coverage and snow density are the two major error parameters in passive microwave snow mapping. The error on snow water equivalence estimation is directly proportional to the error in estimated snow density and forest coverage. For Quebec, ignoring the fraction of the forest cover may cause up to 49% snow depth or water equivalence underestimation. The ground measured snow depth and snow density data are necessary for calibrating satellite derived snow depth and mean snow density within forest covered regions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lewis, John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh59m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3334343</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Microwave remote sensing -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Snow -- Québec (Province) -- Measurement -- Remote sensing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Snow surveys -- Québec (Province) -- Remote sensing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149r639"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship between scramble competition and social learning : a novel approach to testing adaptive specialization theory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Whittle, Patrick J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines whether scramble competition is associated with social learning. The question is explored via a comparative study involving two species of grassfinches, Amadina fasciata, and Taenopygia guttata. These finches vary in the degree to which they employ scramble competition while foraging, but are otherwise similar behaviourally and morphologically. General problems associated with the application of the comparative method to the testing of learning specializations are discussed. Functional improvements to previously employed approaches are proposed, and then implemented in a novel methodology and statistical approach to analysing the data, the Manova approach. The results of the study suggest that there is no link between scramble competition and social learning in these two species. When the effects of confounding variables are removed from the interspecific comparison, the species do not appear to differ in their social learning abilities. The results also indirectly suggest that some forms of social learning occur through the mechanisms of general learning.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>LeFebvre, Louis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fz70g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r639</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Competition (Biology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Learning in animals</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grass finches -- Psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grass finches -- Behavior</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bk13g"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A novel model of Quinidine induced torsade de pointes arrhythmias in the isolated rabbit heart</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Weerapura, Manjula</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Accumulating evidence suggest the underlying danger of Class IA and Class III antiarrhythmic agents in inducing potentially lethal torsade de pointes arrhythmias (TdP) if associated with hypokalemia and slow heart rates. The primary aim of the following study was to examine the proarrhythmic activity of the Class IA agent quinidine in isolated perfused rabbit hearts in an effort towards developing a reliable model of TdP. Thirty five rabbit hearts were perfused with therapeutic quinidine concentrations (2.5 or 5$ mu$M) in the presence of hypokalemia (K$ sp+$ - 2.7mM) and stimulated at cycle lengths (CLs) ranging from 0.5s-5.5s. Monophasic action potentials (MAPs) were recorded from left endocardial and right epicardial sites along with an ECG. We suggest that the described model of acquired TdP in isolated rabbit hearts can be adapted for the quantitative and qualitative assessment of the proarrhythmic potential of existing and novel antiarrhythmic agents, to test the efficacy of novel therapeutic strategies for the acquired long QT syndrome and/or to clarify the specific mechanism(s) of drug induced TdP. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sasyniuk, B. I.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10ws33w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bk13g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f3237"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stress protein modulation in HIV-1 infected CD4-expressing cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wainberg, Zev</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Heat shock or stress proteins (HSPs), are a large family of phylogenetically conserved molecules that can be constitutively expressed at high levels under normal physiological conditions. These proteins are selectively synthesized following metabolic and environmental insult. This study was designed to determine whether cognate and/or inducible HSP production are altered in CD4-expressing lymphocytic cell lines concomitant with acute and chronic human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-l) infection. Our findings indicate that in CEM.NKR cells, HSP27 production is selectively altered at early stages of acute HIV-infection (6-24h post-infection), subsequent to virus internalization but prior to synthesis of viral progeny. Levels of HSP27 induction were viral dose-dependent and were not accompanied by any alterations in cellular proliferation. In contrast, acute HIV-infection was not associated with significant quantitative changes in the constitutive expression of HSP60, HSP70, or HSP90. Nevertheless, a transient, marked induction of select HSP70 subspecies was evident at early stages of infection, finally disappearing by 48-72h. Acute-infection of Jurkat cells resulted in similar patterns of de novo induction of HSP27 and HSP70 isoforms. Uninfected and chronically-infected CEM extracts showed little detectable constitutive HSP27. However, synthesis of select HSP27 and HSP70 homologues in chronically-infected cells was observed following exposure to a mild heat shock and doses of TNF$ alpha$. Similar HSP70 homologues arose in chronically-infected cells treated with heat-shock and TNF$ alpha$. These findings indicate that HSP pathways are uniquely modulated in CD4+ cells as a consequence of acute and chronic HIV-1 infection.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brenner, Bluma</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193b93z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f3237</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>