<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asf2689395"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Surveillance of central line-associated bloodstream infections in Quebec intensive care units</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fontela, Patricia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Parmi les infections associées aux soins de santé, les bactériémies associées aux cathéters centraux (BACC) occupent une place prédominante, particulièrement dans les unités de soins intensifs. Toutefois, l'épidémiologie des BACC au niveau canadien est peu connue. Dès lors, le premier objectif de cette thèse était de décrire l'épidémiologie des BACC dans les unités de soins intensifs du Québec en utilisant les données du programme de Surveillance Provinciale des Infections Nosocomiales – Bactériémies Associées aux Cathéters Centraux (SPIN-BACC). Nous démontrons que les BACC sont un problème majeur dans les unités de soins intensifs du Québec. Néanmoins, les taux d'incidence de BACC ont progressivement baissé depuis 2007 et la proportion de Staphylococcus aureus résistants à la méthicilline se maintient &lt;40% depuis 2006 (chapitre 6). Les programmes de surveillance sont essentiels pour générer des étalons externes. Toutefois, au cours des dernières années, plusieurs programmes régionaux et nationaux ont aboli la participation continue comme préalable. Cette décision pourrait avoir compromis la validité de leurs résultats car le nombre minimal de mois lesquels les établissements doivent soumettre des données à ces programmes afin d'obtenir des taux d'incidence régionaux/provinciaux ou nationaux valides est inconnu. Notre deuxième objectif était de déterminer, à l'aide de simulations, l'impact de différents seuils minimum de participation sur la capacité des programmes de surveillance régionaux/provinciaux et nationaux à fournir des estimations valides du vrai taux d'incidence des BACC dans les unités de soins intensifs. Nous démontrons que la réduction des seuils de participation peut être appropriée pour les programmes nationaux si les données sont soumises de façon aléatoire. Toutefois, les programmes régionaux/provinciaux, ainsi que les petits sous-ensembles des unités de soins intensifs, devraient opter pour une participation continue afin d'éviter le risque de générer des étalons externes biaisés (chapitre 7). Par ailleurs, les programmes de surveillance peuvent aussi être utilisés comme outils pour réduire le taux d'incidence des BACC dans les unités de soins intensifs. Toutefois, l'importance de cet effet n'a pas encore été déterminée de façon définitive, car les études antérieures ont presenté une vaste gamme d'effets de tailles différentes. Dès lors, notre troisième objectif était de déterminer l'effet de SPIN-BACC sur les BACC dans les unités de soins intensifs du Québec et d'identifier les variables associées à un taux d'incidence des BACC plus élevé. Nous observons des réductions importantes des taux d'incidence des BACC parmi les unités de soins intensifs qui n'avaient jamais été exposées à la surveillance (31%), ainsi que parmi les unités de soins intensifs non-universitaires (27%) qui ont participé à SPIN-BACC pendant 3 années. Toutefois, ces résultats n'étaient pas statistiquement significatifs à cause de notre petite taille d'échantillon. Les unités de soins intensifs néonatales et les unités qui n'avaient jamais été exposées à la surveillance étaient associées à un taux d'incidence des BACC plus élevé (chapitre 8). En bref, nous avons démontré que les BACC constituent un lourd fardeau au sein de la population de patients admis aux unités de soins intensifs dans la province de Québec. Notre deuxième étude a suggéré que les programmes de surveillance de petite et moyenne tailles devraient effectuer leur surveillance de façon continue. Enfin, l'effet d'un programme de surveillance ciblé sur les taux d'incidence des BACC semble être plus prononcé au sein des unités de soins intensifs n'ayant jamais exposées à la surveillance et les unités de soins intensifs qui ne sont pas affiliées à des universités. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Central line-associated bloodstream infections (CLABSI) figure as one of the most important healthcare-associated infections (HAI), particularly in intensive care units (ICU). Despite their clinical and public health importance, little is known about CLABSI in Canadian ICUs. Thus, the first objective of this thesis was to describe the epidemiology of CLABSI in Quebec ICUs, using data from the Surveillance Provinciale des Infections Nosocomiales – Bactériémies Associées aux Cathéters Centraux (SPIN-BACC) program. We showed that CLABSIs are an important problem in Quebec ICUs, but CLABSI incidence rates have decreased since 2007. Moreover, the proportion of methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus has declined to &lt;40% since 2006 (chapter 6). Surveillance programs are essential to establish benchmarks. In the last years, several regional and national CLABSI surveillance programs have decided to eliminate continuous participation requirements from hospitals. This might have jeopardized the validity of these programs' results because the minimal number of months hospitals should participate in such programs to generate valid annual benchmarks for CLABSI incidence rates have yet to be determined. Our second objective was to determine, through simulation, the impact of different participation requirements on the ability of national and provincial/regional surveillance programs to yield valid estimates of the true annual ICU CLABSI pooled incidence rates. We demonstrated that shortening participation requirements might be suitable for national ICU CLABSI surveillance programs if data are randomly collected. Nevertheless, regional/provincial programs should opt for continuous participation to avoid biased benchmarks (chapter 7). Furthermore, surveillance programs can also be used as a tool to reduce CLABSI incidence rates in ICUs. However, the magnitude of this effect has not been definitely determined as earlier studies presented a wide range of effect estimates. We hypothesized that the effect of surveillance on CLABSI rates differs depending on the characteristics of participating ICUs. Our third objective was to determine the effect of SPIN-BACC on the CLABSI incidence rates in Quebec ICUs, and identify ICU-level variables associated with higher CLABSI incidence rates. There were important reductions in the CLABSI incidence rates of "surveillance-naïve" (31%) and of non-university affiliated ICUs (27%) that participated in SPIN-BACC for 3 years. However, due to our small sample size, these results were not statistically significant. Neonatal and "surveillance-naïve" units were associated with higher CLABSI incidence rates (chapter 8). In conclusion, our first study described the CLABSI burden on ICU patients in Quebec. Our simulation study suggested that small and medium sizes surveillance programs should perform continuous surveillance to avoid biased benchmarks. Finally, we suggested that reductions in ICU CLABSI incidence rates associated with targeted surveillance may be more pronounced among "surveillance-naïve" and non-university affiliated ICUs. All the different applications of CLABSI surveillance data demonstrated in this thesis have the ultimate goal of improving patient care and safety.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Caroline Quach-Thanh</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Robert William Platt</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xj83b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2689395</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p452p"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dissecting the interactions of protein disulfide isomerases</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Määttänen, Veli-Pekka</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The folding and assembly of proteins into their functional three dimensional shape in the secretory pathway is often accompanied by the formation of disulfide bonds that covalently link together cysteines within a single chain, or cysteines from separate chains. Secreted proteins are folded and assembled in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER), an organelle rich in chaperones and folding catalysts that prevent incorrect interactions, and ensure the formation of correct disulfide linkages between cysteines. The protein disulfide isomerases (PDIs) are a family of 20 proteins in the ER that carry out these functions in cooperation with other resident chaperones and folding catalysts. To gain insight into the functions of PDIs, we study the interactions of the three most abundant family members: ERp57, PDI, and ERp72. ERp57 cooperates with the lectin chaperones calnexin and calreticulin. We combine isothermal titration calorimetry, x-ray crystallography, and NMR, to define a surface of ERp57 and a critical arginine residue that enable binding to calnexin and calreticulin. By applying a similarly focused structural strategy to PDI, we define a hydrophobic region within its structure that binds directly to substrates and model peptides. Finally, we combine ER-specific affinity purification and yeast two-hybrid methods to identify novel interacting partners of PDIs. We discover a novel partnership between ERp72 and another folding catalyst, the peptidyl-prolyl cis-trans isomerase cyclophilin B that can cooperate to assemble fragments of antibody chains in vitro. By dissecting the structural determinants of the ERp72/cyclophilin B interaction, we identify a conserved surface of cyclophilin B that binds acidic stretches of ERp72 and the chaperone GRp94, uncovering a novel interaction mechanism in the ER. Moreover, mutations that abrogate cyclophilin B-ERp72/GRp94 interactions alter the localization of cyclophilin B, suggesting a previously unappreciated spatial partitioning of cyclophilin B. Together, these studies provide insight into the functional interactions of PDIs with other ER proteins, and highlight the interconnectedness of protein folding machineries in the ER. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le repliement et l'assemblage des protéines de sécrétion en leurs formes fonctionnelles tridimensionnelles est souvent accompagné par la formation de ponts disulfures, lesquels relient ensemble de façon covalente les cystéines d'une même chaîne ou de chaînes différentes. Les protéines de sécrétion sont repliées et assemblées dans le réticulum endoplasmique (RE), une organelle riche en chaperons et catalyseurs de repliement qui prévient les interactions incorrectes et assurent la formation appropriée de liaisons disulfures entre les cystéines. Les protéines disulfures isomérases (PDIs) sont une famille de 20 protéines du RE qui effectuent ces fonctions de concert avec d'autres chaperons et catalyseurs de repliement résidants. Afin de comprendre davantage les fonctions des PDIs, nous étudions les interactions des trois membres les plus abondants de cette famille : ERp57, PDI et ERp72. ERp57 coopère avec les chaperons de type lectine calnexine et calréticuline. Nous combinons donc la calorimétrie de titration isothermique, la cristallographie à rayon X et le RMN, afin d'indentifier la région d'ERp57 et un résidu d'arginine essentiel permettant la liaison au calnexine et au calréticuline. En appliquant une stratégie structurale focalisée similaire pour PDI, nous définissons une région hydrophobe responsable de l'attachement directe aux substrats et peptides modèles. Finalement, nous combinons les méthodes de purification par affinité spécifique au RE et de deux-hybride de levure pour identifier de nouveaux partenaires d'interaction pour les PDIs. Nous découvrons une association novatrice entre ERp72 et un catalyseur de repliement différent, la peptidyl-prolyl cis-trans isomérase cyclophiline B, laquel peut coopérer pour assembler in vitro des fragments de chaînes d'anticorps. Nous identifions également une région conservée de la cyclophiline B qui relie des séquences acides d'ERp72 et du chaperon GRp94, révélant un nouveau mécanisme d'interaction dans le RE. De plus, les mutations qui empêchent les interactions cyclophiline B-ERp72/GRp94 modifient la localisation de la cyclophiline B, suggérant une division spatiale de celle-ci inconnue jusqu'à ce jour. Ensemble, ces études permettent d'approfondir les connaissances sur les interactions fonctionnelles des PDIs avec d'autres protéines du RE et soulignent l'interconnexité des machineries de repliement du RE.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David Thomas</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30px78j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p452p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94ht69v"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Corrosion initiation of concrete bridge elements exposed to de-icing salts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wolofsky, Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A large portion of bridges in North America was built 50 to 75 years ago, designed with a similar service lifespan. As a result, many existing bridges require full inspections, repairs, retrofitting or decommissioning. With limited resources available, it is crucial that maintenance strategies and rehabilitations are planned accordingly. To do so, designers, engineers and owners must be informed on the timeframe of the degradation process. Deterioration of reinforced concrete bridges is strongly associated with corrosion of steel caused by the application of deicing salts. In Montreal, the severity and duration of the winter period is a major concern. Motorists require safe roads to commute, thus large quantities of salt are spread each winter season to achieve bare pavement. The chlorides from the deicing salt enter the concrete and destroy the passive oxide layer protecting the reinforcing steel, making the steel vulnerable to corrosion. In this work, the "TransChlor" computer software was used to simulate chloride ion ingress into concrete cover. A climatic model for Montreal weather was used in the simulations to accurately portray real life environmental conditions. Cumulative probability distributions for corrosion initiation with respect to time and embedment depths were produced for mist, direct, and splash exposure conditions.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Une grande partie des ponts en Amérique du Nord a été construite il y a 50 à 75 ans, et conçus avec une durée de vie de service similaire. En conséquence, de nombreux ponts existants requièrent des inspections complètes, des réparations, lune modernisation ou un déclassement. Avec les ressources limitées disponibles, il est essentiel que des stratégies de maintenance et de réhabilitation soient planifiées. Pour ce faire, les concepteurs, les ingénieurs et les propriétaires doivent être informés sur les processus de dégradation. La détérioration des ponts en béton armé est fortement associée à la corrosion de l'acier par l'application de sels de déglaçage. À Montréal, la sévérité et la durée de la période hivernale est un problème majeur. Les automobilistes ont besoin des routes sûres et, une grande quantité de sel est utilisée chaque hiver pour déglacer les routes. Les chlorures provenant du sel de déglaçage pénètrent le béton et détruisent la couche d'oxyde passive qui protège l'acier d'armature, et rend l'acier plus vulnérable à la corrosion. Dans ce travail, le logiciel "TransChlor" a été utilisé pour simuler la pénétration des ions chlorures dans la couverture de béton. Un modèle climatique de Montréal pour la météorologie a été utilisé dans les simulations pour représenter exactement les conditions réelles de l'environnement. Les distributions de probabilité cumulative du temps requis pour l'initiation de la corrosion ont été obtenus en fonction de la couverture de béton pour des conditions d'exposition de brouillard, d'exposition directe, et par éclaboussures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Luc E. Chouinard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dk81s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94ht69v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An009w634f"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigating the effects of heritage culture on problem behaviour and academic achievement in a specific First Nations community</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rochester, Lynda Simone</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude a eu pour but d'examiner l'effet modérateur que le sens d'appartenance à sa culture a sur les comportements. L'étude regarde aussi si ce même sens d'appartenance a une influence positive sur le succès scolaire. Un groupe de 30 élèves des Premières Nations dans une école située dans une petite communauté située au nord de Montréal, a répondu à des questionnaires portant sur leurs comportements et leurs affiliations à leur culture.  L'analyse des corrélations entre les variables précédemment mentionnées a produit un résultat significatif entre l'année scolaire et le comportement, mais une analyse de régression n'a pas eu de résultats concluants entre le succès scolaire et l'affiliation a sa culture. L'impact favorable qu'a l'affiliation culturelle sur le comportement est discuté. Le potentiel positif que peut exhorter l'affiliation culturelle sur le succès scolaire par l'attachement à son école et à ses parents, des programmes pédagogiques culturels et par le développement de l'estime de soi est aussi discuté.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The objective of this study was to examine the influence of heritage culture on academic achievement and problem behavior in minority youth. A sample of 30 First Nations students from a small community in Quebec participated in this study by answering questionnaires on their cultural affiliation and problem behaviour. The bivariate correlations on all variables only demonstrated a relationship between grade level and problem behaviour. Further probing into the inter-relations was performed through hierarchical regression analyses to ascertain the contributing significance between gender, grade level, academic achievement, problem behaviour and affiliation to heritage culture. Significant results were found between heritage culture and problem behaviour. There were no significant results involving academic achievement and heritage culture. Cultural affiliation may be a positive mediator to problem behaviour. Although no significance was found between heritage culture and academic achievement, potential positive influence within this relationship through attachment, school programs, personal resources and self-esteem will be discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jacob A. Burack</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583z015p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w634f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arj430879h"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Skin innervation patterns and neurotrophic factor expression in neuropathic pain models</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Peleshok, Jennifer</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La douleur neuropathique peut se présenter sous plusieurs formes.  Dans cette thèse, j'analyse les mécanismes périphériques pouvant déclencher et maintenir la douleur neuropathique. L'approche adoptée dans cette thèse est surtout basée sur une analyse de la concentration et distribution anatomique de protéines, avec l'idée sous-jacente que son niveau d'expression (ou absence d'expression) est révélatrice de changements physiologiques dans les structures qui produisent ou sécrètent ces protéines. Le focus de ce travail se déroule dans la périphérie, en particulier la peau non couverte de poils de la surface plantaire du membre postérieur du rat. Cette peau est innervée par des fibres nerveuses sensorielles provenant du nerf sciatique. Ces fibres sont normalement classées comme  afférences myélinisées épaisses et finement myélinisées (A-bêta et A-delta respectivement), ainsi que comme fibres amyéliniques (C). La dernière population peut être divisée en deux sous-groupes en fonction de présence ou absence de neuropeptides en peptidergiques et non-peptidergiques. Cette région reçoit également une innervation par des fibres post-ganglionnaires sympathiques. Cette thèse est composée de trois chapitres expérimentaux. Le premier chapitre se penche sur les changements à long terme de l'innervation cutanée qui se produisent après l'application d'un modèle de douleur neuropathique couramment utilisé, à savoir la blessure par constriction chronique du nerf sciatique (CCI). J'ai examiné les changements des fibres myélinisées, des fibres amyéliniques peptidergiques, ainsi que des fibres non-peptidergiques dès trois jours après l'application de la lésion jusqu'à un an et demi après la lésion.  Il y avait une perte persistante des afférences myélinisées, une perte suivie d'une récupération tardive des fibres C non-peptidergiques ainsi qu'une brève perte suivie de récupération permanente des afférences peptidergiques dans la partie supérieure du derme. Le second chapitre expérimental est un examen comparatif des changements morphologiques après l'application de deux modèles très similaires de douleur neuropathique. Le premier est la constriction chronique du nerf sciatique (CCI) suivant l'application de 4 ligatures; dans le deuxième la constriction du nerf sciatique est obtenue par l'application autour du nerf d'un segment de tube polyéthylène (cuff). L'application du « cuff » résultait en une hypersensibilité mécanique persistante, contrairement au  CCI dans lequel l'hypersensibilité mécanique disparaissait dans un mois environ. Toutefois, les résultats de l'application des deux modèles sur la sensibilité thermique étaient similaires, avec une hyper-sensitivité à la chaleur qui durait environ un mois. Les afférences myélinisées étaient réduites en densité dans la partie supérieure du derme dans les deux modèles et cette baisse était permanente. Cependant, les afférences non-peptidergiques ont souffert une baisse de densité suivie d'un retour retardé à des valeurs des contrôles dans le modèle « cuff ». Dans ce dernier modèle, les afférences peptidergiques ont diminué progressivement en densité et n'ont pas récupéré, à la différence de l'application de la CCI. Le troisième chapitre expérimental concerne les changements dans l'expression du facteur de croissance nerveuse (NGF) et de ses récepteurs dans des animaux avec une lésion CCI. Le précurseur du NGF, proNGF a été localisé dans l'épiderme de la peau naïve. À la suite de la lésion CCI, nous avons détecté une augmentation du proNGF. Après la lésion, les cellules de Schwann avaient une expression très augmentée du récepteur du NGF p75. Les récepteurs au NGF, TrkA et p75 sont différentiellement régulés dans la période  après la  lésion du nerf.  Le travail de cette thèse a eu comme objectif de clarifier les changements morphologiques contribuant au déclanchement et la manutention de la douleur neuropathique, ainsi que les mécanismes moléculaires de ces changements.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Neuropathic pain presents itself with many faces. It can be devastatingly painful leading to a person's inability to lead a productive life or it can be mild.  In this thesis I discuss one of the countless possible mechanisms which could underlie the development and maintenance of this disorder; namely the involvement of peripheral changes in innervation. The approach taken in this thesis was mainly based on protein analyses, based on the assumption that protein expression (or lack thereof) is indicative of changes in the physiological properties of structures that either express or secrete proteins. I also address the models which are commonly used by researchers to elucidate the mechanisms underlying chronic neuropathic pain in hopes of developing viable treatments. The focus of this work is on the periphery, more specifically involving the glabrous skin of the rat hind paw. This skin is innervated by branches of the sciatic nerve which are comprised of, in part, sensory fibres. These are sub-classified into the thickly and thinly myelinated A-beta and A-delta afferents, respectively, as well as unmyelinated C-fibres. The latter population can be divided into two subgroups based on their peptide content where the peptide rich are termed peptidergic and the peptide-poor, non-peptidergic. This area also receives innervation from post-ganglionic sympathetic efferents. This thesis comprises three experimental chapters of my independent work into further exploring the models and mechanisms underlying the maintenance and generation of neuropathic pain.  The first experimental chapter addresses the long term changes of skin innervation which occur following the application of a commonly used model of neuropathic pain, namely the chronic constriction injury (CCI) of the sciatic nerve model. I examined the myelinated afferent population as a whole, the unmyelinated peptidergic afferents as well as the non-peptidergic C-fibres from three days through 1.5 years following the application of the nerve injury.  There was a persistent loss of myelinated afferents, loss and delayed sprouting of non-peptidergic C-fibres as well as a brief loss and permanent sprouting of peptidergic afferents within the upper dermis. The second study is a comparative examination of the morphological and behavioural changes following application of two very similar models of neuropathic pain. The CCI model is based on the application of loose chromic gut ligatures and the variation of this is the cuff model in which the chromic gut ligatures are replaced by a fixed diameter polyethylene cuff. The application of the cuff model resulted in a persistent mechanical hypersensitivity in contrast to the CCI in which the mechanical hypersensitivity resolved within about a month. However, the application of either model resulted in a transient thermal hypersensitivity. Innervation changes following application of the cuff model included a reduction in myelinated afferent density within the upper dermis in both models, the unmyelinated, non-peptidergic afferents declined in fibre density followed by a delayed recovery in the cuff model and the peptidergic afferents gradually declined and remained so following application of the cuff in contrast to the application of the CCI. The third chapter addresses the changes in the expression of nerve growth factor (NGF) and its receptors following CCI. The precursor form of NGF, proNGF was localized to mast cells, vascular endothelium and keratinocytes in the epidermis in naïve skin. Following injury, proNGF increased.  After lesion, Schwann cells expressed high levels of the NGF receptor p75. The two receptors for NGF, TrkA and p75, were differentially regulated during the progression of the nerve injury. The work of this thesis has provided new findings documenting the morphological changes underlying the generation and maintenance of neuropathic pain as well as the molecular generators of these changes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alfredo Ribeiro Da Silva</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wh63m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430879h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vq05j"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>State authority structures and the rule of law in post-colonial societies: a comparison of Jamaica and Barbados</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dawson, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine les déterminants de la légitimité de la loi dans les sociétés post-coloniales à travers la comparaison entre la Barbade et la Jamaique, deux pays similaires à plusieurs niveaux, mais dont la légitimité de la loi s'exerce on ne peut plus différemment. Ce projet de recherche propose une comparaison historique, ayant pour angle une recherche des origines de cette divergence de la légitimité de la loi entre ces deux pays pendant leur transition vers l'indépendance. L'analyse propose que le degré des divisions ethniques à influencer la culture politique de la masse lors de la transition au suffrage universel vers la fin de la période coloniale. C'était le facteur critique qui a déterminé si la violence et le favoritisme politiques étaient institutionnalisés, ce qui a conduit à la détérioration de la capacité de l'état à promouvoir la légitimité de la loi. Des divergences entourant quatre éléments-clés (la présence d'une corrélation race-classe sociale, le niveau d'identification de la population Afro-Antillaise à la communauté nationale, l'orientation de la religion de la classe inférieure envers l'ordre établi, et les conditions qui ont facilité l'autonomie culturelle des classes inférieures) se sont développés entre les deux îles pendant le début de l'ère coloniale et ont influencé le développement des divisions ethniques entre les classes, entraînant une influence de la culture politique de la masse. En Jamaique, la division ethnique entre les classes moyennes et inférieures ont poussé ces dernières à adopter une culture politique qui défiait  l'autorité de l'état colonial, qui, combiné avec l'inaction des autorités coloniales, a eu pour résultat l'établissement d'un système politique démocratique basé sur la violence, l'absence de lois et le patronage  durant cette période critique d'instabilité sur l'île (la transition vers le suffrage universel et l'indépendance). À la Barbade, l'absence de divisions ethniques a entraîné l'adoption de la culture politique par la masse. Il y avait une large acceptation de la légitimité de l'autorité judiciaire de l'État, avec tous les principaux partis politiques faisant appel à l'électorat sur une base rationnelle, ce qui a empêché l'escalade et l'institutionnalisation de la violence politique et du favoritisme. Par ailleurs, la compatibilité entre la culture politique et la structure d'autorité de l'État à la Barbade a constitué le fondement d'une légitimité de la loi forte pendant la période post-coloniale.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the determinants of a strong rule of law in post-colonial societies by comparing Jamaica and Barbados, two countries with many similarities, but with divergent outcomes concerning the rule of law. The research takes a comparative historical approach, specifically investigating the origins of the divergence of the rule of law between Jamaica and Barbados during the transition to independence. The analysis suggests that the extent of communal divisions influenced the political culture of the masses during the transition to universal suffrage in the late colonial period. This proved to be the critical factor that determined whether political violence and patronage politics were institutionalized, which ultimately led to the deterioration in the capacity of the state to promote the rule of law. Differences along four key dimensions (the extent of a race-class correlation, the extent to which the Afro-Caribbean population viewed themselves as members of the national community, the orientation of the religion of the lower classes towards the established order, and the structural conditions that facilitated the cultural autonomy of the lower classes) developed between the two islands during the early colonial period that influenced the formation of communal divisions along class lines, which in turn influenced the political culture of the masses. In Jamaica, the ethnic division between the lower and middle classes led the former to adopt a political culture that challenged the authority of the colonial state, which, combined with the inaction of colonial authorities, ultimately resulted in the establishment of a democratic political system based on violence, lawlessness and patronage that emerged during a critical period of instability on the island (the transition to both universal suffrage and independence). In Barbados, the absence of communal divisions resulted in the adoption of the dominant political culture by the masses.  As such, there was broad-based acceptance of the legitimacy of legal state authority, with all major political parties appealing to the electorate on a rational basis, thereby hindering the escalation and institutionalization of political violence and clientelism. Moreover, the compatibility between the political culture and the state authority structure in Barbados provided the foundation for a strong rule of law during the post-colonial period.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Matthew Lange</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kp78g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vq05j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology - Social Structure and Development</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702qb459"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reevaluating the mechanism of partial agonism at kainate receptors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Andrews, Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Kainate-type ionotropic glutamate receptors (iGluRs) fulfill important neuromodulatory roles in the mammalian CNS, and as such have been subject to much structural and functional analysis. However, proposed models of partial agonism at these receptors still suffer from several issues. For example, contrary to conventional understanding, agonist efficacy at KARs does not always correlate with the cleft closure of its agonist binding domain (ABD). And it is not yet determined how activation of these receptors leads to responses containing a large transient component, followed by a considerably smaller sustained component. Recent work from the Bowie lab showed the importance of the KAR ABD closed-cleft stability for the activation of the transient component response. My research work identifies the role of another region of kainate receptor, the ABD dimer interface, for the steady state component of KAR response. In support of this, my work reveals that stabilizing the dimer interface by covalent crosslinking locks the KAR into low conductance states with macroscopic and single-channel properties similar to that of wild-type KAR steady-state response. Surprisingly, restriction of movement at the dimer interface renders L-glutamate a weak partial agonist to such an extent that the receptor spends much of its time cycling through long-lived, closed states between activations. This finding diverges from the established understanding that stabilizing the dimer interface prevents onset of KAR desensitization.  From our data, we also suggest that protein interactions formed at the dimer interface during transient and steady state activation of the receptor are agonist-specific. Thus, my work demonstrates how the dimer interface stability and the ABD cleft closure stability work together to generate specific components of the KAR response.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les récepteurs ionotropiques de glutamate (iGluRs) de type kaïnate (KAR) remplissent des rôles neuromodulatoires importantes dans le système nerveux central (SNC) mammalien, et ainsi plusieurs études structurelles et fonctionnelles y sont consacrées. Cependant, les modèles d'efficacité d'agonistes chez ces récepteurs souffrent encore de divers problèmes. Par exemple, contrairement à l'entente conventionnelle, l'efficacité d'agoniste chez les récepteurs de kaïnate ne reste pas avec le degré de fermeture du domaine de liaison des ligands (ABD). De plus, ce n'est pas encore déterminé comment l'activation de ces récepteurs résulte dans des réponses contenant une portion large et transitoire, et une autre portion beaucoup plus petite et soutenue. Des résultats obtenus récemment dans le laboratoire Bowie démontrent l'importance de la stabilité de la fermeture du ABD suivant liaison de l'agoniste pour l'activation de la portion de réponse transitoire. Data obtenue de ma recherche identifie une autre région du récepteur, l'interface dimère de l'ABD, étant responsable pour la portion de KAR réponse constante. À l'appui de ceci, mon travail de recherche démontre pour la première fois qu'en stabilisant l'interface dimère avec réticulations covalentes, le KAR est bloqué dans des niveaux de conductance bas avec des propriétés macroscopiques et microscopiques similaires à celles du KAR (type sauvage) portion constante. Curieusement, ce restriction du mouvement à l'interface dimère rend aussi le neurotransmitteur glutamate comme agoniste partiel aussi faible que le récepteur reste la majorité de son temps dans des niveaux fermés et longs entre activations. Cette découverte est divergente de l'entente établie que la stabilisation de l'interface dimère prévient la désensibilisation du KAR. Nous suggérons aussi que les interactions formées à l'interface dimère durant l'activation transitoire et constante du récepteur sont spécifiques à l'agoniste.  Ainsi, les résultats de ma recherche démontrent comment l'interface dimère et la stabilité de la fermeture du ABD travaillent ensemble pour générer des composants spécifiques de la réponse agoniste chez le KAR. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gregory Miller</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Derek Bowie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jj66t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702qb459</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2227mv04r"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>spa</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Hispanic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>De la soledad y el fracaso la recuperacion del individuo roto en el teatro de Paloma Pedrero: desde 'En el tunel un pajaro' hasta 'Caidos del cielo'</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fialdini Zambrano, Rossana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le but de cette dissertation est double: d'abord, il s'agit de tracer dans le théâtre de Paloma Pedrero une cartographie du processus de dégradation morale et sociale de certains individus dans la société contemporaine à travers duquel ils ont terminé leur vie dans la rue, un espace où ils complètent leur dégradation au point qu'ils perdent leur droit de citoyenneté et leur droit d'être une personne. Deuxièmement, on examine la potentialité du théâtre à réparer et à récupérer la dignité perdue chez les individus qui ont tout perdu dans leur vie.  Pedrero est une auteure profondément impliquée dans les circonstances socio-historiques de l'Espagne post-franquiste et aussi une dramaturge qui, due à son expérience comme actrice, écrivaine de théâtre, directrice et gestionnaire de théâtre, peut être considérée une véritable “femme de théâtre.” Son théâtre est en dialogue critique permanent avec les circonstances socio-historiques, ce qui lui a permis de percevoir ceux qui sont socialement vulnérables dans la société contemporaine, les vrai perdants d'aujourd'hui et de les récupérer dans plusieurs personnages principaux de certaines de ses œuvres où l'on peut constater comment ils ont été écrasés, anéantis comme êtres humains et jetés à la rue. Après avoir réalisé la nécessaire vue d'ensemble socio-historique de l'auteur et son œuvre, on a délimité ici deux pratiques principales : la première examine la solitude comme un catalyseur qui mène à la dévastation personnelle, problématique qui nous amène à la terrible misère des sans-abri. La deuxième explore la proposition originale de Pedrero de résister la dégradation morale et sociale à l'aide du théâtre, un projet pensé pour et avec les sans-abri.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The object of this dissertation is twofold: first to trace in Paloma Pedrero's theatre a cartography of the process of the moral and social degradation of certain individuals in contemporary society whereby they are forced out onto the street, a space where their degradation is complete to the extent that they lose their right of citizenship and of being a true person, and, secondly, to examine the author's avowed intention of using the potential of theatre to repair and recuperate such loss of personal dignity in real life. Pedrero is at once an author deeply involved in the socio-historical circumstances of post-Francoist Spain and a dramatist who, by virtue of her experience as an actress, playwright, director, and theatre manager, is truly “a women of the theatre.” As such her theatre is in permanent critical dialogue with socio-historical circumstances, while her assessment of the socially vulnerable in contemporary society, today's real losers, is a striking feature of a large number of the principal characters in her many-faceted plays who demonstrate how they are crushed, wiped out as social beings, and thrown to the street. Following the necessary socio-historical review of the author and her work, two main features are, thus, delineated here. First, the issue of loneliness as a catalyst leading to personal devastation is taken up and followed through to the reality of the plight of the abject poverty of the homeless. Then Pedrero's original plan to resist such moral and social degradation by means of a theatrical project for and with the homeless is explored.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kathleen M. Sibbald</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xd644.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mv04r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Modern</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cf851"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Remote sensing of light use effeciency in a boreal forest and peatland in James Bay, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rogers, Cheryl</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'indice de réflectance photochimique (IRP) est un indice de végétation par télédétection qui détecte une diminution de la réflectance spectrale à 531nm associée à l'activité du cycle des xanthophylles. Il a été démontré que l'IRP est associé à l'efficacité d'utilisation de lumière (EUL) dans un certain nombre d'espèces végétales. L'IRP permet donc d'améliorer notre capacité à détecter les flux photosynthétiques du CO2 à distance. Cependant, il n'a pas été testé dans tous les environnements, et son applicabilité est particulièrement incertaine pour les écosystèmes tels que les tourbières dominées par les mousses. Cette étude examine la capacité des IRP de déceler l'EUL dans une forêt boréale et une tourbière, et examine le signal spectral associé à l'activité du cycle xanthophylle dans des parcelles hétérogènes d'une tourbière. Cette étude explore également la relation entre l'IRP et l'indice de surface foliaire (ISF) dans l'espace et le temps dans une tourbière.Nous avons trouvé que la plupart des parcelles examinées dans la tourbière ne présentent pas un signal spectral associé à l'activité du cycle de xanthophylle lorsqu'exposées à des conditions passant de l'obscurité à la lumière du soleil. Cette transition de luminosité devrait mener à la de-époxydation des xanthopylles dans les tissus foliaires et à une diminution de la réflectance à 531 nm. Les parcelles qui ont montré une telle diminution de la réflectance à 531 nm après les changements de luminosité ont aussi affiché une baisse de l'IRP.  Ceci indique que l'IRP peut détecter le signal à 531 nm ainsi que l'activité du cycle de xanthophylle et le stress lumineux dans ces parcelles. Par contre, la variabilité de la réponse spectrale à l'évolution des conditions de lumière peuvent confondre le signal de l'IRP, ce qui rend difficile d'interpréter les résultats provenant de données aériennes ou satellitaires. Nous avons également constaté que l'IRP dans la  tourbière  est sensible et directement corrélé avec la variabilité spatiale de l'ISF, et négativement corrélé avec la variabilité temporelle de l'ISF. Ces caractéristiques peuvent entraîner des difficultés supplémentaires quant à l'application de l'IRP dans les tourbières.L'IRP et l'EUL étaient corrélés à la forêt et à la tourbière, mais il y avait saturation du signal de l'IRP autour de 500 µmol m-2 s-1 du rayonnement photosynthétiquement actif (RPA) aux deux sites. Cet effet de saturation n'a pas, à notre connaissance, été signalé dans d'autres études. La saturation du signal de l'IRP peut limiter notre capacité à déterminer les flux de carbone provenant de données aériennes ou satellitaires  qui sont généralement recueillies sous un ciel clair pendant les parties les plus brillantes de la journée où la RPA dépasse 500 µmol m-2 s-1.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The photochemical reflectance index (PRI) is a remotely sensed vegetation index that detects a decrease in spectral reflectance at 531nm associated with xanthophyll cycle activity. PRI has been shown to track light use efficiency (LUE) in a number of plant species. PRI shows great promise in improving our ability to sense photosynthetic fluxes of CO2 remotely. However, it has not been tested in all environments, and its applicability is particularly uncertain for peatland environments dominated by mosses. This research investigates the ability of PRI to track LUE in a boreal forest and peatland, and examines the spectral signal associated with xanthophyll cycle activity in heterogeneous peatland plots. This research also investigates the relationship between PRI and leaf area index (LAI) over space and time in a peatland. We found most plots examined in the peatland site did not exhibit a spectral signal associated with xanthophyll cycle activity when exposed to a transition from dark conditions to full sunlight. This transition should lead to a de-epoxidation of xanthophylls in leaf tissues and a decrease in reflectance at 531nm. Plots that did show the decrease in reflectance at 531nm after this change in light conditions also displayed a decrease in PRI. This indicates that PRI effectively detects the 531nm signal as well as xanthophyll cycle activity and light stress in these plots. However, the variability in the strength of the spectral response to changing light conditions may confound the PRI signal in practice, and make it difficult to interpret results of airborne or satellite data. We also found PRI at the peatland site to be sensitive to and directly correlated with spatial variability in LAI, and negatively correlated with temporal variability in LAI. These characteristics may result in further difficulties applying PRI in peatlands. PRI and LUE were correlated at both the forest and peatland site, however at both sites the PRI signal saturated around 500 µmol m-2 s-1 of photosynthetically active radiation (PAR). This saturation effect has not, to our knowledge, been reported in other studies. Saturation of the PRI signal may limit our ability to determine carbon fluxes from airborne or satellite based remotely sensed data which is generally collected under clear skies during the brightest parts of the day when PAR exceeds 500 µmol m-2 s-1.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ian Brett Strachan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558j22b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cf851</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Remote Sensing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0z7091789"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Internet-based menu planning in type 2 diabetes and its impact on weight, A1C and blood pressure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bader, Abeer</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Weight loss in overweight and obese persons with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) decreases risk of cardiovascular disease. There is some evidence that written menu plans and Internet-based menu programs advocating healthy eating are associated with weight loss in non-diabetic obese persons, particularly in those who frequently log-into such programs, but this approach has not been assessed in T2DM. To address this gap in knowledge, the objective of this study was to determine whether the number of weeks participants logged-into SOSCuisine, an Internet-based menu program, over a 24-week period was predictive of weight loss in overweight/obese adults with T2DM. Data were collected on 33 adults (57.8 ±7.4 years) recruited through collaborating registered dietitians at outpatient diabetes clinics of McGill University-affiliated hospitals (Montréal, Québec, Canada). Each participant's dietitian consulted with the SOSCuisine dietitian to individualize the menu plan. Body weight, other adiposity markers, blood pressure and A1C were measured at baseline and 24-weeks after initiating the program. The number of weeks participants logged-into the program was tracked electronically. After adjustment for age and sex and using multiple imputations to account for missing data, a 10-week increase in log-ins to the program was associated with a -2.0% [95% CI, -3.0 to -1.0%] weight change. A 5% or greater weight reduction was achieved by 18.0% of participants overall and 27.8% of those defined as adherent (i.e., those who accessed the web-based program once per week for a minimum of 18/24 weeks). A 1% weight reduction was associated with a -2.4 mm Hg change in systolic blood pressure [95% CI, -3.5 to -1.2 mm Hg] and a -0.8 mm Hg change in diastolic blood pressure [95% CI, -1.4 to -0.2 mm Hg]. Weight changes were not conclusively related to A1C changes (glycemic control). Our findings indicate that an Internet-based menu program leads to a clinically important weight loss in 1/5 of those who enroll and 1/3 of those who adhere. We have demonstrated a clear association between log-in frequency and weight change, again emphasizing the importance of adherence. The weight change was conclusively related to reductions in blood pressure, confirming clinically important effects.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La perte de poids chez les personnes en surpoids/obèses souffrant de diabète sucré de type 2 (DST2) réduit le risque de maladies cardiovasculaires. Certaines données indiquent que les plans-repas écrits et les programmes de plans-repas sur Internet pour une alimentation plus saine sont associés à une perte de poids chez les personnes non-diabétiques, surtout ceux qui fréquentent ces programmes en ligne, mais ce phénomène n'avait pas été évalué chez les personnes atteintes de DST2. Pour combler cette lacune, on a cherché à déterminer si le nombre de semaines de fréquentation du site SOSCuisine, des plans-repas sur Internet, pendant 24 semaines, permettait de prédire la perte de poids chez les adultes en surpoids/ obèses atteints de DST2. Les données ont été recueillies auprès de 33 adultes (57,8 ±7,4 ans) par des diététistes d'hôpitaux affiliés à l'Université McGill. Ces diététistes ont consulté celui de SOSCuisine pour personnaliser le plan-repas du sujet. Le poids corporel, d'autres marqueurs de l'adiposité, la tension artérielle et l'A1C ont été mesurés au début de l'étude et après 24 semaines, le taux de fréquentation faisant l'objet d'une surveillance électronique. En tenant compte de l'âge et du sexe des participants et à l'aide d'imputations multiples pour compenser les données manquantes, il ressort qu'une augmentation de 10 semaines de fréquentation de SOSCuisine est associée à une baisse du poids de -2,0% [IC 95%, de -3,0 à  1,0%]. Une réduction de 5% ou plus a été observée chez 18.0% (1/3) de tous les participants et chez 27,8% (1/5) des « adhérents » – les personnes ayant fréquenté le site au cours d'au moins 18 des 24 semaines de l'étude. Une perte de poids de 1% était associée à une variation de la tension artérielle systolique de -2,4 mm Hg [IC 95%, de -3,5 à  1,2 mm Hg] et de la tension artérielle diastolique de -0,8 mm Hg [IC 95%, de  1,4 à -0,2 mm Hg]. Il n'a pas été possible de relier la variation de poids à celle de l'A1C (le contrôle de la glycémie) de manière concluante. Nous avons démontré une association claire entre la fréquence d'accès au site et la perte de poids, ce qui souligne l'importance de l'adhésion. La perte de poids a pu être reliée irréfutablement à des réductions de la tension artérielle, confirmant ainsi d'importants effets sur le plan clinique. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rejeanne Denise Gougeon</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Kaberi Dasgupta</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f775h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z7091789</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dk83b"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of somatic symptoms in assessing symptoms of depression: do physical health and gender matter?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Delisle, Vanessa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le Trouble Dépressif Majeur (TDM) est fréquent chez les personnes malades et plus commun chez les femmes que chez les hommes. Afin d'assurer la validité des comparaisons du taux de prévalence de TDM et des sévérités des symptômes auto-déclarés parmi les groupes, il est important d'établir que les méthodes de diagnostic et les questionnaires sur les symptômes de dépression qui évaluent la gravité mesurent le même concept entre ces groupes. Il y a relativement peu de recherches qui ont tenté de comprendre l'influence potentielle des symptômes somatiques rapportés sur le taux de sévérité des symptômes de dépression, et les études existantes montrent des limitations importantes. Ainsi, l'objectif de la première étude de cette thèse était d'évaluer à quel point les symptômes somatiques rapportés pouvaient influencer les résultats sur un questionnaire des symptômes auto-déclarés de dépression (le "Beck Depression Inventory (BDI)") parmi les patients qui ont subi un infarctus du myocarde (IM) et qui ont des limites physiques importantes associées à cette maladie, comparés aux patients externe de psychiatrie. L'objectif de la deuxième études était aussi d'évaluer à quel point les symptômes somatiques rapportés pouvaient influencer les résultats sur un autre questionnaire des symptômes auto-déclarés de dépression (le "BDI-II") parmi les patientes externes femelles en psychiatrie par rapport aux patients externes mâles. La première étude a démontré que l'évaluation des symptômes de dépression avec le BDI parmi les patients qui ont subi un IM pouvait exagérer la gravité des symptômes dus à l'influence des symptômes somatiques qui surviennent fréquemment suite à un IM, mais qui ne seraient pas dus à la dépression. Ces résultats, considérés dans le contexte d'une étude précédente du BDI-II qui n'a pas identifié de différences entre les patients qui ont subi un IM et les patients externes de psychiatrie, suggère que le BDI-II peut-être préférable au BDI dans les études épidémiologiques de la dépression chez les patients qui ont subi un IM. Cependant, d'autres études sont nécessaires pour comparer directement l'influence des symptômes somatiques sur le BDI et le BDI-II chez les patients souffrant de maladies cardiovasculaires. Les résultats de la deuxième étude suggèrent que les hommes et les femmes présentent des niveaux similaires de symptômes cognitifs/affectifs et somatiques de dépression. Les résultats de cette deuxième étude ne supportent pas les conclusions des études précédentes qui suggèrent que les femmes rapportent plus de symptômes somatiques de dépression que les hommes et que cela expliquerait les différences entre les sexes dans les taux de dépression et la sévérité des symptômes. Les études futures devraient se concentrer sur d'autres explications.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) is common among people with medical illnesses and is more common in women compared to men. In order for comparisons of MDD prevalence rates and self-reported symptom severity across groups to be valid, it is important to establish that diagnostic methods or depression symptom questionnaires that assess severity are measuring the same construct across the groups. There is relatively little research that has attempted to dissect the potential influence of somatic symptom reporting on depression symptom severity ratings, and existing research has important limitations. Thus, the objective of the studies in this thesis was to assess the degree to which differences in somatic symptom reporting might influence scores on a commonly used self-report depression symptom questionnaire, the Beck Depression Inventory (BDI), among post-myocardial infarction (MI) patients, who have a high somatic burden associated with acute cardiovascular disease, compared to psychiatry outpatients, as well as scores on the BDI-II among female compared to male psychiatry outpatients. The first study found evidence that assessing depression symptoms with the BDI post-MI may exaggerate depression symptom severity scores due to the influence of somatic symptoms that commonly occur post-MI, but which are not due to depression. These results, considered in the context of a previous study of the BDI-II that did not find any differences between post-MI and psychiatry outpatients, suggest that the BDI-II may be preferable to the BDI in epidemiological studies of depression among post-MI patients. However, more studies are needed that directly compare the influence of somatic symptoms on the BDI and BDI-II among cardiovascular disease patients. The results of the second study suggest that men and women report similar levels of cognitive/affective and somatic symptoms of depression. Previous suggestions that women report more somatic symptoms of depression than men and that this explains gender differences in depression rates and symptom severity are not supported by the evidence, and future studies should focus on alternative explanations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brett David Thombs</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xq73k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dk83b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9w032708h"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of urine-based rapid tests for smoking and isoniazid treatment monitoring in adult patients</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nicolau, Ioana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Contexte: Globalement, la tuberculose (TB) affecte 9,4 millions de personnes chaque année, avec environ 2 millions de décès. L'efficacité de l'INH, lorsqu'utilisé dans une stratégie de contrôle et de traitement de la TB latente, est limitée parce que les patients ne le prennent pas comme prescrit. La recherche a démontré que le tabac était un facteur de risque pour la tuberculose, et que les fumeurs auraient plus de difficulté à maintenir leur adhésion au traitement contre la tuberculose. Il existe maintenant de nouveaux tests rapides capables de détecter les fumeurs ainsi que l'adhésion au traitement à l'isoniazide, et ces tests d'urine peuvent facilement être utilisés en clinique. Objectif: L'objectif de l'étude était de valider IsoScreen et SmokeScreen, deux nouveaux tests d'urine utilisés en clinique pour détecter les métabolites INH et les métabolites de cotinine. Les résultats de chaque test ont été comparés aux algorithmes des standards de référence développés pour chaque test pour déterminer si le patient prend la pilule INH et son statut de fumeur. Méthodes: Les principaux résultats mesurés étaient la précision et la fiabilité des tests IsoScreen et SmokeScreen. La précision a été mesurée en comparant les valeurs de sensibilité et de spécificité de chaque test à leurs standards de référence: le Standard de référence pour le statut de l'INH et le Standard de référence pour le statut de fumeur. La fiabilité a été mesurée avec statistique kappa pour déterminer l'accord intra-évaluateur et inter-évaluateurs. Résultats: Dans cette étude, nous avons recruté 200 patients externes adultes de la clinique de tuberculose et/ou de la clinique de cessation tabagique à l'Institut thoracique de Montréal. Les patients recrutés étaient des patients qui prenaient ou non des médicaments INH et des fumeurs ou des non-fumeurs. IsoScreen avait une sensibilité de 93.2% (intervalle de confiance à 95% [IC] à 80.3, 98.2) et une spécificité de 98.7% (94.8, 99.8). L'accord intra-évaluateur pour IsoScreen était de 0.75 (0.48, 0.94) et l'accord inter-évaluateurs était de 0.61 (0.27, 0.90). SmokeScreen avait une sensibilité de 69.2% (56.4, 79.8) et une spécificité de 81.6% (73.0, 88.0). L'accord intra-évaluateur pour le test SmokeScreen était de 0.77 (0.56, 0.94) et l'accord inter-évaluateurs était 0.66 (0.42, 0.88).Conclusion: Le test IsoScreen avait une grande précision et une grande fiabilité, alors que SmokeScreen avait une précision et une fiabilité modestes. D'autres recherches devraient être menées dans des contextes cliniques différents, en mettant l'accent sur l'impact de l'utilisation de ces tests sur la gestion des patients.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Background: Globally, tuberculosis (TB) affects 9.4 million people every year, with an estimated 2 million deaths. Effective treatment of latent TB infection with isoniazid (INH) as a TB control strategy has been hampered by poor adherence to therapy. Research has shown that smoking is a risk factor for TB and that adherence to TB therapy may be lower among smoking individuals. Rapid tests are now available to detect smoking status as well as isoniazid treatment adherence in a clinic setting. Objective: The objective was to validate IsoScreen and SmokeScreen, two new point-of-care urine-based tests for INH metabolites and cotinine metabolites. The results from each of the two tests were compared with the corresponding reference standard algorithm developed in this study for measuring INH intake and smoking status. Methods: The main outcomes measured were accuracy and reliability of IsoScreen and SmokeScreen. Accuracy was measured using sensitivity and specificity values for each test against the corresponding reference standard: INH Intake Reference Standard Scale and the Smoking Status Reference Standard. Reliability was measured using kappa statistic for inter-rater and intra-rater agreement. Results: In this study, we recruited 200 adult outpatients attending the tuberculosis clinic and/or the smoking cessation clinic at the Montreal Chest Institute. The patients recruited were a combination of patients on or not on INH medication and smokers or non-smokers. IsoScreen had a sensitivity of 93.2% (95% confidence intervals [CI] 80.3, 98.2) and specificity of 98.7% (94.8, 99.8). IsoScreen had intra-rater agreement of 0.75 (0.48, 0.94) and inter-rater agreement of 0.61 (0.27, 0.90). SmokeScreen had a sensitivity of 69.2% (56.4, 79.8) and specificity of 81.6% (73.0, 88.0). SmokeScreen had intra-rater agreement of 0.77 (0.56, 0.94) and inter-rater agreement of 0.66 (0.42, 0.88).Conclusion: IsoScreen had high accuracy and reliability, whereas SmokeScreen had modest accuracy and modest reliability in tuberculosis and smoking cessation clinic settings. Further research should be conducted in various clinic settings with a focus on the impact of the tests on patient management.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madhukar Pai</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816r66m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032708h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rj520"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Show me the truth: the conditions of possibility for the invention of photography</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Delmas, Didier</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La vulgarisation de la science au cours du dix-huitième siècle créa, vers la fin du siècle, une anxiété épistémologique qui toucha toute les couches de la population depuis les savants les plus instruits jusqu'aux paysans les plus pauvres, depuis les adeptes des équations différentielles jusqu'aux témoins des vols de montgolfières. Livres, magasines, écoles, salons privés, et démonstrations publiques contribuent à cette angoisse quasi-universelle. Vers la fin du siècle apparaissent des spectacles qui sont simultanément des expressions et des tentatives de remèdes à ce malaise. Parmi eux on citera la fantasmagorie, le panorama, et le diorama, tous associés à la photographie. Dans cette thèse j'examine la montée progressive, au cours du dix-huitième siècle, d'un désir d'une représentation précise et véridique du monde naturel qui aboutira à l'invention de la photographie en 1839. Plutôt que considérer la photo comme l'inévitable résultat du progrès des sciences de l'optique et de la chimie je considère les conditions additionnelles nécessaires a l'invention de la photographie. Ces conditions incluent une crise de la connaissance qui s'amplifie au cours du 18ème siècle quand un ordre bâtit sur la solidité de la raison menace un système de connaissance de la nature fondé sur la théologie et introduit la notion de la fragilité de la pensée humaine et l'incertitude de l'observation ; ainsi une inquiétude s'attache aux questions, « pouvons-nous nous fier à ce que nous savons ? Comment être sûr de savoir ce que nous savons ?»Mais dès lors de son invention, la photographie se fragmente en pratiques parfois opposées l'une à l'autre. Si, d'un coté, les scientifiques s'engagent dans la photographie «objective», de l'autre, les artistes détournent cette invention pour leur propres besoins créatifs. De ce fait la pratique de la photographie annule, ou au moins complique, son intention originale ; ce que certains historiens ont perçu comme la deuxième invention de la photographie. Nous pouvons comprendre cette deuxième invention de la photographie si l'on considère que le 18ème siècle n'est pas seulement caractérisé par le règne de la Raison mais aussi par la spéculation philosophique, la vulgarisation des sciences, et les spectacles de masse qui se combinent pour exposer les questions concernant la vérité et le doute à un large segment de la population urbaine. Ainsi, le public du 19ème siècle devient très préoccupée par la question de la compréhension du monde physique. Ma thèse essaie de reconnecter la pratique de la photographie avec sa pré-histoire.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The popularization of science during the eighteenth century generated, toward the end of the century, an epistemological anxiety that reached all levels of the population from the most literate scientist to the poorest peasant, the expert in differential calculus like the witness of the flights of Montgolfières.  Books, periodicals, schooling, private salons, and public demonstrations contributed to this quasi-universal anguish. Toward the end of the century, spectacles appeared that were at once expressions and tentatives to remedy the period's epistemic malaise; among those spectacles the phantasmagoria, the panorama, and the diorama, all connected to the history of photography, figure prominently. In this dissertation I focus on the progressive build-up through the eighteenth century of the yearning for an accurate and truthful representation of the natural world that culminated in the 1839 invention of photography. Rather than seeing photography as the inevitable result of improved knowledge in the specific sciences of optics and chemistry, I consider that what else was needed to create the conditions of possibility for photography's invention was the 18th century's crisis of knowledge. A crisis that intensified as the Enlightenment's new order built on the strength of reason both threatened the traditional understanding of nature based on theology and introduced a new understanding of the fragility of the human mind and the uncertainty of perception, and hence anxiety around the question, "How do we trust what we see? How can we be certain of what we know?" If problems linked to the nature of knowledge drove the invention of photography, as soon as it was invented, photography split in a variety of practices sometime opposed to each others. Scientists forged ahead with using "objective" photography on one side, and artists coerced the medium for their own creative needs on the other. Thus, on its way to what it has become today, photography practices cancel or at least complicate the original intent; what some historians have perceived as photography's second invention. This "second invention" of photography is one we can understand if we consider that the 18th century was not only characterized by Reason's reign but also by philosophical speculation, the popularization of science, and mass entertainments that together exposed a wide segment of urban society to the unsettling tension between truth and skepticism. My dissertation thus seeks to reconnect 19th-century photographic practices with photography's pre-history, which was also very much concerned with the question of how to apprehend the world of solid objects given a growing understanding of a reflexive subject.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jonathan Sterne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f776s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rj520</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Mass Communications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612s75g"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Climate variability and leishmaniasis in Peru: an exploratory analysis of surveillance data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Findlater, Aidan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction: La température moyenne mondiale va augmenter de 0,2 º C dans la prochaine décennie. Les effets de cette hausse sur la santé humaine sont inconnus mais peuvent inclure une augmentation des populations des hôtes ou des vecteurs de maladies à transmission vectorielle. Cette étude a été entreprise pour évaluer l'effet qu'une variabilité de la température de la surface de la mer (TSM) aurait sur les cas de leishmaniose, une maladie à transmission vectorielle, au Pérou, ainsi que pour étudier les moyens de modéliser cette relation.Méthodes: L'incidence mensuelle de la leishmaniose cutanée ou cutanéo-muqueuse entre 2002 et 2008 a été combinée avec les anomalies de TSM de l'indice des régions El Niño 1 et 2 (ENI1+2) ou des stations côtières fixes de surveillance. Plusieurs modèles bayésiens ont été comparés en utilisant le critère d'information de déviance (DIC) comme mesure de la qualité de l'ajustement. Le décalage entre l'augmentation de TSM et la hausse ou la baisse de l'incidence de la leishmaniose a été choisi en minimisant le DIC.Résultats: Le modèle qui a donné le meilleur ajustement aux données était un modèle binomial négatif hiérarchique qui avait un terme de tendance linéaire et une fonction cosinus pour modéliser l'incidence de la maladie. Dans ce modèle, chaque degré Celsius au-dessus de la température prévue par les stations de surveillance de TSM donnait une augmentation de l'incidence nationale de la leishmaniose cutanée de 5% cinq mois plus tard (risque relatif 1,05; 95% CI 0,93 à 1,18); chaque degré Celsius au-dessus de la température prévue par ENI1+2 avait comme résultat une augmentation de l'incidence nationale de la leishmaniose cutanée de 26% six mois plus tard (risque relatif 1,26; 95% IC 1,18 à 1,35). Les estimations des effets régionaux variaient beaucoup plus dans le modèle qui utilisait les stations de TSM que dans le modèle basé sur ENI1+2. En général, les régions dans le nord-est avaient des risques relatifs plus élevés que celles du sud. Les résultats pour la leishmaniose cutanéo-muqueuse avaient des intervalles de confiance beaucoup plus larges, mais ils suivaient les mêmes tendances que ceux de la leishmaniose cutanée.Conclusions: Les modèles binomiaux négatifs hiérarchiques qui modèlent le caractère saisonnier de l'incidence avec une fonction cosinus fournissent une bonne qualité d'ajustement aux données de la leishmaniose. Nos résultats indiquent que le réchauffement régional peut contribuer à une augmentation de la transmission de la leishmaniose au Pérou.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introduction: Mean global temperature is expected to increase by 0.2ºC in the next decade. The human health impacts of this increase are uncertain, but may include increases in host or vector populations of vector-borne diseases. This study was undertaken to evaluate the effect of sea surface temperature (SST) variability on leishmaniasis cases, a vector-borne disease, in Peru, and to investigate ways of modelling the relationship. Methods: Monthly incidence of cutaneous and mucocutaneous leishmaniasis data by region for 2002-2008 was combined with SST anomaly data from either El Niño index regions 1 and 2 (ENI1+2) or from fixed coastal monitoring stations. Several Bayesian models were compared, using the deviance information criterion (DIC) as a measure of model fit. The lag between an increase in SST and the resulting increase or decrease in leishmaniasis incidence was chosen by minimizing the DIC. Results: The model that gave the best fit was a hierarchical negative binomial model that used a linear trend term and a cosine function to model the disease incidence. In this model, each degree Celsius above expected temperature of the SST monitoring stations led to an increase in the national incidence of cutaneous leishmaniasis of 5% five months later (risk ratio 1.05; 95% CI 0.93 to 1.18); each degree Celsius above expected temperature of ENI1+2 led to an increase in the national incidence of cutaneous leishmaniasis of 26% six months later (risk ratio 1.26; 95% CI 1.18 to 1.35). Department-specific estimates of effect varied much more in the SST station model than in the ENI1+2 model, and departments in the north-east showing generally higher risk ratios than those in the south. Results for mucocutaneous leishmaniasis had much wider confidence intervals, but followed the same overall patterns as cutaneous leishmaniasis. Conclusions: Hierarchical negative binomial models that model seasonality with a cosine function provide a good fit for leishmaniasis data. Our results indicate that regional warming may contribute to increased transmission of leishmaniasis in Peru.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Timothy Brewer</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Antonio Ciampi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623h69c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612s75g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g9049"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cognitive errors and coping patterns in Major Depressive Disorder and changes over the course of cognitive therapy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blake, Emily</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Major Depressive Disorder (MDD), affects up to 16.2% of adults (Kessler et al., 2003), and is associated with immense personal suffering, and decreases in functioning and well-being (Scott &amp; Sensky, 2003).  The most well researched psychological treatment for depression is cognitive therapy (CT), developed by Beck and colleagues (Beck et al., 1979). Integral to CT is that negative early life experiences may create latent cognitive vulnerabilities in the form of core beliefs.  Once activated by stressful events, these core beliefs may give rise to other forms of distorted cognitions such as dysfunctional attitudes, automatic thoughts, and cognitive errors, which reinforce depressive thinking and maintain symptoms of depression (Sacco &amp; Beck, 1995). Similarly, coping patterns may also amplify or reduce the impacts of stress (Skinner et al., 2003). As such, CT aims to treat depression by reducing cognitive distortions and increasing the use of adaptive coping patterns (Oei &amp; Free, 1995). Although the efficacy of CT has been well established (e.g., Dobson, 1989; Driessen &amp; Hollon, 2010; Lynch, Laws, &amp; McKenna, 2010), little is known about the mechanisms through which its successful results are achieved (Kazdin, 2007).  Few studies have examined the frequency and type of cognitive errors and coping patterns in depression, nor how these variables change over the course of CT.  In a series of three studies, this dissertation examined: 1. An early therapy profile of cognitive errors in depression, 2. Changes in cognitive errors from early to late cognitive therapy, 3. An early therapy profile of coping patterns in depression, and 4. Changes in coping patterns over the course of CT.  Implications for research and practice are discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les troubles dépressifs majeurs (TDM) affectent jusqu'à 16.2% de la population adulte (Kessler et al., 2003), infligent de la souffrance et diminuent les capacités et le bien-être des personnes affligées (Scott et Sensky, 2003). De nombreuses recherches ont été effectuées sur l'efficacité de la thérapie cognitivo-comportementale (TC) développée par Beck et ses collègues (Beck et al., 1979) pour le traitement de la dépression. Selon la théorie derrière la TC, les expériences négatives de l'enfance peuvent créer des vulnérabilités cognitives latentes sous la forme d'idées préconçues. Une fois activées par des événements stressants, ces idées préconçues peuvent donner naissance à d'autres problèmes cognitifs tels qu'une attitude dysfonctionnelle, de la pensée automatique et des erreurs cognitives qui renforcent l'état dépressif et maintiennent les symptômes de la dépression (Sacco et Beck, 1995). D'autre part, les stratégies d'évitement peuvent amplifier ou réduire les impacts du stress (Skinner et al., 2003). Conséquemment, la TC vise à traiter la dépression en réduisant les distorsions cognitives et en augmentant l'usage de stratégies adaptativs (Oei et Free, 1995). Même si l'efficacité de la TC est bien établie (e.g. Dobson, 1989; Driessen &amp; Hollon, 2010; Lynch, Laws, &amp; McKenna, 2010), les mécanismes d'action menant aux résultats positifs sont peu connus (Kazdin, 2007).  Peu d'études ont examiné la fréquence, le type d'erreurs cognitives et la transformation des stratégies d'évitement tout au long du traitement de la dépression ainsi que la façon que ces variables changent en cours de thérapie. Un traitement efficace ne devrait pas seulement faire disparaître les symptômes de la dépression mais aussi affecter les facteurs sous-jacents qui selon la théorie, mènent à la condition dépressive. Dans une série de trois études, cette dissertation a examiné les points suivants : 1.  Le profil d'erreurs cognitive au début de la thérapie, 2. Le changement dans les erreurs cognitives durant la thérapie, 3. Le profil de stratégies de coping au début du traitement et 4. Le changement dans  les stratégies de coping en cours de thérapie. Les implications pour la recherche et la pratique sont abordées.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Martin Drapeau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mk42k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g9049</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278z48k"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Segmental representations in interlanguage grammars: the case of francophones and English /h</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mah, Jennifer</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The concept that knowledge is transferred from a speaker's first language grammar into the interlanguage grammar being constructed for his second language makes testable predictions for how learners should behave given certain combinations of first and second language. This thesis examines the perceptual and productive abilities of francophones in order to gain insight into why francophones encounter such persistent difficulty in their acquisition of English /h/. We will see that although the target representation of English /h/ is not a structure that can be acquired by francophones, there are a number of representational options for the phonetic segment [h] that will yield the same acoustic result, and (at least) one of these is predicted to be acquirable. The observation that francophones do not seem to have access to any representation for this segment in the grammar these is therefore puzzling.The experimental work reported in this thesis begins by refuting the possibility that the acoustic properties of [h] are such that francophones cannot reliably detect this segment in the speech stream. We then go on to show that the problem is indeed a matter of linguistic representation in the grammar: francophones are unable to construct phonological representations containing /h/ in lexical entries. Finally, evidence from a production task is examined, showing that francophones' behaviour in supplying aspiration on voiceless stops matches the pattern that has been observed for suppliance of /h/, supporting the proposal of a common representational problem. Further, the acoustic properties of francophone productions of /h/ are examined and argued to shed light on the question of why alternate representations for /h/ are unavailable to the interlanguage grammar: it is argued that [h] is not being analyzed as a consonant, but as a partially devoiced vowel.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le concept du transfert de connaissances de la langue maternelle vers la grammaire construite lors de l'apprentissage d'une deuxième langue nous permet de prédire d'une manière vérifiable le développement des locuteurs apprenant une nouvelle langue, sachant quelle sont leur langue maternelle et la langue étant apprise. Cette thèse évalue les habiletés en perception et en production des francophones afin de comprendre pourquoi ceux-ci se retrouvent confrontés à de telles difficultés dans l'acquisition du /h/ anglais. Nous verrons que même si la représentation requise pour le /h/ anglais n'est pas possible pour les francophones, il existe d'autres représentations phonétiques pour le [h] qui auront le même effet acoustique, et (au moins) une de celles-ci devrait être possible. L'observation que les francophones ne peuvent utiliser aucune de ces représentations pour ce segment phonétique dans la grammaire est donc curieuse.Les expériences rapportées dans cette thèse commencent par réfuter la possibilité que les propriétés acoustiques du [h] sont telles que les francophones ne peuvent pas le détecter dans la parole d'une manière fiable. Ensuite, nous démontrons qu'il s'agit d'un problème de représentation linguistique dans la grammaire: les francophones ne peuvent pas construire des entrées lexicales contenant des représentations phonologiques avec le /h/. Finalement, nous examinons les productions des francophones, où les résultats démontrent que la production de l'aspiration des occlusives sourdes est identique à la production observée du /h/, soutenant la proposition d'un seul problème de représentation pour ces troubles. De plus, nous examinons les propriétés acoustiques de la production du /h/ par les francophones, et nous proposons que ceux-ci peuvent aider à expliquer pourquoi toutes les autres représentations possibles semblent ne pas être disponibles à la grammaire de l'apprenant: on soutient que le [h] n'est pas analysé en tant que consonne, mais en tant que voyelle partiellement muette.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Heather Goad</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524js89r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278z48k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Language - Linguistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6q182q31j"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Towards a deeper understanding of epistemic beliefs development: the contribution of threshold concepts and implications for understanding the ways of knowing and being of experienced educational developers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Timmermans, Julie Anita</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In education, the term "development" is used in many contexts.  For example, we refer to the "development of student learning," the "development of epistemic beliefs," and the "development of expertise."  The term "development" is also central to our identity and work as educational developers.  The frequent use of this term suggests a commonly agreed-upon understanding; however, closer analysis reveals that the definition of this term remains vague.  Drawing on literature in the areas of epistemic beliefs and threshold concepts, this dissertation intends to elucidate the notion of development by exploring what development is and how it happens.  Insights from this research are then used to examine the transformation of educational developers' ways of knowing and being and to explore the meaning of development in educational development. The dissertation consists of three manuscripts.  The purpose of Manuscript 1 is to propose an explanation of epistemic beliefs development. Understanding epistemic development is crucial, for epistemic beliefs shape the perspectives from which we make meaning of the world (Kegan, 1982; 1994; 2000).  Drawing on Kegan's Constructive-Developmental Theory of Meaning-Making, as well as research in biology, philosophy, and psychology, this manuscript identifies the principles of development that underlie and thereby unify these fields.  In proposing an explanation of epistemic beliefs development, the manuscript contributes to the current endeavour in the field to elaborate an integrative model of epistemic beliefs development. Manuscript 2 pursues the purpose of the dissertation of gaining a better understanding of development by using threshold concepts (Meyer &amp; Land, 2003) as a lens for clarifying the little-understood issue of how the development of epistemic beliefs proceeds between stages. Understanding the process of transformation between stages is vital for educators, since this is where much of our work with learners occurs.  The characteristics often used to describe threshold concepts reveal their potential to contribute to the development of epistemic beliefs; however, threshold concepts have hitherto not been situated within a developmental framework.  By relating the principles of development explored in Manuscript 1 to the characteristics of threshold concepts, this manuscript proposes threshold concepts as potentially powerful sources of epistemic beliefs development and clarifies the cognitive and affective nature of transformation between stages.  Implications for educators' role of facilitating learning are also explored.  Manuscript 3 is the report of a multiple case study designed to identify threshold concepts in educational development.  As there is currently a collective effort in the field of educational development to conceptualise the identity and roles of educational developers, threshold concepts are used as a lens for uncovering the ways of knowing and ways of being of educational developers.  Semi-structured interviews with four experienced educational developers from Canadian universities were conducted to identify the ideas that have been threshold concepts for them in their careers as educational developers.  A cross-case analysis of threshold concepts identified within each case revealed three categories of common threshold concepts: (a) Ways of Knowing and Being that Facilitate Change in Individuals and in Groups, (b) Ways of Knowing and Being that Facilitate Systemic Change, and (c) Ways of Knowing and Being of Professionals. The dissertation conclusion summarises and weaves together findings from the three manuscripts.  A model capturing the salient insights about development that emerged from this research is presented.  These insights are then related to the threshold concepts identified by experienced educational developers in Manuscript 3 in an effort to explore the meaning of development in educational development.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>En éducation, le terme «développement» est utilisé dans plusieurs contextes. On réfère au développement des apprentissages de l'étudiant, au développement des croyances épistémiques, et au développement de l'expertise. Le terme «développement» est également primordial à l'identité et au travail des conseillers pédagogiques. Le fréquent usage de ce terme suggère une compréhension communément convenue; des analyses révèlent toutefois que la définition demeure vague. S'appuyant sur la recherche dans les domaines des croyances épistémiques et des concepts seuils, cette thèse a pour but de clarifier la notion de développement en explorant ce qu'est le développement et comment il se déroule. Les fruits de cette recherche sont utilisés pour examiner la transformation des façons d'être et de connaître des conseillers pédagogiques et pour explorer la signification du développement dans le domaine du soutien pédagogique. La thèse contient trois manuscrits. Le but du manuscrit 1 est de proposer une explication du développement des croyances épistémiques. Comprendre le développement épistémique est crucial, car les croyances épistémiques façonnent les perspectives par lesquelles nous donnons sens au monde. S'appuyant sur la théorie constructive-développementale de Kegan concernant la construction du sens, ainsi que sur les recherches en biologie, philosophie, et psychologie, les principes du développement unifiant ces domaines sont identifiés. En proposant une explication du développement des croyances épistémiques, ce manuscrit contribue aux études visant l'élaboration d'un modèle intégratif du développement des croyances épistémiques. Le manuscrit 2 utilise les concepts seuils pour clarifier la façon dont se déroule le développement des croyances épistémiques entre les stades. Comprendre le processus de transformation entre les stades est indispensable pour les éducateurs, puisque c'est ici que la plus grande part du travail avec les apprenants s'accomplit. Les caractéristiques souvent utilisées pour décrire les concepts seuils révèlent leur potentiel à contribuer au développement des croyances épistémiques; cependant, les concepts seuils n'ont pas, jusqu'à présent, été situés dans un cadre développemental.  En rapportant les connaissances acquises dans le manuscrit 1 concernant les principes de développement aux caractéristiques des concepts seuils, ce document propose les concepts seuils comme source potentielle solide dans le développement des croyances épistémiques.  Ce travail précise également la nature cognitive et affective de la transformation entre les stades du développement. Les implications concernant le rôle des éducateurs à la facilitation de l'apprentissage sont explorées. Le manuscrit 3 rapporte une étude de cas multiples élaborée dans le but d'identifier les concepts seuils présents en soutien pédagogique. Comme il y a actuellement un effort commun dans le domaine pour conceptualiser l'identité et les rôles des conseillers pédagogiques, les concepts seuils ont été utilisés pour découvrir les manières d'être et de connaître des conseillers pédagogiques. Des entrevues semi-structurées ont été menées auprès de quatre conseillers pédagogiques expérimentés provenant d'universités canadiennes afin d'identifier les idées qui ont été des concepts seuils dans leurs carrières comme conseillers pédagogiques. Une analyse transversale a révélé trois catégories de concepts seuils communs portant sur les manières d'être et de connaître (a) facilitant le changement chez les individus et les groupes, (b) facilitant le changement systémique, et (c) professionnelles. La conclusion résume et établie un lien entre les trois manuscrits. Un modèle proposant les idées saillantes sur le développement est présenté. Ces idées sont mises en relation avec les concepts seuils proposés par les conseillers pédagogiques expérimentés dans le manuscrit 3, ce qui permet d'explorer la signification du développement dans le domaine du soutien pédagogique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cynthia B. Weston</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nj85s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182q31j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axp68km248"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The perception and production of interdental fricatives in second language acquisition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brannen, Kathleen Joan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette dissertation explore la substitution différentielle des fricatives interdentales par les apprenants de l'anglais langue seconde. La substitution différentielle se produit quand les apprenants dont la langue maternelle (L1) ne contient pas ces sons, substituent ces phonèmes par un autre. Dépendamment de la L1, la substitution se fait avec [t,d], [s,z] ou [f,v]. Au cours des années, plusieurs propositions ont été émises pour expliquer ce phénomène. Ces hypothèses reposent principalement sur les différences structurelles des systèmes phonémiques de diverses langues. Cette thèse examine la substitution de [θ,ð] par des locuteurs de différentes langues ou dialectes, à savoir: le japonais, le russe, le français européen, et le français québécois. Le japonais et le français européen sont caractérisés par les substituts [s,z], tandis que pour le français québécois et le russe, par [t,d]. Puisque le français européen et le français québécois ont le même inventaire contrastif de segments obstruants, cette dissertation explore la contribution de l'information non-contrastive à la substitution des interdentales, de la perspective de la perception et de la production. Il est proposé que la perception sous-tend la production de telle manière que les erreurs observées dans la production correspondent aux sons substitués au niveau de la perception. De plus, il est considéré que les traits non-contrastifs jouent un rôle déterminant dans le transfert. Spécifiquement, il est proposé que le trait STRIDENT est central au choix de substituts pour les interdentales. Pour expliquer comment les apprenants des langues secondes projettent les sons cibles sur leur représentation interne dans la perception, le modèle de distance auditoire est développé. Ce modèle est basé sur les hypothèses suivantes: à la phase initiale de l'acquisition, les apprenants ont potentiellement accès à tous les traits phonétiques fournis par la grammaire universelle. Cependant, cet ensemble de traits est limité à l'inventaire phonétique de la langue spécifique. Ainsi, l'absence de traits ou de combinaisons spécifiques de traits dans la grammaire de la langue maternelle force l'apprenant à choisir parmi les sons de sa L1 ceux qui sont phonétiquement les plus proches. Ceci est accompli via un algorithme qui évalue la correspondance entre les traits cibles et ceux de la L1 ainsi que leur poids relatifs. Le poids d'un trait peut être augmenté s'il se trouve dans une relation de rehaussement avec un autre trait. Les traits rehaussés sont préférables, mais pas obligatoires, dans les systèmes linguistiques. Alors la variation phonétique et inter-linguistique de même que la diversité dans le poids des traits qui résulte, sont les facteurs qui déterminent la substitution différentielle dans la perception et de là, dans la production. Ces hypothèses sont vérifiées empiriquement dans cinq études. Les deux premières, AXB-1 et AXB-2, ont été construites pour capter le traitement phonétique et phonémique dans des conditions distinctes pour démontrer que les réflexes de la substitution différentielle émergent dans le traitement phonétique et non phonémique. La troisième, l'identification d'image, examine le traitement phonémique. Les deux dernières études analysent la production. Les résultats d'une de ces dernières, une tâche sur la production de mots, sont comparés avec les résultats des analyses de la perception. L'autre consiste en une analyse spectrographique de la fricative coronale [s] de la L1 pour déterminer à quel degré le trait STRIDENT est manifesté acoustiquement pour chacune des langues. En général, les résultats de ces études appuient les hypothèses décrites ci-haut. Pour rendre compte des quelques divergences entre les prédictions et les résultats, la discussion aborde le rôle de l'information visuelle dans les représentations lexicales et la possibilité de la distorsion induite par la tâche.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This dissertation investigates the differential substitution of interdental fricatives ([θ,ð]) by learners of English as a second language. Differential substitution (or transfer) occurs when learners whose native language does not include the "th" sounds, substitute different segments in their place, depending on the particular L1: [t,d], [s,z], or [f,v]. Throughout the past 50 years, various proposals have been forwarded to explain this phenomenon. The majority of these approaches have focussed on structural differences within the contrastive phonemic systems of various languages. This thesis examines two languages and two dialects of the same language: Japanese, Russian, European French, and Québec French. Japanese and European French are known to substitute [s,z] in place of [θ,ð], while for Québec French and Russian, [t,d] are reported. Since European and Québec French arguably have the same phonemic inventory of obstruents, this thesis explores the function of non-contrastive phonetic information in interdental substitution, in both perception and production. It is hypothesized that perception underlies production, such that those errors observed in production will be the sounds that are apt to be perceptually associated with the target. Furthermore, it is considered that non-contrastive features play a determining role in segmental transfer. In particular, the feature STRIDENT is hypothesized to be key in the choice of interdental substitute. To account for how second language learners perceptually map target sounds to their internal representations, the Auditory Distance Model is developed. This model is based upon the following hypotheses. In the initial state of acquisition, learners potentially have access to all phonetic features provided by Universal Grammar. However, availability of this universal set of features is limited by the language-specific phonetic inventory, such that the absence of features or particular combinations of features in the L1 grammar forces the L2 learner to choose from among the phonetically closest L1 sounds. The selection process is implemented via the Auditory Distance Algorithm which compares the target intake features with those encoded on L1 segments. The Algorithm evaluates whether the intake and L1 features constitute matches or mis-matches and additionally calculates their relative weight. A feature's weight can be augmented if it stands in an enhancement relation with another feature. Enhanced features are preferred, but not mandatory, in linguistic systems. Thus cross-linguistic phonetic variation and the resulting diversity in feature weight is what determines differential substitution in perception and hence in production. These hypotheses are empirically verified in five studies. The first two, the AXB-1 and AXB-2 perception tasks, were designed to tap phonetic and phonemic processing in separate conditions to demonstrate that the observed patterns of differential substitution emerge in phonetic, but not phonemic processing. The third perception experiment, Picture Identification, examines phonemic processing. The final studies analyze production. The results of one, a Word Production task, are compared with the perception findings. The other involves a Spectrographic Analysis of the L1 coronal fricative [s] to determine the degree to which the feature STRIDENT is acoustically manifested for each of the languages.The results from these studies largely support the hypotheses outlined above. To account for discrepancies between predictions and results, the role of visual information in lexical representations and the possibility of task-induced bias are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Heather Goad</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wh64w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68km248</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Language - Linguistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85ng27q"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Positive emotions in psychotherapy: an exploratory study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marini, Nadia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les émotions et le traitement des émotions sont considérés comme d'importants processus de changement en vertu de nombreuses modalités thérapeutiques, mais l'expérience d'émotions positives a rarement été étudiée dans un cadre thérapeutique.  Dans son modèle broaden-and-build (élargissement et construction), Barbara Fredrickson (2001) avance que les émotions positives suscitent un élargissement momentané de la pensée par l'expansion du champ cognitif et des actions possibles.  La présente étude portait sur les émotions positives et l'élargissement dans un cadre thérapeutique.  L'objectif principal de cette étude fondée sur une méthodologie exploratoire axée sur la découverte était de déterminer l'issue d'une thérapie lorsque les clients faisaient l'expérience d'émotions positives.  Les séances de thérapies ont été soumises à une analyse des tâches (une méthode qualitative visant à décomposer le changement thérapeutique étape par étape) et à une série d'analyses exploratoires.  Les clients étaient des étudiants au premier cycle inscrits à un cours de counseling qui se sont portés volontaires pour suivre une thérapie auprès d'étudiants de première année à la maîtrise en psychothérapie.  Dans le cadre de brèves entrevues rétrospectives, douze clients ont été invités à rendre compte de leur expérience d'émotions positives et à préciser les moments où sont survenues ces émotions au cours de la séance.  Les entrevues ont été soumises à une analyse phénoménologique dont les résultats ont servi à valider les données de l'analyse des tâches.  Deux ensembles d'épisodes émotionnels ont été comparés : un ensemble comportant l'expérience d'un nouvel accomplissement par le client (c.-à-d. une expérience émotionnelle, de compréhension ou de perspective intérieure) et un ensemble n'en comportant aucun.  Les résultats de l'analyse des tâches n'ont pas été concluants, mais la série d'analyses exploratoires s'est traduite par de nombreux résultats probants en lien avec les émotions positives et l'élargissement.  Ainsi, avant et après les émotions positives, les clients ont connu un élargissement du traitement cognitif.  En outre, les épisodes émotionnels comportant un nouvel accomplissement étaient associés à un nombre supérieur de codes de processus et à un élargissement plus étoffé comparativement aux épisodes qui n'en comportaient aucun.  Aucune émotion spécifique ne caractérisait les cas comportant un nouvel accomplissement par rapport aux autres.  Un élargissement étoffé précédait le nouvel accomplissement, tandis qu'aucune relation entre émotion positive et nouvel accomplissement n'a été établie.  L'analyse phénoménologique des entrevues avec les clients a permis de valider les résultats, c'est-à-dire que les émotions positives ont favorisé la bonne disposition du client à l'égard de sa démarche exploratoire, stimulé sa motivation à travailler en vue d'atteindre ses objectifs et augmenté sa confiance et son enthousiasme.  Globalement, les résultats commencent à démontrer l'utilité de la phénoménologie clinique des émotions positives dans un cadre thérapeutique.  Porter attention aux émotions positives pourrait favoriser des processus thérapeutiques fructueux.  La sélection d'outils d'évaluation du traitement cognitif des clients fait partie des implications pour la recherche.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Emotion and emotional processing are recognized as important change processes across therapeutic modalities but positive emotional experiences have rarely been studied in therapy.  In her Broaden-and-Build model of positive emotions, Barbara Fredrickson (2001) theorized that positive emotions momentarily broaden thinking by expanding the range of thoughts and potential action.  This study explored positive emotions and broadening in therapy.  The primary objective was to examine what happens in therapy when clients experience positive emotion, using a discovery-oriented, exploratory methodology.  Task analysis, a qualitative method that identifies components of moment-by-moment therapeutic change, and a series of exploratory analyses were used to study therapy sessions.  Clients were students enrolled in an undergraduate counselling course who volunteered for therapy with first-year Master's student therapists.  Brief-structured recall interviews were conducted with 12 clients to report how they experienced positive emotion and to locate the experiences in the sessions.  Interviews were subjected to a phenomenological analysis and the resulting data was used to validate the task analytic data.  Two groups of emotion episodes were compared: one group containing a new performance (i.e., understanding, insight, or emotional experience) and one group where clients had no new performance.  While the results of the task analysis per se were inconclusive, the series of exploratory analyses had several findings that related positive emotions and broadening.  Preceding and following positive emotion, clients engaged in broadened cognitive processing.  The emotion episodes containing a new performance had a greater number of process codes and demonstrated more differentiated broadening compared to those with no new performance.  Differentiated broadening preceded new performance, while no pattern between positive emotion and new performance was found.  No specific positive emotion distinguished new performance and no new performance cases.  The phenomenological analysis of client interviews validated the finding that positive emotion helped clients to be more open and willing to explore, more motivated to work on goals, and more confident and energized.  Overall, the findings begin to illustrate the clinical phenomenology of positive emotions in therapy.  Actively attending to positive emotions can potentially generate productive therapeutic processes.  Research implications include selecting instruments that measure clients' cognitive processing. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marilyn R. Fitzpatrick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920g184d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85ng27q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692tb426"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hardware-based temporal logic checkers for the debugging of digital integrated circuits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chenard, Jean-Samuel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La complexité des circuits intégrés augmente sans cesse et à un tel point que le procéssus de déboggage pose de nombreux problèmes techniques et engendre des retards dans la production. Une approche d'ensemble de conception pour le déboggage (Design-for-Debug) devient donc rapidement une nécessité.  Cette thèse propose une approche détaillée de niveau système, intégrant des circuits de surveillance sur puce. L'approche proposée s'appuie sur la réutilisation de déclarations écrites en language de logique temporelle afin de les transformer en circuits digitaux efficaces.  Ces derniers seront intégrés à la puce à travers son interface d'image mémoire afin qu'ils puissent servir au processus de déboggage ainsi qu'à une utilisation dans le système lorsque la puce est intégrée dans son environement. Cette thèse présente une série d'ajout au procéssus de transformation d'instructions de logique temporelle de manière à faciliter le procéssus de déboggage. Une méthode qui automatise l'intégration des sorties et du contrôle des circuits de surveillance est présentée ainsi que la manière dont une utilisation de ces circuits peut être accomplie dans le contexte d'un système d'exploitation moderne (Linux). Finalement, une méthode globale d'intégration des circuits de vérification dans le contexte de systèmes basés sur les réseaux-sur-puce est présentée, accompagnée de la chaine d'outils requise pour supporter ce nouveau processus de conception. Cette méthode propose l'utilisation de facteurs de qualité de test, de surveillance et de déboggage (Test, Monitoring and Debug) permettant une meilleure sélection des circuits ainsi qu'une intégration plus efficace au niveau des resources matérielles.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Integrated circuit complexity is ever increasing and the debug process of modern devices pose important technical challenges and cause delays in production. A comprehensive Design-for-Debug methodology is therefore rapidly becoming a necessity.  This thesis presents a comprehensive system-level approach to debugging based on insilicon hardware checkers. The proposed approach leverages existing assertion-based verification libraries by translating useful temporal logic statements into efficient hardware circuits. Those checker circuits are then integrated in the device as part of the memory map, so they can provide on-line monitoring and debug assistance in addition to accelerating the integration of performance monitoring counters. The thesis presents a set of enhancements to the translation process from temporal language to hardware, targeted such that an eventual debug process is made more efficient. Automating the integration of the checker's output and control structures is covered along with a practical method that allow transparent access to the resulting registers within a modern (Linux) operating system. Finally, a method of integration of the hardware checkers in future Network-on-Chip systems is proposed. The use of a quality metric encompassing test, monitoring and debug considerations is defined along with the necessary tool flow required to support theprocess.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zeljko Zilic</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526h359.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692tb426</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bt443"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of teachers' pedagogical and subject-matter knowledge in planning and enacting science-inquiry instruction and in assessing students' science-inquiry learning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Birlean, Camelia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude a exploré la relation entre les connaissances pédagogiques et disciplinaires, dans le contexte de l'approche par investigation du processus d'enseignement des sciences et leur relation avec la performance des enseignants dans le processus d'enseignement.Cette recherche s'est concentrée sur trois catégories distinctes d'enseignants: le Pédagogue Apprenti-le Scientifique Apprenti, le Pédagogue Apprenti-le Scientifique Expert et le Pédagogue Expert-le Scientifique Expert; elle examine leurs ressemblances et leurs différences, tout en explorant les processus cognitifs que ces enseignants ont utilisés durant la planification et le déroulement de la situation d'enseignement investigatif.La démarche par investigation a varié à travers ces catégories de participants, en allant de très structurée à très ouverte.  L'approche scientifique du participant Apprenti-Apprenti était prédominant traditionnelle.  Au contraire, l'approche scientifique de l'Expert-Expert et de l'Apprenti-Expert ont mis l'emphase sur la stratégie d'investigation qui variait de structurée à plus ouverte.  L'investigation ouverte était une approche utilisée seulement par l'Expert-Expert durant la classe de recherche des sciences avancées, en mettant l'accent sur l'aspect créatif de la génération des problèmes.L'Expert-Expert s'est distingué de deux autres participants par son point de vue sur la planification, qui met en évidence l'aspect dynamique et flexible de ce processus d'enseignement.  L'Expert-Expert a identifié la planification occasionnelle, laquelle comprend la planification des habilités et des contenus spécifiques et critiques pour le processus d'apprentissage des élèves pendant ces investigations indépendants.  La performance observée des trois participants était partiellement reflétée dans leur planification; l'alignement était moins fréquent pour ce qui est de l'Apprenti-Apprenti.L'évaluation des projets basés sur l'approche par investigation a varié d'un participant à l'autre.  Chaque participant a évalué une série de trois projets de science basés sur l'approche par investigation, projets qui étaient différents en ce qui concerne la qualité et cette variation a augmenté quand les projets ont été comparés entre les participants.Les projets de science basés sur l'investigation ont varié selon le degré de complexité, l'originalité de la problématique et la méthode d'investigation.  Les projets issus de l'enseignement de l'Expert-Expert ont été supérieurs du point de vue de la qualité et comparaison avec ceux évalués par les participants Apprenti-Expert et Apprenti-Apprenti.  De plus, ces projets basés sur l'investigation ont été les seuls projets qui ont rencontré les critères de l'originalité.Le modèle du processus d'enseignement du participant Expert-Expert décrit dans cette recherche représente le début d'un modèle d'alignement d'approche d'investigation dans lequel la planification, le déroulement de la planification et l'évaluation ont été examinés comme trois processus inter-liés qui se renseignent et se complètent.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This study explored the relation between pedagogical knowledge and subject-matter knowledge, in the context of inquiry-driven science instruction, and their relation to instructors' performance in the instructional process.  This multiple case study focused on three distinct categories of teachers--Novice in Inquiry and in Science, Novice in Inquiry and Expert in Science, and Expert in Inquiry and in Science--and examined the commonalities and differences among them by exploring the cognitive processes these teachers used when planning and enacting an inquiry instructional situation, as well as when assessing students' learning resulting from this specific instructional event. Inquiry instruction varied across cases from largely structured to largely open.  The Novice-Novice's science instruction, predominantly traditional in the approach, differed greatly from that of the Expert-Expert and of the Novice-Expert.  The latter two emphasized--to various extents structured, guided, and open--inquiry strategy as part of their ongoing instruction.  The open inquiry was an approach embraced solely by the Expert-Expert teacher throughout the Advanced Science Research instruction, emphasizing the creative aspect of problem generation.  Edward teacher also distinguished himself from the other two participants in his view of planning and terminology used to describe it, both of which emphasized the dynamic and flexible feature of this instructional process.  The Expert-Expert identified occasional planning, planning of specific skills and content critical to students' learning process during their independent inquiry.  The observed teaching performance of the three participants partly reflected their planning; the alignment was least frequent for the Novice-Novice.The assessment of inquiry-based projects varied greatly across participants.  Each teacher participant evaluated a set of three inquiry-based science projects that differed in their quality, and this variation increased when the inquiry-based projects were compared across participants.  The inquiry-based science projects varied in their degree of complexity, sophistication, originality of the topic, and method of investigation.  The projects originating from Edward teacher's instruction were qualitatively superior to those assessed by the Novice-Expert and Novice-Novice teachers.  In addition, these inquiry-based projects were the only projects that addressed the criterion of originality. The instructional model depicted within the Expert-Expert teacher's case provide the beginning of a model of instructional alignment in which planning, teaching, and assessing are examined as three interconnected processes that mutually informed and continuously enhance each other.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bruce M. Shore</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jz54v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bt443</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Curriculum and Instruction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236639n"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Standardization and internal validation of a bacteria identification method utilizing focal-plane-array fourier transformed infrared spectroscopy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carranza Masso, Laura Carolina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Food-borne diseases collectively affect significant portions of the world's population. In Canada recent food-borne outbreaks and diseases resulted in significant expenses and resource allocations. Consequently, finding methods that can detect and identify microorganisms in faster, reliable and cost effective ways is a pressing need. Microbial identification methods based on the infrared spectral analysis of microorganisms have been shown to be potentially viable. The recent development of focal plane array Fourier transform infrared (FPA-FTIR) spectroscopy provided the means of acquiring thousands of infrared spectra in the time it takes to record a single spectrum. The increased number of infrared spectra of each organism provides infrared-based microbial differentiation and identification methods with added reliability. Accordingly, we generated a comprehensive standardized and internally validated the FPA-FTIR based bacteria identification method. All infrared spectra were collected from bacterial colonies, lifted from agar and deposited on zinc selenide (ZnSe) slides, on a Agilent Excalibur FTIR spectrometer equipped with a UMA-600 infrared microscope and a 32 x 32 (1024 pixels) mercury-cadmium-telluride focal-plane-array detector and operated under Resolutions Pro 4.0 software (Agilent Technologies, Melbourne, Australia). The effect of growth media formulations, growth time and inactivation techniques on the spectral reproducibility of microorganism was tested. Most of these variables showed some degree of influence on spectral variability, therefore a single combination of these was recommended in the form of a laboratory protocol for consistent microbial preparations. This enabled the construction of a comprehensive spectral database including spectra from 180 different microbial strains. The FPA-FTIR based method was assessed for the discrimination of Campylobacter jejuni and C. coli isolated from poultry. The method was also evaluated as a tool for the identification of Escherichia coli and Listeria monocytogenes strains isolated from deliberately inoculated food matrices. In all cases identification of bacteria based on their FPA-FTIR spectra was highly reliable and comparable to standard methods of bacteria identification; provided that the unknown bacteria samples and reference strains were prepared in a consistent manner, and that appropriate spectral databases were employed. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les maladies d'origine alimentaire affectent une proportion significative de la population mondiale. Au Canada, les cas récents d'éclosions d'intoxications alimentaires et de maladies d'origine alimentaire ont eu des conséquences significatives en termes de dépenses et d'utilisation de ressources. Pour cette raison, développer des méthodes permettant la détection et l'identification de micro-organismes de manière fiable, rentable et plus rapide, s'avère une nécessité urgente. Les méthodes d'identification microbienne basées sur l'analyse spectrale infrarouge des micro-organismes apparaissent potentiellement viables. Le développement récent de la spectroscopie infrarouge à transformée de Fourier couplée à un détecteur de type « matrice à plan focal » (FPA-FTIR) à balayage rapide, a permis d'acquérir, dans le temps préalablement requis pour un seul spectre, des milliers de spectres infrarouges à être enregistrés. L'augmentation du nombre de spectres infrarouge pour chaque organisme accroît la fiabilité des méthodes de différentiation et d'identification microbiennes basées sur l'infrarouge. En conséquence, nous avons élaboré une méthode standardisée et validée à l'interne d'identification des bactéries basée sur la méthode FPA-FTIR. Tous les spectres infrarouges ont été collectés à partir de colonies bactériennes, prises sur l'agar et déposées sur des glissières de séléniure de zinc (ZnSe), grâce à un spectromètre d'Agilent Excalibur FTIR équipé d'un microscope UMA-600 infrarouge et d'un détecteur type « matrice à plan focal » de mercure-cadmium-tellurure 32 x 32 (1024 pixels) et opéré par le logiciel Resolutions Pro 4.0 (Agilent Technologies, Melbourne, Australie). L'effet des formulations de milieu de croissance, des temps de croissance et des techniques d'inactivation sur la reproductibilité spectrale des micro-organismes a été examiné. La plupart de ces variables ont montré un certain degré d'influence sur la variabilité spectrale, de sorte qu'une combinaison spécifique de ces dernières a été recommandée dans un protocole de laboratoire afin d'obtenir des préparations microbiennes constantes. Ceci a permis la construction d'une base de données spectrales complète comprenant des spectres de 180 souches microbiennes différentes. La méthode FPA-FTIR a été évaluée pour la discrimination de Campylobacter jejuni et C. coli, isolés à partir de volailles. La méthode a été également évaluée comme un outil d'identification de souches d'Escherichia coli et de Listeria monocytogenes isolés à partir d'aliments ou de matrices alimentaires inoculées délibérément. Dans tous les cas, l'identification des bactéries à partir de leurs spectres FPA-FTIR s'est avérée d'une grande fiabilité et comparable aux méthodes standards d'identification de bactéries, à condition que les échantillons de bactéries inconnues et les souches de référence aient été préparés d'une façon systématique et que des bases de données spectrales appropriées aient été utilisées. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ashraf A. Ismail</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c464g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236639n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816r685"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mapping the carnival: conceptions of public safety in conservative prison policy and in the work of prison abolition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Strauss, Catherine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis I examine a punitive moment in Canadian corrections policy and practice that began in 2006 with the Conservative Party's election to office. I consider this moment through its founding policy document, A Roadmap to Strengthening Public Safety. The Roadmap's key punitive arguments are based in its construction of a Changing Offender Profile, a term that draws upon the archetypal colonial constructions of the lawless Native offender and the law-abiding Canadian national. These constructions still inform dominant notions of 'prisoner' and 'public' today. In contrast, the political theatre piece Parole Sans Parole rejects the neoliberal citizen-making project of both the Roadmap and parole policies. It reverses positions of power through techniques of the carnival, linking the physical and political safety of the non-incarcerated to the safety of the incarcerated. This performance strategy radically alters the position of the public in relation to the lives of prisoners and parolees and the issues they face in the current state of Canadian imprisonment.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans ce mémoire j'examine une période punitive de la politique correctionnelle Canadienne qui a débuté en 2006 lorsque le Parti Conservateur a été porté au pouvoir. J'étudie cette période par le biais de son document politique fondateur, La Feuille de route pour une sécurité publique accrue. Les argumentspunitifs clé de la Feuille de route sont basés sur sa construction du concept de « profil de contrevenant en pleine évolution », une idée qui tire ses sources des archétypes colonialistes du contrevenant amérindien hors-la-loi et du citoyen canadien profondément respectueux de la loi. Aujourd'hui, ces constructionscontinuent à influencer les notions dominantes de ce qu'est un « prisonnier » ou un « public ». En opposition avec cette vision, la pièce de théâtre politique Parole Sans Parole rejette le projet néo-libéral de créer le citoyen idéal, projet qui sous-tend la Feuille de route et les politiques de mise en libération conditionnelle. La pièce utilise des techniques du carnavalèsque pour renverser les positions de pouvoir et montre que la sécurité physique et politique des personnes en liberté est étroitement liée à la sécurité des personnes incarcérées. Cette stratégie théâtrale transforme radicalement la position du public en rapport avec la vie des personnes détenues et placées en libération conditionnelle et les enjeux auxquels elles sont confrontées dans l'état actuel du système carcéral canadien.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carrie Rentschler</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dx54v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816r685</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Mass Communications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537526z"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An efficient radial basis function mesh deformation scheme within an adjoint-based aerodynamic optimization framework</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poirier, Vincent</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les méthodes de déformation de maillage jouent un rôle important dans le domaine d'optimisation numérique aérodynamique. Lorsqu'une géométrie aérodynamique change de forme pendant l'optimisation, le maillage doit s'adapter pour assurer qu'il se conforme bien à la nouvelle géométrie. Cette thèse présente l'extension d'une méthode de déformation de maillage à base de fonctions basiques radiales(RBF). La rapidité de l'algorithme RBF peut être améliorée en utilisant un sous-ensemble de points à la surface de la géométrie pour gouverner la déformation du maillage. Par contre, cela introduit des erreurs dans la paramétrisation de la géométrie puisque les déplacements de tous les point de surface ne seront pas correctement récupérés. Ainsi, cette thèse propose l'utilisation d'une deuxième méthode de déformation de maillage afin d'ajuster le déplacement des points de surface pour bien récupérer la nouvelle géométrie modifiée. La méthode adjointe est employée dans le cadre d'analyse 3D d'écoulement de fluide Euler. La méthode proposée de déformation de maillage est validée en l'appliquant à l'optimisation de la trainée d'un Boeing-747 et d'une aile Onera-M6. Aussi, un cas de design qui récupère une distribution spécifique de pression statique est exécuté pour l'aile Onera-M6.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Mesh deformation schemes play an important role in numerical aerodynamic optimization. As the aerodynamic shape changes, the computational mesh must adapt to conform to the deformed geometry. In this work, an extension to an existing fast and robust Radial Basis Function (RBF) mesh movement scheme is presented. Using a reduced set of surface points to define the mesh deformation increases the efficiency of the RBF method; however, at the cost of introducing errors into the parameterization by not recovering the exact displacement of all surface points. A secondary mesh movement is implemented, within an adjoint-based optimization framework, to eliminate these errors. The proposed scheme is tested within a 3D Euler flow by reducing the pressure drag while maintaining lift of a wing-body configured Boeing-747 and an Onera-M6 wing. As well, an inverse pressure design is executed on the Onera-M6 wing and an inverse span loading case is presented for a wing-body configured DLR-F6 aircraft.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sivakumaran Nadarajah</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v977p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537526z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8336h573r"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Emerging academic identities : how education PhD students experience the doctorate</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martek, Marian Jazvac</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose ofthis qualitative, multi-case, and longitudinal study was to examine how doctoral students’ experiences of the doctorate influence their emerging academic identities. The development of academic identities is often alluded to in higher education research as the heart of the doctoral pursuit. There is, however, little information on how the activities of the doctorate, particularly everyday student experiences, contribute to the emergence of academic identities. The guiding framework for this study was a social-psychological role identity perspective, blended with elements of Activity Theory. Through this combined view, identity is constructed through and embedded in interpersonal relationships, with identity emerging as a property of interactions with others. Data for the study were collected over a two year period. Nine Education doctoral students participated by tracking their experiences for a particular week every month across four academic semesters (15 months) and then discussed these in interviews at the end of each year. These students were selected from a larger sample based on their explicit aim to pursue academic careers upon completion of their degrees. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette étude de cas multiples, à la fois qualitative et longitudinale, a permis d’examiner chez des doctorants comment l’expérience au quotidien de leur programme d’études influençait l’émergence d’une identité universitaire. Dans le domaine des recherches portant sur l’enseignement supérieur, on réfère souvent au développement d’une identité universitaire comme étant au coeur même de l’expérience doctorale. Il existe toutefois peu d’informations qui précisent comment les activités inhérentes au doctorat, notamment les expériences vécues au quotidien par les doctorants, contribuent à l’émergence de cette identité universitaire. Le cadre d’analyse de cette recherche s’est élaboré autour d’une perspective socio-psychologique du rôle identitaire amalgamée avec des éléments de la théorie de l’activité humaine. Examinée de ce double point de vue, l’identité se construit au fil des relations interpersonnelles et s’y intègre. L’identité se révèle ainsi comme une propriété des relations avec les autres personnes. Les données de cette étude ont été amassées sur une période de deux ans. Chaque mois, l’expérience quotidienne de neuf doctorants en éducation était documentée pendant une semaine complète. À la fin de chaque année scolaire, ces expériences ont été discutées dans le cadre d’entrevues. Ces doctorants ont été sélectionnés à partir d’un échantillon plus large d’étudiants au doctorat en raison de leur intention explicite de s’engager dans une carrière universitaire à la fin de leur programme d’études. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McAlpine, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042z17b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h573r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>College teachers -- Training of</dc:subject><dc:subject>Doctoral students</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education, Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>