<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440s751"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The synchronization of time-slotted photonic star networks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>El Shazli, Abdalla</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Photonics is a technology capable of supporting very high bit-rates of data. However, with the current state of photonic technologies logic and memory functions are very difficult to implement in the photonic domain. In photonic star networks using time division multiplexing (such as the Agile All Photonic Network), timeslots from the edges of the network have to arrive at the star point at exactly the same instant to be switched because they cannot be buffered in the photonic domain. The switching requires that the time at which the timeslots are transmitted must be coordinated and tightly controlled. This thesis addresses methods of synchronizing the components at the edge of the network to compensate for heterogeneous propagation delays between the edges and the star point. Different methods of providing this compensation are described and assessed in terms of their capabilities and performance.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kn355.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440s751</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Optical communications</dc:subject><dc:subject>Data transmission systems</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w7484"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigations into Indigenous research and education through an experiential and place-based lens</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>O'Connor, Kevin Barry</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The lack of Indigenous cultural knowledge and perspectives in the school curriculum has been identified as a significant factor in school failure amongst Indigenous students. This thesis includes a literature review of Indigenous education, as articulated by Indigenous scholars. Issues of identity, self-determination, local control, community, culture and a return to a traditional-holistic model of education are investigated. An analysis of experiential and place-based educational models is taken as these alternative practices have shown success in addressing Indigenous students needs. The fundamental significance story, narrative and the concept of place has in Indigenous culture and knowledge development is explored, as well as the effects colonial influences have had on Indigenous story, voice and sense of place. Using self-study methodologies and the formation of a "narrative identity" through reflexive writings, the author attempts to uncover his motives and reasoning as a non-Indigenous educator and researcher in pursuing research in Indigenous education and to develop principles that understand, are respectful and conducive to Indigenous thought.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mj20s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w7484</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Indigenous peoples -- Education -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aww72bb78c"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Islam in Sudan : identity, citizenship and conflict</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>O'Mahony, Geraldine Maria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis will examine the role of Islamist political parties and what effect their interpretation of national identity has played in dividing the people of Sudan, resulting in two civil wars. It will examine the manifestations and interpretations of Islam and pan-Arabism among the various Islamist parties of Northern Sudan, exploring the ethnic and religious factors which influence Islamist political groups, as well as their social bases which are tied to economics, language, and the conception of a distinctly "Arab" or "African" culture. This thesis will argue that the predominance of these Islamist political parties in the Sudanese government combined with the lack of a Sudanese identity and historical factors have combined to prevent the consolidation of state power, leading to situations of protracted conflict. The imposition, or attempted imposition, of an Islamic identity on the state as a whole prevents unity as it necessarily excludes certain parts of the population as well as disenfranchising those who, whilst they might be Muslim, do not subscribe to the same interpretation of Islamic identity.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sj883.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bb78c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nationalism -- Sudan -- History -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islam -- Sudan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islam and politics -- Sudan</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kn36f"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La dynamique des genres chez Boyer d'Argens</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Naud, Marie-Claude</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Jean-Baptiste Boyer d'Argens, a dissident and libertine writer, has played an important role by spreading Enlightenment ideas to Frederic II of Prussia. He began to write in the 1730s, a particularly productive and innovative period. His work is a testimony of the profound transformation of the novel toward the modern approach. By blending different formal genres (novel and memoirs), he made use of an hybrid genre in which moral truth is greater than historical accuracy. His entire repertoire converges toward a principal theme, the emancipation of man. This notion of freedom not only implies to the freedom of thought, conduct and writing form, it is the foundation of Boyer d'Argens' life and poetics. This author, not too conservative, not too eccentric, is a good representation of the common trend of thinking of the Enlightenment.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591882v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kn36f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Argens, Jean-Baptiste de Boyer, marquis d', 1704-1771 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z110z"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Old bridge in Mostar : a bridge between Muslims and Croats?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nordtvedt, Kaia Kathryn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One city in Bosnia-Herzegovina can be seen as a microcosm of a greater ethnic and religious conflict. The city of Mostar has drawn much attention from the international community not only because of its position in Bosnia but because of a small bridge over the Neretva River. This bridge has evolved into an international symbol of hope and reconciliation while at the same time embodying segregation and destruction. This thesis aims to analyse this old bridge in Mostar as a symbol of cultural intervention by the international community. The successes and failures that the bridge encompasses speak to the tumultuous time the international community at large has had in reunifying the war-torn city of Mostar and in extension the country of Bosnia. The bridge has become more than a path over water, but a reflection of the mood and culture of an entire city.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wg26q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z110z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bridges -- Bosnia and Hercegovina -- Mostar</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mostar (Bosnia and Hercegovina) -- Ethnic relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atq57nr25f"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigating NNS English teachers' self-assessed language proficiency in an EFL context</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tang, Ting. 1982-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The vast majority of secondary school English teachers in China are non-native English speakers (NNS). These teachers might not have adequate language proficiency to promote a communicative language environment for students. This has raised an ongoing discussion concerning the growing need to foster NNS teachers' communicative language proficiency, which has been identified as one of the most important qualifications for successful ESL/EFL (English as a Second Language/English as a Foreign Language) teachers (Murdoch, 1994; Kamhi-Stein &amp; Lee, 1999; Nunan, 2003). In this study, 53 secondary NNS teachers from Chinese secondary schools were asked to self-assess their English proficiency as well as to specify the minimum level of proficiency that they felt was needed to teach English effectively at the secondary school level in seven skill domains (listening comprehension, speaking ability, reading comprehension, writing ability, pronunciation, vocabulary and grammar). Paired sample t tests revealed that statistically significant differences were identified in six of the seven skill domains. Teachers perceived substantial gaps between their English proficiency and the minimum level needed to teach effectively. Teachers' perceptions about the relationship between their language proficiency and their teaching expertise were also explored through face-to-face interviews. The findings provide valuable information and have implications for language teachers in EFL contexts as well as for teacher educators.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kj88w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nr25f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching (Secondary) -- China</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language teachers -- China</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn106z35s"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>&amp;quot;Death to all fascists! liberty to the people!&amp;quot; : history and popular culture in Yugoslavia 1945-1990</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Turković, Dajana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This essay analyzes the changing portrayal of Yugoslavia's World War II experience in music, film, and literature. It argues that the disappearance of unifying themes from the cultural sphere opened the doors to the popularization of controversial and divisive subjects. Shifting perceptions of how Yugoslavs fought and survived the Second World War contributed to the destruction of Yugoslavia. The first chapter focuses on World War II in Yugoslavia. The second chapter discusses the early development of Yugoslav culture and its dependence on the Second World War. The third chapter follows the development of Yugoslav culture through the 1960s and 1970s when political liberalization promoted greater freedom in the arts. Aside from inspiring artists to address new themes and approach old themes from a fresh perspective, it also permitted the stirrings of political dissent. The fourth chapter addresses the disappearance of the Yugoslav idea from the cultural realm during the 1980s.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93gz78z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn106z35s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Literature and the war</dc:subject><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Motion pictures and the war</dc:subject><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Yugoslavia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Popular culture -- Yugoslavia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445cd342"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Conceptions of poverty and development in a Malawian village setting</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Waldorff, Pétur</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is the result of ethnographic fieldwork conducted in Phalombe District in Malawi, Southern Africa, where I studied agricultural development projects in the village of Kachala. The focus of this investigation is on people's perceptions and ideas of development co-operation and the meanings of development and poverty in general. Perceptions of development and poverty among villagers in Kachala are compared to those of development agents working for development organizations in the area. These perceptions are also compared to the definitions of development and poverty found throughout development literature. This research demonstrates - through examples from Phalombe District and elsewhere - how notions of development are relative, diverse and context-specific, and therefore not static and universally applicable. Finally, participatory development ideals and the structurally unequal donor-recipient relationships, at the core of the current development system, are discussed. This thesis illustrates how the common portrayal of development as an oppressive, disempowering industry, characterized by top-down interventions, does not always apply.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cq71x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cd342</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Poverty -- Malawi</dc:subject><dc:subject>Malawi -- Economic conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Agricultural development projects -- Malawi</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kq70w"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of East Asian Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Transgressing boundaries : hybridity in Zhang Ailing's writing and its multidimensional interpretations in contemporary China</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Yuan, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Zhang Ailing is an extraordinary yet important literary figure in 1940s China. In her writing, the specificity of hybridity breaks through restriction of domestic, social, political and cultural issues and makes her writing surpass the boundaries of races, cultures and space and time. It integrates Zhang's profound concern for human life and humanity with her exquisite literary sensibility. In my thesis, I deploy my study on this hybrid specificity, and also on the cultural phenomena relevant to Zhang Ailing in 1990s China, namely the "Zhang Ailing fever" and the nostalgia theme in Hong Kong film. By exploring the underlying relationship between the two issues on the basis of respective analyses of them, I try to enrich our understanding of this legendary writer and stimulate further thought on the broad and complex process of the "rehabilitation" of Zhang's literary reputation in both Western sinology and Chinese academia.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jr43m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kq70w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Zhang, Ailing -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g3007"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Attention skills and response to a computer-based literacy intervention</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Deault, Louise C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Inattention is often associated with early reading difficulties and to non-responsiveness to reading interventions. The aim of the present study was to explore the relationships between attention skills and literacy skills over the course of the computer-based literacy intervention, ABRACADABRA. The design included a contrast of two interventions, Synthetic Phonics and Rime, against a classroom control, enabling a comparison of different types of literacy contexts for grade one students with varying attention skills. Attention skills, as measured by both parent ratings and a sustained attention task, were found to predict reading-related skills and students' improvement over the course of the intervention. However, the predictive power of attention changed across different literacy contexts. For students who did not participate in the intervention, sustained attention predicted growth in blending skills and inattention predicted reading comprehension improvement, while the Synthetic Phonics group no longer showed these associations. These results suggest that the literacy environment has an impact on the mapping of associations between literacy and attention skills.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032332r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g3007</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Language arts -- Computer-assisted instruction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Attention</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78tc24x"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>De Versailles à Clarens : nature et politique dans les jardins littéraires de l'âge classique</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dufresne, Virginie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During the 17th and 18th centuries, the French garden history witnesses the triumph and then the decline of the French formal garden, to which succeeds the fashion of landscape gardening of foreign inspiration. Integrating and nourishing this debate, the literary texts of that period enable to grasp the stakes that it brings up. The garden notably lends itself to the expression of an emerging sentiment of nature, as well it also serves that of a political thought enlightened by new ideas. Effectively, the treatment that these texts give to the garden is a witness to the revival that installs itself in the way of conceiving nature, and the relation that nature holds with man and the art of the gardens. The garden's topic and scenography are a testimony of changes that in turn affect its imaginary and that of the walk. Finally, the critical discourse exploits the analogy that establishes itself between the art of the gardens and the exercise of power, polarizing the debate around the political metaphor.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z8035.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc24x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gardens in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>French literature -- 18th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>French literature -- 17th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913q155"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le métissage dans l'œuvre indochinoise de Marguerite Duras</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Desaulniers, Elisabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation focuses on the issue of hybridity in Marguerite Duras' corpus of Indochinese texts, as well as on the meeting of identities in the colonial realm. In order to identify the problematics of colonial coexistence, we will address the themes of the encounter between the Orient and the Occident, the use of hybrid discourse and the role of memory in the process of rewriting. Edward Said's Orientalism theory as well as Homi Bhabha's concept of ambivalence in colonial discourse will serve as the basis for the analysis of the Indochinese cycle. Far from being a totalizing experience, hybridity will reveal itself as being a harrowing dichotomy.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g776j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913q155</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Duras, Marguerite -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Miscegenation in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aht24wj66t"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Italian</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ossessione in context : an analysis of the foundations and achievements of Luchino Visconti's first film</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Della Motta, Marco</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The following thesis focuses on the Italian director, Luchino Visconti and his first feature film, Ossessione. It evaluates his film in relation not only to the director's biography but also to its historical and cinematic context. It deals with the manner in which Ossessione was adapted from an American roman noir, refashioning it in its own distinctive way. In addition, it analyses the film's relation to generic modes of representation, specifically realism and melodrama, and concludes by situating the work as a precursor of the Neorealist movement of the mid-20th century.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kb00b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wj66t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Visconti, Luchino, 1906-1976. Ossessione</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000021r"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design of an autonomous navigation system for a mobile robot</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paul, André</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An autonomous navigational system for a mobile robot was developed based on a Laser-Range-Finder-based path planning and navigational algorithms. The system was enhanced by incorporating collision avoidance algorithms using data from a sonar sensor array, and further improved by establishing two virtual regions in front of the robot for obstacle detection and avoidance. Several virtual detector bands with varying dimensions were also added to the sides of the robot to check for rotational clearance safety and to determine the direction of rotation. The autonomous navigational system was tested extensively under indoor environment. Test results showed that the system performed satisfactorily in navigating the mobile robot in three structured mazes under indoor conditions. An artificial landmark localization algorithm was also developed to continuously record the positions of the robot whilst it was moving. The algorithm was tested on a grid layout of 6 m x 6 m. The performance of the artificial landmark localization technique was compared with odometric and inertial measurements obtained using a dead-reckoning method and a gyroscope-corrected dead-reckoning method. The artificial landmark localization method resulted in much smaller root mean square error (0.033 m) of position estimates compared to the other two methods (0.175 m and 0.135 m respectively).</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j5953.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000021r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Precision farming</dc:subject><dc:subject>Robots -- Motion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Robots -- Control systems</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n203z40w"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Crown wards in child welfare : comparison of access arrangements with best practice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Savoie, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Access arrangements for birth parents of crown wards are a concern for child protection workers. Data on 84 crown wards were collected from 11 in care workers at a Children's Aid Society in Ontario, to determine whether best practice guidelines were being observed. Best practice derived from literature was operationalized as: (1) inclusion of birth parents and others in decisions affecting the child, and (2) connectivity ---maintaining family ties. Regression analyses were performed to identify predictors of inclusion and connectivity scores. Results showed three significant predictors of inclusion---worker knowledge, years in child welfare, and birth parents' source of income---and two predictors of connectivity---worker knowledge and parents' source of income. Findings suggest that agency training and support of workers can have a positive effect on implementation of best practice. The effect of income source is a puzzle, as income from employment was associated with lower inclusion scores, but higher connectivity scores.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613mx805.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n203z40w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Parent and child -- Ontario</dc:subject><dc:subject>Visitation rights (Domestic relations) -- Ontario</dc:subject><dc:subject>Foster home care -- Ontario</dc:subject><dc:subject>Custody of children -- Ontario</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s161646v"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Missing voices : a qualitative study of mothers experiencing the loss of a child through Crown Wardship No Access</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wright, Peggy D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The intent of this study was to gain an appreciation for the experiences of mothers whose parental rights have been permanently severed through child welfare court orders of Crown Wardship with No Access. The study utilized an explorative, qualitative design approach and included semi-structured, in-depth interviews with four women. Participant text and found poetry presented the voice of mothers, something not often the focus in the child welfare literature. Themes of betrayal, loss, anger, and disenfranchised grief were reported in the research findings. The role of the social worker emerged as an important factor influencing the mothers. This study found that mothers need acknowledgment for their losses and support for their grief. Consideration for social work implications and further research are also discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354f50j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161646v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Birthmothers -- Ontario</dc:subject><dc:subject>Adoption -- Ontario -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Child welfare -- Ontario -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n203z394"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Suicide survivors and the reactive suicide phenomenon</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shepherd, Nicole</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A mail survey was conducted with 49 suicide survivors from 13 different suicide support groups across Canada. Participants were asked about their experiences of grieving a suicide and if the suicide was part of a cluster. Quantitative and qualitative research methodology was used in the coding and analysis of the data. A theory diagram was devised to test four hypotheses. Results of the regression analyses contradicted one hypothesis: showing that an increase in coping mechanisms may heighten levels of grief for a suicide survivor. The number of possible suicide linkages was highly significant with 5 of the 49 participants answering positively when asked if the suicide they were grieving was part of a cluster. Suicide bereavement groups were consistently rated as beneficial or very beneficial by participants. Lastly, content analysis of the open-ended questions showed a common experience of stigma associated with a suicidal death for survivors.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301168d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n203z394</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Suicide victims -- Family relationships</dc:subject><dc:subject>Suicide -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bereavement -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93gz797"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of electrochemical (Bio)sensors for the detection of dopamine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Skaf, Tania</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The development of dopamine (DA) electrochemical sensors and biosensors is described in this thesis. The aim was to develop (bio)sensors that would continuously and specifically detect DA over a wide concentration range, with high sensitivity and low detection limits. The electrode surfaces used were platinum (Pt), boron-doped-diamond (BDD), and carbon-paste (CP). The first two were used to construct DA sensors, while Pt was shown to be superior for the construction of biosensors. The DA biosensor configurations were based on the use of a Pt electrode as a transducer surface, polyphenol oxidase (PPO) as an enzyme, ferrocene (Fc) as a mediator, and polypyrrole (PPY) and Nafion as membranes. A range of electrochemical techniques were employed in this research. It was determined that the oxidation of DA on bare Pt is a surface-controlled reaction, occurring at low overpotentials. The reaction is electrochemically reversible, involving the spontaneous adsorption of DA on the electrode surface. The Pt and BDD sensors were efficiently used to determine DA in aqueous solutions. In order to increase their resistance to the ascorbic acid (AA) interference, the sensor surfaces were modified by a thin Nafion film. This configuration was shown to selectively detect DA even when AA was present with DA at a 1000-time larger concentration. The lowest DA detection limit was achieved using the unmodified BDD sensor, 50 nM. Nevertheless, both the unmodified and Nafion-modified Pt and BDD sensors were suitable for monitoring of DA at concentration levels typical for urine samples. It was shown that the sensitivity and detection limit of the developed Pt-based biosensors depend on the amount of PPO and Fc incorporated into the PPY membrane, and also on their ratio. The modification of the biosensor by a Nafion membrane offered three benefits: an increase in sensitivity, an improvement in detection limit, and a significant minimization of the AA interference. An optimum biosensor architecture was made by polymerizing PPY for 40 minutes from a pyrrole solution containing 2,400 U mL-1 of PPO and 10 mM of Fc, on top of which a thin Nafion film was formed. Using chronoamperometry as a detection technique, this biosensor yielded a DA detection limit of 20 nM, which makes it suitable for monitoring DA levels in brain. Even a lower detection limit, 10 nM, and higher sensitivity were achieved by using electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) as a detection technique. Unfortunately, the developed biosensor lacked operational stability, predominately due to the leakage of PPO and Fc into the storage solution.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kj895.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93gz797</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322d51q"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Inventory, condition assessment and diagnosis water supply and sewage systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sipos, Cristian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This project describes a methodology for developing a digitized GIS-based inventory of underground municipal utilities, and recommends an approach for developing a database, which will assist with considerably improved management of buried systems and effective use of limited available resources. The study also discusses the water and sewer infrastructure debt and the total infrastructure debt in Canada. Some other issues related to the Canadian water infrastructure, such as water pricing and consumption patterns, along with the deterioration mechanisms of the underground services, are also discussed. The study focuses on the main services of water supply and sewage systems in any Canadian municipality, which presently are in an advanced state of deterioration. The steps required to develop such an inventory are reviewed and suggestions are made for condition assessment of the system using non-destructive techniques, employing simple methods, as well as more sophisticated tests in critical sectors, where further investigation is required. These methods are also summarily revised. The underground infrastructure of the McGill Downtown Campus is summarily described; it comprises the various underground features which exist in a small community, e.g. water-supply and sewage system, electrical lines, gas pipelines, telecommunication networks, etc., which are similar with Montreal's underground services, in terms of age, materials employed, workmanship and technologies available over the past 175 to 200 years. The framework for the underground infrastructure inventory is proposed for implementation in a small community such as the McGill Downtown Campus. The long-term goal of the project is to extrapolate the McGill "model", and to enhance it such that the municipalities in Canada can implement it as a basis for development of GIS-based inventories and condition assessment, and prioritization for effective management of underground services, which include scheduling, financing and implementation of repair, rehabilitation and replacement of underground and other infrastructure.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3655478.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322d51q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak930bx455"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Transmit antenna selected spatial multiplexing systems with power allocation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shi, Zhengyan, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Vertical Bell Lab Layered Space-Time (VBLAST) is an emerging spatial modulation technique, that provides high spectral efficiency due to its use of multiple transmit and receiver antennas. We present novel schemes; consisting of combinations of Transmit Antenna Selection (TAS) with Power Allocation (PA), to improve the error rate performance of VBLAST systems. Our schemes provide significant performance gain over VLAST because of enhanced transmit diversity introduced by transmit antenna selection. Our scheme may be used for uplink wireless system, where the total power is limited by the mobile terminal battery. The effect of limited rate feedback link is investigated by sending quantized power weights from receiver to transmitter. The simulation results show that even one-bit, codebook for power weights can achieve performance close to that of unlimited rate feedback link in low and medium SNR regions. We also present a novel PA technique alloting power in the joint space-frequency domain to reduce the error rate, and apply our scheme to frequency selective MIMO-OFDM channels. In addition, an analytical analysis of transmit correlated Successive interference Cancelling Zero Forcing (SIC-ZF) VBLAST in flat fading channels is presented. Over frequency selective channels, the performance of SIC-ZF VBLAST is assessed by computer simulation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pd20p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bx455</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Electricity and Magnetism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tv37z"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Efficient nonlinear distortion analysis of RF circuits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tannir, Dani A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The third order intercept point (IP3) is an important figure of merit which gives a measure of the linearity of communication circuits. There are two classes of methods for calculating the IP3 of a circuit. The first is analytical and is usually based on Volterra series. This approach is cumbersome and is difficult to apply to arbitrary circuits with arbitrary non-linearities. The second class of methods is based on multi-tone simulations and is general and flexible but requires significant CPU cost. In this thesis a new method based on the computation of the circuit moments is proposed. The new approach uses the circuit moments in order to numerically compute the Volterra kernels. This automates the process of numerically obtaining such kernels for any circuit and results in an efficient approach for the computation of IP3 for arbitrary circuits. The proposed approach is simple to apply and presents a significant improvement in CPU cost over existing methods.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bx44w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tv37z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75dc74c"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Failure of extruded magnesium alloy tubes during hydroforming</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hiscocks, Jessica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Research is currently being conducted on the feasibility of hydroforming extruded magnesium tubes to integrate multiple parts into a single hydroformed section. Among other advantages, such sections would reduce the weight of both cars and planes, particularly when used in the vehicle frame. This would lead to either reduced fuel costs, or the ability to carry an increased payload. Magnesium generally has limited ductility, which in the case of the current extruded tubes is even further reduced at the extrusion seams. These are locations where the material flow separates and rejoins during extrusion and are unavoidable when a hollow profile die is used. When the tubes are stressed in a circumferential direction by hydroforming, tube ruptures consistently occur along the extrusion seams of the tubes. This has led to the current project, an inquiry into the exact cause of failure at these locations. An overview of the nature of magnesium, including deformation systems is presented and the creation of irregularities at the longitudinal seams of the tube is discussed. The sources of these irregularities are considered together with their roles in producing the failures. The experimental results of cone wedge testing at various temperatures and compression rates are presented and compared to the results of certain free expansion hydroforming trials. Several possible means of improving the magnesium tubes during production are included. The results are summarized and the most fruitful directions for future work are outlined.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719m66j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dc74c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859f92z"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the partial Haar dual adaptive filter for sparse echo cancellation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kechichian, Patrick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Typical sparse echo cancellers employ adaptive filtering algorithms that, update only a small number of filter coefficients that, produce the actual echo. Usually, these algorithms provide increased convergence speed at the cost of an increase in computational complexity for locating these significant filter coefficients. Recently, a coupled echo canceller was proposed that uses two short adaptive filters in tandem. The first adaptive filter operates in the partial Haar domain and is solely used to estimate the location of the channel's dispersive region. A short time-domain filter is then centred around this estimate to cancel echo. Using two short filters instead of one long filter not only reduces computational complexity, while substantially increasing the convergence speed of the echo canceller. The focus of this thesis is twofold. First, it analyzes the partial Haar echo canceller and attempts to clarify some issues with its implementation. Second and foremost, it, identifies and proposes feasible solutions to three inherent weaknesses of the coupled echo canceller. These include alleviating the adverse effect caused by the shift-variant property of wavelets, improving the tracking performance of the coupled echo canceller in response to abrupt changes in the echo path impulse response, and extending the original echo canceller to support the cancellation of multiple echoes. Simulations support the resulting improvements when each of the proposed solutions is incorporated into the coupled echo canceller.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xh908.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859f92z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rh259"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Application of the Flexible Local Approximation Method to photonic crystal cavities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Huang, Guo Qin, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates the application of a recently developed numerical technique, the Flexible Local Approximation Method (FLAME) to compute the resonances of 2D photonic crystal (PC) cavities, formed by a defect in a regular array of dielectric rods. FLAME is a finite-difference-like method which is ideally suited to problems consisting of large numbers of identical structures. The anisotropic perfectly matched layer (PML) is used as an artificial absorbing layer to truncate the computational domain. The parameters of the PML are chosen carefully to provide adequate absorption without a large computational cost. FLAME method and PML boundaries are applied to cavities with 3x3, 5x5 and 7x7 arrays of rods. The resonant modes, field distribution, and quality factor are computed and compared with previously-published results. Good agreement is obtained. However, the matrix eigenproblem generated by FLAME is of a kind for which sparse-matrix algorithms are not available and dense-matrix software had to be used. This limitation will have to be overcome if FLAME is to be widely used for PC cavities.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rp016.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rh259</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Optics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021f44x"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Oscillatory flows in periodically interrupted rectangular passages in heat exchangers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lamoureux, Alexandre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Computational and experimental studies of fluid flow and heat transfer phenomena in interrupted-surface passages are presented. The computational investigation was focused on developing and fully-developed (spatially and temporally) laminar flow and heat transfer in essentially two-dimensional regions of the following passages: (1) a straight rectangular duct with spatially periodic in-line plate inserts; and (2) staggered-plate arrays. A second-order finite-volume method was developed, validated, and used to solve these problems. Time-mean modular friction factors and Colburn factors were obtained from the domain inlet to the spatially-periodic fully-developed region for a Reynolds number range of 100 to 600, thus exploring the laminar steady and unsteady regimes. Additionally, various cyclic domains were investigated. In the experimental investigation, single hot-wire measurements were used to obtain ensemble-averaged power spectrums and Strouhal numbers in the fully-developed region of the rectangular duct with spatially periodic in-line plate inserts, for Reynolds numbers ranging from 2000 to 30000.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vr22k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021f44x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>