<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zq07k"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A simplified model for lightning exposure of wind turbines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lo, Pape Momar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Reliability requirements of wind turbines become more important as the share of wind energy in the global energy balance continues to grow. Lightning protection of wind turbines has therefore become an issue of great importance considering the location and size of modern wind turbines.   Analysis of lightning performance of wind turbines includes both lightning exposure and lightning response once a turbine is actually struck.  In Chapter 1, lightning exposure and protection of wind turbines is introduced from a technical and field point of view, and common methods of analysis are mentioned.   In Chapter 2, basic lightning attachment theories with special reference to wind turbine exposure and methods of analysis are presented. Models used in previous work to determine lightning incidence to structures are described in details.  In Chapter 3, a simplified model for lightning exposure of wind turbines is presented. Based on electric field and space potential calculations, it has been shown that a wind turbine with a down conductor can be treated as a slender structure.   Due to the enormous difference between the speed of downward stepped leader and the blade speed, it has been shown that from a lightning exposure point of view, a wind turbine blade could be treated as static.  The findings of the thesis allow significant simplification of the analysis of lightning exposure of the wind turbines.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les exigences de fiabilité des éoliennes deviennent de plus en plus  importantes vu que la place qu’occupe l'énergie éolienne dans le bilan énergétique global ne cesse de croître.  Prenant en compte l’emplacement et de la taille des éoliennes aujourd’hui, leur protection contre la foudre est devenu une question de grande envergure.L’analyse de l’effet de la foudre sur les éoliennes réside sur l’analyse de leur exposition à celle-ci et sur les impacts après foudroiement.Dans le chapitre 1, les concepts d’exposition et de protection des éoliennes contre la foudre d’un point de vue technique et pratique sont mis en avant. Des méthodes d'analyse sont aussi mentionnées. Dans le chapitre 2, nous présentons des théories fondamentales sur la foudre avec une attention particulière sur l'exposition des éoliennes à celle –ci et sur des méthodes d'analyse. Les modèles utilisés lors de recherches antérieures afin de déterminer l'incidence de la foudre sur les structures sont décrits en détails.Dans le chapitre 3, un modèle simplifié de l’exposition des éoliennes à la foudre est présenté. En se basant sur des calculs de champ électrique et de potentiel, nous avons démontré qu’une éolienne et son câble de protection peuvent être représentés par une tige cylindrique.En raison de l'énorme différence entre la vitesse de descente des éclairs et la vitesse des pales des éoliennes, nous avons démontré que les pales peuvent être considérées stagnantes lors de nos analyses.Cette thèse met en avant une simplification de l'analyse de l’exposition des éoliennes à la foudre.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Farouk A. M. Rizk</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236373b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq07k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bn36n"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Human papillomavirus infection and transmission among couples through heterosexual activity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Burchell, Ann</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le virus du papillome humain (VPH) est l'infection transmissible sexuellement (ITS) la plus répandue. Une grande majorité des infections à VPH se résorbent spontanément. Cependant, la petite proportion d’infections à VPH persistantes peut avoir des coûts substantiels de traitement et de morbidité comme conséquence. Des génotypes de VPH à haut risque oncologique (HR-HPV), y compris HPV-16 et 18, sont identifiés sans équivoque comme facteur causal principal pour le cancer cervical, et peuvent également causer d'autres cancers anogénitaux, de la tête et du cou. Les infections avec des génotypes de VPH à bas risque oncologique (LR-HPV), comme HPV-6 et -11, sont associées aux lésions bénignes comprenant les verrues génitales. Plusieurs projections de l'impact des nouveaux vaccins de VPH et des techniques de dépistage utilisent des modèles de transmission dynamiques qui exigent des évaluations précises de la probabilité de transmission lors de l'exposition. En outre, les limitations biologiques et pratiques des vaccins courants exigent que nous explorions autant d'options de prévention que possibles. Une question critique de recherches est de savoir si les condoms assurent une protection. Les objectifs principaux de la thèse consistaient à caractériser des modèles typiques d’infection au VPH parmi les couples hétérosexuels dans une nouvelle relation, identifier des facteurs de risque pour l'infection au VPH, et estimer les probabilités de transmission du VPH par relation de couple et par acte coïtal. J'ai effectué une simulation préliminaire de Monte Carlo pour estimer la probabilité de transmission de VPH, puis j’ai conçu et entrepris une étude des couples hétérosexuels. Les objectifs de thèse ont été élaborés en utilisant les données de base de l'étude de cohorte HITCH (HPV Infection and Transmission among Couples through Heterosexual activity) qui se poursuit toujours. La population de l’étude est composée$</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Human papillomavirus (HPV) is the most common sexually transmitted infection (STI). The vast majority of these infections clear spontaneously. The small proportion that persists may result in substantial morbidity and treatment costs. High oncogenic risk HPV (HR-HPV) types, including HPV-16 and 18, are recognised unequivocally as the main causal factor for cervical cancer, and may also cause other anogenital neoplasms and head and neck cancers. Infections with types that have low oncogenic risk (LR-HPV), such as HPV-6 and -11, are associated with benign lesions including genital warts. Many projections of the impact of the new HPV vaccines and screening technologies use dynamic transmission models which require sound estimates of the probability of transmission upon exposure. Furthermore, biological and practical limitations of the current vaccines require that we explore as many prevention options as possible. A critical research question is whether condoms provide protection. The main aims of the thesis were to characterize patterns of HPV infection among heterosexual couples in a new relationship, to identify risk factors for HPV infection, and to estimate HPV transmission probabilities per partnership and per coital act. I carried out a preliminary Monte Carlo simulation to estimate the probability of HPV transmission, then designed and conducted a study of heterosexual couples. The thesis objectives were addressed using baseline data from the ongoing HITCH Cohort Study (HPV Infection and Transmission among Couples through Heterosexual activity). The study population consists of young (aged 18-24) women attending a university or junior college (CEGEP) in Montreal and their male partners.    Results from the simulation analysis suggested that HPV is highly transmissible, which was confirmed by the cross-sectional analysis of the HITCH study. Among the 263 couples enrolled between 05/2005 and 08/2008, HPV prevalence was 56% among women and men. In nearly two th</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eduardo L. F. Franco</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d8208.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn36n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5h73px592"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of molecules regulating Clathrin- and COPI- trafficking</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Burman, Jonathon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Understanding the molecular mechanisms by which eukaryotic cells direct and distribute essential components is of central importance to cell biology, as well as to the unravelling of the underpinnings of many disease states. Two major membrane trafficking systems through which eukaryotes maintain cellular homeostasis are the clathrin and coatomer I (COPI) coat machineries, whose core components share evolutionary homology. Clathrin functions at the plasma membrane in clathrin mediated endocytosis (CME), and at the trans-Golgi network and endosomes in clathrin mediated membrane budding. COPI function is best described in the early secretory pathway on cis-Golgi cisternae and the endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-Golgi intermediate compartment (ERGIC). In the process of trying to understand how cells take up and sort biological substrates we have identified a role for the aftiphilin and Scyl1 proteins as regulatory components of the clathrin and COPI trafficking systems, respectively. The following body of work reveals a commonality between clathrin and COPI coats in an ability to bind small peptide motifs present in regulatory factors. Specifically, this work assigns aftiphilin as a component of the clathrin machinery in neurons, finds a new function for the Scyl1 protein and links perturbations in COPI trafficking to a progressive neurodegenerative disease for the first time. Indeed, the large number of proteins that act as accessory or regulatory factors for membrane trafficking in the mammalian genome suggests that the more complex a cell becomes, for example a highly polarized cell like a neuron, the greater the variety of accessory proteins necessary to direct multiple trafficking routes, with diverse cargo, to a variety of specialized sub-domains. This thesis supports the hypothesis that the diversity and demands of membrane trafficking in neurons could underlie the long standing mystery of selective vulnerability in some neurodegenerative diseases.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Comprendre les mécanismes moléculaires par lesquels les cellules eucaryotes direct et la distribution de composants essentiels est d'une importance centrale pour la biologie cellulaire, ainsi que de l'effondrement de la sous-tendent de nombreuses maladies. Deux grands systèmes de trafic membranaire, qui eukaryotes maintenir l'homéostasie cellulaire, la clathrine et coatomer I (COPI) couche mécanismes, dont les composantes essentielles part évolutive homologie. Clathrin fonctions à la membrane plasmique de l'endocytose médiée par la clathrine (CME), et au réseau trans-Golgi et endosomes dans clathrin mediated membrane herbe (clathrin mediated membrane budding). COPI fonction est décrite dans la voie de sécrétion précoce sur cisternae cis-Golgi et le réticulum endoplasmique (ER)-Golgi compartiments intermédiaires (ERGIC). Dans le processus d'essayer de comprendre comment les cellules et trier les substrats biologiques, nous avons identifié un rôle pour le aftiphilin et Scyl1 composants des protéines de régulation de la clathrine et COPI traite des systèmes respectivement. L'organisme suivant de travail révèle un point commun entre la clathrine et des manteaux COPI dans une capacité de lier les motifs de petits peptides présents dans les facteurs de régulation. Plus précisément, ce travail affecte aftiphilin comme une composante de la clathrine machines dans les neurones, trouve une nouvelle fonction pour les protéines et les liens Scyl1 perturbations dans le trafic COPI à une maladie neurodégénérative progressive, pour la première fois. En effet, le grand nombre de protéines accessoires dans le génome des mammifères suggère que la plus complexe d'une cellule devient, par exemple, une cellule hautement polarisée comme un neurone, la plus grande de la variété des protéines accessoires nécessaires à l'approvisionnement de plusieurs itinéraires de trafic à une variété de services spécialisés sous -domaines. Cette thèse</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peter Scott McPherson</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801ph89q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73px592</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811km27k"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis and covalent surface modification of carbon nanotubes for preparation of stabilized nanofluid suspensions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vandsburger, Leron</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les nanotubes de carbone (NTC) font présentement l’objet de plusieurs études. Parmi leurs nombreuses propriétés, les conductivités thermique et électrique des NTC font en sorte qu’ils trouvent des applications dans plusieurs domaines, allant des écrans ultra-minces à des surfaces optimisant les transferts thermiques/électriques, ou comme éléments dispersés formant des polymères conducteurs. De nombreuses études ont démontré que les NTC ont également un avenir prometteur dans les nanofluides. Un nanofluide est une suspension d’objets nanométriques (e.g. nanoparticules, NTC) dans un liquide hôte qui permet le transfert de chaleur avec une meilleure efficacité. En effet, des augmentations importantes de la conductivité de certains liquides hôtes ont été observés suite à la dispersion de NTC. Par contre, l’applicabilité de ces suspensions est remise en question dans des procédés où le fluide serait assujetti à des températures ou des flux de chaleur élevés. Afin de permettre l’usage de nanofluides de NTC dans ces situations, les tubes doivent être modifiés chimiquement pour favoriser leur interaction à long terme avec le liquide hôte.À cette fin, cet ouvrage présente deux avenues de recherche complémentaires : la synthèse de NTC par dépôt thermo-chimique en phase vapeur et la modification par plasma de la surface de NTC afin d’améliorer l’interaction avec des liquides polaires et non-polaires. Des suspensions aqueuses de NTC ont été préparées et caractérisées. Ces dernières font preuve de stabilité à long terme (plus d’un mois après la synthèse, à température ambiante) et de stabilité thermique (suite à un chauffage important et même l’ébullition). L’effet du traitement par plasma radio fréquence de argon/oxygène/ethane sur la chimie des surfaces des NTC est également étudié.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Carbon nanotubes are the current object of fervent research. Their unique properties, including anisotropic heat and electrical conductivities, make them promising candidates for applications ranging from super-thin displays to optimized heat transfer surfaces or polymer-CNT composites. Another application is as a component in a polar nanofluid for use in heat transfer. Numerous studies have reported that including carbon nanotubes in liquids can augment their thermal conductivities greatly, but one great disadvantage of current techniques is their limited applicability to situations of high heat flux or temperature, such as boiling or superheating, respectively.  For this to be a possibility, carbon nanotubes must be chemically altered to increase their interaction with polar liquids in a persistent and uniform way.  To that end, this work presents two separate but complementary research efforts. The first is a study on the synthesis of carbon nanotubes by thermal chemical vapour deposition, and the second is on the covalent surface modification of carbon nanotubes for both polar and nonpolar interactions. Ultimately, the goal is the preparation and characterisation of aqueous suspensions of carbon nanotubes. The principal results of the latter study are the successful synthesis of carbon nanotube suspensions that are stable at room temperature, beyond one month after preparation, and in high temperature environments, including boiling, and new information about the effect of radio-frequency plasma treatment in an Argon/Oxygen/Ethane mixture on the surface chemistry of carbon nanotubes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sylvain Coulombe</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jean-Luc Meunier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f222.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km27k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rm897"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Desautels Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Deal characteristics and collective rumination: how employees make sense of a merger announcement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marmenout, Katty</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ce projet de thèse concerne l'aspect humain des fusions et acquisitions.  Je propose et teste un modèle intégrant les perspectives culturelles, sociales et psychologiques. Cette réplication expérimentale d’une annonce de fusion comble une lacune dans la littérature, à savoir le manque de recherche liant les niveaux micro et macro dans ce domaine.  J’examine notamment comment les caractéristiques de la fusion affectent les réactions des employés. Les résultats de mon étude multiméthode basée sur un modèle longitudinal ont non seulement permis d’établir l'existence d'un effet des variables contextuelles sur les attitudes des employés, mais également de démontrer à quel point l’interaction avec un groupe de collègues peut être néfaste.  En effet, une analyse complémentaire des données qualitatives permet de constater la présence d’un phénomène de “rumination collective” suite à l’annonce de la fusion.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The purpose of this dissertation is to increase our understanding of how employees make sense of a merger announcement.  This dissertation addresses a gap in the literature by examining the relationship between deal characteristics and employee reactions.  A theoretical model incorporating the cultural, psychological and social perspectives is developed and tested. This experimental study also examines how attitudes about the merger change following peer interaction.  Quantitative and qualitative methods are combined to investigate the relationship between deal characteristics and employee reactions observed in mergers.  Findings indicate that deal characteristics not only significantly affect initial employee reactions, but also affect how employee attitudes evolve over time as they discuss the event with peers. The study establishes an overall detrimental effect of social interaction on employee attitudes, described as collective rumination.  Finally, the study sheds new light on power in mergers by establishing the relevance of one’s position in the deal structure with respect to sensemaking and attitudes following the discussion of the event with colleagues.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alfred M. Jaeger</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107068q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rm897</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Business Administration - Management</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pp51h"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of a quantitative accelerated sulphate attack test for mine back fill</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shnorhokian, Shahe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les opérations minières produisent de grandes quantités de rejets miniers qui sont soit stockés en surface dans des haldes, soit réutilisés comme remblais sous terre. La minéralogie de ces déchets est dictée par la géologie des lieux, et il est commun de trouver des rejets qui ont une teneur élevée en  minéraux sulfurés comme la pyrite et la pyrrhotite. Les sulfures sont oxydés en présence d’eau et d’oxygène et produisent une eau acide et riche en sulfates. Dans l’industrie du béton, un des grands problèmes provient de la réaction des sulfates de sources externes avec le ciment du béton pour former de l’ettringite et du gypse. Étant donné que les remblais dans les mines se servent des rejets et d’agents de liaison comme le ciment, ils sont sensibles aux attaques des sulfates si les conditions sont propices. En ce moment dans les laboratoires, on s’intéresse surtout aux paramètres mécaniques comme la résistance en compression et l’impact chimique que les rejets miniers ont sur l’environnement. Aucune recherche concrète n’a été faite sur les dangers de l’attaque des sulfates sur les remblais dans les mines et sur les différents agents de liaisons, afin de déterminer leurs résistances à de telles attaques.Les directives actuelles de l’ASTM pour tester l’attaque des sulfates se sont avérées inadéquates. En effet, ces tests sont seulement basés sur l’expansion, ce qui ne se produit pas forcément lors de l’attaque par des sulfates. De plus, ces tests sont trop longs et ne peuvent s’appliquer qu’à certains mélanges spécifiques de ciment et pas à d’autres comme la pouzzolane. Sur ces faits, un test accéléré a été mis en place par certains chercheurs. Après un séchage accéléré dans un four à 50ºC, des échantillons sont immergés dans des solutions de sulfate de sodium et d’acide sulfurique pendant 28 jours d’une part. D’autre part, d’autres échantillons sont immergés à moi</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Mining operations produce large amounts of tailings that are either disposed of in surface impoundments or used in the production of backfill to be placed underground. Their mineralogy is determined by the local geology, and it is not uncommon to come across tailings with a relatively high sulphide mineral content, including pyrite and pyrrhotite. Sulphides oxidize in the presence of oxygen and water to produce sulphate and acidity. In the concrete industry, sulphate is known to produce detrimental effects by reacting with the cement paste to produce the minerals ettringite and gypsum. Because mine backfill uses tailings and binders – including cement – it is therefore prone to sulphate attack where the required conditions are met. Currently, laboratory tests on mine backfill mostly measure mechanical properties such as strength parameters, and the study of the chemical aspects is restricted to the impact of tailings on the environment. The potential of sulphate attack in mine backfill has not been studied at length, and no tests are conducted on binders used in backfill for their resistance to attack. Current ASTM guidelines for sulphate attack tests have been deemed inadequate by several authors due to their measurement of only expansion as an indicator of attack. Furthermore, the tests take too long to perform or are restricted to cement mortars only, and not to mixed binders that include pozzolans. Based on these, an accelerated test for sulphate attack was developed in this work through modifying and compiling procedures that had been suggested by different authors. Small cubes of two different binders were fully immersed in daily-monitored sodium sulphate and sulphuric acid solutions for a total of 28 days, after 7 days of accelerated curing at 50ºC. In addition, four binders were partially immersed in the same solutions for 8 days for an accelerated attack process. The two procedures were conducted in tandem with leach tests using a mixed solution of</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jacques Ouellet</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Faramarz P. Hassani</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wr802.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp51h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r716s"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Puzzles rather than answers: co-constructing a pedagogy of experiential, place-based and critical learning in Indigenous education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>O'Connor, Kevin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette recherche examine les défis éducatifs actuels auxquels font face les étudiants des premières nations du nord du Canada, par le biais de l’étude de deux programmes éducatifs expérientiels et basés sur le lieu. Ces programmes d’études sont présentement appliqués par le système public (au niveau primaire et secondaire) du territoire du Yukon ainsi que dans deux écoles de la nation Cree et de la nation Dene, dans le nord de l’Alberta. Cette recherche collaborative puise à même les observations, descriptions et connaissances des participants afin de répondre a trois questions principales De quelle façon les étudiants, éducateurs, et membres de communauté interprètent le domaine d’éducation expérientielle et basée sur le lieu?   Quelles sont les manières par lesquelles les éducateurs et membres de la communauté peuvent partager leurs valeurs et pratiques afin de créer une classe pratique plus déterminée ? De quelle façon le système éducatif traditionnel peut redéfinir ses pratiques pour répondre aux besoins des autochtones tout en améliorant l’engagement des étudiants et leur succès?  L’objectif premier de cette recherche appliquée est de découvrir quels éléments de l’éducation expérientielle et basée sur le lieu mènent à un engagement accru des étudiants autochtones et améliorent les résultats scolaires. Les résultats d’études de cas comparatives ont démontré plusieurs similitudes parmi les facteurs menant à un engagement accru des étudiants autochtones dans les deux programmes.  Par un procédé récursif d’analyse de données, des thèmes spécifiques ont émergés, lesquels ont été considérés décisifs aux deux initiatives expérientielles.  J’explore ces thèmes à travers la voix des participants.  Ces thèmes sont : l’importance de partenariat à l’intérieur de la communauté, l’application de forme alternative d’évaluation, l’utilisation d’observation sur le terr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This research examines the current educational challenges facing First Nation students of northern Canada, through the exploration of two experiential and place-based educational programs. These programs of study are presently being applied in the public school system (primary and secondary) of the Yukon Territory and in two Cree and Dene Nation reserve schools in northern Alberta. The collaborative research draws on observations and participants’ descriptions and insights to address three principal questions: How do students, educators and community members interpret the field of experiential and place-based education? In what ways can educators and community members share values and practices to create more purposeful classroom praxis? and, How can current educational systems redefine its practices to address Indigenous needs, as well as improve student engagement and success?  The primary objective of this action research is to discover which elements of experiential and place-based education lead to greater engagement of Indigenous students and improved educational outcomes. The results of comparative case studies indicated many similarities among the factors leading to greater engagement of Indigenous students in the two programs. Through a recursive process of data analysis, specific themes emerged that were deemed crucial to both experiential initiatives. I explore those themes through the participants’ voices. They are: the importance of Partnerships within the community; the application of alternative forms of Evaluation; the use of Field Studies to deliver curriculum and engage students; an incorporation of Indigenous Culture and Knowledge in many aspects of the educational context; and the issues of Sustainability that include alternative structures and scheduling of the experiential programs. Finally, specific suggestions are made for building on current experiential and place-based educational research and practice.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steve Jordan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj008.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r716s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Curriculum and Instruction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53wx350"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ethics of health care practice in humanitarian crises</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hunt, Matthew Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Humanitarian emergencies and natural disasters can overwhelm the capacity of local and national agencies to respond to the needs of affected populations.  In such cases, international relief organizations are frequently involved in the provision of emergency assistance.  Health care professionals play a key role in these interventions.  This practice environment is significantly different from the context of health care delivery in the home countries of expatriate health care professionals.  Clinicians who travel from a developed nation to a resource-poor setting where a humanitarian crisis has occurred experience a shift of professional, social, cultural and regulatory environments.  In this dissertation I examine the ethics of health care practice in humanitarian work.  I evaluate the literature of global bioethics, global health ethics and the ethics of humanitarian assistance, and consider the contributions of various ethics frameworks and normative approaches.  I also develop a set of questions to guide health care professionals as they address ethically complex issues arising in clinical practice during humanitarian crises.  In the empirical component of this research program I use Interpretive Description methodology to examine the moral experience of health care professionals in humanitarian relief work, and clinician experiences of resources and constraints for addressing ethical issues in humanitarian settings.  Building upon the inductively derived findings, I argue for strategies and approaches that humanitarian organizations, project teams, and health care professionals can adopt to respond to the ethics of this field of practice.  I also provide a critical review of Interpretive Description methodology.  The research presented in this dissertation makes an important contribution to the ethical analysis of health care practice in humanitarian work.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>En contexte d’urgences humanitaires et de sinistres naturels, la capacité des agences locales et nationales à répondre aux besoins des populations affectées est lourdement entravée.  Dans ces situations de crise, des organismes internationaux d'aide humanitaire sont souvent impliqués pour offrir leur assistance.  Les professionnels des soins de santé jouent un rôle important dans ces interventions.  Ces contextes singuliers de pratique pour ces professionnels de la santé expatriés diffèrent beaucoup de l’environnement familier dans lequel ils évoluent dans leur pays d’origine.  Les cliniciens qui sont transportés d’un pays développé à des régions dévastées par des crises humanitaires vivent des changements d’environnement professionnel, social, culturel et juridique souvent drastiques.  Dans ce projet de thèse, j'examine l'éthique de la pratique en santé dans des zones de crises humanitaires.  En premier lieu, j’effectue une recension critique de la littérature consacrée à la bioéthique globale, à l’éthique de la santé globale et à l’éthique humanitaire en vue d’identifier la contribution de certains modèles éthiques et d’approches normatives sur les problèmes qui me préoccupent.  Je développe également une série de questions destinée aux professionnels de la santé pour les aider à mieux analyser la nature des enjeux moraux auxquels ils sont confrontés, de même que pour orienter leur processus décisionnel face aux dilemmes rencontrés.  Le volet empirique de ce programme de recherche examine l’expérience morale des professionnels des soins de santé en contexte de travail humanitaire, ainsi que les expériences des cliniciens des ressources et des contraintes pour aborder les enjeux moraux en situation de crise humanitaire.  Je propose des stratégies et des approches que les organismes humanitaires, les équipes locales d’intervenants, ainsi que les professionnels de la santé peuvent développ</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leigh Turner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm58z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx350</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613n0188"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comparisons of international seismic code provisions for bridges</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Drak El Sebai, Aguiade</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a comparison between the AASHTO-2004,  BSI-EN1998-2:2005, NBCC-2005 and the 2007 proposed AASHTO LRFD seismic design provisions with that of the 2006 CSA S6 Canadian Highway Bridge Design Code (CHBDC). A regular 2 span-90m long bridge was used to apply the seismic design loads determined from the codes investigated. The superstructure consists of a 2-lane prestressed concrete box girder, supported by a single column and two abutments. The single column is a 2400 mm circular pier with two different amounts of longitudinal reinforcements. One column had 36-45M longitudinal bars, transversely tied with 15M bars spaced at 50 mm. The second column contained 36-55M bars. The design of the bridge was carried out for three different seismic regions, Montreal, Toronto and Vancouver. In addition, the soil conditions were assumed to match those of NEHRP Soil Profile Types B and E. The research compared the effects of the seismic design spectra and overstrength factors in developing the design moments, shears and displacement ductility demands of the bridge. This research provides recommendations for updating the current CHBDC seismic design provisions.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse  présente une comparaison entre les normes « AASHTO-2004 », « BSI-EN1998-2:2005 », « CNB-2005 » ainsi qu’une comparaison entre les exigences de la nouvelle norme « AASHTO LRFD 2007 » et la norme « CSA-S6 2006 » du Code Canadien sur le Calcul des Ponts. Un pont régulier de deux travées ayant une longueur de 90 m à fait l’objet d’une analyse conformément aux exigences des divers normes et codes relatives à la conception parasismique. La superstructure consiste en un système composé d’une poutre-caisson en béton précontraint alors que l’infrastructure consiste d’un poteau et de deux culées. Le poteau (de diamètre de 2400 mm) avait deux quantités différentes d’armature longitudinales (36 barres - 45M  et 36 barres - 55M) avec des armatures transversales ayant un espacement de 50 mm.  Le pont à été conçu selon les exigences parasismiques de trois divers zones sismiques dont : Montréal, Toronto et Vancouver. Les conditions de sol de types B et E de la norme  « NEHRP » ont été utilisées lors de l’analyse. De plus, cette étude a comparé l’effet de divers spectres sismiques et facteurs de surcharge lors du calcul des moments et des efforts de cisaillement ainsi que lors de l’analyse de la ductilité de la structure.  Enfin, ce projet de recherche propose des recommandations  pour mettre à jour les provisions parasismiques du Code Canadien sur le Calcul des Ponts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denis Mitchell</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x311.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n0188</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386k95m"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of expression recognition in social information processing and poor social adjustment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>August, Pamela Joan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Children with poor social adjustment are at risk for a number of maladaptive outcomes in adolescence and adulthood, such as psychopathology, conduct problems, and substance abuse. Social information processing (SIP) theory consists of six distinct but interrelated steps through which individuals process and respond to incoming social information. The ability of individuals to accurately process social information at all six steps has been used to predict aspects of social adjustment such as aggression and social skills. Similarly, the ability of individuals to accurately process and recognize facial expressions of emotion has also been used to predict social adjustment. However, despite the presence of facial expressions as an important piece of social information, no researchers have attempted to examine the specific role of expression recognition in social information processing, or to determine whether or not expression recognition ability may contribute to the predictive power of the SIP model. The goal of the current study is to demonstrate that expression recognition is an integral yet overlooked aspect of SIP, specifically of the first two steps of processing, encoding, and interpretation of cues. Seventy-four elementary school students in grades three and four participated in this study. Verbal and nonverbal measures of encoding were used, as well as an attribution task to measure children’s ability to interpret cues. Participants completed measures of expression recognition accuracy and cognitive ability, and teachers were asked to respond to standardized questionnaires regarding the social skills and aggressive behaviour of participating students. Children who were accurate at recognizing facial expressions were also more accurate at processing social information. However, after accounting for the variance explained by age, ethnic group, and cognitive ability, expression recognition did not account for a significant amount of variance in teacher repor</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les enfants éprouvant des difficultés au plan de l’ajustement social présentent un risque élevé de vivre des problèmes d’ajustement à l’adolescence et à l’âge adulte, notamment la psychopathologie, les difficultés de conduite, et l’abus de substances.  La théorie du traitement de l’information sociale (social information processing theory – SIP) inclue six étapes associées mais distinctes au fil desquelles les individus traitent et répondent à l’information sociale leur étant présentée. L’habileté des individus à correctement traiter l’information sociale à chacune des six étapes du modèle SIP a été utilisée comme prédicteur de divers aspects de l’ajustement social, incluant l’agressivité et les habiletés sociales. De la même façon, l’habileté des individus à correctement traiter et reconnaître les expressions faciales de diverses émotions a également été utilisée comme prédicteur de l’ajustement social. Toutefois, malgré l’importance des expressions faciales en tant que source d’information sociale, les chercheurs n’ont pas tenté d’examiner le rôle spécifique de la reconnaissance des expressions faciales dans le traitement de l’information sociale, ou de déterminer si l’habileté à reconnaître les expressions faciales contribue au pouvoir prédicteur du modèle SIP. Le but de la présente étude est de démontrer que la reconnaissance des expressions faciales est une partie intégrale mais négligée du SIP, spécifiquement des deux premières étapes du traitement, soit l’encodage et l’interprétation des indices sociaux. Soixante-quatorze élèves de la troisième et quatrième année du primaire ont participé à cette étude. Des tâches d’encodage verbal et non-verbal ont été utilisées, ainsi qu’une tâche d’attribution mesurant l’habileté des enfants à interpréter les indices sociaux. Les participants ont complété des tâches de reconnaissance des exp</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ingrid Sladeczek</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw09m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386k95m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801ph90g"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of Collapsin Response Mediator Protein 1 (CRMP1) on cell migration and invasion in glioma</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shiroky, Jonah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le glioblastome multiforme (GBM) est un stade avancé de cancer du cerveau avec un très faible taux de survie.  Sa récurrence est assez fréquente, causée par la présence de cellules tumorales en dehors de la masse primaire, ce qui rend difficile la résection chirurgicale. Des recherches antérieures dans notre laboratoire ont suggéré un lien entre le pouvoir envahissant du GBM et CRMP1 (Collapsin Response Mediator Protein 1), un membre d'une famille de phosphoprotéines impliquées dans la dynamique du cytosquelette et déjà considéré comme un gène suppresseur d’invasion dans le cancer du poumon. Le but de cette étude était d'examiner le rôle du CRMP1 dans la migration cellulaire des GBM. Plusieurs autres membres de la famille CRMP ainsi que leurs isoformes épissées differentiellement (forme longue - L, la forme normale - S) ont également été examinés afin de déterminer les propriétés en commun. L’ADN complémentaire des CRMP a été transfecté dans les lignées de cellules de gliome (U87, U251N) pour générer des populations stables qui ont été caractérisées in vitro et in vivo sur le plan de la viabilité cellulaire, la migration cellulaire et la croissance de la tumeur. Bien qu'il n'y ait pas eu de différence significative dans la prolifération cellulaire par rapport a la lignée contrôle, beaucoup moins de cellules migrèrent dans un essai de type Boyden dans les lignées surexprimant soit CRMP1-S, CRMP2-S, ou CRMP4-S. Dans les souris thimoprivées, l'implantation intracérébrale de cellules surexprimant CRMP1-S a produit des tumeurs qui ont été nettement plus faible en volume par rapport à celles produites par des cellules contrôles. En outre, l'analyse des profils d'expression génique dans les échantillons des patients GBM recueillis par l'Institut national du cancer (Rembrandt) a démontré un lien entre la survie des patients et les niveaux du CRMP1 et CRMP4. En conclusion, nos résultats suggèrent que CRMPs 1,</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>GBM is an advanced-stage form of brain cancer with an extremely low survival rate.  Tumour reoccurrence is quite common, resulting from micropockets of tumour cells outside the primary mass, which makes surgical resection extremely difficult.  Previous research in our laboratory suggested a link between GBM invasiveness and  CRMP1 (Collapsin Response Mediator Protein 1), a member of a family of phosphoproteins involved in cytoskeletal dynamics and already considered a tumour invasion suppressor gene in Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)1.  The aim of this study was to examine the role of CRMP1 in GBM cell migration.  Several CRMP members and longer alternatively spliced variants (long form - L, normal form - S) were also examined to determine common/distinct properties.  CRMP cDNAs were transfected into glioma cell lines (U87, U251N) to generate stable pooled populations which were characterized in vitro and in vivo in terms of cell viability, cell migration and tumour growth. Although there was no significant difference in cell proliferation as compared to control neo-transfected glioma cell lines, significantly fewer cells migrated in a Boyden chemotactic assay in lines overexpressing CRMP1-S, CRMP2-S, or CRMP4-S.  In athymic mice, intracerebral implantation of cells overexpressing CRMP1-S yielded tumours that were significantly smaller in volume as compared to those produced by control glioma cells.  In addition, the analysis of gene expression profiles in GBM patient samples collected by the National Cancer Institute (REMBRANDT) established a link between patient survival and CRMP1 and CRMP4 levels.  In conclusion, our results suggest that CRMPs 1, 2 and 4 may regulate glioma cell migration and CRMP1 and CRMP4, may be involved in GBM patient survival.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Josephine Nalbantoglu</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8382143.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801ph90g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5t34sm036"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>CSA, revictimization, and dissociation: a meta-analysis investigation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Das, Alpana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Over the past decade, research attempts have been made to clarify the relationship between female child sexual abuse (CSA) and dissociation and furthermore, its impact on sexual revictimization.  However, these research efforts have yielded mixed findings, which have left the role of dissociation to still remain unclear.  Indeed, there has been an upsurge of research literature questioning the role of dissociation within revictimization frameworks, and moreover, whether dissociation should be further researched or dropped from further analysis.   Accordingly, the objective was set out to better understand the link between dissociation, CSA and revictimization.  As a result, this study was aimed at informing potential revisions to the role of dissociation, by utilizing a meta-analysis technique and comparing dissociation scores of both revictimized and non- revictimized women subsequent to CSA.   Following Lipsey &amp; Wilson’s (2001) guidelines, a comprehensive literature search identified 8 eligible studies, both from published and unpublished sources, appearing in the literature from 1987 to 2007.  Fixed effects analyses, incorporating a hedges g unbiased method indicated associations between dissociation, CSA and revictimization, by establishing a moderate effect size (d=0.38).  These meta-analytic findings suggest that among CSA survivors, dissociation is associated with sexual revictimization in women.  Furthermore, this thesis supports that dissociation should be reconsidered as a possible mediator, along with other psychological and systemic factors, which contribute to the sexual revictimization process in women subsequent to CSA.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Au cours de cette dernière décennie, des recherches ont tenté de clarifier le rapport entre l’agression sexuelle (AS) vécue par les filles durant leur enfance et les symptômes de dissociation, ainsi que son impact sur la revictimisation sexuelle.  Cependant, ces efforts ont donné des résultats mitigés, ce qui explique jusqu'à date le rôle ambigu de la dissociation.  Conséquemment, il y a eu une forte augmentation des recherches mettant en question le rôle de la dissociation dans le cadre de la revictimisation, et de plus, si la dissociation devrait être recherchée davantage ou exclue des analyses subséquentes. Dans cette lignée, l’objectif de la présente recherche était d’avoir une meilleure compréhension du lien entre la dissociation, l’AS durant l’enfance et la revictimisation. Cette étude visait à faire part de toutes révisions éventuelles du rôle de la dissociation, en utilisant une technique de méta-analyse et en comparant les scores de dissociation chez les femmes ayant subi une AS durant leur enfance et qui ont vécu une AS à nouveau à l’âge adulte de celles qui ne l’ont pas revécue. Suivant les directives de Lipsey et Wilson (2001), une recension systématique des écrits a identifié 8 études éligibles provenant de sources publiées et non-publiées, figurant dans la période des années 1987 à 2007.  Des analyses d’effets fixes, incorporant le g de Hedges, une méthode non biaisée, ont démontré, par le résultat d’une ampleur d’effet modérée (d=0.38), que la dissociation, l’AS durant l’enfance et la revictimisation sont liées. Ces résultats de méta-analyse suggèrent que, parmi les survivants d’AS durant l’enfance, la dissociation est associée à la revictimisation sexuelle chez les femmes. En outre, cette thèse soutient la position que la dissociation devrait être reconsidérée comme médiateur possible au même titre que d’autres facteurs psychologiques et systémiques, dans la$</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Delphine Collin-Vezina</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p14h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm036</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adr26xz98s"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of pre- and post- UV disinfection conditions on photoreactivation of fecal coliforms from a physiochemical wastewater effluent</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hallmich, Catherine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Diminuer la photoréactivation des bactéries suivant leur désinfection à l’UV peut entraîner une baisse considérable des coûts du capital et d’opération. Les objectifs de cette étude visent à déterminer quelles conditions, avant ou après le rayonnement à l’UV, permettent de diminuer la photoréactivation des coliformes fécaux contenus dans les eaux traitées de la Station d’Épuration des Eaux Usées de Montréal. Les résultats indiquent qu’à des doses d’UV de 10 et 20 mJ/cm2, un retard de 3 heures à l’illumination photoréactivante permet de prévenir la photoréactivation. De plus, une lumière photoréactivante de minimum 440 lux est nécessaire pour initier la photoréactivation, et 700 lux et plus est requis pour obtenir une photoréactivation maximale.Des expériences supplémentaires démontrent qu’une irradiation à la lumière visible avant ou pendant la désinfection à l’UV permet de diminuer la photoréactivation. L’effet est plus grand pour les bactéries d’hiver, chez lesquelles la photoréactivation diminue de moitié. Aussi, l’effet de la pré-illumination à la lumière visible est conservé pendant au moins 30 minutes. Finalement, les résultats suggèrent que les bactéries d’été ont une plus grande sensibilité à l’inactivation à l’UV et une plus faible capacité à photoréactiver que leurs consoeurs d’hiver.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Decreasing photoreactivation after wastewater UV disinfection can lead to considerable savings in capital and operating costs. Objectives of this study were to determine pre- and post-UV irradiation conditions able to decrease fecal coliform photoreactivation in a wastewater effluent from the Montreal Wastewater Treatment Plant.   Results of the study indicated that delaying exposure to photoreactivating light for three hours suppressed photoreactivation at UV doses of 10 and 20 mJ/cm2. At least 440 lux of visible light was needed to initiate photoreactivation, and 700 lux or greater for maximum effect.  Additional experiments showed that photoreactivation was significantly decreased when visible light (400-800 nm) was simultaneously applied prior and during UV irradiation. This was more obvious for winter samples, where photoreactivation was decreased by nearly 50 %. Moreover, the effect of pre-illumination with visible light was maintained for at least 30 minutes. Finally, summer populations were more sensitive to inactivation and less able to photoreactivate than winter populations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ronald Gehr</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q483.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26xz98s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50gx74x"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Heat transfer studies of liquidparticle mixtures in cans subjected to end-over-end processing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sablani, Shyam Swaroop</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Overall heat transfer coefficient (U) and fluid to particle heat transfer coefficient (h$ sb{ rm fp}$) in canned liquid/particle mixtures, subjected to end-over-end processing, were experimentally evaluated. A methodology was developed to measure heat transfer coefficients, while allowing the movement of the particle inside the can, by attaching it to a flexible fine wire thermocouple. Heat transfer coefficients were evaluated under two conditions: (1) with a single particle in the can, (2) with multiple particles in the can. In the single particle experiments, a spherical particle was used to evaluate the influence of system parameters and product parameters on associated U and h$ sb{ rm fp}$. Increasing values of all four system variables improved the heat transfer coefficients. The effects of rotational speed and headspace were most significant. The particle density had no significant effect, but liquid viscosity and rotational speed had significant effects on U. The h$ sb{ rm fp}$ values were influenced by rotational speed, liquid viscosity and particle density, with particle density most significant. With multiple particles (Nylon) in cans, the associated convective heat transfer coefficients (U and h$ sb{ rm fp}$) were evaluated. Heat transfer coefficients increased with decreasing particle diameter, increasing particle concentration and increasing sphericity. Flow visualization studies were carried out. With a single particle, liquid viscosity, particle density and rotational speed influenced particle motion. With multiple particles, motion/mixing was influenced by particle concentration, size, and shape, liquid viscosity and rotational speed. Dimensionless correlations were developed for the predictive modeling of convective heat transfer coefficients. For U with a single particle, Nusselt number (Nu) was correlated to Reynolds number (Re), Prandtl number (Pr) and relative can headspace while with multiple particles, Re, Pr, ratio of particle to liquid concentration, relative particle diameter and particle sphericity were found to be significant. For h$ sb{ rm fp}$ with a single particle in the can, three different correlations, one each for a sphere, a cylinder and a cube were developed and the Nu was correlated to Re, Pr, density simplex, relative can headspace and the ratio of the sum of the diameter of rotation and diameter of the can to the can diameter. With multiple particles Nu was correlated to Re or Peclet number, ratio of particle to liquid thermal conductivity, particle to liquid concentration and particle sphericity. A multi-layer artificial neural network (ANN) was used to model heat transfer parameters under conduction and convection heating conditions. The network was found to predict optimal sterilization temperatures with an accuracy of $ pm$0.5$ sp circ$C, and other responses such as process time and integrated heating time for quality attribute with less than 5% associated errors. Multi-layer neural network models were trained based on the experimental values of U and h$ sb{ rm fp}$, was obtained. The trained network was found to predict U and h$ sb{ rm fp}$ with less than 3% and 5% errors, respectively. The neural network models were more accurate than the dimensionless number models, for predicting U and h$ sb{ rm fp}$. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ramaswamy, H. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g6619.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gx74x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Heat -- Transmission</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canning and preserving</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cz067"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biophysical and functional properties of lipid-modified proteins and model lipopeptides</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shahinian, Sarkis Serge</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Three related studies were carried out to understand better the physical properties, cellular function, and means to prepare artificially proteins 'anchored' to membranes by two hydrophobic chains. The first study entailed the development of efficient methodologies to conjugate antibody Fab$ sp prime$ fragments to suitable lipid 'anchors' in liposomes, to allow for the targeted delivery of liposome-associated materials to cells expressing the appropriate cell surface determinant. To monitor the production of Fab$ sp prime$ fragments bearing reactive thiol groups, we developed a maleimide-polyethylene glycol (PEG) conjugate 'thiol reagent' for use in an SDS-PAGE mobility shift assay. Optimizing conditions for Fab$ sp prime$ preparation developed by this approach, we achieved efficient and reproducible coupling of Fab$ sp prime$ fragments to liposomes via a novel lipid 'anchor'. Such Fab$ sp prime$-'targeted' liposomes efficiently delivered encapsulated materials to cultured cells in vitro. The second study used lipid-modified peptides to investigate the strength of membrane anchoring conferred by dual lipid modifications of the types attached to various intracellular proteins. Based on kinetic measurements of interbilayer transfer of such peptides and peptide-macromolecule conjugates, we suggest that doubly-modified proteins exhibit extremely slow rates of spontaneous intermembrane transfer. We have proposed mechanisms by which this property of 'dual-anchored' proteins may be exploited to achieve efficient subcellular targeting by 'trapping' mechanisms. The third study sought to assess current models of the mechanism of preferential localization of glycosylphosphatidylinositol (GPI)-proteins to specialized plasma membrane invaginations known as caveolae. This was accomplished using cell membrane-incorporated lipid-PEG-biotin-streptavidin conjugates, whose lateral distribution under various conditions ($ pm$ crosslinking) shows significant overlap with that of endogenous GPI-proteins. We propose a novel mechanistic model based on 'surface-crowding' effects, for the preferential association of lipid-anchored molecules with caveolae, particularly upon crosslinking.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Silvius, John R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xz992.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz067</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biophysics, General</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am900nw15h"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ṭûbâ : an African eschatology in Islam</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ross, Eric, 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thesis "Tuba: an African eschatology in Islam" adopts afrocentric hypotheses for the study of Islam. First, the thesis demonstrates how certain phenomena specific to Islam in Africa, those usually qualified as products of religious syncretism, are on the contrary indicative of the ongoing process of synthesis and enrichment within Islam, and, secondly, that African spiritual tradition continues today as in the past to participate along with others in this constructive process. In order to demonstrate this hypothesis the spiritual significance of the modern Islamic holy city of Touba in Senegal will be analyzed. Touba is named for the Tree of Paradise (Tuba) of Islamic tradition and the holy city has been constructed around the singular arboreal image. The spiritual meaning imparted by Touba, a deliberate creation, is expressed in the topography of the holy city, in its geographic configuration. The thesis adapts the methodologies of spatial analysis, and specifically the semiotic reading of landscape, to the study of a religious phenomenon, i.e., the creation of a holy city. in order to explain the significance of this holy city for Islamic eschatology, the meanings which three distinct religious traditions (Islam, West Africa, Ancient Egypt) have attached to the image of the cosmic tree are inventoried. The tree as archetype here serves to establish the continuity of African religious thought from pharaonic Egypt to modern Muslim Senegal.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Turgay, A. Uner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s401q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw15h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Islamic shrines -- Senegal -- Touba</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islam -- Senegal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muslim pilgrims and pilgrimages -- Senegal -- Touba</dc:subject><dc:subject>Touba (Senegal) -- Religious life and customs</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75r937p"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intimate relations : reflections on history, power, and gender in Koriak women's lives in northern Kamchatka</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rethmann, Petra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis deals with issues of gender, power, and history in Koriak women's lives in northern Kamchatka. The Koriak represent one of the indigenous populations of Russia's north. They migrate with the reindeer over vast, rugged tundra territory, and live by the products the animals and the land yield. This cultural order has increasingly been threatened by encroachments of first the Soviet, and now the Russian, state. Today, the Koriak are marginalized within the powerful model of the nation state, and their lives are marked by dissolution and despair. I conducted my research in two villages, Tymlat and Ossora, situated at the northeastern shore of the Kamchatka peninsula. In particular I worked with Koriak women whose various discourses of love, erotics, and desire I examine in this thesis. I adopt a wider framework of history, state power, and marginalization to analyze their practices of femininity and sexuality. In order to exemplify the Koriak experience of everyday life in northern Kamchatka I draw on women's narratives to elucidate various strategies of gender and cultural positionings in the life-world of Tymlat and Ossora. Moreover, I explore Koriak descriptions of Soviet history as a critical commentary on Soviet and Russian descriptions of historical processes in northern Kamchatka.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Galaty, John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j703s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r937p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Koryak women</dc:subject><dc:subject>Feminist anthropology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Koryaks -- Social conditions</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atq57ns47p"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>spa</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Hispanic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>El monólogo en el teatro español desde los años setenta : un estudio sobre las funciones del lenguaje en un "nuevo" género dramático</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lauzière, Carole</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The object of this thesis is to study the monologue, a dramatic genre that re-emerged on the Spanish literary scene in the 1970s. Despite the fact that a number of well-known Iberian playwrights have cultivated this genre assiduously over the past three decades, their work has received relatively little critical attention from either academic or theatre circles. What is sought here, therefore, is the means to demonstrate the importance and richness of the monologue as an autonomous dramatic creation. To do this it was necessary to establish a sufficiently large corpus--some eighty long and short monologues--and identify those particular conventions and the structural diversity that would make possible the formulation of a theory of connected language functions in the monologue by adapting existing theoretical principles to the study of this singular genre. The application of this theoretical construct enabled me to determine the nature of the functions of expression, communication and persuasion present in the discourse of a single speaker. Specifically, in considering the function of expression I reflect both upon the coherent discourse that derives from the (exterior) verbalization of (interior) thought and emotion, and upon the objectives and consequences of such expressions of the mental and emotional states of the individual. Secondly, I focus attention on the same verbal discourse inasmuch as it reflects the complex function of communication manifested in both an immanent and in a transcendental form. Such complexity derives from the fact that, if verbal discourse here is enunciated either in isolation or before an interiorized addressee (a fictional being), it is always emitted in the "presence" of an external addressee (the theatre audience/or reader). Finally, my study of the function of persuasion underscores the idea of empowerment: the authority of the word that is wielded by the monologist upon his/her addressee(s), a verbal manipulation that takes place both within the fictional world and beyond. In short, this thesis seeks to show how the monologue as a fictional dramatic genre questions the viability of interpersonal relationships.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sibbald, K. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sf30w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57ns47p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Spanish drama -- 20th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Monologue</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f514c"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Built environment education : a curriculum paradigm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Langdon, Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The expansion of Built Environment Education into art programs is a relatively recent phenomenon but very timely. The need to develop in students an understanding of their living environment is urgent as they inherit a world that is experiencing the depletion of its resources and erosion of its ecological balance. There is a fundamental need for more comprehensive curriculum planning in built environment education. The goal of this research is to develop a curriculum paradigm that can be used to create curriculum plans and instructional designs for built environment education as part of the art class in secondary schools. The built environment content of this curriculum paradigm is based on the active investigation of the students' internal world with all its different perceptions and lived experience and how this affects their understanding of the greater built environment. Through a more intense investigation of the greater built environment, the students will then analyze the effect that this environment has on their own perceptions and living habits. By developing a more conscious understanding of the built environment, the students will be better equipped to make informed decisions on how to better adapt to or change their environment. A guiding principle for the curriculum paradigm was to ensure that the introduction of a new subject area, such as built environment education, into art education curriculum involved processes of creativity and discovery along with self-reflective and participatory action for both the teacher and students. To be effective, the content material must not only be accessible through the traditional modes of academic literature research but also made valid through observation, reflection and interaction with the particular built environment of the teacher and students themselves. Vigilance and active participation in the process of urban change are vital. These changes can only be effective and enduring if we acknowledge the capacity of the built environment to enrich our lives as private and communal beings. One of the essential goals of this curriculum paradigm is to capture the excitement and potential that the built environment offers as a pervasive agent for understanding and celebrating constructed past, present and future.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dillon, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zj29v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f514c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Architecture -- Study and teaching (Secondary)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cities and towns -- Study and teaching (Secondary)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Art -- Study and teaching (Secondary)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741t39z"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of computer-assisted methods for the resonance assignment of heteronuclear 3D NMR spectra of proteins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Kuo-Bin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An automated sequential assignment protocol for proteins is presented using heteronuclear 3D NMR. For the observed amino acid spin systems, the protocol includes an algorithm to determine their amino acid types. For the detected polypeptides, the protocol includes another algorithm to sequentially map them to the primary sequence. The former algorithm measures the similarity between the detected spin systems and the 20 standard amino acid patterns. Both chemical shift and topological likeness are considered. Knowing the amino acid types, the mapping algorithm assigns the detected polypeptides to proper positions within the protein primary sequence. The assignment protocol can be applied to spin systems generated from many different approaches. To demonstrate the assignment protocol, a few computer algorithms were designed to deduce the backbone and side-chain spin systems of proteins using heteronuclear 3D NMR. Magnetization transfer through peptide bonds can be observed in triple resonance 3D NMR. To automate the backbone assignment using the through-bond correlations, a generic algorithm is proposed. This algorithm searches and merges cross peaks among all available NMR spectra. Individual spin systems can be extracted and linked to create polypeptide chains based on the observed interresidue correlations. The algorithm is not restricted to any particular type of experiment. It is shown to be applicable to two sets of NMR spectra: the five experiment set of 3D HNCO, HNCA, HN(CO)CA, HCACO, $ sp{15}$N TOCSY-HMQC and the one-experiment set of 3D CBCANH. For the side chain assignment, an automated approach using a constrained partitioning algorithm has been developed to extract side chain spin systems of proteins by analyzing the 3D HCCH-COSY/TOCSY spectra. The extracted amino acid spin systems show the chemical shifts of the component nuclear spins as well as the connectivities between these spins. A 90-residue protein, the N-domain of chicken skeletal troponin-C</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sanctuary, B. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs036.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t39z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Analytical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Physical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqv33rz24b"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation, expression and cloning of mammalian amino acid transporter</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lin, Guorong</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Using a reconstitution assay, we have shown that the acidic phospholipids, phosphatidic acid and cardiolipin are specifically required for the reconstruction of $ rm Na sp+$ dependent transport system A from Ehrlich cells. The unsaturated fatty acyl in the $ beta$ position in the phosphatidic acid is essential for optimal reconstitution of system A transport. Regulation of system A transport has been studied for a few decades. Insulin has been shown to regulate this transporter in various cell types. The requirement for de novo protein synthesis of transporter has usually been implicated by indirect evidence. We directly proved this mechanism using oocyte expression with the mRNA from GF-14 cells treated with insulin. In Ehrlich cells, however, the regulatory mechanism affected by insulin appears to involve translocation of the transporter from an internal membrane to the plasma membrane. In an attempt to identify an amino acid transporter from Ehrlich cells by complementation in yeast, we have isolated a clone referred to E51 from Ehrlich cell. Clone E51 is highly homologous to $ gamma$ actin, a cytoskeletal protein. Expression of E51 stimulates endogenous amino acid transporters in oocytes and GF-14 lymphocytes, suggesting that E51 is a regulator. A second clone L21 has also been isolated from L6 cells by complementation of yeast transport mutation. L21 has a unique amino acid sequence with a predicted molecular weight of 25 kDa and 4 potential transmembrane domains. Yeast expressed L21 show characteristics of both ASC and L transporters. However, transport of L21 also prefers acidic conditions, inconsistent with properties of most mammalian transporters. The mammalian transporter represented by L21 remains to be defined.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Johnstone, Rose M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v014c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz24b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj9602241s"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Solvent extraction of rhodium from chloride solutions in the presence of SnCl2 with Kelex 100tm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Benguerel, Elyse</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of this work was to devise and investigate a solvent extraction system for rhodium, from aqueous chloride solutions, having potential industrial applicability. The extractant investigated was Kelex 100, a commercially available derivative of 8-hydroxyquinoline. Ultimately, two different systems were developed. Both are based on an initial complexation reaction between the aqueous rhodium chloride complexes, (RhCl$ rm sb{6-n}(H sb2O) sb{n} rbrack sp{(3-n)-}$ and stannous chloride, referred to as the activation stage, but the two systems use a different Sn:Rh molar ratio. In both cases, the Rh-Sn complexes, either (Rh(SnCl$ sb3) sb5 rbrack sp{4-}$ or (RhCl$ rm sb3(SnCl sb3) sb3 rbrack sp{3-},$ respond well to extraction with Kelex 100. One of the main differences between the two systems is in the stripping medium which is used to transfer the rhodium from the loaded organic phase back into an aqueous phase. In the case of the high Sn:Rh ratio feeds, the stripping stage is based on sulfuric acid, whereas in the case of low Sn:Rh ratio feeds, the rhodium is stripped from the organic phase using a sulfite containing hydrochloric acid solution. The two systems were characterized in terms of their equilibrium and kinetic behaviour during all three stages; activation, extraction, and stripping. Activation was found to proceed either at room temperature or at elevated temperatures and the above-mentioned expected Rh-Sn complexes were identified through $ sp{119}$Sn NMR and Raman spectroscopy. The extraction stage was found to be quantitative for rhodium and it was also found to be very rapid, with contact times of less than five minutes sufficient for rhodium extraction. The extraction mechanism was determined to be ion-pair formation with the protonated Kelex 100 molecules at a stoichiometry such that the overall charge in the organic phase is neutral, i.e., three Kelex 100 molecules for (RhCl$ rm sb3(SnCl sb3) sb3 rbrack sp{3-}$ and four for (Rh(SnCl$ sb3) sb5 rbrack sp{4-}.$ The stripping stages were the most problematic for both systems. In one case, the system was eventually abandoned due to limitations in the amount of rhodium which could be transferred to the sulfuric acid strip solution. For the low Sn:Rh system, reasonable rhodium transfer and concentration level were obtained. The rhodium complex in the strip solution has been proposed to be (RhCl$ rm sb2(SO sb3) rbrack sp{3-}.$ Strip solutions up to $4 times10 sp{-2}$M in rhodium concentration have been produced, from initial feed solutions having a rhodium concentration of about $4 times10 sp{-3}$M. Preliminary flowsheets are proposed for further refinement for both systems, although only the second system, the low Sn:Rh ratio system which uses sulfite stripping, is advocated for further development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Demopoulos, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v9497.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602241s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Industrial</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xk18z"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>In vivo radiolabeling and immunoblotting studies on the formation, secretion, and short-term fate of enamel proteins produced by rat incisor ameloblasts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Wei-Yu, 1950-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Enamel is produced by a layer of ectodermally derived cells called ameloblasts. These cells first create the entire thickness of enamel in the form of a protein-rich, partially mineralized extracellular layer. During the maturation stage, most of the proteins are degraded and replaced by mineral. At least three types of proteins--amelogenins, enamelins/non-amelogenins/tuftelins, and proteinases--are believed to be involved in enamel formation, but the exact number of secretory proteins produced by ameloblasts and the changes in molecular weight these proteins undergo in traversing the secretory pathway and following their release extracellularly are still very controversial. The purpose of this investigation was to use conventional radiolabeling and immunoprecipitation techniques in combination with rapid freeze-drying, dissection, and extraction procedures that optimized sample preservation to characterize intracellular forms of the main enamel matrix proteins produced by ameloblasts and to determine their fate over the first 4 hours following their secretion. The data indicate that ameloblasts translate 6, and possibly 7 or more, proteins that are secreted directly into the developing enamel layer. One of the proteins, starting at 57 kDa, is posttranslationally modified with sugars and sulfate and is released as a 65 kDa sulfated protein that is rapidly converted into a 49 kDa and 25 kDa, and numerous other intermediate, derived forms. Another protein undergoes phosphorylation and is secreted as a 27 kDa phosphoprotein with immunoreactivity different from classic amelogenin. Three proteins near 31, 27, and 23 kDa appear as the primary secretory forms of classic amelogenin formed by rat incisor ameloblasts. The 31 kDa protein is rapidly converted into a 29 kDa form extracellularly but the 27 and 23 kDa proteins do not show any major changes over 4 hours. Additional proteins of unknown class-type near 31 and 29 kDa also appear to be secreted by rat incisor amelob</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Smith, Charles E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j042k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk18z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278v78p"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Digital image analysis of rock fragmentation from blasting</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bedair, Ayman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A novel digital image analysis technique to measure the size of fragments on the surface of a muck-pile is presented in this thesis. The technique takes into consideration the physical characteristics of fragment representation and measurement problems. Using an adaptive smoothing filter prior to edge detection, each fragment on the surface is represented by a group of edge segments outlining its boundaries. These segments are then grouped to form continuous contours. A multi-layer analysis of the digital image is then formulated where fragments on the surface are grouped into three layers, each of which is categorized by global characteristics and is related to other neighbouring layers by local characteristics. These local relationships between the layers are used to approximate the missing parts of the fragment contour. An extensive analysis of the sieving process is used in building the relationship between the shape and the size of individual fragments. Using this relation, a new multivariable measure for each fragment is developed. These measures are used in estimating the size distribution of the muck-pile and compared with other existing measurement techniques. This comparison proves the robustness of the technique developed in this thesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daneshmend, L. K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk197.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278v78p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj9602240h"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design and implementation of an autonomous inductively coupled plasma atomic emission spectrometer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Branagh, Wayne A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The design and implementation of a framework for the automated analysis of samples by inductively coupled plasma atomic emission spectroscopy (ICP-AES) is presented. Various components of this framework have been explored and validated. After initial work was undertaken to determine a suitable pattern recognition technique for sample classification, approaches for detecting the presence of a problematic matrix, and for selecting analysis conditions and calibration methodologies were developed. For the small universe of 14 elements used, the system performed well when matrix effects were due to concomitants in the examined universe. The application of generalized regression neural networks (GRNN) to compensate for spectral interferences and matrix effects and for correcting long-term drift was also examined. In post-processing the analysis results, the size of the GRNN training sets were found to be too small to permit accurate correction of matrix effects though accurate drift correction was possible.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Salin, Eric D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mw99x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602240h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Analytical</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>