<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9c67wr515"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mantle source and petrogenesis of kimberlites from the Foxtrot Kimberlite Field of northern Québec, Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Patterson, Michael Vincent, 1964-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Kimberlite whole rock geochemistry has been under-appreciated in deciphering Group I kimberlite petrogenesis. Although there is considerable debate on the definition of Group I kimberlite, there is agreement on certain characteristics. These include that Group I kimberlites are ultramafic rocks (MgO &gt;15 wt%), have near primitive mantle nickel (~ 1400 ppm) and chromium (~1600 ppm) contents, have close to bulk silicate earth radiogenic isotopic signatures, are volatile rich (predominantly CO2) and have stable isotopic signatures typical of mantle sources. The debate, however, centers on petrogenetic models and parental magmatic compositions of Group I kimberlites. Petrogenetic models include both low degree (&lt;1 %) partial melting of metasomatized asthenospheric mantle (Dalton and Presnall, 1998a; 1998b; Becker and Le Roex, 2006) and, conversely, high degree partial melting (10&lt;20 %) of metasomatized veined asthenospheric mantle (Mitchell, 1995, 2004). Inferred kimberlite parental magma compositions have been suggested to be low silica (&lt;5 wt%) and high CO2 (&lt;44 wt%) melts, as suggested by high-pressure melt experiments conducted on synthetic carbonatized mantle (Dalton &amp; Presnall, 1998a, 1998b), or much higher silica (&lt;30 wt%) and lower CO2 (&lt;12 wt%) melts as suggested by geochemical analysis of aphanitic kimberlite (Price et al., 2000; Kopylova et al., 2007). In an effort to contribute to the resolution of this debate on petrogenic models and parental magma compositions of Group I kimberlites, I have completed a systematic investigation of the whole rock geochemistry and petrology of three kimberlite occurrences in the Foxtrot Kimberlite Field of Northern Quebec. A clear correlation exists between whole rock chemistry, mantle source, and diamond grade of the three Group I kimberlites in the Foxtrot Kimberlite Field. Two phases, olivine and carbonate, dominant theserocks and thus control the kimberlites geochemistry. Electron microprobe analysis of over 800 olivines in the Foxtrot kimberlite indicate that it is predominantly xenocrystic (Mg# (Mg/(Mg+Fe)) of 91.5), largely derived from harzburgite mantle, but the absence of harzburgitic orthopyroxene in the Foxtrot kimberlites suggests that it has been assimilated. Whole rock geochemistry (major and trace elements) of the Foxtrot hypabyssal kimberlite dykes indicate they have chemical characteristics similar to Group I kimberlite from the Slave Province. The olivine content of the Foxtrot kimberlites, and thus their Mg#'s, are positively correlated with diamond abundance indicating that diamond grade is a reflection of the incorporation of harzburgite mantle. These results indicate that Group I kimberlite petrogenesis in the Foxtrot example is best modeled as a mixture of harzburgitic mantle xenocrysts and a carbonate rich fluid, and that the parental magma is silica poor "5 wt %) and CO 2 rich (&lt;40 wt%).</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rs597.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wr515</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Kimberlite -- Québec (Province) -- Otish Mountains Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Petrogenesis -- Québec (Province) -- Otish Mountains Region</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021j773"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The law of neutrality in outer space</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jarman, Robert W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Satellite telecommunications, global navigation and remote sensing systems are key drivers in the ongoing transformation of an industrial based global economic order to one increasingly dominated by information services. A growing number of States are establishing an independent presence in outer space and all States (and indeed, individuals) can access a broad range of affordable space-related products and services (e.g., Google Earth imagery, GPS receivers, and global voice and data transmissions). Consistent with broad historical trends, these technologies are inevitably influencing the way States think about, plan for, and conduct warfare. Inspired by the prospect of seizing the ultimate "high ground" of outer space and achieving "information superiority" over an enemy, militaries around the world are rapidly pursuing independent space capabilities and adapting their strategies, doctrine and force structures to reflect these capabilities. These trends have prompted various political and legal efforts to ban the placement and/or use of weapons in outer space. As these efforts have failed to gain traction and seem unlikely to do so in the foreseeable future, this thesis argues that existing bodies of international law grounded in a pragmatic acceptance of armed conflict must be consulted if humankind wishes to mitigate the impact and spread of warfare conducted in, from and through outer space. In particular, this thesis will examine how the traditional customary principles underlying the law of neutrality may be reconceptualized by States to serve as a mechanism to mediate competing claims of belligerents and neutrals during armed conflict in outer space. After a brief introduction, Chapters One and Two will develop the economic and military trends discussed above. Chapter Three will provide an overview of the relevant international law governing military activities in outer space. Chapter four will analyze the law governing State responsibility for outer space activities to determine which State(s) will bear primary international responsibility for satellite support provided to belligerents during armed conflict. Chapter Five will provide a detailed overview of the law of neutrality and attempt a preliminary analysis of how belligerent and neutral States may seek to adapt this law to suit their interests during armed conflict in outer space. Concluding that the law of neutrality may serve to mitigate the impact and spread of armed conflict in outer space, this thesis offers various proposals designed to facilitate the application of this law.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182p81j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021j773</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Space warfare</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neutrality</dc:subject><dc:subject>Astronautics, Military -- Law and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612s258"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Access to health care services : East-End Montreal (Quebec) English-speaking elderly experience</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thomas, Rosemary Hellen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To better understand Anglophone elderly experience in accessing health care services in a Francophone area, it is important to look beyond availability of healthcare services near their homes. This study explored factors such as language competence, preference, motivation, reaching and waiting times, as contributors to elderly people's choice. A questionnaire designed for this study was administered to 199 males and females, aged 55 years and older, recruited from the only Anglophone Seniors' Centre in East-End Montreal. It was found that elderly people with limited French proficiency were more likely to travel out of their area for healthcare services, resulting in significantly longer average travel and waiting times. Of those who would have liked an interpreter, very few were actually able to get one. The most frequently expressed need was for more English or bilingual workers and services. To improve access and enhance elderly people's quality of life, training and intervention programs need to be developed in collaboration with the government.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pr526.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612s258</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health services accessibility -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Older people -- Medical care -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vp64h"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The regulation of human B cell effector cytokine profiles by exogenous T helper cell cytokines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ghorayeb, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Bar-Or laboratory recently reported that human B cells from normal subjects can produce either pro-inflammatory (TNF-alpha; LT) or regulatory (IL-10) effector cytokines depending on their context of activation. It was of interest to investigate the change in B cell cytokine profiles from normal subjects when activated in the context of a Th1 pro-inflammatory environment or a Th2 anti-inflammatory environment. It was found that the B cell regulatory network of effector cytokines from normal subjects is significantly modulated depending on the local cytokine milieu. In addition, it was of interest to study how MS patients' B cell cytokine network would respond in a Th1 pro-inflammatory and a Th2 anti-inflammatory context. It was found that MS patients' B cell cytokine network was dysregulated compared to B cell responses from normal subjects. The findings define a novel regulatory network involving human B cells from normal subjects and point to a newly discovered abnormality in MS patients' B cells.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b710x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp64h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>B-Lymphocytes -- immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>T-Lymphocytes, Helper-Inducer -- immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multiple Sclerosis -- immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>T-Lymphocytes -- immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5t34sn98z"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pharmacologic inhibition of insulin receptor tyrosine kinase activity has antineoplastic effects similar to alloxan-induced insulin deficiency with less acute metabolic toxicity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dool, Carly Jade, 1985-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Recent population studies provide evidence that individuals with high circulating insulin levels have a poor prognosis and/or increased risk of cancer development; however, laboratory studies concerning the role of insulin in breast cancer biology are sparse. We compared the growth of 4T1 murine breast cancer allografts in control mice, alloxan-induced hypoinsulinemic mice, and mice treated with the insulin/insulin-like growth factor-1 receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitor BMS-536924. Both interventions significantly decreased tumor growth versus control and decreased pathway activation downstream of the insulin receptor as reflected by Aktser473 phosphorylation status in the neoplastic tissue. Alloxan-treated mice exhibited signs of insulin deficiency, while BMS-536924-treated animals showed only minor metabolic derangements. Skeletal muscle displayed reduced pAktser473 in alloxan-treated mice. In contrast, BMS-536924 treatment increased pAktser473 in muscle. This raises the possibility that the relative lack of metabolic toxicity of BMS-536924 involves varying tissue levels of the drug. These results support the view that host insulin physiology is a potentially modifiable determinant of breast cancer behaviour.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988p64c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sn98z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mice, Inbred BALB C</dc:subject><dc:subject>Receptor, IGF Type 1 -- antagonists &amp; inhibitors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Benzimidazoles -- pharmacology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diabetes Mellitus, Experimental</dc:subject><dc:subject>Receptor, Insulin -- antagonists &amp; inhibitors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mice</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pyridones -- pharmacology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Breast Neoplasms -- metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gm09d"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Maternal dietary fat intake alters the neonatal stress response and metabolic profile in the offspring : participation of the endocannabinoid system?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>D'Asti, Esterina, 1984-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Endocannabinoids are products of phospholipid-derived arachidonic acid that regulate hypothalamus-pituitary-adrenal axis activity. We hypothesize that differences in the quality and quantity of maternal dietary fat will modulate the neonatal phospholipid arachidonic acid content of the brain affecting the stress response via differences in endocannabinoid concentration of stress-activated brain areas. Dams were fed a 5% (C) or 300.10 fat diet rich in either n-6 (C, HF) or n-3 (HFF) fat during the perinatal period. PND4-5 HFF milk displays a reduced n-6/n-3 ratio compared to C and HF milk. PND10 hypothalamic and hippocampal PL AA levels are reduced in HFF pups relative to C and HF offspring; and predict endocannabinoid levels in a region-specific manner. In all pups pre-treated with an endocannabinoid receptor antagonist (AM251) or an inhibitor of the endocannabinoid degradative enzyme (URB597), basal and stress-induced ACTH secretion dose-dependently increased. Moreover, HFF pups exhibited a tendency towards reduced AM251 sensitivity under stressful conditions. These data suggest that the nature of perinatal dietary fat can differentially influence neonatal brain arachidonic acid levels and their endocannabinoid derivatives; and endocannabinoid signaling may be altered between diet groups since pups exhibit differences in sensitivity to endocannabinoid receptor blockade.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hd42c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gm09d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rats</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rats, Sprague-Dawley</dc:subject><dc:subject>Animals, Newborn</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stress, Psychological -- physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Receptors, Cannabinoid -- physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dietary Fats -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Endocannabinoids -- physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429f12b"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of 5,10-methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase and nutritional deficiencies in cardiac development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chan, Jessica See Wen, 1984-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Disruptions in folate metabolism are known to increase the risk for neural tube defects (NTD) and this is preventable by folic acid supplementation. However, the relationship between folate metabolism and cardiac development remains unclear. The interaction between other folate pathway nutrients, choline and riboflavin, and folate metabolism was studied in a murine model of methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR) deficiency. Maternal choline deficiency, riboflavin deficiency and MTHFR deficiency adversely affected embryonic or heart development. The promoters of MTHFR were also examined for interactions with GATA-4, TBX5, MEF2A and NKX-2.5, known transcription factors of cardiac development. Upstream promoter activity was increased in the presence of GATA-4 and this interaction was further enhanced upon the addition of MEF2A. TBX5 appeared to decrease upstream promoter activity. GATA-4 modestly increased downstream promoter activity. These results highlight the importance of adequate nutrient intake during pregnancy and provide a link between folate metabolism and cardiac development.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hg83q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429f12b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Diet</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heart Defects, Congenital -- etiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Methylenetetrahydrofolate Reductase (NADPH2) -- deficiency</dc:subject><dc:subject>Folic Acid Deficiency -- complications</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mice</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heart Defects, Congenital -- enzymology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n2042762"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of HD-PTP phosphatase activity and identification of its substratesbinding partners</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Yu Ling</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Histidine-Domain-Protein-Tyrosine-Phosphatase (HD-PTP) has been classified as a non-transmembrane protein tyrosine phosphatase (PTP), however, its catalytic activity has not been appropriately characterized. In this thesis, the tyrosine phosphatase activity of HD-PTP was characterized. To do so, the HD-PTP protein was successfully purified using the FLAG-TAG purification system and an enzymatic assay was carried out using the DiFMUP fluorogenic substrate. My results suggest that HD-PTP is an inactive PTP that can be reactivated upon the back mutation of a conserved amino acid located in its catalytic domain motif 9, which diverges from the PTP consensus sequence. Interestingly, the gene which encodes for HD-PTP is located within the tumor suppressor region on the human chromosome 3p21.3. Furthermore, we determined through colony formation assays that the active mutation does not affect the tumor suppressor potential of HD-PTP. Although wild type HD-PTP is an inactive tyrosine phosphatase, it may act as a natural trapping mutant, thus preserving its strong binding potential for phosphorylated signaling proteins. Since the active HD-PTP mutant should have lost its ability to bind phosphorylated signaling proteins, it was used in a substrate trapping experiment to identify potential binding partners. Four putative binding partners were then purified and identified through multidimensional protein identification technique (MudPIT). Lastly, cell lines that stably express HD-PTP were generated for future studies in the identification of binding partners.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945v57d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n2042762</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Catalysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Protein Tyrosine Phosphatases, Non-Receptor -- metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5t34sn997"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic characterization of gamma-aminobutyrate metabolism in Sinorhizobium meliloti</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Trottier, Oliver</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Transcriptional fusion mutants and Tn5-B20 transposon mutants were isolated where the only genes affected are believed to either be involved in the hypothetical GABA shunt or code for subunits of the alpha-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase enzyme complex of Sinorhizobium meliloti. The growth phenotypes of Rm30222 (gabT) and eight mutants in gabD1, 2, 3, and 4 on minimal media were comparable to that of the wild-type. Compared to wild-type, Rm30222 (gabT) lacked alpha-ketoglutarate-dependent gamma-aminobutyrate transaminase activity showed high induction of gabT on GABA but produced green plants indicative of being Fix+. Mutants in gabD alleles maintained wild-type levels of succinic semialdehyde dehydrogenase activity and could fix nitrogen as well as the wild-type in symbiosis. Mutation of sucB encoding a subunit of a-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase produced a mutant, Rm30230, that initially had difficulty growing on minimal media supplemented with either arabinose or glutamate. In symbiosis with alfalfa, Rm30230 had a fix- phenotype and was also devoid of alpha-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase activity. The ability of Rm30230 to grow on arabinose or glutamate, without alpha-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase activity, strengthens the hypothesis that S. meliloti has a functional GABA shunt allowing it to circumvent the forward-direction TCA cycle from alpha-ketoglutarate to succinate. Mutation of the second potential dihydrolipoamide succinyltransferase component (E2) of alpha-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase yielded Rm30267 (SMb20019) with wild-type growth on minimal media and a Fix+ phenotype in plants. The introduction or a sucB mutation into the SMb20019 mutant background (Rm30275) was comparable to the sole sucB mutation. This finding shows that the locus SMb20019 cannot be substituted for sucB in the alpha-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase enzyme complex.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gh556.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sn997</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rhizobium meliloti -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>GABA -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transposons</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053k911"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Novel biophysical appliations [sic] of STICS</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vaillancourt, Benoit</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The object of this thesis is to present two novel applications of Spatiotemporal Image Correlation Spectroscopy (STICS) to biological systems. STICS is a technique which uses the correlations in pixel intensity fluctuations of an image time series, captured under fluorescence microscopy, to measure the speed and direction of a flowing population of fluorescently labeled molecules. The method was first applied to measure the dynamics of transport vesicles inside growing pollen tubes of lily flowers. The measured vector maps allowed to confirm the presence of actin filaments along the periphery of the tubes, as well as the presence of a reverse-fountain pattern in the apical region. In a second set of experiments, STICS was used to measure the retrograde flow of filamentous actin in migrating chick DRG neuronal growth cones. These results serve as proof of principle that STICS can be used to probe the response of the growth cone cytoskeleton to external chemical cues.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161996p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053k911</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fluorescence spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Confocal fluorescence microscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Image analysis -- Data processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Actin</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278z00d"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Extraction, purification, and characterization of the lipase from the viscera of porgy (Stenotomus chrysops)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tian, Feng, 1980-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lipase, from porgy (Stenotomus chrysops) viscera, was purified by polyethylene glycol (PEG) 1000 precipitation, followed by dialysis and affinity chromatography on EAH-Sepharose 48. The digestive lipase from porgy showed seasonal variation in activity with high activity found in late summer and early fall compared with a spring sample. Polyethylene glycol (PEG) precipitation fraction was used to characterize this enzyme using p-nitrophenyl palmitate (pNPP) as substrate. Porgy lipase did not behave like a bile salt activated/depended lipase because it was able to hydrolyze pNPP without bile salt (e.g., sodium cholate). Porgy lipase was stable within the pH range of pH 6.0-10.0, with an optimum activity at pH 8.5. The enzyme was quite stable at temperatures below 40°C, but lost its activity rapidly at temperatures above 40°C. The optimum activity for hydrolysis pNPP was at 40°C, but the enzyme also demonstrated relatively high activity at temperatures below 40°C (i.e., 10-40°C) as well. Detergents, Triton X-100, Tween 40 and Tween 80, at final concentrations of 0.5 mM and 1 mM were found to have inhibitory effects on porgy digestive lipase activity. However, all three tested detergents appeared to increase the activity of porgy digestive lipase at elevated temperatures (i.e., 60-80°C).</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t14c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278z00d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Stenotomus chrysops</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sparus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lipase -- Separation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak930c194w"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structural basis for the recruitment of the SerThr kinase Mnk1 by the scaffolding proteins DAP5 and elF4G</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Talje, Lama</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Scaffolding proteins control the localization of protein kinases. During translation, the scaffolding proteins eIF4G and DAP5 recruit the Ser/Thr kinase Mnk1 to phosphorylate the mRNA cap-binding protein eIF4E and modulate translation. Biochemical deletion analysis previously showed that the interaction between Mnk1 and eIF4G/DAP5 is mediated by N-terminal residues in Mnk1 and C-terminal residues in eIF4G/DAP5. Using X-ray crystallography I have determined the structure (1.5 A) of the C-terminal domain of DAP5 (DAP5C). This structure reveals that DAP5C contains two atypical HEAT domains similar to the ones seen previously in the structure of the C-terminal region of eIF4G (4GC). Using ITC I showed that the Kd for the interaction between the N-terminus ofMnk1 and 4GCIDAPSC is 20 muM and 10 muM, respectively. Using NMR chemical shifts we have mapped the residues on both Mnk1 and 4GC/DAP5C which are important for maintaining this interaction. Finally, using SAXS a low resolution configuration of the hMnk1-4GC complex was modeled. It is hoped that an understanding of the structural basis for the recruitment of protein kinases to their sites of action will allow the design of small-molecule compounds that can be used to modulate the location of the kinase and hence its activity.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kk87b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c194w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Eukaryotic Initiation Factor-4G -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Protein-Serine-Threonine Kinases -- metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924g38q"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The deubiquitinating enzyme USP19 negatively regulates the expression of muscle-specific genes in L6 muscle cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sundaram, Priyanka</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Muscle wasting is a significant complication of many diseases including diabetes mellitus, renal and liver failure, HIV/AIDS, and cancer. Sustained loss of skeletal muscle can severely impair a patient's quality of life and often results in poor tolerance and responsiveness to disease treatments. The increased protein breakdown observed during muscle atrophy has been attributed to accelerated activity of the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway, but the precise mechanisms by which this activation stimulates muscle protein loss are poorly understood. Previous work showed that the deubiquitinating enzyme USP19 is upregulated in rat skeletal muscle in various forms of muscle wasting, including streptozotocin induced diabetes, cancer, and dexamethasone treatment. 1 To further explore the role of USP19 in muscle wasting, siRNA-mediated depletion of the enzyme was carried out in L6 myotubes. Knockdown of USP19 resulted in more rapid differentiation of myoblasts into myotubes, with a greater extent of myoblast fusion. It also produced tubes that were visibly larger than those formed by myoblasts transfected with a control siRNA. At the molecular level, silencing of USP19 increased the amount of myosin heavy chain (MHC) and tropomyosin proteins. It also increased levels of MHC transcript, suggesting that USP19 acts at the level of gene transcription or mRNA stability rather than protein degradation. USP19 may mediate its effects on muscle-specific gene expression through the myogenic transcription factor myogenin, since depletion of USP19 increased protein and mRNA levels myogenin but did not affect protein levels of the related transcription factor Myf5. Moreover, the increased tropomyosin and MHC observed upon USP19 knockdown could be abolished when myogenin was simultaneously depleted using siRNA. Collectively, these results suggest that USP19 functions to inhibit the synthesis of key muscle proteins and may therefore be a promising target for the treatment of muscle atrophy.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k8852.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924g38q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Muscular Atrophy -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Endopeptidases -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muscle, Skeletal -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muscle Proteins -- biosynthesis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613n220q"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lax probabilistic bisimulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Taylor, Jonathan, 1981-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Probabilistic bisimulation is a widely studied equivalence relation for stochastic systems. However, it requires the behavior of the states to match on actions with matching labels. This does not allow bisimulation to capture symmetries in the system. In this thesis we define lax probabilistic bisimulation, in which actions are only required to match within given action equivalence classes. We provide a logical characterization and an algorithm for computing this equivalence relation for finite systems. We also specify a metric on states which assigns distance 0 to lax-bisimilar states. We end by examining the use of lax bisimulation for analyzing Markov Decision Processes (MDPs) and show that it corresponds to the notion of a MDP homomorphism, introduced by Ravindran &amp; Barto. Our metric provides an algorithm for generating an approximate MDP homomorphism and provides bounds on the quality of the best control policy that can be computed using this approximation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343w62b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n220q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Markov processes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stochastic systems</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010t66j"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Extraction, partial purification and characterization of transglutaminase from the liver of bluefish (Pomatomus saltatrix)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Subramanian, Vidya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Transglutaminases (EC 2.3.2.13) are a group of thiol enzymes that catalyse acyl-transfer reaction in which the gamma-carboxyamide groups of peptide-bound glutaminyl residues are the acyl donors. They cause post-translational modification of proteins mainly by protein to protein cross-linking, but also through acyl transfer reaction and deamidation of glutamine residues. Crude liver and flesh extracts of bluefish (Pomatomus saltatrix ) were investigated to ascertain the effects of storage time and temperature on the stability and activity of transglutaminase (TGase). TGase activity was measured and the enzyme was subsequently characterized using CBZ-L-glutaminylglycine and hydroxylamine as substrates. Frozen bluefish liver and flesh extracts had higher specific activities (0.321 Units and 0.230 Units respectively) in comparison to refrigerated liver and flesh extracts (0.124 Units and 0.071 Units respectively) at the end of a 30 day storage period with the frozen liver extract retaining the highest stability. The optimum temperature for the crude bluefish liver TGase reaction with CBZ-L-glutaminylglycine and hydroxylamine was between 40°C and 45°C. The enzyme was stable at temperatures below 55°C, beyond which it lost activity progressively. The crude enzyme extract was active within the pH range of 6.0-7.5, with an optimum pH of 7.0, and was stable from pH 6.5-8.0. TGase was partially purified from the frozen liver extract of bluefish by gel filtration on 8ephacryl S-200 HR. The partially purified extract was further characterized with respect to its response to temperature and pH. The effects of sodium as well as calcium chloride and other divalent cations, and the inhibitory effects of various chemicals on the activity of the partially purified TGase were also investigated. The partially purified bluefish TGase had an optimum temperature of 40°C via the reaction with CBZ-L-glutaminylglycine and hydroxylamine. The enzyme was observed to be stable at temperatures below 50°C and approximately 90% of the initial TGase activity was retained at the end of a 30 min incubation period. The partially purified bluefish TGase had a pH optimum of pH 7.5 and was stable within a narrow pH range of 7.0 - 8.0. The partially purified enzyme showed requirement for calcium (Ca 2+) ions for activity and no activity was observed in the absence of Ca2+. The replacement of Ca2+ by other divalent cations such as Mg2+, Mn2+, Ba2+, Zn2+ and Fe2+ produced various levels of activity with the enzyme, albeit less than that achieved with Ca2+. Increasing NaCl concentrations, 0 - 15mM, did not seem to have an enhancing effect on the activity of partially purified bluefish TGase. TGase was inhibited by sulfhydryl alkylating agents (monoiodoacetic acid (IAA) and N'-ethylmaleimide (NEM)).</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mk11k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010t66j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bluefish</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transglutaminases -- Separation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859k398"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Neuromolecular changes in developing offspring following maternal infection : implications for schizophrenia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vanderbyl, Brandy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Environmental and genetic factors contribute to the development of schizophrenia. For example, epidemiological evidence has linked infections during pregnancy with increased incidence of schizophrenia in the adult offspring. At the same time mutation to DISC1, a protein involved in neurone migration and synaptic plasticity, is an important genetic risk for the disorder. Accordingly, the aim of this project was to determine if these environmental and genetic influences converge along a common pathogenic pathway leading to schizophrenia. Using a model of prenatal infection by bacterial endotoxin in rodents, we demonstrated a 50% reduction in DISC1 protein expression in the hippocampus and cortex of juvenile offspring. In addition, we found a significant induction of prostaglandins (final mediators of the inflammatory process) in the fetal brain while many cytokines remained unaltered. Taken together our results identify prostaglandins as potential mediators of the teratogenic effects of prenatal infection and show that prenatal infection itself can affect systems related to genetic risk factors for schizophrenia, in this case DISC1.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77st655.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859k398</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nerve Tissue Proteins -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Schizophrenia -- genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Prenatal Exposure Delayed Effects -- physiopathology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rats</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rats, Sprague-Dawley</dc:subject><dc:subject>Schizophrenia -- etiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acz30px450"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigating oligodendrocyte development and stability using organotypic hippocampal slices, confocal imaging and viral gene delivery methods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vautrin, Sandrine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Myelin plays an essential function in the behaviour of higher organisms by increasing the speed of axonal conduction. Indeed, myelin deficiency or damage can lead to serious motor and sensory dysfunction. In the central nervous system, myelin is produced by a specialized macroglial cell known as the oligodendrocyte. Although much is known about oligodendrocytes with respect to their role in myelin production, many details regarding their development and maintenance still remain unclear. These details may be of great importance for fully understanding the fundamental properties of oligodendrocytes and for devising strategies for treating myelin-related diseases. In this thesis, we report the development of a system using organotypic hippocampal slices, viral gene delivery methods, immunostaining techniques and confocal imaging that can be used to study the properties of oligodendrocytes and myelin. This system preserves many features of the intact brain and can be used to investigate cells of the oligodendrocyte lineage at different developmental stages. Individual oligodendrocytes were targeted using this system and we showed that they can be induced to express various proteins, such as proteolipid protein and neurofascin-155, that localized to specific compartments of oligodendrocytes. This system was then used to address the importance of glutamate receptor signalling on myelin. Studies were performed at the light microscopic level using agonists and antagonists of ionotropic glutamate receptors. Myelin showed progressive pathology over the course of hours following exposure to glutamate receptor agonists and, interestingly, glutamate signalling was not essential for myelin maintenance over a 48 hour period. This thesis work thus describes the use of a novel system that can help analyze both the cellular and molecular aspects of oligodendrocyte development and maintenance.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k6092.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30px450</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hippocampus -- growth &amp; development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oligodendroglia -- virology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oligodendroglia -- cytology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Semliki forest virus -- genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fluorescent Antibody Technique -- methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hippocampus -- cytology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mice</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bq248"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The incidence and prevalence of hypertension in the Province of Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vallée, Michel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objectives of this study were to estimate the prevalence, incidence and lifetime risk of developing hypertension after a given age in the Province of Quebec. An administrative database was used to form a cohort of 20,000 subjects selected in 1987 from a random sample of individuals aged 45 or older, living in the Province of Quebec. These individuals were followed from 1986 to 2003. Incident cases of essential hypertension were selected on the basis of an outpatient diagnosis of hypertension. The Framingham approach was used to calculate incidence rate. The incidence of hypertension in the Quebec cohort was 22 per 1,000 person-years for men and 31 per 1,000 person-years for women; it was higher for women for all the age groups under study. The lifetime risk of developing hypertension for subjects who attained the age of 46 free of hypertension in the Quebec cohort was 66%; this was 20% higher for women than for men (72% compared with 59%). In the Quebec cohort, the incidence of hypertension is very high particularly for women. The data provide evidence that, in Quebec, detection of hypertension is to be maximized, for both men and women.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r689n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bq248</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Quebec -- epidemiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sex Factors -- Quebec</dc:subject><dc:subject>Follow-Up Studies -- Quebec</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hypertension -- epidemiology -- Quebec</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w835j"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synoptic regimes in the lower Arctic troposphere during 1955</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wilson, Cynthia. V.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During the past five years the continuous flow of data from the Arctic region has made possible a more reliable daily synoptic analysis bath for the surface and upper levels. Much work has already been done to establish the monthly and seasonal broad-scale features of the lower and mid-troposphere, and to study in greater detail the perturbations. In 1952 the Extended Forecasting Section of the United States Weather Bureau published a revised version of their monthly normal maps for the northern hemisphere.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hare, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096b74h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w835j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rp92z"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History and Classical Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The government in Rome from 88 B.C. to 82 B.C.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Weller, Judith. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Government in Rome from 88 - 82 B.C. is a politically important period to students of Roman History, since it is the only period when the Democratic Party was in complete control of affairs. Toe traditional picture of these years ~ writers, both modern and ancient, is one bespattered with the blood of proscriptions, the hunger and filth of economic distress and poverty. In general, complete and utter maladministration. However1 after a careful study of extant sources, one cannot help but consider the writers somewhat biased in their opinions. This thesis is an effort to point out and assist readers in visualizing what Rome was like during those years. The aim is to alter the prevalent opinion, bringing those years into clearer focus and into their proper perspective. T'M purpose is not to prove that the men of the times like Cinna, Garbo, Flaccus, and Marius were merely much maligned individuals whose good intentions have since been lost in the brilliant rhetoric of Cicero, or in the invective of Velleius but rather that their government was an honest effort towards the betterment of the underprivileged classes, even though 'they themselves may have been anxiously working towards the solidification of their somewhat precarious positions as demagogues. […]  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gordon, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827g529.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rp92z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rome -- History -- Mithridatic Wars, 88-63 B.C</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1831cp54c"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Immunochemical and physico-chemical studies on the biocolloids in normal human urine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Webb, Tom</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The physiology and anatomy of the kidney are relatively well known due to the large number of investigations which have been carried out. One aspect of kidney function which has been neglected is that dealing with the excretion and reabsorption of biocolloids. In many disease conditions large quantities of a great variety of proteins may be excreted in the urine. The nature of the pathological changes involved in many of these diseases is not understood. One of the reasons for this lack of understanding is the absence of direct evidence concerning the normal processes involved.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sehon, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xd377.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cp54c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93h3291"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Techniques of extracorporeal circulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Warshawski, Frances. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The past decade has seen a remarkable world-wide development in the field of thoracic surgery. Following the lead of surgeons in the United States, the United Kingdom and Sweden, and the original pioneering contributions made by our own Canadian surgeons, namely Doctor Edward Archibald, Dr. William Mustard and Doctor W.G. Bigelow, rapid strides are being made not only in the scope of thoracic surgery, generally, but, more specifically, in the advancement of cardiac surgery. The measure of success achieved by efforts to correct congenital cardiac anomalies by indirect surgical procedures has served to encourage world-wide research in developing techniques by which cardiac defects may be corrected by direct methods under direct vision.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webster, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xg559.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h3291</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fm84d"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rates of acetic acid formation from ethanol by Acetobacter suboxydans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Walke, Lacey</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ordinary vinegar is dilute acetic acid obtained from the oxidation of alcoholic liquids, and it was probably in this form that it was known from the earliest times. Vinegar was mentioned in three books of the Old Testament and Hippocrates is reported to have prescribed it as a medicine for his patients. Livy, the Latin prose writer, reported in his book No. XXI that Hannibal overcame the difficulty offered to the passage of his army in crossing the rocks or the Alps by dissolving the rocks with vinegar so that a pathway could be made. Thus, vinegar was known for a long time.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Blackwood, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bj595.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fm84d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Bacteriology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acf95jf89r"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Tendencies in the evolution of the centres of Canadian cities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Walford, Dorice. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Centre of a city is generally thought of as the centre of community life and of business life for the city. Ideally, it is more than this. Underlying the functional relationship of the parts comprising the Centre, are the guiding principles that foster the social, economic, architectural and planning aspects of the Centre. In contrast to some other areas of the city, the Centre is seldom professionally planned from the beginning, except in the case of a new town. The development of a city Centre, therefore, is largely concerned with the redesign and extension of an existing city Centre. Many of the problems of the city of today have been brought about by mass production, mass consumption, and mass transportation, and these forces have been responsible for city growth.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Spence-Sales, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494d00z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jf89r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Architecture</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab5644w369"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The reactions of active nitrogen with nitric oxide and nitrogen dioxide</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Verbeke, Gentil. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lewis (1) in 1900 was the first to observe the yellow afterglow resulting from the passage of an electrical discharge through nitrogen and to identify its banded spectrum as that of nitrogen. In 1911 Strutt, later Lord Rayleigh (2), published the first in a series of papers on the chemical reactions of active nitrogen and the emission spectra associated with active nitrogen and its interaction with other substances. Metallic vapours, he found, were converted to the nitrides whereas various hydrocarbons, saturated, unsaturated and even substituted, yielded hydrogen cyanide with a concurrent emission of the CN spectrum.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720h61d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644w369</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>