<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avd66w0203"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Influence of early-rearing conditions on mesocorticolimbic dopamine function in the rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pomarenski, Amanda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This project focused on the influence of early life rearing conditions on dopamine (DA) function in rats.  Epidemiological evidence indicates that individuals that experience early life adversity are at increased risk for developing psychopathology later in life, resulting in part from developmental alterations in DA function.  Thus, I investigated the influence, first, of maternal separation and then of naturally occurring variations in maternal care, on behavioural and neurochemical responses to amphetamine (AMPH) of adult and periadolescent male offspring. Study 1 failed to confirm that maternal separation alters D3 receptor-mediated locomotor activity and enhances behavioral sensitization to AMPH.  Study 2 revealed that periadolescent offspring of low-licking/grooming (LG) dams exhibited greater AMPH-induced locomotion than high-LG offspring, but only when previously stressed.  Results of Study 3 indicated that the periadolescent neuroendocrine and DA responses to stress do not differ in high- versus low-LG offspring, although differences in testosterone, basal corticosterone, and amygdala DA content were observed.  In Study 4, in vivo microdialysis was used to monitor AMPH-induced changes in extracellular nucleus accumbens (NAc) DA levels of previously-stressed periadolescent high- and low-LG offspring.  The NAc DA response to AMPH was significantly dampened in low- versus high-LG animals.  Autoradiography revealed that levels of D1 receptor and DA transporter (DAT) binding in the striatum, NAc, and substantia nigra were significantly elevated in experimentally naïve periadolescent low-LG relative to high-LG offspring.  The focus of Study 5 was on the DA response to AMPH of adult high- and low-LG animals.  Repeated AMPH administration during periadolescence sensitized both adult high- and low-LG animals equally to the drug's locomotor stimulant effect.  Densities of NAc D1, D2 receptor, and DAT sites did not differ in adult high- versus low-LG animals.  In conclusion, natural variations in maternal care influence periadolescent responsivity to AMPH primarily as a consequence of developmental alterations in DA receptor and DAT expression and/or pruning.  These data also suggest that observed differences in periadolescent DA function resulting from variations in maternal care dissipate once the animals reach adulthood.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Mon projet était orienté sur influence des conditions d'élevage en début de vie sur le système dopaminergique chez le rat.  Une évidence épidémiologique indique qu'un individu qui aurait subi des événements malheureux durant le début de sa vie augmente le risque de développer une psychopathologie plus tard dans sa vie.  L'hypothèse que les troubles comme la toxicomanie, la dépression, et le ADHD se manifesteraient d'une part par une altération des fonctions dopaminergiques du système central.  J'ai étudié l'influence, de la séparation maternelle, puis les variations de comportements de soins maternels et neurobiochimie en réponse a l'amphétamine (AMPH) chez le rat mâle adolescent et adulte. Étude 1 n'a pas pu confirmer la preuve précédente que la séparation maternelle altère chez le rat adulte, l'activité locomotrice par l'entremise des récepteurs D3 stimule le développement de la sensibilisation comportementale à AMPH.  Étude 2 a révélé que la lignée low-licking/grooming (LG) à l'adolescence présentée une forte réponse à AMPH tandis que la lignée high-LG présente une forte réponse seulement lorsqu"ils sont stressés préalablement.  Les résultats de l'étude 3 indiquent que le système neuroendocrinien et DA chez adolescent ne présence pas de différence en réponse au stress high- versus low-LG  bien que l'on retrouve des différences entre les groupes pour la testostérone, corticostérone (basal) et DA (amygdale).  Étude 4 la microdialyse in vivo a été utiliser pour mesure les changements extracellulaires dans le nucleus accumbens (NAc) soit les concentrations de DA chez les lignes high- et low-LG adolescent préalablement stresses.  La réponse DA du NAc par AMPH a été significativement atténue chez les animaux low- versus high-LG.  J'ai ensuite examiné les récepteurs D1, D2, D3 et le transporteur DA (DAT) la densité diffère du high- versus low-LG.  Le niveau association du  récepteur D1 et DAT dans le striatum, NAc, et substantia nigra est significativement élever chez les animaux low-LG relativement des high-LG.  L'objectif de l'étude 5 a été la réponse DA par AMPH chez les animaux adultes high- et low-LG.  L'administration répéter AMPH pendant adolescence sensibilise les adultes high- et low-LG également a l'effet du médicament  lors de la stimulation locomotrice, en contraste avec les animaux adolescent, le densité des récepteurs D1, D2, D3 et site DAT dans le NAc ne différent pas des adultes high- versus low-LG. En conclusion, les variations naturelles de l'influence des soins maternels influence la réponse a AMPH chez adolescence principalement en raison de modifications dans le développement des récepteurs DA et l'expression DAT et ou la taille. Mes données suggèrent également que les différences observées dans la fonction DA chez adolescent résultant de variations dans les soins maternels disparaît des que les animaux atteignent l'âge adulte.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alain Gratton</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720d11k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w0203</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9z9030248"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of genetic variants in hypertension and heart disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chami, Nathalie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background: Angiotensinogen (AGT) is a vasopressor agent and is part of the Renin-Angiotensin System (RAS) which plays an essential role in blood pressure regulation. The M235T polymorphism in AGT has been inconsistently associated with both hypertension and cardiovascular disease. We examined the role of M235T in hypertension and myocardial infarction (MI) and investigated whether this polymorphism interacts with other risk factors. Methods: We genotyped a subset of 7,232 individuals from the INTERHEART population, a global case-control study and sought replication in a subset of 12,206 individuals from the DREAM/EpiDREAM trial. Results: The T variant was significantly associated with MI in the two largest INTERHEART populations, Europeans (P&lt;0.036) and South Asians (P&lt;0.0005).  Interestingly, we observed a more significant result in females (P&lt; 0.0002) compared to males (P&lt; 0.01). M235T was also associated with hypertension in a weighted meta-analysis adjusted for age and sex in both INTERHEART (P&lt;0.01) and DREAM/EpiDREAM (P&lt;0.001). Testing for an association with MI after adjusting for hypertension did not greatly alter the odds ratios obtained prior to adjustment, suggesting that only part of the effect on MI can be attributed to hypertension. We further hypothesized that M235T may have a different effect in certain sub-groups. We tested for the association with MI within low risk and high risk subgroups separately and observed an interaction with MI risk factors across multiple ethnicities.  The Breslow-Day test for homogeneity of effect size between the low and high risk groups in the combined analysis yielded P&lt;0.002. This trend was also observed in the DREAM/EpiDREAM subset. Conclusion: These results confirm the association of the T variant of M235T with both MI and hypertension. In addition, they demonstrate that M235T interacts with known risk factors and is involved in the pathogenesis of MI independently of hypertension.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Contexte: L'angiotensinogène (AGT) est un agent vasopresseur qui fait partie du système  rénine-angiotensine (SRA) et qui joue un rôle essentiel dans la régulation de la pression artérielle.  Le rôle du polymorphisme M235T, situé dans l'AGT, dans l'hypertension et la maladie cardiovasculaire est inconsistent.  Nous avons voulu examiner le rôle de ce polymorphisme dans l'hypertension et dans l'infarctus du myocarde (IM) et étudier son interaction avec d'autres facteurs de risque. Méthodes: Nous avons génotypé un sous-ensemble de 7,232 individus provenant du projet INTERHEART, une étude de cas témoins internationale. Nous avons voulu confirmer nos résultats en analysant un sous-ensemble de 13,669 individus provenant de l'étude DREAM/EpiDREAM. Résultats: Le variant T est associé de façon significative avec l'IM dans les deux plus importantes populations d'INTERHEART, soient les populations  européenne (P&lt;0.04)  et de l'Asie du Sud (P&lt;0.0004).  Il est intéressant de noter que nous avons observé un effet plus important chez les femmes (P&lt; 0.0002) que chez les hommes (P&lt; 0.01). M235T a aussi été associé avec l'hypertension dans une méta-analyse pondérée ajustée pour le sexe et l'âge (P&lt;0.01).  L'étude  DREAM/EpiDREAM nous a permis de confirmer cette association dans le cas de l'hypertension. Le variant T a été associé avec l'hypertension auto-déclarée (OR=1.08, P=0.018), et avec la tension artérielle systolique (P=0.05) and diastolique (P=0.001). Un test d'association avec l'IM après ajustement pour l'hypertensions n'a pas considérablement modifié le rapport de cotes, suggérant que seule une partie de l'effet sur l'IM peut être attribuable à l'hypertension. Nous avons formulé l'hypothèse que M235T puisse avoir un effet différent dans certains groupes. Nous avons testé l'association avec l'IM parmi les groupes à faible et à haut risque séparément et avons observé une interaction avec les facteurs de risque de l'IM à travers toutes les ethnies testées. Le test de Breslow-Day pour l'homogénéité de la taille d'effet entre les groupes à risque faible et à risque élevé dans l'analyse combinée a produit une valeur de P&lt;0.002. Cette tendance a aussi été observée dans les échantillons de DREAM/EpiDREAM. Ajuster pour l'hypertension ou exclure les individus hypertendus n'a pas modifié la taille d'effet. Conclusion: Ces résultats confirment l'association du variant T à la fois avec l'IM et l'hypertension.  De plus, ils démontrent l'interaction entre le polymorphisme M235T et des facteurs de risque connus ainsi que son implication dans la pathogénie de l'IM, indépendamment de celle de l'hypertension.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>James Engert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25x897v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9030248</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343s59d"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Claiming a life of permanence: Filipina caregivers' migration experiences in Canada's live-in caregiver program</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Miller, Meagan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Drawing on in-depth interviews with migrant caregivers, community workers and government employees, this thesis explores the dream among Filipina women working in Canada's Live-In Caregiver Program (LCP) to build a life in Canada. Uncovering the actions they take on the path to realizing this dream, I first examine the common challenges caregivers encounter while working as temporary workers in the LCP. The analysis deepens to reveal the struggles caregivers engage in to improve their lives, despite institutional obstacles to exercising their rights. Ultimately, the analysis addresses the wider institutional context by examining Canada's contemporary citizenship regime. Throughout their journey to claiming a permanent home in Canada, caregivers are confronted with vulnerabilities rooted in this regime. However, those who experience greater social inclusion in the local community find strength and courage to overcome adversity.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Basée sur des entrevues approfondies avec des aides familiales immigrantes, ainsi que des employés provenant des milieux communautaire et gouvernemental, cette thèse explore le rêve des femmes philippines travaillant dans le cadre du Programme des aides familiaux résidants (PAFR) de s'établir au Canada. Tout en retraçant les actions qu'elles entreprennent pour réaliser ce rêve, j'examine d'abord les défis auxquels ces femmes sont confrontées et ensuite les épreuves qu'elles tentent de surmonter pour améliorer leur vie malgré la présence de plusieurs obstacles institutionnels à l'exercice de leurs droits.  Finalement, l'analyse se concentre sur le contexte institutionnel plus général en examinant le régime de citoyenneté du Canada. Tout au long de leur parcours vers l'obtention de la résidence permanente, les aides familiales sont confrontées aux faiblesses de ce régime. Par contre, celles qui sont mieux intégrées à leur communauté locale trouvent la force et le courage de surmonter l'adversité. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elaine Weiner</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Marc Ancelovici</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g5478.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s59d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology - Ethnic and Racial Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354f58r"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanism of action of Type I and Type II combi-molecules designed to target DNA and epidermal growth factor receptor in solid tomours</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Todorova Bratanova, Margarita</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'hétérogénéité de la plupart des tumeurs solides est caractérisée par la surexpression de plusieurs récepteurs et le disfonctionnement des voies de transduction des signaux. Les thérapies actuelles contre les tumeurs surexprimant le récepteur du facteur de croissance épidermique (EGFR) utilisent des inhibiteurs de l'EGFR, agents relativement bien tolérés en clinique. Cependant, l'efficacité de ces inhibiteurs est atténuée par plusieurs facteurs tels que les mutations dans les voies de signalisation et par l'hétérogénéité des récepteurs. Pour palier ce problème, nous avons récemment conçu une stratégie basée sur la synthèse des molécules «programmées» pour libérer un inhibiteur de l'EGFR et un agent cytotoxique capable d'endommager l'ADN. Ces molécules, combinant des agents  ciblant l'EGFR et l'ADN, sont dénommées «combi-molécules de type I». Les travaux réalisés précédemment au laboratoire ont démontré que ces composés (1) inhibent la phosphorylation de l'EGFR et (2) endommagent l'ADN. Cependant, la corrélation entre leur dégradation, leur localisation et leur distribution au sein de la cellule et leur mécanisme d'action n'a pas encore été élucidée. Au cours de cette thèse de doctorat, nous avons élaboré une combi-molécule, AL237, marquée d'un groupe fluorescent et « programmée» pour libérer un inhibiteur de l'EGFR fluorescant dans le bleu et une entité fluorescant dans le vert ciblant l'ADN. Les résultats ont démontré que AL237 bloque la phosphorylation de l'EGFR et de la voie de signalisation des MAP kinases, accompagnée par la réduction sousjacente de l'expression de XRCC1 et ERCC1: deux enzymes impliquées dans la réparation de l'ADN. Après avoir démontré la capacité de AL237 à bloquer entièrement la voie de signalisation des MAP kinases, nous avons étudié la localisation de cette molécule dans des cellules cancéreuses par microscopie en fluorescence. Les résultats ont montré que la quinazoline libérée est colocalisée avec l'EGFR dans la région périnucléaire et que le signal de fluorescence vert est détecté dans les noyaux isolés. Ces résultats mettent en valeur un  modèle ou la combi-molécule entre dans la cellule, s'associe au REGF au niveau de la membrane plasmique, empêchant ainsi la transduction des signaux, puis se localise abondamment dans la région périnucléaire où les espèces alkylantes sont libérées et peuvent ainsi diffuser dans le noyau. Ce mécanisme permet d'expliquer la forte concentration d'espèces ciblant l'ADN observée dans les noyaux des cellules exprimant l'EGFR. D'autre part, des études utilisant les propriétés de fluorescence de AL237 ont démontré que la toxicité de cette molécule n'est pas affectée par la présence de la P-glycoprotéine (P-gp) dans les cellules. Cette observation peut être expliquée par le fait que, AL237 se dégrade intracellulairement en deux petites molécules empêchant ainsi l'efflux de la macrostructure intacte. Au cours de cette thèse, d'autres travaux ont été réalisés sur des combi-molécules, dites de type II, qui ne nécessitent pas d'hydrolyse pour générer les deux espèces actives et montrent une toxicité élevée à des concentrations submicromolaires. Les études élaborées pour élucider le mécanisme de l'exceptionnelle activité de ZR2008, une combi-molécule exemple de type II, ont montré qu'elle induit des niveaux significatifs d'apoptose indépendamment du statut d'AKT dans les cellules. Une constante dans son activité est sa capacité à bloquer les cellules dans les phases G1/S du cycle cellulaire et à inhiber le niveau de la survivine, une protéine antiapoptotique. Nos résultats suggèrent que les voies de signalisation, menant à l'inhibition de la survivine, pourraient jouer un rôle déterminant pour la cytotoxicité de ZR2008. En conclusion, les travaux de cette thèse ont contribué à l'élucidation des mécanismes d'action des deux classes de combi-molécules : type I et type II.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The overexpression of several receptors and dysfunction of signal transduction pathways characterize the heterogeneity of many solid tumours. Targeted therapies against epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)-overexpressing tumours involve well tolerated EGFR inhibitors. However, the potency of these inhibitors is mitigated by several factors including mutations in signaling pathways and receptor heterogeneity. To circumvent this problem, we recently designed a novel strategy that seeks to synthesize molecules "programmed" to release an EGFR inhibitor and a cytotoxic DNA-damaging agent. This led to mixed EGFR-DNA targeting agents, termed "type I combi-molecules". Previous work demonstrated that these compounds: (1) inhibited EGFR and (2) damaged DNA. However, the correlation of their degradation, localization and distribution in the cell with their mechanism of action remained elusive. In this thesis, we designed a fluorescence-labeled combi-molecule AL237 "programmed" to release a blue fluorescent EGFR inhibitor and a green DNA targeting species. The results showed that AL237 blocked EGFR phosphorylation and downstream MAPK pathway, subsequently leading to downregulation of XRCC1 and ERCC1, two DNA repair enzymes. Following demonstration of the ability of AL237 to fully block the MAPK pathway, we studied its localization in the tumour cells by fluorescence microscopy. The results showed that the released quinazoline colocalized with EGFR in the perinuclear region and the green fluorescence was detected in isolated nuclei. This led to a model whereby combi-molecule entered the cell, bind to the EGFR at the plasma membrane to prevent signal transduction and abundantly localized in the perinuclear region from where the released alkylating species could diffuse to the nucleus. This mechanism explained the significantly high levels of DNA damaging species in the nuclei of cells expressing EGFR. Further studies exploiting AL237 fluorescence properties demonstrated that its potency did not depend on the P-gp status of the cells. The P-gp independence of AL237 effect was explained by its intracellular degradation that prevented the efflux of the intact structure. Further studies on combi-molecules that do not require hydrolysis to generate the two targeting species (type II combi-molecules) showed that they exhibited potency in the submicromolar range. Studies designed to elucidate the mechanism underlying the exquisite potency of ZR2008 showed that it induced significant levels of apoptosis, independently of the AKT status of the cells. A constant in its potency was its ability to block cells in G1/S and to downregulate the antiapoptotic protein survivin. Our findings suggest that pathways leading to the inhibition of survivin could be a major molecular determinant for the cytotoxicity of ZR2008. The results from this work in toto contributed to the elucidation of the mechanism of action of two classes of combi-molecules: type I and type II. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bertrand Jean-Claude</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333255f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f58r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r3492"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dissection of Semaphorin reverse signaling in axon guidance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yu, Li</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ma thèse de doctorat s'intéresse au rôle des protéines transmembranaires Semaphorin1a (Sema1a) et PlexinA (Plexa) au cours du guidage axonal des photorécepteurs ou cellules R dans le système visuel de la Drosophile. Mes résultats indiquent que Sema1a agit comme un récepteur contrôlant la transmission d'un signal attractif, tandis que PlexA agit en amont de Sema1a. Les sémaphorines sont des protéines soit sécrétées soit transmembranaires qui participent au guidage du cône axonal des neurones, à la régénération axonale, ainsi qu'au développement du tissu nerveux et d'autres tissus. Il a été démontré dans le système neuromusculaire de la Drosophile que Sema1a est une protéine transmembranaire qui, une fois liée a son récepteur PlexA, induit un signal répulsif. Notre analyse de mutants de perte-de-fonction Sema1a révèle que Sema1a est requise pour le guidage des cellules R1-6 et la mise en place de la topographie précise des terminaisons neuronales. La surexpression de Sema1a cause une hyper-fasciculation qui se traduit par la formation de faisceaux neuronaux anormalement épais dans la lamina et la medulla. De plus, nous avons trouvé que la portion cytoplasmique de Sema1a est requise pour son rôle dans le guidage des cellules R.  Ainsi, mes résultats suggèrent un nouveau rôle pour Sema-1a en tant que récepteur modulant un effet attractif lors de la projection axonale. Qui plus est, par une approche de gènes candidats j'ai étudié les ligands en amont de Sema-1a. Cette analyse m'a permis de montrer que la perte de fonction ainsi que la surexpression de PlexA induisent des phénotypes similaires a ceux observés chez le mutant Sema1a ou lors de la surexpression de Sema-1a. J'ai également démontré que PlexA interagit génétiquement avec Sema-1a. Ces résultats démontrent que PlexA et Sema-1a fonctionnent au sein de la même voie de signalisation.  De façon intéressante la queue cytoplasmique de PlexA est dispensable pour la formation des fascicules neuronaux suggérant que PlexA fonctionne comme un ligand. Finalement des études épistatiques suggèrent que PlexA est en amont de Sema-1a. En conclusion, nous proposons que dans le système visuel de la Drosophile, PlexA soit le ligand de Sema-1a dans une voie de signalisation Sema-1a inversée. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>My PhD thesis describes original study in the guidance of photoreceptor (R-cell) axons in the developing Drosophila visual system. I investigate the role of the transmembrane protein Semaphorin1a (Sema1a) and PlexinA (PlexA) in R-cell axon guidance and dissect the Sema1a reverse signaling pathway. My results indicate that Sema1a functions as a receptor to mediate an attractive response in the Drosophila visual system, and PlexA acts as the upstream regulator of Sema1a.Semaphorins belong to a large family of both secreted and transmembrane proteins known as axon guidance molecules in vertebrates and invertebrates. Drosophila Sema1a is a transmembrane protein. Previous studies have shown that Sema1a functions as the ligand of its receptor PlexA together with Otk inducing a repulsive signaling pathway in the Drosophila neuromuscular system. However, whether it is the case in the Drosophila visual system remains unknown. Our results revealed that sema1a is required in R1-R6 axons for their association and guidance to form a proper topographic termination layer. The function of sema1a in R cells is cell-autonomous. Overexpression of sema1a causes a hyper-fasciculation phenotype in which abnormal thicker bundles are formed in both lamina and medulla. Interestingly, we found that the cytoplasmic domain of Sema1a is required for its function in R-cell axon guidance. All these results suggest that Sema1a functions as an attractive receptor to mediate R-cell interactions during R-cell axon projections, which is totally different with previous studies.Furthermore, I investigate the upstream ligand of Sema1a in our model by testing candidate-gene approach. I found that plexA displays a sema1a-like loss-of-function and gain-of-function phenotype in the Drosophila visual system. In addition, plexA genetically interacts with sema1a. These results indicate that plexA and sema1a function in the same signaling pathway. Interestingly, the cytoplasmic domain of PlexA is dispensable for its function in inducing the hyper-fasciculation phenotype in R-cell axon guidance, suggesting that PlexA functions as a ligand. Epistasis analysis suggests that plexA functions as an upstream regulator of sema1a. Taken all together, we propose that PlexA functions as the ligand of Sema1a in the Sema1a reverse signaling pathway in the Drosophila visual system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yong Rao</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000030q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r3492</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042t48h"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Desautels Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Maladaptive eating and the dynamic interactions between component processes in "cold" and "hot" systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lu, Ji</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La consommation d'aliments malsains est impulsive sur un processus induit aux signaux "chauds" qui est lié à un biais attentionnel aux signaux enrichissants. Les consommateurs peuvent également compter sur un processus exécutif "froid" pour contrôler leur régime alimentaire. Cette thèse propose le contrôle de l'exécutif, qui se compose de processus composants, y compris l'attention sélective, le contrôle inhibiteur, et la flexibilité mentale. Une interaction dynamique entre ces composantes et le biais attentionnel des indices enrichissants peut s'expliquer par une déficience des fonctions exécutives. Une étude empirique emploie "Affectif Shifting Task" pour accéder à des différences individuelles dans l'interaction de ces composants, les reliant par la même occasion à la consommation quotidienne des collations riches en calories. Les résultats montrent à  quel extrême le biais attentionnel peuvent interférer avec les fonctions exécutives et peuvent prédire la consommation d'aliments malsains d'un individu. En outre, les mangeurs qui se retiennent et qui sont plus vulnérables quand à l'exposition aux aliments malsains montrent de bien pire flexibilité mentale, mais de meilleur contrôle inhibiteur.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Unhealthy food consumption is impulsively driven by a "hot" cue-induced process that is tied to an attentional bias to rewarding cues. Consumers are also able to rely on a "cold" executive process to control their eating behaviour. This thesis proposes that executive control consists of component processes, including selective attention, inhibitory control, and mental flexibility. A dynamic interaction between these components and an attentional bias toward rewarding cues can be reflected in impaired executive functions. An empirical study employs Affective Shifting Task to access individual difference in these interacting components, and links them to everyday high-caloric snack consumption. The results show that to what extent the attentional bias can interfere with executive functions is predictive of one's unhealthy food consumption. Furthermore, restrained eaters, who are more vulnerable to unhealthy food craving, exhibit worse mental flexibility but better inhibitory control.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Laurette Dube</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405s969k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042t48h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Business Administration - Marketing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816m93p"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Desautels Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Solving unconstrained nonlinear programs using ACCPM</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dehghani, Ahad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, we address three main subjects. Wefirst introducethe relation between linear inequality systems and linear programmingproblems, and  continue by introducing the analyticcenter of a polyhedron and its calculation. Secondly, we study themultiple analytic center cutting plane method ACCPM and its proximalvariant. Finally, since ACCPM and proximal ACCPM are well knowntechniques for convexprogramming problems, we propose a sequential convex programming methodbased on ACCPM and convexification techniques to tackle unconstrainedproblems with a non-convex objective function in the last chapter. Wealso report a comparison of ourmethod with some existing algorithms: the steepest descent method andnonlinear conjugate gradient algorithms</dc:abstract><dc:abstract> Dans cette thèse, nous abordons trois thèmes principaux. Nous commençons par présenter la relation entre les systèmes d'inégalités linéaires et les problèmes de programmation linéaire. Nous poursuivons avec l'introduction de la notion de centre analytique d'un polyèdre et son calcul. Deuxièmement, nous étudions la méthode des coupes analytiques multiples ACCPM et sa variante proximale. En-ﬁn, puisque ACCPM et sa variante proximale sont des techniques bien connues pour les problèmes de programmation convexe, nous proposons une méthode de programmation séquentielle convexe fondée sur ACCPM ainsi que des techniques de convexiﬁcation destinées à traiter les problèmes dont la fonction objectif est non convexe dans le dernier chapitre. Nous présentons aussi une comparaison de nos méthode avec certains algorithmes existants tels que la méthode la plus forte pente et la méthode du gradient conjugué non linéaire. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dominique Orban</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jean-Louis Goffin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462583c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816m93p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Operations Research</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128b299"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structural and functional correlates of mental musical transformation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Foster, Nicholas Elgin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La musique représente à la fois un élément omniprésent dans la culture humaine et une discipline très complexe dans laquelle certaines personnes consacrent des décennies de pratique. La musique est ainsi un moyen idéal pour sonder la perception auditive humaine sur un large éventail de compétences. Les différences dans la structure et la fonction du cerveau ont été rapportées chez des musiciens (vs. individus non entraînés), mais en raison de limites méthodologiques, les liens réunissant les comportements, la structure et la fonction sont restés indirects. Cette thèse consiste en trois études en neuroimagerie qui ensemble, élucident quelques substrats anatomiques et fonctionnels des aspects de la perception mélodique. L'étude 1 utilise l'imagerie par résonance magnétique fonctionnelle (IRMf) et une tâche de transposition mentale de la hauteur des notes pour localiser l'activité corticale liée à la manipulation mentale de séquences mélodiques; les résultats ont montré que le recrutement du sulcus intrapariétal (SIP) est relié spécifiquement à la réussite d'une transposition mentale. L'étude 2 a utilisé l'IRMf pour répondre aux deux questions suivantes, à savoir si la même sous-région du SIP est également impliquée dans la manipulation temporelle des mélodies, et si la transposition de notes plus distantes évoque une plus grande activation dans le SIP. Les résultats ont montré que chez des sujets individuels, une aire commune dans le SIP favorise les transformations mélodiques mentales à la fois basées sur la hauteur des notes et sur des cadres de référence basés sur le temps, et que la magnitude de l'activation dans le SIP est associée avec la magnitude des transformations requises. L'étude 3 a testé les corrélats anatomiques de la capacité de transposition mentale de la hauteur des notes, et a montré qu'à la fois la concentration de matière grise et l'épaisseur dans le cortex auditif et dans le SIP prédit la performance à la tâche. Les effets structuraux dans le SIP étaient en étroite correspondance spatiale avec les effets fonctionnels dans les études 1 et 2. Bien que les effets anatomiques et fonctionnels aient montré des corrélations positives avec l'expérience musicale, il y avait aussi la preuve d'une corrélation entre la capacité de transposition mentale et la structure/fonction dans le SIP, indépendante de l'entraînement, appuyant l'idée qu'une variation comportementale préexistante est en outre modifiée par l'entraînement. Ces études sont par conséquent des preuves structurelles et fonctionnelles convergentes pour un rôle spécifique du SIP dans un aspect complexe de la perception musicale. Les résultats sont en accord avec les modèles du traitement sensoriel dorsal qui mettent l'accent sur des traitements non-spatiaux abstraits, et renforcent l'idée que le cortex pariétal postérieur est important pour des transformations musicales systématiques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Music represents both a ubiquitous element in human cultures and a highly complex discipline to which some individuals devote decades of practice. Music is therefore an ideal medium with which to probe human auditory perception over a wide range of skill. Differences in brain structure and function have been reported in musicians (vs. untrained individuals), but because of methodological limitations, the links bringing together behavior, structure and function have remained indirect. This thesis consists of three neuroimaging studies that, together, elucidate some of the functional and anatomical substrates of aspects of melodic perception. Study 1 used functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) and a mental pitch transposition task to localize cortical activity related to mental manipulation of melodic sequences; the results showed that recruitment of the intraparietal sulcus (IPS) is specifically related to successful mental transposition. Study 2 employed fMRI to test two follow-up questions: whether the same subregion of IPS is also involved in temporal manipulation of melodies, and whether transposition to more distant keys evokes greater activation in IPS. The results showed that in individual subjects, a common area of IPS subserves mental melodic transformations in both pitch-based and time-based reference frames, and that the magnitude of IPS activation is associated with the magnitude of the transformation required. Study 3 tested for anatomical correlates of mental pitch transposition ability, and found that both gray matter concentration and thickness in auditory cortex and IPS predict performance on this task. The structural effects in IPS were in close spatial correspondence with the functional effects in Studies 1 and 2. Although structural and functional effects showed positive correlations with musical experience, there was also evidence for a training-independent correlation between mental transposition ability and IPS structure/function, supporting the idea that pre-existing behaviorally relevant variation is further modified by training. These studies therefore provide convergent structural and functional evidence of a specific role for the IPS in a complex aspect of musical perception. The results are in agreement with models of dorsal sensory processing that emphasize abstract non-spatial computations, and advance the idea that posterior parietal cortex is important for systematic musical transformations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robert J. Zatorre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nb595.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128b299</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fh453"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Soldiering in the Canadian forces: how and why gender counts!</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gouliquer, Margaret Lynne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La vie de soldat dans les Forces canadiennes: un point de vue sexospécifique!Les femmes ont parcouru beaucoup de chemin depuis la Commission royale d'enquête sur le statut de la femme au Canada qui, en 1970, formulait 167 recommandations visant à corriger des inégalités et iniquités connues. De celles-ci, six portaient plus particulièrement sur l'intégration complète des femmes aux Forces canadiennes. En 1989, un tribunal canadien des droits de la personne ordonnait aux Forces canadiennes de procéder à l'intégration complète des femmes. L'élimination de ces barrières sexospécifiques représente une étape importante dans l'atteinte de l'égalité au sein de l'armée. Peu de nations peuvent se vanter en effet d'offrir aux femmes un accès libre à tous les métiers militaires. Il appert toutefois que les Forces ont peiné, voire échoué, à satisfaire aux exigences de ces politiques législatives (Davis, 1994; Chapstick, Farley, Wild et Parkes, 2005; O'Hara, 1998a, 1998b; Tanner, 1999). La présente étude examine la vie quotidienne de soldates canadiennes afin d'approfondir les questions liées au genre au sein des Forces canadiennes.Une approche quantitative et qualitative a été privilégiée. D'un point de vue quantitatif, les statistiques fournissent des renseignements matériels sur les avancées réalisées par les femmes (p. ex., l'équité en matière d'emploi). D'un point de vue qualitatif, l'étude des textes des décisions et d'expériences vécues par des soldates permettent de mieux comprendre les pratiques institutionnelles et la culture de l'armée. L'approche comparative et multiméthode permet de dresser un portrait inégal de l'intégration des femmes. Les résultats quantitatifs montrent que les femmes militaires du rang réussissent relativement bien. Par contre, pour exercer leur métier de soldat, les femmes doivent renoncer à avoir une famille, un choix que les hommes n'ont pas à faire. Pour ce qui est des femmes sous-officières, les défis sont plus nombreux : elles gagnent moins que leurs collègues masculins et, contrairement à ceux-ci, éprouvent des difficultés à équilibrer activités militaires et vie de famille.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Women have advanced in Canada since the Royal Commission on the Status of Women in 1970. This Commission made 167 recommendations to redress documented inequalities and inequities. Six pertained directly to the full integration of women in the Canadian Forces (CF). In 1989, a Canadian Human Rights Tribunal instructed the CF to "fully integrate" women. Removing these gender-specific barriers in the Canadian military signifies a major step toward equality. Few nations allow women unrestricted access to all military occupations. Since these legislative policies, the evidence indicates that the CF has been slow and unsuccessful to meet demands (Davis, 1994; Chapstick, Farley, Wild, &amp; Parkes, 2005; O'Hara, 1998a, 1998b; Tanner, 1999). The present study examines the everyday soldiering experiences of Canadian female soldiers as a step toward an increased understanding of gender and the CF.This research utilises both quantitative and qualitative approaches. Quantitatively, statistics reveal tangible information regarding women's success (e.g., earnings equality). Qualitatively, the focus rests on the examination of ruling texts and female soldiers' life experiences as a means to explicate current institutional practices and the culture of soldiering. Using this multi-method comparative approach, the story of women's integration emerges as varied. Quantitative results show that Non-Commissioned Member (NCM) female soldiers succeed relatively well. Yet, to do soldiering work, women give up on having a family, whereas men can do both. Female soldiers in the Officer class face more challenges; they do not earn as much as their male colleagues, and unlike them, they also face difficulties in maintaining both military work and family life. There has been progress, but the military is a governmental body publically controlled, thus, findings reveal insufficient efforts for such an agency. Although the military ideology is underpinned by obedience to orders, the CF did not obey fully the order to integrate women. Given the lengthy delay since the commission, and the moral and legal pressure that followed (human rights decision, employment equity act), the achieved results are mediocre. Such findings do not bode well for women in companies and organisations that do not fall under the employment equity act.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elaine Weiner</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Suzanne Staggenborg</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hp933.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh453</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology - Organizational</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zh205"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of education on mortality in Canada: a micro-econometric analysis using census data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lim, Helen Gek Neo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A number of studies have examined whether education has a causal impact on health, with some finding a positive effect and others no significant effect.  Evidence on the relationship between education and health in the Canadian context is however scarce.  The first two chapters in this thesis address this gap by presenting econometric analyses of the effect of education on health using Canadian Census data.  Chapter 1 uses data on changes to the compulsory schooling laws in Canada as instruments for educational attainment.  Using the Census master dataset for the ten provinces, the results in Chapter 1 indicate that education does indeed have a causal impact on mortality (a robust indicator for health).  Increasing pre-tertiary education by an additional year reduces the 5-year adult mortality rate by between 2% and 3.5%.  These findings suggest that traditional methods of evaluating the benefits of education may in fact understate its true importance.In Chapter 2, the instrument used for education is potential eligibility for the university education benefits under the Canadian Veterans Rehabilitation Act.  Because the VRA affected large numbers of anglophone Ontario-born men and extremely few francophone Quebec-born men, the latter is used as the control group for the treatment group consisting of the cohorts of Ontario men of university age at the end of World War II.  Using the Canadian Census Public Use Microdata Files for Quebec and Ontario, the results from the main analysis in Chapter 2 suffer from large standard errors due to measurement error in the dependent variable and a sample size that is too small.  An alternative analysis using administrative data on mortality rates yields results suggesting that an additional year of tertiary schooling reduces the 5-year mortality rate by 1.9%.Inspired by the measurement error problem in Chapter 2, Chapter 3 is an empirical investigation of the impact of measurement errors on estimation results.  The main contribution of this chapter to the literature relates to implications for statistical inference of random versus non-random measurement errors in the dependent variable, based on Monte Carlo simulation results.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Plusieurs études ont examiné si l'éducation a un impact causal sur la santé, avec certains qui trouvent un effet positif et d'autres aucun effet.  L'évidence sur le rapport entre l'éducation et la santé dans le contexte canadien est cependant rare.  Les deux premiers chapitres dans cette thèse adressent ce manque d'évidence en présentant des analyses économétriques de l'effet de l'éducation sur la santé utilisant des données de recensement canadiennes.En utilisant les changements apportés aux lois sur scolarité obligatoire au Canada comme instruments pour l'éducation, les résultats en Chapitre 1 indiquent que l'éducation a un impact causal sur la mortalité (un indicateur robuste de santé).  L'accroissement de l'éducation d'une année réduit le taux de mortalité adulte de cinq ans de 2,0% à 3,5%.  Ces résultats laissent penser que les méthodes traditionnelles d'évaluation des bénéfices de l'éducation pourraient en fait sous-estimer sa véritable importance.En Chapitre 2, l'instrument utilisé pour l'éducation est l'acceptabilité potentielle pour l'aide financière à l'éducation universitaire sous la Loi sur la Réadaptation des Anciens Combattants.  Puisque la Loi a affecté un grand nombre d'hommes anglophones nés en Ontario et extrêmement peu d'hommes francophones nés au Québec, ce dernier est employé en tant que groupe de comparaison pour les cohortes des hommes nés en Ontario ayant l'âge d'aller à l'université à la fin de la deuxième guerre mondiale.  Utilisant les données publics de recensement canadien pour le Québec et l'Ontario, les résultats de l'analyse principale en Chapitre 2 souffrent de erreur-type due à l'erreur de mesure dans la variable dépendente et une échantillon qui est trop-petite.  Une analyse alternative utilisant des données administratives sur des taux de mortalité donne des résultats suggérant qu'une année additionnelle de l'éducation (tertiaire) réduise le taux de mortalité de cinq ans de 1,9%.Inspiré par le problème d'erreur de mesure découvert en Chapitre 2, le Chapitre 3 est une recherche empirique sur l'impact des erreurs de mesure sur des résultats d'évaluation.  La contribution principale de ce chapitre se rapporte aux implications pour l'inférence statistique des erreurs de mesure aléatoire et non-aléatoires dans la variable dépendente, basée sur des résultats de simulation Monte Carlo.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daniel Parent</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Franque Grimard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wj75s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh205</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848q90c"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>In the service of the stakeholder: a critical, mixed-method program of research in high-stakes language assessment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baker, Beverly Anne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les trois études présentées ici forment une programme de recherche unie, étalé sur deux ans, qui explore de manière critique une étude de cas se rapportant aux enjeux majeurs de l'évaluation de la langue et en particulier,  au jugement de la compétence en anglais dans la certification des enseignants du Québec.La première étude est une exploration de l'ancienne épreuve finale du test écrit  évaluant cette compétence. Celle-ci trace un portrait des divergences de perceptions des partis impliqués (étudiants, administrateurs et correcteurs) de la tâche exigée par cette épreuve. La deuxième étude examine l'administration pilote d'un nouveau test (The English Exam for Teacher Certification ou EETC). Cette étude s'attarde à l'environnement sociopolitique du processus d'évaluation et tente de déterminer en quoi les perceptions des conséquences d'échec entretenues par les évaluateurs peuvent affecter le score attribué. La troisième étude porte sur la première administration officielle du EETC.  Dans une perspective sociocognitive, le comportement de l'évaluateur y est analysé. Cette étude cherche à déterminer comment l'information est perçue et traitée selon le style cognitive des évaluateurs et en quoi ce style peut affecter leur décision.Ce programme de recherche est critique dans le sens qu'il :-a intégré des valeurs sociales et politiques tout au long du processus de validation du test ;-a impliqué les différents acteurs concernés (étudiants, administrateurs et correcteurs) dans l'orientation de ce projet ; -a pris en compte les divers points de vue et intérêts des partis impliqués pour enrichir le programme de recherche.Ces études contribueront à l'élargissement des connaissances dans le domaine de l'évaluation de la langue. Entre autres, les résultats de celles-ci permettront de mieux saisir les interactions de chacun des partis impliqués dans cette situation d'évaluation. Cette recherche critique sur l'évaluation de la compétence de la langue pour la certification professionnelle a donné lieu à trois études menées dans une perspective progressiste et responsable. De plus, le recours à des méthodes variées  pour chacune des études s'inscrit dans le domaine émergeant des méthodologiques mixtes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The three studies presented here represent a two-year program of research that critically explored one case of high-stakes language assessment—English proficiency assessment for teacher certification in Quebec, Canada.The first study was an examination of the final administration of a writing test used for this purpose at one Quebec university before this test was replaced. In this study, mismatches were revealed in stakeholder perceptions of the task to be produced in this assessment. The second study examined the pilot administration of a new replacement test. It focused on the socio-political environment of the test—namely, how the perception of high or low stakes by raters affected scoring. Results from this study suggested that test stakes—to all stakeholders, including raters—is a worthwhile focus of study. The third study examined the first official administration of the new test, and focused on rater behavior from a socio-cognitive perspective, suggesting that information on decision-making style may provide insight into variability in rater scoring.This program of research has been critical in that •it has integrated social and political values into the test validation process;•test stakeholders, including the test takers themselves, have not only been consulted but  have determined the direction of the research program to a great extent; and•the conflicting views and competing interests of the stakeholders have been embraced and have enriched the research program.These studies will make contributions to the field of language assessment, and in particular, in better understanding how all elements of the subjectively-scored assessment situation interact.  Because of its critical approach, these studies have demonstrated a responsible and progressive approach to researching the assessment of language proficiency for professional certification. In addition, the use of mixed methods designs in all three studies has been somewhat innovative and will add to the emerging field of mixed method research.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carolyn E. Turner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623d03n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848q90c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Language - Rhetoric and Composition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1831ck330"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modeling the Sauter mean bubble diameter in mechanical forced-air flotation machines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nesset, Jan Edward</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Présentement aucun modèle ne permet de prédire le diamètre moyen de Sauter d'une bulle, D32, dans une cellule mécanique de flottation à partir des variables clés de ce même procédé. Cette lacune est significative puisque la flottation est un procédé dépendant de l'aire surfacique (des bulles), le paramètre clé étant le flux d'aire surfacique de bulles, Sb, défini comme étant 6 Jg/D32 où Jg est la vélocité superficielle du gaz. La façon dont les variables clés influencent la distribution des tailles de bulles (DTB) et par conséquent Sb est une confirmation essentielle pour comprendre et optimiser le procédé.L'objectif de travaux de recherche de cette thèse est de développer une expression mathématique pour la détermination du D32 basée sur des variables clés : type et concentration du moussant, vélocité superficielle du gaz, puissance d'agitation, viscosité du liquide et l'altitude (élévation au-dessus du niveau de la mer).Afin de mesurer efficacement la DTB en lien avec le Sb des bulles quittant la phase de pulpe, une cellule relativement grande (700 litres) soit une unité pilote Metso RCSTM  de 0,8 m3, a été choisie. Cette unité, qui a un plateau déflecteur interne, produit une séparation des zones de turbulence (près de l'agitateur) et de quiescence (près de l'écume) assurant ainsi que la DTB mesurée est le reflet exact de flux surfacique de bulles quittant la pulpe. Cette démarche constitue en soit une contribution importante car elle rectifie une mauvaise interprétation souvent retrouvée dans les travaux d'autres chercheurs.Les travaux entrepris ont aussi permis de découvrir que le D32 est fonction du Jg 0,5 avec une notion de « création de la taille de bulle » à Jg = 0 cm/s. Le D32 est également fonction de la viscosité à 20 ºC par une relation de puissance avec un exposant de 0,776, alors quelle a moins de dépendance à (densité de gaz) avec un exposant de -0,132.De façon surprenante, il a été découvert que la vitesse de l'agitateur n'avait pas un effet significatif sur le D32 dans la plage testée, soit une augmentation de l'intensité de puissance de l'ordre de 8 fois et le doublement de la vitesse en bout de l'agitateur. Il est postulé que les conditions hydrodynamiques à l'intérieur de la zone agitateur/stator  sont celles où le niveau élevé de turbulence à écoulement libre et la fraction de vide élevée (taux de rétention de gaz) résultent en un coefficient de traînée non constant plus bas pour les bulles individuelles, signifiant une force (perturbatrice) de traînée moins dépendante de la vélocité relative des fluides mais avec plus d'effet de viscosité.Finalement, le modèle D32 développé pour un système biphasé (air-eau) montre une bonne concordance avec les données mesurées en usine dans 5 sites industriels, représentant des systèmes de flottation à 3 phases (air-eau-solides).  Les courbes Sb-Jg produites par le modèle peuvent être utilisées comme un abaque pour étalonner les opérations en usine tel qu'illustré par l'étude de cas de la mine de palladium du Lac des Îles en Ontario confirmant ainsi l'utilité du modèle, une avancé en soit pour la compréhension et l'optimisation du procédé de flottation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract> There currently exists no available model for predicting the Sauter mean bubble diameter, D32, from the key process variables for mechanical flotation machines. This is seen as a significant shortcoming since flotation is a surface area (of bubbles) dependent process, the key metric being the bubble surface area flux, Sb, defined as 6 Jg/ D32, where Jg is the superficial gas velocity. Knowledge of how key variables affect the bubble size distribution (BSD), and hence Sb, is seen as an essential component of process understanding and optimization. The objective of this work was to develop a mathematical expression for D32 based on the key process variables of frother type and concentration, superficial gas velocity, power intensity (impeller tip speed), liquid viscosity, and altitude (elevation above sea level). In order to effectively measure the BSD that links to the Sb leaving the pulp phase, a relatively large 700 liter cell, a Metso RCS™ 0.8 m3 pilot unit, was selected. This unit, having an internal shelf baffle, produced separation of turbulent (near impeller) and quiescent (near froth) regions, ensuring that the measured BSD was truly reflective of the surface area flux leaving the pulp zone. Failure to adequately address this has been a shortcoming of work by others. The Metso unit was powered by a variable speed drive that permitted an 8-fold increase in power intensity covering the full range of industrial impeller tip speed (4.6 to 9.2 m/s). Five frothers were tested, covering a broad range in types including alcohols and polyglycols, Viscosity was modeled by varying water temperature between 4 and 40 oC. Altitude was modeled by varying gas density, an air-helium mixture fed to a smaller 5.5 liter laboratory Denver cell. The McGill gas dispersion sensors; bubble viewer and Jg probe, were used for measurement. The work showed that the effect on D32 for all frothers can be normalized to the same set of curves when dividing concentration by a frother's CCC95 value. The notion of CCC95 is introduced and is equivalent to Laskowski's CCC (critical coalescence concentration) but more suitable for mathematical analysis and model development. It represents the frother concentration (ppm) for which 95% reduction in D32 has been achieved.  Frother concentration was found to be the variable with the largest impact on D32 and is modeled with an exponential decay function that reaches a limiting bubble size at frother concentration exceeding the CCC95 value. Higher CCC95 results in a lower limiting bubble size. It appears that the CCC95 value for a frother may be predicted from its' basic molecular structure using the Hydrophile-Lipophile Balance/Mol. Wt. parameter. It was also found that the CCC95 value for a frother increases with increasing Jg. D32 was found to depend on Jg0.5 with a notional "bubble creation size" at Jg = 0 cm/s. The dependence on viscosity relative to that at 20 oC was a power relationship having an exponent of 0.776, while similarly, that for simulated altitude (gas density relative to air density at sea level)) showed less dependency with an exponent of -0.132. Surprisingly, impeller speed was found not to have any significant effect on D32 across the range representing an 8-fold increase in power intensity and a doubling of impeller tip speed.The overall D32 model, developed in a 2-phase air-water system, shows very good agreement with measured plant data from 5 operating sites worldwide, representing 3-phase (air-water-solids) flotation systems. The Sb- Jg curves produced by the model can be used as a "road-map" to benchmark plant operation as illustrated by a case study from the Lac des Iles palladium mine in Ontario. This approach is seen as a significant development for process understanding and optimization.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>James A. Finch</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806009x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831ck330</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax059c780z"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Desautels Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The content, structure, and outcomes of differentiated pleasure: An exploration</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sears, Donna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation aimed to empirically test and advance the conceptualization of pleasure as a differentiated phenomenon, which holds that hedonic experiences can produce different types of pleasures.  A second goal of this work was to examine the benefits of a four-type differentiated conceptualization of pleasure for assessing the marketing outcomes of hedonic experiences.  Across four independent complementary studies, results confirmed that experiences may be classified into four types of pleasure: sensory, social, emotional, and intellectual.  Study 1 was a qualitative inquiry into the scripts formed around everyday hedonic experiences.  The study produced rich and comprehensive details of the content and unfolding of such experiences and provided material for the subsequent studies.  Study 2, study 3, and study 4 tested the superior validity of a four differentiated pleasure typology (versus more parsimonious conceptualizations) and moved toward the development of a quantitative assessment tool for these pleasures.  Study 2 examined different types of pleasures associated with product categories.  Exploratory factor analysis supported the four-pleasure typology.  Study 3 explored pleasures gained from brand websites; confirmatory factor analysis validated the four-pleasure structure.  In the study, the impact of pleasure types and personality traits on marketing outcomes showed a combination of contrast (negative relationship between the value assigned to the target and the context) and assimilation (positive relationship between the value assigned to the target and the context) effects.  Study 4 tested the impact of four different advertisements, each promising one of the four pleasures at a fictitious café, thus testing a differentiated hedonic positioning strategy.  Again, results demonstrated the appropriateness of a four pleasure typology.  Consistent with study 3, the impact of differentiated pleasures on marketing outcomes (e.g., timing of visit, attitude toward ad/brand, intent to visit/recommend) revealed a combination of contrast and assimilation effects.  This dissertation addressed two previously overlooked issues.  First, it provided evidence for the validity of a four factor differentiated view of pleasure, positioning it as complementary to the unitary view, which affords no room for qualitative differences between pleasurable experiences.  Second, the research addressed the dearth of scientific investigation regarding the evaluation of hedonic consumption experiences and their marketing outcomes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse développe une conceptualisation du plaisir en tant que  phénomène différencié qui fait des expériences hédonistes la source de différents types de plaisirs. De manière empirique, les bénéfices de cette conceptualisation pour évaluer les conséquences de chaque type de plaisir sont examinés.  Quatre études confirment la validité d'une conceptualisation incluant quatre types de plaisirs : sensoriel, social, émotif et intellectuel.  La  première étude, une enquête qualitative présentant des scénarios formés autour d'expériences hédonistes, a permis de recueillir de riches détails quant au contenu et au  déroulement de ces expériences.  Les trois autres études visent à tester la validité  de quatre types de plaisirs différenciés (par opposition aux conceptualisations alternatives plus parcimonieuses) pour se diriger vers l'évolution d'un outil quantitatif d'évaluation des plaisirs.  Plus spécifiquement, la seconde étude examine divers types de plaisirs tels qu'associés à des catégories de produits en général.  La troisième étude s'attarde aux plaisirs que procurent les sites Web de grandes marques.  Grâce à l'analyse factorielle, ces deux études supportent la typologie des quatre plaisirs.  L'impact des types de plaisirs et des traits de personnalité sur les mesures d'intérêt pour des professionnels du marketing  démontre divers effets de contraste (relation négative entre la valeur assignée à la cible et au contexte) et  d'assimilation (relation positive entre la valeur assignée à la cible et au contexte).  La dernière étude vérifie l'impact de quatre publicités présentant chacune un des quatre plaisirs dans un café fictif, et met à l'épreuve une stratégie de positionnement hédoniste différencié.  Les résultats démontrent la pertinence de la typologie des quatre plaisirs.  Ici aussi, l'impact des plaisirs différenciés sur les conséquences marketing (par ex. : intention de fréquenter le café, attitude envers la publicité et la marque, intention de revisiter ou de recommander) révèle des effets de contraste et d'assimilation.  En termes de contribution scientifique, cette thèse fournit une conceptualisation différenciée du plaisir, complémentaire à la vision unitaire qui ne laisse aucune place aux nuances qualitatives.  Également, elle contribue à minimiser la pénurie de recherche scientifique sur l'évaluation des expériences hédonistes de consommation et leurs conséquences sur les comportements de consommation. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Laurette Dube</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jordan Le Bel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848q92x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c780z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Business Administration - Marketing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pg58h"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>PLAGL1/ZAC, a transient neonatal diabetes mellitus locus gene, in pancreatic beta-cell development and function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Du, Xiaoyu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Studies on congenital disorders of the pancreas have contributed to the identification of genes that are critical in beta-cell development and function. Transient neonatal diabetes mellitus (TNDM) is a rare congenital disorder of the pancreas. It involves severe insulin deficiency at birth that reverses over weeks or months but may relapse with diabetes in later life. PLAGL1 (pleiomorphic adenoma gene-like 1, also known as ZAC, zinc finger protein that regulates apoptosis and cell cycle arrest, and LOT1, Lost On Transformation 1) is one of the two possible genes at the TNDM locus and the multiple functions of PLAGL1/ZAC strongly suggest it as the causative gene of TNDM. We hypothesized that double dose expression of PLAGL1/ZAC impairs both beta-cell development and function. To test this hypothesis, we began with the study of ZAC ontogeny. In developing human pancreas, ZAC is expressed with considerable specificity in differentiated beta-cells, and its expression decreases dramatically from the second trimester to adult. These results imply a role of ZAC in a critical time window in beta-cell development, supporting its role in TNDM and explaining the transient nature of the TNDM. In vitro, effects of ZAC overexpression on beta-cell function was observed in INS-1 cells by using tetracycline regulatable system. Overexpression of ZAC inhibits glucose-stimulated insulin exocytosis and proinsulin biosynthesis. Glucose was found to be able to downregulate Lot1/Zac1 expression in INS-1 cells and mouse islets. These data suggest ZAC as a negative regulator in some glucose-regulated pathways whose abnormally high level impairs beta-cell function that explains the relapse of diabetes in TNDM. Finally, a gene expression profile study of INS-1 cells with or without induced ZAC expression identified STC1, IGF1R, SNAP25, GRP78, and P58IPK as possible targets of ZAC that mediate beta-cell dysfunctions. CRABP2, strongly upregulated by ZAC, together with G0S2, GADD45alpha, and FHL2, may mediate ZAC function in both normal beta-cell development and TNDM pathophysiology. In general, these studies suggest that tightly controlled expression level of ZAC is critical for beta-cell development and function. It provides strong evidence that ZAC overexpression causes TNDM. In addition, two previously unstudied genes, STC1 and CRABP2, are suggested to play potential important roles in beta-cell function and development.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les études portant sur les désordres congénitaux du pancréas ont contribué à l'identification de gènes critiques pour le développement et la fonction des cellules bêta. Le diabète néonatal transitoire (DNNT) est une maladie héréditaire du pancréas. Elle est caractérisée par une déficience sévère en insuline à la naissance qui disparaît après quelques semaines/mois mais pouvant réapparaître plus tard au cours de la vie. PLAGL1 (pleiomorphic adenoma gene-like 1, aussi connu comme ZAC, zinc finger protein that regulates apoptosis and cell cycle arrest, et LOT1, Lost On Transformation 1) est un des deux gènes dans la région critique du DNNT et ses multiples fonctions en font le candidat causatif le plus probable. Notre hypothèse est que sa surexpression compromet la fonction et le développement des cellules bêta. Notre étude ontgénique de ZAC dans le pancréas en développement, démontre que ZAC était exprimé avec une spécificité considérable dans les cellules bêta, expression qui diminuait à partir du second trimestre. Ces résultats supportent l'existence d'une fenêtre temporelle critique pour la fonction de ZAC dans le développement des cellules bêta, compatible avec la nature transitoire du DNNT. In vitro, les effets de la surexpression de ZAC ont été observés dans les cellules bêta INS-1 en utilisant un système d'expréssion inductible par la tétracycline. L'exocytose glucose-dépendante de l'insuline et la biosynthèse de la proinsuline sont diminués par la surexpression de ZAC. Le glucose pouvait diminuer l'expression de Lot1/Zac1 dans les INS-1 et dans les îlots murins, une observation qui propose ZAC comme un régulateur négatif de voies métaboliques régulées par le glucose dont les niveaux anormalement élevés affectent la fonction des cellules bêta. Le profile d'expression génique sur les INS-1 après induction de ZAC a identifié STC1, IGF1R, SNAP25, GRP78 et P58IPK comme cibles potentielles de ZAC intervenant dans les dysfonctionnements des cellules bêta. CRABP2, qui est fortement augmenté, tout comme G0S2, GADD45alpha et FHL2, pourrait servir de médiateur de ZAC dans le développement des cellules bêta et dans le DNNT. Ces études indiquent qu'une expression minutieusement contrôlés de ZAC est critiques pour le développement et la fonction des cellules bêta et que sa surexpression peut causer le DNNT. Finalement, un rôle de STC1 et CRABP2 dans la fonction et le développement des cellules bêta est suggéré.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Constantin Polychronakos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sg66x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pg58h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405s970b"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Is improving gait post-stroke at the tip of our fingers? the effects on enhanced sensory input (haptics and walking aids)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Perez, Claire Fritzi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nous savons déjà que le toucher léger peut augmenter le contrôle postural en position debout mais les effets haptiques, lors la marche, chez une population saine ou neurologique, sont peu connus. L'objectif de cette étude est d'examiner l'ajout d'information somatosensorielle provenant 1) du bout d'un doigt et 2) d'une canne instrumentée sur la marche d'individus ayant subi un AVC. Neuf adultes post-AVC et 9 individus sains ont marché sur un tapis roulant, à une vitesse qu'ils contrôlaient eux-mêmes. Le tapis roulant était fixé sur une plate-forme mobile faisant face à une scène virtuelle. Les conditions expérimentales consistaient à marcher sur une surface plane, inclinée de 5° vers le haut ou vers le bas: 1) sans aucun toucher, 2) avec un toucher léger du bout d'un doigt sur un capteur spécialisé et 3) en utilisant une canne instrumentée.  La variabilité de la marche, exprimée par le coefficient de variation de la durée du cycle de marche (CV), la largeur des pas et la vitesse étaient les paramètres étudiés. Les résultats ont démontré que le toucher léger est une façon efficace pour améliorer la marche sur les plans inclinés chez les personnes post-AVC et peut être plus efficace que la canne lors la marche sur un plan incliné vers le bas. Des stratégies spécifiques (toucher léger ou canne) peuvent donc améliorer la marche de façon différente selon la tâche (surface plane ou inclinée). Ces effets n'ont pas été observés chez les personnes saines.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>While postural control during quiet stance can be enhanced by haptic input, the role of tactile cues on gait ability in healthy or neurological populations is not well understood.  The aim of this study was to examine the effects of enhanced somatosensory input from (1) light fingertip touch and (2) cane use, on gait performance during level and slope walking in people post-stroke. Nine people post-stroke and 9 healthy individuals walked on a self-paced treadmill mounted on a motion platform while viewing a virtual scene.  The experimental conditions were to walk level, up or down a 5° sloped surface:  1) without touch, 2) with light fingertip touch on a bar and 3) with an instrumented cane. Gait variability, expressed as the coefficient of variation of stride duration (CV), step width and gait speed were measured.  Results reveal that light touch is an effective means of improving gait in people post-stroke.  Light touch can be as effective compared to the cane even under the challenge of slope walking and may be more effective in downslope walking.  Task specific (level, up and downslope) stabilizing strategies (use of either light touch or a cane) may offer specific gait improvements.  These effects were not seen in the healthy controls.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Joyce Fung</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r350t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405s970b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Physical Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jt96j"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A putative role for PCSK9 in synaptic remodelling and plasticity in response to brain injury: implications for Alzheimer's disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bélanger Jasmin, Stéphanie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Depuis la découverte que l'allèle ε4 de l'apolipoprotein E (apoE) est associé avec un risque plus élevé de développer la maladie d'Alzheimer (MA), un nombre grandissant d'études démontre que le cholestérol joue un rôle important dans les mécanismes pathophysiologiques reliés à cette maladie. Plusieurs gènes impliqués dans le métabolisme du cholestérol ont fait l'objet d'études et démontré une associationgénétique avec la MA. PCSK9 est une proprotein convertase qui récemment, fut associée à l'hypercholestérolémie familiale. Cette convertase est un régulateur principal des niveaux de cholestérol plasmatique par sa capacité à promouvoir la dégradation d'un récepteur de surface, le récepteur des lipoprotéines à faible densité (LDLR). Les travaux de ce projet sont basés sur l'hypothèse initiale que dans le cerveau, PCSK9 pourrait également jouer un rôle dans l'homéostasie du cholestérol en contrôlant l'expression protéique des récepteurs de LDL sous des conditions normales et neurodégénératives. Le premier volet expérimental avait pour objectif de comparer les niveaux d'expression de PCSK9 dans des cerveaux de patients identifiés à la MA ou considérés comme contrôles sains. De plus, une étude d'association génétique a été effectué afin de déterminer l'effet de polymorphismes de PCSK9 sur le risque de la MA ainsi que sur le contrôle de l'expression de PCSK9. Dans la deuxième étude, l'utilisation d'un modèle murin de lésion du cortex entorhinal a permis d'évaluer le rôle de PCSK9 dans des processus de synaptogénèse suite à un dommage neuronal. La troisième étude avait pour objectif de déterminer les effets de PCSK9, lorsque surexprimé, sur le remodelage et plasticité neuronale en réponse à une lésion dans un modèle cellulaire. Les résultats de ce projet ont démontré entre autre, une augmentation des niveaux d'expression de PCSK9 dans les régions du cortex frontal ainsi que l'hippocampe de cerveaux obtenus de patients Alzheimer en fin de maladie. Cette augmentation n'est pas causée par l'un des cinq variants génétiques de PCSK9 étudiés et aucune corrélation a été observé entre cette convertase et les marqueurs pathologiques caractérisant la MA; ce qui suggère l'implication de PCSK9 en réponse à la neurodégénération. Conformément à cette hypothèse, les niveaux de PCSK9 sont également augmentés lors de la phase active de remodelage membranaire suite à la lésion du cortex entorhinal. La surexpression de PCSK9 dans des cellules de type neuronal a causé une augmentation de la densité synaptique tant sous des conditions normales que lorsque les cellules sont activement en mode de réparation suivant la lésion, supportant ainsi un rôle pour PCSK9 dans les mécanismes de synaptogénèse et de plasticité synaptique. Alors que les niveaux de récepteurs aux LDL (LDLR) dans les cerveaux Alzheimer en plus des récepteurs de type apoER2 lors de processus de plasticité in vitro sont affectés de façon négative par PCSK9, les niveaux de LDLR suite à la lésion du cortex entorhinal ne semblent pas affectés par PCSK9 mais plutôt, parallèlement à apoE et PCSK9, sont augmentés dans la phase active de remodelage synaptique. Globalement, ces résultats indiquent que PCSK9 joue un rôle important dans les mécanismes compensatoires de réparation neuronal associés au vieillissement, à un dommage cérébrale ou à des conditions chroniques de dégénération tel qu'observées lors de la MA. Son expression dans le cerveau réflète possiblement une régulation de l'homéostasie du cholestérol ou des voies de signalisation par le contrôle de récepteurs de surface aux LDL lors de remodelage membranaires et synaptiques en réponse à un dommage neuronal. Ces résultats sont en accord avec le lien existant entre les processus d'homeostasies lipidiques et les mécanismes pathologiques associés à la MA et indiquent que PCSK9 pourrait être un nouveau joueur participant à ce phénomène. Ainsi, PCSK9 mérite de plus amples investigations dans un contexte de maladies neurodégénératives. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Since the association of the ε4 allele of the apolipoprotein E (apoE) withAlzheimer's disease (AD) risk, growing evidences support a role for cholesterolmetabolism in the pathophysiology of this disease. Many genes involved in lipidmetabolism have now been studied and associate with the risk of AD. PCSK9 is aproprotein convertase recently identified as the third gene linked to familialhypercholesterolemia. It is a key regulator of plasma cholesterol concentrations byenhancing the degradation of cell surface low-density-lipoprotein receptor (LDLR). Thepresent project derives from the global hypothesis that in the brain, PCSK9 may play arole in cholesterol homeostasis by regulating the expression of the LDLR proteins undernormal and especially, neurodegenerative conditions.A first study was conducted to evaluate potential variations in PCSK9 expressionin the brain of autopsy-confirmed AD compared to age-matched control subjects. Agenetic association study was also performed to determine the effect of five commonPCSK9 polymorphisms on AD risk and modulation of gene expression. Using theentorhinal cortex lesion (ECL) model in a second study, a role for PCSK9 in reactivesynaptogenesis was evaluated in response to brain damage in this in vivo paradigm inmice. A third study investigated in an in vitro model of reactive neuronal plasticity, theeffect of PCSK9 on synaptogenesis and remodelling processes in response to neuronalinjury.The results show a cortical and hippocampal upregulation of PCSK9 expression inthe brain of end-stages AD patients which do not result from the five studied geneticvariants. No correlations were observed for PCSK9 with markers of AD pathology;suggesting an involvement of PCSK9 in response to neurodegeneration. Consistent withthis idea, PCSK9 levels were increased during the active phase of neuronal membraneremodelling following ECL. In vitro, overexpression of PCSK9 in normal or neuronallikecells undergoing post-injury reactive plasticity caused increased synaptic densitywhich supports a role for PCSK9 in synaptogenesis and plasticity. While PCSK9 wasfound to negatively affect the LDLR levels in AD brains and both the LDLR and apoER2during reactive plasticity in vitro, levels of the LDLR in ECL mice was not affected byPCSK9 but instead, together with apoE, levels were upregulated in the early phase ofsynaptic remodelling.Together, these findings indicate that PCSK9 plays an important role incompensatory neuronal repair associated with age, brain injury or chronic degeneration asfound in AD. Its expression in the brain possibly regulates cholesterol homeostasis and/orsignalling pathways mediated by the apoE/LDLR pathway or other members of theLDLR family during axonal and synaptic remodelling. These findings are consistent withthe relationship that exists between lipid homeostatic processes and AD pathology andindicate that PCSK9 may be a new player in the regulation of these processes that worthsfurther investigation in a context of neurodegenerative disorders.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Judes Poirier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246s45t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jt96j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adr26xx715"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Measurement of oligomerization states of membrane proteins via spatial fluorescence intensity fluctuation analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sergeev, Mikhail</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'objectif de cette thèse réside dans le développement et l'utilisation d'une nouvelle technique de mesure de fluctuation de fluorescence. Cette technique d'imagerie par microscopie permet de déterminer in situ l'état d'oligomérisation de protéines couplées à un fluorophore. L'analyse par mesure de moments d'ordres supérieurs d'intensité de fluctuation de fluorescence d'images obtenues à partir d'un microscope confocal à balayage laser (CLSM) a été développée afin de mesurer la distribution en monomères/oligomères de protéines marquées par fluorescence. En utilisant des simulations par ordinateur ainsi que des expériences avec des microsphères fluorescentes, les limites de détection et l'exactitude de cette approche statistique ont pu être déterminées. Une série d'expériences contrôles a été effectuée afin de valider l'étude d'état d'oligomérisation de récepteurs membranaires présentée dans cette thèse. Cette méthode a ensuite été appliquée à l'étude de l'état d'oligomérisation dans divers systèmes biologiques. Le récepteur au facteur de croissance épidermique (EGFR) joue un rôle critique dans la croissance, la prolifération et la survie cellulaire. Les étapes d'activation des voies de transduction du signal sont connues pour impliquer l'oligomérisation de l'EGFR. Des études de pharmaco-dynamique d'agglomération provoquée par liaison d'un ligand ont été conduites. La technique d'analyse de distribution spatiale d'intensité (SpIDA), qui permet de mesurer précisément la distribution de monomères/dimères a été utilisée pour mesurer l'augmentation de la population de dimères d'EGFR après liaison du ligand (EGF). La distribution des agrégats se formant au cours de l'internalisation d'EGFR a été mesurée par analyse de moments pour deux populations. Les résultats confirment une hypothèse proposant deux voies distinctes d'internalisation du récepteur. Le co-transporteur électrogénique au bicarbonate de sodium NBCe1-A joue un rôle important dans l'absorption du bicarbonate de sodium à travers la membrane baso-latérale du tubule proximal rénal. Les analyses par moments de fluorescence et SpIDA ont été appliquées pour étudier l'état d'oligomérisation de NBCe1-A dans des cellules mammifères en cultures exprimant plusieurs mutants du co-transporteur. L'analyse de fluctuation spatiale montre que NBCe1-A est présent majoritairement sous forme de monomère sur la membrane cellulaire et de façon négligeable sous forme d'oligomères d'ordres supérieurs. Afin de mesurer l'état d'oligomérisation du co-transporteur naturel, des échantillons de reins de rats ont été préparés et NBCe1-A a été marqué par immunoréaction avec des anticorps fluorescents reconnaissant le type naturel du co-transporteur. L'analyse d'image indique que NBCe1-A est présent sous forme de dimère et rarement sous forme de monomère ou d'oligomères d'ordre supérieurs sur la membrane baso-latérale des tubules proximaux. Le virus humain d'immunodéficience (VIH) détourne la machinerie cellulaire ESCRT pour promouvoir la sortie de la cellule hôte de virions nouvellement formés. L'ATPase VPS4A est impliquée à une étape avancée de la fonction ESCRT en produisant de l'énergie pour la dissociation du complexe ESCRT et l'invagination de la membrane plasmique. L'analyse du moment de fluorescence d'images de VPS4A-eGFP montre une distribution monomérique à l'extérieur des sites de bourgeonnement ainsi que la présence de deux à quatre dodécamères sur les sites de bourgeonnement. La combinaison des résultats des études de la dynamique de VPS4A ainsi que l'analyse de la taille des pics d'intensité lumineux permet de mieux comprendre le cycle de vie du VIH ainsi que son processus de relargage.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The objective of this thesis is the development and use of a novel fluorescence fluctuation technique for determining the oligomeric state of fluorescently labeled proteins in situ via microscopy imaging. High order moment analysis of fluorescence intensity fluctuations from individual confocal laser scanning microscopy (CLSM) images applied to study monomer-oligomer distributions of fluorescently labeled proteins was developed. Using computer simulations and experiments with fluorescent microspheres and organic fluorescent dyes, the detection limits and accuracy of this statistical approach were determined. A series of control experiments were carried out to support the membrane receptor oligomerization studies in this thesis. The methods were then applied to study oligomerization states in various biological systems. Epidermal growth factor receptors (EGFR) play a critical role in cell growth, proliferation and survival. The activation steps of signal transduction pathways are known to involve EGFR oligomerization. Pharmacodynamic studies of ligand-induced clustering of EGF receptors were carried out. Spatial intensity distribution analysis (SpIDA), which accurately measures monomer-dimer distributions, was used to measure the increase in EGFR dimeric population upon addition of EGF ligand. The distribution of aggregates forming in the course of EGFR internalization was evaluated using two-population moment analysis. The findings supported an existing model proposing two distinct receptor internalization pathways. The electrogenic sodium bicarbonate cotransporter NBCe1-A plays an important role in absorbing sodium bicarbonate across the basolateral membrane of the proximal tubule. The fluorescence moment image analysis and SpIDA were applied to study the oligomeric state of NBCe1-A in cultured mammalian cells expressing various mutants of cotransporter. Spatial fluctuation analysis revealed that NBCe1-A existed on the cell membrane predominantly as a monomer and negligibly as higher order oligomers. To measure the oligomerization state of the native cotransporter, samples of rat kidney tissues were prepared and the native NBCe1-A was immunostained using fluorescently labeled primary antibody against the wild type cotransporter. The image analysis showed that NBCe1-A was present on the proximal tubule basolateral membrane in predominantly dimeric and rarely monomeric or higher order oligomeric states. Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) diverts the cellular ESCRT machinery to promote the release of newly formed virions from host cells. The ATPase, VPS4A, acts at a late stage of ESCRT function. It provides energy for dissociation of ESCRT complexes and membrane abscision. The fluorescence moment analysis of VPS4A-eGFP images revealed the monomeric distribution of the protein in the plasma membrane outside budding sites and formation of two to five VPS4A dodecamers at the budding sites. The combination of the results of VPS4A dynamics studies together with the VPS4A burst size analysis shed light on steps in the HIV lifecycle and release.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul Wiseman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vb65k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26xx715</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pg60j"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of perioperative insulin therapy on patients undergoing major liver resections</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hassanain, Mazen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les tissus traumatiques chirurgicaux stimulent la libération d'hormones de stress et de cytokines pro-inflammatoires afin de créer les éléments nécessaires pour la cicatrisation.  Une réponse au stress aggravée par le jeune préopératoire limite la capacité du foie à se régénérer en puisant dans ses réserves d'énergie. Ce changement de métabolisme conduit  à un état de résistance insulinémique et d'hyperglycémie chez le patient. Un supplément de dextrose et d'insuline par voie intraveineuse durant la période périopératoire offre des résultats post-chirurgicaux supérieurs tout en laissant le foie préserver son glycogène et maintenir un contrôle glycémique stricte. Le but de cette étude était d'étudier les avantages reliés à l'utilisation d'un protocole de soutien métabolique impliquant la perfusion de glucides et d'insuline par le biais d'une pince hyperinsulinémique normoglycémiques (HNC) sur des patients cédulés pour une résection hépatique. Cette étude a été réalisée dans le cadre d'une étude clinique randomisé-contrôlées enregistré sous NCT00774098 sur clinicaltrial.gov. Au départ, 5 patients, dont 1 atteint de diabète Type I, ont été randomisés sur le protocole   HNC durant l'hépatectomie majeure. Cette étude de faisabilité nous a aidés à affiner le protocole afin de le reproduire, tout en sécurité, sur un plus grand échantillon. Nous avons généré un essai clinique randomisé incluant 60 patients afin d`étudier les effets bénéfiques reliés à ce type de protocole au niveau de l'accroissement du niveau de glycogène dans le foie et la réduction des complications post opératoires. Les patients ont été randomisés soit sur le protocole HNC ou le groupe de contrôle. Les patients randomisés sur l'étude recevaient, en plus du HNC durant la période intra et post opératoire, des suppléments élevés de glucide par voie orale, suivie d'une perfusion de dextrose par voie intraveineuse à 2 mg / kg / min dans les 24 heures précédant l'intervention chirurgicale. Le groupe de contrôle était gérer en suivant le protocole standard de l'hôpital.  Des échantillons de sang et de foie ont été prélevés à divers moments afin de suivre de près la fonction hépatique et la teneur de glycogène dans le foie. En plus, des tests  d'expression génétique ont été faits sur certains de ces échantillons. Les échantillons de sang et de foie étaient analysés pour étudier le cycle métabolique, inflammatoire et cellulaire. Une surcharge de glucide combiné avec l'utilisation du HNC durant l'opération et la période post-opératoire a augmenté le niveau de glycogène dans le foie et a réduit les complications post-opératoires.  Les diabétiques et les non-diabétiques ont bénéficié d'une telle thérapie.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Tissue injury related to liver surgery stimulates the release of stress hormones and proinflammatory cytokines to produce the necessary elements needed for healing. An exaggerated stress response compounded by preoperative fasting limits the liver's capacity to regenerate by depleting its energy stores.  This change in metabolism leads to an insulin resistant state in the patient and associated hyperglycaemia. Dextrose supplementation coupled with intravenous insulin given perioperatively affords superior surgical outcomes through preservation of liver glycogen and strict glycaemia control.The goal of this research was to investigate the benefits of a metabolic support protocol involving carbohydrate loading and insulin infusion provided by a hyperinsulinemic normoglycaemic clamp (HNC), for patients undergoing hepatic resection. Studies were performed in the context of a randomized-controlled clinical trial registered at clinicaltrial.gov NCT00774098. Initially, 5 patients including 1 with diabetes mellitus were given the HNC protocol while undergoing a major hepatectomy. This feasibility study helped fine-tune the protocol towards improving its safety and reproducibility, and prompted expansion and randomization of the trial to include sixty patients. The goal of the expanded trial was to study the benefits of the protocol in augmenting liver glycogen and reducing postoperative complications. The patients were randomly assigned to either intervention or control groups. Intervention patients received a 24-hour oral carbohydrate-load, followed by an IV dextrose infusion (2 mg/kg/min) in the 24 hours leading to surgery, followed by insulin therapy given intra- and postoperatively. Controls adhered to routine management. Blood and tissue samples were taken at various time points for monitoring liver glycogen content and function. In the final stage of the project a subset of patients was selected for genetic expression testing. Blood and liver tissue samples were analyzed to identify specific inflammatory, metabolic and cell cycles pathways stimulated by the protocol.Carbohydrate loading combined with intra- and postoperative use of the HNC protocol augmented liver glycogen and reduced postoperative complications. Diabetic and nondiabetic patients alike benefited from this therapy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peter Metrakos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fx23w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pg60j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237hs27w"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Philosophizing Shakespeare</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Coodin, Sara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ma thèse Philosophizing Shakespeare explore l'impact de l'éthique de la vertu classique sur l'art dramatique de Shakespeare, à savoir sur l'art de sa caractérisation.  L'éthique de la vertu pendant la renaissance anglaise comprend une vaste sélection d'écrits et d'écrivains, des interprètes de Thomas d'Aquin aux pamphlétaires.  Dans cette thèse, je me focalise sur la tradition vernaculaire de l'éthique de la vertu pratique en Angleterre de la Renaissance – une tradition qui est particulièrement distincte de la philosophie latine institutionnelle, mais qui est également coincé par la pensée éthique aristotélicienne.  Contrairement à la philosophie académique, les écrits vernaculaires de la philosophie morale s'inscrivent à l'intérêt de Shakespeare pour la dynamique du raisonnement moral dans des situations spécifiques, particulièrement dans les domaines de la vie sociale et domestique.  Cette emphase pratique et mondaine représente le fondement pour le savoir décisif éthique et pour l'ethos, ou le caractère moral, celui-ci étant présent dans des manuels de comportement en anglais et des traités sur la santé humaine et l'émotion.  Je propose ici qu'il existe un lien considérable entre la conception de soi offerte par la philosophie morale articulée par ces écrivains et la caractérisation shakespearienne des individus tels que Shylock.  A travers l'exploration ce qui constitue l'analyse des personnages de Shakespeare comme ayant une conception éthique, je me focalise sur les manières dont les notions de vertu servent de source de ce qui s'avère être une orientation hautement idiosyncratique pour les personnages de Shakespeare.  Ainsi, je fournis un contexte pour leurs choix pratiques qui dote ces choix et leur comportement d'une signification morale.  En plaçant les écrits de la philosophie morale en langue anglaise dans le contexte de la tradition de la pensée de la Renaissance aristotélicienne, et en particulière, dans la trop négligée variété d'aristotélisme vernaculaire pendant la Renaissance, je me base sur l'érudition de Charles Schmitt et David Lines, qui ont reformulé Aristote comme ayant une influence formatrice, quoique éclectique, sur la culture européenne de la Renaissance jusque le dix-septième siècle était bien entamé.  A la fois, nous considérons l'usage de Shakespeare des concepts philosophiques aristotéliciens comme une espèce d'adaptation typiquement éclectique.  En se focalisant sur des problèmes philosophiques tels que l'acrasie (l'incontinence, ou la faiblesse de volonté), l'auto déception, et l'excès émotionnel, les chapitres individuels de ma thèse se concentrent sur les manières dont les pièces de Shakespeare représentent en même temps que problématisent des « soi » façonnés classiquement.                </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Philosophizing Shakespeare explores the impact of Classical virtue ethics on Shakespeare's dramatic art, particularly his art of characterization. By focusing on the vernacular tradition of practical virtue ethics in Renaissance England – a tradition importantly distinct from institutional Latin philosophizing, but equally bound up with Aristotle's ethical thought -- I maintain that vernacular moral-philosophical writings share Shakespeare's interest in the dynamics of situated moral reasoning, particularly within the domains of social and domestic life. This practical, worldly emphasis, I argue, represents the foundation for ethical decision-making and for ethos (moral character) in Shakespeare. Philosophizing Shakespeare therefore argues for the importance of thinking about Shakespeare's characters as moral agents, while also demonstrating some of the historical and philosophical roots to the concept of moral agency in Shakespeare's England.By contextualizing practical English-language moral-philosophical writings within the tradition of Renaissance Aristotelian thought and, in particular, the critically neglected strain of vernacular Aristotelianism in the Renaissance, Philosophizing Shakespeare builds on recent historical scholarship by Charles Schmitt and David Lines, who have recast Aristotle as a formative though eclectic influence on Renaissance European culture until well into the seventeenth century. At the same time, I consider Shakespeare's use of Aristotelian philosophical ideas as a typically eclectic kind of adaptation. In my discussion on The Merchant of Venice, I propose that Shylock is animated by a concept of virtue quite distinct from Aristotle's, but nevertheless just as central to his motivation as a character and behavior within the play. By focusing on the philosophical problem of akrasia (weakness of the will or moral incontinence), I also emphasize ways in which plays such as The Winter's Tale problematize Classically modeled selves. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael D. Bristol</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Theodore W. Folkerth</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290976b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hs27w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As7526c699"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The ecological and evolutionary assembly of trophic metacommunities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pillay, Pradeep</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite the important role spatial processes play in natural communities, far too little theoretical work has been devoted to exploring how complex food web communities may be assembled in space, and how the spatial structure of trophic interactions may provide a stabilizing mechanism for complex food web networks. In this thesis I develop a food web metacommunity model based on a classic Levins-type patch-dynamic model which views trophic interactions between species as occurring in a spatially subdivided habitat. I then use this model to explore both simple and complex trophic networks in an ecological and evolutionary context. I first review and evaluate previous attempts at defining a patch-dynamic metacommunity model of trophic interactions. After correcting the flaws in previously published models I develop a corrected model and apply it to simple trophic configurations. I show how the stability of simple trophic interactions, like omnivory loops, depends upon the interacting effects of space and network configuration. I then use the model to study the evolution of dispersal in a simple predator-prey system. Specifically, I investigate how both predator and prey dispersal rates will evolve in response to increasing patch extinction rates caused by locally strong top-down predator effects. I show how the predator's evolutionarily stable (ESS) dispersal rate will increase, as expected, in response to increasing local extinction, while the prey's ESS dispersal rate exhibits a counterintuitive nonmonotonic response – actually decreasing for some ranges of extinction. I explain how the prey's counterintuitive response arises because of the way trophic interactions between species play out at different spatial scales. After applying the model to simple networks I then explore the assembly of complex food webs. I show that, under very simple assumptions, diverse and complex food web networks can be assembled through the creation of network branches which provide opportunities for the build-up species and multiple food chain paths in the food web. I also show how these network branches can emerge simply as the result of the spatial distribution of trophic interactions, and the structural support provided by omnivory and generalist feeding links. I then attempt to determine if natural food webs show a relationship between biodiversity and network branching. To this end I examine a set of empirical food webs and observe a striking linear scaling relationship between food web size and the degree of branching in the minimum spanning tree of a food web.  This empirical corroboration of the theory suggests that the theory reported here may be of value as a guide to how space and dispersal interact to structure natural food webs at large scales.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Malgré l'importance des processus spatiaux dans les communautés écologiques naturelles, peu de théories examinent le rôle de l'espace dans l'assemblage et la stabilisation des réseaux trophiques complexes. Dans cette thèse, je développe un modèle de réseau trophique spatial (métacommunauté) fondé sur un model dynamique de métapopulation du type Levins, où les interactions trophiques entres les espèces ont lieu au sein d'une série de populations locales. Ce modèle de métacommunauté me permet d'examiner les réseaux trophiques simples et complexes dans un contexte écologique et évolutif.Dans le premier chapitre, je résume et critique les modèles actuels de métacommunauté du type Levins incorporant les interactions trophiques dans un contexte spatial. Après avoir identifié les erreurs de ces modèles, je développe un modèle corrigé afin d'examiner des réseaux trophiques simples. Je montre que la stabilité des interactions trophiques simples (telles que les boucles omnivores) dépend de l'interaction entre la structure spatiale et la topologie du réseau trophique. Dans le deuxième chapitre, j'utilise ce modèle afin de déterminer l'évolution du taux de dispersion du prédateur et de sa proie lorsque la prédation favorise l'extinction des populations locales. Je montre que face à une augmentation du taux d'extinction, le taux de dispersion évolutivement stable du prédateur augmente de façon monotone  alors que celui de la proie varie de façon non-monotone et diminue pour certains niveaux d'extinction. Je démontre que cette réponse contre-intuitive de la proie est due à la structure spatiale des interactions trophiques entre les espèces.Dans le troisième chapitre, j'utilise le modèle afin d'étudier l'assemblage de réseaux trophiques complexes dans l'espace. Je montre que l'addition de branches dans le réseau trophique (ramification) permet l'accumulation d'espèces dans des chaînes alimentaires distinctes et la création de réseaux trophiques complexes.   Je démontre que cette ramification du réseau trophique est due à la distribution spatiale des interactions trophiques ainsi que le support structurel apporté par les boucles omnivores et généralistes.Dans le quatrième chapitre, j'essaye de déterminer si la relation entre la biodiversité et la ramification des réseaux trophiques observée dans le modèle est applicable aux réseaux trophiques naturels. Je montre qu'il existe une forte relation linéaire entre la taille des réseaux trophiques naturels et le nombre de branches qui caractérise leur arbre couvrant minimum. Cette vérification empirique du modèle indique que la théorie développée dans cette thèse pourrait permettre de mieux comprendre les rôles que jouent l'espace et de la dispersion dans l'assemblage et la structure des réseaux trophiques naturels à grandes échelles.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michel Loreau</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Andrew Gonzalez</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579s58c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526c699</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Ecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2v23vt70c"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quantitative magnetic resonance imaging of cortical multiple sclerosis pathology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tardif, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Immunohistochemistry (IHC) and advanced magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) studies over the last decade have corroborated that grey matter (GM) structures are extensively involved in multiple sclerosis (MS) pathology, revolutionizing the long time perception of MS as a white matter disease. Yet cortical GM lesions remain notoriously difficult to detect in vivo using MRI. The main objective of this thesis was to create a quantitative MRI acquisition and analysis framework for the study of cortical MS pathology in vivo. To achieve this, two complementary approaches were used: brain morphometry and quantitative imaging of magnetic resonance properties (qMRI). The first aim was to develop an optimal acquisition protocol for voxel-based morphometry (VBM) of GM density to quantitatively study regional GM atrophy in MS. The sensitivity of VBM results to MR field strength and acquisition sequences was characterized by performing a VBM study of healthy controls using the two most common T1-weighted anatomical sequences, FLASH and MP-RAGE, at both 1.5 and 3 Tesla. The subsequent study introduced a new implementation of the MDEFT sequence for VBM at 3 Tesla, and compared it to FLASH and MP-RAGE. MDEFT showed the highest contrast-to-noise ratio between brain tissues, and required the smallest number of subjects to detect a significant difference in GM density. The second aim was to create a quantitative MR model of cortical lesions, a valuable tool to guide the design of qMRI acquisition methodologies for in vivo cortical lesion detection, and for the interpretation of in vivo MRI results. A combined high-resolution qMRI and IHC study of a post mortem MS hemisphere was performed. Cortical demyelinated lesions were characterized by an increase in T1 and T2 relaxation times and proton density, and by a decrease in magnetization transfer ratio. Finally, both approaches were combined to develop a cortical lesion segmentation technique based on laminar profile shape analysis of qMR images. This technique was demonstrated and validated using the post mortem qMRI and IHC data set. Collectively, these quantitative imaging methodologies have the potential to improve our understanding of the evolution of GM MS pathology in vivo, and the correlation with clinical/cognitive disability.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Au cours des dix dernières années, l'immunohistologie et l'imagerie par résonance magnétique (IRM) ont corroboré l'étendue de la pathologie de la sclérose en plaques (SEP) dans la substance grise, révolutionnant ainsi la perception de la SEP comme maladie de la substance blanche. Les lésions corticales demeurent toutefois très difficiles à discerner in vivo au moyen de l'IRM. L'objectif central de cette thèse de doctorat était de créer un cadre d'acquisition et d'analyse quantitatives d'IRM pour étudier la pathologie corticale de la SEP in vivo. À cette fin, deux approches complémentaires ont été utilisées : la neuro-morphométrie et l'imagerie quantitative des propriétés de résonance magnétique des tissus cérébraux. En premier lieu, nous avons développé un protocol d'acquisition d'image optimisé pour la morphométrie voxel à voxel (VBM) de la substance grise afin de quantifier l'atrophie locale de la substance grise causée par la SEP. La sensibilité des résultats de VBM à la force du champ magnétique ainsi qu'à la séquence d'acquisition a été caractérisée par une étude VBM sur des sujets sains utilisant les deux séquences en pondération T1 les plus répandues, FLASH et MP-RAGE, à 1,5 et 3 Tesla. Une implémentation innovatrice de la séquence MDEFT pour le VBM à 3 Tesla a ensuite été comparée à FLASH et à MP-RAGE. MDEFT a démontré le rapport contraste sur bruit le plus élevé entre la substance blanche et la substance grise, et a exigé le plus petit nombre de sujets pour détecter une différence significative dans la densité de la substance grise. En second lieu, nous avons créé un modèle quantitatif de résonance magnétique des lésions corticales, un outil indispendable à la conception de nouvelles méthodes d'acquisition d'IRM pour la détection de plaques corticales in vivo, et pour l'interprétation des observations d'IRM in vivo. Nous avons réalisé une étude d'IRM quantitative à haute résolution d'un hémisphère post mortem atteint de SEP, qui a ensuite été validée par l'immunohistologie. Les lésions corticales démyélinisées sont caractérisées par un prolongement des temps de relaxation T1 et T2, une augmentation de la densité de protons et une diminution du ratio de transfert de magnétisation. Finalement, les deux approches ont été jumelées pour développer une méthode de segmentation des lésions corticales sur IRM basée sur l'analyse de la forme des profils laminaires du cortex. La méthode a été appliquée et validée sur l'ensemble des données d'IRM et d'immunohistologie de l'hémisphère post mortem. L'ensemble de ces méthodes quantitatives d'IRM a le potentiel d'améliorer notre compréhension de l'évolution de la pathologie affectant la substance grise en SEP, ainsi que d'améliorer la corrélation avec les déficiences cliniques et cognitives.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gilbert Bruce Pike</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g056q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vt70c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj67314267"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimization techniques for distributed logic simulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xu, Qing</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gate level simulation is a necessary step to verify the correctness of a circuitdesign before fabrication. It is a very time-consuming application, especially in lightof current circuit sizes. Since circuits are continually growing in size and complexity,there is a need for more efficient simulation techniques to keep the circuit verificationtime acceptably small. The use of parallel or distributed simulation is such a technique.When executed on a network of workstations, distributed simulation is alsoa very cost-effective technique. This research focuses on optimization techniques forTime Warp based gate-level logic simulations. The techniques which are described inthis thesis are oriented towards distributed platforms. The first major contributionof this thesis was the creation of an object oriented distributed simulator, XTW. Ituses an optimistic synchronization algorithm and incorporates a number of knownoptimization techniques targeting different aspects of distributed logic simulation.XEQ, an O(1) event scheduling algorithm for this simulator was developed for usein XTW. XEQ enabled us to execute gate level simulations up to 9.4 times fasterthan the same simulator using a skip-list (O(lg n)) event queue. rb-messagea mechanism which reduces the cost of rollback in Time Warp was also developedfor use in XTW. Our experiments revealed that the rb-message mechanism reducedthe number of anti-messages sent in a Time Warp based logic simulation by 76%on average. Moreover, based on the observations that (1)not all circuits should besimulated in parallel and (2) different circuits achieve their best parallel simulationperformance with a different number of compute nodes, an algorithm that uses theK-NN machine learning algorithm was devised to determine the most effective softwareand hardware combination for a logic simulation. After an extensive trainingregime, it was shown to make a correct prediction 99% of the time on whether touse a parallel or sequential simulator. The predicted number of nodes to use on aparallel platform was shown to produce an average execution time which was notmore than 12% of the smallest execution time. The configuration which resulted inthe minimal execution time was picked 61% of the time. A final contribution of thisthesis is an effort to link together commercial single processor simulators making useof Verilog PLI.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La simulation "gate-level" est une tape ncessaire pour vrifier la conformit dela conception d'un circuit avant sa fabrication. C'est un programme qui prendbeaucoup de temps, compte tenu particulirement de la taille actuelle des circuits.Ceux-ci ne cessant de se dvelopper en taille et en complexit, il y a un rel besoin detechniques de simulation plus efficaces afin de maintenir la dure de vrification ducircuit raisonnablement courte. Une de ces techniques consiste utiliser la simulationparallle ou distribue. Quand excute sur un rseau de postes de travail, la simulationdistribue se rvle galement tre une technique trs rentable. Cette recherche se concentresur l'optimisation des techniques de simulations "gate-level" logiques bases surTime Warp. Les techniques qui sont dcrites dans cet expos sont orientes vers lesplateformes distribues. La premire contribution majeure de cet expos a t la crationd'un simulateur distribu orient sur l'objet, XTW. Il utilise un algorithme de synchronisationoptimiste et incorpore un certain nombre de techniques d'optimisationconnues visant diffrents aspects de la simulation distribue logique. XEQ, un algorithmeprogrammateur d'vnements O(1) pour ce simulateur a t dvelopp pour treutilis dans XTW. XEQ nous permet d'excuter des simulations "gate-level" jusqu'9,4 fois plus rapides qu'avec le mme simulateur utilisant une suite d'vnement en"skip-list" (O(lg n)). "rb-message" – un mcanisme qui diminue le co?t de rductiondans Time Warp a galement t mis au point pour tre utilis dans XTW. Nos essaisont rvl que le mcanisme de "rb-message" permettait de diminuer le nombre des antimessagesenvoys au cours d'une simulation logique base sur Time Warp de 76 % enmoyenne. Il a t en outre con?u, en se basant sur les observations que (1) certainscircuits ne devraient pas tre simuls en parallle et (2) que diffrents circuits atteignentleur meilleure performance de simulation parallle avec un nombre diffrent de noeudsde calculs, un algorithme utilisant l'algorithme d'apprentissage de la machine K-NNafin de dterminer quelle tait l'association de logiciel et de matriel la plus efficacedans le cadre d'une simulation logique. l'issue d'un entra?nement approfondi, ilest apparu qu'il pouvait faire un pronostic juste 99 % tablissant quand utiliser unsimulateur parallle ou squentiel. Le nombre annonc de noeuds utiliser sur une plateformeparallle s'est avr permettre une dure d'excution moyenne gale 12 % de la pluscourte dure d'excution. La configuration ayant abouti la dure d'excution minimalea t reprise dans 61 % des cas. Dernire contribution apporte par cet expos, relier lessimulateurs commerciaux processeur unique utilisant Verilog PLI.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carl Tropper</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fh47n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67314267</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603qx816"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Welding High Strength Modern Line Pipe Steel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Goodall, Graeme</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effect of modern mechanized girth welding on high strength line pipe has been investigated. The single cycle grain coarsened heat affected zone in three grade 690 line pipe steels and a grade 550 steel has been simulated using a Gleeble thermo-mechanical simulator. The continuous cooling transformation diagrams applicable to the grain coarsened heat affected zone resulting from a range of heat inputs applicable to modern mechanized welding have been established by dilatometry and metallography. The coarse grained heat affected zone was found to transform to lath martensite, bainite, and granular bainite depending on the cooling rate. The impact toughness of the steels was measured using Charpy impact toughness and compared to the toughness of the grain coarsened heat affected zone corresponding to a welding thermal cycle. The ductile to brittle transition temperature was found to be lowest for the steel with the highest hardenability. The toughness resulting from three different thermal cycles including a novel interrupted intercritically reheated grain coarsened (NTR ICR GC HAZ) that can result from dual torch welding at fast travel speed and close torch spacing have been investigated. All of the thermally HAZ regions showed reduced toughness that was attributed to bainitic microstructure and large effective grain sizes. Continuous cooling transformation diagrams for five weld metal chemistries applicable to mechanized pulsed gas metal arc welding of modern high strength pipe steel (SMYS&gt;550 MPa) have been constructed. Welds at heat inputs of 1.5 kJmm-1 and 0.5 kJmm-1 have been created for simulation and analysis. Dilatometric analysis was performed on weld metal specimens cut from single pass 1.5 kJmm-1 as deposited beads. The resulting microstructures were found to range from martensite to polygonal ferrite. There is excellent agreement between the simulated and as deposited weld metal regions. Toughness testing indicates improved energy absorption at -20 °C with increased cooling time.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'effet des méthodes modernes de soudage circonférentiel mécanisé sur des aciers à forte résistance utilisés pour les tubes de canalisation a été investigué. La zone affectée thermiquement ayant subi une croissance de grain lors d'un cycle thermique simple de soudage a été simulée pour trois grades d'acier à tubes de canalisation 690 et un grade d'acier 550 à l'aide d'un appareil de simulation thermomécanique Gleeble. Les diagrammes de transformation en refroidissement continu pour la zone affectée thermiquement ayant subi une croissance de grains ont été établis pour un spectre de chaleur induite représentatif du procédé de soudage mécanisé en utilisant la dilatométrie ainsi que des analyses métallographiques. Il résulte que la zone affectée thermiquement ayant subi une croissance de grain connaît un changement de phase vers une martensite massive, une bainite ou une bainite granulaire selon le taux de refroidissement rencontré. La résistance des aciers étudiés a été mesurée par essais Charpy et comparée à la résistance obtenue pour la zone affectée thermiquement ayant subi une croissance de grains correspondant à un cycle thermique de soudage. Le plus bas température de transition ductile-fragile a été obtenue pour les grades d'acier ayant la plus grande aptitude à la trempe. La résistance résultante des structures obtenues pour trois différents cycles thermique, notamment un nouveau cycle thermique interrompu par recuit intercritique similaire à l'effet que peut avoir un soudage à double torche à déplacement rapide et espacement réduit, a été étudié. Toutes les zones affectée thermiquement montrent une baisse de résistance causée par l'apparition d'une structure bainitique et la croissance des grains.Les diagrammes de transformations en refroidissement continu ont été établis pour 5 alliages de soudage applicable pour le soudage pulsé à l'arc sous gas des aciers à tube modernes à haute résistance. Des soudures avec un apport de chaleur de 1,5 kJmm-1 et 0,5 kJmm-1 ont été utilisées pour les simulations et les analyses. Des essais de dilatométrie ont été faits sur des échantillons prélevés des cordons de soudure déposés en une passe à 1,5 kJmm-1. L'observation métallographique des échantillons présente une structure allant de la martensite à la ferrite polygonale. Une excellente concordance a été établie entre la structure du métal obtenu par simulation et telle que déposé.  Les tests de résistance indiquent une amélioration de l'énergie absorbée à -20°C lorsque le temps de refroidissement est plus long.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mathieu Brochu</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>John Bowker</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b3919.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qx816</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88cg91s"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular ecology and evolution in "Hypoplectrus" coral reef fishes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Puebla, Oscar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'environnement marin présente moins de barrières au flux génétique que ses équivalents terrestres et d'eau douce. De plus, les phases planctoniques larvaires prévalences chez les espèces marines peuvent potentiellement maintenir un flux génétique a travers de grandes distances géographiques. Ces observations soulèvent deux questions fondamentales. Comment se développent de nouvelles espèces dans le milieu marin? Considérant le flux génétique potentiellement important, il demeure incertain dans quelle mesure la spéciation allopatrique peut expliquer la grande diversité observée dans le milieu marin, si la speciation opère également en présence de "flux génétique, et si oui par quels mécanismes. Quelle distance parcourent les phases larvaires planctoniques avec les courants marins? La structure génétique généralement faible parmi les populations marines suggère une dispersion extensive, mais les larves planctoniques sont notoirement difficiles a suivre en raison de leur petite taille et par conséquent I’ échelle spatiale de la dispersion marine échappe encore largement aux écologues.lci, je considère les poissons de récifs coralliens brillamment colores du genre HypopJectrus (Serranidae) comme systeme modèle pour aborder ces deux questions. Je démontre comment la speciation écologique avec flux génétique peut opérer dans ce système par I’ effet plëiotropique du patron de coloration, qui semble être impliquée dans le mimétisme ainsi que dans le choix d'un partenaire sexuel. Je montre que des processus locaux opèrent  a I’ échelle des  Caraïbes dans ce systeme, ce qui suggère une dispersion limitée. Je teste et confirme cette hypothèse en reportant de I’ isolement génétique par la distance chez HypopJectrus puella des échelles spatiales allant de 175 a3,200 km. Afin d'estimer la distance de dispersion moyenne je complémente les données génétiques avec des relèves de densités de population couvrant</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The marine environment presents fewer absolute geographic barriers to gene flow than its terrestrial and freshwater counterparts. In addition, the prevalence of planktonic larval stages in marine taxa provides potential for gene flow across large geographic distances. These observations raise two fundamental questions. How do new species arise in the marine environment? Considering the potential for gene flow in marine systems, it remains unclear to what extent allopatric speciation alone can account for the high levels of diversity observed in the marine realm, whether marine speciation also operates in the presence of gene flow, and if it does under what specific mechanisms. How far do planktonic larvae travel with marine currents? The generally low levels of genetic structure among marine populations suggests extensive dispersal, yet planktonic larvae are notoriously difficult to track owing to their small size and as a consequence the spatial scale of marine dispersal is still largely eluding ecologists.  Here, I consider brightly colored coral reef fishes in the genus Hypop/ectrus (Serranidae) as a model system to address these two questions. I demonstrate the potential for ecological speciation with gene flow to operate in this system through the pleiotropic effect of color pattern, which appears to be involved both in mimicry and mate choice. I show that local processes are operating at the Caribbean scale in this system, suggesting dispersal limitation. I test and confirm this hypothesis by reporting genetic isolation by distance in the barred hamlet (Hypop/ectrus puel/a) at spatial scales ranging from 175 to 3,200 km. In order to estimate mean dispersal distance, I complement genetic data with SCUBA surveys of population densities covering 94,000 m2 of reef and provide dispersal estimates ranging between 2 and 14 km for specific dispersal functions notwithstanding the three-week pelagic larval stage of H. puel/a and very low levels of genetic structure a</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bermingham, Elderedge</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Guichard, Frederic</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580m984.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cg91s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3r074v45s"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Assessment of Pyrolysis techniques of lignocellulosic biomass for Biochar production</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dutta, Baishali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La pyrolyse de biomasse à des températures excédant 300°C, suivi d'un retour au sol du produit de carbonisation de matériel biologique, s'avère une stratégie permettant de possiblement atténuer le changement climatique et réduire la consommation de combustibles fossiles.  Dans la présente étude, nous tentâmes de créer un modèle d'éléments finis (MEF) permettant de coupler le réchauffement thermique et les phénomènes de transfert de chaleur et de masse opérant durant la pyrolyse. Cette démarche de modélisation et simulation numérique améliora notre habilité à visualiser le procédé et à optimiser la production de biochar. Des sections cylindriques de biomasse de bois de bouleau furent soumises à une pyrolyse dans un désorbeur thermique de laboratoire. L'influence de la température finale de pyrolyse, la vitesse d'élévation de température, et l'atmosphère de pyrolyse fut investiguée. Les résultants démontrèrent que tandis que le rendement en produits de pyrolyse diminua avec une augmentation de la température et du temps de la pyrolyse, le contenu en charbon du bois augmenta avec une augmentation ces paramètres, tout autant pour une pyrolyse lente qu'une pyrolyse rapide. A travers cette démarche, nous identifiâmes une technique permettant de maximiser la quantité de charbon dans les produits de pyrolyse ainsi que le rendement global du procédé. Le biochar ainsi généré fut testé par analyse immédiate et analyse calorimétrique à compensation de puissance afin de déterminer ses propriétés thermodynamiques, qui furent analysées et comparées selon les caractéristiques physiques des différents biochars, soit leur porosité et leur réflectance. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Biomass pyrolysis at temperatures above 300°C, with the biochar being returned to the soil is a possible strategy for climate change mitigation and reducing fossil fuel consumption. In this study, an attempt has been made to develop a finite element model (FEM) in order to couple thermal heating and heat and mass transfer phenomena during pyrolysis. This numerical modelling and simulation approach helped the visualization of the process and optimized the production of biochar. In this work, cylindrical sections of birch wood biomass were pyrolysed in a laboratory-scale thermal desorption unit. The influences of final pyrolysis temperature, heating rate, and pyrolysis atmosphere on the product yields were investigated. Results showed that the yield of pyrolysis products was reduced with increasing time and temperature. On the other hand, the char content in the wood increased together with increasing pyrolysis temperature as well as time for both slow and fast pyrolysis. A technique to maximize the amount of char in the product was also identified through this study and optimized along with the yield. The resulting biochar was tested through proximate analysis and differential scanning calorimetry to determine its thermodynamic qualities, which were analysed and compared according to their physical characteristics like porosity and reflectance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>G. S. Vijaya Raghavan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278t41t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074v45s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>