<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10ws10k"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electrophysiological and reflex studies on delta opioid receptor actions on spinal nociceptive mechanisms in the rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Jing, 1974 April 3-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Delta opioid receptor agonists have been proposed as a new generation of opioids analgesics. They have been implicated in antinociception in the spinal cord in acute and chronic pain models. Yet the precise means by which this role is achieved is still unclear. The first aim of this study was to determine whether delta opioid receptors could modulate the action of pro-nociceptive transmitters in the spinal cord using reflex studies. The second aim of this study was to examine the effect of a delta-1 opioid receptor agonist on excitatory amino acid evoked responses and synaptically elicited responses of rat single spinal dorsal horn neurons to natural stimulation of peripheral receptive fields in electrophysiological experiments. Our findings in the first part of the study indicate that the mechanism of antinociception of delta opioids at the spinal level may include a selective blockade of the action of some of pro-nociceptive transmitters. In the second part of the study, the preferential inhibition of DPDPE on the after discharge induced by noxious stimulation and NMDA induced excitation suggests that delta opioid receptor agonists may have the potential to treat chronic pain. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Henry, J. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q74q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws10k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A44558g06j"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of the voltage-gated K+ Channel Kv4.2 in rat sympathetic neuron Af currents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Virard, Isabelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Potassium currents play an essential role in integrating neuronal signals by modulating the excitability of neurons and determining the action potential waveforms and firing patterns. Previously, Cooper and colleagues characterized voltage-gated K currents in neonatal neurons from the rat superior cervical ganglia (SCG). They demonstrated a positive correlation between the appearance of fast-inactivated currents (IAf) and the mRNA levels for the Kv4.2 voltage-gated potassium channel gene. Particularly, in cultured postnatal day 1 (P1) SCG neurons, both IAf and Kv4.2 mRNA decrease to very low levels after 14 days in culture. However, mRNA levels for other Kv genes that could also be responsible for Af currents on SCG neurons remained to be determined. My hypothesis was that Kv4.2 encodes K channel subunits underlying IAf in sympathetic neurons. To test this hypothesis, I built an adenoviral construct with a Kv4.2 insert to manipulate Kv4.2 expression in these neurons and compare the electrophysiological and pharmacological profiles of native IAf and Kv4.2-induced currents. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cooper, Ellis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jd11n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558g06j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cv79q"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors governing the quantity and shape of alveolar bone in the edentulous maxilla and mandible</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Villafranca, Melissa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bone is constantly undergoing remodeling of its bony matrix in response to various stimuli impinged upon the tissue. Bony remodeling occurs in both the dentate and edentulous states, but the edentulous lose more bone over time. This study analyzed sex, age and years edentulous for their influence on the height, width and shape of the anterior residual alveolar ridge of the jaws. Significantly greater amounts of mandibular residual alveolar bone height were found in males (p &lt; 0.0001) and in those with more edentulous years in the maxilla (p = 0.003). The maxilla showed significantly greater amounts of residual alveolar bone height in the group with fewer edentulous years (p = 0.004). No significant associations were detected when sex, age and years edentulous were compared with anterior maxillary bone width. Statistical analysis of this study population also revealed no significant associations between sex, age, and years edentulous and anterior maxillary bone shape.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Feine, J. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k691s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv79q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mp171"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of lipid-lowering pharmacotherapy on concurrent diet and exercise behaviors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Staples, Heidi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The National Cholesterol Education Program Adult Treatment Panel II (NCEP ATP II) unequivocally advocates an initial trial of dietary modification in both primary and secondary prevention prior to the institution of pharmacotherapy. Perhaps the rationale for this delay rests in the inherent, yet unsubstantiated, fear among clinicians that lifestyle change will be compromised in the presence of concurrent pharmacotherapy. However, the question of adherence to diet and exercise interventions following the initiation of lipid-lowering drug therapy has seemingly never been addressed scientifically. It was therefore hypothesized that pharmacologically-treated patients with untreated hypercholesterolemia started on a program of lifestyle modification would achieve relatively less reduction in dietary fat intake and body weight, and participate less often in physical activity, if a pharmacologic agent was simultaneously prescribed. This was tested by a protocol in which these and related variables were assessed in participants who thought they were taking a lipid-lowering medication at diagnosis, compared to conventional initial treatment of diet and exercise alone. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yale, Jean-Francois</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b208.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp171</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hypercholesteremia -- Exercise therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hypercholesteremia -- Treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hypercholesteremia -- Diet therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021h06x"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of two novel functional regulatory motifs in the unique region of the protein tyrosine kinase P56Lck</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Soussou, David Y.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>p56Lck, a member of the Src family of tyrosine kinases, is hypophosphorylated at its inhibitory c-terminal tyrosine residue, Y505, in resting cells. Previous studies showed that the amino-terminal "unique region" regulates this dephosphorylation. In this study, we mapped the motif within the "unique region" maintaining Y505 dephosphorylation as well as identified another function for the "unique region". The 17 c-terminal residues of the unique region constitute the carboxy-terminal phospho-tyrosine regulatory (CPR) motif. Deletion of any part of it raised the state of Y505 phosphorylation by 5--10 fold in resting cells. CPR activity is independent of the serine phosphorylation sites within the "unique region", or the ability of the "unique region" to (i) bind CD4/CD8, or (ii) restrict the access of Lck to detergent insoluble glycosphingolipid enriched microdomains (DIGs). Further, CPR does not regulate global tyrosine dephosphorylation in Lck, as the positive regulatory tyrosine, Y394 is not regulated by it. Finally we show that the "unique region" hampers the ability of the SH4 domain to target Lck to DIGs. This involves serine 59, as its phosphorylation by PMA reduces the amount of Lck in DIGs, while its mutation to alanine, increases it. This work brings new insight on the role of the "unique region" in both the negative and positive regulation of Lck.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Veillette, Andre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b21j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021h06x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afq977w85p"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The origin and timing of late-stage carbonate cements in Devonian carbonates of the deep Alberta basin : based on fluid inclusion and isotopic evidence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith, Sean G. W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Deep basin Leduc Obed and Swan Hills Simonette calcite fluid inclusions yielded Th ranges of 127 to 172°C and 122 to 158°C; while saddle dolomites have Th from 136 to 148°C and 133 to 162°C, respectively. Calcite data from the subsurface suggest a 20°C/km geothermal gradient and saddle dolomite data a gradient around 23°C. Vug-filling calcites from Spray Lakes, Parker's Ridge and Big Hill, yielded Th data (128.0 to 155.1°C) similar to vug-filling cements from Obed and Simonette. Fluids in the fracture-filling saddle dolomites analysed have an average T h of 171.6°C and salinity of 17.1. Post-thrusting fractures yielded calcites with the lowest Th and salinity suggesting precipitation from cooler, largely meteoric waters. Homogenization temperature data for vug and fracture-filling from subsurface and outcrops suggest that late calcite and dolomite phases were precipitated near maximum burial, in the Paleocene. Many of the Obed and Simonette late-stage calcites and dolomites have very high 87Sr/86Sr signatures (up to 0.7370). Obed late calcites show a strong east to west increasing trend in Sr isotopes across the buildup---suggesting fault control of this margin. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mountjoy, Eric W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v45q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977w85p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q810s"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Universal deformations, rigidity, and Ihara's cocycle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stewart, Colin, 1976-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In [Iha86b), Ihara constructs a universal cocycle GalQ/Q →Zp t0,t1 ,tinfinity /(t0+1 t1 +1tinfinity +1-1) arising from the action of Gal Q/Q on certain quotients of the Jacobians of the Fermat curves xpn+ypn=1 for each n ≥ 1. This thesis gives a different construction of part of Ihara's cocycle by considering the universal deformation of certain two-dimensional representations of IIQ, , where IIQ is the algebraic fundamental group of P1Q &amp;bsol;0,1,infinity . More precisely, we determine, with and without certain deformation conditions, the universal deformation ring arising from a residual representation r:II Q→GL2 Fp Belyi&amp;breve;'s Rigidity Theorem is used to extend each determinant one universal deformation to a representation of IIK, where K is a finite cyclotomic extension of Qmpinfinity . For a particular r , we give a geometric construction of one such extended universal deformation r , and show that part of Ihara's cocycle can be recovered by specializing r at infinity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Darmon, Henri</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks30b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q810s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m3644"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Agricultural productivity and rural-urban migration : the case of Senegal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ndarishikanye, Barnabe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Rural-urban migration in Sub-Saharan African countries has been increasing since the 1960s. In Senegal from 1961 to 1996, it grew 7.6% per annum. Labour market in the modern industrial and service sectors is so depressed that urban workers face high unemployment and poverty rates, and live in substandard conditions in the fringe urban sector. The purpose of this study is to examine policies needed to reduce rural-urban migration through selected agricultural investments, especially given that a long run of low agricultural productivity has been a major cause of rural-urban migration flows. Based on a recursive system of equations, an estimate was made of rural-urban migration elasticity caused by agricultural inputs and their impact on migration. The model used combines a Cobb-Douglas agricultural production equation along with a rural-urban migration equation with agricultural output as an explanatory variable. The study period is 36 years from 1961 to 1996. Our findings support the hypothesis that rural-urban migration is a positive outcome function of the urban-rural wage ratio that is proxied by the ratio of urban per capita income to rural per capita income. The results justify the design of a policy aimed at reducing rural-urban migration flows through increasing per capita earnings by means of increased agricultural investments. For instance, 10% increase of fertiliser lowers rural-urban migration by 20.5% while 10% increase of agricultural infrastructure reduces rural-urban migration of about 32.2%. If one extrapolates these results, fertiliser and infrastructure need to be increased respectively by 36% and 25% or both inputs by 13.09% to reach rural-urban migration annual rate of 2%, the level of industrial labour demand.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gunjal, Kisan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v4822.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m3644</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural productivity -- Senegal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rural-urban migration -- Senegal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dp21c"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Innovation rate, brain size and species richness in birds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nicolakakis, Nektaria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The number of species varies greatly among taxa. In birds, for example, the parvorder Passerida contains 3556 species while the Odontophorida (New World Quails) contains only six species. This uneven distribution of species among avian taxa is not random and therefore warrants an explanation. The behavioral drive hypothesis stipulates that the capacity for innovation, coupled with the rapid transmission of the behavioral novelty to conspecifics, may expose individuals to new selective pressures and help fix mutations that would otherwise not be expressed. This should lead to accelerated rates of evolution. I test this hypothesis by examining the link between behavioral flexibility and the number of species per taxon. I adopt a comparative approach and seek a general explanation of richness, thereby removing the traditional focus placed on the success of the songbirds and on their complex singing apparatus. I use two measures of flexibility, feeding innovation rate and relative brain size. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lefebvre, Louis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m122f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp21c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Birds -- Variation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Birds -- Behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Prosencephalon</dc:subject><dc:subject>Birds -- Food</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb397b06z"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The correlates of smoking, and low fruit and vegetable intake among Québec adolescent females</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Newhouse, Marcella K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Smoking and low fruit and vegetable intake (LFVI) are correlated with cardiovascular disease (CVD) and cancer, two leading causes of death in Canada and the U.S. The prevalence of smoking in Canadian and U.S. female adolescents has risen in the past ten years. Recent surveillance data also show that Canadian and U.S. female adolescents consume levels of fruit and vegetables far below national recommendations. The correlates of current smoking and LFVI among adolescent girls were investigated in a secondary data analysis of a multi-stage, stratified, cluster sample school survey of 13 and 16 year-old girls in Quebec, called the Quebec Children and Adolescent Health and Social Survey (QCAHS). Data were collected from 80.2% of eligible 13 year-old females and 81.4% of eligible 16 year-old females. Multivariate logistic analysis was used. Our results could be used to identify adolescent females at increased risk for smoking and LFVI. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paradis, Gilles</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp963.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397b06z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10ws11v"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Acetylation of the homeodomain transcription factor, CCAAT displacement protein (CDP)Cut</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Muzzin, Oriana Maria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Acetylation is emerging as a major post-translational modification that affects diverse protein functions and is an important regulatory mechanism in many biological processes. CDP/Cut is a homeodomain transcription factor that contains four DNA binding domains. CDP/Cut functions both as a transcriptional activator and repressor and its activity is regulated in a cell cycle dependent manner. Several post-translational modifications of CDP/Cut capable of modifying its activity have been discovered. This work demonstrates that CDP/Cut is acetylated by the acetyltransferase PCAF (p300/CBP associated factor) in vitro and CDP/Cut is acetylated in vivo. Acetylation of CDP/Cut within the homeodomain does not affect CDP/Cut DNA binding activity. PCAF activity does, however, affect two distinct post-translational modifications of CDP/Cut: phosphorylation and proteolytic processing. Acetylation of CDP/Cut inhibits its phosphorylation by cyclin A associated kinase activities. Additionally, expression of PCAF and CDP/Cut in mammalian cells increases proteolytic processing of CDP/Cut.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nepveu, Alain</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n978f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws11v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xw85k"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>International and trafficking of Mu and Delta opioid receptors in rat primary cortical culture and their response to chronic naloxone and morphine treatment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Mao-Cheng, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Mu and Delta opioid receptors (MOR &amp; DOR) have been shown to undergo complex regulatory changes in response to ligand exposure in transfected cells. However, little is known regarding receptor regulation in neurons. In this study, we have investigated the internalization and trafficking of the MOR and DOR agonists, fluodemorphin (fluo-DRM) and fluo-demorphin-I (fluo-DLT-I), respectively, and the fate of these receptors following ligand binding. Experiments were performed on primary rat cortical neuronal cultures using a ligand binding internalization assay and immunocytochemistry. Incubation of neurons with fluo-DRM and fluo-DLT-I resulted in the specific internalization of the fluo-ligands. The internalization was blocked by phenylarsine oxide, indicating that it is clathrin-mediated. Both fluo-ligands accumulated in the soma while no change was evident in the neuronal processes. Exposure to the microtubule disruptor nocadazole resulted in the accumulation of fluo-ligands in the neuronal processes and decrease in their accumulation in soma, suggesting that fluo-ligands are targeted to the cell soma following internalization. Immunocytochemistry of MOR and DOR revealed that receptor compartmentalization did not change after exposure to their respective opioid agonists suggesting that in contrast to internalized ligands, internalized receptors are recycled locally. The internalization and trafficking of opioid ligands and receptors were also determined after chronic treatment of neuronal cultures with morphine. Chronic morphine treatment led to a profound decrease in fluo-DRM internalization along the processes, but had no effect on the intensity of MOR immunolabeling. However, DOR immunolabeling as well as fluo-DLT-I internalization were greatly increased. This study is the first to demonstrate the internalization and targeting of opioid receptor ligands in neurons. After ligand exposure, MOR and DOR internalize, dissociate from their bound ligands and recycl</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beaudet, Alain</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng508.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw85k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rq52w"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A population-based, case-control study of breast cancer and alcohol consumption among postmenopausal women living in Montreal, Quebec, Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lenz, Sarah K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the present population-based, case-control study of incident, postmenopausal breast cancer, we obtained an extensive history of alcohol consumption. Indices reflecting age-specific exposure, duration and cumulative exposure of alcohol were developed for specific types of alcoholic beverages as well as the combination of these beverages. Unconditional logistic regression, within the context of the Generalized Additive Models, was used to estimate adjusted odds ratios (OR) and 95% confidence intervals (CI). Case subjects included all new histologically-confirmed cases of malignant breast cancer among postmenopausal women, age 51--75 years, diagnosed or treated in 1996 and 1997 in all major hospitals in Montreal. Control subjects were selected randomly from other histologically-confirmed sites of cancer from the same hospitals as the cases. The response rate was 82% for cases and 75% for controls. Current drinkers of any kind of alcohol were at an increased risk of breast cancer (OR = 1.47; 95%CI: 1.01--2.15). In particular, the risk of breast cancer was increased by 1.6-fold among weekly and current exclusive drinkers of wine. Other factors suggestive of an increased risk of breast cancer include early-age at first consumption of alcohol (≤30 years old) and increased number of years (&gt;15 years) of consuming wine among women who only drank wine. We did not find, however, monotonically increasing risks with levels of consumption. Although, the associations found were relatively weak, our findings provide further support for a positive association between the risk of breast cancer and alcohol consumption, particularly wine.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Goldberg, Mark S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763884v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq52w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rg31t"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lymph node involvement in breast carcinoma metastasis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>LeBedis, Christina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since lymph node stromal cells remain largely uncharacterized with respect to cell surface markers and function, their role in regulating the growth and invasion of disseminated cancer cells, including breast carcinoma has, to date, been virtually unexplored. In the present study, we asked whether peripheral lymph node cells could modulate the growth of breast carcinoma cells and, thereby, contribute to the progression of the metastatic process. Primary cultures of rat peripheral lymph node stromal cells were obtained by limiting dilution and two sublines, STA4 and STB12, with breast carcinoma growth-promoting activities were isolated. Immunocytochemistry performed on these cells revealed that they express vimentin, S-100 and fibronectin, but neither cytokeratin nor von Willebrand factor indicating that they are stromal and dendritic in origin. Several functional studies were performed using media conditioned by STA4 and STB12 cells. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brodt, Pnina</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv61q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rg31t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fz57x"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Converting the flavor of a quantum bit commitment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Légaré, Frédéric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The results presented in the thesis show how to convert a statistically binding but computationally concealing quantum bit commitment scheme into a computationally binding but statistically concealing scheme. For a security parameter n, the construction of the statistically concealing scheme requires O(n2) executions of the statistically binding scheme. As a consequence of the reduction, statistically concealing but computationally binding quantum bit commitments can be based upon any family of quantum one-way functions. Such a construction is not known to exist in the classical world.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crepeau, Claude</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g4569.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz57x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anp193b77k"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intracellular signalling during murine oocyte growth</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hurtubise, Patricia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During the growth phase of oogenesis, mammalian oocytes increase several hundred-fold in volume. Although it is known that ovarian granulosa cells send growth promoting signals, neither these external signals nor the transduction pathways that become activated in the oocyte are known. Therefore, the presence and the activity of candidate signaling pathways in growing murine oocytes were investigated. By immunoblotting, the MAP kinases, ERK1 and ERK2, as well as their activating kinase MEK, were detected in oocytes at all stages of growth. However, using a phospho-specific anti-ERK antibody, no immunoreactive species were detectable in isolated granulosa cells or oocytes at any stage of growth, except metaphase II. Phosphorylated ERK was also present, although in smaller quantities, in oocyte-granulosa cell complexes at the later stages of growth. Furthermore, when ovarian sections were stained with an anti-ERK antibody, the protein was found to be highly concentrated in the cytoplasm of oocytes at all stages of growth, with lower levels in the nucleus. Another member of the MAP kinase family, Jun kinase (JNK), was investigated. By immunoblotting, JNK was detected in growing oocytes. Experiments using an anti-JNK antibody on ovary sections revealed the protein to be uniformly distributed in non-growing and growing oocytes with no evidence of preferential nuclear localization. These results imply that an interaction between the oocyte and the granulosa cells may be required to generate phosphorylated ERK. They also imply that growth signals probably are not relayed through ERK, but do not exclude a role for Jun kinase in mediating oocyte growth.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clarke, Hugh J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp97c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193b77k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cell interaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mice -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oogenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAP Kinase Signaling System</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mitogen-activated protein kinases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mice -- Embryology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bn564"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Isolation of microglia from goldfish brain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Houalla, Tarek</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study aims at providing a new technique for the isolation and culture of goldfish microglial cells. So far no protocol has been designed for the growth of these cells in vitro, despite the growing interest in the remarkable capacity of goldfish central nervous system (CNS) for regenerating severed axons. This newly developed technique has little or no similarity to those used in the isolation of mammalian microglia, and is distinguished by its simple setup and its fast yield for microglial cells. In addition, a virtually pure population of microglia was generated when plated on untreated plastic dishes, eliminating further need for purification. This technique may thus provide a starting point for future characterization of the microglial cells in vitro, which may eventually help toward building a better understanding of the function and biology of these cells. A preliminary morphological characterization of the cells has also been conducted, in addition to groundwork experiments on the phagocytic activity of these cells in vitro, using myelin to stimulate phagocytosis. These assays were oriented toward providing a comparison to the mammalian cultures of microglia, and so far, displayed several similarities in morphologies and phagocytosis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Levine, Robert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z21d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn564</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Goldfish -- Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microglia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cell separation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Optic nerve -- Regeneration</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579v08k"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Examination of the concurrent validity of the neurobehavioral assessment for preterm infants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hyman, Chaya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Neurobehavioral Assessment for Preterm Infants (NAPI) is an instrument that was developed to measure the progression of neurobehavioral development in preterm infants born from 32 weeks conceptional age to term. This study examined the concurrent validity of the NAPI against another neonatal criterion instrument, the Einstein Neonatal Neurobehavioral Assessment Scale (ENNAS), which measures similar constructs and has demonstrated excellent reliability and validity. The results indicated that there was good correlation between many similar items and clusters found on both the NAPI and ENNAS. There was also a good correlation between NAPI cluster scores and performance and the ENNAS total deviant score, and the NAPI was sensitive to differences between infants classified as normal or abnormal by the ENNAS. Clinicians and researchers require instruments with psychometrically sound properties so that accurate tests results are obtained and this study has contributed to strengthening the validity of the NAPI.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Snider, Laurie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn9998507.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v08k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Human Development</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1j92g926r"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of chromogranin A</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hou, Yu, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Chromogranin A (CgA) is an acidic glycoprotein that is specifically expressed in neuroendocrine tissue. It is the best characterized member of the granin family, which includes proteins proposed to be involved in the regulation of peptide hormone and neurotransmitter secretion in the regulated secretors pathway by helping granule formation, targeting peptide hormones and neurotransmitters to the granules, affecting peptide hormone processing and controlling secretion through a feedback mechanism. Although elaborate in vitro studies have been conducted on CgA, its precise neuroendocrine function and the complete elements that control its neuroendocrine specific expression remain unclear. This project applied transgenic technology to study CgA regulation and function in vivo. For the study of the regulation of CgA gene expression, four constructs, containing one of two promoter portions of the CgA gene (the 184bp proximal promoter portion and the 6kb 5'-flanking region) in two reporter systems (beta-galactosidase and green fluorescent protein systems), were constructed. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hendy, G. N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m211.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g926r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35tb304"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Immunomodulatory effects following naked DNA transfer in an autoimmune model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>De Pooter, Renee</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Immune modulation is one treatment modality which is being explored in the context of human diseases and disorders. Methods of such manipulation which use gene therapy have an advantage in the treatment of chronic diseases such as autoimmunity because they are less invasive and more persistent. Furthermore, naked plasmid has advantages as a vector over other methods: it is more persistent and less immunogenic and cytotoxic than viral vectors, and simpler than DNA-conjugate vectors. Thus, naked plasmid is a viable alternative treatment to study in the context of an autoimmune disease such as diabetes mellitus, despite it's disadvantages of low transfection and expression rates. Here, we demonstrate that treatment of an autoimmune model, the non-obese diabetic (NOD) mouse, with an autoantigen to which a signal sequence had been added was protective, even in the apparent absence of secretion of that gene product. In contrast, treatment with the native cDNA of the same antigen was not protective. Furthermore, we show by immunohistochemistry that gene expression is still detectable in the muscle 22 weeks after injection. Other experiments demonstrate that multiple vaccinations with the altered form of the antigen were essentially as protective as a single vaccination following by multiple injections of blank plasmid, suggesting an important role for immunostimulatory sequences in bacterial DNA in causing surveying dendritic cells to migrate out of the tissue and present antigen in draining lymph nodes. Attempts to study the results of DNA vaccination by comparing immunization via different routes were inconclusive. We have demonstrated that DNA vaccination of an autoimmune model with a autoantigen can delay disease. The simplicity and economy of such vectors and the benefits they have for the treatment of chronic disease in contrast to more inflammatory viral vectors, support future research into their use in the treatment of autoimmune diseases.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Prud'homme, G. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j977d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb304</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0z708z66x"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Differences in the response of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis to psychological stress and alcohol as a function of family history of alcoholism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dai, Xing, 1963-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A number of studies have indicated that both genetic and environmental factors play significant roles in determining alcohol consumption. Stress is one environmental factor shown to influence the initiation and continuation of heavy drinking. The present study investigates the differences between high risk (HR) and low risk (LR) subjects for the future development of alcoholism, as determined from their family history, in the response of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) axis to stress and alcohol. 20 HR and 20 LR male subjects, between 18--25 years old, participated in five separate experimental sessions: (1) a placebo drink; (2) a drink containing 0.5g alcohol/Kg.B.Wt; (3) a placebo drink and 30 minutes later the performance of a stress inducing task; (4) an alcohol containing drink and 30 minutes later the performance of a stress inducing task; and (5) the performance of a stress inducing task and 30 minutes later an alcohol containing drink. The response of the HPA-axis was determined by measuring the changes in the plasma adrenal corticotropic hormone (ACTH) and cortisol contents prior to and for four hours following initiation of the treatment. HR subjects presented a lower stress induced increase of plasma ACTH and cortisol contents and a delayed hormone recovery to basal levels. Alcohol consumption prior to the stress task attenuated the stress induced increase in the plasma hormone contents by both LR and HR subjects, while alcohol consumption after the stress task led to a faster return of the hormone contents to basal levels in the HR subjects. Thus, alcohol alters the response of the HPA axis to stress by both the HR and LR subjects. However, there are differences in both, the response of the HPA-axis to stress, and the influence of alcohol consumption on stress responses, as a function of the family history of alcoholism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gianoulakis, Christina</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj243.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z66x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Psychobiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q812b"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Landowners' willingness to accept compensation for selling saltwater marshes to a conservation program : a multiple bounded discrete choice approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>De Maio Sukic, Alejandro</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Saltwater marshes in the Bay of Fundy act as greenhouse gases sinks and reservoirs by fixing atmospheric carbon dioxide and storing it in carbon rich deposits. There are approximately 3,131.5 hectares of saltwater marsh in the Bay of Fundy, of which 958 ha are currently owned by the government or conservation organizations and 2,173.5 ha are owned by private landowners. A multiple bounded discrete choice contingent valuation survey was conducted to estimate landowners' willingness to accept compensation for selling their saltwater marshes to a conservation program. A multiple bounded model developed by Gregory Poe and Michael Welsh (1995) was used to analyze the responses. Mean willingness to accept compensation for one hectare of saltwater marsh was estimated to be $1,004.22, and aggregate willingness to accept compensation for the total of 2,173.5 ha of saltwater marsh owned by private landowners was approximately $2,180,000. Using these estimates and the rate of carbon dioxide-equivalent absorption of saltwater marshes, the opportunity cost of one tonne of carbon dioxide-equivalent sequestered by saltwater marshes in the Bay of Fundy was calculated to range between $16.70 and $19.95. Decision-makers can use this result for policy purposes concerning the achievement by Canada of its greenhouse gases emission reduction commitment under the Kyoto Protocol (1997).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thomassin, Paul J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w86z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q812b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Estuarine area conservation -- Economic aspects -- Fundy, Bay of</dc:subject><dc:subject>Salt marshes -- Fundy, Bay of</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carbon sequestration -- Economic aspects -- Fundy, Bay of</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap2676x54b"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthetic routes to phosphorus (III)- and nitrogen-containing dendritic polymers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dasgupta, Mohua</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The incorporation of phosphine or amine structural units into dendritic polymers offer significant potential in building macromolecular species with desired properties for heterogenizing homogeneous catalysis. To this end, synthetic methodologies based on the chemistry of acid-base hydrolysis of aminosilanes with molecules possessing hydroxyl end groups, and that of phosphorus halides/amides with alkynyl/alcohol monomers were explored as approaches to construct phosphorus(III)- and nitrogen-containing dendritic polymers. Attempted implementation of a three-step, divergent synthetic methodology led to the discovery of two new phosphorus(III)-based compounds, P[O(CH2) 2C≡CH]3 and P[O(CH2)2C≡CSn(CH 3)3]3. Efforts to execute a two-step, divergent synthetic route to nitrogen-containing dendrimers afforded first- and second-generation dendrimers, N4 and N10. Attempts to adapt this methodology to one-pot procedures for hyperbranched polyamines show promise. Finally, single-step and pseudo-single-step procedures for synthesizing hyperbranched polyphosphines were employed in the preparation of several phosphorus(III)-containing macromolecules. These materials were successfully functionalized with Rh(I) organometallic complexes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kakkar, Ashok K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v483b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676x54b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Inorganic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301323g"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The use of the transition cost accounting system to compare costs of treatment between Canada and the United States : methodological issues based on the case of acute myocardial infarction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Azoulay, Arik</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Transition cost accounting system integrates clinical, resource utilization, and financial information and is currently being used by several hospitals in Canada and the United States (U.S.) to calculate the costs of patient care. The potential use of the Transition system for estimating in-hospital costs in health services research, however, depends on the accuracy of the system's measurements. Thus, the objectives of this thesis were (1) to assess the use of hospital-based cost accounting systems to measure costs of treatment, (2) to identify potential sources of measurement error inherent to the Transition system methodology, (3) to collect audit documentation in order to evaluate the accuracy of the Transition system's information, and to collect cost of treatment data from Canadian and U.S. hospitals in order to illustrate the system's use in health services research, and (4) to discuss the potential use of the Transition system in health services research in Canada and the U.S. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eisenberg, Mark J.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Platt, Robert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719p04z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301323g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Business Administration, Accounting</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Health Care Management</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az316q3388"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sanctity of life : exploring its significance in modern medicine and bioethics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ballesteros Gallego, Fabián Andrés</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores the concept of "Sanctity of Life" from the perspective of what "life," in particular human life, means today. With the rapid advances in science and modern medical practice, the concept of life has undergone many changes, shaking the foundations of what before made us view life as sacred. Modern thought has brought new forms of understanding to the concept of life. I question the goals of modern medicine and biotechnology, and criticize the reductionist view of life. And finally, I highlight a new ethical approach that could bridge science and moral convictions about the concept of life. This approach explores the argument of sanctity of life and its utility in approaching assisted medical techniques and genetic intervention. It is my opinion that this ethical principle has not lost importance and could be reshaped and adapted to a contemporary understanding of life in the light of our democratic and pluralistic society.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Glannon, Walter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k908k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q3388</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>