<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795d13m"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The reconstruction of the physiological environment for growing in-vitrio human salivary organoids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pham, Hieu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction: Salivary glands and their function are crucial to the maintenance of good oral hygiene and health. The loss of such functions results in a condition known as xerostomia which can lead to further complications such as difficulty in speech, mastication, and increased susceptibility to dental caries and oral infections and diseases. Annually, approximately 900,000 new patients risk these complications due hypo- or dysfunctional salivary function from head and neck cancer (HNC) radiotherapy or the onset of Sjögren’s Syndrome (SS). While some palliative treatments are available for patients suffering with xerostomia, there are no curative treatments to date.Objectives: This project addresses this issue by attempting to optimize the growing conditions such as the culture media and bio-scaffold for salivary glands grown in 3D. These 3D glands (organoids) can then be used for studies in support of a curative treatment for xerostomia such as drug therapy testing or disease modeling. This project is a pilot study which establishes and observes the potential of a novel animal-product free media, and an Egg White Alginate (EWA) scaffold for culturing salivary organoids.Methods: NS-SV-AC and SMG-hu-1 cell line proliferation was measured and compared across Animal Product-free Epithelial Cell Culture (APFECC), Epi Max, and Keratinocyte Growth Media – Gold (KGM-Gold) using an MTT assay over eight days. Cell viability of both NS-SV-AC and SMG-hu-1 cell line was observed over 20 days and 10 days using a Live-Dead stain and AlamarBlue assay respectively.Results: The results indicated that the novel animal product-free media, APFECC growth media, was not significantly different from Epi Max and KGM-Gold; APFECC growth media’s ability to induce cell proliferation was evident. Results for the EWA scaffold suggested that it is an excellent candidate for salivary organoid as it can sustain cell survivability in two salivary cell lines—NS-SV-AC and SMG-hu-1—however it is unclear if proliferation was present.Conclusion: While it was evident that APFECC growth media can support cells, further studies need to be conducted to reoptimize the growth media. Similarly, while EWA can support salivary cells grown in 3D even after 20 days, further studies need to be carried out to determine if there were any phenotypic changes in the cell culture, and also to further characterize the scaffold. Both products should be tested with human primary salivary cells to truly test its potential. Regardless, the results found here provide new insights and tools for researchers to culture salivary cells in both 2D and 3D depending on their goals</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introduction: Les glandes salivaires et leur fonction sont essentielles au maintien d'une bonne hygiène de santé bucco-dentaire. La perte de ces fonctions entraîne une maladie appelée xérostomie qui peut entraîner d'autres complications telles que des difficultés d'élocution, de mastication, et d’une susceptibilité accrue aux caries dentaires et aux infections et maladies bucco-dentaires. Chaque année, environ 900 000 nouveaux patients risquent ces complications en raison de la fonction salivaire hypo- ou dysfonctionnelle de la radiothérapie pour le cancer de la tête et du cou ou de l’apparition du syndrome de Sjögren (SS). Bien que certains traitements palliatifs soient disponibles pour les patients souffrant de xérostomie, il n’existe aucun traitement curatif à ce jour.Objectifs: Ce projet s'attaque à ce problème en tentant d'optimiser les conditions de croissance telles que le milieu de culture et l'échafaudage biologique pour les glandes salivaires cultivées en 3D. Ces glandes 3D (organoïdes) peuvent ensuite être utilisées pour des études à l'appui d'un traitement curatif de la xérostomie, tel que les tests de pharmacothérapie ou la modélisation de maladies. Ce projet est une étude pilote qui établit et observe le potentiel d'un nouveau milieu exempt de produits d'origine animale et d'un échafaudage en alginate de blanc d'œuf (EWA) pour la culture d'organoïdes salivaires.Méthodes: La prolifération des lignées cellulaires NS-SV-AC et SMG-hu-1 a été mesurée et comparée sur des cultures de cellules épithéliales sans produit animal (APFECC), Epi Max et des milieux de croissance kératinocytaire - Or (KGM-Gold) à l'aide d'un dosage au MTT sur huit jours. La viabilité cellulaire des lignées cellulaires NS-SV-AC et SMG-hu-1 a été observée sur 20 jours et 10 jours en utilisant une coloration Live-Dead et le test AlamarBlue, respectivement.Résultats: Les résultats ont indiqué que le nouveau milieu sans produit animal, le milieu de croissance APFECC, n'était pas significativement différent des milieux de croissance Epi Max et KGM-Gold; la capacité du milieu de croissance APFECC à induire une prolifération cellulaire était évident. Les résultats d’échafaudage EWA suggèrent qu’il s’agit d’un excellent candidat pour les organoïdes salivaires, car il permet de maintenir la survie des cellules dans deux lignées cellulaires salivaires - NS-SV-AC et SMG-hu-1 -, mais il n’est pas clair si la prolifération était présente.Conclusion: Bien qu’il soit évident que le milieu de croissance APFECC peut supporter les cellules, des études supplémentaires doivent être menées pour réoptimiser le milieu de croissance. De même, bien que EWA puisse prendre en charge des cellules salivaires développées en 3D même après 20 jours, des études supplémentaires doivent être menées pour déterminer s'il existe des modifications phénotypiques dans la culture cellulaire et pour caractériser davantage l'échafaudage. Les deux produits doivent être testés avec des cellules salivaires primaires humaines afin de véritablement tester leur potentiel. Quoi qu'il en soit, les résultats présentés ici fournissent aux chercheurs de nouvelles idées et outils pour la culture de cellules salivaires en 2D et 3D, en fonction de leurs objectifs</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Simon Tran</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848v68p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795d13m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418s51d"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of amino acids on macrophage metabolism and function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eng, Mikaela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le syndrome respiratoire aigu est un état clinique mortel caractérisé par la rupture de la membrane alvéolaire-capillaire et par une défaillance respiratoire. Cette condition peut se survenir après une atteinte inflammatoire directe (une pneumonie) ou indirecte (une sepsie). Les macrophages jouent un rôle important dans le contexte du syndrome respiratoire aigu. Leur activité est contrôlée par des modifications métaboliques et transcriptionnelles des gènes nécessaires pour monter une réponse suffisante au stress et pour la production de cytokines. Celles-ci sont strictement régulées par la protéine kinase connu sous le nom de “cible de la rapamycine chez les mammifères » (mTOR), qui nucléent deux complexes macromoléculaires conservés: le complexe mTOR-1 (mTORC1) et mTORC2. mTORC1 est un détecteur cellulaire de la disponibilité des acides aminés essentiels par la protéine «GCN2» (GCN2).  Des études cliniques démontrent une association entre la disponibilité des acides aminés et les résultats cliniques chez les personnes gravement malades. Nous avons donc proposé que la disponibilité des acides aminés essentiels, en particulier de la leucine et / ou de l’arginine, soit vital pour les réponses métaboliques, le stress et les réactions inflammatoires des macrophages liés au syndrome respiratoire aigu. Les macrophages dérivés de la moelle osseuse ont été exposés à un milieu de croissance complet ou dépourvu de leucine, d'arginine et de lysine, en présence ou en absence de saline ou de lipopolysaccharide d'E. Coli et d'interféron gamma (LPS / IFN-γ) pendant 6 h. La rapamycine, l’inhibiteur de mTORC1, a réduit la consommation d'oxygène cellulaire liée à la phosphorylation oxydative dans les macrophages dérives de la moelle osseuse. Les effets de LPS / IFN-γ ou la restriction des acides aminés essentiels sur le métabolisme n'ont pas pu être évalués en raison de difficultés techniques. Cependant, l'induction de l'ARNm et de la protéine d'interleukine-6 (IL-6) par le LPS / IFN-γ était entravé par la restriction des acides aminés essentiels. Bien au contraire, l'induction d’IL-6 a été restaurée par l’addition de leucine seul. De plus, l'induction d’IL-6 était inhibée par l'exposition à un milieu dépourvu de leucine seul. La restriction des acides aminés essentiels a augmenté l'induction des gènes de réponse au stress de la réticulum endoplasmique (CHOP, GADD34) par LPS / IFN-γ. Comme on pouvait s'y attendre, la restriction acide aminés essentiels a bloqué l'activité de la voie mTOR (c'est-à-dire la phosphorylation de 4EBP1) et a augmenté celle de la voie du stress de la réticulum endoplasmique (c'est-à-dire la phosphorylation de eiF2α). Nos résultats indiquent que mTOR et son mécanisme de détection de la leucine sont important pour la régulation du stress et des réponses inflammatoires des macrophages et constituent la base des futures études identifiant de nouveaux biomarqueurs cliniques ou cibles thérapeutiques pour le syndrome respiratoire aigu</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Acute lung injury (ALI) is a life-threatening condition characterized by breakdown of the lung alveolar-capillary barrier and respiratory failure that can occur after a direct (e.g., pneumonia) or indirect (e.g., sepsis) inflammatory insult. Macrophages play an important role in ALI, and their activity is regulated by changes in metabolism and gene transcription required for stress responses and cytokine production. These are tightly controlled by the protein kinase ‘mammalian target of rapamycin’ (mTOR) and the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress response. mTOR nucleates two highly-conserved macromolecular complexes – mTOR complex-1 (mTORC1) and mTORC2. mTORC1 and the ER stress response, via the protein ‘general control nonderepressible 2’ (GCN2) are cellular sensors of essential amino acid (EAA) availability, and clinical studies demonstrate an association between protein availability and clinical outcomes in the critically ill. We therefore proposed that the availability of EAAs, particularly leucine and/or arginine, is critical for metabolic, stress, and inflammatory responses in macrophages that are related to ALI.  Bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) were exposed to control media or that lacking leucine, arginine, and lysine (EAA restriction), in the presence or absence of saline or E. coli lipopolysaccharide and interferon-gamma (LPS and IFN-γ) for 6 h. The mTORC1 inhibitor rapamycin reduced cellular oxygen consumption related to oxidative phosphorylation in BMDMs; the effects of LPS and IFN-γ or EAA restriction on metabolism could not be assessed for technical reasons. However, the induction of interleukin-6 (IL-6) mRNA and protein by LPS and IFN-γ was inhibited by EAA restriction; IL-6 induction was restored by the addition of leucine alone. Moreover, IL-6 induction was inhibited by exposure to media lacking leucine alone. EAA restriction enhanced the induction of ER stress response genes (i.e., CHOP, GADD34) by LPS and IFN-γ. As expected, EAA restriction blocked activity of the mTOR pathway (i.e., phosphorylation of 4EBP1) and enhanced that of the ER stress pathway (i.e., phosphorylation of eiF2α). Our results point to ER stress and/or mTORC1 and leucine sensing as important regulators of macrophage stress and inflammatory responses. These results form the basis for future studies identifying novel clinical biomarkers or therapeutic targets in ALI</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Arnold Scott Kristof</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Maziar Divangahi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945w31g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418s51d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Microbiology and Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A736669187"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Phenotypic modulation of the translational products of CFTR premature termination codons</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saleh, Alla</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The functional expression defect of the cAMP-dependent protein kinase A (PKA)-regulated CFTR anion channel at the apical plasma membrane (PM) causes cystic fibrosis (CF).In-frame premature termination codon (PTC) introduced by nonsense, frameshifts or splicingmutations accounts for ~10% of individuals with CF. The clinical phenotype of these patients maybe influenced by the PTC localization via the severity of i) CFTR transcript level reduction bynonsense mediated decay (NMD), ii) the folding/stability defect, and iii) the gating defect of therespective translational product. Considering the lack of approved or late-stage clinicaldevelopment drugs for treating CF patients bearing PTCs, we set out to characterize the moleculardefects and pharmacological susceptibilities of eleven CF-associated PTCs that manifest intranslation products by deleting 26-168 amino acids from the C-terminus of CFTR.Here, we show that truncating &gt;50 a.a. from CFTR C-terminus result in &gt;70% loss-ofexpressionof the truncated CFTR variants at the PM, measured by PM-ELISA in human bronchialepithelia and normalized for transcript level. These PTC variants exhibit accelerated PM turnoverand impaired PKA-activation. To rescue the PM expression and loss-of function phenotype, wetested the FDA-approved CFTR folding correctors (VX-809 or VX-661) and gating activator (VX-770), alone or in combination with preclinical CFTR modulators, using PM-ELISA and PKAactivatedshort-circuit current measurements, respectively. We show that truncated CFTRs withsevere loss-of-expression phenotype, were resistant to folding corrector or corrector-combinationtreatment. Truncating &gt;63 a.a. residues confer resistant to single potentiator. Remarkably, dual,structurally distinct potentiator combinations were able to restore Q1412X-, Q1411X-, Q1382XandQ1390X-CFTR channel significantly, providing a possible framework to develop noveltherapeutics to alleviate the loss-of-function of PTCs in CF</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La fibrose kystique (FK) est provoquée par un défaut d'expression fonctionnelle de CFTR,un canal anionique régulé par la protéine kinase A (PKA), au niveau apical de la membraneplasmique (MP). Chez environ 10% des individus qui souffrent de la FK, on peut trouver un codonstopprématuré dans le cadre de lecture (CSP) du canal, introduit par des mutations non-sens, quidécalent le cadre de lecture, ou au niveau d’un site d’épissage. Le dégrée de sévérité du phénotypeclinique des patients atteins de FK peut dépendre de la localisation du CSP qui affecte i) la quantitéde transcription de CFTR réduit par dégradation des ARNm non-sens, ii) le défaut d’assemblage /stabilité, et iii) le défaut de fonctionnement du produit traduit. Compte tenu de l’absence demédicaments en développement, au stade avancé, ou approuvés par la FDA pour traiter la FKprovoquée par un CSP, nous avons entrepris de caractériser les défauts moléculaires et lessusceptibilités pharmacologiques de onze CSP qui peuvent causer la FK, et qui suppriment 26 à168 acides aminés du C-terminus du produit transcrit de CFTR.Dans cette étude, nous démontrons que tronquer de plus de 50 acides aminés l’extrémitéC-terminal de CFTR diminue à 70% la quantité de canaux à la MP, mesurée par MP-ELISA, dansdes cellules d’épithélium bronchique humain et normalisée à la quantité de CFTR transcrit. Cesproduits avec un CSP se renouvellent plus rapidement à la MP, et leur activation par PKA estaltérée. Afin d’améliorer le phénotype d'expression et de perte de fonction du canal à la MP, nousavons testé seuls ou en combinaison avec des modulateurs précliniques de CFTR, des correcteursde l’assemblage de CFTR approuvés par la FDA (VX-809 ou VX-661) et un activateur dudéclenchement du canal (VX-770). Pour cela, nous avons respectivement utilisé un MP-ELISA,et mesuré la quantité de courants ressortant d’un PKA-induit court-circuit. Nous avons pudémontrer que les canaux CFTR tronqués, très peu exprimés à la MP, ne peuvent être traités pardes correcteurs de l’assemblage du canal, ou par une combinaison de correcteurs. Les délétionsaux extrémités C-terminales plus grandes que 63 acides aminés confèrent une résistance aupotentialisateur unique. Cependant, et de manière remarquable, des combinaisons depotentialisateurs doubles, bien que structurellement distincts, ont été en mesure de restaurersignificativement l’activité des canaux Q1412X, Q1411X, Q1382X et Q1390X-CFTR. Cetteobservation ouvre une fenêtre de possibilité pour de nouveaux traitements permettant de réduirela perte de fonction de CFTR causé par un CSP</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gergely Lukacs</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k9573.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736669187</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354k70v"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Profiling the protein corona of human saliva interacted dietary particles and Understanding the effect of silica particles on the structure and function of salivary alpha-amylase</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Srinivasan, Divya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>While NPs (NPs) are copiously incorporated into different food products, the protein corona profile of saliva interacted dietary NPs and its potential influence on the function of proteins involved have received little attention in the past. In this study the most widely used NPs such as food grade silicon dioxide (SiO2), titanium dioxide (TiO2) and emerging NP with application in food industry- silver (Ag) were interacted with human saliva. These particles were characterized for their physicochemical properties in their pristine state and after interacting with saliva. Analysis of the protein corona composition of saliva interacted dietary particles were carried by employing 1D gel electrophoresis and LC-MS/MS. We observed a net decrease in the negative surface charge and change in agglomeration size in saliva interacted NPs.  Significant differences in corona composition, and protein abundance were noted among the tested particles. Several proteins with vital functions in digestion and host protections were found to be enriched on the surface of particles. For instance, Lysozyme, Lactoferrin, Apolipoprotein B100 &amp; E, and Annexin A2 were the most enriched proteins on NPs of SiO2. In order to verify if the binding of proteins have any effect on their function, we tested the amylase and lysozyme activities of saliva in the presence and absence of NPs of SiO2 and TiO2. Our results showed that these particles could compromise the enzymes function wherein NPs of SiO2 showed the highest effect. Overall, our study, identified salivary proteins involved in the protein corona of dietary particles and showed that vital functions of saliva such as digestion and antimicrobial properties could be partially affected by NP-Protein interactions in saliva</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Alors que les nanoparticules (NPs) sont copieusement incorporées dans différents produits alimentaires, le profil de la couronne de protéines salivaire interagit avec les NPs originaires de la diète. L’influence potentielle des NPs par rapport à la fonction des protéines impliquées n’ont reçu que peu d’attention dans le passé. Dans cette étude, les NPs les plus couramment retrouvées dans l’alimentation telles que le silicone alimentaire (SiO2) et le dioxide de titane (TiO2) ainsi qu’une NP émergeante qui possède des applications dans le domaine alimentaire soit l’argent alimentaire (Ag) ont tous été mises en contact avec de la salive humaine. Ces particules étaient caractérisées pour leur propriété physicochimique sous leur forme intacte et après avoir interagit avec la salive humaine. L’analyse de la composition de la couronne de protéines des molécules de salive ayant interagit avec les particules d’origine alimentaire ont été réalisés par électrophorèse 1D avec gel et par LC-MS/MS. On a observé une décroissance nette de la charge négative de surface ainsi qu’un changement de taille des agglomérations dans la salive ayant interagit avec les NPs. Des différences significatives dans la composition de la couronne de protéines et dans l’abondance de protéines ont été notées parmi les particules à l’étude. Plusieurs protéines avec des fonctions vitales de digestion et de protection de l’hôte ont été retrouvées enrichies à la surface des particules. Par exemple, Lysozyme, Lactoferrine, Apolipoprotéine B100 &amp; E et Annexine A2 étaient les protéines les plus enrichies sur les NPs de SiO2. Afin de vérifier si la liaison de protéines avaient un effet quelconque sur leur fonction, on a testé l’activité de l’amylase et la lysozyme de la salive dans la présence et l’absence de NPs de SiO2 et de TiO2. Nos résultats ont montré que ces particules pouvaient compromettre la fonction des enzymes, l’effet le plus important étant celui avec les NPs de SiO2. Globalement, notre étude identifie les protéines salivaires impliqués dans la couronne des protéines des particules originaires de la diète et démontre que certaines fonctions vitales de la salive telles que la digestion et les propriétés antimicrobiennes peuvent être affectées par l’interaction protéine-nanoparticule dans la salive</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Saji George</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000437g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354k70v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395wc69q"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sacred and secular laws : a study of conflict and resolution in Indonesia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lukito, Ratno, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates the history and phenomenon of legal pluralism in Indonesia. The need to explore this topic has been urged by the revival there of Islamic law and adat law, the two greatest non-state normative orderings, in the last two decades. At the same time the ideal of modernity in Indonesia has been characterized by a state-driven effort in the post-colonial era to make the institution of law an inseparable part of national development. The result has been a conception of law as a homogenous system in which the ideology of legal positivism represents the basic tool for lawmaking. This, however, has led to an impasse, seeing that pluralism and multiculturalism are in fact self-evident phenomena in the society. The state has been obliged, therefore, to accommodate these non-state normative orderings. The discussion of Indonesian legal pluralism in this thesis focuses on understanding the state's attitude and behavior towards the three largest legal traditions currently operative in the society, i.e., adat law, Islamic law and civil law. Socio-political factors are shown to have much influenced the relations between state and non-state laws. The state's strategy of accommodation of legal pluralism has in fact largely depended on the extent to which those legal traditions have been able to conform to national ideology. Certain "national legal postulates" have functioned as a yardstick by which the country's legislative and judicial institutions have measured the extent of their accommodation of legal pluralism, although they have had little choice but to do so. Influenced by Masaji Chiba's theory of "three levels of law" (i.e., official law, unofficial law and legal postulates), this thesis analyzes two aspects of legal pluralism in Indonesia: the political and "conflictual" domains of legal pluralism. The analysis is thus generally based on the state policy of legal pluralism reflected in the legal and political strategies confronting the issue of unofficial laws as well as the conflicts arising from such situations. The first aspect is addressed by looking at a number of statutes and regulations promulgated specifically to deal with Islamic law and adat law, while the second is analyzed in terms of actual cases of private interpersonal law arising from conflict between state and non-state legal traditions, as reflected in legislation and court decisions. From a discussion of these two aspects, the thesis concludes that, although the form of the relations between official and unofficial laws may have changed in conjunction with the socio-political situation of the country, the logic behind legal pluralism has in fact never altered, i.e., to use law as a tool of state modernism. Thus conflicts arising from the encounter between different legal traditions will usually be resolved by means of "national legal postulates," making the unofficial laws more susceptible to the state's domination of legal interpretation and resolution.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qv126.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wc69q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Adat law -- Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islamic law -- Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Civil law -- Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Legal polycentricity -- Indonesia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qp03q"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Représentations culturelles et identité d'immigrants adultes de Montréal apprenant le français</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Amireault, Valérie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'environnement cosmopolite montréalais s'enrichit et se modifie au fil des annéesavec la mobilité des populations et l'arrivée de nouveaux immigrants. Dans ce contexte,il apparaît essentiel de connaître le développement des représentations culturelles desimmigrants en lien avec leur propre identité culturelle, et envers la langue française et lesgens qui parlent cette langue. Pour le milieu de l'enseignement du français, une telleconnaissance est essentielle pour susciter le développement de curriculum répondant auxbesoins langagiers et culturels des immigrants. L'éducation en langues secondes peutdonc fournir des opportunités pour mieux connaître l'Autre, sa langue et sa culture, etéventuellement pour permettre de le comprendre et de l'apprécier davantage.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Montreal's cosmopolitan environment becomes richer and is modified as the years go by with the increased mobility and the arrival of new immigrants. In this context, it seems essential to know the development of the immigrants' cultural representations related to their own cultural identity, and related to the French language and people who speak this language. For the French teaching milieu, such knowledge is essential to inspire the development of curriculum to fulfil the new arrivals' linguistic and cultural needs and to better intervene in the classroom. Second language education can therefore provide opportunities for better knowing, understanding and appreciating the Other as well as the other language and culture. This enquiry explores the cultural, representations of adult immigrants from different cultural backgrounds learning French in Montreal in various post-secondary institutions sanctioned by the ministere de l'Immigration et des Communautes culturelles du Quebec (MICC). This study uses quantitative and qualitative survey instruments in order to examine the cultural representations of these immigrants in relation to their integration, their linguistic, cultural and social practices, a new definition of their cultural identity, their reactions in instances of intercultural contact as well as their motivation to study French. In total, 110 immigrants answered our written questionnaire and 14 of them participated in an interview. Findings suggest that the participants generally hold positive cultural representations towards the French language and French-speaking Quebecois. The study indicates that immigrants are mostly looking for informal French learning experiences within their host society. Moreover, participants acknowledge that learning and mastering French is very important for them, both to interact with French-speaking Quebecois, and to obtain a good job in Quebec. Findings related to the immigrants' cultural identity reveal that they seem to experience a "me-them" cultural duality in their host province. The implications of this study are mainly related to the importance of emphasizing the informal learning of the French language so that immigrants can become better integrated into the French-speaking society. Further study perspectives could include the development of French language programs and the content of the French courses offered by the MICC, the use of different data collection methods as well as the participation of immigrants from specific cultural origins.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mp02p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qp03q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Immigrants -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>French language -- Study and teaching (Adult education)</dc:subject><dc:subject>French language -- Study and teaching -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>French language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w8861"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The &amp;quot;sphere of walāyah&amp;quot; : Ismā'īlī ta'wīl in practice according to al-Mu'ayyad (d.ca. 1078 C.E.)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alexandrin, Elizabeth R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In his collection of lectures, the Majalis al-Mu'ayyadiyyah, al-Mu'ayyad fi al-Din al-Shirazi's (d.ca. 1078 C.E.) typologies of the imam set forth a distinctive concept of the Isma`ili imam, as it subsequently results from al-Mu'ayyad's engagement in the works of his predecessors and contemporaries in the Isma`ili missionary organization (da`wah). Al-Mu'ayyad's refutations against the "Exaggerators" (Ghulat) and the "Shortcomers" (Muqaṣṣirun) call attention to the importance of walayah as a doctrine of religious authority and guidance in the light of debates concerning the divinity or humanity of the figure of the imam in the mediaeval Shi`i tradition. In his main doctrinal work, the concept of the human being (al-insan) and a theory of prophetic anthropology are inherently enmeshed in al-Mu'ayyad's skillful presentation of the Isma`ili imam and the "friends of God" (awliya' Allah ). The shared significance of the da`wah and the "ranks of religion" (ḥudud al-din) as vehicles for perfection on the level of the individual human being stresses the necessity of religious guidance throughout the individual practitioner's formation and development (al-nash'ah). Through the guidance of the "friends of God", the individual practitioner may potentially attain to a true humanity that is associated with another birth and formation ( al-nash'ah al-akhirah); another formation that is spiritual rather than physical, and which takes place in the individual's subtle soul. Underlying al-Mu'ayyad's typologies of the imam, where one of the specified lower ranks of the ḥudud al-din may potentially qualify to become the imam, is the idea that there has to be one specific imam at any time who is manifest and physically present so that individual practitioners can benefit from the presence of the imam. As this dissertation aims to elucidate, al-Mu'ayyad's introduction of the imam as the "absolute human being" (al-insan al-muṭlaq) and the concepts of the "imam at any (undetermined) time" (al-imam al-muṭlaq ) and the "seal of the imams" (khatam al-a'immah) into the 11th-century Faṭimid Isma`ili technical lexicon has broader implications for the internal mediaeval Isma'ili debates concerning the concept of walayah and the hierarchy of the "friends of God". In terms of al-Mu'ayyad's definition of the parameters of the "sphere of walayah", the soteriological doctrines associated with the final perfection of prophetic revelation through the guidance of the "friends of God" culminate in the appearance of the Messiah (al-Qa'im ) at the end of time.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n270x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w8861</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hermeneutics -- Religious aspects -- Islam</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ismailites</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muʼayyad fī al-Dīn Hibat Allāh ibn Mūsá, d. 1077 or 8</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abg257j87k"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Al-Ḥusayn ibn 'Alī : a study of his uprising and death based on classical Arabic sources (3rd and 4th century A.H.9th and 10th century A.D.)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ahmad, Riadh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation deals with al-Ḥusayn's uprising and death based on the classical Arabic sources. It is argued that al-Ḥusayn's uprising and opposition to Yazid's caliphate were directly connected to the matter of the caliphate and the caliph's qualifications. He refused to recognize Yazid's caliphate because he considered it as illegitimate due to the fact that Yazid was not qualified to assume such an important office. It is also argued that because of Mu`awiya, who attempted to secure Yazid's succession by forcing all Muslims to pay homage to him, Yazid became caliph. Wanting to remove the real meaning of the caliphate and intending to transform it to a kingship (mulk) inherited among his offspring, Mu`awiya himself rejected the principle of the early Companions of the Prophet by choosing the caliph. Al-Ḥusayn refused to listen to those who advised him to submit to the established authority (de facto) and to enter into whatever the community had entered into and agreed upon. Yazid's caliphate, in al-Ḥusayn's eyes, was a deviation from the Sunna of the Prophet and the conduct of the Rightly Guided Caliphs, and represented corruption in the community of his grandfather. As the Prophet's grandson, he believed that he was committed to following in the footsteps of his grandfather and was more responsible than anybody else for preventing corruption. Even when he became convinced of the Kufans' failure to stand with him, al-Ḥusayn refused to give the bay`a to Yazid and also felt obliged to revolt against him. Furthermore and apart of his strategy, he did decide to take his family with him in order that they would play a significant role after his death. Amongst the results obtained during this research were the three different patterns of writing in our sources; namely, pro-Sunni, pro-Shi`i and a moderate, who escaped being classified as pro-Sunni or pro-Shi`i.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483p42f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257j87k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Yazīd I, Caliph, ca. 642-683</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ḥusayn ibn ʻAlī, d. 680</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698c94c"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Restricting rights, losing control : immigrants, refugees, asylum seekers, and the regulation of Canada's border, 1867-1988</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anderson, Christopher G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Through an in-depth study of the Canadian case, this thesis demonstrates how a loss of control over national borders can result from liberal-democratic state efforts to restrict the rights of non-citizens. It argues that the gaps created between certain fundamental due process and equality rights and state control practice increase the risk of policy failure by opening up avenues along which the authority and capacity of the state can be challenged effectively---by encouraging rights-based politics, irregular migration, and administrative inefficiencies. Part I provides an overview of recent international migration trends, followed by a detailed examination of the liberal-democratic control literature, identifying three biases---restrictionist, domestic-statist, and historical---that obscure the state's role in the creation and perpetuation of control problems. In response, this thesis employs an analytic framework rooted in the concept of the universe of political discourse to trace the evolution and interaction of two competing perspectives that have defined Canadian control policy debates and developments since Confederation, Liberal Internationalism and Liberal Nationalism, each of which posits a different relationship between the rights of non-citizens and the state. Part II presents a thorough account of Canadian control policies towards immigrants and refugees from 1867 to 1965, and reveals that the proposed link between rights-restrictive policies and control problems has deep liberal-democratic roots in Canada. Part III focuses on Canadian policies towards asylum seekers from 1965 to 1988, and demonstrates the central role that the state's rights-restrictive approach played in the creation, breakdown, and replacement of the country's first inland refugee status determination system. Parts II and III are based on an extensive examination of published Canadian government documents, and secondary materials from the fields of history, legal studies, and politics, among other sources. In a concluding chapter, it is argued that by giving greater conceptual and empirical clarity to control, the findings presented in this thesis are of continued relevance to the study of control policies---contemporary or historical---in Canada and other liberal democracies.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bn61j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698c94c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Refugees -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Emigration and immigration</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax346d830t"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Education and technology : a critical study of introduction of computers in Pakistani public schools</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Arshad-Ayaz, Adeela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The importance of technology in education cannot be underestimated. There are compelling reasons for developing nations like Pakistan to introduce technology in their educational systems. Nevertheless the approach and methods used in introducing technology in schools are premised on an economic ideology and based on a techno-centric curriculum that leads to new forms of dependency by keeping individuals from controlling the decisions that significantly shape their lives. Introduction of technology does not automatically guarantee enhanced learning or effective teaching. Technology in education should be used as a tool to increase communication, create awareness, break down existing hierarchies, develop new styles of creating knowledge, and make schooling and education more inclusive. Mere technical use of computers in education does nothing to empower students. The techno-centric introduction of technology in Pakistani public schools is likely to produce inequality. A number of practices in Pakistan's educational and social structure will have to change for the potential of technology to be fully achieved. A shift is needed from 'learning about the computers' to 'using computers in learning', from 'acquisition of limited skills' to 'construction of knowledge', from 'teacher-dependency' to 'independent inquiry' and from 'teacher-centered' to 'student-centered' teaching methods. However, such a change can only take place within a critical framework of education. The critical model based on integrated curriculum treats the computer not as an isolated subject but as a tool that helps learners enhance their critical thinking skills and seek various alternatives to solve problems. Thus, it is important for educational policy-makers to realize that any effort at introducing technology in the educational realm requires theoretical discussion and a societal dialogue to arrive at a framework for technology's place in socio-educational contexts. Pakistan needs to develop and introduce educational technology to seek solutions for its unique economic, social, cultural and human and social development requirements based on its present level of development and evolution.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429f62j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d830t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education -- Pakistan -- Data processing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ast74cv853"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Desautels Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>In the middle of things : how ego networks and context perceptions influence individual creativity in work groups</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anderson, Troy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigates individual creative performance in the context of social networks in medium sized work groups (n = 15 - 25) by combining individual, contextual, and social network antecedents. It is an effort to build a balanced model that takes into account the position of the individual within the social system, as well as individual motivation and perceptions of organizational context. The results show that the effects of motivational and contextual factors on creative performance are mediated by creative behavior performed by the individual. The individual's position in the social network and the nature (strong or weak) of the individual's ties with others in the network, in contrast, exercise both direct and indirect effects (via creative behavior) on creative performance. As predicted, intrinsic motivation, empowerment, and organizational support had positive effects on creative performance. Surprisingly, formal structure also exerted a positive influence on creative performance. Another unexpected finding is that both local brokerage and weak ties exerted overall negative effects on creative performance. As hypothesized, centrality exerted a strong positive effect on creative performance. The results, which are in part inconsistent with previous findings, suggest that the direction of the effects of both social network position and tie strength on creative performance may depend on group size, and that ego network characteristics also affect perceptions of the organizational context. The preferred model showed a strong fit to the data, providing support for the inclusion of network variables in any comprehensive theory of creative behavior in organizations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w4038.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cv853</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Teams in the workplace</dc:subject><dc:subject>Creative ability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social networks</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aww72bg89q"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Floodplain dynamics and traditional livelihoods in the upper Amazon : a study along the central Ucayali River, Peru</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abizaid, Christian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Poor people in rural areas of developing countries are considered to be particularly vulnerable. Research shows that the rural poor tend to live in risky environments and face greater difficulties coping because they are excluded from formal safety nets and have few assets. Today, there is much concern that risk, especially environmental risk, contributes to perpetuate poverty and threatens livelihood security, yet our understanding of the implications of environmental risk for rural livelihood remains incipient. This dissertation explores peasant livelihood within the context of environmental change through a study of peasant responses to rapid river changes along the Central Ucayali River, a highly active meandering river and a major Amazon tributary in Peru. Livelihood responses to floodplain dynamics were examined using the case of a recent meander cut-off near the city of Pucallpa as a "natural experiment." Participant observation and a household survey with 68 ribereno households, in three different villages upstream and downstream from the cut-off, served to investigate: (1) livelihood before and after the cut-off; (2) the role of humans in facilitating the cut-off, (3) land tenure; and (4) the links between shocks and asset evolution. Descriptive analysis indicates that riberenos modified their livelihoods in response to the biophysical changes attributed to the cut-off and derived important economic opportunities. Results suggest that riberenos actually intervened to facilitate the cut-off to reduce travel time and make boat travel safer. Despite the potential for unclear rights and overlapping claims, due to land instability and the coexistence of formal and customary tenure rules, land disputes did not result in physical violence. Examples from two villages were used to illustrate how tenure rules are renegotiated as the resource base expands or contracts. Descriptive and statistical analyses show that riverbank slumps were the main form of risk along the Ucayali and, despite their direct effect on land holdings, environmental shocks did not necessarily constrain land accumulation or increase inequality. This study argues that environmental risk can increase vulnerability and reduce welfare but, under certain circumstances it creates new opportunities for rural people in developing countries. The implications of these findings for vulnerability reduction, human adaptation to environmental change, and Amazonian cultural ecology are discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les populations pauvres des regions rurales des pays en développement sontconsidérées comme étant particulièrement vulnérables. Les recherches passées ontdémontré que les membres de ces populations tendent à vivre dans des environnements àrisques et font face à de plus grands défis parce qu'exclus du filet de sécurité socialeformel et parce que possédant comparativement moins de biens mobiliers et immobiliers.Aujourd'hui, de beaucoup s'inquiètent de la contribution de ces risques, en particulier desriques environnementaux, à perpétuer la pauvreté et du danger qu'ils posent pour lemaintient des modes de vie. Malgré ces inquiétudes, notre compéhension desimplications des risques environnementaux pour les modes de vie ruraux demeure faible.Cette dissertation explore le mode de vie paysan en période de changementsenvironnementaux. Il s'agit d'une étude de la réponse des paysans du moyen Ucayali auxrapides changements dans la dynamique du fleuve. L'Ucayali est un affluent majeur dufleuve Amazone, au Pérou.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257j88v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bg89q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Land tenure -- Peru -- Ucayali River Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Environmental degradation -- Peru -- Ucayali River Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Peasants -- Peru -- Ucayali River Region -- Economic conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Floodplains -- Peru -- Ucayali River Region</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pm38v"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The epididymis and spermatozoa : changes occurring with age and in response to oxidative challenge</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zubkova, Ekaterina V.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Aging is accompanied by an increase in reactive oxygen species (ROS). Spermatozoa are vulnerable to the effects of ROS; these result in damage to membranes and chromatin, the former affecting their motility and the latter impeding successful progeny outcome. The epididymis is important in protecting spermatozoa by removing ROS using glutathione and antioxidant enzymes. Therefore, our goals were to investigate how aging affects (i) the redox capacity of the epididymis, spermatozoal motility and spermatozoal chromatin packaging and integrity, as well as (ii) the susceptibility of these parameters to in vivo and in vitro oxidative challenge. Caput, corpus and cauda segments of the epididymides from young and old male Brown Norway rats were collected and glutathione and antioxidant enzyme activities were measured. Spermatozoa from the cauda epididymidis were analyzed for motility; chromatin packaging and integrity were evaluated in spermatozoa from both the caput and cauda epididymides. In vivo oxidative challenge was induced by 7-day systemic administration of L-buthionine-S,R-sulfoximine (BSO), which is an inhibitor of glutathione synthesis, and in vitro oxidative challenge was induced by incubating spermatozoa in H 2O2. We found that the redox capacity of the cauda epididymidis was altered with age, where the balance shifted towards conserving glutathione. Spermatozoal chromatin become more tightly packaged and less prone to dissociation and DNA quality decreased. Additionally, spermatozoa from old rats contained fewer overall thiols and disulfide bonds, which was due to the appearance of a low-thiol population. After BSO administration glutathione recycling increased and alternative pathways became upregulated throughout the epididymis; this response was greatest in the corpus region, whereas the cauda was affected in an age-dependent manner. Spermatozoal motility became compromised after BSO, where the effect was greater in spermatozoa from older rats. Exposure to BSO and H2O2 revealed that spermatozoa from the cauda epididymidis of older rats had a unique susceptibility to their combined effects. In summary, spermatozoal quality becomes altered in an age-dependent and epididymal segment-specific manner; it is proposed that this may be attributable to the effect of aging on the cauda epididymidis. Susceptibility to oxidative challenge also increases with age, both at the level of spermatozoal chromatin and motility.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000426z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pm38v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad217qv13g"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Melt processing of thermoplasticclay nanocomposites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Borse, Nitin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Polymer/clay nanocomposites are materials composed of a polymer matrix and nanometer size clay particles. They exhibit significant improvements in tensile modulus and strength, reduced permeability to gases and liquids, compared to the pure polymer. These property improvements can be realized while retaining clarity of the polymer without a significant increase in density (typical clay loading is 2--5%). The aim of this research was to achieve maximum exfoliation of the clay and property enhancement in the nanocomposite by melt processing. The components of the Hansen solubility parameters and the Hamaker constants of the constituents were used to establish the compatibility between the polymer matrix and nanoclay. A mathematical model was formulated to study the mechanism of exfoliation of clay platelets in the polymer matrix. The mechanism of size reduction of clay particles was shown to be by erosion or surface peeling. A novel continuous process (System A) was developed and implemented to produce nanocomposites. The process incorporates chaotic mixing, efficient shearing and stretching of the melt, frequent changes in flow direction and higher residence time, in order to enhance exfoliation. The efficiency of the process was demonstrated, using transmission electron microscopy, wide angle X-ray diffraction, viscosity measurements, tensile and highspeed impact testing, and oxygen permeability measurements. Polyamide nanocomposites prepared with System A show a higher degree of exfoliation and better enhancements in mechanical and barrier properties than those prepared using conventional twin-screw extrusion (System C). Polystyrene nanocomposites show higher increase in the d-spacing of organoclay and improvement in barrier properties for System A than for System C, indicating higher specific surface area for the filler particles. The Pukanszky parameter was negative for PS nanocomposites, indicating poor polymer/clay adhesion. The crystallization kinetics of PA-6 nanocomposites were studied using high pressure dilatometry. The nanoclay seems to act as nucleating agent, increasing the rate of crystallization of PA-6 in the nanocomposite. The effect of the clay on the kinetics of formation of different PA-6 crystalline phases was evaluated and explained.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xd776.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qv13g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579x62s"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Peter Martyr Vermigli (1499-1562) and the outward instruments of divine grace</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zuidema, Jason Nathanael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Reformed exegete and theologian Peter Martyr Vermigli (1499--1562) was an unoriginal, but consistent thinker. Theological insights were not packaged separately from each other, but consistently linked together. In all his thought he sought to steer the middle course between theological extremes in taking what was good and rejecting what was bad from each. Typical of this tendency to steer the middle course are his insights into the outward instruments of divine grace. According to Vermigli such instruments---the human nature of Christ, the audible words of Scripture and the visible words of the Sacraments---should not be over-carnalized, nor over-spiritualized. Although God could work immediately (i.e. without instruments), he has chosen to work through these instruments for salvation. Hence, the inward spiritual power and the outward instrument must not be divorced from each other. The Spirit of God does not normally work without the outward instrument, nor can the outward instrument effect grace without the Spirit's power. Modern scholarship has done much to define the sources of Vermigli's thought, but more needs to be said. The more Vermigli is studied, the more it is necessary to qualify characterizations of him. He is not a thinker who is easily pigeon-holed into a certain theological school or movement. As a well-educated biblical and humanistic scholar, Vermigli took independent and well-reasoned positions on the whole variety of theological questions current in his day. As such, this study attempts to view the inter-connected nature of Vermigli's thought so as to gain a better view of the whole of his thought.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cq02t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579x62s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Vermigli, Pietro Martire, 1499-1562</dc:subject><dc:subject>Word of God (Christian theology) -- History of doctrines -- 16th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Salvation -- Christianity -- History of doctrines -- 16th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xq82j"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Political and social influences on religious school : a historical perspective on Indonesian Islamic school curricula</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zuhdi, Muhammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As the most populous Muslim country in the world, Indonesia has a unique experience in dealing with Islamic education, a system that was established years before the country's independence. This dissertation focuses on the development of Indonesian Islamic schools in facing the challenges of modernization and globalization, with special reference to their changing curricula. Using the social constructionist perspective as an approach, this study examines the significance of political and social changes to the development of Islamic schools' curricula throughout the country's history. This study finds evidences of a reciprocal relationship between the changing curricula of Indonesian Islamic schools and the changing social and political circumstances.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b7647.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xq82j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Islamic education -- Indonesia -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nn29g"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>3D parallel computations of turbofan noise propagation using a spectral element method</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Taghaddosi, Farzad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A three-dimensional code has been developed for the simulation of tone noise generated by turbofan engine inlets using computational aeroacoustics. The governing equations are the linearized Euler equations, which are further simplified to a set of equations in terms of acoustic potential, using the irrotational flow assumption, and subsequently solved in the frequency domain. Due to the special nature of acoustic wave propagation, the spatial discretization is performed using a spectral element method, where a tensor product of the nth-degree polynomials based on Chebyshev orthogonal functions is used to approximate variations within hexahedral elements. Non-reflecting boundary conditions are imposed at the far-field using a damping layer concept. This is done by augmenting the continuity equation with an additional term without modifying the governing equations as in PML methods. Solution of the linear system of equations for the acoustic problem is based on the Schur complement method, which is a nonoverlapping domain decomposition technique. The Schur matrix is first solved using a matrix-free iterative method, whose convergence is accelerated with a novel local preconditioner. The solution in the entire domain is then obtained by finding solutions in smaller subdomains. The 3D code also contains a mean flow solver based on the full potential equation in order to take into account the effects of flow variations around the nacelle on the scattering of the radiated sound field. All aspects of numerical simulations, including building and assembling the coefficient matrices, implementation of the Schur complement method, and solution of the system of equations for both the acoustic and mean flow problems are performed on multiprocessors in parallel using the resources of the CLUMEQ Supercomputer Center. A large number of test cases are presented, ranging in size from 100 000-2 000 000 unknowns for which, depending on the size of the problem, between 8-48 CPU's are used. The developed code is demonstrated to be robust and efficient in simulating acoustic propagation for a large number of problems, with an excellent parallel performance.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2677083c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nn29g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Aerospace</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adr26z2252"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The neurobiology of latent learning in the rat using salt appetite and its dissociation from conditioning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stouffer, Eric M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The brain areas required for latent learning in the rat are not currently understood. Previous tasks used to assess latent learning, defined as the acquisition of neutral information that does not immediately influence behavior, have shared characteristics that prevented their use to determine the neurobiology of latent learning. This thesis describes a new task called the Latent Cue Preference (LCP) task, derived from the Conditioned Cue Preference (CCP) task that has been successfully used to determine the brain areas required for conditioning in the rat and other animals. In the LCP task, water deprived rats alternately drink a salt solution in one distinctive compartment of a CCP box apparatus and water in the other compartment over 8 days (training trials). They are then given a choice between the two compartments with no solutions present (preference test). The results of the behavioral experiments showed that this training results in two parallel forms of learning: (1) latent learning of an association between salt and salt-paired compartment cues, and (2) conditioning to water-paired compartment cues. Latent learning itself involved two components: (1) the latent association between salt and salt-paired cues, and (2) motivational information about salt deprivation used to retrieve the latent association, and used to compete with the conditioning to water-paired cues. In addition, the findings showed that latent learning and conditioning involve different neural circuits. Latent learning required an intact cortical-to-hippocampus circuit via the entorhinal cortex, while conditioning required an intact subcortical-to-hippocampus circuit via the fimbria-fornix. The acquisition and storage of the latent association depended on an intact entorhinal cortex/dorsal hippocampus circuit, while the use of motivational information to retrieve the association recruited the ventral hippocampus. Conditioning, on the other hand, required an intact fimbria-fornix, lateral amygdala, and hippocampus. These findings provide new knowledge to the field of learning and memory research, and allowed an update of the current Multiple Memory Systems model.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qh39m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z2252</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neurobiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Learning -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Memory -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75rd12f"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role BAP31 complex at the endoplasmic reticulum in normal cell physiology and apoptosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stojanovic, Marina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The endoplasmic reticulum (ER) plays a vital role in synthesis, folding and sorting of newly synthesized secretory cargo proteins. Quality control mechanism in the ER is a key regulator of this process, which separates correctly folded proteins from immature or misfolded secretory proteins, and ultimately retains and disposes the latter before they can exit the ER. Numerous diseases have been associated with defects in the regulation of the egress of the nascent membrane proteins out of ER to the cell surface. BAP31, a polytopic integral membrane protein at the ER, has been implicated as a putative quality control factor and/or cargo protein in regulating the export of specific sets of nascent membrane proteins. Here, I demonstrate BAP31 to be an important player in regulating and maintaining functional integrity of the cell surface. Both truncated (p20BAP31) and deletion (BAP31-null) mutants of BAP31 significantly abrogated expression of tetraspanins at the cell surface, and thus integrin-mediated cell adhesion and survival due to BAP31 effects on tetraspanin transport from the ER. Consistent with its role as a chaperone or cargo receptor, BAP31 was found to interact with Sec61beta and TRAM, components of the nascent protein translocation machinery and to form an important part of the ribosome-translocon complexes at the ER. In addition to its predicted role in quality control mechanism in the ER, BAP31, a BCL-2 associated protein, is recognized as an important regulator of apoptosis, an essential physiological mechanism of cell suicide in development and homeostasis in all multicellular organisms. Here, I characterized SPIKE, a new proposed pro-apoptotic BCL-2 protein and interacting partner of BAP31. SPIKE is a novel and untypical pro-apoptotic BH3 only protein capable of inducing apoptosis without binding to anti-apoptotic BCL-2 partners and endogenous BAP31, whose role in specific apoptotic pathway remains to be elucidated. Thus, BAP31 plays important, but distinct roles in both normal cell physiology and apoptosis.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rq48m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rd12f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612s84f"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Multi-camera object segmentation in dynamically textured scenes using disparity contours</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sun, Wei, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a stereo-based object segmentation system that combines the simplicity and efficiency of the background subtraction approach with the capacity of dealing with dynamic lighting and background texture and large textureless regions. The method proposed here does not rely on full stereo reconstruction or empirical parameter tuning, but employs disparity-based hypothesis verification to separate multiple objects at different depths. The proposed stereo-based segmentation system uses a pair of calibrated cameras with a small baseline and factors the segmentation problem into two stages: a well-understood offline stage and a novel online one. Based on the calibrated parameters, the offline stage models the 3D geometry of a background by constructing a complete disparity map. The online stage compares corresponding new frames synchronously captured by the two cameras according to the background disparity map in order to falsify the hypothesis that the scene contains only background. The resulting object boundary contours possess a number of useful features that can be exploited for object segmentation. Three different approaches to contour extraction and object segmentation were experimented with and their advantages and limitations analyzed. The system demonstrates its ability to extract multiple objects from a complex scene with near real-time performance. The algorithm also has the potential of providing precise object boundaries rather than just bounding boxes, and is extensible to perform 2D and 3D object tracking and online background update.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n535n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612s84f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214t40r"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of edible films and coatings for extending the postharvest shelf life of avocado</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maftoon Azad, Neda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The focus of this thesis is to develop pectin-based edible films for application of fruits and vegetables to extend their post harvest shelf life. Preliminary research demonstrated that edible coatings could effectively extend the shelf life of based avocado and peach. The respiration rate, moisture loss, firmness, chemical parameters and color changed in a lower rate in coated fruits as compared with the control. Pectin-based film formulations were then evaluated to identify the proper type and concentration of pectin, lipids and plasticizers in the film. The effects of pectin, beeswax and sorbitol concentration on water vapor permeability, mechanical properties and opacity of the films were then evaluated using response surface methodology to identify appropriate levels of different components. Results of studies on film structure revealed that water vapor permeability increased by pectin and sorbitol concentration and was decreased by beeswax concentration. Mechanical properties were mainly affected by pectin and sorbitol concentration. Beeswax was the most influential factor that affected opacity which increased with increasing beeswax concentration. In order to successfully employ these films, their adsorption behavior, thermal and thermomechanical properties were evaluated as a function of moisture content and sorbitol concentration. The adsorption behavior was strongly influenced by sorbitol concentration. Moisture content and sorbitol concentration increased the films elongation at break, but decreased tensile strength, modulus of elasticity and Tg, and increased water vapor permeability of the films. Finally, avocado was coated with a pectin-based film and the associated quality changes were evaluated during storage. From storage studies, kinetic parameters (rate constants) and activation energy were quantified to help model the quality changes in avocado quality as function of storage temperature and time. Pectin-based coating resulted in slowing down the rate of quality changes in avocado at each storage temperature. In general, most changes were well described by some form of zero or first order rate. Temperature sensitivity of rate constant was adequately described by the Arrhenius model. A hyperspectral imaging technique was also used to gather additional tools for following quality changes associated with stored avocados. Artificial neural network (ANN) concepts were evaluated as alternated models for predicting quality changes in coated and non-coated avocados during storage at different temperature. Modeling of quality changes in avocado indicated that compared to conventional mathematical models, ANN has more feasibility to predict of these changes. Models developed for firmness, weight loss and total color difference had better fitness than respiration rate. Finally, the effect of coating on disease severity and different properties of avocados infected by Lasiodiplodia theobromae was studied. The coated fruits demonstrated slower rate of disease progress, respiration rate, softening and color changes. Respiration rate, firmness and color parameters were sensitive to coating and disease severity, and thus these parameters could successfully used to predict fruit quality from disease in coated and uncoated avocados.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r745s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214t40r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Avocado -- Postharvest physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Edible coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>Avocado -- Preservation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aks65hh51n"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ethics of war in Muslim cultures : a critical and comparative perspective</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mahallati, Mohammad Jafar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Rules of engagement, ethics of war, and codes of chivalry are all phrases which remind one of human attempts to rein in and regulate what is perhaps the most anarchic and illogical of all human activities: organized war. The role of the great religions of the world both in propagating war through crusades and jihads as well as their attempts at transcending its savagery through images of miles Christianus or the pious ghazi has also been much discussed. The aim of this thesis is to study the ethics of war in the context of Islamic societies in the Early Middle Ages from several complementary perspectives. Our sources for the period vary greatly from decade to decade and from region to region. This has often led historians of ideas and mentalities to concentrate on one aspect to the exclusion of others. This is particularly so in the case of ethics of war where most of the argument seems to concentrate on a few passages from the Qur'an, supplemented by some quotations from manuals of ḥadith and commentaries on them in the legal textbooks of the different religious schools. That all these are crucial for an understanding of Muslim attitudes and reactions to war throughout centuries is beyond dispute. But it remains, nevertheless, a lop-sided view: neglecting large areas of debate and speculation in literature, philosophy, and mystical meditations, presented as fully-fledged arguments or as occasional remarks and observations embedded in the extant texts from the period. By evaluating these scattered sources and listening to the different voices heard through them, I hope to show some of the different attitudes and responses to the ethics of war and avoid the monolithic and doggedly timeless approach which, at its worst and most extreme, envisages a non-existing consensus among the Muslims from the rise of Islam to the beginning of this new century and neglects the evidence of regional traditions and innovative thinkers by relying solely on a handful of quotes.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70n051j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hh51n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>War -- Moral and ethical aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>War -- Religious aspects -- Islam -- History of doctrines</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dk96d"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Measurement and chemical modeling of calcium sulfate solubilities in concentrated chloride media</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Zhibao, 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Measurement and chemical modeling of CaSO₄ solubilities in HCl-containing multi-component aqueous chloride solutions have been thoroughly investigated. Solubilities of calcium sulfate dehydrate, hemihydrate and anhydrite in concentrated HCl (up to 12 mol·dm⁻³), CaCl₂ (up to 3.5 mol·dm⁻³) and their mixed aqueous solutions were experimentally determined by using the classic isothermal dissolution method at the temperature range from (283 to 353) K. A self-consistent chemical model based on a single set of model parameters for all three CaSO₄ modifications was developed with the aid of OLI Systems software platform. This was accomplished via regression of experimental solubility data that led to the determination of new Bromley-Zemaitis model parameters for the Ca²⁺---SO₄²⁻ and Ca²⁺ --HSO₄⁻ ion pairs. The model was successfully tested for the estimation of CaSO₄ solubilities in concentrated (up to 20 mol·kg⁻¹) HCl-CaCl₂-H₂O systems up to 373 K. In addition this newly developed OLI-based chemical model was successfully applied to construct the CaSO₄ phase transition diagrams in the HCl-CaCl₂-H₂O system. The effect of various chloride salts (NaCl, MgCl₂, FeCl₂, AlCl₃ and FeCl₃) on the solubility of CaSO₄ phases in aqueous HCl or HCl + CaCl₂ solutions up to 353 K was further investigated by experiment and modeling. This led to the development of a truly global model of CaSO₄ solubility in the H + Na + Ca + Mg + Al + Fe(II) + Cl + SO₄+ H₂O system. The new model makes use of new Bromley-Zemaitis activity coefficient model parameters for many ion pairs consisting of cations (Na⁺, Mg²⁺, Fe²⁺, and Al³⁺) and anions (SO₄⁻, HSO₄⁻, and Al(SO₄)₂⁻), as well as new empirical dissociation constant parameters for the species, MgSO₄(aq), AlSO₄⁺, and Al(SO₄)²⁻. The new model was shown to successfully predict the solubility of calcium sulfate phases in multi-component systems not used in model parameterization.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913v00c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dk96d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amp48sj02b"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Statistical contributions to data analysis for high-throughput screening of chemical compounds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Malo, Nathalie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>High-throughput Screening (HTS) is a relatively new process which allows several thousand chemical compounds to be tested rapidly in order to identify their potential as drug candidates. Despite increasing numbers of promising candidates, however, the numbers of new compounds that ultimately reach the market have declined. One way to improve upon this situation is to develop efficient and accurate data processing and statistical testing methods tailored for HTS. Human, biological or mechanical errors may develop across the several days it takes to run the entire screen and cause unwanted variation or "noise". Consequently, HTS data need to be preprocessed in order to reduce the effect of systematic errors. Robust statistical methods for outlier detection can then be applied to identify the most promising compounds. Current practice typically uses only single measurements, which negates the use of standard statistical methods and forces scientists to rely on strong untested assumptions and on arbitrary choices of significance thresholds. The broad objectives of this research are to develop and evaluate robust and reliable statistical methods for both data preprocessing and statistical inference. This thesis is divided into three papers. The first manuscript is a critical review of the current practices in HTS data analysis. It includes several recommendations for improving sensitivity and specificity of screens. The second manuscript compares the performance of different robust preprocessing methods applied to replicated two-way data with respect to detection of outlying cells. The third manuscript evaluates some of the statistical methods described in the first manuscript with respect to their performance when applied to several empirical data sets.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t60g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sj02b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6q182q43b"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of chromatin in the transcriptional regulation of Hoxd4 during hindbrain development and neural differentiation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kobrossy, Laila</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mammalian Hox genes encode a highly conserved family of homeodomain-containing transcription factors that play a crucial role in specifying regional identity and embryonic patterning. Thirty-nine Hox genes are organized into four clusters on different chromosomes each containing up to eleven genes. Importantly, there is a correlation between the genomic location of a specific Hox gene within a cluster and its time and functional domain of expression during development, a phenomenon termed "colinearity". Altering normal Hox expression results in homeotic transformations and malformation, establishing the biological relevance of this tightly controlled expression pattern. Given the integral role of chromatin remodeling in gene regulation, colinear Hox gene activation could be explained in part by successive 3' to 5' conversion from closed to open chromatin along the length of a Hox cluster. We investigated the role of chromatin in regulating Hoxd4, a member of Hox paralog group 4, which is expressed in the CNS with an anterior boundary at r6/7. Previous studies in our laboratory mapped a 3' neural enhancer containing a critical retinoic acid response element absolutely necessary for Hoxd4 expression in the CNS. Moreover, transcripts originating from the P1 proximal promoter are more active in anterior domains of Hoxd4 expression and are responsive to the 3' neural enhancer. We used chromatin immunoprecipitation to detect chromatin changes at the Hoxd4 locus during neurogenesis in P19 cells and embryonic day (E) 8.0 and E 10.5 mouse embryos. In Chapter II, we show that during Hoxd4 induction in both systems, histone modifications typical of transcriptionally active chromatin occur first at the 3' neural enhancer, followed by the promoter. Moreover, the sequential distribution of histone modifications between E8.0 and E10.5 is consistent with a spreading of open chromatin starting with the enhancer, followed by successively more 5' intervening sequences, and culminating at the promoter. In Chapter III, we identify components of the Hoxd4 P1 promoter directing expression in neurally differentiating P19 cells. Our results show that three nucleosomes are positioned at the P1 promoter and are subsequently remodeled into an open chromatin state upon RA-induced Hoxd4 transcription. Moreover, an autoregulatory element was shown to recruit HOXD4 and its cofactor P13X1, and to positively regulate Hoxd4 expression. Conversely, YY1 binds to an inter-nucleosomel linker and represses Hoxd4 transcription before and during transcriptional activation, while the Polycomb Group protein member MEL 18 is co-recruited with YY1 only in undifferentiated P19 cells. In Chapter IV, we discuss the role of sequential chromatin opening in regulating Hox gene expression, and more specifically in controlling transcriptional initiation from P1. Finally, we discuss the consequences of transcription factor binding to P1, and the transcriptional characteristics of P1 that are crucial for regulating Hoxd4 transcription.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859k800.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182q43b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>