<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236261b"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sodium channel mutations causing epilepsy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Loukas, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ion channels mediate the electrical properties of neurons and  other excitable cells. Mutations in ion channel genes have been linked to several  neurological disorders. For example, a rare familial form of epilepsy, generalized  epilepsy with febrile seizures plus (GEFS+), is associated with mutations in voltage  gated sodium channels. We examined how two such mutations (C121W, D188V) alter the  functional properties of the channel through voltage-clamp studies in Xenopus  oocytes and HEK cells respectively. D188V is located in the alpha subunit and C121W  in the auxiliary beta1 subunit of the sodium channel. The C121W mutation causes a 100 fold reduction in efficacy of  current modulation as well as a reduction of current amplitude. This may cause  increased sodium currents via a negative shift of the steady-state inactivation  curve. alpha-D188V channels recover faster from the inactivated state which causes a  resistance to frequency-dependent cumulative inactivation of current amplitude. This  may contribute to cellular hyperexcitability resulting in ictal events in the  epileptic patient.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ragsdale, David S.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nx52j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236261b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw3763745z"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genomic organization and expression of an avermectin receptor subunit from Haemonchus contortus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liu, Jie, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Avermectins and milbemycins are believed to exert their  anthelmintic effects by binding to glutamate-gated chloride channels (GluCls). Two  GluCl subunits have been localized in the pharynx in Caenorhabditis elegans , and  the pharynx has been implicated as a major target for avermectins in C. elegans. The  HcGluCla gene encoding an alpha-type GluCl subunit has been cloned from Haemonchus  contortus previously, however the localization of this gene has not been identified.  To begin to investigate the expression site of this HcGluCla gene we have isolated a  1439bp 5'-flanking region and the entire genomic organization of this gene. The  1439bp 5'-flanking region and the first exon and intron and part of the second exon  of the HcGluCla gene were fused to the green fluorescent protein reporter gene and  microinjected into the gonads of C. elegans. After microinjection of the construct  into C. elegans, four stable transformed lines were established and assayed for GFP  expression. The transformed animals exhibited fluorescence in the two pairs of MC  and M2 pharyngeal neurons, but no expression was detected in the muscle cells. This  result provides evidence that the pharynx is a major site for the mode of action of  avermectins and milbemycins on parasitic nematodes, such as H.  contortus.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Prichard, Roger</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v8512.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763745z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Haemonchus contortus -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anthelmintics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Avermectins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chloride channels</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085k72q"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The environmental Kuznets curve reexamined for CO₂ emissions in Canadian manufacturing industries</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Zhe, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Recent studies of the environmental Kuznets curve raise  questions regarding the relationship between environmental indicators and GDP and  the fundamental reasons that explain this relationship. In response, this thesis  presents one-sector and two-sector models to analyze the alternative causal  relationships between an environmental indicator and GDP at different stages of  economic development. These models analyze how economic scale, technology,  preferences, and economic structure influence the causality and shape of the  relationship. These theoretical studies are followed by two empirical studies. The  first tests the causal relationship between CO2 emissions and GDP in Canadian  manufacturing industries. The second explores several factors as the fundamental  causes that influence the CO2 emissions in the same industries. Factors, such as  economic scale, preferences, technological progress, structural change, and energy  input, are found to be crucial in the determination of CO2 emissions. The empirical  results are positive, but there are data limitations. The empirical studies can be  re-evaluated as more data becomes available.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Henning, John</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rh58v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085k72q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Carbon dioxide -- Environmental aspects -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gross domestic product</dc:subject><dc:subject>Manufacturing industries -- Environmental aspects -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Environmental indicators</dc:subject><dc:subject>Environmental economics -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amc87pq883"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Usefulness of the 1998 American academy of pediatrics recommendations to screen children and adolescents for raised blood low density lipoprotein-cholesterol levels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lauzon, Béatrice</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The American Academy of Pediatrics recommends that children and  adolescents with a family history of premature cardiovascular disease (CVD) and/or  parental total cholesterol (TC) ≥6.2 mmol/L be screened for  hypercholesterolemia. Questionnaires (from children and parents), clinical and blood  sample data were collected in a provincially representative sample of 9-, 13-, and  16-year-olds (n = 2217) in Quebec to evaluate the usefulness of parental history  (PH) of CVD and/or parental hypercholesterolemia to screen youth for raised low  density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C). Mean bias assessed by an external  laboratory gold standard ranged from 1.0% to 2.1%, -0.4% to 5.1%, and -1.4% to 0.1%  according to TC, triglyceride, and high density lipoprotein cholesterol tertiles.  LDL-C was calculated using the Friedewald equation. Positive PH was defined as  one/both biological parents diagnosed with a high cholesterol level, and/or taking  cholesterol-lowering medication, and/or ever having had a heart attack, angina,  stroke, cerebral vascular disease, peripheral vascular disease, and/or taking  medication 'for the heart'. Performance statistics were calculated to determine the  usefulness of PH in predicting borderline/high LDL-C (LDL-C ≥2.8 mmol/L) and  high LDL-C (LDL-C ≥3.4 mmo1/L). 18.3% and 4.8% of subjects had  borderline/high LDL-C and high LDL-C; positive predictive value (PPV) was 23.7% and  7.7%, respectively. Therefore PPVs were only marginally higher than the  corresponding population prevalences and likelihood ratios were respectively 1.38  and 1.63: close to 1.00. In conclusion, PH offers little improvement over random  screening.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>O'Loughlin, Jennifer</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sd33h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pq883</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g077g"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanisms of TrkA-induced cell death of neuroblastoma</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lavoie, Jean-François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Neuroblastoma is the most frequent solid extra-cranial tumor in  children. Its clinical prognosis correlates with the expression pattern of members  of the Trk neurotrophin receptor family, which includes TrkA, TrkB, and TrkC. TrkA  expression is associated with favorable prognosis, while TrkB expression is  associated with poor prognosis. Here we show that TrkA overexpression also induces  neuroblastoma apoptotic cell death, and does so by modulating the levels or  activities of a number of proteins involved in regulating cell survival and  apoptosis, including p53, Bcl-2 and caspase-3. In addition, treatment with a caspase  inhibitor or overexpression of Bcl-XL prevented TrkA from inducing apoptosis. These  results identify apoptosis as a novel biological response of TrkA, implying that  TrkA is a good prognosis marker for neuroblastoma due to its ability to induce  apoptosis when highly expressed, and suggest that therapies based upon TrkA  overexpression or stimulation will be efficacious for the treatment of  neuroblastoma.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kaplan, David</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zf10s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g077g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g078r"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comparison of the effects of two human milk fortifiers with different energy sources on the body composition of premature infants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kean, Penni</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Human milk fortification is recommended to meet the nutritional  requirements of preterm infants. Most human milk fortifiers (HMFs) contain  non-protein energy (NPE) predominantly as carbohydrate which may lead to high fat  deposition relative to lean mass accretion. We hypothesized that fortifying human  milk with a HMF containing NPE predominantly as fat (fatHMF) would result in a  higher (1) lean mass accretion (percent lean mass) and (2) growth (anthropometry),  compared to fortifying with an isocaloric, isonitrogenous HMF containing NPE  predominantly as carbohydrate (carbHMF). In a double-blind randomized trial, 29  infants (≤32 weeks and appropriate for gestational age) admitted to the  Neonatal Intensive Care Unit received either mother's milk fortified with the fatHMF  (n = 14) or the carbHMF (n = 15). Body composition and growth measurements were  performed at Baseline (at ≤10% of goal intake 150 ml/kg), Phase 1, and Phase  2 (3 weeks and 6 weeks, respectively, from starting HMF). Although neither percent  lean (fat) mass nor growth were statistically different, by Phase 2 infants  receiving fatHMF showed a 63% increase in percent fat mass, gained 1194 g in weight  and 8.8 cm in length, whereas the carbHMF showed a 96% increase in percent fat mass,  gained 1005 g in weight and 6.9 cm in length (p = 0.3586, 0.3815, and 0.1851  respectively). By Phase 2, the fatHMF infants gained 128 g in absolute dry lean  tissue, whereas the carbHMF infants gained 99 g (p = 0.0362, Post hoc analysis).  Differences of this magnitude are clinically important, but a larger study is  required to demonstrate statistical significance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beaumier, Louis</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Wykes, Linda</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x457b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g078r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Premature infants -- Nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Premature infants -- Growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Breast milk</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6m311p91n"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pharmacogenetic studies of methotrexate and metafolin in a mouse model of severe and mild 5, 10-methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase deficiency</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Karp, Natalya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR) is a critical enzyme  in folate metabolism. Severe enzymatic deficiency results in metabolic disease with  occasional early demise. Mild deficiency is due to a common polymorphism (A222V)  which increases risk for several common disorders. Pharmacogenetic studies of the  antifolate methotrexate on Mthfr heterozygous knockout mice (Mthfr +/-), a model of  the mild human deficiency, revealed significantly higher apoptosis rates in several  tissues compared to wildtype mice (Mthfr +/+). These results suggest that mild MTHFR  deficiency is a risk factor for methotrexate toxicity in mice and possibly in  humans. A new medication, metafolin, was administered to Mthfr +/- mothers to assess  survival of their Mthfr -/- pups. Survival rate of pups at 5 weeks of age from  treated mothers was significantly higher than that from untreated mothers (54%  versus 20%). The results of this study suggest that metafolin could be useful for  treatment of severe MTHFR deficiency in humans.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rozen, Rima</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53ww38m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311p91n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78tc591"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of CadPlan for electron beam treatment planning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hodefi, Deborah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The electron pencil beam algorithm particular to the CadPlan  treatment planning system (Varian) was evaluated for energies and field sizes  spanning the clinical range. Calculated distributions were compared to measured data  from an Elekta SL 25 linear accelerator. Excellent accordance was achieved between  measured and calculated distributions for all energies and field sizes in cases of a  uniform medium with a flat surface, perpendicular beam incidence and the standard  source to surface distance (SSD) of 100 cm. CadPlan was also proficient at producing  accurate distributions involving varied SSDs within the range typically employed in  the clinic, 98--102 cm. However, when beam incidence was non-orthogonal to the  surface, calculated distributions differed from measurement by up to 2.5 mm or 7%.  The most severe discrepancies were observed for larger gantry angles. Calculated  percent depth dose (PDD) curves in cases of simple slab heterogeneities were found  to deviate from measured curves by at most 1.5 mm. Discontinuities appeared in all  CadPlan-predicted curves, worsening in instances of non-standard conditions. Many  errors stemming from such discontinuity problems could be eliminated by  interpolating between values of fitting parameters tabulated in CadPlan and by  offering more pencil beam and calculation grid sizes. As CadPlan has no means of  accounting for scattered radiation specific to the jaws and applicator, it is unable  to predict output factors with any accuracy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Blais, Noel</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Podgorsak, Ervin</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k7840.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc591</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Radiation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237hs49x"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electrophysiological assessment of chronic cytokine-mediated inflammation in rat ordanotypic hippocampal slice culture</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hellstrom, Ian C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Chronic neuroinflammation was studied using whole-cell  patch-clamp technique in rat organotypic hippocampal slice culture through exposure  to lipopolysaccharide (LPS), an inflammatory stimulus that acts primarily by the  induction of pro-inflammatory mediators known as cytokines. Seven-day exposure to  LPS (100 ng/ml) resulted in significant changes in both intrinsic and synaptic  properties of CA1 pyramidal neurons, which included decreases in membrane resistance  and action potential (AP) discharge frequency; and potentiations of evoked  monosynaptic excitatory post-synaptic current (EPSC) and inhibitory post-synaptic  potential (IPSP) amplitudes. Changes in inhibitory synaptic transmission were  suppressed when cultures were co-incubated with the interleukin-1 receptor  antagonist (IL-1Ra, 50 ng/ml), suggesting that the cytokine IL-1 has an integral  role in mediating this effect. Collectively, these data show that chronic  inflammatory treatment produces important changes in CA1 neuronal properties, and  that the effect on GABAergic transmission appears to be mediated by  IL-1.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Williams, Sylvain</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Luheshi, Giamal</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pb003.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hs49x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149q480"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of feeding raw, micronized and extruded flaxseed on ruminal fermentation and biohydrogenation, nutrient utilization and blood and milk composition of Holstein cows</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gonthier, Christian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Four lactating Holstein cows fitted with ruminal and duodenal  cannulae were used in a 4 x 4 Latin square design to determine the effects of  feeding raw and heat-treated flaxseed on ruminal fermentation parameters, ruminal  fatty acid biohydrogenation (BH), nutrient utilization in various segments of the  gastrointestinal tract, and plasma and milk composition of lactating dairy cows.  Four diets were formulated: a control diet with no flaxseed (C); a raw flaxseed  (RF); a micronized flaxseed (MF); and an extruded flaxseed (EF) diet. Ruminal pH,  NH3N and total volatile fatty acids were not affected by dietary treatments.  However, feeding flaxseed decreased ( P &lt; 0.01) molar proportion of acetate  and increased ( P &lt; 0.01) that of propionate. Ruminal fiber digestion was  lower (P &lt; 0.04) for cows fed the flaxseed diets relative to those fed C.  Feeding flaxseed had no effect on milk yield, milk fat and protein content, and milk  fat yield, but decreased (P = 0.02) milk protein yield. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mustafa, Arif F.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375w92z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149q480</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rumen fermentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Milk -- Composition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Holstein-Friesian cattle -- Feeding and feeds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Flaxseed</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719n00n"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Study of Ds photoproduction at HERA</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gliga, Sebastian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The photoproduction of D+/-s mesons has been measured with the  ZEUS detector at HERA. The data sample corresponds to an integrated luminosity of  121.6 pb-1 . The total and differential cross-sections as functions of the Ds  transverse momentum, pseudorapidity and photon-proton center-of-mass energy are  measured for 3 &lt; pt( Ds) &lt; 12 GeV, |eta(Ds)| &lt; 1.5 and 130  &lt; W &lt; 280 GeV. The total measured cross-section is sep→DsX =  3.869+/-0.286+0.134-0.150 nb. The measurements are compared with leading-order Monte  Carlo simulations as well as next-to-leading order perturbative QCD  calculations. The ratio of D+/-s to D*+/- mesons cross-sections was used to  measure the strangeness suppression factor gamma s within the Lund string  fragmentation model. Using PYTHIA and CASCADE Monte Carlo simulations, the obtained  values are gamma s = 0.281+/-0.205+0.0096-0.0116 and gammas =  0.263+/-0.0189+0.0081-0.0133 , respectively, which are in good agreement with  previous measurements and with e+e- annihilations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Corriveau, Francois</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q454j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n00n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623d209"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A disease specific self-management intervention reduces hospital utilization in patients with COPD : the effect remains at 2 years</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gadoury, Marc-André</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It has recently been demonstrated that a continuum of  self-management (SM) for COPD patients provided by a trained health professional  significantly reduce the utilisation of health care services (Bourbeau et al Arch  Intern Med March 2003). The objective of the present study was to assess in COPD  patients who received a self-management program of the beneficial effect of reduce  hospitalisation could be maintained at long term. A multicentre, randomised clinical  trial was carried out in 191 COPD patients from 7 hospitals. Patients who all had  one hospitalisation in the year preceding study enrolment were assigned to a  self-management program or to usual care. The self-management program "Living  Well with COPD(c)" consisted of a multi-component patient education program  administered through weekly visits by trained health professionals over a 2 months  period with monthly telephone follow-up for 12 months. All cause hospitalisations,  the main outcome, were marked using the provincial hospital database  (MED-ECHO). Most patients were elderly, not highly educated and had advanced  COPD reflected by a mean FEV1 of 1L and 46% reported a dyspnea score of 5/5  (modified MRC). The long-term effectiveness of the self-management program was  assessed with an intention-to-threat analysis. The group-level chi-square analysis  shows a statistically significant difference of 29% in the rate of all-cause  hospitalization between the intervention group and the usual-care group. The  individual-level proportional odds model analysis shows a statistically significant  risk estimate of 0.566. The study shows that patients with COPD, who received an  education intervention with supervision and support based on disease specific  self-management, still had a significant reduction in hospitalisations at 2 years.  Within normal practice such program should be an integral part of the continuum of  care of patients with COPD.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bourbeau, Jean</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405s992c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623d209</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0r9674319"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lung mechanics in mice : effect of decorin deficiency</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fust, Anita</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Decorin is required for the normal fibrillogenesis and spatial  arrangement of collagen. As collagen is important in determining the elastic  behaviour of the lung, we hypothesized that lung tissue mechanics would be altered  in decorin deficient (Dcn-/-) mice. Complex impedance, pressure-volume curves, and  length-stress curves of lung parenchyma were measured in C57BL/6 mice, 6 Dcn-/- and  6 wildtype ( Dcn+/+), both in vivo and in vitro. Immunohistochemistry and Western  blotting were performed to identify decorin and biglycan in the lung tissues. In  vivo, airway resistance was decreased and lung compliance was increased in Dcn-/-  mice. In vitro, length-stress curves showed increased compliance in the Dcn-/- mice.  Immunohistochemistry showed decorin staining in the airway and vessel walls of  Dcn+/+ but not Dcn-/- mice; Western blots showed that biglycan levels were not  different in the Dcn-/- mice. These data support a critical role for decorin in the  formation of the lung collagen network. Lack of decorin alters lung tissue  mechanical behaviour. Additionally, the data from Dcn+/+ mice were compared to those  from other species, and is consistent with the evidence in the literature that mouse  lungs differ structurally from other species. Finally, differences observed in vivo  vs. in vitro suggest that measurements made in the strip more accurately reflect  lung tissue properties.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ludwig, Mara S.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3655702.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r9674319</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xs262"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Targeted transgenesis : the hypoxanthine phosphoribosyl transferase (HPRT) gene locus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>El-Gouhary, Inas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To overcome the limitations that accompanied traditional  transgenesis using pronuclear injections, multiple methods have been employed to  target a single copy of a transgenic sequence to a chosen location in the genome.  One of which is the introduction of a construct as a single copy, in a known  orientation, upstream of the hprt (hypoxanthine phosphoribosyl transferase) gene.  The present study is designed to characterize the influence this locus could impose  on the expression capability of the docked sequence. Consistent ectopic expression of reporter constructs bearing  different Myelin Basic Protein (mbp) regulatory elements and docked at the hprt  locus was noted in cardiomyocytes and major CNS blood vessels; two sites in which  mbp is not thought to be expressed. This ectopic expression originated from  endogenous hprt enhancer activity as similar mbp reporter constructs, randomly  inserted, did not reproduce the same expression phenotypes. In addition, this work also unraveled aspects of the complex  nature of mbp gene regulation. The results obtained from this study reveal that  reporter constructs containing mbp enhancer elements docked in hprt locus expressed  ectopically in the cartilagenous cells of the vertebral bodies during the mouse  mid-fetal development period. Finally, analysis of the "enhancer trap" construct  exposed additional ectopic expression in the muscles of the back and tongue  uncovering further hprt enhancer activity. Surprisingly, when mbp enhancer sequences  were added to the "enhancer trap" construct, marked reduction in muscle  expression was noted.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peterson, A. C.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xf840.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xs262</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj38607609"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Breast cancer surgery QOL scale : development, validity, and reliability</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>El Farrah, Khassan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The SF-36 scale is widely used to evaluate the quality of life  among breast cancer patients, but provides an inadequate reflection of their quality  of life; therefore, we aimed to set up a new scale, a breast cancer surgery quality  of life (BCSQOL) scale and to assess its reliability and validity. The analysis  review showed that 75% to 91% of surgically treated patients (59/79) found that the  questionnaire items were an accurate reflection of their feelings and were clear.  The validity coefficient analysis showed a highly correlated extent of commonality  (alpha = 0.778) between BCSQOL and SF-36 and a significant strength of relationship  (rho = 0.785). Strong to moderate correlation reliability coefficient analysis  (alpha = 0.779--0.351) was observed for the association among all items of the  scale. BCSQOL scale may help health care providers to better understand the health  status of breast cancer subjects, rendering them more equipped to improve their  quality of life.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sampalis, J. S.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451j10f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j38607609</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301197v"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Function of valois in germ plasm assembly and posterior development of Drosophila melanogaster</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cavey, Matthieu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We report the cloning and characterization of valois (vls), a  posterior group gene of Drosophila melanogaster , which was initially identified in  a screen for female steriles. Three EMS alleles of vls contain premature stop codons  in the open reading frame. Sequence analyses show the presence of WD domains in Vls  and find significant similarity with the human MEP50 protein which is involved in  the assembly of the splicing machinery. We did not find evidence that this function  is conserved in flies yet. We created a null mutant for vls, which shows a maternal effect  lethal phenotype accompanied by posterior polarity defects in the embryos.  Hemizygous vlsEMS females show a weaker, partially maternal-effect lethal and a  fully penetrant grandchildless phenotype. The posterior localization of Vasa is  disrupted in vlsnull ovaries, but the initial distribution of Oskar protein and mRNA  appear normal. However, levels of the Short Oskar isoform responsible for pole plasm  assembly are greatly reduced and Vasa appears to be differently modified  post-translationally. Furthermore, a Vls::GFP fusion protein is detected all  throughout oogenesis in the nurse cell and oocyte cytoplasm. Taken together, these  data suggest that Vls is a cytoplasmic protein involved in the transport or  activation of Vasa at the posterior of the oocyte essential for the accumulation of  Short Osk.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Suter, Beat</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278t62k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301197v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Oogenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drosophila melanogaster -- Development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drosophila melanogaster -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2v23vt96h"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Estrogen-related receptor [alpha] (ERR[alpha]), estrogen receptor [alpha] (ERA[alpha]) and erbB-E (Neu) crosstalk in a mouse model of human breast cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chahrour, Ghada</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Estrogen (17-beta estradiol) and its receptor (ERalpha) have  important physiological roles and are well implicated in human breast cancer, but  less is known about the function of estrogen-related orphan nuclear receptor alpha  (ERRalpha). The close kinship between ERalpha and ERRalpha and the existing, but yet  to be fully characterized, interplay between ERalpha and erbB2 (Neu) protooncogene  signaling pathways, suggest that ERRalpha may also play a significant role in breast  cancer. Thus, the focus of the current study was to determine the extent of ERRalpha  cross talk with ERalpha, its physiological role, as well as its possible implication  in erbB2-driven mammary tumorigenesis. Using a well characterized erbB2 mouse model  of human breast cancer where tumorigenesis occurs following a long latency period,  we generated ERRalpha deficient mice (ERRalphaKO) expressing an activated erbB2  oncogene.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Giguere, V.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591908s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vt96h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bp847"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Economic feasibility of anaerobic digestion of swine manure for a grower-to-finisher hog operation in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Apushev, Nurlan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Swine manure creates much public resentment in Quebec due to  nutrient overloading, potential water pollution and odour. Anaerobic digestion is  one of the solutions that allows to lessen the odour problem. Anaerobic bacteria in  manure produce methane. The latter can be burnt to produce heat and electricity on  farms. Moreover, there is a potential for receiving carbon emission reduction  credits for the capturing of methane. Investment analysis was performed to assess the economic  feasibility of a potential anaerobic digestion system on a grower-to-finisher hog  operation. The study was conducted for a case farm, which had plans to expand from  2000 to 4800 pigs. Greenhouse gas emission reduction credits were incorporated into  one of the scenarios. A sensitivity analysis revealed the most important variables  which affect the economic feasibility of anaerobic digestion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thomassin, Paul</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mm85r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bp847</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sewage -- Purification -- Anaerobic treatment -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Greenhouse gas mitigation -- Economic aspects -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Swine -- Manure -- Economic aspects -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rf182"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Invariant and group theoretical integrations over the unitary group</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aubert, Samuel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Integrals of products of unitary matrix elements over the  unitary group will be discussed. A group theoretical formula is available to convert  them into multiple sums, but unfortunately the latter are often tedious to compute.  In this thesis, we develop an alternative method in which these sums are avoided,  and group theory is rendered unnecessary. Only unitarity and the invariance of the  Haar measure are required for the computation. Then, we return to the more  traditional group theoretical approach, and compare its strengths and weaknesses  with those of our invariant method. As a result, we are able to introduce another  method that combines the respective strengths of the other two methods. There are  many examples illustrating how each of the approaches works.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lam, C. S.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sq71p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rf182</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag732d9616"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of lead softening</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vineberg, Daryl Geoffrey</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Softening represents one of the stages in the pyrometallurgical  refining of lead, in which oxygen is top-blown into a bath of impure bullion through  a group of lances in order to preferentially oxidize arsenic, antimony and tin  dissolved in the melt. The oxides of these species float to the melt surface, where  they are removed as dross. It has been observed at Teck Cominco Lead Operations in Trail,  BC that there is an "ignition temperature" in the range of 600°C,  below which the softening reactions are reported to occur very slowly, if at all.  Currently, disproportionately large efforts are made to initiate and sustain the  softening process. This research was motivated by Teck Cominco's wish to have a  clearer understanding of the ignition temperature phenomena, and a more robust and  reliable process control. Experimental trials were performed using a homemade  thermogravimetric analyzer with a data acquisition system. The unit was constructed  in such a way as to allow for simultaneous video recording of the sample surface,  for future examination and reference.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Harris, Ralph</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ch112.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732d9616</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010q65n"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The fast calculation of magnetic field using the local refinement method</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Tongyu, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The speed of the Finite Element Method (FEM) is an obstacle to  the fast calculation of magnetic fields. A fast Local Refinement Method (LRM) using  the first-order FEM is presented for quickly tracking the magnetic field changes  while electromagnetic models have small changes made to their shape. This method  resolves the potentials in the local mesh or submesh extracted from the whole mesh,  with a boundary condition that is calculated by the initial solution based on the  whole mesh. Instead of being re-meshed in the local area, the extracted submesh is  coarsened and reshaped by the LRM to speed up the calculation time by sharply  decreasing the time used for building the S matrix and solving the matrix equation  Ax = b. The new potentials in the submesh are, with an acceptable error, embedded  back into the whole problem to update the magnetic fields which provide designers or  users with a fast visual feedback to their adjustment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lowther, David A.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fr87x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010q65n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Electricity and Magnetism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q700b"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the feasibility of MEMS micro-mirrors for adaptive alignment in free-space optical interconnects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Prentice, James D. B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is an investigation in the feasibility of the use of  MEMS micro-mirror devices for adaptive alignment applications in free-space optical  interconnects. In this scheme, dynamic beam steering is used as the mechanism to  improve minimum system tolerances. Based on the parameters of a previously  implemented interconnect, an optimized integrated design is presented. Two sets of  micro-mirror designs were prototyped using the MUMPs foundry service. Numerical  modeling of the integrated system indicated significant improvement in lateral and  angular tilt misalignment tolerances using the MEMS beam steering system. The effect  of mirror surface curvature on the integrated system was also investigated,  indicating a high dependency of system performance on micro-mirror surface sag.  Testing and characterization of the mirror prototypes indicated significant  deviation from theoretical predictions. Nevertheless, future work in optimizing  mirror designs will allow for improved performance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kirk, Andrew G.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r153h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q700b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af4752h309"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A multi-interface total-internal-reflection based electro-optic switch</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pulikkaseril, Cibby</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A novel method for implementing a 1 x 3 electro-optic switch in  lithium tantalate is presented. Using multiple total-internal-reflection interfaces,  an input beam is deflected to switch ports by reflection at a grazing angle; these  interfaces are turned on by application of high voltage to a surface electrode. The  expected performance of the device was simulated using a combination of in-house and  commercial software, and the device was fabricated using a combination of university  facilities and service vendors. Testing of the device showed that the concept of  using multiple electro-optic interfaces is feasible and has potential applications  in the creation of a package optical switch.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Plant, David V.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sq737.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752h309</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322d97b"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of reactive power dispatch under restructured power systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Jinbo, 1961-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis analyzes generator reactive power dispatch under  restructured power systems from two different perspectives. The first follows the two-step approach adopted by some  electricity markets where first, the generators' real powers are dispatched in the  energy market, followed by the dispatching of the generator reactive power support  services in the ancillary services market. Once the generators' real power has been dispatched in the  energy market, the generators' reactive power is dispatched according to the  minimization of a combination of multiple objectives: network MW loss cost,  generator opportunity cost, and generator MW shift cost. The MW loss cost is  represented as a function of bus voltage magnitudes and angles as well as the nodal  prices in $/MWh found in the first step. Opportunity cost is represented as a  function of the generator reactive powers, whose cost parameters are derived in  terms of the MW dispatch, the MW nodal prices and the generators' capabilities. The  generator shift cost is represented as a function of the generator real powers and  the MW shift weighting factor. As these three objectives may conflict, compromises  are needed to arrive at an optimum solution. The second reactive power dispatch approach unifies real and  reactive power dispatch by minimizing both MW and MVAr generation costs while  enforcing the MW and MVAr/voltage constraints simultaneously. This unified dispatch  avoids a disadvantage of the two-step MVAr dispatch, that is, that the MW price  signal determined in the energy market may be distorted by the subsequent MVAr  dispatch in the ancillary services market. Several numerical examples under different conditions are  presented to examine and compare the effectiveness of these two  methods.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Galiana, F. D.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pw693.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322d97b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m475j"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Behaviour and modeling of deep beams with high shear span-to-depth ratios</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Ding, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A study of the response of eight full-scale deep beams was  carried out at McGill University. Four beams were tested by Li (2003) and this  thesis reports on the testing of the remaining four beams. The deep beams reported  in this thesis were 2000 mm long by 400 mm thick. Two beams had an overall depth of  520 mm and the other two beams had an overall depth of 810 mm. Two beams were  reinforced with main tension tie reinforcement only, while the other two contained  both vertical and horizontal uniformly distributed reinforcement. These beams were tested under concentrated load to investigate  the influence of span-to-depth ratio and the influence of uniformly distributed  horizontal and vertical reinforcement. The presence of uniformly distributed steel  resulted in higher capacities, better crack control and also served to control bond  splitting failures near the supports. Four approaches were used to predict the  capacities: a plane-section model, a simplified strut-and-tie model, a model based  on the 1996 FIP Recommendations and a refined strut-and-tie model. The 1996 FIP  (Federation Internationale de la Precontrainte) Recommendations gave conservative  predictions suitable for design. The refined strut-and-tie model gave the most  accurate predictions due to the fact that this approach accounted for the  contributions of both the horizontal and vertical uniformly distributed  reinforcement in the strut-and-tie model.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mitchell, Denis</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354f84c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m475j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>