<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An870zv53z"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of age, hypertension and arteriosclerosis on the chemical composition of human arterial smooth muscle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Weigensberg, Bernard. I.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Historically, it is of interest that Bright (30) in 1836 was probably the first to recognize the existence of hypertension in man. He had no instrument for measuring blood pressure and based his deductions on the gross pathological changes observed in patients dying of dropsy. As a result of the development of instruments for measuring blood pressure and improvements in microscopic technique, correlations were made between elevation of blood pressure, thickening of the walls of the arterioles and hypertrophy of the left ventricle of the heart.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Evelyn, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m805p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zv53z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arb68xg940"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of Hypomolyx piceus (De G.) (Coleoptera: Curculionidae) and its relationship to white spruce, Picea glauca (Moench) Voss..</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Warren, George. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study of Hypomolyx piceus (De G.) was initiated in 1951. The need for the study arose indirectly through the Laboratory of Forest Pathology, Canada Department of Agriculture at Saskatoon. Members of that laboratory, while investigating root diseases of white spruce in Manitoba and Saskatchewan, discovered root – wounding by the larvae of this insect. Since it was thought that there might be a relationship between this wounding and the incidence of disease, a co-operative study of the insect and root diseases of white spruce was undertaken.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>DuPorte, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322j73k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xg940</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az029p8749"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Oblique impact on sand</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Townsend, David. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>By the very nature of its subject, soil mechanics as compared to a modern science is inexact. Of necessity, idealized sections have been assumed in the determination of the various theories which govern the action of a soil. However, in the field all the local vagaries of nature come into play and the resulting heterogeneous mass is difficult to analyse and inconsistent in its properties.  Thus, the field or soil mechanics has seen two parallel paths utilized in its development. The theoretical path has led to a fuller understanding of the stresses and strains which affect the soil; but the rigorous application of these theories has not proved completely satisfactory in the field.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wilson, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kp69h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p8749</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j9257"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The mixing of cold air jets with a hot gas steam in a varying area duct</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sullivan, Lorne. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The recent and rapid emergence of the gas turbine engine to its top position in many fields of application, in particular the aircraft field, has not been achieved without attendant difficulties. During the early stages of gas turbine investigation and design, recognition was given to the special problems likely to be encountered in the development of the combustion chamber. The present state of development has been accomplished largely by empirical means. Results of any change of operating conditions required "trial and error" design and testing with little margin for satisfactory prediction. Data obtained from experimental results and early combustion chamber design schemes has been supplemented by combustion research programs, and many successful designs have resulted.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mordell, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107306b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j9257</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afq977z99f"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design and development of a frequency-shift, voice frequency carrier telegraph without relays</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stachiewicz, Bogdan. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the design and development of a frequency shift carrier telegraph system operating at voice frequencies and using no relays. The design was carried out in the laboratories of Lenkurt Electric Co. for a customer acting as an agent for the U. S. Government. The author was assigned to this project in the capacity of project engineer and was directly responsible to the chief engineer of the company for the design and development of this equipment. Prototype models were delivered to the customer upon completion of preliminary design and were approved without electrical changes. The performance of the equipment was very satisfactory under all conditions of operation, and very favorable comments from the customer and government inspectors were received.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Howes, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w623x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977z99f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pf56k"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A geomorphological study of the Stanstead area, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sangree, Anne. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Location of the Stanstead area. The Stanstead area comprises a region approximately 230 square miles in extent in the southwestern part of the Eastern Townships of Quebec. Including Stanstead Township, the southern parts of Hatley and Hagog townships, and the western edge of Barnston Township, it occupies the eastern half of the Memphremagog topographic map sheet (31 H/L), the eastern and northern boundaries being those of the map sheet, the western boundary, Lake Memphremagog, and the southern, the International Boundary between Quebec and Vermont.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hare, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xq67f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pf56k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514nq34h"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Near field diffraction patterns of conical and rectangular horn radiators</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shkarofsky, Issie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The field patterns in the aperture and in front of the mouth of conical horns, with small flare angles, under TEll excitation, are measured. In the aperture, electric and magnetic fields are determined, both in the E and H-planes, for effective apertures, varying in diameter from 5 to 8. Field patterns in the Fresnel region are taken for horns, having mouth diameters of 5 and 8. Measurements are given, as well, for a square horn, of aperture 8 to a side, under TEIO excitation. Deviations, from the field values in a horn of infinite length, occur in the electromagnetic field in front of the horn and in the aperture. These deviations are ascribed to diffraction, and to the possible existence of higher modes. Similar pertubation patterns in the aperture are obtained for conical horns, whose diameters differ by 2. Some Fresnel field measurements are compared with calculations, by the method of Kirchhoff and by Lommel. If the correct variation in the incident field is taken into account, favourable agreement is obtained, for patterns sufficiently far from the aperture. Results are in terms of Lommel's universal co-ordinates.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Howes, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/000003955.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nq34h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m806z"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The substances extracted by water from white spruce bark, pretreated with liquid ammonia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sanderson, Edwin. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present research is one of a series, some items of which have been concluded, and some of which are still in progress, on the constitution of the bark of white spruce (Picea glauca). The disposaI of bark has become a major problem to the pulp and paper industry of this country and the discovery of useful compounds in bark, and of practical methods of obtaining them, would be of considerable importance. Up to the present time, research in the field of bark has been focused on the investigation of fractions obtained by the extraction of bark with water and such organic solvents as alcohols and ether.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Purves, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xg958.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m806z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z4922"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The microflora of apple leaves and its relationship to Venturia inaequalis (CKE.) Wint..</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ross, Robert. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Venturia inaequalis (Cke.) Wint., the apple s cab fungus, grows during the summer on the living leaf, producing a mycelium which develops only between the cuticle and the epidermis. But when the infected leaf dies naturally, this mycelium then grows as a saprophyte and sends its hyphae all through the tissues of the dead leaf. It is during this saprophytic part of its life cycle that the fungus passes through it s sexual stage. Ascogonial hyphae arise in the mesophyll of the dead leaves and after fertilization by antheridia from oppositely sexed thalli, initiate the perithecia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Coulson, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719r14m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z4922</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r935d"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Surface studies on the arterial intima</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rota, Alexander. N.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In much of the work devoted within recent years to the study of atherosclerosis, great emphasss has been placed on the biochemical changes associated with the disease - particularly changes in the lipid and lipoprotein composition of the blood. Studies of the structure of the arterial wall and of the structural changes occurring during the development of atherosclerotic lesions have been relatively neglected. Atherosclerosis is, however, a focal disease. In studying the pathogenesis of the lesions, and in attempting to account tor their localization, one must consider not only the composition and pressure of the fluid bathing and passing into the arterial wall, but also, obviously, the structure of the wall itself.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Duff, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698c712.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r935d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579x390"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Temperature distributions in heat exchanger tube plates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rogers, James. T.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The problem of temperature distribution in heat exchanger tube sheets was investigated from three aspects, (a) a theoretical analysis of tube plate temperatures (b) an investigation of tube entrance length heat transfer coefficients under conditions of high turbulence and relatively high temperature, (c) an experimental confirmation of the applicability of the method of analysis. Results may be summarized as follows: (a) The approximate method of temperature analysis shows good agreement with more exact methods. A cooled and protected tube sheet for high temperature service was analyzed by the technique. (b) A correlation was obtained for heat transfer in turbulent now in the entrance length of tubes which predicts much higher coefficients than those formed by other workers. Reasons for this were advanced.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mordell, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204302g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579x390</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117s89r"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>General principles for the planning of sub-arctic settlements</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ridge, Frank. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the northwestern part of Canada there lies a region of 734,566 square miles, equal to about one-fifth of the entire area of the Dominion, occupied by 19,375 people. This sub-Arctic region, north of the 60th parallel of latitude and west of the 102nd meridian of longitude, is virtually a Dominion within a Dominion. Designated herein as the Northwest, this great expanse of mountains, plains and plateau comprises the entire Yukon Territory and the District of Mackenzie, Northwest Territories. This vast region first came into prominence in 1789 as a result of Alexander Mackenzie's famous journey to the mouth of the river named in his honour.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hare, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859k64m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117s89r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655m441"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Wall rock alteration around base metal sulphide deposits of northwestern Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Riddell, John. E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Abitibi district has been a subject of interest and geological investigation since 1872 when McOuat made a reconnaissance traverse through the area. In 1904 W. A. Parks traversed the country north of Lake Temiakaming. During the years 1908, 1910 and 1911, M. E. Wilson of the Geological Survey of Canada made a general reconnaissance of the western part of the area lying between the Interprovincial Boundary and Kawagama Lake. The results of this work were published as Summary Reports of the Geological Survey of Canada together with a map on a scale of 1/255,400 (Wilson, 1908, 1910, 1911, 1913), and later republished as Memoirs 17 and 39.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gill, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wv585.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655m441</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bn455"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The nitrogenous components and the amino acid metabolism in the ovaries of Ascaris lumbricoides</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pollak, John. K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Little is known of the biochemistry of Helminths even though some aspects, notably the production of fatty acids by the nematode Ascaris lumbricoides, have been under investigation for more than fifty years. Helminth literature is mainly concerned with the biology of parasitic helminths and with the clinical effects which they cause. The work which has been carried out on the metabolism of parasitic helminths has been frequently reviewed (von Brand 1938, 1946, 1952; von Brand and Jahn; Bueding 1949; Geiman and McKee 1950; Hobson 1948; Lapage 1951; McCoy 1935; Smyth 1947).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fairbairn, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qd800.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bn455</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924g77d"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Stark effect in silver</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Piggott, Carmen. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis deals primarily with observations of the Stark effect on a rather uncommon arrangement of neighbouring doublet terms in the arc spectrum of silver. The aim of the research was to resolve the inconsistencies existent in earlier investigations and to provide an extension to the apparently incomplete experimental data. This was essential to any understanding of the part played by the electron spin in determining the Stark patterns. The new data has made possible the realization of this objective since the new components appear to complete the analysis for the groups concerned.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Foster, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nj76t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924g77d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440x721"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the action of some drugs on frogs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pedley, Norah. F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The discovery by Loewi (1921) that the slowing of the heart during vagal stimulation was due to the release at the nerve ending of a chemical substance, led to the study of transmission at other synapses. Although much success has been achieved at various periferal synapses, no chemical transmitter at the G.N.S. synapses has definitely been discovered or proven. The complexity of the G.N.S. is such that many supposedly similar experiments give conflicting results. One explanation for these conflicting results obtained when dealing with the G.N.S. would be that there is probably more than one synaptic transmitter, and that a substance may be excitatory at one synapse but inhibitory at another.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burns, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hh23g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440x721</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612s657"><ual:graduationDate>1928</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Montreal Negro Community</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Israel, Wilfred Emmerson</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Montreal of 1928 presents a striking contrast to the Ville Marie as founded by Maisonneuve.  From its particular geographic location it was destined to occupy a position of dominance in the growth of Canada.  The peculiar physiographic features of the St. Lawrence River on the South and Mount Royal on the North have given the direction fo the city growth its own particular form.  The phenomenon of th4e two nationalities, diverse in language, traditions, religion and culture, living side by side and paying allegiance to a common sovereign has marked the city with an atmosphere that adds to its own natural charms.  With the majority French speaking people carrying on their own particular life and the English residents developing their own culture the city has been justly termed the Paris of America. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd3761695.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612s657</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Race relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Blacks -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sociology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4t64gs268"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the hydrolysis of casein</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pedersen, Jorgen. W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A great part of our modern knowledge about the structure and composition of proteins originates from the analysis of the products formed by their hydrolysis. Since Braconnot, in 1820, hydrolysed gelatin with dilute sulfuric acid, proteins have been hydrolysed with acids at concentrations as high as sixteen normal. Hydrolysis has also been effected by heating proteins with barium hydroxide solutions or other alkalies and by incubating them with pancreatic and other proteolytic enzymes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baker, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vg491.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gs268</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asf2689327"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cervical fascia: anatomic and clinical</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mohiuddin, Syed. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The applied anatomy of the cervical fascia and the traps or spaces therein have been revised and reviewed from the early part of the Nineties up to the present date. A great many investigations of both in anatomical and clinical nature have contributed to our present day knowledge of the subject. But considerable diversity both of opinion and description is revealed in these contributions. Actually, only a few investigators have taken the subject really to task; partially, this may be due to the difficulty of dissection in the region, and clinically because suppuration in this region is often diffuse and obscures the boundaries of the fascial spaces.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Martin, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225g14r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2689327</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g412g"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The electromagnetic field within circular apertures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Milne, Allen. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The electromagnetic field components within a circular aperture in a plane conducting screen have been investigated experimentally. The measured fields and those predicted by some recent theories are compared for plane waves irradiating the screen at normal incidence, using apertures from one-quarter to two wavelengths in diameter. Several measurements for non-normal incidence are included. Experimental techniques have been devised for the measurement of the aperture fields very close to the diffracting edge. A sharp increase in the magnitude of some of the field components has been observed to occur in the region less than 0.15 wavelengths from the edge. This result supports recent theoretical predictions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Woonton, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b281f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g412g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kv354"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Population distribution in the Riding Mountains, Duck Mountains, and adjacent plains of Manitoba and Saskatchewan, 1870-1946</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Merrill, Lesly. I.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study is essentially an investigation of the way in which people have become distributed over the region of the Riding Mountains, Duck Mountains, and the adjacent; plains, during a period of seventy-six years. The nature of growth and change in the population distribution, and the main economic, physical, and social factors involved, constitute the fundamental problem of the thesis. It is believed by the author that such a study will make a contribution toward understanding the nature of population distribution, and so toward understanding another facet of human geography.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zaborski, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4308698.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kv354</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sf57m"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experiments in rheomorphism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McCuaig, James. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The first high temperature experiments on natural rocks were carried out by Sir James Hall, and the results published in the "Transactions of the Royal Society of Edinburgh" in 1798. In these experiments, Hall heated a number of rocks in a furnace that was used for making bricks. The temperature was measured by means or a resistance thermometer (the first of its kind) which was constructed by Wedgwood. Hall found that hornblende and other mafic minerals were the first to melt when the rocks were heated. These minerals vitrified at moderate heat but the feldspar remained unchanged.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kranck, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n7230.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sf57m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajw827g90q"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of variation of the thermodynamic properties of the working fluid on the performance of gas turbines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McArthur, Beverly. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is common practice when determining experimentally the performance characteristics of an axial flow turbine, to assume that for any particular entry temperature the thermodynamic properties of the working fluid remain essentially unchanged as the expansion process takes place. As these properties are determined by the values of Cp and y this means that their values remain constant as the gas expands through the turbine. It is known that the thermodynamic properties of a gas vary with the temperature and the air-fuel ratio in any turbine engine.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mordell, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x778q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827g90q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aks65hh24r"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The radiation resistance of resonant parallel strip transmission lines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Matusiak, Marvin. E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The “Chipman Method” was used in the measurement of the radiation resistance of resonant parallel strip transmission lines in the frequency range 350 - 1350 Mc./Sec. Measurements were made at three different conductor spacings with line lengths varying from one-quarter wavelength up to four wavelengths. With a probable error of about 5% it was found that the radiation resistance was independent of line length and was very nearly proportional to the square of both frequency and conductor separation. Unlike the radiation resistance for lines composed of thin circular conductors, the magnitude of the radiation resistance for strip lines with short circuit terminations was found to be considerably greater than that for strip lines with open circuit terminations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Howes, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xg96j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hh24r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3t945v938"><ual:graduationDate>1953</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of certain factors affecting the adaptation of bird’s-foot trefoil (Lotus corniculatus L.)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martineau, Real</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is a known fact that under the climatic conditions prevailing in Eastern Canada most pastures make poor growth during the drought period 0f midsummer, namely during July and August. Moreover there are large areas of sandy soils and up-lands that are too dry, too low in fertility or too acid to grow successfully the better know legumes such as alfalfa, red clover and Ladino. Alfalfa is a perennial plant, but it is confined to fertile and well-drained deep soils which have a pH 6.5 or higher.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steppler, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268933h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945v938</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>