<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719p00v"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Automation in facilitation of air transport</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Piera, Alejandro J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The air transport industry is at present subject to dramatic traffic growth, which is expected to triple in the next 20 years. The industry must attempt to meet this unavoidable challenge by somehow accommodating the increase in passenger flow. This thesis proposes to examine how automation devices may assist in meeting this challenge by facilitating passenger clearance. They would do so by improving the lengthy, formalistic, and overly-bureaucratic, immigration and customs procedures. A myriad of different legal issues are engaged by these initiatives. Although many of them are mentioned throughout this thesis, the core legal analysis focuses on the challenge to privacy triggered by these endeavours, and the conflicting interests of individuals and industry players. Finally, a proposal to eliminate, or at least to reduce, this conflict is recommended.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x49q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719p00v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Air travel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Passenger traffic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741t56m"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Triceps surae fatigue, and its effects on intrinsic and reflex contributions of human ankle dynamics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Qita, Wissam A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Muscle fatigue may be defined as any exercise-related reduction in the force-generating capacity of a muscle. Its effect on joint stiffness is not well understood. The purpose of this study was: (1) to characterize triceps surae muscle fatigue, and (2) to determine its effect on the dynamic stiffness of the ankle joint. To address the first question, subjects were asked to maintain constant, submaximal, isometric contractions at levels ranging from 10--50% of maximum voluntary contraction (MVC) for as long as they could. Position, torque, and electromyograph (EMG) signals were recorded. EMGs from ankle extensors---triceps surae group---and flexors---tibialis anterior---measured the progression of fatigue. Generally, EMG RMS, tracking error and tremor increased with fatigue. The synergistic triceps surae muscles exhibited alternate activity between two states: active and silent. Moreover, as contraction level was increased, both alternation onset time and endurance time decreased. To address the second question, pseudorandom binary sequence (PRBS) displacements were applied before, during, and after fatiguing contractions of the triceps surae. Position and torque were recorded and analyzed to identify the intrinsic and reflex contributions to ankle stiffness. Fatigue caused significant changes in both intrinsic and reflex properties. For intrinsic properties, there was a decrease in the elasticity, and an increase in the viscosity of the joint. For reflex properties, there was an increase in the gain and a change in the reflex dynamics. Thus, it appears that, during fatigue, reflex stiffness increases to compensate, at least in part, for decreased intrinsic stiffness.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kearney, Robert E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q590m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t56m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zq32x"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the precipitation and stability of scorodite produced from sulphate media at 950C</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Singhania, Shalabh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Arsenic is a major contaminant in the non-ferrous extractive metallurgical industry and its disposal poses a serious environmental threat. Precipitation of arsenic from aqueous acidic solutions in the form of crystalline scorodite (FeAsO4.2H2O), which is a naturally-occurring mineral, is proposed as an arsenic fixation method. The production of scorodite is usually done in autoclave at high temperature and pressure. However, in a breakthrough at McGill University, a step-wise neutralization procedure has been developed where scorodite can be formed at ambient pressure (95°C). This work investigates the relation between precipitation conditions in sulphate media with the crystallinity, yield, and above all, solubility of scorodite produced. This work has investigated the effect of (1) type of seed, (2) type of base, (3) cationic and anionic additives, (4) Fe/As ratio, and (5) presence of Fe(II) in the precipitation media. It was found that crystalline scorodite can be produced via the use of various types of seed such as hematite and gypsum in addition to scorodite. The stability of the product was not found to be affected measurably upon change of base from MgO to CaO and in the presence of various cations (Cu, Zn, Ni, Co, and Mn) and anions (sulphate, nitrate and phosphate). Most solubilities measured were between 1 and 3 mg/L at pH 5. Solubilities as low as 0.5 mg/L were found when Fe(III):As(V) was 3:1 but the yield was low. Following these results, Fe(II) was added to the system and solubilities as low as 0.2 ppm were observed with yields of over 80% in a single precipitation step.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Demopoulos, George P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp16h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq32x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bw32d"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microstructure and properties of TMP papers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Porubská, Jana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Paper is comprised of quasi-randomly distributed fibres, fines and different additives. The properties of paper depend on the type of fibres used, their uniformity of distribution, the amount and type of fines and fillers. It is difficult to predict how a particular component will behave in a mixture. This will depend on the form of material introduced (flocculated or dispersed) and on what kind of interactions will take place. These factors can be controlled by various wet-end strategies based on known colloidal behaviour of various additives. Thus, applying this knowledge to papermaking, one should be able to predict and control final structures of paper, which will be reflected in optical and mechanical properties. A thorough understanding of the effects of different materials, such as fines and fillers, on optical and mechanical properties of paper can only be obtained from a systematic study. Therefore, this research focused on elucidating the relationship between the nature and amount of fines and fillers and paper properties. The studies were mainly limited to papers made from thermomechanical pulps (TMP), although occasionally comparisons with other pulps were made as well.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Garnier, G.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Van De Ven, T. G. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f098.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw32d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Agriculture, Wood Technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sc06q"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>SMES for power quality improvement and uninterruptible power supply</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pan, Haibo, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The history of applied superconductor-based equipment in industry, especially in power system, is briefly reviewed. The thesis presents a development of a superconducting magnetic energy storage system for power quality improvement and uninterruptible power supply (PQ/UPS SMES). The configuration of such a system and its control concept are analyzed in full details. Evaluation tests of an SMES system operating on a simple power system are presented and analyzed. They validate the applicability of such a system, as an attractive alternative for power quality improvement and uninterruptable power supply. The PQ/UPS SMES system as well as the power network has been modeled using Matlab/Simulink simulation environment for convenience. The Simulink models of all relevant components are also presented. Finally, all the evaluation tests are also done in Simulink simulation environment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gavrilovic, Momcilo M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn13b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sc06q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqv33rz44t"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Heat transfer enhancement under a turbulent impinging slot jet</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anantawaraskul, Siripon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Heat transfer characteristics under a single turbulent confined slot jet were determined experimentally. New enhancement techniques for the impingement heat transfer rate are proposed and tested experimentally. The results from each enhancement technique are compared with those for a smooth slot nozzle configuration with the same apparatus. The impingement heat transfer rate was observed to increase due to internal finning of the slot nozzles. Both rectangular and triangular fins were tested. The fins acted as roughness elements. Experimental results with the "rough" nozzle show that the stagnation and average heat transfer rates can be enhanced by up to 15% and 10%, respectively. However, an increase in pressure drop across the nozzles is also noted. Use of inclined confinement surfaces of 10° and 20° angles accelerate the exit flow provides average impingement heat transfer rates comparable with those for parallel wall confinement. Experimental results show no significant change in the heat transfer distribution for the inclination angle of 10°, while the average heat transfer coefficient is in fact decreased slightly for the inclination angle of 20° at high jet Reynolds numbers. It was found that insertion of a single turbulence generator in the jet flow provides superior impingement heat transfer without any increase in the system pressure drop. Two types of turbulence generators (square rod and thin plate) were investigated. Both turbulence generators provide the same level of average heat transfer enhancement (up to 15%).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mujumdar, Arun S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kv641.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz44t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m584q"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bullets to ballots : the Lebanonization of Hizballah</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zigby, Mohammed Ak.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the span of two decades, Hizballah has evolved from an armed resistance movement against Israeli occupation into an efficient political party and---by extension---into a permanent fixture on Lebanon's mainstream political stage. The present analysis traces the evolution of the party from its inception and assesses its performance vis-a-vis the major players of Iran, Israel and Syria. Factors including the characteristics of the movement and the Shiite community itself, the shifting position, interests and policies of various regional actors, and the changing domestic conditions in Lebanon were isolated in order to adequately explain the behaviour and development of Hizballah. As a result, such alternatives to cultural factors (i.e the "Islamic variable") were found to be stronger explanatory factors rather than the Islamic factor. Ultimately, the essay illustrates that Islamic considerations are secondary, if not tertiary, when political decisions are to be made in different contexts. Rather, it is the interests of the more powerful actors that govern the organization's next move, in addition to the aforementioned variables. On the basis of such assumptions and findings, conclusions were finally drawn regarding Hizballah's future developments and its prospects following an Israeli withdrawal.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brynn, Rex</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg67j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m584q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lebanon -- Politics and government -- 1975-1990</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hizballah (Lebanon)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lebanon -- Politics and government -- 1990-</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g680h"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>spa</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Hispanic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"Déjame que te cuente" : oralidad e intertextualidad en La última mudanza de Felipe Carrillo de Alfredo Bryce Echenique</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Valladares Ruiz, Patricia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis offers an analysis of the novel La ultima mudanza de Felipe Carrillo of the Peruvian writer Alfredo Bryce Echenique. It is an approach to the narrative strategies which allow the reader to recreate an oral atmosphere through writing, and which propose, consequently, new perspectives to reading fiction. First, the distinctive features of the Post-boom novel are studied so that the links which associate Bryce's work with this literary period can be established (chapter one). Second, the narrative techniques presented in the novel are studied, namely, orality, musical and literary intertexts, digression, and dialogic unstableness (chapter two). These elements---especially orality and intertextuality---make possible the construction of a conversational dynamic in which the author develops the different thematic axes of his work: search for love (chapter three), search of a national, as well as a social and creative identities (chapter four), and literary self-consciousness (chapter five).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cohn, Deborah</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gq10z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g680h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bryce Echenique, Alfredo, 1939- Ultima mudanza de Felipe Carrillo</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zc92d"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hydrogen in enameling steel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ahn, ByeoungSoo, 1959-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Enameling steel, used in a vast range of applications, can suffer from a surface defect resembling fish scale. In this study, the effects of several microstructural, physical and coating factors on the hydrogen diffusion in low carbon steel were investigated using an electrochemical permeation apparatus, to find out the way to prevent the surface defects on the enamel coatings. A new mechanism explaining the formation of the surface defects on the enameling steel was proposed after summarizing the experimental results. Then, the effects of porosity, dislocation density, the surface roughness of a steel substrate, oxide passive layer and Pd coating on the hydrogen diffusion coefficient, hydrogen concentration and hydrogen flux were investigated. The variations of hydrogen diffusion coefficient, hydrogen concentration in steel and hydrogen flux caused by all factors listed previously were calculated in order to understand the effect of these factors on hydrogen diffusion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Szpunar, Jerzy A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zc93p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc92d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cc72j"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Static types to dynamic variables : re-assessing the methods of prehistoric Huron chipped stone tool documentation and analysis in Ontario</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lerner, Harry, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An assemblage of prehistoric Huron chipped stone tools has been analyzed in terms of its inherently dynamic properties. It is hypothesized that the series of measurements and ratios that has been developed is more efficient than existing systems for gauging the changing nature of these implements over time. The statistical evaluation of the data revealed strong linear relationships between various pairs of variables, such as projectile point length and tip angle and end scraper bit edge angles and bit height. It was found that comparing these data to other attributes of these tools, such as use-wear traces and reduction techniques, can be very informative about how each category of tools changed through manufacture, use, and maintenance. The results of this analysis were then compared to those of a more traditional study of a contemporaneous collection of Huron stone tools (Poulton, 1985), demonstrating the utility of the techniques developed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Trigger, Bruce</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gv41j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc72j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Huron Indians -- Ontario -- Antiquities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tools, Prehistoric -- Ontario -- Analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stone implements -- Ontario -- Analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Archaeology -- Methodology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dp17s"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le grotesque dans Les diaboliques de Barbey d'Aurevilly</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marleau, Tania</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The grotesque is an unsettled notion which is difficult to define. Over the years, there have been several attempts to formulate a satisfactory definition. Today, a few definitions prevail, namely that proposed by Hugo, Bakhtine and Kayser. In my opinion, the latter is the most appropriate for the analysis of the grotesque in Barbey d'Aurevilly's Diaboliques . Indeed, Wolfgang Kayser's theory of the grotesque is based on the idea of a world that has suddenly become "estranged". Barbey's "diabolical" characters are peculiar beings, both passionate and inscrutable, who by their actions and attitudes manage to overwhelm most characters of their universe. By their very mystery, the diaboliques remain deeply present in others' minds, thereby changing their existence forever. In Barbey's stories, there are no mythical beasts, no monstrous grotesque per se. However, when examined from Kayser's perspective, light is shed on the grotesque aspect of their characters.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boucher, Jean-Pierre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c235m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp17s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Grotesque in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Barbey d'Aurevilly, J. (Jules), 1808-1889. Diaboliques</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqz20sv52r"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of East Asian Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Managerial relationships in Sino-foreign joint ventures : a cross-cultural perspective</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Lifen, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study explores the dynamics of the managerial relationship in Sino-foreign joint ventures from the perspectives of both Western expatriates and local Chinese. It is based on observations of one joint venture and some formal and informal interviews of a few other joint ventures. Through examining cross-cultural trust, communication, decision making and conflict management, this study has presented some of the problems which have appeared, shed light on their origins and suggests possible resolution strategies. The author argues that mutual understanding between Westerners and Chinese is needed to form a basis for successful managerial relationships. Furthermore, understanding must be based on equality, respect and a knowledge and appreciation of the other people's different customs and forms of self-expression. This study also cautions against the use of Western concepts in pursuing cross-cultural studies of managerial relationships in the Sino-foreign joint venture context.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dean, Kenneth</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Noumoff, Samuel J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q331b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sv52r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Joint ventures -- Management -- China</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr172000p"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of East Asian Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Woman writing about women : Li Shuyi (1817-?) and her gendered project</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Xiaorong, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the life and poetry collection of the woman poet Li Shuyi (1817--?) within the context of women's literary culture in late imperial China. In particular, the textuality of Li Shuyi's poetry collection Shuyinglou mingshu baiyong (One Hundred Poems from Shuying Tower on Famous Women) forms the centre of critical analysis, which aims to articulate her gendered intervention into representations of women's image in poetry. The thesis is organized into three interconnected sections: the reconstruction of Li Shuyi's life in order to provide a context to articulate her relationship to writing, a reading of Li Shuyi's self-preface to discuss her motivation to write, and critical analysis of poems according to the three thematic categories of "beauty, talent, and qing ." The thesis demonstrates how a woman author's self-perception leads to her becoming a conscious writing subject, and how this self-realization then motivates her to produce a gendered writing project.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks26r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172000p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women poets, Chinese -- 19th century -- Biography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Li, Shuyi, b. 1817</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mp103"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Examining the effectiveness of grand round scenarios using BioWorld : does real-world practice improve real-world learning?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Espinosa, Maria Rowena</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to examine the effectiveness of cased-based learning, writing and peer discussions on learning about digestive diseases in a computer-based learning environment, BioWorld. This method was called the Grand Rounds method. Thirty-one, ninth grade biology students participated in the study. Two classes were randomly selected as the Rounds group and the No Rounds group. All students worked collaboratively in pairs to solve diagnostic problems on BioWorld. The Rounds group then engaged in the Grand Rounds activities while the No Rounds group conducted a web search and solved a final BioWorld problem. Both treatments demonstrated significant knowledge gains of digestive problems from pretest to posttest but the gains were greater in the Rounds group. There were no significant changes from pre to post questionnaire in students' attitudes towards biology or peer work/discussion. The verbal protocols revealed students used diagnostic heuristics while solving cases, and discourse communities emerged among the students. Overall, this study confirms the benefits of written and oral discourse, and authentic learning activities in classrooms.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lajoie, Susanne P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv531.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp103</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Metacognition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Case-based reasoning</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010r96v"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Children's and adolescents' internal working models of peer interaction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dolenszky, Eva</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study examined whether children and adolescents develop mental models of peer relations that reflect observed gender differences in size and in density of friendship structures. A total of 278 children and adolescents, ranging from preschool level to CEGEP, participated in the study. Participants were given a questionnaire, consisting of schematic drawings of different forms of peer interactions, to assess their ideas about how friendships are organized for children of their age. Results indicated that both female and male participants at all grade levels judged typical boys to have a greater preference for group than dyadic interactions than did typical girls. Typical girls, however, were not judged to have preference for either dyadic or group interactions. Results also indicated that both female and male participants at all grades judged that the probability of mutual friends also being friends as higher for typical boys than for typical girls. Overall, the findings from the present study demonstrated that children and adolescents of both genders possess internal working models of peer interactions, beginning in early childhood, that are gender differentiated in a way that reflects patterns of behaviour.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Benenson, Joyce</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq31w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010r96v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social interaction in children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Age groups</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sex differences (Psychology) in children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000194g"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Parents' and teachers' acceptability of conjoint behavioral consultation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Duggan, Vanessa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study examined parents' and teachers' acceptability of conjoint behavioral consultation for children with problem behaviors at school and at home. Also examined was the relationship between perceived treatment acceptability and treatment outcome, and time to treatment effectiveness. An A/B design was used and participants included 14 children, their parents, and teachers. Results indicated that conjoint behavioral consultation was an equally acceptable intervention prior to and following implementation for both parents and teachers. Results also indicated that parents' perceptions of treatment acceptability at posttest were not related to the effectiveness of the intervention as measured by direct observations. On the other hand, teachers' perceptions of treatment acceptability following implementation were found to be positively related to the effectiveness of the intervention. Furthermore, both parents and teachers perceptions of treatment acceptability were found to be significantly related to perceptions of treatment effectiveness and time to effectiveness. Results are discussed in light of their practical and theoretical implications.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sladeczek, Ingrid</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b15d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000194g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Behavioral assessment of children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Problem children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rg30j"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lorenzo Monaco's Man of sorrows</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Emery, Beth A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines Lorenzo Monaco's altarpiece the Man of Sorrows with the Virgin, St. John the Evangelist, with the Emblems and Episodes of the Passion, (c. 1404) under historical, religious, political, and liturgical rubrics. While comparing various depictions of the Man of Sorrows, this project places Lorenzo Monaco's unique interpretation within the context of events surrounding the painting's conception and realization. With particular attention to Lorenzo's distinctive composition, techniques and juxtaposition of imagery, this study shows that his Man of Sorrows in fact conveys a complex message about Florentine society in Late Gothic times.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boker, Hans J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j067f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rg30j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lorenzo, Monaco, 1370 or 71-1425. Man of sorrows</dc:subject><dc:subject>Christian art and symbolism -- Italy -- Florence -- Medieval, 500-1500</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jesus Christ -- Art</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5t34sm24z"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Privacy in homes of Shaamy Muslim immigrants : a study of privacy patterns in single-family detached homes and townhouses of middle-class immigrants in Montreal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hallak, Mahmoud Essam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>After W.W.II several waves of mostly highly educated, middle-class, traditional Muslim families from Shaam arrived in Canada. The major problem that faced them, as a result of cultural differences with their new milieu, was the unresponsiveness of their living environment in Montreal to their distinguished religious and cultural needs---most notably those involving the idea of privacy . The purpose of this study is to examine privacy patterns in homes of the Shaamy community in Montreal, by analyzing the physical characteristics of their single-family detached homes and townhouses, usage patterns of domestic space, and inhabitants' social behavior. The research goes further to explore privacy-induced patterns of change in the physical environment of the home, space functions, and domestic behavior, which aim to improve privacy conditions in community homes. In particular, this research provides a description and analysis of the indigenous lifestyle and the socio-religious and cultural privacy concepts of this community. The research then scrutinizes the correlation between these elements and the physical characteristics of Montreal's housing patterns, and privacy concepts which are embodied in their designs. Both internal home layouts and functions, and outdoor settings are analyzed in relation to community privacy conceptions. This investigation process intends to diagnose major privacy deficiencies in the design of their homes and to highlight domestic privacy mechanisms and utilization modes of the home environment. Finally, criteria are established for improving the design of community detached homes and townhouses, with minimal change to their physical structure and patterns.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bhatt, Vikram</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr1720027.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm24z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Immigrants -- Dwellings -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Privacy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muslims -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Social life and customs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muslims -- Dwellings -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dwellings -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anv9354771"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Construction products that contribute to increased flexibility in wood-frame low-rise housing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lu, Wen-Chieh Richard, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>With the greatly increased rate of social and economic change in North America since World War II, the flexible/adaptable house has become an alternative to the conventional single-family, detached housing that both exceeds the needs and means of many non-traditional households. Theories and experience worldwide have shown that housing flexibility that is based on user participation allows decision-makers to adapt housing projects to meet the changing general needs. However, technological bottlenecks in the invention of new materials and techniques can restrict flexibility. This study examines construction products that contribute to increased flexibility in wood-frame low-rise housing. Prefabrication has been the construction industry's approach to achieving housing flexibility. The strategy has been to incorporate flexibility into each subsystem or component through the use of new materials and techniques, in order to create overall building flexibility. The research presented in this thesis shows that different products offer different levels of flexibility, and that combining them does not necessarily produce greater overall flexibility. By examining the positive and negative aspects of these products, the author is able to suggest new directions for the development of future innovations in housing flexibility.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Friedman, Avi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xb340.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv9354771</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Building materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>Modular coordination (Architecture)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wooden-frame houses -- Design and construction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924d49t"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>High-rise housing development in Shanghai since 1972</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bao, Haiyu, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The past three decades have been a time of intensive development for high-rise housing in Shanghai. It has grown from an experimental prototype to the city's predominant form of housing. In this thesis, three periods in the developmental progress of Shanghai's high-rise housing will be examined, beginning in 1972. The interrelationships between the specific socioeconomic contexts, building codes, and design strategies are explored sequentially, and twelve typical high-rise housing projects are discussed, in an effort to trace the evolution of high-rise housing design strategies. The study focuses primarily on three aspects of high-rise housing design: site organization, building design and unit layout. Responses to socio-economic transformation and building code regulations related to architectural design strategies are explored from the macro to the micro level. The experiences and lessons learned from previous works are reviewed, as well as suggestions for improving the performance of future projects, through approaches to architectural design and building-code adjustments.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Adams, Annmarie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr78t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d49t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>High-rise apartment buildings -- China -- Shanghai -- Social aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>High-rise apartment buildings -- China -- Shanghai -- Designs and plans</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354h100"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Chitin and chitosan industry and its potential in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Teftal, Hassan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The shrimp processing industry has to deal with the ever-growing costs associated with the disposal of their residuals. However, investigation into the possibility of making high-value biopolymers (chitin and chitosan) from this waste shows significant potential for developing a chitin and chitosan industry in Quebec. The pharmaceutical and medicine industry is the target market for high-grade chitosan. Based on the related data of cellulose derivatives (the closest substitute for chitosan), the Bass model was used to forecast the sales of high-grade chitosan in Quebec. It is estimated that the potential market for chitosan in Quebec is worth 37 million dollars (in 1999 prices) cumulative for the next 20 year period and 59 million for Canada. In the first year of marketing chitosan, sales in Canada (high-grade) are expected to reach $3.2 million from which $1.55 million is expected to be generated in Quebec. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Goldsmith, Peter</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Gunjal, Kissan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k686x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354h100</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chitin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shrimp industry -- Québec (Province) -- By-products</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fishery processing industries -- Québec (Province) -- By-products</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chitosan</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cz32v"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The seizure and detention of aircraft by Canadian airports and the Convention on International Interests in Mobile Equipment : a critical analysis of non-consensual rights under the Unidroit regime</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maniatis, Dimitri</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Canadian airport authorities benefit from the right to seize and detain aircraft where airport charges remain unpaid. By objective measures, this right constitutes a preferred non-consensual right or interest that takes priority under Canadian law over all competing rights and interests in the aircraft subject to seizure and detention, including, for example, the interests of an owner, lessor or secured creditor. In this manner, airport authorities may recover outstanding user fees from both the airlines themselves and from the aircraft owners or lessors. The Unidroit Convention attempts to harmonise the law applicable to aircraft finance transactions. As such, it targets private law rights. However, its breadth and scope touch upon the statutory rights of third parties with non-consensual interests in aircraft, including those of airport authorities to seize and detain aircraft. The interplay between the Unidroit regime and the seizure and detention rights of Canada's airport is the focus of this academic discourse. It demonstrates that even though this right, recourse and remedy is of fundamental importance to Canada's National Airports System and its transportation infrastructure generally, the Unidroit Convention could, if implemented as drafted, effectively compromise the ability of Canadian airports to seize and detain aircraft.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc90v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz32v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Security (Law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aircraft leasing and renting -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Finance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Airlines -- Finance</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816p267"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The convergence of U.S. military and commercial space activities : self-defense and cyber-attack, "peaceful use" and the space station, and the need for legal reform</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Petras, Christopher M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The ever-increasing convergence of U.S. military and commercial space activities poses new challenges to the viability of the legal concepts that have traditionally governed the use of outer space, and particularly the military use of space, from the beginning of the space age. This paper will look at two examples of where the melding of U.S. military and commercial space activities necessitates a reexamination of the applicable legal theories. Part I will examine the concept of self-defense in outer space, by considering the legality of the use of conventional military force to defend against "cyber-attack" on its commercial space assets. Part II will examine the concept of the use of outer space for "peaceful purposes" under international law, by focusing on the permissibility of military use of the International Space Station. As private commercial entities increasingly take their place aside State actors in outer space, understanding the impact of space commercialization on the law governing military-related activities in outer space becomes more-and-more important to policymakers, military planners, legal scholars and space law practitioners alike.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301312z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p267</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Space industrialization -- Law anfd legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Space stations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Astronautics, Military -- Law and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax346d604s"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Islamic Fiqh and the contract of international carriage of passengers by air</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Naji, Alaa A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>GOD says in the Holy Qur'aan "O' people, I have created you from a single pair of a male and a female, and made you into nations and tribes that ye may know each other. Verily the most honored of you in the sight of GOD is the most righteous of you..." (Holy Qur'aan, 49:13). This thesis is laid down in accordance with GOD's order to connect civilizations with each other and to benefit from each other's experience and knowledge toward a much better future for humanity. The thesis tries to reflect upon the opinions of Islamic Fiqh with regard to the contract of international carriage of passengers by air and e-ticketing in a manner that is understandable to both Fiqh oriented and Western Law oriented readers. Therefore, it has been designed to include three major Parts where the first introduces the Western Law oriented reader to Islamic Fiqh. The Second Part introduces the Fiqh Oriented reader to the world of tickets and travel documents. Finally, the third chapter concentrates on the issue of electronic ticketing. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c4469.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d604s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Contracts (Islamic law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islamic law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97ks271"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rethinking antidumping laws</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Osseiran, Marwan Hani</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis evaluates the arguments for replacing antidumping laws with competition laws or, alternatively, for recasting antidumping laws in the pattern of competition laws. The work discusses the objectives and criteria used in antidumping and antitrust cases. It highlights the harmful and chilling effects of antidumping sanctions. It is a study of whether antidumping laws should be replaced by either supra national (Competition laws) or harmonised domestic antitrust regimes, which penalise international predatory pricing without at the same time penalising non-predatory international price discrimination. It is suggested that progressive reforms of antidumping rules should become an agenda item of all future WTO Rounds and should focus on reconciling antidumping rules with antitrust treatment of predatory pricing practices. The progressive inclusion of antitrust criteria into WTO antidumping laws should be made a condition for progress in future WTO negotiations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>de Mestral, A. L. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v728b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks271</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Antitrust law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antidumping duties -- Law and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>