<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913t45h"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Sacred Theology</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Religion</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The doctrine of atonement in the theology of Pail Tillich</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thompson, Arthington. F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The doctrine of atonement attempts to elaborate the statement of the Creed that it was "for us men and for our salvation" that Jesus Christ was born, lived, died and rose again. It has tried to show how these facts are central for the establishment of a new community between God and man. The fact that this doctrine has never been defined as dogma may derive partly from uncertainty about the use of language; but most certain it derives from the fact that what is here spoken of is the mystery of an ‘act of God’. Atonement bas been made and is established from beyond the human world.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McLelland, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xj48r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913t45h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Divinity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77fw28k"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A law, above and beyond an analysis and concept for the law of space</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tamm, John. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To evaluate the relationship of the natural law of the Universe and apply it to a concept of man-made or man-defined law, one must consider to some extent the over-all picture of the Universe as we know and understand it today. Primarily our main concern is the small portion of the world in which we, as individuals, reside. Occasionally we broaden our concern to our state and nation, and possibly to our world. Until recently our interest has been with our law (as each individual or sovereign nation sees it), our control, our flight in space.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rosevear, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rp85j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fw28k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Air and Space Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An296x283c"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A method of performance determination and analysis for the internal combustion engine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Szirtes, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis includes the test of a modified Jacob L-6MB 7-cylinder radial engine. In its original form the engine was not suitable for bench test measurements (the reason for this is explained in Chapter 5). Therefore, six cylinders out of the seven were disconnected and all of the tests and investigations were executed on the single-cylinder engine. The emphasis of this investigation was placed on the various relationships among the operational variables, viz, speed, torque, power, fuel consumption, specific fuel consumption, charge of fuel, charge of air, mixture strength, gas temperature, etc.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bruce, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z880j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x283c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579w93k"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agronomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some effects of variations in seeding rate and date and intensity of defoliation on the response of Timothy (Phleum pratense L.) and Bromegrass (Bromus inermis Leyss.) during the establishment period</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Swift, Graham</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There exists today in Eastern Canada an estimated fourteen million acres of pasture land, of which a large proportion remains at a law level of production. The growing recognition that grass is a crop has given added stimulus to pasture improvement, its development and utilisation. Where the live stock farmer predominates, in an area in which forage species are adapted, much importance is attached to grassland resources as the cheapest source of feed. Under this situation, which prevails in Eastern Canada, the value of sound• pasture management, and the need for further knowledge of the principles upon which such a system may be attained, cannot be overemphasised.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steppler, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g861q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579w93k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418r88v"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Edmond Richer et la tradition Gallicane</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sutto, Claude. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une étude du genre de celle que nous entreprenons ne saurait commencer abruptement, et pour ce, nous croyons nécessaire de formuler dans cette introduction, un certain nombre de remarques préliminaires sur le Gallicanisme. Le principal problème qui se pose tout naturellement à l'esprit est celui d'une définition. On pourrait décrire le Gallicanisme comme un mouvement d'inspiration à la fois religieuse et politique, voire économique, qui, du XIVe au XIXe siècles, sous prétexte d'assurer l'indépendance du Royaume contre les empiètements de la Papauté, contribua à séparer la France de Rome, en donnant à l'Église gallicane un statut particulier.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290f19j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r88v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nf76f"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The executive in Indonesia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Suny, Ismail</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The nationalist movement of Indonesia promptly seized power in the country two days after the collapse of Japan, and proclaimed an Independent Republic of Indonesia on August 17, 1945. The Indonesian Constitution, as "a revolutionary constitution", was established on August 18, 1945 by the Indonesian Independence Preparatory Committee (Panitia Persiapan Kemerdekaan Indonesia) in a document called the Constitution (Oendang-Oendang Dasar) of the Republic of Indonesia. From a juristic point of view a victorious revolution itself becomes a lawcreating fact, and therefore the legality of the Constitution of the Republic of Indonesia is judged by reference to the success of the Indonesian revolution.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Scott, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v637n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nf76f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r901k"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The galvanomagnetic properties of some solids at low temperatures and high magnetic fields</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Storey, Samuel. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The galvanomagnetic properties of solids at low temperatures and high magnetic fields have been of interest since 1930, when the oscillatory dependence of the transverse magnetoresistance of Bismuth on the magnetic field was discovered by Schubnikow and de Haas (1). This discovery was followed in the same year by the discovery of similar oscillatory behaviour in the magnetic susceptibility by de Haas and van Alphen (2).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wallace, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wn990.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r901k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak3569785f"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nucleic acids of normal and neoplastic tissues</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Spencer, John. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1868 Miescher (1), by digesting pus cells with pepsin-hydrochloric acid and then shaking with ether, isolated nuclei and prepared from them an unknown compound which he called "nuclein". The substance was acidic in nature, insoluble in dilute acid but readily soluble in dilute alkali, and contained a high proportion of phosphorus. This latter property was noteworthy, for at that time the only known organic compound of phosphorus in the tissues was lecithin. Be subsequently prepared nucleins from a variety of tissues.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Quastel, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dq77f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569785f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arj430827r"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Philosophy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Karl R. Popper and the problem of historical prediction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Solomon, Edward. B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Karl R. Popper, Professor of Logic and Scientific Method in the University of London, is primarily a physicist and a philosopher of science. In this capacity, he is interested in: the criterion demarcating science from pseudo-science, the method of science, and especially the method of social sciences. He thinks the method employed there is the cause of the trouble, since it is based on a misunderstanding of the method used in the physical sciences.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Currie, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c6178.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430827r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859k28r"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experimental studies on the pathogenesis of ascending biliary infection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sigman, Harvey. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The surgeon is often called upon to treat patients suffering from post-hepatic obstructive jaundice. This treatment may simply consist of removal of stones from the common duct or relief of spasm or stenosis of the sphincter choledochus by sphincterotomy. On the other hand, stricture or tumour of the duct may necessitate the performance of extensive reconstructive procedures on the biliary channels. The first side-tracking operation for obstructive jaundice was carried out in 1882 (180) at which time the gall bladder was anastamosed to the colon in seven stages over a seventeen month period.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webster, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h8066.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859k28r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arb68xg516"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Melville’s Moby Dick and Pierre: different approaches to the same cosmic theme</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sigal, Goldie. K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>"To produce a mighty book, you must choose a mighty theme", said Herman Melville in Moby Dick. Despite conspicuous differences in approach, the underlying theme of Moby Dick and Pierre is indeed a cosmic one. It is a theme with which Melville grappled throughout his life; one with which all great artists and religious teachers have wrestled since the dawn of human expression, and which so intensely concerned the first New Englanders and many of their descendants.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Files, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z709133z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xg516</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As7526g82g"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nitrogen transformation by soil microorganisms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shieh, Hang. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The organic forms of nitrogen in the soil are derived largely from plant residues, such as stubble, weeds, leaves, and pine needles etc. The amount of protein in these organic materials is often very large. For example, the protein content of cereal straw and wood shaving may be as much as 2 or even 15 per cent, and the protein content of certain defatted meals, may be 40 or even 60 per cent. The phenomenon of growth and death of bacteria in ordinary culture media has been studied in considerable detail.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Knowles, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dt09p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526g82g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Bacteriology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mn547"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comparative chemistry and taxonomy of the “Hamamelidales”.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shaw, Elizabeth. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Present day systematists have at least 150,000 species of angiospermous plants to deal with. Obviously, this large number must be divided into smaller groups, and several methods have been devised to separate them. The earliest workers used rather simple characters, resulting in very arbitrary divisions. For example, Theophrastus recognized trees, shrubs, under-shrubs and herbs. However, one modern taxonomist also uses this sort of division. Hutchinson (1926, 1948, 1959) divides the dicotyledons and monocotyledons into two main lines of development; i.e., the "Lignosae", or woody line, and the "Herbaceae" or herbaceous line.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gibbs, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fs39s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mn547</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Botany</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bx97f"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structural obstacles to economic development in India</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shah, Said. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the period since the end of World War II increasing attention has been focussed on the problems of economic development of areas commonly described as "underdeveloped". Within such areas much of this interest has come to the forefront following the achievement of national independence. And among the more industrialized nations the interest is partly the result of a genuine desire to aid the underdeveloped areas and partly to attempt to influence their political direction in the global ideological conflict of the midtwentieth contury.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wright, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mg57v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx97f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m543s"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the relation between the Laplace and the Fourier transforms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Senez, John. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The subject of integral transforms is generally introduced as an extension of the Fourier series representation of periodic functions. The fundamental expression, the Fourier integral formula, is derived from these series by a purely formal process, and, from it, the Fourier transform and the inversion formula are defined. The validity of these expressions is then ascertained by the proof of the fundamental theorem of convergence for functions satisfying given conditions. The Laplace transform and its corresponding inversion formula are introduced, in such discussions, in an equally formal manner by the simple expedient of a definition.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Schwerdtfeger, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pr462.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m543s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x7501"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les femmes de bonne volonté et les autres dans les hommes de bonne volonté de Jules Romains</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schroeder, Maida. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans le roman-neuve, Les Hommes de Bonne Volonté, grande fresque qui dépeint vingt-cinq années de civilisation entre le 6 octobre 1908 et le 7 octobre 1933, Jules Romains passe en revue plus de trois cents femmes. Elles sont de toutes les classes, de toutes les conditions : duchesses, marquises, comédiennes, doctoresses, institutrices, gouvernantes, modistes, boutiquières, concierges, femmes de chambre et femmes de ménage, tireuses de cartes, procureuses, filles du trottoir; elles sont jeunes, mariées, mères, veuves, fiancées, vieilles filles, femmes trompées, femmes trompeuses et femmes entretenues. Certaines ne font que passer : ce sont ‘les oueds dans le sable’; d’autres paraissent à plusieurs reprises.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Launay, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53x047c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x7501</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440x44v"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The pyrolysis of peracetic acid</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schmidt, Cirill</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Combustion has always been a subject of great interest. The oxidation of hydrocarbons and of related compounds has been studied by numerous investigators (1, 2, 3, 4) with an intention of elucidating the mechanism of these reactions. The investigations of the rates of oxidation of different hydrocarbons have been interpreted in terms of complex chain reactions involving free radicals such as OH, H, CH, C2 etc. (5), but as yet no unequivocal and satisfactory mechanism has been established for any combustion reaction.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sehon, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999b29d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440x44v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw9505407n"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on milk powders</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Samuels, Eric. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The production of good quality milk powders is a relatively recent enterprise. Although reference to edible milk powder dates back to the thirteenth century, it was not until the early twentieth century that milk powders were produced in any appreciable quantities. This comparatively slow development of the dried milk industry can be attributed to the inherent difficulties involved in the manufacture of whole milk powder of a satisfactory keeping quality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baker, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mt50n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505407n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j4644"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Behaviour of fluid drops in sheared suspension</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rumscheidt, Fritz. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The flow inside and outside of undeformed fluid drops suspended in an immiscible liquid in shear and hyperbolic flow was studied under conditions where the transmission of shear stresses across the interface was unimpeded. Excellent agreement with a previously developed theory was found. The effect of surface-active substances was to inhibit the internal circulation by forming an elastic interface capable of resisting shear stresses. The deformation, orientation and burst of drops in the two flow fields were investigated for a wide variety of systems. The deformation and orientation were in excellent quantitative accord with the theories due to Taylor and Cerf.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mason, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892f67c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j4644</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acv43p1822"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Voltaire critique de Corneille d’après les commentaires sur Corneille</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rosmarin, Leonard. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Au début d'Octobre 1760, Voltaire reçoit à Ferney une ode grandiloquente d'un nommé Lebrun, secrétaire du prince de Conti, oh est évoqué le pitoyable sort d'une jeune héritière du grand Corneille "qui voit couler dans l'oubli ses destins et ses pleurs". Vivement ému, Voltaire éprouve aussitôt de généreux sentiments envers l'illustre dramaturge et sa déplorable héritière : "Pierre est un grand homme, déclare-t-il, il le sera toujours et nous, à côté, nous sommes des polissons."</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Larivière, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mr08g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p1822</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb397c838"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the nitration of amines and n-oxides of phenanthridine, acridine and quinoline</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roberts, René</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As recently as 1950 Schofield (1) was able to state that the electrophilic substitution of heterocyclic compounds lacked a comprehensive explanation. Since then considerable progress has been made both on the experimental and on the theoretical side, but there still remain many problems to clarify. The systematic investigations of Ochiai and den Hertog on the properties of heterocyclic N-oxides presented interesting new possibilities.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Taurins, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz8063711.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397c838</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s1619919"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The B vitamin requirements of the house cricket</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ritchot, Claude</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>McFarlane, J.The house cricket Acheta domesticus (L.) is a very convenient laboratory insect; it is easy to rear (Ghouri and McFarlane 1958), it has a sufficiently short life cycle, the eggs and young nymphs are large enough not to necessitate any special apparatus to be manipulated, and, finally, neither diseases nor parasites are factors influencing the results. Nevertheless, A. domesticus has not been used very often by research workers, and the first to study seriously some aspects or its nutrition were Ghouri and McFarlane (1958), and McFarlane et al. (1959).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McFarlane, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666834d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1619919</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anz8063729"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Motivational effects of lesions in the thalamus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Replogle, Anne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis reports a study of the motivational and emotional function of the midline and intralaminar structures of the thalamus of the rat. Following the work of Moruzzi and Magoun (1949), and the activation theory of emotion developed by Lindsley (1951), a great deal of psychological research has been devoted to the relation between behavior and the activity of the non-specific projection system (or systems) of the brain stem. Most of this work, however, has been directed toward the functions of the ascending reticular formation of the medulla and mesencephalon.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hebb, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117s523.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz8063729</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429f03c"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The geology of Buchans Mine, Newfoundland</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Relly, Bruce. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The town of Buchans is four miles north of Red Indian Lake, in about the centre or Newfoundland, lat. 48° 50'W; long. 56° 46'W (see fig.1). The Buchans Mining Company Limited is a subsidiary of the American Smelting and Refining Company. The mineral rights are leased from Terra Nova Properties Limited, which is a subsidiary of the Anglo-Newfoundland Development Company Ltd. The town of Buchans is linked to the Canadian National Railway line at Millertown Junction by a private single-track line. This was the only means of ground transport to Buchans until a road to the Trans-Canada highway was completed in 1955.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gill, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vv52x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429f03c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw3763b50f"><ual:graduationDate>1960</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A cytological survery of certain American species of the genus Gryllus Linnaeus, 1758, formerly Acheta, Fabricus, 1775, (Orthoptera: Gryllidae) and their hybrids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Randell, Robert. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mayr, Linsley and Usinger (1953) have defined three levels of taxonomic study; the first or alpha level dealing with the recognition and description of new species, the second or beta level dealing with the arrangements of these described species into the hierarchical system and the third or gamma level dealing with the study of infraspecific variation and the evolution of taxa. It is probably the general rule that, in any one group, progress is made by passing through these various levels in turn as they suggest in the following quotation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kevan, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vs17g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763b50f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>